Speaker 0: It's Thursday, February 11th, 2021.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We are talking about calendars.
Speaker 1: Let's do this All right?
Speaker 1: So when I was back in the office at work Right, I had this thing to play with.
Speaker 1: that was called the fidget cube that I kick-started.
Speaker 1: you can Pretty cheap.
Speaker 1: It's just like a little knobbly and it's got buttons and spinners and you know, whatever right wait Are you not having this?
Speaker 0: Is that why you keep fucking with the knob up for the volume on geek night?
Speaker 1: I'm not fucking with that knob.
Speaker 1: So, you know, I was just you know Thinking like hey, I should get something to fiddle with at my home desk.
Speaker 1: That thing is still at work.
Speaker 1: I can't go get it.
Speaker 0: In my work desk are two geek nights microphones one of my cameras and one of them is I Got like I had some good stuff at the work desk.
Speaker 0: Anyway, and hopefully I hope not but I think there might be an apple in my drawer.
Speaker 1: Hopefully someone found that anyway, so I was thinking oh what should I?
Speaker 1: you know, I should get something to fiddle with.
Speaker 1: and now I realized You know what?
Speaker 1: My whole life I've never solved the Rubik's Cube.
Speaker 1: they got to be cheap a few bucks, right?
Speaker 1: I don't have to get into the like the speed cubing hobby that you know, I just like do it once like feel it.
Speaker 1: It's like yeah, I just want to.
Speaker 1: I just want to learn how to do the Rubik's Cube slowly and you know Normally right.
Speaker 0: and it's like I've never worse the Rubik's Cube without.
Speaker 1: I was about to ask if you've solved one.
Speaker 0: Nope I uh as a kid like I wanted to but I realized that much like a fellow the Heuristics of doing it are not natural and I didn't find them interesting and I kind of decided to never bother.
Speaker 1: Well, let's talk about that.
Speaker 1: So So I got.
Speaker 1: so I got.
Speaker 1: not only did I get a Rubik's Cube, right I also saw that they had, you know You always see like they always have these.
Speaker 1: I knew that they had these more complex cubes for the people for whom The three by three is not enough.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah what I didn't know and what I ordered?
Speaker 1: I was thinking Hey, this will help get me to solve the three by three.
Speaker 1: They make a two by two Rubik's Cube list.
Speaker 0: I feel like larger cubes while there's more to do are actually easier, but I can't back that up by anything.
Speaker 1: No, the the bigger it is.
Speaker 1: It's harder.
Speaker 1: It's just more work.
Speaker 0: Oh my god Here's the world record for a 15 by 15.
Speaker 0: It takes 10 minutes Yep.
Speaker 1: So anyway, so I get the Rubik's Cube and I'm trying to learn, you know Just how to solve it slowly normally consciously, right?
Speaker 1: I know there's websites you can go to where you type it.
Speaker 1: You basically tell it what your cube looks like now and it tells you the moves to make to solve it Exactly and you know, but then I search and I'm like, okay, I don't want to Actually like speed cube, I don't just want to solve the cube right just I don't want to make it solved.
Speaker 1: I want to understand how to solve it, you know with my brain I'll admit I today do not understand the algorithms fundamentally to do it.
Speaker 1: Well, I learned some things, right?
Speaker 1: So the first thing that bothered me a lot is when you search on the internet for like how to solve Rubik's Cube Pretty much everyone is like, oh, here's the algorithms, right?
Speaker 1: But for them the algorithm is basically just memorize a series of steps.
Speaker 1: It's literally like memorize this right side forward top side left and it's like fuck you I don't want to just memorize.
Speaker 1: that's like telling me Oh to do a bubble sort.
Speaker 1: Just take the you know, the middle thing and it's like no I want to understand why you move that thing there on the same page.
Speaker 0: I wanted to know why my uncle when I was a kid was like trying to teach me the algorithms and that's part of why I don't like Rubik's Cubes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like every see.
Speaker 1: all the whole Rubik's Cube community seems to be revolving around.
Speaker 1: this Method is different methods, but they all involve like just memorizing like yeah, it's like no show me.
Speaker 1: How does it move?
Speaker 1: Why does that movement that you're doing?
Speaker 1: Why does that work?
Speaker 1: How does that get that piece from there to there without disturbing the other pieces or resetting them to where they started, right?
Speaker 1: How did you derive that algorithm?
Speaker 1: You can't derive that algorithm, right?
Speaker 1: From base, you know spatial reasoning.
Speaker 1: if all you have done is memorized it.
Speaker 1: I don't consider you to be someone who has solved the Rubik's Cube, right?
Speaker 0: You have implemented the solution to the Rubik's Cube Exactly, you couldn't.
Speaker 1: if you couldn't come up with that algorithm on your own, you know with no one helping you then you did not.
Speaker 0: You are high school geometry.
Speaker 0: show your proof.
Speaker 1: Show me the proof Exactly, and I couldn't find.
Speaker 1: I'm sure it's on the internet somewhere, but I couldn't find it.
Speaker 0: So I just googled for Rubik's Cube theory and I think I found it.
Speaker 1: But anyway, send me those links, but I did learn one thing on my own, right?
Speaker 1: I have reached the ability to where I can solve one layer of Rubik's Cube either on the small one or the big one.
Speaker 1: and what I learned is Basically, it's you know, since it's been how many the last time I even thought about a Rubik's Cube I must have been single-digit age, right?
Speaker 1: So, you know, I can play I can I can criticize my younger self for not realizing this But it's sort of obvious when you think about it, right?
Speaker 1: Let's say you look at the top of a Rubik's Cube, right and you see it's all the same color and you're like BAM.
Speaker 1: That side is solved, right?
Speaker 1: It's nine nine yellows, right?
Speaker 1: Well, actually No If you look at this cube here it the top layer is solved, right?
Speaker 1: It's all white.
Speaker 1: But when I look at one side, right because this is the same piece, right and it's like yeah It's white red green and you see three red on the side three blue on this side, right?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: See you could have a situation where you look at one face and it's all the same color But if you look at the edges of the pieces that are on that face, they're all jumbled up They're actually in the wrong spots.
Speaker 1: So I have derived.
Speaker 1: I Can do without any memorization of algorithm?
Speaker 1: I can solve one layer of any square Rubik's Cube given sufficient time now But I don't.
Speaker 1: what I need to figure out is, you know, I could just repeat that now to solve the bottom layer.
Speaker 1: But that leaves the middle track.
Speaker 1: Well the middle the middle first of all.
Speaker 1: The problem is a if I solve the bottom using the same method I used to solve the top.
Speaker 1: I'll mess up the top.
Speaker 1: And problem two if I is the middle right the the middle Center for pieces at least on a three by three they don't move.
Speaker 1: It's only the edge eight pieces on any face that move when you think about it, right?
Speaker 1: There's only you know, one two Three four, there's only six faces that you know of a cube.
Speaker 1: Yeah six faces.
Speaker 1: There's only six faces in two directions.
Speaker 1: So at any given time there's only 12 12 things to choose from.
Speaker 1: right is because each side is can go clockwise or counterclockwise.
Speaker 1: So at any given state.
Speaker 1: you have 12 things to choose from With at least with a three by three.
Speaker 1: the two by two similarly, but you have less things to choose from.
Speaker 1: Maybe same know the.
Speaker 1: so my two is actually the same number of choices, but the difference is this is no Center immovable pieces on it.
Speaker 0: So if you are interested, I'll post a link in the forum after this.
Speaker 0: but I found a page that talks about the mathematics of Rubik's Cubes and
Speaker 1: That sounds good, yeah,
Speaker 0: essentially this looks like what you want that the whole theory of them is around the idea of permutation groups Like groups of permutations, but the math is all shown by unrolling the cube into a 2d Representation
Speaker 1: where yeah, I've seen some.
Speaker 1: I've seen some things like that.
Speaker 1: This way if you look for example This is is a pamphlet.
Speaker 1: people on the stream can see the pamphlet, right?
Speaker 1: They came with the the cube and it's basically literally like oh if your cube looks like this Right memorize these steps right F and they have a code where it's like FR you are prime you F prime.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm basically just means counterclockwise.
Speaker 1: So it's like this means Oh, if your cube looks like this memorize, you know front face clockwise right face clockwise.
Speaker 1: You know top face clockwise right face counterclockwise up face counterclockwise front place clockwise.
Speaker 1: and it's like no That's not and I'm not.
Speaker 1: that's not what the point it is.
Speaker 0: Do you want to know why?
Speaker 0: Permutations do what they do.
Speaker 0: Fundamentals area of this.
Speaker 0: So the other thing I'm reading here is the gods number if you're encountered that yet That's not in this community.
Speaker 0: God's number is the Maximum number of moves required to solve any Rubik's Cube.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's interesting.
Speaker 1: and the answer for a three by three I've learned I think I think I read that there were like the total number of possible Arrangements of a three by three cube is like 16 quadrillion or some ridiculous number.
Speaker 0: Three by three by three can be solved in exactly 20 moves or less.
Speaker 0: No, okay, no matter what it was an estimated originally in the 80s to be 52.
Speaker 0: It was not known to be 20 until 2010 not that long as they used thanks to computers Thanks to a brute force computer idling thing that baby.
Speaker 1: Yes Of course But yeah, I think you know, the Rubik's Cube and stuff is interesting from a puzzle math perspective.
Speaker 1: I just personally don't find.
Speaker 1: I mean, there's definitely skill involved in the memorization and Dexterity fast and movement to solve quickly, but I'm not interested in any of that.
Speaker 0: You know in the same way that I appreciate the massive skill and complexity of like zoomed in MOBAs Like the the ape like the way you are good at a MOBA, but I am not interested in like that execution of my own.
Speaker 0: I'm interested in this higher level of the game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I can recommend a Rubik's Cube, you know what even if like I'm not sometimes I'm not even trying to solve it Just spinning it.
Speaker 1: It's just nice hand exercise.
Speaker 1: It just feels good to fit to spin it around even if you're not trying to solve it or thinking about it in a puzzle Sort of way.
Speaker 1: It's just a nice, you know, it's as good as the fidget cube was for spinning and fiddling.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I can recommend.
Speaker 1: I recommend the no I got.
Speaker 1: these are the first ones I've ever I've known they existed.
Speaker 1: But these are the first ones that I've personally handled that are not stickered.
Speaker 1: They're just you know plastic.
Speaker 0: Oh, wow Yeah, mine was like an old old old one that had the old stickers and was worn the fuck out.
Speaker 1: yeah, this is not.
Speaker 1: these are not stickered and The only thing I can say about I like that.
Speaker 1: they're not stickered because like they're gonna be permanently good-looking But they do get a little bit hand greasy, right?
Speaker 1: Cuz they're just sort of slick And as you fiddle with them, they get a little bit slimy and like you every time you mess with them a bunch You go wash your hands.
Speaker 1: so I recommend Some partially Rubik's Cube.
Speaker 1: It was it was.
Speaker 1: it's already been worthwhile to spend a few bucks just to get a cube.
Speaker 0: I'm never gonna get a station.
Speaker 1: I'm never gonna.
Speaker 1: yeah, I'm never getting a more than a 3x3 cube though.
Speaker 1: Screw that That's unnecessary.
Speaker 0: So in the news and we're not gonna talk about it because you can just watch it yourself.
Speaker 0: Nothing we say will in any way change our opinion But the impeachment trial is ongoing and honestly you should watch it on like go watch this.
Speaker 0: it's not that long like it's shorter than Wanda vision is gonna be and it's Interesting how very direct straightforward and simple the argument is.
Speaker 1: It's not you know, well if you think about it, right?
Speaker 1: It's a lot like, you know, you ever watch like Court TV or something like that, right?
Speaker 1: Usually those are kind of boring Yeah, and a lot of times those right.
Speaker 1: here is a case about something that at least Indirectly involves every person in the country.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right is and basically you are you know It's.
Speaker 1: it's just being presented to a jury, right?
Speaker 1: And so you're just hearing a case as if you were a jury And there's lawyers telling you trying to convince you to vote guilty or not guilty.
Speaker 1: And the thing is I don't think anything here.
Speaker 0: Challenge any with trial.
Speaker 1: it's not it's a puzzle not affect the right.
Speaker 1: It's not going to affect the outcome It's not going to change anyone's mind whether they're a senator or not.
Speaker 1: You know me maybe this somewhere someone whose mind will be changed by this.
Speaker 0: But there's like that that small amount of like quote-unquote centrist in the suburbs of like the Midwest.
Speaker 1: Yes, these imaginary non-existent person.
Speaker 1: but What I think is good about watching it Is that if you I mean if you're on the the Trump side it is like there's no hope for you.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like you stop.
Speaker 1: Why are you even listening to this kid?
Speaker 0: How did you find this podcast?
Speaker 1: Right, but if you're a good person, right you Might not fully understand like, you know the nature of the crime.
Speaker 0: I would use the word in Normandy in this case.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a good word.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so think about like another crime.
Speaker 1: think about like it's like, you know, Charles Manson way bad, right?
Speaker 1: you've heard of Charles Manson, but do you really know all the details of exactly what Charles Manson did and how horrifying and how bad Of a person that person is?
Speaker 1: but also you really?
Speaker 1: what?
Speaker 0: what were the cross like legally?
Speaker 0: what crimes did he?
Speaker 0: Actually commit compared to his followers and why is he in jail?
Speaker 0: despite that?
Speaker 0: that is a really important thing to know Right, so that's important.
Speaker 1: it's kind of important to know well that concept not that particular case necessary, right, right that pretty right.
Speaker 1: But it's like do you really need to know about Charles and specifically in your life?
Speaker 1: You're living right now?
Speaker 1: Not really, but this is much more important to know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right and but it's the same questions, right?
Speaker 1: It's like yeah, you know that they you know The former president incited an insurrection attack against the White House the White House the cap.
Speaker 1: Right, okay, right trying to overthrow the government, but do you really know everything that went down there?
Speaker 1: It seems kind of important that.
Speaker 1: maybe you should know that like Details of that.
Speaker 0: I said this before on Twitter, but this trial which again is short It is shorter than like most anime you will ever watch gonna be.
Speaker 1: it's gonna be over pretty soon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and Like there is going to be an entire goddamn chapter about this in social studies books
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm,
Speaker 0: just like when you were a kid and you had the lesson on like that like times like monumental events in American history like when they signed the Constitution when they did the equal rights like this is gonna be that level of big deal.
Speaker 1: Well, I think that's the thing is like you go we we go to school at least in the United States, right?
Speaker 1: And then after school, that's it.
Speaker 1: Any further learning is on you.
Speaker 1: Yep, right and You know if the later on you go to school and also many other factors obviously.
Speaker 1: But the more at least in history class the more history you learn.
Speaker 1: but also in other classes, right?
Speaker 1: Maybe in physics class if we've discovered more physics.
Speaker 1: Yeah Since I was in high school Someone who takes a physics class now has the opportunity to learn things like archaea and were discovered after I graduated high school in college.
Speaker 1: Fundamental ideas about biology have radically changed since I was in high school Exactly, but history is the most because that one's constant right sometimes, you know some sciences and maths, you know It's like how often is there new trigonometry?
Speaker 1: History happens every day Quoting someone.
Speaker 0: I remember who but there was.
Speaker 0: I might have been one of the Green Brothers But they made a point that was literally like but history is always happening.
Speaker 0: It never stops happening
Speaker 1: So it'll later on you go to history because so it's up to you no matter who you are Right or no matter what your life is like right to spend some amount of it I'm not saying what amount because that varies wildly but on catching up on the history that happened since you were in school Yep, right and which is the best way to do it would be to catch up entirely and then just pay attention to what's happening Right now a little bit every day.
Speaker 0: Yep, and then you're you're good, but the thing about this trailer trial I really want to highlight and honestly don't even you may not even need to watch the defense because it's not even a legal argument.
Speaker 1: It's not worth your time.
Speaker 0: It literally was not a legal argument.
Speaker 1: Like they did not actually argue Anything anyway, but you could watch it just to understand how awful it was.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the point I want to like the thing to really look at is that It seems like government and these kinds of things are very complex and law is really complex and it like normal people don't really Like think about it on this detail level.
Speaker 0: but one of the most important skills in the world is to take something complex and Explain it simply.
Speaker 0: and this trial like the house impeachment managers This is like a case study.
Speaker 0: in taking something that was complex and describing it simply they are doing such an amazing job That even if you don't know anything about American government or history or politics you will understand a lot by the end of just.
Speaker 1: I highly recommend People from other countries watch this not because you know that you know.
Speaker 1: I think the u.s.
Speaker 1: Is worth paying attention to if you're lucky enough not to live here But also if anyone in another country Right has a similar thing from your country along these lines for us to watch Right, like maybe there was.
Speaker 1: I've watched at least a few You know like trials of like various.
Speaker 0: I watched a sub war criminals.
Speaker 0: I watched one of these places in Poland because Poland is getting like fascist right-wing in a hurry.
Speaker 0: But I was watching some of those debates around abortion because they were.
Speaker 0: it's a lot.
Speaker 0: The Polish law is so fundamentally different from American law in terms like Poland.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the the only news I've seen from Poland which which really made me curious was how basically the right-wing people are also Instituting some amount of left-wing social program.
Speaker 1: It's like free health care and also Right, it's like this mix of like.
Speaker 1: where is it?
Speaker 1: You know, you couldn't imagine that mix possibly in the United States, right?
Speaker 0: well The United States is interesting in that everything is divided into literally a side where and every idea is bad and a side that is Literally everything.
Speaker 0: yet those bad ideas.
Speaker 1: but but but imagine if like, you know The Republicans right in the United States who are just like, you know literal white supremacists.
Speaker 1: We're also like we're all we're also and on the side of Medicare for all and the Democrats weren't Medicare for all But the Democrats weren't white supremacist.
Speaker 1: that level of partisanship I've seen multiple scholars are and it's sort of like trying to convince you to vote for the white supremacist.
Speaker 1: cuz hey free hunger.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, sure.
Speaker 1: They'll do and they were let's say the Republicans were also doing the free student loans.
Speaker 0: And I've seen multiple scholars argue recently that the Part the partisan divide in America is unique on the global stage.
Speaker 0: right now There are.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's like wouldn't that?
Speaker 1: it's like if you're a if you're actually a strategic, you know white supremacist.
Speaker 1: Why wouldn't you Trojan horse your white supremacy you actually care about inside of the social program?
Speaker 0: But no one of the are ages I saw they want all their cake.
Speaker 0: One of those articles was very succinct and it pointed out that the white supremacist violent extremists who are evil and awful But they exist in Europe.
Speaker 0: They believe that climate change is real.
Speaker 0: They believe awful things about what to do about it But they don't disagree that it is happening.
Speaker 0: yet in America that became a partisan issue.
Speaker 0: So right-wing people also don't believe climate change is real.
Speaker 0: hmm, anyway anyway in some other news a Hacker tried to poison an entire city's water supply last week.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so this is something we've know.
Speaker 1: we've talked about this on Mondays a lot.
Speaker 1: It's definitely a real threat.
Speaker 0: I'm sure this never happened before like this was.
Speaker 0: we've known.
Speaker 1: this has been a real threat.
Speaker 1: But obviously much of the infrastructure in the world, but especially the United States is hooked up to computer systems.
Speaker 1: Yep Ideally those computer systems should not be connected to the internet in any way.
Speaker 1: ever.
Speaker 1: if a computer is controlling the power plants There should be no way to connect to that computer right via internet.
Speaker 0: Right the super powerful computer that had the secret shit was not on the internet.
Speaker 0: Tom Cruise had to break into that building to get that data exactly, and that's you know in that way.
Speaker 1: a you know, sure the computer should still be updated and secured to prevent say Insiders from messing with it, right?
Speaker 1: You know It's just sitting there Unlocked and anyone in the power plant like the janitor could walk over and push your button to turn the power off.
Speaker 1: That's a problem.
Speaker 1: But at least if it's not in the internet, no one else can do it, right?
Speaker 1: You have to get into the power plant to begin with and this power plants right near us.
Speaker 1: They're surrounded with walls.
Speaker 1: It's not easy to get in rain.
Speaker 1: There's barbed wire and shit.
Speaker 1: It's not friend.
Speaker 1: It's not fun.
Speaker 1: So it's also dangerous to try to get in there.
Speaker 0: so in terms of water supply stuff It is really easy to break into those physical Sure is cuz well cuz.
Speaker 1: water supply.
Speaker 1: unlike power plants power plants are much more easy to defend.
Speaker 1: they're centralized and all right.
Speaker 0: There's people like water and beacons.
Speaker 0: city water is all we used to live in Beacon, right?
Speaker 0: There's a reservoir up in the mountains like Janda's water.
Speaker 1: There's water stuff like all over like a cell tower.
Speaker 1: It's like cell towers just be sitting there in the woods.
Speaker 1: No one's guarding one all day.
Speaker 1: It's just got a little fence around it.
Speaker 1: You could bust in there.
Speaker 1: Maybe someone will know.
Speaker 1: Maybe some alarm gets triggered or maybe there's a camera or something.
Speaker 0: It's illegal to swim and then You know who swims in.
Speaker 0: that has has swum in that reservoir many times.
Speaker 1: everyone and you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a bunch of our friends Sure, but but this is unsecured.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry God.
Speaker 1: No, I'm just saying is that we've known for a long time that the infrastructure and their computers.
Speaker 1: You should be doing these things and by and large we are not we have.
Speaker 1: it's a known vulnerability that some people are watching out for.
Speaker 1: but if you wanted to attack the Infrastructure of the United States right telecommunications power water utilities Things of that nature the telecommunications are probably more secured but in general you could do it.
Speaker 1: It's there a lot of things that are set up poorly and a lot of those systems are You know not centrally or uniformly set up.
Speaker 1: They're set up by Municipalities in various places with various levels of technical expertise.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, so One of the I've always thought that Like one of the things that gives me a little bit of hope for humanity Because there's a lot of reasons to not have a lot of hope for humanity.
Speaker 0: Especially lately is that despite how utterly easy it would be to stage those kinds of attacks They have been shockingly rare in America until now where this happened and it happened for real.
Speaker 0: what had?
Speaker 0: the summary is Some hacker got into a system and I'll talk about that in a second because now we know more as of like this morning.
Speaker 0: We know everything now and everything that system controls in Florida, Florida, by the way Yeah controls the chemical balance of the water treatment facility Mmm, they poked around at it and then left it alone.
Speaker 0: They returned later and Did the specific thing that would cause the most harm to people as fast as possible?
Speaker 0: There is like clear intent that they wanted to poison the water supply.
Speaker 0: They basically turned the lie level to maximum.
Speaker 0: that would have made the water undrinkable and dangerous.
Speaker 0: It also might pretty much really corroded the infrastructure.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if there's if there's anything you could do with access to that computer system to cause the most harm That was it.
Speaker 1: That was the other thing you've damaged.
Speaker 1: there are other things you could have done if you had axe Unrestricted access to that system but like maybe cause a flood or who knows what you have done But that was probably most likely the most harmful thing you could have done now If you had done it successfully.
Speaker 0: there were other detection safeguards in place through other facilities and other systems such that if this hacker had succeeded and not getting caught the Poisoned water would have been prevented from getting further But it might have destroyed that water supply and caused a lot of problem.
Speaker 0: It was not a good situation, but it is unlikely due to another set of controls that it would have actually poisoned People in that town before the water was just cut off though.
Speaker 1: The people were in no time where the people actually Sure Yep, anyway so so Now we know exactly how they got in.
Speaker 0: they used some remote desktop software that a called team viewer.
Speaker 0: That is Widely used around the world to give access to system.
Speaker 1: I never even heard of.
Speaker 1: I've heard of VNC go to meeting.
Speaker 1: I know Apple has one built in I'm pretty sure and is my.
Speaker 0: Microsoft has the one built into Windows And I was like, oh, it's probably go to meeting or some shit like.
Speaker 0: that team viewer is Scarily widely used.
Speaker 0: it is software that basically lets you open up a Windows computer So that other people can connect to it to perform maintenance with some amount of authentication.
Speaker 0: It is ripe for abuse like I would not.
Speaker 1: most and using that thing I hear most about remote desktops is how like if you fall for one of those Scam phone calls or emails about tech support.
Speaker 0: That's the first thing they do.
Speaker 1: They make you install some remote desktop thing and then they use it, right?
Speaker 1: It's like it's not.
Speaker 1: Obviously.
Speaker 1: don't use remote desktop for anything ever anymore.
Speaker 1: I used to use it back in the day But now I use it for nothing.
Speaker 0: I use it for work in that during kovat times one of the BCP things I have is I can just remote into my desktop in the office and have everything be exactly like It would be.
Speaker 1: my work computer is a laptop that I brought home and as I'm has been on my desk since you know I've been home, but also any connection I have to make to work is via VPN and SSH.
Speaker 0: Do that, but I don't because I'm not an engineer like.
Speaker 0: I don't need access to all those systems.
Speaker 0: So it's much easier to just use my desktop at work or log into the thing directly because you know We don't just have a work laptop that you can.
Speaker 0: just I could get one.
Speaker 0: I chose not to Hmm.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that's all I have.
Speaker 0: Yep So one the only reason this was caught and this disaster was diverted was that a human happened to notice that the mouse was moving on the screen and He was like and they happen to be paying it to have to actually be paying attention at that moment.
Speaker 0: Yep, like literally dude happened to see it briefly walking by.
Speaker 0: so we're really lucky this got caught - This whole system is controlled by like unpatched Windows 7 machines running team viewer.
Speaker 0: yep, this is a shit show and Short of the US actually.
Speaker 1: but the thing is that while it was a shit show it seems like the People handling it after the fact are.
Speaker 1: it seems like they're just going about it, you know
Speaker 0: while Security is basically bullshit pretty much everywhere except tech companies and capital markets companies like there's no security anywhere else because I know hospitals like medical stuff is secure because of the lack of regulations and Also the brain drain the brain drain in this case being There's a small number of industries that can afford to pay a lot of money and they hire all The good tech people like all of them.
Speaker 0: So us like the water supply They cannot afford someone who is good at security that nor can they afford the software or the effort it would take to actually implement Security.
Speaker 1: they can only outsource to a consultancy that does have tech people that are split across that and many other things.
Speaker 0: Security is just garbage at best every if they choose to pay for it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the people who work in these places, even if they are not that technologically savvy They are aware of how insecure and bullshit this is there.
Speaker 0: in my experience those people are Constantly complaining to and like telling their management and anyone who will listen that this is a disaster waiting to happen and everyone ignores them.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, I always remember that story when from the Obama days when Hillary Clinton was Secretary of State Oh, yeah, and all the State Department people, right?
Speaker 1: so the State Department people must have some technical savvy, but they're Largely diplomats and and that sort of foreign affairs people right that they know about passports.
Speaker 1: They're not more than they know about computers All right, and they were making a big deal that they really wanted to use Firefox on there.
Speaker 1: It was like a huge deal for like like one or two days in the news how they really wanted to use Firefox.
Speaker 1: and it's like because they knew just like how shitty like the rules or their computer systems were.
Speaker 1: that the.
Speaker 1: you know We're under federal government restrictions right and other federal employees that I know also often complain about how The computer systems are.
Speaker 1: and some things are because a it is more secure and therefore more of a pain in the ass Just like having ten locks on your door, you know and special hinges that can't be you know hammered or whatever Is more secure but also more of a pain in the ass, but also just also shitty Yeah, and not good.
Speaker 0: So moving on a little bit in some other news really briefly if you didn't see this.
Speaker 0: so there's an actress who played a good character in the Mandalorian and She was a super piece of shit.
Speaker 1: Like the actress was.
Speaker 1: the character in the show is not a piece of character was actually like very good person But was played by actress.
Speaker 1: playing the character in that person in real life was a piece of shit.
Speaker 0: Yep, and For better or worse what?
Speaker 0: while we're continuing to be a vile piece of shit She stepped over the line where even Disney and like everyone all the professionals involved had to do something.
Speaker 0: So they fired her her talent.
Speaker 0: a post editor share her characters just out of the Mandalorian forever done.
Speaker 1: Yep, she posted, you know stupid shit on the internet on her social.
Speaker 0: She went Saying Republican things which is evil to saying like Directly racist things to then being full-on QAnon like in a hurry.
Speaker 1: Well, well then they just yeah Just like goodbye.
Speaker 1: None of those are protected class so you can be fired for that.
Speaker 0: So, uh, I'm assuming it's just yet.
Speaker 0: her x-wing crashed and there were no survivors something like that.
Speaker 0: so last something that we are also somewhat heated about as you might notice there's a global pandemic going on, but Madison Square Garden in New York City is gonna be allowed and is going to actually do it.
Speaker 0: They're gonna let some fans come and watch sports live.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this makes no sense to me, right?
Speaker 1: So in other states, they've been doing this and it Like.
Speaker 1: I saw them like the number of people at the Super Bowl.
Speaker 1: while at one on the one hand It looked like more people than it was because of the car cutouts in the stand and other effects They used to look more crowded Was still way too crowded.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well cuz on one hand sure It's like sort of outdoors and like it's a big space everyone spread out but you could clearly see like when the halftime show was starting.
Speaker 0: they did this like pan and All those people who had been spread out were all clumped together going to the bathroom at the same time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, anyway, so the point is even if you're spread out It's like why are you going to a large gathering of people right at the height of the original?
Speaker 1: Bump and pandemic and like April right the numbers I'm looking at for New York at least Were like seven day average.
Speaker 1: nine thousand cases, right?
Speaker 1: So currently right?
Speaker 1: We've been in in like, you know, January.
Speaker 1: We were way over that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we were like 16,000 seven-day average.
Speaker 1: it's been going down since January and you would presume that co-ed at least correlates to vaccines.
Speaker 1: So it looks like vaccines working which is good news, but It's currently at 80. let's see yesterday two days.
Speaker 1: Yeah yesterday.
Speaker 1: It says current.
Speaker 1: the number I'm looking at on Google is 8,500 seven-day average.
Speaker 1: that's pretty close to that nine.
Speaker 1: It's only like a thousand less than the seven-day average from the peak in April when basically everything was shut down everywhere.
Speaker 1: So, why would you why would be at the same number?
Speaker 1: shouldn't we still be shut down everywhere with the same number, right?
Speaker 1: Shouldn't like in the summer when the number was really low like hundreds of cases We were way less open than we are now, right?
Speaker 1: Oh, you couldn't have a concert this summer But why would you allow people to have a concert now when we're the lowest when everything was closed?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like just like just it's just a dream.
Speaker 1: go back to the extreme.
Speaker 0: It's rolling out like there's light at the end of the tunnel.
Speaker 0: Just like send people some income and Guarantee rent for restaurants and just ride it out.
Speaker 0: We're near the just extreme extreme.
Speaker 1: shut down everything like no one is allowed to go Outside.
Speaker 1: fuck you unless you're an essentially, you know an essential person.
Speaker 1: everyone else stay inside like core like not even quarantine like What's it called curfew 24/7.
Speaker 1: you may not leave your house for it.
Speaker 0: You let you accept unless you're a deliverer is a point in the early days where the right answer Was the military and National Guard being deployed to distribute food to people who are not allowed to leave their homes.
Speaker 1: If we just did that for probably I'm not, you know, not an expert on this, right?
Speaker 1: But it feels like you know, if you just did that for a month and kept distributing vaccines like yeah, right But instead no, they want to open up and let 2,000 people go watch hockey games.
Speaker 1: So the thing that bothers me the most is not only this nonsensical business, right?
Speaker 1: but the people who are defending it, yep, and The people defending it and this is just a general problem I think in the whole world, especially in the US but also the rest of the world is just this like Devaluing of you know, not just you know Not just like a racist person who devalues the human life of people who aren't like them But the devaluing of just any human life like even someone who's just like you.
Speaker 1: it's like somebody I wrote.
Speaker 1: I wrote a comment like, you know, shut it down and someone was like.
Speaker 1: the comment they made was What 99% survival rate I'll take my chances.
Speaker 1: and it's like hold on right?
Speaker 1: So You're telling me that a you're fine with getting horrifically sick, you know And losing your sense of taste and smell possibly for a long time more permanently To watch a hockey game in person or to eat at a restaurant.
Speaker 1: It's that's worth the risk to you.
Speaker 1: Yeah What's wrong with you?
Speaker 0: the list of beings that I would be willing to risk a 1% chance of death on?
Speaker 0: Like near the top of that list are ridiculous things like saving someone's life saving the world doing some ridiculous ski thing.
Speaker 0: You know, what's at the bottom of that list?
Speaker 0: eating at a TGI Fridays, right?
Speaker 1: I know I would need TGI Fridays, even if there was no Right.
Speaker 1: But you're also risking other people's lives to do this thing, right?
Speaker 1: You know the usher at the Madison Square Garden has to go to work where they haven't been working.
Speaker 1: now You're gonna make them go there and risk their life, right?
Speaker 1: But the other argument, okay.
Speaker 1: So let's say you let 2,000 people let you.
Speaker 1: so, okay.
Speaker 1: So let's say you take your chances, right?
Speaker 1: You're letting 2,000 people go in one.
Speaker 1: if it's a super spreader event, which it very well could be 1% of people die, right?
Speaker 1: What's 1% of 2,000 20 people?
Speaker 1: Okay, you we're gonna.
Speaker 1: you're basically saying it's okay to kill like dead 20 people so that they can watch a hockey game.
Speaker 1: That's worth it.
Speaker 1: So let's all right.
Speaker 1: if we think if you say that that's worth it We're gonna take the 20 people from your family.
Speaker 1: You take 20 people that you love and care about and we're gonna sacrifice them on an altar Right, and that will be the 20 deaths.
Speaker 1: and now everyone can watch hockey.
Speaker 1: Are you okay with that?
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you're not okay with that then shut the fuck up and stay home.
Speaker 0: And also They trot.
Speaker 0: they pick 20 people out of the audience.
Speaker 0: They line them up They shoot them on the air and then the hockey game proceeds.
Speaker 1: Right, or how about this right?
Speaker 1: If you're okay with that, that means you're okay with.
Speaker 1: okay, you know We'll sell you this hockey ticket, right?
Speaker 1: They're gonna have 2,000 hockey tickets.
Speaker 1: We're gonna sell them right and then we're gonna pick 20 random numbers from 1 to 2,000 and those 20 people will be shot In the head.
Speaker 1: well, are you gonna still buy that hockey ticket?
Speaker 1: Well, no Then you were fogging lying when you said you're gonna take your chances weren't you?
Speaker 0: now?
Speaker 0: the the main argument people make when they're not Like excited about sports is always back to the economy.
Speaker 0: But I just want to remind you and let's not get too deep into this to run to our main bit The economy is fake.
Speaker 0: like the government could just give people money to stay home.
Speaker 0: They don't because the Republicans refuse to.
Speaker 1: the government could.
Speaker 1: just even if you don't give people money you can do the equivalent Things like just say yeah, all right food is free and you know Rent is illegal.
Speaker 1: Everyone is a lot every if you can find any squatting is legal right now.
Speaker 1: if you're homeless and you can find a place that No one's living you're allowed to live in it.
Speaker 1: In fact, you own it now.
Speaker 1: tough shit to whoever owned the property before.
Speaker 1: If no one is living there, it's not yours anymore.
Speaker 1: That's all perfectly legal.
Speaker 1: They could just if they write laws.
Speaker 0: you can write almost anything in a law like, you know, the Constitution is I Don't blame as much like the restaurant that that's owned by someone and they open because they're allowed to because otherwise they can't make Their rent and can't feed their family.
Speaker 0: But you know who it deserves the most blame the people who fucking eat at that restaurant when it's open Exactly, but if everyone was good and didn't go eat People who well done anything in the people eat at the restaurant get the second most blame.
Speaker 1: the first most blame government for letting The government that didn't just give them money and also the landlord who continues to charge rent, even though it's a pandemic.
Speaker 1: Yep, right Those are the top the the top baddies.
Speaker 0: and the worst part is there were Proposed.
Speaker 1: if I owned a building and I was a landlord and I had first of all, I wouldn't do that But I wouldn't be evil right, but if I was a landlord and I was already, you know charging rent I wouldn't have charged.
Speaker 1: read the whole pandemic time.
Speaker 1: It's just obvious, right?
Speaker 0: And if you couldn't afford to do that again the government at least not.
Speaker 1: not.
Speaker 1: if that if the tenant could afford it I'd still charge him.
Speaker 0: Well, like the government could have not a restaurant to do things like they could have done even capitalist things like freeze rent Guarantee the income of the landlords and sort it all out after kovat.
Speaker 0: But they didn't do it.
Speaker 1: You don't even have to guarantee the income of the landlord You can just cancel their property tax for the same period.
Speaker 1: That's most where their money has that.
Speaker 0: oh that now we can't afford to pay for the schools.
Speaker 0: Guess what?
Speaker 0: Just raise taxes.
Speaker 1: Not the property tax though, right Some other tax not the property one.
Speaker 0: Yeah raise the taxes.
Speaker 0: Maybe I don't know.
Speaker 0: text Amazon and rich people.
Speaker 0: Yeah
Speaker 1: Something yeah things that are making money off the pandemic just be like hey Every Amazon package that gets delivered right you put a tax on it and then you say well Amazon You're not allowed to you just you're right and everyone's like oh if you do that Then you know this, you know Cuz there was someone who had that idea and but their idea was that the people ordering would end up having to pay that tax And the idea is to try to get them to shop locally.
Speaker 1: instead.
Speaker 1: It's like oh you could just write you could just write in the law.
Speaker 1: Right just add more words and say yeah We are gonna tax every package that's delivered and Amazon is the one that has to pay.
Speaker 1: you're not allowed to pass the buck on To the customer.
Speaker 1: You're not allowed to raise prices.
Speaker 1: You could have made it against the law.
Speaker 1: make more and if you're and then you write you could write in the law.
Speaker 1: if the Company is caught raising prices on the customer or passing this tax on to the customer Then the entire company is owned by the government nationalized the.
Speaker 1: you could write any consequence you go out you could write Yeah, penalty.
Speaker 1: death penalty is still legal.
Speaker 1: He's not in New York, but it's like.
Speaker 1: I'm not and I'm against the death penalty, obviously But you could say if your company commits these crimes the CEO is subject to capital punishment.
Speaker 1: That's pertinent legal and the only thing you can't do it could be done.
Speaker 0: It's a bill of attainder.
Speaker 0: And if you don't know what that is, the impeachment trial will actually explain it and you'll know Sure, but anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: so this is funny like it's one of those funny YouTube mashup things, but I cannot stress enough the shocking high level of quality effort and care of The Legend of Beavis.
Speaker 0: like this would have been funny if they had done a half-assed joke like if they had made like a two-minute YouTube video, this would have been funny, but My hat is off to the creator of the Legend of Beavis.
Speaker 0: This goes above and beyond what is reasonable.
Speaker 1: Well, you're already like a Beavis and Butthead person.
Speaker 0: I'm already.
Speaker 0: I was so I've started watching Beavis and Butthead near at the beginning of its run.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I watched it when you know the beginning of its run.
Speaker 1: I watched it, you know, occasionally, right?
Speaker 0: My whole family would sit down and like watch it.
Speaker 0: This is what I was very young.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I would just watch it now and then you know when it was on.
Speaker 0: I was always a big fan of Beavis and Butthead but until later seasons I was mostly only a fan of them MST3K-ing the music videos because the cartoon was okay But just like super violent and weird.
Speaker 1: but the cartoon depended on which some of the episodes were more or less, right?
Speaker 0: but this is the Legend of Zelda cartoon the Nintendo one that was like weird and part of the Super Mario Brothers Super Show and Excuse me princess, etc.
Speaker 0: But they've.
Speaker 0: they've kept the voice of the princess normal but they've replaced link with Beavis and the king with Butthead and It's just perfect.
Speaker 0: It is too funny for this earth.
Speaker 1: This is definitely along the lines of a Charles.
Speaker 0: Yep This is Literally like.
Speaker 0: it is a coherent story.
Speaker 0: It makes sense Every use of Beavis and Butthead in this.
Speaker 0: this could be an episode of a real show and you wouldn't know if you'd never heard of Beavis and Butthead.
Speaker 1: Maybe yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So my thing of the day, this is a really short video.
Speaker 1: It's like really quick But yeah, you know In this video, right?
Speaker 1: We always have this I guess sort of stereotyped image of the police in Japan.
Speaker 1: I'm sure some of it is based on fact but not having been there I can't say right but you know through anime through you know The Japanese things nerds see right you get this image of the Japanese police that they're more polite, right?
Speaker 1: They're not you know.
Speaker 1: Like the you you know There's like little police standing in police boxes that you can go and say hi to and get help from in the neighborhood Right.
Speaker 1: I know that that is a thing, right?
Speaker 1: I don't know how widespread it still is.
Speaker 0: Can you imagine tapping on one of those little police boxes in the subway and asking the cop in there to do it?
Speaker 1: They'd be like what the fuck you want.
Speaker 1: But anyway So this video which looks like it's real footage You see a Japanese police car and with the limited Japanese language I know I can basically saying tell that over the little PA megaphone that they have in the police car They're they're yelling at the person on a scooter and they're basically saying excuse me.
Speaker 1: Would you would you pull over please, right?
Speaker 1: Like, you know, right they're politely asking the scooter to pull over.
Speaker 1: is that they can?
Speaker 1: there must be something about them that they need to be pulled over for.
Speaker 1: or you know some reason the cops want to pull them over even if it's wrong or a wrong reason.
Speaker 1: right because Cops are bad in every country And the scooter gets away or obviously because otherwise it wouldn't be a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: how the scooter gets away is Right, and that's why it's worth.
Speaker 1: it's worth, you know, and then whoever edited this video put a little Grand Theft Auto joke on there at the end.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is worth what the 30 to 60 seconds of your time it takes to watch this video.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz the lead.
Speaker 1: maybe maybe this technique will help you in life.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz the letter writing a scooter or a bicycle and the cops are asking politely asking to pull you over ten minutes long.
Speaker 0: Oh, wow, but it it continued like it is ten minutes of that high quality like they went all out complete perfect lip-sync and everything dang.
Speaker 0: But uh, yeah Driver, please stop on the left side of the road.
Speaker 0: Like if I translated it, I think the voice would be like, please Please stop driver, please.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so metamoment we're stuck at home not reading books playing train games.
Speaker 0: It's all I got.
Speaker 1: Yeah, come and look for us on the Internet if for some reason you're watching this or listening to it or whatever and you have Not gone on your favorite big website, right?
Speaker 1: We even have a subreddit.
Speaker 1: not that anything's going on there.
Speaker 1: It's not that anyone's in there, but it exists, right?
Speaker 1: It hasn't been posted on in maybe years I don't know but it exists.
Speaker 1: We got a Twitter.
Speaker 1: We got a. we even have a Facebook.
Speaker 1: There's nothing there either Instagram.
Speaker 1: so we got everything.
Speaker 1: Go to those places Follow us in those places.
Speaker 1: You mean you're listening to me talking right now.
Speaker 1: You must Want to also do that right like go to our YouTube channels and subscribe to them, right?
Speaker 1: It's like Or unsubscribe from all of those things because you don't and stop listening right now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like we got discord Server we got a forum right.
Speaker 1: just so go to our website My front row crew calm and from there and plus.
Speaker 1: with your Google skills combined and the word geek nights You should be able to find us pretty much everywhere.
Speaker 1: You know how to use internet, right?
Speaker 1: so There you go.
Speaker 0: All right, so You got ideas for Thursday shows let us know.
Speaker 0: so we're gonna talk about Calendars.
Speaker 1: so I thought of this show idea because there was some Secret Santa going on in December, right?
Speaker 1: It's obviously February already.
Speaker 0: Oh my god This is just a February You know, what's really making it feel long is all the normal breaks of like all these conventions Like this is the middle of convention season.
Speaker 1: Yep but anyway.
Speaker 1: So the things I put on my secret Santa list because I don't want anything right was donate to non evil charity in my name Something to hang on the front door of our apartment like in the hallway Right like a welcome sign kind of thing because we only have some of those for certain seasons and we don't have them for other seasons And they're kind of hard to find ones that are better that you know Fit and suit the bill and are tasteful and aren't gaudy or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And then the other one I wrote was like a cool calendar right from you know, a cool independent artist.
Speaker 1: That is really awesome, right?
Speaker 1: So what showed up in the Secret Santa was the calendar is some calendar that from the I was.
Speaker 1: I was first I was a little worried because actually the cover of the calendar has a sort of It basically an art that looks like the Baron from Whisper of the heart.
Speaker 1: it was okay, but then inside every single month in the calendar was like incredible and I was like, whoa Okay, this is the cover is like probably the worst art in the whole calendar, right?
Speaker 1: So I was very happy with that calendar and I'm like, okay Can we do a show on calendars if we bring in all the other calendar related topics?
Speaker 1: Not just calendars themselves the physical object But also, you know calendars in terms of like lunar calendar Gregorian Right, but also if we really need to stretch it we can talk about like planners right agenda books You know a digital calendar even though it reaches into Monday territory.
Speaker 1: Yeah We can talk about that.
Speaker 0: until the food shows up I think we'll go all the way back.
Speaker 0: cuz I'm in like we grew up in a pre digital era.
Speaker 0: So for most of my life I needed a calendar like like physically like I needed a calendar to know what day it was.
Speaker 1: Yeah Even the oldest computers, let's say you were mega-rich right in the 80s and you had like IBM whatever XT, right?
Speaker 1: It's like Yeah, that could tell you the date and time because there's a battery in there like Every time you want.
Speaker 1: it's like it is Yeah, but even if you just leave it on all the time, it's like well, you're not running a clock app.
Speaker 1: You know what, you know, it's like it only runs one application at a time.
Speaker 1: If you app you're running doesn't have a clock in it on display.
Speaker 1: That's not helping you, right?
Speaker 1: You have a you have an actual clock and an actual calendar somewhere right your computer like, you know There weren't like you think.
Speaker 1: Oh Google Calendar, right?
Speaker 1: So you can go back in time and look at calendar apps at a certain point Calendar apps disappear like yeah, was there even a calendar app for Windows 95?
Speaker 0: By then I wasn't like doing that kind of thing in there, but it's like you didn't.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like there might have been but like it wasn't, you know.
Speaker 1: But now you get a phone and calendar app is like a default built-in thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there it is.
Speaker 0: It's interesting because when I think back When I like calendars were in pop culture like in sitcoms everywhere like you in movies You see like a calendar with like a date circle Like that would be a thing and that was normal people's lives.
Speaker 0: Like when I was a kid like I could walk through the kitchen and I could look at the calendar and I'd see dates circled and if I was a Kid was curious like oh When is the dog going to the vet?
Speaker 0: or when's mom's birthday?
Speaker 0: because I'm a kid and I don't remember all that stuff.
Speaker 0: Like when are we going to grandma grandpa's house?
Speaker 0: Like they were all just written in pen on a calendar I could just look at and the whole family would like put their shit on this shared calendar.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: We also.
Speaker 1: there was a lot of different styles of calendars, too.
Speaker 1: I'm sure all the styles still exist, but it's like there was the style obviously the standard wall calendar Which I think one we used as a family.
Speaker 0: There's a big one.
Speaker 0: I still like a big wall calendar, right?
Speaker 1: But the one I got here that I got from the you know, Secret Santa it's like yeah, it's a wall calendar.
Speaker 1: But actually it's appropriately the the actual calendar part of it is just tiny and it's just a bunch of numbers and there's not really like.
Speaker 1: you couldn't Plan anything on this right?
Speaker 1: it.
Speaker 1: more than half of the paper is just artwork, right?
Speaker 1: It's a decoration more that you change every month more than it is.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah for a long time Our family calendar was a giant one that had no real art in it.
Speaker 0: It was literally just like it had enough space to put every up.
Speaker 1: You also that that giant style.
Speaker 1: They also used to make ones that were the giant style and you'd put them flat on your desk Right and like you wouldn't.
Speaker 1: this is before people had keyboards, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, like you would sit at your desk and there, you know, you might be doing something on top of the calendar But your calendar was like your desk mat underneath everything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was how I would do my homework on my.
Speaker 1: I have not seen anyone do that style calendar on any desk in like a very, you know,
Speaker 0: funnily enough I was watching a little bit of Rutenna because I'm still poking at the Rutenna thing and I just I saw this shot of like their dorm room and there's two desks and there aren't computers on the desks.
Speaker 0: And I had this moment of what the fuck did they do on those desks?
Speaker 1: Read books.
Speaker 1: Yeah and do their homework.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly Like.
Speaker 0: there is nowhere to write things on my desk.
Speaker 0: if I need to use a desk to write things I need a different desk.
Speaker 1: Oh, I can write things on my desk.
Speaker 1: I just had to push the keyboard out of the way.
Speaker 0: Well, my desk is smaller than yours, but other style of calendar, right?
Speaker 1: So you got we hang on the wall.
Speaker 1: We got you know big mat or big big one on the wall.
Speaker 1: the other style of calendar They pretty sure still exists and I've got.
Speaker 1: I used to get more often and have terror ways.
Speaker 1: Yes, the tearaway kind
Speaker 0: every kid
Speaker 1: I
Speaker 0: do at a far-side one
Speaker 1: Far-side was definitely the best one I think that I can think of and
Speaker 0: I had some other plan as a kid to not look ahead At all and everybody and every morning there because that calendar served a different purpose.
Speaker 0: The wall calendar was like the planning calendar.
Speaker 0: The tearaway calendar was the one that was in my bedroom next to my bed And when I woke when my alarm went off every morning I would turn on news radio to find out if anything happened in the world and then I would tear a page off the calendar and See what day it was and what the shit I had to do that day.
Speaker 1: Oh, see the tearaway calendar for me was.
Speaker 1: it was on my desk.
Speaker 1: I did tear it away every day, right?
Speaker 0: I turned away the moment.
Speaker 0: I woke up.
Speaker 1: I woke up like it was a thing maybe but you know I mean I did it after I got out of the bed.
Speaker 0: when I woke up, but I would lay in bed It was literally within arm's reach of my it doesn't Like.
Speaker 0: look at.
Speaker 1: the point is is that that calendar would be a way for you not having a computer That's on displaying a date all the time not having a phone to Say what day is today because you have the wall calendar.
Speaker 1: the wall calendar unless you're exiting it off religiously, which you might Doesn't tell you what today's date is the tearaway calendar.
Speaker 1: you glance at it You know what today's date is and also in addition It provides you like a thing to check and like a little shot of serotonin or dopamine or whatever every day.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I pull it and there's a new fireside comic.
Speaker 0: even though I'd already read every fireside comic I would get a little sensible chuckle out of it, right?
Speaker 1: So even in a day when you didn't you couldn't doom scroll whenever you needed some brain juice, right?
Speaker 1: You could get a little brain juice every day from a tearaway calendar.
Speaker 0: I always forget that there was a time in my life when I didn't just have a little box that would give me infinite brain juice Exactly.
Speaker 1: You can just only get brain juice.
Speaker 1: You get this little tiny brain juice once a day from your little calendar, right?
Speaker 1: and some of the ones I don't.
Speaker 1: I think Some of these are my brother.
Speaker 1: I think he got them more than me.
Speaker 1: There was like a Mets trivia one.
Speaker 1: There was a Simpsons one that was like full color that had like Simpsons quotes and things.
Speaker 1: Definitely every single newspaper comic strip, you know fireside included had one where each day would be a different strip.
Speaker 1: I don't.
Speaker 1: I don't think maybe Calvin Hobbes didn't have one because he didn't like merchandise.
Speaker 0: but yeah And I'm pretty sure at one point I had a foxtrot one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think I had a Dilbert one too because I didn't know I may have had a Dilbert one Which is like.
Speaker 1: at the time Dilbert was fine.
Speaker 1: And now the Dilbert guy is like the worst person.
Speaker 0: It's like Dilbert was okay funny at that time and we didn't know anything about the person and then learn about the person.
Speaker 0: and also Dilbert Got worse, but simultaneously Knowing what I know.
Speaker 0: now old Dilbert has a sinister undercurrent.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but there were also ones that are like, you know cute cat picture, right and you couldn't just get cute cat pictures.
Speaker 1: in 1990 something On the internet in the 90s took a while.
Speaker 1: It's like you.
Speaker 1: there wasn't a plate you couldn't go to like reddit slash our Imgur or whatever and just type cat and see cute cat pictures for days.
Speaker 1: There was no such thing.
Speaker 1: So getting one cute cat picture a day was worth paying money for.
Speaker 1: yeah You never seen those cats or dogs or whatever fish, you know, whatever calendar they sold.
Speaker 0: but So what's interesting to me is because I never had calendars where I particularly like the art And I kind of avoided buying them like even if they were really good art because I could only have one or two calendars up At any given time, it would
Speaker 1: be really weird to have a whole bunch of calendars.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I knew who had like a lot of calendars for some reason.
Speaker 1: It's not like having four clocks for different time zones.
Speaker 1: It's like you put four calendars in the hall really just to show off your four different arts.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you'd only change the calendars like that.
Speaker 1: You only change them once a month.
Speaker 1: So it's sort of like, you know, you're not getting you're only getting your you know, your brain juice once a month.
Speaker 1: That's not really what those are for right?
Speaker 0: Yep, and I had a day play like a planner that I would use too But that's kind of a separate topic that will.
Speaker 1: let's talk about that.
Speaker 1: So well, I don't know.
Speaker 1: so planners, right?
Speaker 1: So I do.
Speaker 1: I do remember I got an anecdote right.
Speaker 1: is my dad What he would use for work?
Speaker 1: is there was I don't know if they still must still exist.
Speaker 1: There was a company that was or brand called.
Speaker 1: I think was called day runner and they made you could.
Speaker 1: there's like a whole section at staples with like day runner stuff and they Sell these little binders and that were small and they would sell all kinds of different things.
Speaker 1: You could put in the binder right calendars and you you never seen these.
Speaker 0: I've seen similar things.
Speaker 0: I don't think I know.
Speaker 0: that sounds like the moleskine equivalent of the things I used.
Speaker 1: It was like the opposite of moleskine right?
Speaker 1: It was like moleskine is like blank pages.
Speaker 1: This is like Extreme like you can buy different packs of stuff to put in.
Speaker 1: Note pages, you know Rolodex pages, you know plan your whole day agenda by the hour pages meeting notes like specialized pages That are exactly the right size to fit in your day runner, which that honestly
Speaker 0: Really important because you didn't have a little box that told you all the things you had to do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it totally made sense for the time, right?
Speaker 1: It was like it was basically making a palm pilot out of paper And you choose which pages you put in there in what order.
Speaker 1: right and there could be.
Speaker 1: there was like a you get like a Contact thing.
Speaker 1: there was the thing you could buy.
Speaker 1: that had like little tabs on the side like a through Z. So you could and you could you know, write down all the names and phone numbers of all your contacts.
Speaker 0: I had a literal Rolodex that was also on my nightstand of all my contacts.
Speaker 1: But if you had this thing It would basically be everything in one.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: your calendar right for that your monthly calendar your daily agenda right meeting at 3 p.m Kind of stuff right.
Speaker 1: your contact list your notes like literally if you were actually a business person Yeah, you would.
Speaker 1: you know, you spend some money on this thing.
Speaker 1: It's kind of fancy and kind of you know, a little gimmicky, but it would work out in a pre-pump pilot days.
Speaker 1: yeah, you know pre anyway, but pre smartphone days, but So the thing is my dad would use that at work for real.
Speaker 1: he used it Legitimately and they're just having to be extra day runners stuff.
Speaker 1: So I basically made my own Runner and I would go to Staples and I bought some packs.
Speaker 1: I didn't use it properly Cuz I was in what like fourth or fifth grade.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would.
Speaker 0: I had a lot of things to try to organize my life But I didn't have that much to organize.
Speaker 1: But I would like carry it around and like have you know fun, I guess pretending to use it whatever kinda.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so that was the thing and honestly like nothing changed in this ecosystem of calendars until like Pretty much after we got out of college.
Speaker 0: Okay, so day runner is now at a glance Cuz like okay, but like thinking even in RIT like there weren't smartphones yet We had a calendar in the kitchen in the geek not geek house Or the geek apartment.
Speaker 0: I guess like I had to use like physical calendars to track stuff.
Speaker 0: There weren't really good apps.
Speaker 0: Like I wasn't gonna pay for outlook or anything.
Speaker 0: So Even all right, like as late as college I still had physical paper calendars to remember like when is the final exam?
Speaker 0: When am I going home?
Speaker 0: What's going on in my life?
Speaker 0: the moment where that changed was when I went off to work at IBM while I was at RIT on my first co-op and I won cuz I didn't have any fucking money.
Speaker 0: I won a fancy color palm pilot in a raffle among all the co-ops at IBM.
Speaker 0: Remember that little guy That like I was great.
Speaker 0: I used it as a calendar.
Speaker 0: I actually put all my calendar ink into it in like forever.
Speaker 0: Like I stopped using physical calendars and it was fucking amazing Mm-hmm, not like me with the day runner.
Speaker 1: I didn't actually use it.
Speaker 0: You actually used it cuz that was right when my life got more complex Like I had work meetings and then like I had to plan like what weekend am I gonna go back to RIT and hang out With Scott?
Speaker 0: like oh this weekend.
Speaker 0: We're busy.
Speaker 0: that weekend is an anime music night.
Speaker 0: So that's the weekend.
Speaker 0: I'll go back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think that you know What happened was is there were?
Speaker 1: I did have several attempts to use some sort of digital calendar situation.
Speaker 1: The first one I think was probably Thunderbird because at the time, you know pre gmail We used the Thunderbird email client right to connect to pop or imap email Whatever your service was and that all you know, the whole Mozilla suite right which originally Mozilla was, you know, not just Browser but also the email the composer and the cow.
Speaker 1: It was like all those things combined.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically, they took the browser and made it Firefox and then all the other stuff was in Thunderbird, right?
Speaker 1: And the composer I think went in the trash.
Speaker 1: But Thunderbird did have that calendar in it Yeah, and I tried to use it.
Speaker 1: but like I just as much as I tried several times to use Different digital calendaring solutions like I never fully bought into one.
Speaker 1: I think early in the iPhone days I was using the iPhone calendar app like sort of but like I wasn't.
Speaker 1: It wasn't like really I wasn't putting everything in there.
Speaker 1: I wasn't really checking it, you know, well,
Speaker 0: you know There's this weird time period where I had the Palm Pilot which made it easier like I started using it digitally but I had a calendar for my real life and a Separate calendar for work as I started having the kind of job where I had to have like meetings and stuff all the time.
Speaker 0: But I used Lotus Notes for that because I worked at IBM and then outlook when I've got my next jobs after IBM.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that you know, it wasn't until I think Google Calendar I was.
Speaker 0: that was the one that was when I converged everything.
Speaker 1: Right, but then I don't know when like when did I actually start because there definitely was a time period between The launch of Google Calendar and then me actually using it for reals.
Speaker 0: I started using Google Calendar almost immediately and I got stopped using my Palm Pilot like basically then.
Speaker 1: Okay, so when was this?
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay, so I'm a back as Google Calendar came out in 2006 just as we were like moving to beacon.
Speaker 1: Okay, so if I'm looking like 2008 like yeah, there's some events in there, but really it's sparse.
Speaker 1: It's just like this.
Speaker 1: I'm not.
Speaker 0: I'd have to look at my other old gmail account that I don't use anymore.
Speaker 1: Okay, but yeah in 2008 2009 I'm using it a little bit like I'm seeing convention as like only special events like convention Mets game, you know day off work stuff like that.
Speaker 1: It's not like, you know, I look at today, right today I'm really you know, it's like.
Speaker 1: okay here are you know, and not only is it calendar?
Speaker 1: It's also.
Speaker 1: I got Google tasks and reminders integrated into the calendar, right?
Speaker 1: It's like there's two work meetings.
Speaker 1: There's something someone else is doing because I have their calendar on my calendar.
Speaker 1: There's geek nights on the calendar.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 1: now we're really using the calendar.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think I've been.
Speaker 1: I think I've been really using it from at least maybe 10 ish years.
Speaker 0: I think it bothers me.
Speaker 0: the most though Is that like I have my work calendar and I have my life calendar and like I just internalize like the differences and that's all Fine, but most of the adults I know won't respond to a calendar invitation.
Speaker 0: They don't use digital calendars the way we do ever at least.
Speaker 1: everyone at my work everyone uses at work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they work.
Speaker 0: Everyone is fine like at work.
Speaker 1: Everyone uses Google Calendar and Google Meet.
Speaker 1: the integrations, right?
Speaker 1: Actually, you know the less I'm actually.
Speaker 1: the people who are less computer II than me are actually better at using the cool calendar stuff than I I'm talking about Outside of work like people don't like if I send a calendar invite to a normal person.
Speaker 0: They just won't see it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no outside of work I mean first of all, the one thing is that when you're at work and even though there's this universal Cal dev thing Which is a Monday topic that does provide integration between different calendar formats whether someone's using Outlook or Apple or?
Speaker 1: And it does work if you know how to you know People just can't do it for whatever reason.
Speaker 0: I don't know why it does just work.
Speaker 0: if someone uses fucking outlook and sends me an email with an iCal in it It'll just work for me.
Speaker 1: It'll just work in your Google Calendar.
Speaker 0: Yes Seems capable of this right?
Speaker 1: But yeah, if you're all using the same system It is still a little bit easier, even though the inter system stuff does work well with the Cal files.
Speaker 1: Yeah But yeah, people can't seem to deal with it.
Speaker 1: if like, you know, we try to use some Google Calendar with friends.
Speaker 0: So I'd I discovered.
Speaker 0: I won't name any names But the impression I get from most of these some some friends are doing it.
Speaker 1: The problem is unless all the necessary people do it doesn't?
Speaker 1: it doesn't work.
Speaker 0: many of our friends just still use physical calendars for some Reason.
Speaker 0: a lot of people a lot of adults.
Speaker 0: I know you all.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's you might not have a smartphone, but All of our friends have a fully smart phones.
Speaker 1: That is correct.
Speaker 0: I don't understand this.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: I've even had people like I like oh Can I send you a calendar invite and they like.
Speaker 0: they understand what I asked?
Speaker 0: They're not that far gone, but they are.
Speaker 0: they get weird about it.
Speaker 0: They're like, why just like?
Speaker 0: why do you want to count?
Speaker 0: Like why do you need this?
Speaker 0: Why do you want this?
Speaker 0: It's because it's easy also because you're gonna.
Speaker 1: you have to.
Speaker 1: I know you're gonna write it up And also you.
Speaker 1: when you have the calendar on your phone digitally or even on your desktop you get the reminders Right and not only do you get the reminders?
Speaker 1: But let's say you create a meeting right between five people and you get all the five people together.
Speaker 1: You're all.
Speaker 1: you're all together.
Speaker 1: now you're on a phone call.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you say okay or meeting Friday at 3. everyone writes in their paper calendar.
Speaker 1: Friday at 3 p.m.
Speaker 1: Meeting call so-and-so, right?
Speaker 1: Okay, bye, right Friday at 3 rolls around.
Speaker 1: no reminder, right?
Speaker 1: But even if you you were looking at your calendar you make the call.
Speaker 1: Someone isn't on the call.
Speaker 1: what happened to them?
Speaker 1: I don't know if you had used the digital calendar, even if you had different systems and somebody would be like, ah shit I can't make it.
Speaker 1: taking them going They can go click on it and say can't make it.
Speaker 1: and now suddenly on everyone else's calendar It syncs up and it's like hey you you know meeting canceled so-and-so can't make it.
Speaker 1: And now you don't bother making that phone call at 3.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right You can see who's showing up when who's not showing up what meet where it is.
Speaker 1: if the location changes the location changes.
Speaker 1: You don't have to like oh shit.
Speaker 1: I forgot to write the different location on my account on my paper calendar.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like the paper calendar is just dead for life organizing.
Speaker 0: I've noticed a lot of the people I know not just friends But just like acquaintances and co-workers in their normal lives if they have a family with a bunch of kids They tend to like.
Speaker 0: their calendar doesn't really intersect with other people's calendars.
Speaker 0: So they just use a physical one that could work.
Speaker 1: You could all you know, yeah, I mean if you don't want to you know Put up a whole TV on the wall.
Speaker 1: just display the Google the family Google Calendar, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah paper calendar for the family schedules makes perfect sense even in 2020.
Speaker 0: The other thing I noticed is some people resisted as being like They have this weird social hang up of.
Speaker 0: it's weird to send someone a calendar invitation for a social or non-work thing.
Speaker 0: Like they have this weird idea that that's weird or awkward.
Speaker 1: Why is that?
Speaker 0: It doesn't seem I don't know But I see that resistance happen in real time.
Speaker 1: I haven't I don't know.
Speaker 1: That's just strange.
Speaker 1: Like why wouldn't you do then?
Speaker 1: I could see someone who's super paper calendary and like to switch to digital calendar.
Speaker 1: They'd have to spend some time putting in all existing things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right into it and that initial Roadblock might stop someone from making that crossover.
Speaker 1: But I think it was easier for me to just because I wasn't Calendaring that much to begin with right and so by I just started for nothing and then I just calendared more over time.
Speaker 0: Well, cuz my calendar really the only things I put in calendars now are When there's when I have travel When I gotta do something at a specific time or date for some reason Or like appointments with like doctors like specifically personal appointments just for the reminders Like I don't have that much occurs granted.
Speaker 0: It's COVID time.
Speaker 0: So there's fucking nothing in my calendar right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah Actually, you know what?
Speaker 0: I have in my calendar on Monday play games.
Speaker 0: I just put it says play games all day event very nice.
Speaker 0: Oh, I just looked at my calendar of magfest is still there.
Speaker 1: Oh, no.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, I just want to quickly talk about the third part, you know, cuz the food isn't here yet The types of calendar.
Speaker 1: So everyone uses the same.
Speaker 1: I think pretty much the whole world right is mostly using the same Calendar.
Speaker 0: Yes, January February There's are sometimes used in parallel in a lot of countries.
Speaker 0: like there's a lot of that but yes There are.
Speaker 1: you know, I being a Jew I've seen you know There's the Hebrew calendar and they always.
Speaker 1: basically it's a lunar.
Speaker 1: if you don't know the Hebrew calendar is a lunar calendar.
Speaker 1: So a new day starts when the Sun sets And the you know moon rises theoretically Even though the moon can rise at other times.
Speaker 1: I know how the moon works But a day starts when the Sun sets and there's less days in a month because it's synced to the phases of the moon Right, and then what they do is they base to catch up to like the real the Gregorian calendar Right and for other reasons as well.
Speaker 1: Every so I think it's every four years.
Speaker 1: They have a leap month.
Speaker 1: There's a month of the Hebrew calendar called Adar and it's a dar the first and then they'll every every few years.
Speaker 1: They'll be in a dar and a dar - It'd be like if there was January and then every four years there was January - yeah.
Speaker 1: And what's interesting is actually the a dar - is actually the real a dar.
Speaker 1: the a dar one is the extra time The leave one before the.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure that's true.
Speaker 0: There's a Wikipedia page that lists in Order every country formally adopting the Gregorian calendar Starting with Belgium.
Speaker 0: in 1582 a whole bunch of countries for Belgium was the first day.
Speaker 0: Well, Belgium is the first in the list because it starts with B. Much of Europe adopted it in 1582 for reasons that I hope you learned in social studies.
Speaker 1: Was that was that around?
Speaker 1: was that when Gregor was still around?
Speaker 0: Greg or stabbed Julian?
Speaker 0: I heard Yeah, it's to February.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so if you scroll through like there's this like slow and steady adoption of a good chunk of the world like in the 1700s like a lot of the Nordic countries all adopted it.
Speaker 0: But if you go all the way to the bottom, I'm curious because I did not I did not know this.
Speaker 0: What do you think was the most recent country to adopt the Gregorian calendar officially?
Speaker 0: Antarctica, it's not a country.
Speaker 1: I Guess not technically not again.
Speaker 0: I was surprised but it makes sense based on all the other things.
Speaker 0: I know but I just didn't think about it.
Speaker 0: I'll tell you the year it happened.
Speaker 1: Okay a country that wouldn't it hasn't adopted.
Speaker 0: it's a big real country, too.
Speaker 0: This isn't some like bullshit technicality of like Andorra or something.
Speaker 0: No, no.
Speaker 0: Mongolia Saudi Arabia No, that makes they shifted from the Islamic calendar to the Gregorian calendar on October 1st, 2016.
Speaker 1: That makes sense.
Speaker 0: so the previous time anyone adopted it was basically World War one like Greek Civil War and World War one like Greece was 1923. a whole bunch of countries.
Speaker 0: 1919 1918 like Russia Russian Revolution like that makes sense.
Speaker 0: That's why 1918.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically, you know, how did it get adopted?
Speaker 1: mostly colonialism, right?
Speaker 1: It's like so much of the world was using it because the colonialism and then people in countries were you know Need to communicate with each other and work with each other.
Speaker 1: So they needed to have dates that were the same.
Speaker 1: and then which calendar?
Speaker 1: one?
Speaker 1: the one that more people were using already From the Julian calendar It's just handled.
Speaker 1: uh and handle is the earth goes around that regardless of what calendar you're using It's gonna be based on some sort of celestial movements.
Speaker 1: Yeah something right.
Speaker 1: a day is a day for everybody, right?
Speaker 1: Regardless of what your calendar system is the Sun goes up and the Sun goes down.
Speaker 1: whether you start your day when the Sun goes Down or when it comes up, right?
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: the complication Concept of a day is the same for everyone.
Speaker 1: So from there you synchronize it.
Speaker 1: However, you got to synchronize it.
Speaker 0: The problem is that it takes a non like divisible number of days For the Sun the earth to encircle the Sun.
Speaker 1: You don't even have to have a count that doesn't you mean?
Speaker 1: a lot of calendars are based on that but they don't have to.
Speaker 0: They don't have to be.
Speaker 0: there are proposals or post earth calendars.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you could just have a calendar.
Speaker 1: That's like okay.
Speaker 1: a day is you know?
Speaker 1: one rotation of you know, the earth, you know spinning around its own axis for it.
Speaker 1: You know the Sun to go up and we did have calendars like that.
Speaker 1: The problem was and then you start counting it one and that's the day and there's no years.
Speaker 1: There's no months.
Speaker 1: It's just yeah today's day When the old ice today today's 2005.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I'll see you on 2007.
Speaker 0: the ice elemental wakes up.
Speaker 0: I guess spoilers for Adventure Time if you haven't watched it by now But it was living in our time wakes up in the future and Adventure Time and asks What year is it?
Speaker 0: and Finn just says something like yeah, no one really counts time like that anymore.
Speaker 1: Yep, exactly You know a day's a day, but everything else.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, but is arbitrary?
Speaker 1: We've just agreed arbitrary on the same arbitrary thing to synchronize and help communication Yep, mostly to compare time to previous time like winter time.
Speaker 0: Like, you know when winter was in any year going back in the Gregorian calendar?
Speaker 1: Yeah, if we were just counting days by days, right?
Speaker 1: You'd be like, okay today's to 20,000.
Speaker 1: That means next, you know, it'll be.
Speaker 1: you know, it's currently cold.
Speaker 1: So at twenty thousand three hundred and sixty-five, it'll be cold again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like that's not super prac.
Speaker 0: That's why we have time zone.
Speaker 0: So like noon isn't this midday no matter where you are at any given place Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, and I think that killed enough time and I think I see the dumplings on their way.
Speaker 1: So yeah, my the food should be here like ten minutes.
Speaker 0: Oh, wow.
Speaker 0: Not only did that work fine But we went way over.
Speaker 0: that was a long episode of geek nights.
Speaker 1: Good.
Speaker 1: Tell us your favorite calendar.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and make comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Alan Joyce, honey, McNichol in kiji Graham Finch.
Speaker 0: You hold the key to my heart.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: go through the last Year or so a podcast to make rim sing Clinton Walton written from New Zealand.
Speaker 0: Ryan Perrin review mad bull 34 cowards.
Speaker 0: Give us time.
Speaker 0: Dread lily tenebrae just like a dude guy.
Speaker 0: Chris Reimer Finn sure but von Harlan a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names In the geek night's discord.
Speaker 0: Check it out.
Speaker 0: I am Planning to start up a play your damn turn civilization 6 game with as many of you as we can get in.
Speaker 0: so Check it out and maybe join it.
Speaker 0: You can see our recent episode on asynchronous play where we talked about that kind of thing a little bit But for now, I leave you with.
Speaker 1: It's honestly hard to fathom.
Speaker 1: second our law enforcement The brave officers who were Sacrificing their lives to defend us who could not evacuate or seek cover because they were protecting us.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to go through again what my fellow manager showed you yesterday But let me just say this Those officers serve us faithfully and dutifully and they follow their oaths.
Speaker 1: They deserved a president who upholds his who would not risk their lives and safety To retain power a president who would preserve protect and defend them.
Speaker 1: But that's not what he did.
Speaker 1: When they the police still barricaded and being attacked with poles He said in his video to the people attacking them.
Speaker 1: We love you You're very special.
Speaker 1: What more could we possibly need to know about?
Speaker 1: President Trump's state of mind?
Speaker 1: Senators The evidence is clear.
Speaker 1: We showed you statements videos affidavits that prove President Trump Incited an insurrection an insurrection that he alone had the power to stop and The fact that he didn't stop it The fact that he incited a lawless attack and abdicated his duty to defend us from it The fact that he actually further inflamed
Speaker 0: the mob further inflamed that
Speaker 1: mob Attacking his vice president while assassins were pursuing
Speaker 0: him
Speaker 1: in this capital more than requires conviction and disqualification.
Speaker 1: We humbly Humbly ask you to convict President Trump for the crime for which he is overwhelmingly guilty of because if you don't if we pretend This didn't happen Or worse if we let it go unanswered who's to say it won't happen again?