Speaker 0: It's Wednesday, March 17th, 2021.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, we are talking about the 1977 anime, Vultus 5.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So a few of you pointed out, and I was aware of this when I switched to having that fancy, completely black background behind me recording Geek Nights on the livestreams.
Speaker 0: I was also using that at work to, like, get rid of the background, and it's nice.
Speaker 0: But you might have noticed, I was a little bit washed out and white.
Speaker 0: The problem I ran into that I had to actually spend some time to figure out and deal with was- Was because it was black, the camera was trying to adjust the exposure?
Speaker 0: Yup, because the camera is a webcam, and it's trying to be clever and not too professional, it tried to do a bunch of too clever crap, and it was a terrible idea.
Speaker 0: But it wasn't just a simple thing of going and like-
Speaker 1: If you're calculating exposure to choose black, I mean, you could also tell the webcam to, you know, if you had a real camera, you could tell it, hey, when you're calculating exposure, just look in this area of the frame.
Speaker 1: You know, spot, you could do spot metering, center-weighted metering, or you could just do exposure compensation and be like, yeah, minus, you know-
Speaker 0: Yup, basically,
Speaker 1: because
Speaker 0: this webcam doesn't have, like, the controls on a regular ass, like, professional camera- It should
Speaker 1: have, there should be software that comes with it that can let you-.
Speaker 0: So that was the thing, I had to install that Logitech software that I've never used in my life.
Speaker 1: Yup, yup, and there's a little slider you can slide.
Speaker 0: Yup, and I slid the slider, and it was amazing, because when I slid the slider by default, it didn't actually change anything, it kept me washed out, but the background got darker.
Speaker 0: Like, it did something weird, because it had some automated logic in it, it was trying to prioritize for "exposure," in quotes, instead of doing the thing I would expect a camera to do.
Speaker 0: So I had to turn off, like, all the automation and make it all 100% manual, and then I could fix it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, you know, even the world's most expensive, best cameras that you can buy, right, are only so smart at figuring out, you know, ah, there's a person there, expose for the person and let the background be- Yup.
Speaker 1: That is why you need to, no matter what best automate camera you have, you need to understand photography to some extent.
Speaker 0: Yup, but there is this weird danger zone on the lowest end of prosumer and the highest end of consumer, where you'll need those kinds of capabilities, but the interface is still simplified and automated in a way that either you can't access that functionality directly, or it tries to abstract it away.
Speaker 0: And even if you know about real cameras, you have to figure out what this slider that has weird labels is actually doing before you can-.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, like, if you want to take a photo of, like, you know, the classic example is, like, there's just snow everywhere, so it's frickin' white everywhere, right?
Speaker 1: And if you just take out a camera and just take pictures, no matter, even the world's best camera or an old iPhone, it doesn't matter, it's gonna make the snow look gray, even if your eyeballs tell you the snow is white, just 'cause that's how it works, right?
Speaker 0: It's like taking a picture of fire, good luck.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: On your iPhone, you're gonna have to, you know, there's, like, you can drag up and down in the camera app, the default one at least, to, you know, there's a little picture of a sun, and you can drag it up and down, and you're gonna have to, you know, probably drag it up to fix your snow and make your snow white, right?
Speaker 1: Snow white.
Speaker 1: You know, there's nothing you can do about it.
Speaker 1: Even the smartest iPhone can't determine that it's, you know, supposed to- it's not actually a gray wall and that it's snow.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So I did sort all that out, and the other problem I was having is that because my microphone arm isn't long enough, because it's the cheapest one, I have to sit really close to my monitor, and the problem is, I have a really fancy monitor.
Speaker 0: So the other thing that was messing this up is, if I have a white tab open in front of my face, it's like a spotlight.
Speaker 0: Like, it's so bright.
Speaker 0: But it was all easily fixed, and now I have a pretty good setup, so now I'm good to go.
Speaker 0: I was only mildly annoyed that I had to actually install the software, because I generally have this- I know you do this to a degree, but if I buy like a Logitech mouse, or like anything fancy, like a fancy keyboard, and it has some software that you need to use to configure it or set it up, I try to avoid installing that software to my detriment and at all costs.
Speaker 1: I do try to avoid installing that software, but more recently, I have had to basically relent, for example.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Between the 8-bit dose.
Speaker 1: My mouse has LEDs in it, and I need the software to change the color or to disable the LEDs in the mouse.
Speaker 0: Once I install the software, guess what I could do?
Speaker 0: I could turn off the fucking light on my mouse.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: The cooler on my CPU, the software for that, that will let me turn off those lights.
Speaker 0: There's two softwares.
Speaker 0: There's the NZXT one, if you have NZXT stuff, and there's also the like, uh, Asus Armory that controls like, the lights that are on RAM now.
Speaker 1: I don't have that.
Speaker 1: Well, Emily's motherboard has lights on it.
Speaker 1: I only needed the- I only needed the NZXT one.
Speaker 0: The RAM that had lights on it was significantly cheaper than identical RAM with no lights.
Speaker 1: I could, uh, my motherboard, if my motherboard has lights, I think they're adjusted in the UAFI directly.
Speaker 1: I don't think I have to install Windows software to deal with that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But yeah, that's life.
Speaker 0: So yeah, in the news, there's actually a lot to talk about today, so we might give a few of these things a short shrift.
Speaker 0: But first off, Wolfwalkers, if you're not aware, like we reviewed it, it is one of the better animated films ever made.
Speaker 0: Like, it is a phenomenal film.
Speaker 0: It's one of the best animated films I've seen in recent memory.
Speaker 0: And of course, it got nominated for a bunch of Oscars, well, a bunch of Annie's, and it got nominated- You know, it's not Akira, but it's up there.
Speaker 0: But, uh, I hate to say this, on one hand, it is significant that it was nominated for Best Animated Feature, as it should have been.
Speaker 0: But I am confident it will not win it, and that regardless of the relative merits of these two films, I'm pretty sure Soul's gonna get it because it's Disney.
Speaker 0: Regardless.
Speaker 1: Because the way the stupid Academy Awards work is they let you vote on things you haven't seen, right?
Speaker 1: And it's just mostly old white guys voting, you know, people who are members of the Academy voting, right?
Speaker 0: I'll never forget when Song of the Sea was nominated, and then Big Hero 6, which, not saying Big Hero 6 is a bad movie, but it isn't even in the same, like, remote tier of what Song of the Sea was.
Speaker 1: No, not even close.
Speaker 0: And when that one unnamed Academy member said the words that they didn't vote for the Chinese movie, and they voted for the Disney Pixar, whatever, whatever Disney Pixar thing comes out is what a lot of these Academy members vote for without even watching them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and not even what the nomination process is, right?
Speaker 1: And it's, like, not shitting on Shaun of the Sheep.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's probably a fine movie.
Speaker 1: The people who worked on that probably worked very hard and probably made something.
Speaker 1: I've obviously never seen it and probably won't ever see it.
Speaker 0: But I doubt I would watch it and say, "Wow, that blows Wolfwalkers out of the
Speaker 0: water.".
Speaker 1: Right, I'm sure children would watch it and enjoy it, and it's probably, you know, very well done and such, but is it Oscar-worthy?
Speaker 0: Yeah, because whatever the Oscar ostensibly is, do experts agree that of all the films in this category in this whole year, this one was the best of them?
Speaker 0: There might be a year where all the movies are shit, and best feature is a garbage movie.
Speaker 0: Like, that could happen.
Speaker 1: But, right, ideally speaking, if you made good awards and not shitty ones, and you were going to use the same sort of nomination and then award process, because there are other processes you could use that look nothing like that, but that's, you know, the process that most of these awards have come to, you should look at every category and basically, like, every single nomination should be a hard choice, right?
Speaker 1: And if something obviously, like, is like, "No, no way that could win,".
Speaker 1: why is it, it shouldn't even be nominated?
Speaker 1: I think they have a thing where, like, they have to nominate, like, a certain number.
Speaker 1: Like, you know, it's always five, I think, right?
Speaker 1: It already seems like it's five, at least.
Speaker 1: I'm probably wrong.
Speaker 1: But it's like, you should, it shouldn't, if you're going to use a nominate and then award process, if there are only, like, two things that, like, could win, you should only give out two nominations, right?
Speaker 1: You shouldn't be like, "Well, we have to nominate five just because arbitrary
Speaker 1: number.".
Speaker 1: Well, I could argue that- If there are ten things and it's a tough choice between all ten, you should have ten nominations, right?
Speaker 0: Well, the other thing, I think we even talked about this at Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: that would be interesting.
Speaker 0: One, you gotta find a way to make the Academy Awards, at least, like, force these people to watch the movies.
Speaker 0: Like, they should all have to take a test, like, at some point to prove that they saw the movie, and if they fail that test on any movie that they had a say in the vote for, all their votes get discounted.
Speaker 1: I think they should just do it- Like, name one character from Wolfwalkers.
Speaker 0: If you can't do that, your animated feature vote doesn't count.
Speaker 1: I think it should just be done, you know, if I was in control, right?
Speaker 1: What I would do is I would get together, right, this audience, right, of a diverse audience representing, like, the general populace.
Speaker 1: People who know about movies, people who don't, people of all sorts of colors, shapes, sizes, ages, right?
Speaker 0: Like, nominate the Academy every year.
Speaker 1: And I would pay them money, right?
Speaker 1: You get paid.
Speaker 1: 'Cause we're gonna make you watch a lot of movies, that's time, you should get money for that, right?
Speaker 1: And the Oscars bring in a ton of money, so they have money to pay these people, right?
Speaker 1: And what you should do is you should randomly assign the people to a category, right?
Speaker 1: So, you might randomly get assigned to a category you're familiar with, or one you're unfamiliar with.
Speaker 1: You should get a nice mix of people who are familiar and unfamiliar.
Speaker 1: And then, you sit the people down, and we can go by something, we can't make them watch, say, for example, in a category, every animated feature film from the whole year.
Speaker 1: That would be impossible, right?
Speaker 1: But we can obviously pick based on some other factor, like maybe gross, right?
Speaker 1: The top ten grossing ones to even qualify to get watched or something from anywhere in the world, right, you know?
Speaker 1: And then, we would say, "Okay, you're gonna have to sit here over the course of two, three days, maybe, and watch all these movies, and you're just gonna fill out little survey cards after each movie, and then at the end, a final survey
Speaker 1: card.".
Speaker 1: And that will, you know, will then use that to determine who won.
Speaker 1: And that's, you know, something like that.
Speaker 0: But I guess, Wolfwalkers honestly, like for real, deserves this Oscar, and I am so confident that Soul's gonna get it instead, even though, like, I watched Soul.
Speaker 0: It's a fantastic movie.
Speaker 1: I don't think that, I mean, I also agree that the probability is in Soul's favor, knowing how the Oscars work, but I am not giving Wolfwalkers a 0% chance, because there is Apple money behind it, right?
Speaker 0: Ah, yeah, that is true.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not 0%.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying it's, you know, it's not 0%, but I'm saying it's less than...
Speaker 0: I'm just saying, I am in a pessimistic mood.
Speaker 1: I'm thinking like 80/20, 80/20 for Soul?
Speaker 0: Just because of the fact that the exact same thing happened with Tom Moore's previous movie?
Speaker 1: Of course.
Speaker 1: Alright, so, other anime news.
Speaker 1: If you don't know, Discotek has been saving the US anime world for the past however long they've been doing it.
Speaker 1: And they love, lately, what they've been doing is sort of, you know, Apple-esque sort of keynotes where, you know, they're not at a convention.
Speaker 1: They're just dropping, like, big piles of licensed news all at once, right, in these tweet threads.
Speaker 1: And the last time they did one, we reported it on the news, and we're doing it again.
Speaker 1: So, good marketing job, Discotek.
Speaker 1: So, what did Discotek drop on us this time?
Speaker 1: Number one, they licensed brother, dear brother, they're gonna make boullés.
Speaker 0: You don't have to like this show, but this show is very important.
Speaker 0: This is one of those shows, I think we've reviewed it on Geek Nights in an ancient time.
Speaker 1: The manga for brother, dear brother is made by the same person who made the manga for Rosa Versailles.
Speaker 1: It's legendary in many ways, it is not up everyone's alley, but, you know, if you're a Rosa Versailles liker like I am, you know, it's like I've known about brother, dear brother.
Speaker 0: I watched it all.
Speaker 1: And I've always kinda wanted to see the deal, but I never did, but maybe now's the chance, maybe, you know, it's 'cause it's coming.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna buy boullés, obviously.
Speaker 0: It's one of those shows where you may like it, may not like it, just like Evangelion.
Speaker 0: I respect that some people, like, people don't necessarily like Evangelion, but it is important to anime and animation in ways that unless you see it, you might not realize.
Speaker 0: Brother, dear brother inspired a lot of anime that came long after, and the echoes of this show still reverberate today.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but yeah, they said that the license period is unusually short, so that means that they're basically gonna release boullés and then their license might expire pretty much immediately.
Speaker 1: So you have to buy those, you know, I wouldn't buy boullés, but you're gonna have to jump on this while you can, right?
Speaker 1: Other news, a show that doesn't seem old but actually is ancient and also legendary, Sergeant Frog, they licensed that.
Speaker 1: They're gonna release all 358 episodes in successive SD boullés, 'cause you can fit a lot of episodes on an SD boullé, and the show wasn't in HD to begin with.
Speaker 1: That is 2.7 Sailor Moons.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: So, Sergeant Frog is just, you know, a legendary kids parody comedy show.
Speaker 1: You know, it's been around a super long time.
Speaker 0: I've seen, like, a smattering of random episodes.
Speaker 0: It's funny, it's not something I would necessarily seek out and watch all of.
Speaker 1: But I think it's just a significant show, whether you care about it or not, right?
Speaker 1: So to release all of it in English is something.
Speaker 0: It's funny, you know, one thing that is significant to that show in terms of, like, anime fandom, especially in America, but also in Japan, is that the closers were notable for having dances that people would emulate.
Speaker 1: Some other small shows, they got Kashimashi something, I don't know what that is.
Speaker 1: They're releasing Nyanbo, which is basically a cat version of Cardbo, Cardbo from Yotsuba, right?
Speaker 1: It has this, like, a little CG anime, Nyanbo.
Speaker 0: Oh, Magical Girl Ore.
Speaker 1: Magical Ore, right?
Speaker 1: Some other stuff, right?
Speaker 1: The big news, which we talked about last time, how they couldn't find the original masters for Project Eiko, so they were using, like, this magical restoring device that would basically, you know, do the best job it could with the best laser disc sources they had available.
Speaker 1: What happened is Robert Woodhead, if you don't know Robert Woodhead, Robert Woodhead is a legend in the US anime industry, created Anime Ego, which I'm pretty sure is gone now, but Anime Ego was basically making the best legal anime releases back in the 2000s, 90s even, right?
Speaker 1: Very legendary, important person.
Speaker 1: Robert Woodhead went to some film vault somewhere, and apparently there was just, like, the way it was organized.
Speaker 1: there, like, the catalog or something was messed up, I don't know, a misspelling or a miscategorization?
Speaker 1: And Robert Woodhead knew how to find the Project Eiko masters that were definitely in that vault and were just, you know, not labeled or placed properly for some reason.
Speaker 0: Which means the Project Eiko re-release will now be from the original 35mm print instead of that very clever previous solution, which was pulling the raw data off of the laser discs and doing the best they could.
Speaker 1: Yep, so we're looking forward to this Project Eiko release here.
Speaker 0: Project Eiko was the third anime I ever saw.
Speaker 1: Maybe when it comes out, Geek Night's Time.
Speaker 0: I think it still holds up.
Speaker 0: I have not seen it in, like, a decade, I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen it in forever.
Speaker 0: I am confident it will be just as funny to me now as it was when I was in fourth grade.
Speaker 1: We need Eiko to go outside and find whoever's car alarm keeps going off.
Speaker 1: Of course, Eiko could just probably throw the car into the river and then we'd be fine, right?
Speaker 0: The fact that as a kid I didn't get that it was a comedy and I kind of just treated it as a superhero movie.
Speaker 1: Hmm.
Speaker 1: Alright, other news.
Speaker 1: So, everybody knows about, you know, you think about, like, legendary anime, you know, directors.
Speaker 1: We got our Satoshi Kans, you got your Miyazakis, obviously, right?
Speaker 1: All those people.
Speaker 1: There was a person that is not often mentioned, right, who was named Yasuo Otsuka.
Speaker 1: And Yasuo Otsuka wasn't, like, a director, it was like an animation director, right?
Speaker 1: But Yasuo Otsuka was sort of like even the before times, right?
Speaker 1: You know, he was like, you know, the mentor to the Miyazakis and the Isao Takahata's of the world, right?
Speaker 0: He joined Toei when it had a different name in 1956.
Speaker 1: Right, so he was like, you know, he gets to Toei and it's like, you know, Miyazaki's working on Horace, Prince of Sun.
Speaker 1: And it's like a young guy when Otsuka is already the old guy there, right?
Speaker 1: He worked on a lot of Lupin movies, you know, Future Boy Conan, right?
Speaker 1: All these, like, super old, you know, much older anime and then retired at some point.
Speaker 1: But yeah, the news is that he passed away at the age of 89.
Speaker 1: I'll take 89.
Speaker 1: I can't complain about that.
Speaker 1: But still a sad news, you know, such a legendary figure in the anime industry who does not get the deserved attention, right?
Speaker 1: Not being a, you know, primary director of super popular things that people know about today, right?
Speaker 1: But super important.
Speaker 1: The same way that, like, you know, Ip Man, who supposedly taught Bruce Lee, right, didn't get the attention, right?
Speaker 1: Bruce Lee got all the attention until more recently.
Speaker 1: People are like, oh, Ip Man, because someone made a good Ip Man movie, right?
Speaker 1: This is sort of that kind of deal.
Speaker 0: So instead of news, I've actually got three Geek Bytes because I've been watching a lot of animation lately, and there's a lot of really good stuff out there.
Speaker 0: I'll go brief on these because I'm pretty sure we'll review all three of these on Geek Nights at some point.
Speaker 0: But first, I know I mentioned this, I've seen an entire arc now of The Great Pretender, a recent anime.
Speaker 1: It's on the Netflix.
Speaker 0: It's on the Netflix.
Speaker 0: It's got Cowboy Bebop vibes, like, for real.
Speaker 1: The live-action Cowboy Bebop from Netflix has finished filming, supposedly, for a season.
Speaker 0: It's also got some big Lupin vibes.
Speaker 0: And what I'll say about it is that it is one of the better anime I've seen in a long time.
Speaker 0: You know that feeling when you're watching a show and you kind of like it, you watch a few episodes, you pause, maybe finish it later.
Speaker 0: But you know when you watch a show and an episode ends and all you think is, I just want to watch the next episode.
Speaker 0: This show is that.
Speaker 0: This is the kind of show where if we were still running RIT anime, we would have shown the first four episodes and would have probably done the marathon the following weekend.
Speaker 1: If we were running an anime club, though, today, how would it work getting Netflix permissions to screen things?
Speaker 0: You know what we should do?
Speaker 0: We should ask the RIT anime club.
Speaker 0: I got a lot of contacts there.
Speaker 0: Let's see how they do it.
Speaker 0: I'm curious what they do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm curious what the deal is now.
Speaker 0: I mean, we definitely flew fast and loose.
Speaker 0: One of our favorite techniques was to send a letter to the anime studio or the company that had the rights who we knew would probably say no.
Speaker 0: And we'd basically say, "Hey, we're going to show this on this date in our club.
Speaker 0: Let us know if that's not
Speaker 0: cool.".
Speaker 0: And either they wouldn't respond or the letter would come after we had already shown it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they're not going to, you know, you're basically betting.
Speaker 1: Like if they came after you with a lawyer, it's like the court would obviously see that you were doing this not in good faith.
Speaker 0: Yep, and if the court came after me, I would say, "This is a club and a college.
Speaker 0: I hereby resign from the
Speaker 0: club.".
Speaker 1: Yes, I'm not legally responsible for the thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, guess what, anime kids?
Speaker 0: Now that it's been 20 years, I can spill the sausage on how we actually ran the RIT anime club.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like the school is the one who's going to have to pay, not me.
Speaker 1: I guess they could academically kick you out of the school, right?
Speaker 0: I was just the facilities coordinator.
Speaker 0: I had no idea what the librarian was doing.
Speaker 0: But The Great Pretender is real good, and it is apparent how good it is from the first episode.
Speaker 0: I promise you, if you watch one episode of this, you're probably going to be into it.
Speaker 1: What are they pretending?
Speaker 0: They're con men.
Speaker 0: It's The Sting.
Speaker 0: This is a con artist show.
Speaker 0: The show starts following a small-time con artist in Japan who gets conned himself by a bigger con artist.
Speaker 0: And it just escalates and escalates and escalates.
Speaker 1: And then learns from the master con artist.
Speaker 0: This show goes from "I am pretending to be the water inspector to try to trick you into buying a filter," to "breaking bad with even bigger stakes within a couple
Speaker 0: episodes.".
Speaker 1: I am pretending to be the Prime Minister and getting away with it.
Speaker 0: Episode two, they're running a scam prop plane racing company in Singapore, and it is just going off the charts.
Speaker 0: The show is great.
Speaker 1: What else did you watch?
Speaker 0: So we watched a movie, a recent movie.
Speaker 0: This is a Chinese animated film from 2019, The Legend of Hei.
Speaker 0: We watched it, I think, with G-Kids and the Children's International Film Festival.
Speaker 0: I don't know how to watch it otherwise, because that's done now.
Speaker 1: There's an official trailer.
Speaker 1: That's a nice movie poster with a cute little kitty.
Speaker 0: This movie is about that kitty.
Speaker 0: It is beautiful.
Speaker 0: The characters are great.
Speaker 0: The dub, good enough.
Speaker 0: It's a pretty good dub, because the subtitle version wasn't available, at least when we watched it.
Speaker 0: I highly recommend this movie.
Speaker 0: I think it is specifically up Scott's alley.
Speaker 0: I have very little bad to say about this movie.
Speaker 0: I enjoyed it to the end.
Speaker 0: The ending was good.
Speaker 0: The plot was good.
Speaker 0: The characters were great.
Speaker 0: It moved quick.
Speaker 0: It had a lot of anime tropes that were good, but it also did its own thing.
Speaker 0: It's very clearly a Chinese movie, informed by Chinese sensibilities, Chinese animation.
Speaker 0: You should watch it, and I'd like to say a lot more about it that I think we should save for a review.
Speaker 0: This is a must-see movie.
Speaker 0: If you like animated movies, there's no reason not to watch this movie.
Speaker 1: It does appear that on the New York International Children's Film Festival.org website, nicff.org, you can still buy and watch movies from the festival this year, because it was online.
Speaker 0: I think what expired for us is we bought access to the festival itself.
Speaker 0: We watched all the shorts.
Speaker 1: You can get an encore pass for $60, an all-access pass for $100.
Speaker 1: Take your time.
Speaker 1: Watch the whole slate whenever you want with an all-access pass valid through March 21st.
Speaker 1: So if you buy it for $100, you've got three or four days, basically, depending on where you live and when you hear this, or maybe zero days.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll have to watch The Legend of Hey real soon.
Speaker 0: I think you will specifically like many parts of this movie.
Speaker 1: I guess Sunday would be the end, but yeah, it looks like you still have time.
Speaker 1: That's the point.
Speaker 0: And third, I watched Raya and the Last Dragon, the new Disney movie.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: It is, honestly, pretty fantastic.
Speaker 0: There's a lot to recommend this movie.
Speaker 0: I think the things that I would want to say about it are that one, it's got a really cool dragon character design.
Speaker 0: Who is featured prominently.
Speaker 0: Two, mostly female cast, like it's mostly women.
Speaker 0: There aren't like main dudes in this movie, which I think is a good step for Disney.
Speaker 0: And three, it's just beautiful.
Speaker 0: I want to watch this on the big screen once.
Speaker 0: that's safe to do, because I don't think our little shitty 1080p failing television really did this movie justice.
Speaker 1: It is actually sort of eh, because the TV we have, the 1080p TV we have, it's 50 something, maybe it's 50 inch, I guess, I don't know.
Speaker 1: But it's plenty good, right?
Speaker 1: There's nothing wrong with it.
Speaker 0: Not like mine that is actually failing bit by bit.
Speaker 1: But I bought a 4K monitor, so 4K content is still quite rare.
Speaker 1: But occasionally, there's like a YouTube video that's 4K, and it's like, wow, is it nice to watch it in 4K.
Speaker 0: I got these 4K monitors a while ago, and you came over, and you saw how long ago this was, and I had Auto Chess open before Geek Nights, because I was finishing a match.
Speaker 1: Why does your Auto Chess look so good?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you were like, and I was like, Scott, it's 4K.
Speaker 1: But it's like, yeah, I'm still not going to get a 4K TV, though, until that one breaks, or until lots and lots of content is 4K, and not just the occasional YouTube video, or Netflix.
Speaker 0: But this movie is good, I like this movie a lot, not just because, if you know me at all, you know how into dragons I am, but I like that.
Speaker 0: dragons featured prominently, and didn't just die at the end of the movie, like usually happens with dragon stuff.
Speaker 0: But the ending is good, and I like what they did with it, and I'm being obtuse on purpose, because obviously, let's go see this movie, I'm not going to spoil it for you.
Speaker 0: But the other thing I'll say about it is that I saw a lot of people online complaining that the dragon was too cutesy, too feminine, or too My Little Pony looking, and I would say that the dragon character design is what makes this movie great instead of just good.
Speaker 0: This is a My Little Pony looking character design, and I am here for this.
Speaker 1: Anyone who makes that kind of complaint is just telling it on themselves.
Speaker 0: Yep, yep, yep, those are the literal words I was about to say, and you preempted me.
Speaker 1: Come on, let me know what kind of person you are once you say something like that.
Speaker 0: Yep, but the last thing I'll say is that the character, the dragon, when she comes onto the scene, like appears in the movie, you know that archetype character like Eda in The Owl House, or Ryoko in Tenchi Muyo, like someone who is ancient and powerful, and she's kind of dangerous, but she's also kind of a disaster and a fuck-up.
Speaker 0: Like, that archetype of character is one of my favorite tropes, and the dragon in this movie is that.
Speaker 0: The dragon is kind of like the fuck-up dragon, and it's good.
Speaker 1: How would it be if you made a story where there's like four of those characters?
Speaker 0: That's Tenchi Muyo.
Speaker 1: Is it?
Speaker 1: I thought there's only a couple, anyway.
Speaker 0: I mean, I guess Owl House, there's only one, like Eda, like it's the character who is that, and everyone else around her.
Speaker 1: I guess El Hazzard, aren't there.
Speaker 1: like the several...
Speaker 0: You know what, the three priestesses are all kind of like that.
Speaker 1: That's right, the three priestesses in El Hazzard, but there's sort of like one character?
Speaker 1: I don't know, anyway.
Speaker 0: Also, the teacher, it's not like the female version, but he's the male equivalent of that.
Speaker 0: What does that say?
Speaker 0: He's like the late 30s kind of a fuck-up, but actually does the right thing.
Speaker 0: Out of that whole space of flawed disaster characters who do the right thing in the end, but are actually kind of evil sometimes, too.
Speaker 0: There's something going on that I like about that kind of character.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: Scott called dibs on this thing of the day, so I'll let him go second.
Speaker 0: I did.
Speaker 0: I was hoping he'd forget, like I had it open in a tab, because it's so good.
Speaker 0: So I had to bring the most powerful thing I could bring, and the best I got is... You know the game Among Us?
Speaker 0: There's an imposter.
Speaker 1: It's pretty popular.
Speaker 0: Go Google, I'm not going to explain what Among Us is.
Speaker 0: Another channel I've done before, TwoSet Violin, those two cool violin dudes who talk about violins and like violin playing.
Speaker 0: They did a video.
Speaker 0: This is so perfect.
Speaker 0: They made their own version of Among Us that can only be played by classical string musicians.
Speaker 0: They got a bunch of musicians together.
Speaker 0: They're going to play a piece.
Speaker 0: Four of the people in this group, or two depends, like they have a bunch of different modes.
Speaker 0: they tried, have the same sheet music, except there are specific sections in red that are wrong.
Speaker 0: They have to play the wrong parts and not get caught.
Speaker 1: Okay, okay.
Speaker 0: But everyone else can be like, "Nope, I'm calling a meeting.
Speaker 0: I heard Joey Jojo.
Speaker 0: I think they played a flat...".
Speaker 1: But maybe you just fucked up.
Speaker 0: If you just fuck up, think about it, Among Us, if you just fuck up, you're going to get voted off the island anyway.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: So if you get to the end of the piece and there are still imposters alive, then they win?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so this video is 30 minutes long.
Speaker 0: They made up good rules.
Speaker 0: Watch the video to see.
Speaker 0: They made the rules sufficient to make this work for real, and that is legitimately impressive.
Speaker 0: Most of the time when someone says, "Oh, let's make Among Us but fa, like fubar, like make my own rules, it's always
Speaker 0: garbage."
Speaker 0: Or, "It's just a
Speaker 0: joke.".
Speaker 0: They did this for real, and I'm very impressed by that.
Speaker 1: It sounds fun.
Speaker 1: Something for musicians to do because they can't hold any concerts.
Speaker 1: Did you know that Met Opera laid a bunch of people off?
Speaker 1: I think some large percentage, I heard as high as 40% of people just left New York City, 10% retired.
Speaker 1: They're basically threatening if they come back to negotiate.
Speaker 1: I think I was reading, if they come back to negotiate, they're going to offer them partial money.
Speaker 1: They don't even want to go back because then they'll have a shit deal.
Speaker 1: It's like they're better off just holding out.
Speaker 0: The New Republic Library, this is a total aside, they have a kit.
Speaker 0: If you have a library card, you can just go get it.
Speaker 0: Anyone in New York can get this.
Speaker 0: The kit is if you are a performer or musician of some kind, and you need hardware to be able to stream yourself and create from your house, they'll give you a fancy keyboard, a bunch of recording equipment, lights, cameras, everything in a kit.
Speaker 1: What does that have to do with the people at the Met Opera being screwed out of money?
Speaker 0: Because the rationale for this kit is that a lot of creators in New York City have left New York City or otherwise can't create.
Speaker 0: There's a situation around New York's going to be struggling to find even backup musicians or studio musicians, people to fill in all the creative gaps that currently were previously filled.
Speaker 1: I think that's an incentive to stay.
Speaker 1: If you can hold out through the end and people don't come back so quickly, you can then demand higher wages at the point where it's like, "Who else are you going to
Speaker 1: get?".
Speaker 1: All the other people who play this instrument have left town.
Speaker 1: Who are you going to find to play an oboe in five minutes?
Speaker 1: It's me.
Speaker 1: I'm the only oboe in town now.
Speaker 0: Currently, the whole reason a lot of things are in New York is because you can literally say, "I need extremely long, detailed set of skills," and there are like 10 people who can do that for you.
Speaker 1: I need someone who can play an oboe at a master level and weighs less than this amount because the stage is shoddy.
Speaker 0: Suspended from the sky, and they have to be able to play DDR because we're making a movie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they have to speak this language, and they have to learn this piece or already know it.
Speaker 1: It's like, "Okay, we found two candidates.
Speaker 1: You want to do whole
Speaker 1: auditions?".
Speaker 0: So you got a thing of the day?
Speaker 1: Oh, I do.
Speaker 1: I forgot.
Speaker 1: I was going meta moment land there.
Speaker 1: This thing of the day, it's from that website, The Hard Times, which is basically the onion of video game nerdery.
Speaker 1: I think we've used it for things of the day before.
Speaker 1: But this particular article is that case where parody approaches reality, but you can't tell the difference between parody and reality.
Speaker 1: It's usually a bad thing.
Speaker 1: Someone's making a satirical parody about something awful in the world, and it's like, "No, actually, that's real,".
Speaker 1: and you'll get not the onion.
Speaker 0: Or the joke is just the headline, and the article isn't actually funny.
Speaker 0: It's just to support the joke.
Speaker 1: Right, so this article here, a parody article, supposedly, is about one of my favorite scenes in anime.
Speaker 1: It's actually a scene that happens in many anime, the scene where they're just showing an empty street or terrain in Japan somewhere, usually including homes, trees, power lines, very frequent.
Speaker 1: And you're hearing the noises of the cicadas as they sound in Japan.
Speaker 1: If you're watching an anime, what this scene is supposed to tell you is A, we're filling up time in the episode.
Speaker 1: B, we're pacing the episode with some environmental storytelling.
Speaker 1: And C, it's summer and it's hot.
Speaker 1: We're letting you know what the weather is and the time of year is.
Speaker 1: The only one I've seen where it has even further meanings are in Lain, because the power lines in Lain have an additional meaning, and those are a bigger focus in the visual aspect of the scene.
Speaker 1: And in Evangelion, because in Evangelion, I don't know how many people watch Evangelion and don't realize this, it's always summer.
Speaker 1: Winter has been destroyed.
Speaker 1: No one's having any babies.
Speaker 1: It's a semi-apocalyptic situation that they are stuck in.
Speaker 1: No humans are being born.
Speaker 1: It's super hot everywhere on Earth.
Speaker 1: Is there even precipitation?
Speaker 0: The end of summer is an endless summer, and there is nothing coming after that.
Speaker 1: Right, so that's why there's always cicadas in Evangelion, reminding you it's still hot.
Speaker 1: The hotness has not stopped.
Speaker 1: And then the scenes of characters wiping sweat off all the time because it's so hot out and drinking beers.
Speaker 1: It's hot.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: So here, the article that they made is what?
Speaker 1: Top 10 power lines and cicada noises?
Speaker 0: Static shots of power lines with cicada noises.
Speaker 1: Right, so it's like, for them, they're like, "Ah, it's a joke.
Speaker 1: Lots of anime have this
Speaker 1: scene.".
Speaker 1: But for me, it's like, sincere.
Speaker 1: It's like, I love those.
Speaker 1: I love static shots of power lines and cicada noises.
Speaker 1: Those are a good, somewhat good top 10.
Speaker 0: I have very little disagreement with this list.
Speaker 1: There's a few of the shows I've never heard of.
Speaker 0: But the commentary is real.
Speaker 0: Like, there's a real commentary on each one of these.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like, you know, you read an Onion article.
Speaker 1: Usually, not the Onion article.
Speaker 1: It's like, you're reading a true story and you're like, "This should be on the
Speaker 1: Onion.".
Speaker 1: This is, I'm reading something on an Onion equivalent.
Speaker 1: They're writing it as a joke, but I take it completely at face value.
Speaker 1: I'm like, "Yeah.
Speaker 1: Power lines and cicada noises.
Speaker 1: That's my jam.
Speaker 1: Pick me
Speaker 1: up.".
Speaker 0: Now to see a top 10 "I haven't yet shown you my full
Speaker 0: power.".
Speaker 1: I would agree with that also.
Speaker 1: I love "I haven't yet shown you my full
Speaker 1: power.".
Speaker 0: In the meantime, we can't go anywhere, but our panels can.
Speaker 0: So if you missed the Judge Anime by its Cover panel that we did for the Crunchyroll Expo, well, basically because we couldn't redistribute that on our YouTube channel, almost the exact same panel is going to be at Zenk icon online this weekend.
Speaker 1: Okay, sure.
Speaker 0: Because it's basically, we did 45 minutes of talking about how to judge anime by its cover, and then we only actually talked about shows in the very end.
Speaker 0: And I went back and actually looked at how we judged those shows.
Speaker 0: Gibiade wasn't as good as we hoped it would be.
Speaker 0: But otherwise, we were pretty spot on as far as I could see.
Speaker 1: Otherwise... Oh, so the Book Club book after a year plus, who knows how long, is still The Tale of Genji, the first novel ever written by humans.
Speaker 1: And the human who wrote it is Murasaki Shikibu.
Speaker 1: I read a significant portion of the next chapter that I was reading last night where progress is being made.
Speaker 0: I did not read more since we did a show on Monday, but I'm continuing at a steady pace.
Speaker 1: I am getting close to 10% complete.
Speaker 0: Alright, maybe 10% is a good point.
Speaker 0: 10-12% is a good point for us to do a little brief chat in the moment.
Speaker 1: Are we going to just do 10 episodes instead of one?
Speaker 1: I feel like we can just do one episode when we're done reading 100% like we usually do.
Speaker 1: But yeah, if you want to read along with us, you can.
Speaker 1: Or, you know, wait and we'll do an episode.
Speaker 1: And then, I promise after that, I'm going to at least... I can't help what rim picks for Book Clubs, but I will make a concerted... You know, after this incident of the Book Club that went on too long and a pandemic, right?
Speaker 1: I'm going to basically be like, "Well, a pandemic can happen at any time,
Speaker 1: again.".
Speaker 1: So therefore, we're going to do more rapid book clubbing, at least I hope, afterwards.
Speaker 0: The key is I can get outside, I can sit in a park and read a book, and that really accelerates my book reading.
Speaker 1: Or a beach, hopefully.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, I just want to lay on a beach all day reading books.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Well, anyway.
Speaker 0: Alright, so, Vultus 5 is an anime from 1977.
Speaker 1: So this anime was made, basically, you know, there was a whole bunch of robot shows made back in the day, right?
Speaker 1: And a lot of them were made by the same company.
Speaker 1: They would make one, it would end, you know, for the kids, right?
Speaker 1: And then they would come and they'd make another one for the kids again, right?
Speaker 1: So, you know, there was a lot of studios involved.
Speaker 1: If you look at Wikipedia, it's like, "Studios, Tohoku Shinsha Nippon Sunrise Toei
Speaker 1: Company.".
Speaker 1: It was on TV Asahi, it was the broadcasting company.
Speaker 1: And it's created by Saburo Yatsude.
Speaker 1: Saburo Yatsude is not a person.
Speaker 1: It was basically a made-up name that they would put as the creator of several things, indicating that basically the same team of people was basically creating the show, but they didn't actually put an actual creator's name on it.
Speaker 1: the way that, you know, Leiji Matsumoto is a real person or Kiyo Hayamezaki is a real person.
Speaker 1: And there were several such shows made by the same people.
Speaker 1: The one you're probably most familiar with is Voltron/Beast King Go Lion, right?
Speaker 1: Which we can do a show about someday if we haven't already.
Speaker 1: Voltron came out in 1980, early '80s, right?
Speaker 1: So this preceded Voltron by quite a few years, for four years maybe.
Speaker 1: But you cannot help but compare the two shows because there are so many similarities, but enough differences that are significant and worth discussing, right?
Speaker 1: So it's a show, there's 40 episodes, it is made to sell toys to children.
Speaker 0: Yup, Judy, you cannot escape that fact.
Speaker 0: In literally every episode, The Volt is Five, it'll form, or if it doesn't form, there's a reason why it didn't form.
Speaker 0: And then it's gonna basically spin tops.
Speaker 1: It'll use all of its special attacks, which are advertising the features of the toy, it will use the same special moves, right, or get new special moves.
Speaker 1: There's, you know, stock animation sequences of it transforming or doing special attacks that are repeated every episode.
Speaker 1: Sometimes more than once per episode will have to combine.
Speaker 1: You know, it's basically showing kids all the different ways they can play with this toy, The Volt is Five, which is five vehicles, right, formed that you can combine into a robot in kind of a not great way.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like I think at this point in time, like they probably still weren't great at making the combining toys, right?
Speaker 1: This predates like the Transformers Devastator, it predates Voltron obviously, right?
Speaker 0: A mask which had the most complex transforming toys.
Speaker 1: It predates Matt Cross Valkyries, right?
Speaker 1: So it's the way in which the toy functions and thus the way it appears in the show is very inelegant, right?
Speaker 1: It's like the legs and the waist are just like one big U-shaped boat thing.
Speaker 0: They go to great pains to show you like, "No, this makes sense," when like the cockpit of the main guy will like rotate twice.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the feet are like come off and combine into a vehicle and then separate and just stick on the bottom as the two feet.
Speaker 1: Like the ninja girl's job is to pilot the feet.
Speaker 1: The two arms are vehicles and the rest of it is just one vehicle.
Speaker 1: The head and torso is all one vehicle.
Speaker 1: So it's not very elegant.
Speaker 1: It's kind of cool, right?
Speaker 1: It's called the Volt is Five.
Speaker 1: I think that might have been just some, they tried to use English.
Speaker 1: and it's just the Volt's Five, like Volt as in electricity because it's powered by electromagnetism.
Speaker 0: Yup, the translation of the name is Super Electromagnetic Machine, Volt's Five.
Speaker 1: Right, Volt is Five.
Speaker 1: And it's called Volt is Five because it has five pilots just like Voltron.
Speaker 1: It even has, slash go lion, this main white dude, right?
Speaker 1: There's big dude.
Speaker 1: There's jerky dude in blue.
Speaker 1: It's even the same colors, right?
Speaker 1: Main dude is red.
Speaker 1: Yeah, little kid, right?
Speaker 1: And there's the lady.
Speaker 1: Little kid is in green and then girl, right?
Speaker 1: It's from 1970.
Speaker 1: The sexism and other problems of 1970s Japanese kid show cannot be overlooked.
Speaker 0: They're there.
Speaker 1: They are there in full force.
Speaker 1: And that's what the show is.
Speaker 1: It's monster of the week, right?
Speaker 1: How do they, they form a team to fight an alien invading force that sends evil beast knights, right?
Speaker 1: In Voltron, it was Robeasts, I guess, that came in those awesome coffins that would land.
Speaker 1: Here, the bad guys basically are just building beast knights and sending them to fight.
Speaker 1: Monster of the week.
Speaker 1: And Volt's Five wins every week somehow, unless it's a two-parter or something.
Speaker 1: And then that's the show.
Speaker 1: I don't know what happens at the end because I'm only 17 episodes in.
Speaker 1: I'm seven.
Speaker 0: And I guess what I, I don't think we want to explain the plot and the characters to you.
Speaker 1: I explained the plot just now.
Speaker 0: But there's like the nuances, like each character has their deal.
Speaker 0: Like the jerky guy on the team is an American cowboy who uses a whip.
Speaker 0: And he's a jerk, but then he becomes less of a jerk.
Speaker 1: I don't know if he's Japanese and he spent time in the US or if he's actually American.
Speaker 0: Wasn't super clear, actually.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: Well, his mom blew herself up to kill those wolves.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: But the impressions I had were that, one, I want to get back to this after we talk about more impressions.
Speaker 0: The meta plot is shockingly more complex than it possibly even, like, they did not need to have that much backstory in the show.
Speaker 0: Or that much consistency.
Speaker 0: Like early parts of the show, because I do know some things that happened toward the end of the show, just from knowledge of the show.
Speaker 0: The meta plot is way more complex than you'd realize.
Speaker 0: And every episode reveals little bits of it.
Speaker 0: Like early on, like these beast nights come down.
Speaker 0: But then you learn, I want to say in like episode three or four, that the evil aliens put brains of people, of their own people, into these things.
Speaker 0: And that is not a piece of information to forget.
Speaker 0: That actually seems to matter a lot as the plot goes on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I think that's the two significant things about this show that make it stand out from your typical fight monsters every week.
Speaker 1: Because I actually think in a lot of ways this show is, despite being older and having a crappier toy...
Speaker 0: Oh, it's better than later Monster of the Week shows.
Speaker 1: Yeah, is more advanced even than Go Lion and other shows.
Speaker 1: And for these reasons, number one, you know, Voltron takes place in like this future, you know, like empty planet basically.
Speaker 1: This bad guy's attacking.
Speaker 1: It's literally just Monster of the Week.
Speaker 0: It's a lot like Thundercats, or even Eman to a degree.
Speaker 1: Thundercats has more of a plot that goes on, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but very little of that is revealed episode by episode.
Speaker 1: I remember you didn't see the beginning of Thundercats.
Speaker 0: After the beginning, a lot of the later shows were refined.
Speaker 0: They'd have the beginning episodes.
Speaker 1: Thundercats has the pattern of plot episodes and non-plot episodes, right?
Speaker 0: Voltron has almost no plot episodes.
Speaker 1: Voltron has almost no plot episodes.
Speaker 1: In Volt is Five, every episode I've seen is a plot episode.
Speaker 1: There is not just a Monster of the Week, but something significant happens in every episode.
Speaker 1: Sometimes the significant thing is simply character development, but it's not little character development.
Speaker 1: It'll be like big development for one character, right?
Speaker 1: In some episodes, it will be like, okay, it was just Monster of the Week, but there was a significant danger.
Speaker 1: Like they were not even, they were like getting really ruined.
Speaker 1: Like the base got messed up.
Speaker 0: Well like episode two, the base almost collapses.
Speaker 0: Their mom, I guess spoilers, fucking gets into a fighter jet and kamikazes the beast to buy them time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the thing.
Speaker 1: Some episodes, characters die.
Speaker 1: And it's like, yeah, Voltron, there's like one guy who dies.
Speaker 1: Spoilers.
Speaker 1: But then that's kind of it.
Speaker 1: Here, someone died and someone else died.
Speaker 1: It's like significant primary characters are getting the axe, right?
Speaker 1: Like shit goes down in Volt's Five on a frequent basis.
Speaker 1: And it's like, there is like stuff that like messes with you all the time.
Speaker 1: Like, whoa, this show is really going hardcore.
Speaker 1: There was one episode, right?
Speaker 1: And is the second significant thing.
Speaker 1: I'll tie it in here, right?
Speaker 1: Is that this show actually takes place on an earth, a theoretical future earth that looks a lot like not really that far future an earth.
Speaker 1: But like the earth actually matters.
Speaker 1: There was a whole episode that was political where like the UN equivalent gets together and they can't agree.
Speaker 1: And then the diplomats all get endangered, right?
Speaker 1: And Voltus has to come and save them.
Speaker 1: And then they all agree to like actually ally against the aliens.
Speaker 0: And in the beginning, it's like there's a lot of science fiction and environmental storytelling and like world building.
Speaker 0: Like the global militaries are aligned differently from the current like real world.
Speaker 0: And they all try to fight these things.
Speaker 1: It's like, is it deep?
Speaker 1: No, but for a selling kids toys show, it's deep, right?
Speaker 1: Well, it's deeper than you might realize.
Speaker 1: It's like if you went to a kiddie pool, right?
Speaker 1: And it's like, yes, this is a kiddie pool.
Speaker 1: This is not the real pool.
Speaker 1: It's not the deep end.
Speaker 1: It's a kiddie pool.
Speaker 1: But you get in and suddenly a kiddie pool usually is like what?
Speaker 1: Not even a foot deep usually, right?
Speaker 1: Imagine if the kiddie pool you stepped in and you were up to your waist.
Speaker 1: Like that's surprising.
Speaker 1: Like, you know, you don't expect a kiddie pool to be that deep.
Speaker 0: What I know about the actual show, because I had had the plot described to me before I watched it.
Speaker 0: But what was described to me is like way later plot.
Speaker 0: The home planet of these aliens matters a lot.
Speaker 1: Oh, yes, it does.
Speaker 1: There is.
Speaker 1: there is basically.
Speaker 0: How did Dr.
Speaker 0: Go know that they were coming?
Speaker 0: That is like a whole fucking thing.
Speaker 1: Three of the people in there in the robot, the three are basically sons of these two scientists, one of whom is that mom who mentioned doing kamikaze.
Speaker 1: And the other one is Dr.
Speaker 1: Go, who you never see in the show, at least not at the start.
Speaker 1: And you know that he knew the aliens were coming.
Speaker 1: And therefore he built volts five to defend the earth from the aliens he knew were coming.
Speaker 1: And then he went off into space.
Speaker 1: And you got to assume he went to meet the aliens out there in space.
Speaker 1: And then stuff happens in episodes.
Speaker 1: I saw recently that show that the aliens at least know Dr.
Speaker 1: Go exists.
Speaker 1: And nobody looks like and something is up.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And it's like Voltron doesn't have anything like that.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: And in a lot of ways, it's the biggest takeaway.
Speaker 0: Watch that for even if you don't want to watch a stupid kid show like this.
Speaker 0: Watch the first episode and then go rewatch the first episode of Evangelion.
Speaker 0: They're honestly almost the same thing.
Speaker 0: Like the base they're defending is nerve to a T. Like the way they defended the dynamic of like all the people.
Speaker 1: It's also.
Speaker 1: I think the difference is the base is clearly a toy.
Speaker 1: Nerve is not a toy.
Speaker 0: I mean, yeah, but it's still like.
Speaker 0: those scenes are very similar to the scenes when nerve headquarters is under attack.
Speaker 0: The Dr.
Speaker 0: Go big gendo vibes in terms of the militaries of the world all trying to fight this new menace and they can't.
Speaker 0: And then they turn to that scientist who had a secret project going all along.
Speaker 0: There are so many parallels.
Speaker 0: Evangelion was 100% riffing on like the setup of this show and shows like it.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: The last thing I got to say about the show is that, you know, it is significantly hardcore.
Speaker 0: When Voltus 5 kills a beast knight, like that is a brutal scene with that sword.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Voltus 5 takes out a sword just like to cut the bad guy as like it's finishing blow.
Speaker 1: You know that when the sword comes out, like the bad guys get the beast knights going down.
Speaker 1: Voltus 5, when he does the V attack with the sword, hits the beast knight in its shoulder or whatever its shoulder.
Speaker 0: We learned later these beast knights have sentient brains implanted into them.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: These beast knights also come in, they're really fun and creative.
Speaker 1: The lots of different shapes and sizes.
Speaker 1: The episode I just watched, the beast knight was a flying triceratops.
Speaker 1: Voltus eventually eclipses its wings and it becomes a regular triceratops.
Speaker 1: But there's like, they're always an interesting shape and size and they always like animate them.
Speaker 1: Like there's the stock footage of the combinations, but the battles are not stock footage.
Speaker 1: They're not great animation.
Speaker 1: It's 1970s TV animation.
Speaker 1: But they're like real fights.
Speaker 1: But yeah, they're animating kind of in a pro wrestling kind of fashion.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, the pro wrestling vibe in the battles.
Speaker 1: But yeah, Voltus will take its sword, hit the enemy in its shoulder equivalent, slice down at an angle to near its groin, navel area, twist the sword around.
Speaker 1: And they show this to you like a visceral highlight.
Speaker 1: They highlight the twisting of the sword like it's just a mat.
Speaker 1: You imagine like a sword twisting in your guts like, oh, and then we'll pull the sword back up and out the other shoulder, making a V shaped cut because it's Voltus five Roman numeral V. Right.
Speaker 1: And it's like the V, the sword V attack or whatever.
Speaker 1: And then the enemy will explode like it just got fist of the North Star.
Speaker 1: And this happens every episode.
Speaker 1: It is brutal.
Speaker 1: But not just that brutality, but like characters are getting shot.
Speaker 1: They're like times where like, you know, that the enemies will be like stabbing.
Speaker 1: And you'll see like the enemies, like stabs, like come into the cockpit and almost hit the pilots.
Speaker 0: Or remember, there's the sword wielding demon knight that has that sword, the special magic sword.
Speaker 0: And the one dude has to train to learn how to fight the sword.
Speaker 0: And that training is him.
Speaker 0: get it like that.
Speaker 0: He, the amount of physical injury that is animated on him in that episode is very surprising.
Speaker 1: Now the one, the one in Congress, there's a lot of incongruous things because it's a kid's show.
Speaker 1: But the biggest one for me is that the start of the show, not a spoiler, the bad guys invade and they destroy the shit out of earth.
Speaker 1: Like they wreck it.
Speaker 1: It's like what is even left on earth, right?
Speaker 1: And then in another episode, it's like the kid goes to a model boat sailing contest in Tokyo.
Speaker 1: And it's like, you're having model boat sailing contest, Tokyo still exists?
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure it got destroyed.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, the kids were still going to school in Evangelion for some reason.
Speaker 1: Maybe, but they were going like the nerve school in the protected area, right?
Speaker 1: Not in the city, you know, not in Tokyo.
Speaker 1: Anyway, but then, uh, fricking Tokyo gets destroyed, right?
Speaker 1: And it's like, okay, well now Tokyo is destroyed.
Speaker 1: It's like, no, then it's back to normal.
Speaker 1: They don't seem to like keep like that world is destroyed thing.
Speaker 1: The way that like space battleship Yamato is like, yeah, the world is destroyed.
Speaker 0: Part of the way that seems to fit in is that they, the aliens show up and are fucking up earth and ready to rock.
Speaker 0: But then when Volt is five, the Evangelion appears, they back off.
Speaker 0: They're like, oh shit, there's, there's a danger and actually dangerous thing here.
Speaker 0: We can't just take over.
Speaker 0: And they sort of like retreat to their sanctum to deal with that threat before they resume the invasion.
Speaker 1: Right now, the final thing that really makes me like the show quite a bit is that, you know, when you watch a kid's show, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, why don't the bad guys just do this?
Speaker 1: Why don't the bad guys just do that?
Speaker 0: It's like, I was watching an episode and I thought, wow, the way the show is structured, if they just sent two beast knights at one time, like they're fucked.
Speaker 0: It's over.
Speaker 0: Game over.
Speaker 0: That's, this is a kid's show.
Speaker 0: They should just send two beast knights, literally the next episode.
Speaker 0: They send two beast knights and they almost win because of that.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: That's what it's like.
Speaker 1: The bad guys in this show are not fools, right?
Speaker 0: They are actually not Skeletor fucking up over and over and over again.
Speaker 0: Imagine if Skeletor was like, well, that didn't work.
Speaker 0: Let's try a different plan.
Speaker 1: They're not failing from incompetence, right?
Speaker 1: They're failing, you know, due to simply, you know, volt is five and the Falcon team Falcons, the base, right?
Speaker 1: Like going all out and using, you know, the ingenuity and strength and whatever of humanity, um, to like come through the impossible odds.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: The bad guys are not fools.
Speaker 1: Like they're constantly, they're like, what if we could just stop voltage five from combining?
Speaker 1: It would be five separate shitty vehicles.
Speaker 1: They do it.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Wait, wait, wait.
Speaker 0: The kid's off on his own.
Speaker 0: They, they send a beast knight literally just to murder the kid.
Speaker 1: Like, they're like, Ooh, what?
Speaker 1: They're like, Oh, why did that one vehicle leave the base to go on its own?
Speaker 1: Let's go get it.
Speaker 1: It's separated.
Speaker 1: Let's go, go, go.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: The, the bad guys are not fools.
Speaker 1: They go all out.
Speaker 1: They do not hold back in trying to destroy volt as five, you know, and volt is five, you know, comes really close to losing compared to other big robots I've seen.
Speaker 1: And it only wins by like the skin of its teeth.
Speaker 0: Uh, obviously like in one episode, like actually breaks through that shield.
Speaker 0: You know, that scene in Ava near the very end where an angel busts into the room and it's like, like Misato's looking up at it and they, everyone just freezes and it's, it's about to do its thing.
Speaker 0: One of the beasts kind of does the same thing to the base and they barely survive.
Speaker 0: And it's, it's, it's a pretty good scene.
Speaker 0: They animate that beast, like beating the shit out of the base too.
Speaker 1: So, uh, and like the base like got messed up, like they had to, they couldn't get out from one scene I watched recently.
Speaker 1: You didn't see this.
Speaker 1: The, they couldn't open the gates to get the, you know, to fly the voltage vehicles out of the, I saw that one.
Speaker 0: I think that happens in an episode I saw.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: And then they're like, shoot missiles at it and they blow up the gate.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: They shot, they just blew up the front of the base and flew out.
Speaker 1: And then later, uh, the front of the base is like still blown up.
Speaker 0: Or also like one episode I was thinking, why do they even have all these defenses?
Speaker 0: They just animate these defenses of getting destroyed by the beast.
Speaker 0: Every episode, the next episode, they had a stronger missile that actually like gave the beast pause.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And they have like the tops.
Speaker 1: at first, the tops kind of are garbage.
Speaker 1: I'm like, well, I just pull out the sword right away.
Speaker 1: Sometimes they do just pull out the sword right away.
Speaker 1: Sometimes they do just combine right away.
Speaker 1: Sometimes sometimes they don't even need to combine.
Speaker 1: the other items work.
Speaker 0: They spin a different thing, not the top.
Speaker 0: They spin like some projectile that the beast shot at them.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, they're getting creative and not just doing the same stuff every time in the battle portions.
Speaker 1: Um, cause usually, you know, this kind of show, you just want to see the other parts and fast forward the battle.
Speaker 1: Cause the battle is the same boring thing every time.
Speaker 1: Um, so yeah, volt is five has a lot going on.
Speaker 1: I think, you know, I'm not going to say I recommend it cause it is a kid's show to sell you a toy.
Speaker 0: I would watch this before I would watch go lion.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, this is a show so far from what I seen.
Speaker 1: If you're gonna watch a show to sell kids toys, why not this one?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And you're not going to watch such a show.
Speaker 1: Don't watch any of them.
Speaker 0: But if you're an anime fan at all, like if you actually like think about and care about anime specifically, watch one episode of this and watch the first episode of Evangelion again and do a compare and contrast.
Speaker 0: Like, trust me.
Speaker 1: Or watch it.
Speaker 1: Watch it.
Speaker 1: Go one episode of go lion also random one.
Speaker 1: Cause there are a lot of them are more similar to each other.
Speaker 0: But this show, like if you skip, like I thought like I watched seven episodes.
Speaker 0: I was like, I should skip ahead and watch like a random episode from like a few later.
Speaker 0: so I could like have more to talk about on the show.
Speaker 0: I skipped a few episodes ahead and I have no fucking idea what's going on anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Like I said, the status, there is no like solid status quo.
Speaker 1: It's like they keep changing it.
Speaker 1: And that, you know, under normal, more normal circumstances of this kind of show wouldn't have kept watching.
Speaker 1: But, uh, this one I did.
Speaker 0: So the fact that we both kept watching and didn't just watch the minimum four and then do this show is telling.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So it's on crunchy roll.
Speaker 1: Uh, you can just go watch it.
Speaker 1: Um, and that's that volt is volts five.
Speaker 1: However you want to pronounce it.
Speaker 1: Um, Chodenji machine volts five.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And the Patreon Patrons for this episode of Geek Nights are Alan Joyce, Henry McNichol, Link Gagee, Dredd, Lily Tanner, Chris Reimer, Glenn DeWalt, and Graham Finch.
Speaker 0: Just like a new guy.
Speaker 0: Now go through the last year or so podcast to make room to sing, rent from New Zealand Review, Mad Bull 34, Cowards, Ryan Parrish, Riverfront, Harold Taylor, Ron.
Speaker 0: You hold the key to my heart, and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Speaker 0: And now I leave you with something you probably should have seen coming.