Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, July 27th, 2021.
Speaker 1: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight we are talking about the grindy, pay-to-win, Pokemon Unite MOBA.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So, uh, we're not gonna dwell on it, but, uh, the NHL expansion draft did happen for the newest team that joined the NHL, the Seattle Kraken.
Speaker 0: If you don't understand what that means, it basically, every team chooses which players that are the most important players on their team.
Speaker 0: And there's some list, you have to meet some requirements.
Speaker 0: And then when there's a new team that comes out of nowhere and has no players, that team goes around to all the other teams and they steal one player from each team.
Speaker 1: How fucking cool is that?
Speaker 0: So they're there, but they can't steal the ones that got protected.
Speaker 0: They steal the other, the low hanging, the low fruits.
Speaker 1: You got two games going on.
Speaker 1: If you're a fan of another team, you got to be like, all right.
Speaker 0: It's a lot like, you know, a kickball, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, right.
Speaker 1: I choose Johnny.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And then immediately after that draft, they have the regular draft where you choose from amongst the children of the world to which ones you will have exclusive bargaining rights with.
Speaker 1: Rangers had actually, despite having the amazing draft pick last year, they got like 16th overall again this year, just by luck.
Speaker 0: That's that's pretty much in the middle.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that was OK.
Speaker 1: We got 32 teams now.
Speaker 0: In fact, that's right in the middle.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But the cool thing about this is one now the NHL, like Dr.
Speaker 1: Hibbert would approve, has symmetry.
Speaker 1: There are the same number of teams in every division in the NHL.
Speaker 0: That is correct.
Speaker 0: And two, we don't need any more teams.
Speaker 1: I've seen like.
Speaker 1: I've only seen two expansion drafts like of this format in my life.
Speaker 1: And this one, I actually really enjoyed watching because Seattle, you watched it live.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the reason I watched it live, I just checked the day after and looked at the list.
Speaker 1: So here's what was going on with it.
Speaker 1: For one, I forget who was up on stage, but the guy on the right where the navy blue blazer was like really mean and catty and everything he said was like very like a weird, mean girl.
Speaker 1: Like he kind of made fun of every other NHL team one by one.
Speaker 1: Every time a Canadian team came up that they were taking someone from, he'd mentioned how the teams up north didn't have such a great season.
Speaker 1: And like he just dug into every single team.
Speaker 1: And it was kind of funny to watch.
Speaker 1: But to him aside, the rest of the draft was.
Speaker 1: So remember when the Mighty Ducks became a team and they did the most embarrassing thing that's ever happened in the history of the NHL with their Disney on ice, like nonsense to try to announce the team.
Speaker 1: This was like this weird combination of so wholesome and so pure that I got to respect it.
Speaker 1: Like the Seattle team, like almost all the announcements, they get like someone to do the announcement in a cute, kitschy way.
Speaker 1: Like they had someone who climbed to the top of Mount Rainier announced one of the teams from the top of Mount Rainier.
Speaker 1: And they're like, this is the record for the highest elevation that an expansion draft pick has ever been announced.
Speaker 1: And they did one like in like someone in a scuba suit, in a shark tank.
Speaker 1: And it was like that.
Speaker 1: stuff's all stupid and marketing nonsense.
Speaker 1: But it was also very like kitschy Seattle.
Speaker 1: And I respect that they're leaning into their identity.
Speaker 1: But with all of that, they got some football players and like other Seattle people to give announcements.
Speaker 1: It was very clear which of those people have ever seen a hockey game in their life and which of them have not.
Speaker 1: And that it's worth going back.
Speaker 0: That's how it is with hockey, right?
Speaker 0: Being something that is quite large.
Speaker 0: Hockey is a big, a big thing, but it's not the biggest, right?
Speaker 0: There's a lot of places that just don't have any, right?
Speaker 0: So it's this weird in between thing where it's big enough to be a thing, but not big.
Speaker 0: So it can sort of have some aspects of being huge and having tons of money and some aspects of being this unknown, weird thing.
Speaker 1: But the other thing, the other aspect of it that's interesting, we'll move on to the actual news and stuff.
Speaker 1: There's so much news, we're only going to cover two big stories.
Speaker 1: But with the expansion draft, normally a hockey team with the salary cap era has to grow organically.
Speaker 1: They can't just like pick the right team.
Speaker 1: Like the difference between a D&D character that levels up over the course of four years of your high school versus a D&D character.
Speaker 1: you start at level 10 and choose a path and an end result.
Speaker 1: So expansion draft teams are this interesting case where they, the people in charge of the team, basically get to decide the composition of the team from nothing.
Speaker 1: Like, we want a team that plays like this.
Speaker 1: If we get that player, let's get this other player specifically to complement them.
Speaker 1: And that doesn't happen in Major League sports.
Speaker 1: Like that is a...
Speaker 0: Yeah, usually, because usually you have some players that are already on contracts.
Speaker 0: I mean, you could wait a long time until you basically, you could set it up to where you just let everyone's contract expire, give everyone bridge deals.
Speaker 0: And then like maybe some magically you've timed it out in such a way and, you know, maybe in purposely lost a bunch of games so that you just lose all your players at once.
Speaker 0: But typically you're going to have a significant number of players who are on long term deals.
Speaker 0: that are your core players and you have to build around them because they're on your team.
Speaker 0: You signed them, you know, three years ago, whatever you wanted to keep them, you just, you know, and so the past you, which might not even be you if, you know, the previous GM of your team, right, signed those deals.
Speaker 0: Now you're the new GM.
Speaker 0: It's like you're stuck with the same deals that were there.
Speaker 0: So you have to, you only have a few spots that you can play with on your roster.
Speaker 0: You can't, you know, it takes a long time, several years to like redo, you know, redo your team.
Speaker 1: But instead you get to just craft a team from the ether like it's it's unique.
Speaker 1: And when Vegas did the expansion draft more like recently, I suspected that they were going to do really well because of that, like better than they did.
Speaker 1: Like they almost won the Stanley Cup their first year being a hockey team.
Speaker 1: So I bet the Kraken will do very well like Vegas their first few years and then they'll be like a normal team after that.
Speaker 1: So in the news, whatever other news we were talking about, this is probably the biggest one and it's important.
Speaker 0: Activision and Blizzard independently, which is the same, they're the same company.
Speaker 1: They are the same company now.
Speaker 1: They were a lot.
Speaker 1: So I bring this up because and I'll talk about this more when we talk about the news.
Speaker 1: There was an early narrative of people used to like before these stories all broke that Activision had the bad culture.
Speaker 1: But Blizzard was a good company.
Speaker 1: that was like stuck in the Activision umbrella and Activision was making them more and more toxic.
Speaker 1: And while that may be true, based on this news, it is very clear that Blizzard on its own is also super toxic.
Speaker 0: I assume that every large game company.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Like, don't forget, everyone's mad at Blizzard.
Speaker 1: Ubisoft has a very similar horrifying situation ongoing.
Speaker 1: The news about that is just eclipsed by the recent news about Blizzard.
Speaker 1: Blizzard, Activision, Blizzard, Ubisoft are equal offenders, as are almost all AAA games.
Speaker 0: I pretty much assume that every single like major nerd company, not even just video games, but especially games, that the culture is is like this, except Nintendo, where I believe my my opinion of Nintendo is that the it's probably not broey in this way.
Speaker 0: But I still imagine Nintendo to be, you know, sexist and also have more problems related to overwork, that, you know, knowing the stories I've heard about like Miyamoto overwork, you know, it's I'm.
Speaker 0: you know, I guess those are just Japanese.
Speaker 0: There's also some I guess.
Speaker 0: I guess that's sort of a racist idea also.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And that, you know, it's sort of like.
Speaker 0: that's the stereotype of a Japanese company.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's tough because Nintendo could be an exception, but I just I doubt it.
Speaker 1: So there's a lot going on here.
Speaker 1: But basically, Blizzard had the culture that you all assumed and expected it had that people who have worked there and quit or been fired or pushed out have been telling people about forever.
Speaker 1: But now there's a lawsuit, a big for real lawsuit that
Speaker 0: and not a lawsuit from like people, you know, like just some people who are, you know, employees of the state
Speaker 1: of California,
Speaker 0: state of California, where the company is, is suing the company, which is if the state sues you, you're a much bigger trouble.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Then if your employees try to sue you because your employees, you know, they had to pull their money together with a class action.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like, no, no, no.
Speaker 0: If the state comes after you, they have the state, the state's power, right?
Speaker 0: The tax money.
Speaker 1: I'm going to read.
Speaker 1: I'm going to read a very short excerpt from The Daily Beast because I just I want to.
Speaker 1: this news is big enough to be very precise with exactly what's happening.
Speaker 0: Do you need a content warning for all these sexual assault stories?
Speaker 1: We do not, because what I'm about to read does not get into any specific details.
Speaker 1: That are content warning.
Speaker 1: But if you read, which I have read the actual complaints, serious content warning, it is fucked up shit that was going on in Blizzard.
Speaker 1: And I suspect this is just the alleged, I guess, allegedly, we're not lawyers, allegedly.
Speaker 0: So the court, the case isn't over yet.
Speaker 1: So from The Daily Beast quote, the California Department of Fair Employment and Housing filed suiting its active vision Blizzard, alleging that they subjected its female employees to a degrading, pervasive frat boy workplace culture.
Speaker 1: Women comprise only one fifth of the company's workforce, and those employees were subject to sexual harassment, unequal pay and retaliation.
Speaker 1: The suit alleges female employees who spoke to the bureau said their male colleagues and bosses would make rape jokes hit on them.
Speaker 1: One employee claimed to have an assault situation involving photos that I'm not going to read a detail.
Speaker 1: And it only gets worse from there.
Speaker 1: Like this is this is worse than what even a lot of pessimistic people about the industry had expected and assumed.
Speaker 0: No, no, that's what I expected.
Speaker 0: It is what I expected.
Speaker 1: This is what I have assumed.
Speaker 0: I expect and assume that, you know, let's name another game called Rockstar Games where they make GTA.
Speaker 0: Come on.
Speaker 1: You can't tell me that, you know, I have any rights been in deep shit over this.
Speaker 0: Oh, Riot.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Absolutely.
Speaker 1: It's like enemy number one when it comes to sexist nonsense.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Obviously, I'm not trying to like slander or libel any of these places.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But it's like I'm saying not that these things actually happen there.
Speaker 0: I'm saying that I assume those things actually happen there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I believe they did, even though I have absolutely no evidence whatsoever, other than that's the culture of these places.
Speaker 1: I mean, one of the reasons I am not like did not seriously try to be at one of these large game companies is they don't they don't pay shit.
Speaker 1: Like that's just the thing.
Speaker 0: But it's one of it's one of the reasons I won't work at like any company over a certain size or any company you've ever heard of.
Speaker 1: But I also do not like, like or trust the entire triple A ecosystem.
Speaker 1: like it is just no workers rights, like exploitation, never mind all this harassment and all this sexist stuff and racism.
Speaker 1: There's so much going on there.
Speaker 1: It's just it's a shit show.
Speaker 1: And this lawsuit is serious.
Speaker 1: Their stock dropped on this news significantly and the world like people are taking it seriously.
Speaker 0: So what I would really makes me it makes me think about, right, how over the past few years, so many of the higher up people at Blizzard working, you know, everyone I know, one by one, I'm the Moreheim guy.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: All these people were at Blizzard sort of abandoned ship.
Speaker 0: You know, when the after they guess they got it's like, OK, Activision bought us, we shipped our stuff, we you know, we achieved and then let's bail.
Speaker 0: They all bailed.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: And so many people we know of that was there was there was.
Speaker 0: there was the layoff situation also a while back.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Which made me think it's not a great place to work.
Speaker 0: The products they've been putting out, they've been delivering products less.
Speaker 0: Well, see, it's like.
Speaker 0: which led me to imagine that there was some and the people leaving led me to imagine there was organizational dysfunction where there previously was not or at least it was going downhill.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Like in response to this in response to this lawsuit.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You're seeing comments from people who are still there and also some of those former people.
Speaker 0: And what I've noticed is a lot of the former people were saying things along the line, some along the lines of, yeah, we failed you.
Speaker 0: We fucked up.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Which is, I guess, yeah, you did.
Speaker 0: But the current like executives were like refuting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that is so that this escalated rapidly.
Speaker 1: Executives at Blizzard tried to issue statements to the effect of like either this isn't a problem or.
Speaker 0: But yet the previous executives effectively indirectly admitted it by saying we failed you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but also doesn't which doesn't excuse them for the fact that they failed them.
Speaker 1: That happens in a lot of industries when the white dude who is a senior executive at a company or someone who steps down or resigns or recently stepped down and they say like, yes, we failed, we failed.
Speaker 1: No, you didn't just fail.
Speaker 1: You were actively a part of it if you knew.
Speaker 1: And if you didn't know, you are terrible at your job.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So basically there was the people who were responsible for the bad culture in the past and probably part responsible for starting it because they were there.
Speaker 0: The Moreheim guy, who isn't that?
Speaker 0: the Blizzard guy who was there from the start.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So it happened under his watch.
Speaker 0: The cult people don't realize how much of the culture of a company.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Comes down like from the top.
Speaker 1: Oh, it happens.
Speaker 1: I think you like penny arcade or say big or small.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: The attitude of like a very few executives at the top of a company largely dictates the culture of like the entire company, even if it's massive, even if the CEO is far away and you never hear from them.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But in this case, like this type of situation, the game industry, I think a big part of it like and it's in addition to cultures of racism and sexism and in addition to the exploitation of the workers.
Speaker 1: There's also this specific problem that's more common in the game industry than a lot of other industries of.
Speaker 1: there are specific, well-known harassers who are in the company, who are protected.
Speaker 1: This happens in tech companies a lot, too.
Speaker 1: Who are protected for reasons that I cannot fathom because they tend to not actually be the people who are actually making the products good either.
Speaker 1: It's like their friends in senior management protect them when they are actually causing these problems to a big degree.
Speaker 0: It's the same reason someone doesn't kicked out, isn't kicked out of board game night.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And they're really shitty.
Speaker 0: You know, same same idea.
Speaker 0: But yeah.
Speaker 0: But the current executives.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: They were they're taking the line.
Speaker 0: The current executives, I think there's, you know, some of them recent hires.
Speaker 0: Wasn't there the person who used to work in like the Bush administration?
Speaker 1: Oh, my God.
Speaker 1: I don't actually know all the I don't.
Speaker 1: I have no idea who are these.
Speaker 0: So when they hired these people, it already was looking bad because of the resumes of the people that they hired to replace the outgoing people.
Speaker 0: But yeah, they gave statements like denying that these things were true.
Speaker 0: And so the Blizzard employees, like hundreds of them, perhaps even like up to a thousand.
Speaker 1: So this is breaking news.
Speaker 1: Jason Schreier has been reporting on this pretty thoroughly.
Speaker 1: So I'll link to his they were.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So they put out a letter like saying, that's a bunch of bullshit.
Speaker 0: This is right.
Speaker 0: They were the employees are siding with the state, which tells you that the state is right.
Speaker 0: And then tomorrow, Wednesday, the twenty eighth of July, they're just going to walk out.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The employees are striking tomorrow.
Speaker 1: They're walking out.
Speaker 0: They don't have a union and they have reportedly not discussed making a union.
Speaker 0: They should.
Speaker 1: I think you're looking at the same source.
Speaker 1: I have.
Speaker 1: Schreier confirmed that they have not discussed a union.
Speaker 1: I think they probably should.
Speaker 0: Why aren't they?
Speaker 0: But they're walking out tomorrow.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So they have issued some statements on Twitter, like the people who are organizing the walkout on how they want to be supported.
Speaker 1: And it seems to be double check all this because this situation is evolving.
Speaker 1: Like this is breaking news as of one p.m.
Speaker 1: Eastern today.
Speaker 1: But they do want people to not play Blizzard games tomorrow to log out of Blizzard and Activision Services to end.
Speaker 1: a large number of gaming outlets have agreed to not cover any Blizzard or Activision games or news in any capacity, except as relating to the walkout, the strike and the harassment suits, including.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to play or talk about Overwatch or any of that stuff until this situation is resolved to my satisfaction.
Speaker 0: You know, if it would be, you know, if I ran Twitch or YouTube, I would if I was on Twitch, I would block streaming.
Speaker 0: If I ran if I ran packs, I would be like, you can't have a booth.
Speaker 0: You can't have a panel.
Speaker 0: It's like you can't come.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like every.
Speaker 0: all the other gaming companies should like, you know, block them out.
Speaker 0: Be like, you know, if I was I guess they have their own thing, battle net, so they can't get kicked off of that.
Speaker 0: But if they were on Steam, Steam could be like, oh, we're not selling your games, taking them off.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess if someone owns the game, they can still play them.
Speaker 0: But they go, we're going to kick you out of our store.
Speaker 0: We're going to, you know, basically, you know, and I think people should do that to, you know, that would be.
Speaker 0: that's like, you know, the minimum right.
Speaker 0: Is basically someone who got caught blocking them.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I think that if I was if I had the power to do so, I would go one step further.
Speaker 0: And that one step would be like, hey, other game company to which there is no lawsuit or anything.
Speaker 0: Oh, you want to be you want to continue to be on our platform?
Speaker 0: Well, we're not playing the old innocent until proven guilty game anymore.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I need affirmative proof that your culture is wonderful or else.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, we need this actually so much like leads ratings for like building efficiency or ratings like.
Speaker 1: there's independent organizations in a lot of industries to rate things.
Speaker 1: We almost need a third party independent organization that rates the level of sexism, racism, et cetera, inside of the culture of game companies and certify or decertify them to attaining certain levels of like minimum professionalism.
Speaker 0: So then how do you how do you do that?
Speaker 0: Because when that inspector comes, it's not like when you the health inspector comes to a restaurant and looks around and this rat.
Speaker 1: Oh, there are a lot of ways to do this.
Speaker 0: Surprise, surprise.
Speaker 0: I'm here.
Speaker 0: I see the rats.
Speaker 0: If you go to a company, everyone sees you and now they're going to be on their best behavior.
Speaker 1: That's not how these things tend to work.
Speaker 1: So like unions have experience with this.
Speaker 1: Other industries have things like this.
Speaker 1: For example, one thing that has happened in other industries is when companies that do ratings along those lines are checking out a company to recertify them, they'll do things like.
Speaker 1: they get to come and talk to anyone they want to behind closed doors privately.
Speaker 1: They'll come and set up a system for people to anonymously report anything that they'd like to have looked into.
Speaker 1: Things like that.
Speaker 1: There are ways to protect the workers and also get this information.
Speaker 1: We need something because this is going to keep happening.
Speaker 1: And the response is always the same.
Speaker 1: The executives always say, we're sorry, we failed you, we need to do better, but they never do.
Speaker 0: That's only.
Speaker 0: that's only what the former executive saying.
Speaker 1: I know that's what's even worse.
Speaker 1: It's like Blizzard also own gold by trying to fight against this.
Speaker 1: Like, what do they think that all their employers are going to be like, oh, yeah, no, it's fine.
Speaker 1: Their employees are like, yeah, I didn't even report all my harassment.
Speaker 1: Here we go.
Speaker 1: Who can I call?
Speaker 0: If you work at Activision Blizzard, I'm sure you can call the state attorney general's office in California.
Speaker 0: They are proud.
Speaker 0: They're the ones bringing the suit.
Speaker 0: So I'm sure they would love to hear your story.
Speaker 1: There are also a number of journalistic outfits who have reached out and they have anonymous and protected avenues.
Speaker 1: If you work at Activision Blizzard, where you can tell your story with or without giving them your name and details and contribute to this investigation.
Speaker 0: And not to mention, if you're experiencing any sort of bullshit, not just, you know, workplace bullshit, but, you know, it could be work like landlord bullshit or any kind of bullshit that you feel is, you know, not cool.
Speaker 0: If it's the kind of thing where you have to sue on your own, OK, you have to sue on your own.
Speaker 0: But that's real hard.
Speaker 1: It really works.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But this shows you that there are if it's something's criminal, like let's say your boss is doing wage theft or your landlord is not following your call.
Speaker 0: There is probably all your attorney general.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: There is either an organization in your state like the thing that's going after Blizzard in this case.
Speaker 1: There are to call your attorney general.
Speaker 1: Even call not your senator, like that's a little bit like too small for them.
Speaker 1: But like your house rep, if they're a Democrat, at least, will like surprisingly often like help you out with shit like this, like way more than you would expect.
Speaker 0: There's all kinds of people that you can call.
Speaker 0: And even if they can't directly do anything, they can at least point you somewhere.
Speaker 0: So, you know, these the the state, you know, attorney generals of California didn't bring this case just out of nowhere.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: They heard about this.
Speaker 0: It's not like they're going and looking at every company, you know, companies in California and they're not looking at all of them constantly.
Speaker 0: Someone called them and told them this was going down.
Speaker 0: How else would they know?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So in some other news, because this is going to be an ongoing story and I encourage you to follow it, it looks like I guess Valve is releasing the Game Gear 2.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So Valve announced the people were upset with, you know, we already talked about the the the Switch upgrade.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: If you're mad that the new Switch is not 4K 60 FPS, you have no idea how technology works at all.
Speaker 1: It is literally impossible to do that.
Speaker 0: The they announced the Steam Deck and the Steam Deck is basically a Switch clone.
Speaker 0: But the idea is that it's a basic PC so it can run all every game that's on Steam because it's a PC.
Speaker 0: They just crammed a PC into the smallest rectangle they could with a screen on it, which is a pretty big and a slab, a slab controllers on the side and it's like ports on the top.
Speaker 0: So you could plug it into a monitor and use it as a, you know, because if you could use it as your gaming PC, if you wanted to.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And so, yeah, it's.
Speaker 0: if you look at picture, no one's held it.
Speaker 0: At least I haven't held it.
Speaker 0: So I can't say whether it's comfy or whatever, but I can tell you that looking at it, it doesn't look comfy.
Speaker 0: And the steam controller was a debacle.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So this doesn't look great.
Speaker 0: The thing that really stands out about being bad is that it has, you know, two like touch pads on.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Remember the touch pad they put on the steam controller that the touch pads and the steam controller weren't great.
Speaker 0: Even if these are as great as like the magic touch pads that Apple makes, you know, two of them, one on each thumb is not amazing.
Speaker 1: Also, what I don't like is the buttons and all the controls like like the actual like they're all way near the top and way near the edge.
Speaker 1: It's like, yeah, like.
Speaker 0: I imagine I could be wrong.
Speaker 0: I could be wrong, but it doesn't look comfy.
Speaker 0: Two, just what I know about, you know, the world, it looks big and heavy.
Speaker 1: It does it and it weighs a little more than twice what a switch weighs.
Speaker 1: And already, you know, maybe because I'm approaching 40, but if I'm laying on my back, like in bed playing the switch, like up over my face, my arms get tired after an hour or so.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I could play an hour or so laying in my bed with something that weighs more than twice what a switch weighs.
Speaker 0: It doesn't weigh as much as a Game Gear, but it's close, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, Kevion, we actually tried to look up how much a Game Gear weighs and literally every website I went to listed a different number.
Speaker 0: It also is going to depend on what batteries you put in the Game Gear.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this has built in batteries, so it's a little different.
Speaker 1: But we'll see.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying this is a bad device.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Valve has a mixed track record on hardware.
Speaker 0: Valve has never done well with hardware they've made on their own.
Speaker 1: So Valve VR hardware, best in breed.
Speaker 0: They didn't make that.
Speaker 0: HTC made it and they bought it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, true.
Speaker 1: But the hard but that's the their index.
Speaker 0: They didn't buy this.
Speaker 0: They made this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but their index VR that that was because it's theirs now is like best in breed bar.
Speaker 0: That's not hardware that they made.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't that doesn't count.
Speaker 1: Maybe they got some of the work on this.
Speaker 1: Like, I don't know.
Speaker 0: The hardware that Valve has made on its own from nothing is all garbage.
Speaker 0: I think the more the problem I have link thing garbage.
Speaker 1: The problem I have here is more that garbage.
Speaker 1: Most of the games I at least play on Steam are PC games that kind of assume you're using a mouse and keyboard or like a joystick.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: There is no.
Speaker 0: if there there's basically no game on Steam that I want to play portably.
Speaker 1: That might be the only one.
Speaker 1: But you know what?
Speaker 1: I could also have had some switch like it's there and it's fine.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: Although the listener actually points out something nobody can get fucking video cards.
Speaker 1: This thing actually might be a gaming PC for you if you.
Speaker 1: so it's hard.
Speaker 0: So here's the thing.
Speaker 0: It could be a gaming PC for you.
Speaker 0: Valve claims that every game that they have tried on Steam runs on the Steam deck.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: And that it runs at 30 FPS.
Speaker 0: However, they didn't say anything about the settings.
Speaker 0: So this means obviously they could get every any game they tried by adjusting the settings and turning down your graphics a whole bunch.
Speaker 0: You could eventually get it to run it at 30 FPS.
Speaker 0: Guess what?
Speaker 0: If you don't have a video card because video cards are expensive, you can buy like an Nvidia 770, right?
Speaker 0: A 8, 10 year old, who knows how old, right?
Speaker 0: A very old car.
Speaker 1: Those are actually weirdly hard to get right now because no one can get video cards.
Speaker 1: You realize Emily's using a 770 right now.
Speaker 1: That is the best we could get.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: But if you had a 770 and you turn the settings down, you could run every game at 30 FPS.
Speaker 0: You can get an integrated the integrated CPU video card.
Speaker 0: You're like the Intel IG, whatever it comes on.
Speaker 1: I play a lot of Steam games on my HDPC, which is very old.
Speaker 1: It has a GT450M in it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a 450M can play just about every game at 30 FPS with the settings turned down.
Speaker 0: So it's not really that different.
Speaker 0: Just any video card you can get is going to be as good as this little thing.
Speaker 0: So there's no reason to buy this for its horsepower capabilities.
Speaker 0: The only reason you would buy this is your arms are super strong.
Speaker 0: For some reason, it's comfier than it looks.
Speaker 0: You want to really, really want to play PC games on the go and you don't have any other existing device that already does it.
Speaker 0: This really just seems bad.
Speaker 0: I was very shocked that people reacted positively to this in any way.
Speaker 0: It looks to me like a bunch of garbage.
Speaker 0: Like when I go, when I fly somewhere, like, you know, obviously I'm someone who's like the biggest Steam fanboy who's had Steam since the day Steam existed.
Speaker 1: I just have a laptop and I just plug a controller into a laptop and play them on like planes and things like or I have my Switch.
Speaker 0: Probably a better experience.
Speaker 1: Oh, almost definitely.
Speaker 1: So we'll see.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to preorder one of these.
Speaker 0: I'd love it to be proven wrong because, you know, but... If this thing is good, I'll probably buy one.
Speaker 0: I won't, but I still, I travel a lot.
Speaker 0: I'll acknowledge that it's good if I'm wrong, but I don't see any world in which I buy one, even if it's somehow perfect.
Speaker 1: Like once we're in a post-Covid world...
Speaker 0: I have no use for it.
Speaker 0: I have an iPad and a Switch.
Speaker 0: What the hell do I need another thing for?
Speaker 1: Like for me, once we're in a post-Covid world, like my normal life, not during a pandemic, is I travel a lot, like a lot lot.
Speaker 0: I have an iPad and a Switch and an upgraded GBA and a DS Lite and a 3DS.
Speaker 0: Why do I need this?
Speaker 0: Even if it's amazing.
Speaker 1: And so the other thing about it is the cheapest one, the $400 one, only has 64 gigabytes of space, which is like two games.
Speaker 0: You put in, you put an SD card in there.
Speaker 1: But also, at least it's, you know, it's very slow storage.
Speaker 1: You don't get NVMe, like you don't get real SSDs unless you buy the two big ones.
Speaker 0: So your load times will be slower, but that's not a big deal.
Speaker 0: You're already playing, you're already willing to play at 30 FPS.
Speaker 0: So who wouldn't care if the load times were lower?
Speaker 1: That's the other thing.
Speaker 1: Most PC games...
Speaker 0: It's not a magnetic spinning disk.
Speaker 0: It's still going to be fast enough.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, but here's the other problem.
Speaker 0: NVMe will just be a little bit faster.
Speaker 0: You probably might not even be able to tell the difference for most games.
Speaker 1: Most games I play on a PC assume I'm looking at a gigantic monitor of some kind.
Speaker 1: I'm very curious how many games are actually playable and readable on this tiny screen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you could like play Civ on this, but it wouldn't be...
Speaker 1: Without a mouse, using those tiny little touch pads.
Speaker 0: I think you're better off buying Civ VI for iPad.
Speaker 0: Than, you know, buying it.
Speaker 0: But then again, if you play it on here, you don't have to buy it again.
Speaker 0: If I want to play Civ VI on iPad, I have to buy it again.
Speaker 0: But here, it's like it's your existing Steam libraries.
Speaker 0: You want it to buy games again.
Speaker 0: And that is, I think, the one big selling point of this.
Speaker 0: Is that since it's your Steam library, you've already bought the games.
Speaker 0: Whereas if you were to buy a Switch, or an iPad, or whatever other gaming device.
Speaker 0: You don't have any software to start with.
Speaker 0: So if I had a Steam deck, I could just play Quake immediately.
Speaker 1: Now, here's the other thing.
Speaker 1: This news came out, you can sign up for reservations.
Speaker 1: You realize this shit is not available until at the earliest Q2 2022.
Speaker 1: We're talking a year from now.
Speaker 0: Less than a year from now.
Speaker 1: A little less than a year.
Speaker 0: Three, eight, you know.
Speaker 1: Q2, so April, May, early April at the earliest.
Speaker 1: Or like April, like June-ish.
Speaker 0: Yeah, eight or nine months.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not twelve.
Speaker 1: That's a pretty long, like, at that point I'll just wait and see.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this thing will look sadder then than it does now, right?
Speaker 0: Because there'll be nine other months of stuff getting better.
Speaker 1: Yup, by then, who knows?
Speaker 1: By then you might have like a more, a Switch Pro Pro.
Speaker 1: Like who even knows what's going to happen?
Speaker 0: Not that soon.
Speaker 1: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 1: So we haven't played it much lately.
Speaker 1: We've just been busy.
Speaker 1: But Star Wars Squadrons, fucking fantastic game.
Speaker 1: Like utterly fantastic game.
Speaker 1: Works with VR, like perfectly, but also is totally fine with the same interface if you don't do VR.
Speaker 1: Like it's a perfect, perfect store.
Speaker 1: Motive has published an article that goes into extreme depth on how they did this and also how they made a VR game that is so accessible and involves so little, like it doesn't cause motion sickness.
Speaker 1: All the problems you expect from VR aren't there in a game where you're flying around at breakneck speed in a spaceship.
Speaker 1: They actually go into specific details on how they made that happen.
Speaker 1: Like here is the exact things they did to make this work.
Speaker 1: And this article is just phenomenal.
Speaker 1: It goes into a level of depth that I was surprised they posted publicly.
Speaker 1: And if you are even remotely interested in VR games of any kind, especially from a development standpoint, this is a must read series of articles, little things like.
Speaker 1: I'll give you a tiny example.
Speaker 1: They if you notice when you play Star Wars Squadrons, when you turn in any direction, like you're rotating your ship, the pivot point is around your head, not the center of the ship.
Speaker 1: And this article explains why.
Speaker 1: one of those causes extreme vomit and the other one causes zero discomfort.
Speaker 1: It's just a really, really neat article.
Speaker 0: But of course, that's not real.
Speaker 0: If you were in a real ship, it would pivot around itself and not your head.
Speaker 1: But also if they're spaceships, so.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But also, if you were to design a ship for a human to fly, you would have it move in such a way, right?
Speaker 0: You would design the ship so that maybe your head is near the center of gravity.
Speaker 1: You don't need to, though.
Speaker 0: The only reason you don't need to.
Speaker 1: You don't need to.
Speaker 1: What I'm saying is the only reason you do this in VR is because one of the things that causes motion sickness is when your brain detects certain kinds of motion through your eyes.
Speaker 1: But your inner ear says, hold up, slow down, buckaroo.
Speaker 1: I didn't feel that.
Speaker 1: You must be poisoned.
Speaker 1: Pretty literally, it's like, well, something's wrong.
Speaker 1: You'd better vomit because you must have eaten something bad like that is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that is literally part of what's going on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that is true.
Speaker 0: But I'm just saying, you know, X-wings and TIE fighters are not realistic designs.
Speaker 0: And if the designs of the ships were different, you may not have to do some of the things that they have done.
Speaker 1: That is true as well.
Speaker 1: So what do you got?
Speaker 0: So I learned today.
Speaker 0: you probably you might have already known about this, but I did not.
Speaker 1: So I did not know about this.
Speaker 1: I just came through this video.
Speaker 1: I played a similar game in like long ago, but not not this.
Speaker 0: So there's a game I heard about today, which it seems like such an obvious game.
Speaker 0: How could I not have known about this game?
Speaker 0: It's called Foot Down, and it's a real simple game.
Speaker 0: Everyone gets on their bicycles and you ride in a circle within a restricted area.
Speaker 1: It's got to be a small area or this would be dangerous as fuck.
Speaker 0: And this is a beautiful game because the way it works is it's basically impossible.
Speaker 0: You don't need a referee.
Speaker 0: You don't need penalties.
Speaker 0: It's like it's just a perfect, beautiful game.
Speaker 0: So simple.
Speaker 0: You bike around in a circle and then you start.
Speaker 0: And if you put your foot down on the ground, you're out.
Speaker 0: Or if you leave the bounds of the game area, you're also out.
Speaker 0: And the last person remaining wins.
Speaker 0: The only thing you might need to make this game perfect would be to have like, you know, a video for instant replay in case two people put their foot down, like at the same time.
Speaker 0: And they're the last two people.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter if they're not the last two people, right?
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter who was who went out first.
Speaker 0: It only matters if the two or the most extreme to call.
Speaker 1: You could have something like if it were an Olympic sport, like with fencing, have sensors on the shoes that detect the slightest touch on the ground.
Speaker 0: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it's a beautiful, beautiful game.
Speaker 0: I didn't know existed.
Speaker 0: You know, right.
Speaker 1: It looks super fun.
Speaker 1: I legit want to play it.
Speaker 0: In this video, they discuss variants.
Speaker 0: They say that like in professional, like top tier foot down, if you when you put your foot down, you leave your bicycle behind to create an obstacle.
Speaker 0: But some people don't do that because it could be a threat to to their bicycle.
Speaker 0: But they say that in their games, they've only had minor bicycle.
Speaker 1: I can say like because you've never been mountain biking, a bike, a mountain bike will survive pretty much anything except landing on another mountain bike.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there are playing on mountain bikes.
Speaker 0: I feel like this would be better off playing on it.
Speaker 0: This actually would be a good use for a fixie.
Speaker 0: I feel like you want like a mountain fixie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because then you can race against the pedals and that also braces your rear wheel.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like in a way in this video, this with a couple of years old and has a ton of views that you are taught the game.
Speaker 0: They show you a lot of interesting gameplay out in the square driveway.
Speaker 0: And they also build a battle bike with which to, you know, play foot down with.
Speaker 0: So I'm liking this foot down.
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 0: The only thing stopping me from playing it is that I already own two bicycles, none of which are any good for playing foot down with.
Speaker 0: I would need a third bicycle.
Speaker 1: This reminds me a lot of Luke Burge's the Friday night fight, like competitive versus juggling.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's very similar, you know, in its format of, you know, eliminating people.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You juggle and you know, when you lose it, you lose a club.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: You're out.
Speaker 1: It's also very Smash Brothers adjacent in that regard.
Speaker 1: It's like you could be just stay away from everyone.
Speaker 0: I mean, elimination is a great game format.
Speaker 0: You know, just look at pub G's and Fortnite and whatever is, you know, those just took it to the next level by having one hundred people.
Speaker 0: It's like, why not have one hundred people play foot down in a field?
Speaker 1: This would be.
Speaker 0: And then the problem is, as people get eliminated, the field gets, you know, is still big.
Speaker 0: You need to shrink the field, which is what PUBG does.
Speaker 0: It's real.
Speaker 1: So I think this would be very hard to play on a road bike.
Speaker 0: Uh, impossible.
Speaker 0: You need a mountain bike or a fixie or something like something.
Speaker 0: You can lower your center of gravity, something that can take some bonks.
Speaker 1: Well, like a real mountain bikes, you can hit a button and your seat just retracts down like out of your way.
Speaker 1: You'd want something like that.
Speaker 0: You could do that.
Speaker 0: But yeah, like, you know, a road bike is unstable when not at speed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like an F-16 like road bikes.
Speaker 0: I worry you could play this obviously with BMX bikes.
Speaker 0: That would be very easy to do.
Speaker 0: You know, you get pegs and everything you could stand on, you know, do all kinds of stuff.
Speaker 0: But that might actually be too easy and too hard to force people to put their foot down.
Speaker 1: You'd have to attack people more aggressively, which could lead to more injuries with the BMX bike.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think BMX would be a little more dangerous if you're doing it that way.
Speaker 0: But certainly viable, you know.
Speaker 1: But also, you know what this fits into, because again, you have a really mountain bike.
Speaker 0: Well, if you used BMX bikes, you could play on like one of those BMX, like a skate park or BMX park and get ramps going.
Speaker 0: And you go up a ramp, come down and slam into somebody.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that gets to that injury city.
Speaker 1: So another reason why this works so well for mountain bikes and the reason it works so well as a sport, because again, you've never mountain bike.
Speaker 1: One of the main things you do to practice and get good at technical mountain biking is biking extremely slowly over like very specific obstacles like biking.
Speaker 1: Being able to stop and just stand on your bike with no trouble is a skill you need to have.
Speaker 1: Being able to hop up on just your front wheel, hop up and just your rear wheel.
Speaker 1: Those are the kinds of drills I had to do back when I mountain biked like.
Speaker 1: that's the kind of stuff I can't.
Speaker 1: actually really I can't.
Speaker 1: there is there is no way I could.
Speaker 1: there is no possibility I could get on my front wheel on my hybrid bike safely.
Speaker 1: I would hurt myself immediately if I tried to do that.
Speaker 0: I can't do it.
Speaker 0: It's not the right job.
Speaker 1: I think I'm going to try it.
Speaker 1: I think I would.
Speaker 1: I think I might be able to barely do it for like 10 seconds at most.
Speaker 0: I mean, I think we've done things of the day showing trials biking people who are like, you know, bouncing all basically doing parkour with their bike, riding on really thin rails, bouncing all around that
Speaker 1: you do that slow as practice to be able to do it fast when you're mountain biking where now it's life or death.
Speaker 1: Hmm.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I want to play the shit out of the sport.
Speaker 1: This looks so fun.
Speaker 0: It's going to be hard to get a game of foot down together.
Speaker 1: Why don't we just get some shitty mountain bikes and play it ourselves?
Speaker 0: I'm talking like, well, now it's like, where am I going to put it?
Speaker 1: So our bike room is pretty much empty at this point, like for some reason.
Speaker 0: Well, then go buy go.
Speaker 0: You go use your money.
Speaker 0: Here's the problem.
Speaker 1: Even like I got some bike work done recently.
Speaker 1: The every bike shop is out of parts.
Speaker 1: No one can get anything.
Speaker 1: No one can get new bikes.
Speaker 1: Like there is a bike supply chain crisis going on right now.
Speaker 0: So everything's supply chain crisis.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I'll tell you what.
Speaker 1: Once the supply chain crisis is down and like we're post covid.
Speaker 0: Oh, OK.
Speaker 0: So twenty thirty.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 1: I will at that point look into getting to like piece of shit mountain bikes.
Speaker 1: Like I'm talking like like my old research.
Speaker 0: We can find some New York City foot down league.
Speaker 1: The two of us should go play it.
Speaker 1: If that is the case, I'll get us some shitty mountain bikes and we'll go.
Speaker 1: I'm talking like some 90s Schwinn mountain bikes like hardtails.
Speaker 0: New York City.
Speaker 1: In fact, I bet a hardtail would almost be easier depending.
Speaker 1: I can already think of ways I might customize a bike that would almost be cheating to be better at this.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I'm like I'm looking for if there's a foot down meet up.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Well, you look that up in the moment.
Speaker 1: The Geek Nights Book Club book, The Tale of Genji.
Speaker 1: I'm actually plugging along as Genji sleepwalks through his life.
Speaker 0: You just say you're going to say that.
Speaker 0: you're just going to say that every time because Genji doesn't grow or change as a person.
Speaker 0: As far as I can see, every single episode, sleepwalk through life.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Say that over and over.
Speaker 1: Well, what I'm curious about is I'm about to be out of town.
Speaker 1: There won't be any geek nights next week.
Speaker 0: Oh, good.
Speaker 0: I'll have time to do other things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I'm going to have a lot of time to read more Genji.
Speaker 1: I want to see if Genji grows as a person at any point.
Speaker 1: And I'm hoping I'll read enough in one.
Speaker 1: go to encounter Genji becoming a better person or a worse person or worse person would also be interesting.
Speaker 1: But you should read The Tale of Genji.
Speaker 1: one, because we're going to finish it before around the end of summer and do a show on it.
Speaker 1: Two, it's the first novel ever written by a human.
Speaker 1: I feel like you should read.
Speaker 1: You should try to experience the first of anything just to know where things came from.
Speaker 1: We've said that before about anime, like watch Astro Boy.
Speaker 1: We've said that about comics.
Speaker 1: We've said about video games like play Pong.
Speaker 1: I know there were games before Pong, but anyway, but two, we will not be at PAX West 2021.
Speaker 1: I mean, actually post an announcement about that, partly because I mean, we sort of announced that already.
Speaker 1: We've announced it several times on the show, but I'm going to make a new like an official post about it, because I've noticed something over the years at PAX is a lot of people like
Speaker 0: the
Speaker 1: average geek nights fan does not listen to the geek nights podcast, does not engage in the geek nights community, does not go to the geek nights website.
Speaker 1: So of course, we'll be out of PAX and a lot of people will see us and just walk up, be like, oh, we just got a big fan.
Speaker 1: Are you doing anything at this PAX?
Speaker 1: Like, what's your panel this year?
Speaker 1: Like we post this shit.
Speaker 1: I know you don't read it like it's.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so I want to make it abundantly clear that we are not going to be there because we think it is unsafe.
Speaker 1: We are like we are not attending PAX West because we don't think it's going to be safe to go to.
Speaker 0: The policy is still the same, right?
Speaker 0: They did.
Speaker 0: PAX did, to their credit, change their policy.
Speaker 0: They are now going to require that everyone at PAX either has been vaccinated or has, I guess, a recent ish negative test.
Speaker 0: I don't know how they're going to check for these things.
Speaker 1: There are some like in New York State, there's a way to check for that.
Speaker 1: But I don't know about.
Speaker 0: Yeah, sure.
Speaker 1: But the point is, with people flying there, how are you going to do?
Speaker 0: Regardless, that's their new policy.
Speaker 0: Because that is a load bearing or sure, that is an improvement over the policy they had before.
Speaker 0: But it's just not good enough, right?
Speaker 0: It's it is not safe to have the packs at this time, in my opinion.
Speaker 1: And especially because it's 30 days out and Delta's getting worse.
Speaker 0: When we say I don't want anyone to be confused when we say we're not going to a convention with, you know, a mask or a social distancing requirement.
Speaker 0: That is not because we believe that those things are ineffective or we don't want to comply with those things, because most people who would say, right, I'm not going somewhere where I got to wear a mask are, you know, anti-vaxx, bad people, you know, get them out of here.
Speaker 0: If you're one of those people, stop listening to this show.
Speaker 0: When we say that, we're saying, look, if it's not safe enough in the world for us to have a large gathering with no masks and no special social distancing requirements, then it is, in our opinion, not safe enough to have a large gathering period.
Speaker 0: So if there is a large gathering, I will not go to it, regardless of what the, you know, you know, it's like, oh, you could if they had kit packs and said no masks.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Oh, you know, I still wouldn't go because it's not safe enough.
Speaker 0: It's not safe enough to go without the mask.
Speaker 0: So it's not safe enough to go, period.
Speaker 1: So to be abundantly specifically clear, geek nights will not appear at or attend any convention where masks and/or social distancing measures are prudent and necessary.
Speaker 1: If they are prudent and necessary, the con should not happen.
Speaker 1: In one last little bit, our panel from the last PAX online can't PAX, which was a fantastic event.
Speaker 0: We can go to online PAX, no problem.
Speaker 0: Very safe.
Speaker 0: It was a really safe to go to online.
Speaker 1: It was actually a really good online PAX.
Speaker 1: Like, I had a lot of fun with it.
Speaker 1: And there's a bunch of panels I still got to watch vods of.
Speaker 0: But our panel... I still got to watch the keynote with the jackbox.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You saw they're selling a TKO shirt.
Speaker 1: That's all the TKO characters, like the monsters.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a really good shirt.
Speaker 1: But our panel is on YouTube.
Speaker 1: We'll link to it.
Speaker 1: Atari Game Design.
Speaker 1: The people who watch the panel live with us and the Discord and on Twitch, we're super chill.
Speaker 1: People ask really good questions.
Speaker 1: These online PAXes, like the people who ask questions in the chat.
Speaker 1: Why aren't you people at real PAXes asking those questions?
Speaker 1: Why are the questions from the audience at PAX the worst possible questions?
Speaker 0: Because at PAX online is obviously only the people who are like super pet.
Speaker 0: They care a lot.
Speaker 0: So you're going to get a better, you know, selection.
Speaker 0: Whereas at regular PAX, you got people who just walked in, you know, off the whatever.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So that panel, Atari Game Design is just on YouTube.
Speaker 1: You can just watch it.
Speaker 1: I think I linked to the slides.
Speaker 1: I linked to the list of the games.
Speaker 1: And if you don't, even if you don't watch it, the thing I do want to tell you, go find a ROM of an Atari game called Pitfall 2.
Speaker 1: Because if you've never heard of this game and have no idea what the deal is, you will be like shocked that this is a game that was literally on an Atari 2600 cartridge.
Speaker 1: It is.
Speaker 1: it is amazing that this game exists.
Speaker 1: And that said, Pokemon Unite, the fact that a Pokemon MOBA was announced actually got me pretty excited.
Speaker 0: We did talk about this when it was news, we said, hey, they announced a Pokemon MOBA.
Speaker 0: It's you know, it's going to be a real thing.
Speaker 0: And I completely forgot about it until it came out and a couple of came out, I guess, within the week.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Maybe maybe a week ago.
Speaker 1: I played enough matches to be able to play ranked competitive Pokemon Unite.
Speaker 0: As soon as a couple of days after it came out, I played it and then I played it again yesterday and now I'm ready to discuss.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, this Pokemon MOBA, it actually has at the core of the gameplay, is actually a great idea and a great mechanic that improves MOBA significantly.
Speaker 0: It works is you, your Pokemon and you go around the map and you do, I guess, in other MOBA's, it's called jungling.
Speaker 0: But basically you're doing PvE.
Speaker 0: You're fighting these Pokemon that are just on the map.
Speaker 1: They kind of just stand there and let you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they don't really fight back too hard.
Speaker 0: Some of them do the strong ones, but yeah, you're basically you can just beat up on them pretty easily.
Speaker 0: You beat up on them and you collect little jemmies.
Speaker 0: But, you know, and then what you have to do is you go to the enemy territory and you there are these rings like basketball hoops, basically basketball hoops.
Speaker 0: You slam dunk your points that you've collected.
Speaker 0: You haven't collected any points.
Speaker 0: There's no there's no reason to dunk.
Speaker 0: There's no point like right.
Speaker 0: You collect victory points, but then you have to go into enemy territory to score them.
Speaker 0: And that mechanic alone is solves a lot of what I would all complain about with MOBAs, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, oh, you're playing Dota.
Speaker 0: The goal is to destroy this ancient thing in the in the back.
Speaker 0: OK, I'll go directly to the ancient thing and try to score right away by damaging it.
Speaker 0: That doesn't do shit, right?
Speaker 0: That's an awful idea in Dota, right?
Speaker 0: To score points is a bad idea.
Speaker 0: What kind of stupid game.
Speaker 1: the last hit and he got a mic and poke right in Pokemon Unite.
Speaker 0: You can score points immediately.
Speaker 0: It is in your best interest to score points immediately.
Speaker 0: You're always trying.
Speaker 0: If you want to win, you are effectively either always scoring points or defending and preventing the other team from scoring points.
Speaker 1: You're always leveling up faster than that.
Speaker 0: And if you are right, if you're playing competitively, you are focused on scoring from the beginning to the end of the match.
Speaker 0: And secondly, the match will always be assuming the team doesn't forfeit, which can happen.
Speaker 1: So I looked at my stats almost every match I played where we won the enemy team forfeit.
Speaker 0: We'll get to that.
Speaker 0: The game is exactly 10 minutes long.
Speaker 0: All the other MOBAs, they could end quickly if a team gets routed.
Speaker 0: They could go long, but they're usually 40 minutes ish.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Ten minute battles.
Speaker 0: That is like a really good time.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Playing it was fun.
Speaker 0: The game's long enough that you had a substantial game that wasn't just, you know, over too quickly.
Speaker 0: But it's not so long that it drags out.
Speaker 0: It is a very nice time length for this type of game.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Great.
Speaker 0: Now, the thing is, the game is still a MOBA.
Speaker 0: So you're sort
Speaker 1: of a little bit different here in that it's definitely simpler in terms of how you interact with the game, how you would do like a lot of MOBAs that like your characters have a like, depending on what attack you're using, you'll really only have three different attacks equipped at any given time.
Speaker 0: The biggest the biggest simplification is simply that there's no item shop or whatever.
Speaker 1: It's well, there's not there is, but outside of the match.
Speaker 0: No, no, no.
Speaker 0: There's no item shop while you're playing the match.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Which is usually the most complicated and most significant part of your Dodas in your roles.
Speaker 1: You just have the item or items you pick before the match and that's it.
Speaker 0: We'll talk about that.
Speaker 0: You're getting ahead of yourself.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So your Pokemon and it's Pokemon is like the perfect thing for a mobile.
Speaker 0: You have so many characters.
Speaker 0: You have so many only Pokemon.
Speaker 0: There are hundreds of Pokemon.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: No problem.
Speaker 0: And you pick your Pokemon.
Speaker 0: You start out as a low, unevolved Pokemon.
Speaker 0: I think Gengar, but I started out as fucking, you know, a little ghastly guy.
Speaker 0: And then you you level up over the course of the match, like you do in a MOBA.
Speaker 1: And they have 16 to start like Absol's there, Lucario, Venusaur, like it's a good mix.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they got enough Pokemon where it's interesting and they're already adding a Pokemon.
Speaker 0: So they're not wasting any time in increasing the number of Pokemon.
Speaker 1: Not that you can play with all these Pokemon right away, but I'm getting ahead of myself again.
Speaker 0: You are.
Speaker 0: You pick a Pokemon, you start out unevolved, you level up, you evolve.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And that makes it easier to kill enemies.
Speaker 1: Real fun.
Speaker 1: Like you get your first level real quick unless you are like terrible at this game.
Speaker 1: And you basically every time you level up, like you'll learn a new move.
Speaker 1: And once you've got two moves, you can choose to replace one of your moves with another move or just keep the move you already got.
Speaker 1: And the moves are all like pretty radically different.
Speaker 0: Very Pokemon-esque.
Speaker 0: The moves are very interesting, but also very easy to understand.
Speaker 0: You're playing the MOBA.
Speaker 0: It can't be overstated.
Speaker 0: You're playing this MOBA on the Switch using twin stick and buttons, which is the way all MOBA's should have been controlled.
Speaker 0: The RTS controls in MOBA's are nonsense.
Speaker 0: There's no reason that that's the way.
Speaker 0: a game where you control an individual unit is the.
Speaker 0: you would use mouse and keyboard RTS.
Speaker 1: You could just skip the tutorial, dive into this game, mash buttons and you'll figure it out in like 30 seconds.
Speaker 0: The only reason MOBA's are controlled that way is because the first MOBA's were Warcraft 3 mods.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And so that they controlled that way.
Speaker 0: That is a dumb control scheme, right, for controlling a single character.
Speaker 0: The twin stick gamepad control is perfect for this kind of game.
Speaker 0: It always has been.
Speaker 0: I don't know why Dota and LoL should change their controls to be gamepad based, but Pokemon's doing it the right way.
Speaker 0: So that's pretty much the.
Speaker 0: I guess there's a few other positive things.
Speaker 0: There's some interesting mechanics in the game.
Speaker 1: The mechanics I want to call out because we're not going to explain everything in the game because there's a lot of things in the game to explain.
Speaker 1: The mechanics that are really interesting.
Speaker 1: that I think are also improvements on the MOBA format.
Speaker 1: So this is similar, other MOBA's do a similar thing.
Speaker 1: If you score enough points in one of the hoops, you blow that hoop up and your team kind of controls that area more now.
Speaker 0: So that's effectively similar to like destroying towers in a MOBA, like pressuring a lane.
Speaker 1: But it also means you can't just milk one tower.
Speaker 1: You've got to like diversify and go attack something else at some point.
Speaker 0: Now the towers, the hoops behind each hoop is this sort of speed lane that goes back to your base along the road.
Speaker 1: So you can get back to your defensive zone way faster.
Speaker 0: Well, right.
Speaker 0: When you're in your side of the map in your speed lanes, you go faster.
Speaker 0: If you're behind an enemy hoop in their speed lane, you go slower.
Speaker 0: But if you destroy a hoop, you're destroying the speed lane behind it until the next hoop.
Speaker 0: So when you destroy a hoop, scoring more points means you're going to have to go deeper into enemy territory.
Speaker 0: But you'll be able to get into deeper into enemy territory easier because the slowdown lane is gone.
Speaker 0: And also the enemies will have a harder time getting out of their lane, you know, into your territory because they lost their speed up zone.
Speaker 1: But there's still two lanes, like there's hoops on either side.
Speaker 1: Like there's two lanes and then a jungle in the middle.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you take out the top hoop, you don't have to go deep.
Speaker 1: You take out the bottom hoop, but they take out the top hoop and you're still like pretty evenly matched.
Speaker 0: There's also a little springboard.
Speaker 0: So if you die and respawn, you can step on the springboard to sort of jump out into the battlefield quickly.
Speaker 1: It took me a second to figure out the controls for that.
Speaker 1: It actually wasn't that intuitive.
Speaker 0: It's not that intuitive.
Speaker 0: It's kind of a little bit annoying if you use the right stick.
Speaker 0: It's good to me, but it's at least the mechanically.
Speaker 0: It's good.
Speaker 0: The other interesting mechanic that I like is that sometimes at the top of the map, a rotom will appear or at the bottom of the map.
Speaker 0: I forgot about this other Pokemon, I forget his name.
Speaker 1: And other maps love similar things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're special.
Speaker 0: Apparently this is also mechanic that was in League of Legends that I just didn't know about.
Speaker 0: And if you kill those Pokemon, right, then special things happen.
Speaker 0: So what can happen sometimes is like if a rotom appears, both teams will sort of go to the rotom because you want to be the team that kills it.
Speaker 0: Because then it'll join you and do awesome shit.
Speaker 1: Though in my experience, 100% of the matches I played, the team that wasted their time doing that, they got crushed.
Speaker 0: Oh, really?
Speaker 0: That always worked out well for us.
Speaker 0: When I played, the teams would be fighting over the rotom, right?
Speaker 0: We'd all go there.
Speaker 0: You'd be fighting each other.
Speaker 0: And then it's like, well, if you kill all the enemies first, now the rotom's just sitting there.
Speaker 0: You have to fight it a little bit.
Speaker 0: If you try to go kill it on your own and no one helps you, it's strong enough it'll stop you.
Speaker 1: Another really good mechanic, and this is when you're starting the match.
Speaker 1: Because this game, you click "I want to play" and you're in a match like instantly.
Speaker 1: Like it's pretty good about that.
Speaker 1: Now it's Nintendo.
Speaker 1: No voice chat, like obviously, which is honestly a giant pain in the ass because I hate playing team games without voice chat.
Speaker 1: But this game does do something pretty good.
Speaker 1: A big problem with team games is that people who play them tend to not play with the team.
Speaker 1: When you start the match, Nintendo made it really easy to you hit like ZL, I think, and it opens the menu.
Speaker 1: And you can just tell the team which of the three lanes you're going to go after at the start of the match.
Speaker 1: It'll even put a little route for you to remind you where to go if you do that.
Speaker 1: And it shows you what other members of your team have chosen for their lane.
Speaker 1: So you can pretty easily make a plan without having to talk to other people.
Speaker 1: That is like the bare minimum coordination you need to be able to play a MOBA.
Speaker 1: That's a pretty good design decision.
Speaker 1: If they made it more complex, people wouldn't use it.
Speaker 1: If they didn't put that there, this game would devolve to kids like mashing A in the jungle and not coordinating.
Speaker 1: I saw it work pretty well and I saw people using it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I saw a little bit of use of it, but not that much.
Speaker 0: So yeah, overall it's a simpler MOBA, but in many ways there's still enough gameplay there that it's interesting and fun.
Speaker 1: I enjoyed it a lot.
Speaker 1: I actually would play it more like I would play.
Speaker 0: It's more elegant and more well designed than the popular MOBAs.
Speaker 0: I think it might be.
Speaker 0: in terms of the things we've discussed so far, it may be the best big time MOBA.
Speaker 0: I don't know, there might be some small MOBA out there.
Speaker 0: I've never heard of, right?
Speaker 0: But in terms of the big MOBAs, it may be the best one based on those aspects.
Speaker 1: And up to a point, skill doesn't matter because I was playing matches mostly with people who haven't leveled shit up or bought anything outside of a match.
Speaker 1: Well, we'll get to that, the reason why this game is bullshit.
Speaker 1: And the matches, 100% of the matches I played were either a ridiculous snowball victory or a crushing "we are trapped in our spawn for the entire match" defeat.
Speaker 1: At no point did I ever encounter a match that was even remotely close or fair.
Speaker 1: And I played a ton of matches.
Speaker 0: Gameplay-wise, that is the biggest failing of this game, is that it is still a MOBA.
Speaker 0: You are still statefully, within the context of one match, leveling up.
Speaker 1: And if you level up a little bit faster than the other team...
Speaker 0: If you level up faster than the other team, then you can basically one-shot them, right?
Speaker 0: And now they can't do anything.
Speaker 0: Every single match I played, not like most all, 100% of the matches I played, even when it was all noobs who didn't know what the hell was going on, including myself, or when they were clearly pros who knew what they were doing, every match, everyone was a landslide from one team or the
Speaker 1: other.
Speaker 1: I'm talking scores of like 890 to 20.
Speaker 0: I saw 900 to less than 100 in one match.
Speaker 1: I had a match where the other team got zero.
Speaker 1: We trapped them in their spawn until eventually they all quit.
Speaker 1: They forfeit.
Speaker 0: It didn't matter if, you know, one match someone was AFK, the team, or is there sometimes a reason for the landslide, but in the five versus five matches where both teams played hard the whole time, or at least appeared to, always a landslide victory or a landslide loss.
Speaker 0: Leveling up faster than the other team as soon as, right?
Speaker 0: And a lot of games people, they did, thankfully, include a forfeiting mechanic.
Speaker 0: Your team can vote to quit.
Speaker 1: And that is 90% of all the games I played ended in the other team forfeiting.
Speaker 0: As soon as you're behind by some levels, just resigned.
Speaker 0: What are you going to do to catch up?
Speaker 0: It's like, if you try to go out and like level up some more, the other team will be scoring points.
Speaker 0: If you try to go stop them from scoring points, but defense, they'll kill you.
Speaker 0: So even worse than you, if you try to score points right behind their back, they'll kill, they'll just kill you.
Speaker 0: They're just better than you.
Speaker 0: It's like they've leveled up more.
Speaker 0: What can you do?
Speaker 0: No skill that you have is going to let you like at a lower level, you know, kill the enemy team or do anything to set them back.
Speaker 0: And being killed puts you out of the game.
Speaker 0: So you have to respawn, making you fall further behind, because the time while you're dead, the other team is getting XP and you're waiting to respawn.
Speaker 1: Even worse.
Speaker 1: Now, maybe I'm wrong.
Speaker 1: Correct me if I'm wrong.
Speaker 1: You cannot see the score until the end of the match.
Speaker 0: There you might be able to.
Speaker 0: I think if you like press a button.
Speaker 1: I tried every fucking button I could find, like, and I could not find a way to see the score.
Speaker 0: I think if you open up the score screen that shows like the sort of like the equivalent of pressing tab and counter strike.
Speaker 0: I think it's there.
Speaker 0: It's there somewhere.
Speaker 0: But yes, it makes no sense to me at the top.
Speaker 1: Why isn't it just the score just there like in a basketball match?
Speaker 0: The score should absolutely be.
Speaker 0: That's the only problem with the user interface at the top of the screen.
Speaker 0: And humongous numbers.
Speaker 0: The score should be there constantly.
Speaker 1: Because as a player, I will change my strategy like early on.
Speaker 1: If depending on anything happening in that score, I will be making decisions based on that score.
Speaker 1: Just like, I'll just defend.
Speaker 0: Why am I scoring points?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the other problem is that the game instead will pop up.
Speaker 1: Things that will say it's a pretty close match or your fault.
Speaker 1: You're falling behind.
Speaker 0: I've never seen a message that says it's a pretty close match.
Speaker 1: I saw your team is struggling in the very beginning because we both had someone rush out and score like 10 points right away.
Speaker 1: And it was like, it's a, it said like, it's a pretty close match.
Speaker 1: And then 30 seconds later, it said, we're like, it said we're winning by a lot.
Speaker 0: And it was over winning by a lot or our team is suffering.
Speaker 1: What does it say?
Speaker 1: You're really struggling to catch up.
Speaker 1: is what it says.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that one.
Speaker 1: Basically, if you see it say you're struggling to catch up, your team will probably vote to quit within 10 seconds of that.
Speaker 0: You should vote to quit.
Speaker 0: If you see that message, there's no reason to continue playing.
Speaker 1: I don't think, I think maybe three matches I played made it to the end of the 10 minutes.
Speaker 0: I've made it to the end of 10 minutes quite often, but it was always a landslide.
Speaker 0: The one other mechanic in the game I forgot to mention is there is at the end of the match, cause it is timed and the final minute it's like doubles, like all the points go way up so that this is, could be an interesting catch up mechanic.
Speaker 0: for like the team that's behind.
Speaker 0: They could go and like, they could hold their, you know, don't die, hold the balls you've collected and don't dunk them and wait for the final minute.
Speaker 0: Then go on a dunk spree to score a ton of points and catch up, a surprise come from behind victory.
Speaker 0: I'm sure that's what they were thinking of.
Speaker 0: The problem is it's activated for both teams.
Speaker 0: So the team that's ahead just scores a whole bunch of points.
Speaker 1: They're already behind.
Speaker 1: There's no way for them to possibly score points during that.
Speaker 0: It only serves as like a, as like a fun way to make the end of the match exciting.
Speaker 0: It doesn't really provide any meaning mechanically speaking.
Speaker 0: So, so that all the good parts of the end, the bad parts of this game, this game is like, this game is, I'm going to say it right here.
Speaker 1: I know Kotaku.
Speaker 1: There was a controversy out there.
Speaker 1: This game is shit.
Speaker 1: And it is shit because the game is free to play microtransactions to hell.
Speaker 1: And it's cosmetics and game affecting stuff.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: It is a pay to win game to get more out.
Speaker 1: You got to pay to get more items.
Speaker 1: You got to, all right.
Speaker 1: You have to both grind.
Speaker 1: You have to grind and pay.
Speaker 0: You don't have to grind and pay.
Speaker 0: You can pay or grind.
Speaker 0: So the microtransaction stuff is all over the place.
Speaker 0: There's like, there's 20 different, there's like several different shops and different currencies and all different ways to get, you know, you have a trainer level that goes up.
Speaker 1: So last night I played for like four hours continuously.
Speaker 0: That's a lot more than I played.
Speaker 1: Like just, that was just last night.
Speaker 1: I played for four.
Speaker 1: I just played and played and played.
Speaker 1: And the end of that, I had like 4,000 coins to unlock.
Speaker 1: a new Pokemon was like 13,000 coins.
Speaker 1: And there's 16.
Speaker 0: I didn't know.
Speaker 0: No, it's not there.
Speaker 0: I've never seen a Pokemon that costs 13.
Speaker 0: They all cost eight or 10.
Speaker 1: I saw one.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure one cost 13 for me.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: To get like the Unite pass or whatever.
Speaker 1: There's so many things to unlock that I don't understand them all.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I can't even explain all this too much.
Speaker 1: Like you start with this bullshit item that you can hold.
Speaker 0: And so there are cosmetic things.
Speaker 0: Cosmetic things are expensive, but they're cosmetic things.
Speaker 0: So you can ignore them.
Speaker 0: And everything you can buy, you can buy with either the points that you earn by playing or with the points that you get by spending money.
Speaker 1: I don't think it is possible to get there is no in the game just by playing in the death of the universe timeframe.
Speaker 0: So every single item in the game is.
Speaker 0: there's nothing that is exclusively pay.
Speaker 0: only that I saw.
Speaker 0: And there is nothing exclusively grind.
Speaker 0: Everything is.
Speaker 0: you can achieve anything by either method, but you're correct.
Speaker 0: The prices on everything were ludicrous, right?
Speaker 0: It's like to unlock a Pokemon is 10,000 points.
Speaker 0: If you play this game just regularly, I'm almost at 10,000 points.
Speaker 0: I have to get 9,000 so I can unlock one more Pokemon.
Speaker 0: To spend money to unlock a Pokemon 10,000, it's a different currency, but to basically get enough currency with real dollars to unlock a Pokemon is going to be, I calculated close to $10.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And there's that's a lot of fucking money.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So that's already $150.
Speaker 1: It's like 50 bucks if you want all the Pokemon and your reason I was going to have is the leftover Apple.
Speaker 0: The reason I was able to get to 10,000, almost 10,000 coins is because there's so many bonuses, like things to achieve.
Speaker 0: When you start playing, you're brand new at the game.
Speaker 0: If you were to, if I spent all those on a Pokemon, the amount of time it would take me to earn enough from zero without all these starting bonuses.
Speaker 0: as a new player to get to 10,000 again, to buy another Pokemon would be a very long time.
Speaker 0: If I played regularly, I would get there, but it would take a while.
Speaker 0: And to get all the Pokemon would take, especially because they're already adding another Pokemon.
Speaker 0: to get all of them over time, ungrindable, you will have to pay money.
Speaker 1: If you want all of them, uh, like games I play, if they're competitive, every character is just unlocked from day one.
Speaker 1: That's not where they make them.
Speaker 0: So, right.
Speaker 0: So cosmetic things, they're cosmetic.
Speaker 0: We don't care.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Make your money.
Speaker 0: Pokemon.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: If you don't have access to all the Pokemon, is it a, is it truly purely competitive?
Speaker 0: As long as you can unlock enough, you can unlock plenty.
Speaker 1: I already have like, they give you plenty of Pokemon are broken up into basically like tanks, uh, like tanks slash defense, like, you know, whatever category.
Speaker 0: So you'll, you'll have enough Pokemon.
Speaker 0: Plus it does the same thing.
Speaker 0: League of Legends does where over, you know, depending on what day it is, different Pokemon are just unlocked by default for everybody.
Speaker 1: They're all on the Pareto frontier as far as I can see.
Speaker 0: Well, some of them were OP, but balancing is happening.
Speaker 0: Uh, so, but yeah, you're going to have enough Pokemon to play with at any given time.
Speaker 0: Is that really a big deal that you don't have every Pokemon unlocked?
Speaker 0: You know, not necessarily, but the final thing, and this is what really ruins it is Pokemon can, you know, much like in the real Pokemon game, Pokemon can hold items.
Speaker 0: So w and your trainer level determines how many items Pokemon can hold.
Speaker 0: So if you're less than trainer level seven, I think it's seven.
Speaker 0: Your Pokemon can hold one item.
Speaker 0: If you level up more, your Pokemon can hold two items.
Speaker 0: And if you level up even more, eventually your Pokemon can hold three items, game, game affecting items.
Speaker 0: There's an item that can like an apple core that I have.
Speaker 0: It's like a free Garbo item.
Speaker 0: I got makes Pokemon heal all the time.
Speaker 0: There's another item plus special attack.
Speaker 0: So I played against someone who is using Gengar and they clearly, I could tell based on what was on the screen, uh, they had spent money.
Speaker 1: Clearly they had spent, I'll tell you, anyone who spent the start of the match.
Speaker 0: at the start of the match, their Gengar was just one shotting.
Speaker 0: Uh, it wasn't a Gengar yet, but basically they were one shotting our team out of the gate.
Speaker 0: They leveled up way faster.
Speaker 0: It was a landslide.
Speaker 0: We were trapped in our spawn.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: If you don't buy money, if you pay, there was no way for me to beat that person without also spending money.
Speaker 0: Absolutely no way, no amount of skill or decision-making.
Speaker 0: Pokemon choice, team coordination, nothing we could have done could have overcome the power of the fact that that person spent money.
Speaker 0: We had lost the game before it started.
Speaker 1: You got to grind and pay to get Pokemon.
Speaker 1: You got to grind and pay to have item slots and you got to grind and pay.
Speaker 0: Nine out of 10 players did not appear to have spent money.
Speaker 0: One player spending money tilted the whole game.
Speaker 1: But there are 15 different types of items and within those types, there's different levels and like, there's like, you will never get these items.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's exactly right.
Speaker 0: Not only do you need to get the rare items, right?
Speaker 0: That are the strongest, best items to go with your Pokemon.
Speaker 1: You know, they're going to add more items and more Pokemon.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: And level yourself up enough to be able to use three items at once.
Speaker 0: You need to level up the items themselves.
Speaker 0: There's things you can get to spend on items to upgrade them.
Speaker 0: So you need to get your items maxed out, right?
Speaker 0: If you do that, who's going to beat you unless someone else had also spent money?
Speaker 0: because to level to get the items to unlock the slots and to level up all three items for each Pokemon, right?
Speaker 0: The amount of grinding you would have to do to get all of that maxed out is basically an impossibly long time because your trainer can also have an item.
Speaker 0: Oh, right.
Speaker 0: But yeah, you get the potion item, but there's more items.
Speaker 1: And guess what?
Speaker 1: Same story.
Speaker 0: There are more trainer items.
Speaker 0: So like you get a potion, you see your trainer holds potion and that means you can push X to heal and then the potion cools down.
Speaker 0: But obviously if you get better items, I'm sure this super potion or hyper potion or whatever somewhere, right?
Speaker 0: So yeah, it is a MOBA that is elegantly designed.
Speaker 0: Pokemon are fun.
Speaker 0: We like Pokemon.
Speaker 0: Pokemon goes great with MOBA.
Speaker 0: They made a lot of changes to the MOBA format.
Speaker 0: that are positive, though they didn't change it enough.
Speaker 0: You can still level up and landslide, but at the end of the day, it's a pay to win game and that ruins everything else.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So it sucks because the game is fun and they have ruined it.
Speaker 1: I honestly advise you to never play it because unless you if you want to be good at this game, buy everything, spend money and you'll be the goddamn world champion again.
Speaker 0: I think if you played in a match where everyone spent money and had everything maxed out, that is true, then you would be and everyone was skilled because there is some amount of skill decision making going on.
Speaker 1: You will never achieve that level.
Speaker 0: If you dedicate your life and decide because it's still early, this game is not even a week old.
Speaker 0: If you have a bunch of money, you got nothing to do with because you're just rich.
Speaker 0: And you have nothing better to do.
Speaker 0: And you love Pokemon and you love MOBAs.
Speaker 0: And this game is your game.
Speaker 0: You could spend all your fucking money on it, hundreds and hundreds of dollars, and you could become the champion of Pokemon Unite.
Speaker 0: But I would encourage you not to do this.
Speaker 0: Look at the history of the way Nintendo has treated esports.
Speaker 0: That is not a road you want to go down.
Speaker 0: If you want to become an esports person, wait for a different game from a different company to spend your life on.
Speaker 0: A game that will treat its esport community with more respect than Nintendo.
Speaker 0: And also, you know, you know who had one that's not pay to win.
Speaker 1: This was also Tencent.
Speaker 1: It was a Tencent game in collaboration.
Speaker 0: Tencent made this game.
Speaker 0: It's just Nintendo licensed.
Speaker 0: Nintendo did not make this game, though I'm sure they had some input on it.
Speaker 0: This is largely a Tencent made game.
Speaker 0: It's also going to be on mobile.
Speaker 0: So if you don't have a switch, it'll be a mobile pay to win game as well.
Speaker 1: So my advice, if you want to play this, only play it with groups of friends, like get a bunch of friends to play versus against each other and agree.
Speaker 0: Don't use any items.
Speaker 1: That none of you will ever buy any item and you will never unlock anything but additional Pokemon.
Speaker 0: I would just say, you know, even if you did that, a friend might grind more.
Speaker 1: Even though I'm saying you're not allowed to use any in-game currency except to get right Pokemon.
Speaker 1: Nothing else.
Speaker 0: I would say that everyone has to use potion as their item because you just get it pretty early.
Speaker 1: Everyone has to use that apple core as their held item.
Speaker 0: Everyone uses their apple core and equips no other items, no matter what.
Speaker 0: No leveling up the items, no nothing.
Speaker 0: And then, yeah, that's it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it'd be okay to unlock new Pokemon.
Speaker 0: Friends only.
Speaker 0: Unlock a Pokemon, but don't, you know, that's it.
Speaker 1: If any of you want to play in that mode with us, I would actually be inclined to play with the listener.
Speaker 0: Like that's something I would play with all people I knew who are abiding by like the level zero no spend.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's kind of fun to play that way.
Speaker 0: And, you know, but it would still be a landslide every time, I think, no matter what.
Speaker 1: I'm curious, even if everyone is equal, if everyone was equal and it was people who were all trying hard and people were skilled and intelligent.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because definitely like if I had voice, I would add, I would add very polite words with some people on my teams because it was clearly like, okay, that's either a kid or someone.
Speaker 1: They just wandered off by themselves and got killed a thousand times.
Speaker 1: Never actually did it, contributed anything like that happens.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll go on Twitch and like see, find a streamer who is tolerable, who's playing.
Speaker 0: And I assume they'll be playing with a team against a team.
Speaker 0: Just to see what that looks like.
Speaker 0: Yeah, to see if it looks like to see if there's any sort of semblance of balance there.
Speaker 0: I'm sure there'll be money spending and grinding at that level of play.
Speaker 0: But, you know, there's a match of 10 pros, even if they spent money.
Speaker 0: Will it always, will I be able to find anyone else having a close match?
Speaker 1: Because one thing it does get right that didn't matter because of the landslide was, like we said before, the attacks, like different Pokémon are radically different and interesting.
Speaker 0: Oh, very interesting.
Speaker 1: Like Fly, I'll give you an example, Fly, you literally fly off the map, are invincible for like six fucking seconds and you can choose where you come down and fuck somebody up.
Speaker 0: I picked the crab guy because I like crabs and no one else picked it.
Speaker 0: And it's like I had an attack, the rock wall.
Speaker 0: It's like you forget, I think was it, but it's like it shoots out and then it creates a wall of rocks and sort of an arch.
Speaker 0: So you can use this both for keeping opponents away.
Speaker 0: They can't get through the wall, but also for trapping them in.
Speaker 0: Like you can't get away from me.
Speaker 0: I put a wall in front of you and then I kill you.
Speaker 0: But also some Pokémon like Gengar might have an ability to do a short dash teleport and come right through the wall.
Speaker 0: So there's a lot of that sort of good interplay, even in such a simple game.
Speaker 1: Like I've been rocking.
Speaker 1: I play mostly Talonflame and that's real fun.
Speaker 1: You are so fragile.
Speaker 1: You just are.
Speaker 1: you can get anywhere on the map so quick.
Speaker 1: So like your teammates under attack and suddenly you show up and save the day.
Speaker 1: It's good fun.
Speaker 1: But yeah, this game is pay to win garbage.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And the
Speaker 1: Patreon patrons for this episode of Geek Nights, the one that will be the last one you listen to for a while since we'll be out of town are Heidi McDurkle, Alan Joyce, Link Eiji, Dread Lulu, Tenebrae, Chris Reimer, Clinton Walton, Dex, Finn, Just Like a Dude Guy, Kishiai85, Program Thread, Open Speed, Undertake Law, Adoption, Pierce Absorb, Rebecca Dunn, Review Mad Bull, 34 Cowards, Ryan Parent, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Horrell, Taylor Braun, Ewell, The Key to My Heart and a whole bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Speaker 1: live on the show.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: We're going out of town for a bit.
Speaker 1: Then we'll be back for like a week of shows.
Speaker 1: Then actually we're going to be out of town again.
Speaker 1: There's a tiny chance we'll do at least one special episode during that second out of town outage.
Speaker 1: And then we're pretty much in town forever after that.
Speaker 1: And yeah, we won't be at PAX West.
Speaker 1: We'll see if PAX Unplugged even happens.
Speaker 1: TBD on Magfest.
Speaker 1: And otherwise, I leave you with something that you've probably forgotten.
Speaker 1: Now the Koopa teach you the meaning of mean.
Speaker 1: These Bob-omb birds ain't dropping finales.
Speaker 1: We better split or we'll be full of holies.
Speaker 0: You said, "Canelies, I'm ready to
Speaker 0: eat.".
Speaker 0: In fact, it's lunchtime.
Speaker 1: Time to retreat.
Speaker 0: Koopa, your rap's rotten just like you.
Speaker 0: Good rap will win.
Speaker 1: This ball is through.
Speaker 0: Get a grip, you two.
Speaker 1: You're so, so wrong.
Speaker 1: I think they're playing my favorite song.
Speaker 0: I got me a princess and the king of rap, and they're going to get the point of my Koopa trap.