Speaker 1: It's Thursday, September 2nd, 2021.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight We are talking about outerwear like jackets and shit.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: so, uh Yesterday, I know Scott was going to tennis and I was just home doing my thing and I was sitting around the evening and I had a concept in my head of what the weather forecast was which was some rain will come but it's no big deal.
Speaker 1: But then the weather started changing really rapidly and then I go online and the forecast went from a little bit of rain to Massive dangerous thunderstorm shelter in place.
Speaker 1: that storm system came out of almost nowhere.
Speaker 0: That wasn't what I. so I knew it was gonna.
Speaker 0: I thought it was basically gonna rain all day and I knew the remnants of the hurricane were coming in right later.
Speaker 0: But we were only going to the tennis from noon to 5 and then eating dinner and then going home and I figured we were Gonna just beat the horrible rain home You know and I knew it was probably gonna be a bad rain But I didn't think it was gonna be as bad as it was obviously.
Speaker 0: Yep, but I'm saying the hurricane remnants.
Speaker 0: I guess I think the hurricane just lost less energy than we thought it was gonna lose on its way up.
Speaker 1: Well from what I gather I was looking.
Speaker 1: I was reading some weather calm like reporting on it because I was surprised by it is The system strengthened suddenly and rapidly in Pennsylvania like a bunch of stuff happened along the way But it happened so quickly that the forecast changed way too late for anyone to react to it.
Speaker 0: Mmm, so yeah, usually because usually what happens is once a hurricanes on land.
Speaker 0: There's no Ocean under it for it to get more water.
Speaker 0: So it was just losing water right onto the ground And I guess somehow it gained power even in on land.
Speaker 1: well, sometimes you get situations like I don't you ever experienced like an actual direct show where a Storm will sort of like there'll be a thunderstorm and the forecast is even like yeah thunderstorm But suddenly it's not a tornado.
Speaker 1: The thunderstorm just gets really really really really strong over the matter of minutes out of nowhere And it has a constant wind going in one direction Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: It's a kind of scary if it happens to you and you're outside Especially if you're like out in the woods or something.
Speaker 1: I got hit by one on a hike long ago but The rain that came down officially was the most intense hour of rainfall New York City has ever experienced in our recorded history of trying to track how much rain falls in this area
Speaker 0: Measured in inches in
Speaker 1: inches the second most rainfall.
Speaker 1: the previous record was from two weeks ago Yep, so climate change is real and everyone who is resisting drastic societal changes to address This is honestly in my opinion literally committing violence against society and everyone who lives here against humanity.
Speaker 1: Yep, like that's a crime against humanity at this point, and I don't know what we can do about it.
Speaker 0: like Cut Captain Planet was on fucking TV.
Speaker 0: How many years ago?
Speaker 1: Al Gore had his book.
Speaker 0: I was in before out before anyone who Al Gore was in first grade.
Speaker 0: They were telling us reduce reuse and recycle.
Speaker 0: if they were telling me that in first grade, right?
Speaker 0: It wasn't first graders who came up with that It was adults at the time when I was in first grade people who are now really old Right who decided that that's what I should have been taught in the 80 something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so and that means most of the people at least where we are learn this fucking lesson.
Speaker 0: How come so many people haven't learned a lesson?
Speaker 1: if I learned in first grade and I'm old I can actually say why.
Speaker 1: because one All environmental issues.
Speaker 1: This was a shift that started in the 90s actually started before then but it really came to fruition.
Speaker 1: in the 2000s Anti environmental messaging became a cornerstone of right-wing messaging Solely because it was in opposition to something that was perceived as progressive or liberal Kind of like it definitely was not.
Speaker 1: until it was not most people in America didn't give a shit about a mask mandate.
Speaker 1: if if the Republicans hadn't made masks a thing and the government had just Been like yeah wear masks for the foreseeable future It probably wouldn't have been nearly as contentious of an issue.
Speaker 1: But instead it became a partisan shibboleth.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, you know in the in the 80s and 90s, you know, it was just like yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, and you know, no there was no one around who was like cats and planets the bad guy Let's fuck the environs.
Speaker 0: No one that I saw.
Speaker 1: Yeah But like literal like Republican platform and what a good chunk of Americans believe is one climate change is a myth - even if it's happening Who gives a shit?
Speaker 1: and three we should actively pollute?
Speaker 1: Like that third one you I think I'm joking.
Speaker 1: I am NOT.
Speaker 1: that is there are a Surprising number of people who advocate that we should pollute more and exploit the environment more.
Speaker 1: and the argument is God gave us earth to exploit.
Speaker 1: He would never let us harm it so bad that it would come back to bite us.
Speaker 0: There's many different arguments right?
Speaker 0: there's the argument of it makes me more money.
Speaker 0: therefore, I'll convince some doofus to support it.
Speaker 1: There's the argument.
Speaker 0: I think it's a problem for no reason.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm just I'm a bully the kind of person who would have been.
Speaker 0: it was a bully in school And I just like doing it makes other people mad.
Speaker 0: Therefore.
Speaker 0: It makes me happy.
Speaker 0: I don't really care about what the consequences are Yep, but this is only gonna get worse.
Speaker 1: New York City got fucked up last I saw I think 25 people are dead and there's still a lot of people unaccounted for and New Jersey also is in a state of emergency.
Speaker 1: We have not recovered from this.
Speaker 1: I haven't even been outside yet But from what I can tell there is significant damage even a few blocks away from our apartment.
Speaker 1: We just happen to live literally at the highest point in Long Island City.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm not.
Speaker 0: I'm not at the highest point But you know the height doesn't really matter so much right?
Speaker 0: because if you look at the flood map.
Speaker 0: the flood map is for.
Speaker 0: You know storm surge, you know situations like where the river is coming up, right?
Speaker 0: That's what the flood map is measuring.
Speaker 0: So there are people who lived like not even in flood zones like in a place that's high up where it's like.
Speaker 0: You know, you're not gonna even if the sea level rises a fuck ton Your house will still be on a hill of some on land.
Speaker 0: All right, you're gonna be just fine here.
Speaker 0: But what happens is when it rains It's not the river.
Speaker 0: the river might rise sure But the it's not the river rising that causes a flood.
Speaker 0: the water lands right on you no matter how high you are.
Speaker 0: And if it doesn't drain because the drain is clogged up Well, you're gonna know your basement still gonna flood and if you're at the top of a hill It is a little more complicated than that.
Speaker 1: those maps imply a bunch of things.
Speaker 1: height is the primary thing that matters But they're high definitely helps you sure.
Speaker 0: There were many high up places that still got flooded basements.
Speaker 1: They got flooded a very different way.
Speaker 1: There are two different like mechanisms of flooding.
Speaker 1: one is Standing water and the other is flash flood.
Speaker 1: a lot of those basements flooded because an area had a lot of water pass through it.
Speaker 1: Flood waters didn't stay like the street was no longer flooded almost immediately after the rain stopped.
Speaker 1: but on its way down The rain would find a nice basement and say hey, that's a cool place to hang out go into the base That's also and then have no situation that happens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that happened at my mom's house in Arizona a flash flood.
Speaker 1: So there was this hill on their property and no one knew what it was there for it.
Speaker 1: It wasn't in any of the like topographical diagrams.
Speaker 1: So they got rid of it because it was just annoying it in the way.
Speaker 1: years later a Rare flash flood happened and water came streaming Straight toward the house went past where that little hill used to be and slammed right into the side of the house and completely flooded the basement.
Speaker 0: No, I mean, you know, I think you know in the city, right?
Speaker 0: We're mostly worried about the flood situation because You know forget, you know, you know hills and drains and all that sort of situation.
Speaker 0: Everything's concrete.
Speaker 1: Concrete absorbs a little well, that's why there's so much but it's not.
Speaker 0: it's not dirt, right?
Speaker 1: So that's why there's so much work on all those different mitigation techniques to put green spaces dirt trees grass Yeah around because water goes.
Speaker 0: water goes in dirt It doesn't go in kind of and that'll it.
Speaker 1: that'll give you a buffer even if those things don't drain themselves.
Speaker 1: They'll hold more water and give you a buffer to lower the damage of flash floods.
Speaker 0: You're in a grassy field and you see a little puddle in the grassy field.
Speaker 0: if you took all the water and sucked it out Of the grassy field and put it onto like a you know, piece of concrete you'd be up to like It'd be deep.
Speaker 0: So but if you look out and you say okay.
Speaker 0: Well, the city's got these flooding problems.
Speaker 0: Well, how's it going out there in the in the burbs, right?
Speaker 0: Why don't we just you know, maybe the city time is bad.
Speaker 0: It's like no actually shreds.
Speaker 0: The suburbs got a different problem, right?
Speaker 0: They don't got flooding.
Speaker 0: They got some flooding going on especially in places with shitty infrastructure.
Speaker 0: who?
Speaker 0: nor bad geographies or topologies.
Speaker 0: But their situation is they the trees the trees that are so good.
Speaker 0: They got knocked down by the wind and then you get your powers gets cut out.
Speaker 0: I know my parent my my mom the big giant tree in the front lawn that's been there forever.
Speaker 0: You know, she's or we already lost a shit ton of trees over the years.
Speaker 0: The big tree went down it knocked to hit all the power lines.
Speaker 0: Luckily, it went down towards the street and not onto anyone's house or anything.
Speaker 0: So I can't say that trees enormous And yeah, cut took the power right out.
Speaker 1: every single person who lives in New York City Even if they had to deal with some flooding Showed up at work today like online like they all dialed in.
Speaker 1: Almost everyone who lived upstate couldn't had no power and couldn't kill or no internet and couldn't get to work.
Speaker 0: Yep So, yeah, I mean the other thing is that in the city, you know, it's like yeah, there's a flood But the flood is mostly hitting.
Speaker 0: it's gonna hurt you the most if you're in the basement or first-level Abode which is often this I'm on the floor.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I haven't done the math on this but I'm gonna check to see.
Speaker 0: but I feel like all right.
Speaker 0: Tell me if this if this seems reasonable to you, right?
Speaker 0: Cuz usually when the when you hear them talking about like sea level rise climate predictions They're talking about like inches which is very significant like if the sea goes up a few inches, that's a big fucking deal, right?
Speaker 0: yeah, that's disastrous, but I it feels like okay if that much ridiculous climate change is gonna rise things by inches Which is still devastating and bad, right?
Speaker 0: I'm five stories up.
Speaker 0: I feel like if all the ice and all the glaciers on earth melted Well, I'd probably be dead for many other reasons.
Speaker 0: But I feel like even then the water wouldn't reach the fifth floor, yeah, but that's Literally worthless knowledge.
Speaker 0: that doesn't do anything because I didn't say but I just saying like so but you know if that won't reach the fifth floor then I Floods, you know that are happening now aren't gonna hit the fifth floor now.
Speaker 0: So if we just put buildings up on some stilts or whatever that's gonna keep us at least our shit dry for a little while.
Speaker 1: But you know, it can't just go up on stilts.
Speaker 1: all the infrastructure like a giant building not like Electricity.
Speaker 1: Yeah the internet pipe.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, they'll be poop.
Speaker 0: There'll be poop rivers underneath your build.
Speaker 0: their house Yeah, sure.
Speaker 1: But also the way it will be.
Speaker 1: your places like places where floods happen more often or people build around it.
Speaker 1: Usually.
Speaker 1: what they do is all the nice stuff is on the second and third floor and the first floor is built in a way To where if it gets flooded you have to gut it and rebuild it.
Speaker 1: It's really easy and cheap to do and you can keep living in the top while that happens.
Speaker 0: Yep, just one more thing to mention is that of course you can listen to famous geek night's Thursday episode water in the ceiling.
Speaker 0: Yeah in the city.
Speaker 0: He got a lot of flat roofs and not necessarily the nice pointy roofs.
Speaker 1: Oh, you know, yep Some people had water from the ceiling and water from the ground But I must say there was a lot of water in the ceiling yesterday.
Speaker 1: You saw the videos of what was happening to apartments in the city, especially poorer parts of the city.
Speaker 1: Remember that scene if you saw a parasite where the rain happens at the end and that's a real thing.
Speaker 1: So water is coming up from the ground and if you can imagine where the water coming up from the ground comes from It's really gonna come from primarily your toilet.
Speaker 1: Yep, so I would argue that categorically.
Speaker 1: I will always take water coming from above compared to water coming from below.
Speaker 0: I don't want to come from either day in any direction unless I'm in a water park.
Speaker 0: Yeah, then it comes from every direction.
Speaker 1: god there's.
Speaker 1: I just think of the scene and it's always sunny where long story short two of the characters go to the top of a water slide that was closed and think that they can just do it and they know dump a bunch of buckets of water down it and the scene.
Speaker 1: the way they Portray it is.
Speaker 1: you get this wide shot and you see the guy just jump and you hear this like Streaking noise and a little line of red just grows behind him.
Speaker 1: It gets bigger and bigger and bigger and then he just stops.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's bad, yeah, so uh, how is that pre storm tennis?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so yeah.
Speaker 0: yesterday, you know, we took a day off work, you know, cuz we're not going to PAX West.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the US Open which is one of the four major world tennis tournaments is like right near us in Queens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we never wait because it's always at the same time as packs.
Speaker 0: Right, and I don't care about tennis that much but I like tennis.
Speaker 1: All right, I respect the tennis Sports where I don't really follow a lot of the people I don't care that much who wins other than a very small number of people but I Will pretty much just like.
Speaker 1: watching anyone play high-level tennis is always amusing.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So anyway So I'm like, you know what not going to PAX West.
Speaker 0: Let's go to the tennis.
Speaker 0: So I figured out how tennis tickets work.
Speaker 0: I think you know, we went we go over there and I learned so much about what's going on at the tennis tournament.
Speaker 0: I don't want to.
Speaker 0: I guess I could spend a whole episode talking about it.
Speaker 0: But I think all I got to say right now is that when you go to see tennis like the US Open or something like That it's not the same as going to like a hockey game.
Speaker 0: where you go you watch a hockey game It ends you leave.
Speaker 0: right you go you watch a baseball game.
Speaker 0: It ends you leave.
Speaker 0: Basically, you're going to the packs of tennis.
Speaker 0: It's like a convention and they're just tennis fucking everywhere.
Speaker 0: There's Expo Hall kind of At least all over the place Right and like you can get up and walk around and look at different tennis is like they're like they're freaking pet like tennis courts are busy panel rooms and you can just go all around and see.
Speaker 0: And there's only a few that are special like the main events, you know I think there's two and a half that were like special ones.
Speaker 0: You can't just walk into easily.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it was.
Speaker 0: it was actually a lot of fun even if you don't give a shit about tennis.
Speaker 0: It was cheap because we only went for five hours in the afternoon.
Speaker 0: Right, it caused less than half of a Madison Square Garden hockey game and hockey games like three three hours Maybe right.
Speaker 0: and I was there for five hours.
Speaker 0: So huge huge bargain.
Speaker 0: we sat in the ridiculous nosebleed type seats in the in the place that we had to pay and You could see just fine.
Speaker 0: And even though we mostly saw people we didn't really know or care about.
Speaker 0: It's like even watching no-name people.
Speaker 0: like everyone there is professional tennis player.
Speaker 0: It's like whoa.
Speaker 1: That's what I was saying.
Speaker 1: Like professional tennis is just something to see if you've never seen.
Speaker 0: and sometimes you're really you know You're on a field court.
Speaker 0: It's like sometimes you're really fucking close.
Speaker 0: You just get with the ball.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know these people you'd reach out and touch him if you wanted to.
Speaker 0: you'd get in trouble, but you know Yeah, I was surprised there weren't like fences and more security like around.
Speaker 0: Well, it's like the local tennis court has more security.
Speaker 1: We'll get to this when we do our show.
Speaker 1: the show we were talking about doing around likes going to sports events.
Speaker 1: But I imagine and I'm trying to say this without saying anything specifically classes.
Speaker 1: the average person who goes to a tennis match compared to the average person who goes to an American football match is or a baseball match is far less likely to Get naked and run out onto the field.
Speaker 0: I thought about it.
Speaker 1: I imagine that would be a situation of you're the first one and they're all like, oh shit that's never happened.
Speaker 0: But I was like, wow, there's really nothing stopping me from being that streaker guy.
Speaker 0: and I was like, well, let's see How would I do it?
Speaker 0: All right, and then And then I was like, okay, so now I'm on the court naked running around.
Speaker 0: what's gonna happen next?
Speaker 1: There was whatever incident where dude like ran out and stab someone though.
Speaker 0: Did that's true.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was a big deal.
Speaker 0: And I was thinking about that incident when I said well This is probably what's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: and I was like Is there any way that I could do this and have it not be terrible Monica Celeste back in 1993?
Speaker 0: Yep, but I was like, yep There's pretty much no way I could do that and have it not be the worst.
Speaker 0: so I'm not gonna even think about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah anymore.
Speaker 0: It looks like if you didn't check the news I didn't do it.
Speaker 0: Otherwise you would be like is that's good?
Speaker 0: on the tennis One headline flood number two headline naked guy by God naked bald guy.
Speaker 1: The other thing about the US Open is that it's not it like.
Speaker 1: it goes on for a while.
Speaker 1: It goes to what still like September 12th like this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean we could have we could have gone to it like before or after Pax But it's just.
Speaker 0: it's such a hat, you know, well because we won we go.
Speaker 1: we go to Pax early.
Speaker 1: We usually stay at Pax a little late.
Speaker 1: I usually need time to get my shit together before Pax.
Speaker 1: I'm usually too tired to do anything after Pax.
Speaker 1: So yep.
Speaker 0: It was yeah, I would I would go again.
Speaker 0: I think I Don't feel like I need to go again like oh I don't want to miss it But it's like, you know, if someone was like, hey, let's go again.
Speaker 1: I'm like, alright That or any other tennis I've.
Speaker 1: I still keep thinking about playing tennis again.
Speaker 1: The only reason I haven't is that and I mentioned this on the show a long time ago But in New York City specifically you need to pay for a special city license to legally play tennis in any outdoor court.
Speaker 0: Only the ones that have the little guard there, you know, there are some places you can play.
Speaker 1: So any as far as I've read any New York City Official park with tennis requires that permit even if it's no attendant.
Speaker 1: and legally, I'm saying yes But there are.
Speaker 0: there are places like.
Speaker 0: they'll be like, you know some like playground or basketball.
Speaker 1: Usually those are actually covered by that rule the ones that aren't my private.
Speaker 0: There are places like the back of this like a middle school.
Speaker 0: over here behind the middle school It's just a field of concrete right and there's some basketball hoops and there's some paint on the ground and you know It's barely populated whatever and there happens to be a tennis court painted on the ground.
Speaker 0: if you just put a net there You know with so your weight weight.
Speaker 1: There's no net there.
Speaker 0: No, you have to bring one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so that's not really usable.
Speaker 0: Also, I bet it's it's a floor and you could put a net there and play 10.
Speaker 1: also concrete playing tennis on concrete sucks ass.
Speaker 0: And also I'm just saying you could play tennis there.
Speaker 0: No one's stopping.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'm not gonna buy a net and carry with me on my bike and also I Suspect.
Speaker 1: if I went there with another adult and just started playing tennis with my own net No, I would give a shit.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty confident.
Speaker 1: I would get trespassed off of that place by a cop.
Speaker 0: It's a public park.
Speaker 0: No one's gonna give a shit If it's a public party.
Speaker 0: people people play volleyball in public parks all the fucking time Because volleyball does not have a licensing system.
Speaker 1: Like tennis does.
Speaker 1: tennis is unique in New York City.
Speaker 0: There's all kinds of people.
Speaker 0: you can you can't there.
Speaker 0: you can play guerrilla tennis But the thing is why would you when you can get the license and play on a nice tennis court?
Speaker 1: Even then I did look into that.
Speaker 1: with the license.
Speaker 1: every good tennis court has you have to put in Reservations way in advance and you get like an hour to play at a time.
Speaker 1: It's a giant pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: The only.
Speaker 0: if you go to Astoria Park, there's plenty of tennis courts.
Speaker 0: They're rarely all full.
Speaker 0: you could as wise you can just walk up and play on one of the empty ones and they only kick You out if when more people show up and it's full they kick out.
Speaker 0: Whoever's been there?
Speaker 0: the longest basically.
Speaker 0: That's the.
Speaker 0: that's the system.
Speaker 0: Res pretty much reservations are for like the really popular ones like Central Park and whatnot where people are crowding up in there.
Speaker 1: They're more.
Speaker 0: They're more if you go to go to the Bronx if you go up to like Crotona Park you play tennis all you want.
Speaker 1: Yeah, when I bike up in the Bronx, I see the courts all full all the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's popular.
Speaker 0: But you can absolutely play there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's empty courts.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: I'm saying I've looked into it.
Speaker 1: It's too much of a pain in the ass to be worth it.
Speaker 1: The only good way to play ten.
Speaker 0: the reason I don't play tennis is because I love hitting a ball back and forth.
Speaker 0: hitting a Back-and-forth is awesome.
Speaker 0: I love hitting the ball back and forth the sport.
Speaker 0: I don't like run back and forth the sport.
Speaker 0: So I'll stick to badminton.
Speaker 1: Well, if you don't like run back and forth just play ping-pong.
Speaker 0: Pink feeling.
Speaker 0: the problem is balls too small.
Speaker 0: I can't hit it.
Speaker 1: It sounds like you just don't want to play a sport you're bad at.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, it's like I don't play sports.
Speaker 0: It doesn't upset me.
Speaker 0: It doesn't upset me that I'm bad.
Speaker 0: I don't expect to win it.
Speaker 0: badminton either.
Speaker 0: It's that I will barely be playing because it'll be like someone serves and I can't return it.
Speaker 0: I'm like, I'm not even playing.
Speaker 0: I'm so bad, right?
Speaker 0: If I was a little bit better to where I could actually get a volley going and then get scored on I'd be okay.
Speaker 1: I mean how you do that is you play you take lessons and then you just play again.
Speaker 0: Let's not do that.
Speaker 1: I spent 15 years playing tennis Actually seem worse Lee more than that.
Speaker 1: But what I might do instead is just start playing racquetball or wall ball or something.
Speaker 1: But anyway there is.
Speaker 0: This is coming and we talked about it was happening for a while and then it happened.
Speaker 1: effectively The US Supreme Court has for all intents and purposes overturned Roe vs Wade meaning that there is nothing preventing any state in America from just banning abortion Full stop.
Speaker 0: Well, as long as they do it in a particular way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the way that Texas did it is so egregious and Violent that it's worth pointing out what this law does basically is it bans abortions after six weeks?
Speaker 1: Which for all intents and purposes bans all abortion.
Speaker 1: very few people even know they're pregnant at that point.
Speaker 1: There's your body like.
Speaker 1: there's no way to know unless you get a test.
Speaker 1: You wouldn't think to get a test half the time and to the law says that anyone Literally anyone can sue.
Speaker 1: I guess I guess anyone who's a citizen anyone in Texas can sue anyone who they suspect got an abortion and Get a $10,000 like bounty if in fact that person did get prosecuted for an abortion Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: That is fucked up like beyond belief.
Speaker 0: Why can't we have bounties for other things right like?
Speaker 1: I can tell you why?
Speaker 1: activation because if we did that for anything else the Supreme Court would strike it down.
Speaker 1: the only reason they didn't strike this down is because The sole goal of a lot of people who push for Donald Trump and George Bush and Mitch McConnell Like a big part of why the Republican Party is in the position of power It's in is a dedicated group of people in America whose sole political issue is Banning women's health care.
Speaker 1: they want to ban abortion and then if they are successful they want to ban birth control Like and they don't care what.
Speaker 0: that's the only thing they care about literally they care about nothing else.
Speaker 0: They have like this single mindset.
Speaker 0: So they'll vote for it for whoever will do that.
Speaker 0: And so The you know, and it's a thing we don't want to do.
Speaker 0: So we're not gonna do it to get their votes And the other people just want to win.
Speaker 0: They don't care what they do They only care about winning.
Speaker 0: So that's who they keep voting for and they don't care what other things those, you know People they voted for do so.
Speaker 1: What's even worse the American anti-abortion movement that movement originally came out of and is primarily actually driven by anti-black racism because where that movement came from was a bunch of schools that excluded black students were basically told that they cannot maintain their charitable status as schools like they can't be a charity anymore unless they integrate.
Speaker 1: and the movement that forms Focusing on abortion formed out of the resistance to integration in schools primarily religious schools.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's.
Speaker 0: there's like 10 billion You know, we could go on for a hundred years talking about the history of.
Speaker 0: you know, the abortion issue in the United States.
Speaker 1: Abortion is a 100% human right and if you disagree with that, I'd rather you not.
Speaker 0: it's not any different from any other medical procedure.
Speaker 0: It's only a special separate thing because some religious nutjobs decided to make it a special different thing for some.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right, but I guess it's like banning abortion isn't any.
Speaker 1: it's like you might as well say Ben, you know Appendectomy, it's like yep, so To not focus on that but just focus on what this news means and what it is and you can go read more from experts.
Speaker 1: But there's.
Speaker 1: this is a lot.
Speaker 1: a lot of really important things are gonna come out of this and you Have to internalize that things are gonna get way worse on this front before they because all the other shitty states are gonna do the Same thing.
Speaker 1: pretty much everyone worse every Republican controlled state in America is gonna ban abortion in the coming few months.
Speaker 0: And you have to realize, you know, it's like, you know, you're like, oh, okay.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't care about those shitty states.
Speaker 0: I'll stay in my good state.
Speaker 0: you realize the shitty states are mostly not shitty people.
Speaker 0: It's a minority of people in those states.
Speaker 1: It's about half and half.
Speaker 0: There are all of the red states also the majority of the people in those states, right?
Speaker 0: That's where most of the black people live.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Well, so there's two kinds of red state.
Speaker 1: well, there's three kinds of red state but the two that matter for this conversation and this is something that a lot of Tech bro leftist progressives just erase or don't know or willfully ignore is that half of these red states are Almost entirely white and the far majority of the people there support a lot of what the public place
Speaker 0: like like, Iowa Yeah,
Speaker 1: or West Virginia.
Speaker 1: West Virginia last I checked is like 94 percent white.
Speaker 1: So the population there is low Yes but the other half of red states Wyoming are more like a 60/40 split like only 60% of the people there are vile monsters.
Speaker 1: The other 40% are just trying to live their lives.
Speaker 0: Well, it's not even that it's only in those days 60% of the voting people who aren't different because those states 60% of the people who successfully vote Yeah are vile monsters.
Speaker 0: if you actually Had a vote of every person in the state and forced them to vote and so what kind of person they were?
Speaker 0: a lot of Those states I think are probably actually not red
Speaker 1: because
Speaker 0: a lot of those dates gerrymandering Disenfranchisement, etc, etc, right, you know a lot
Speaker 1: of those things have a very large non-white People that basically can't effectively vote because of voter restrictions that are only in place today Because the Supreme Court overturned the Voting Rights
Speaker 0: Act anyway,
Speaker 1: so Every red state is gonna ban abortion.
Speaker 1: We can't stop it from blue states.
Speaker 1: There is literally no way to stop this legally other than the Congress packing the Supreme Court meaning appointing more justices so that then they can just rerule on this and ban this.
Speaker 1: or Congress passing a law guaranteeing access to abortion which which probably they could do which Probably would be overturned by the compromise Supreme Court.
Speaker 1: So we still have to pack the court.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, the problem is to pack the court.
Speaker 1: we need either 50 Democratic senators willing to overturn the filibuster and a president willing to pack the court.
Speaker 1: We have you don't need to overcome the filibuster to because when it comes to You know filling this note because it's not just it's not just a point It is you you actually change the size of the court via a congressional action and then on that.
Speaker 0: So that action but actually appointing people you don't need to.
Speaker 1: but the changing the size you would yeah You need either 60 senators to agree to effectively overturn the filibuster and agree to pack the court or You need 50 senators plus the president to agree to do it.
Speaker 1: And we only have 50 Democratic senators at least two of which are evil vile people Sinema and Manchin who refuse to do anything on anything that matters to America.
Speaker 1: So as long as the Republicans are 100% opposed to this Democrats there is.
Speaker 0: there is no way within the system of America following the rules That we can do it given the people that are there.
Speaker 1: Yep Because to to fix voting rights so that the people who are disenfranchised in red states could vote You need those states to vote to remove the power of the people who currently control those states.
Speaker 1: and guess what?
Speaker 1: Those people are gonna vote they're gonna vote.
Speaker 0: No Mmm, this is the fundamental problem not just with America but with all systems on the entire Human society.
Speaker 0: is that just about every system we have?
Speaker 0: Right puts the power to control the system in the hands of the people who are winning at the system.
Speaker 0: Alright, so by winning you have the power to keep yourself winning.
Speaker 0: whether it's voting money Business a board game, you know children's classroom games every single system on the whole face of the earth Most of the ones that are human society systems, right or even biological systems, you know.
Speaker 0: It's like if you're a virus.
Speaker 0: that's you know, if you start winning then you have the power to.
Speaker 0: you know Control the ecosystem to make yourself more winning the way humans well and then destroy it to make yourself losing.
Speaker 0: But that's you know, we had to overcome that fundamental rule Systems.
Speaker 0: Yeah to where the winners aren't the people who control the environment in which the winning and losing takes place.
Speaker 1: but that's it's actually a little subtly different here because what happens specifically in America?
Speaker 1: because We have to marry that sort of theory with praxis and like the reality of a specific situation or there's no way to move forward.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of great theories on how to fix this But the practical reality is that the problem literally comes down to the fact that American states Themselves get equal representation to each other despite having radically different populations.
Speaker 1: Yep, that is the fundamental problem.
Speaker 1: that literally prevents anything from being done about this and I think Non-legal action is what we need to do.
Speaker 1: races and I saw a couple other groups Starting to pledge that they're going to keep performing abortions in Texas and just they're gonna do civil disobedience.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's obviously a good idea.
Speaker 1: That's might be the only path.
Speaker 0: The other thing we can do is here's the thing is you're there even if you know Organizations weren't doing abortions in a civil disobedient.
Speaker 0: Like we're doing abortions, right?
Speaker 0: We're sitting at the counter at Walgreens kind of way, right?
Speaker 0: Abortions are happening in Texas.
Speaker 0: No matter what the law is that would always have.
Speaker 0: they would always continue to happen in Texas.
Speaker 1: They happen whether
Speaker 0: they're doctor Nick in the back room whether they're good doctor in the back room whether they're rich Person which right Republican
Speaker 1: here's what's gonna have
Speaker 0: it gets it done Anyway in secret rich
Speaker 1: people in Texas even people who voted for this ban and wanted this ban will secretly get abortions in other states With their money.
Speaker 1: poor people are just fucked.
Speaker 0: or in Texas that you know, nothing's.
Speaker 0: they're rich people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so At least one thing that has happened to and I want to point this out in the news.
Speaker 1: So the Denver guys actually responded pretty quickly.
Speaker 1: The house is gonna vote soon.
Speaker 1: They already put together.
Speaker 1: They're finishing up a bill like as of today.
Speaker 1: This is news that would guarantee abortion access nationally, of course The Senate won't pass it because the Senate is controlled by evil douchebags.
Speaker 1: Nothing can pass the Senate right now literally nothing.
Speaker 1: But the house remember Democrats only control the house by a couple seats.
Speaker 1: And yeah They're gonna vote on this bill Nancy Pelosi the speaker of the house.
Speaker 1: Basically the way American system work is the whoever controls these chamber has full authority to decide anything that even makes the floor in that Chamber.
Speaker 1: so because also a problem Yeah, but so because Democrats control the house they can put legislation down But they probably often won't if they know it won't pass because that usually just hurts them Electorally.
Speaker 1: the fact that Nancy Pelosi says they're gonna vote on this Like soon like this month as soon as possible to pass this bill means they have enough votes to pass it.
Speaker 1: We know Pretty much every Republican is gonna vote against that meaning the Democrats in the US House Which represent a huge diverse chunk of America are in lockstep on this issue.
Speaker 1: that is worth recognizing.
Speaker 0: American Democrats have never been doesn't matter unless those two other people are in lockstep on the issue.
Speaker 1: Oh, it seems like they are.
Speaker 1: I'm saying that the yeah the other people in the Senate.
Speaker 1: the problem with the Senate again Is that it doesn't actually represent the population.
Speaker 0: we've said the same thing a thousand times.
Speaker 0: Yes, it you know say pointing out the problem that we all know doesn't fix the problem cuz I think there's literally no way to Legally fix the problem.
Speaker 1: I don't know what to do about it.
Speaker 0: That's you said the same thing and we've all said the same thing for how many years?
Speaker 1: alright, so then here's the question What do you do about this?
Speaker 1: abortion is just gonna get banned in half this country, and there's nothing we can do I?
Speaker 0: Think that's you know you.
Speaker 0: I think that the the the thing you have to come to terms with is that you know we're sit There's there's problems, and there's Consequences.
Speaker 0: right it's like what we're seeing isn't like oh, we're losing the game.
Speaker 0: We lost the game a long time ago.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, right.
Speaker 0: We've already lost your now.
Speaker 0: We're just suffering the fight.
Speaker 1: the final round of that game was when Al Gore Wrongly was not made president despite winning the popular vote.
Speaker 0: All right, and it's like you know as long as the people who have the power aren't going to you know try.
Speaker 0: It's like there is no within the system way.
Speaker 0: So the question is are you willing to do an out-of-the-system way or not?
Speaker 0: Yeah, right and each person will do what they're gonna do and history is gonna history.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and what you can do in the show do so you.
Speaker 0: so you you know.
Speaker 0: But you the only thing that you can control is what you do.
Speaker 0: You're just.
Speaker 0: you know you're one person, and you know you can do something.
Speaker 0: So you do what you're gonna Do.
Speaker 0: you're one person.
Speaker 0: that is you.
Speaker 0: yeah, maybe convince other people and then with a podcast or something like that Yeah, and then you see what happens and then one day you die.
Speaker 1: yep.
Speaker 1: So what I would recommend you all do right now is the most immediate thing we have to deal with is the harm That's happening to people in Texas.
Speaker 1: in these other states There are lots of charities that will help people get abortions if they need them and that is driving to another state.
Speaker 0: You know do do what in the back?
Speaker 0: Secret?
Speaker 1: those are the organizations to donate to easy the speakeasy abortion.
Speaker 1: you know what I'm saying is those are the organizations to donate to Now because the money you donate for political causes and other activism won't help those people for years.
Speaker 1: So we got to focus on those people first mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So all I really have to say about that is I am definitely never setting foot in Texas again So long as all these laws are in place and if there's a bunch There's a lot.
Speaker 0: I mean I was already not too happy about how many times I did set foot in day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so if there's a pack south this coming year.
Speaker 1: I will not be at it, but that's just one tiny thing.
Speaker 0: I also think you know don't think they should have a pack south in Texas given this situation.
Speaker 0: right given I was already a after the gun situation.
Speaker 0: You know busy, Texas was already at don't forget the anti-transgender rights bill that they just passed and the answer Between the last pack south and now Texas went way over the line.
Speaker 1: they passed over 600 individual Bills that restrict human rights in one way or another.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm like since the last time we were in Texas.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So yeah, you know and I think we talked about how Major League Baseball moved over the voting thing moved the all-star game from you Know Atlanta to Colorado.
Speaker 0: right, Texas is way worse.
Speaker 0: I feel like we should pressure Not just you know packs and penny arcade which are close to us so we can pressure them I guess more because we're close to them at least in some way.
Speaker 0: But we should pressure basically Every organization.
Speaker 0: you know obviously not the ones that are like they're helping people right not those, but basically any capitalist Organization of any kind.
Speaker 0: pressure them to fuck over, Texas as much as possible.
Speaker 0: be like yeah You know and be like hey if you're gonna do business in the state of Texas Fuck you.
Speaker 0: I also think we'll do anything to benefit that state.
Speaker 0: bring that state down to you know ruin I think what would help there too, and I in a way that hurts in a way that hurts money Not a way that hurts the poor people living there.
Speaker 1: so in terms of the latter part of that one angle we could take and I got to read more theory and like Read more from experienced activists to see if this would be helpful or not I think charities to help people who want to leave these states.
Speaker 1: leave them help them find like money and Resources to move get a job in a blue state.
Speaker 1: I think that would one reduce the harm to the people who are trapped in these states.
Speaker 0: How about a purple state instead?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I'm just well I said blue state first because I'm focusing more on their safety.
Speaker 1: Then I'm just gonna fix this.
Speaker 0: if we get all if all the good people of Texas move to like Ohio And to Ohio and Florida right take half the good people in Texas put them in, Ohio Take the other half put them in Florida problem solved.
Speaker 1: That actually wouldn't get us enough Senate seats to pass the Voting Rights Act.
Speaker 0: that would get us.
Speaker 1: So we get us four more.
Speaker 1: we need a level.
Speaker 1: actually we need 12 more to get past cinema and mansion.
Speaker 0: No, we don't we just need.
Speaker 0: if we get four more we can eliminate the filibuster.
Speaker 1: and no because no no we can't necessarily Because there is a lot of evidence that there's a bunch of Democrats at least I've seen like real people who no more brothers than me say between four and twelve who?
Speaker 1: Will not?
Speaker 1: I will absolutely not get rid of the filibuster because they're.
Speaker 1: even if those Mansion and cinema we could expose them by what you described, right?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: and once you knew who they were then if they're in blue states, then they can be outvoted.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we can replace them with another right we can't replace.
Speaker 0: You know mansion with it with a Democrat, right?
Speaker 0: He's gonna get replaced.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that scene is lost.
Speaker 0: We have to pretend that's right to Republicans, but if it turns out that like, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, what's?
Speaker 0: who's a good example, right?
Speaker 0: I mean we should get rid of her.
Speaker 0: Anyway Feinstein in California Yeah, you know if she vote, you know, we can probably get rid of her if she votes Yeah, but then we run into stuff too.
Speaker 1: Like, you know what?
Speaker 1: The primary thing is holding up Medicare for all the two Connecticut senators.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're Democrats, but that state makes all its money from a corrupt industry Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So yeah America is in super deep shit right now And this is gonna get way worse over the next couple years.
Speaker 1: Like this issue is not going to get better anytime soon Prepare for the worst.
Speaker 1: like I'm not.
Speaker 0: even the whole world is just getting worse, right?
Speaker 0: What place on earth is?
Speaker 0: are things on the upswing?
Speaker 1: Uh Parts of Europe are doing better in a lot of ways Like where that's the best I can get.
Speaker 1: honestly Germany is continuing to reach.
Speaker 0: people on the beach are doing better.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah billionaires doing better.
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't get me started on wealth caps again.
Speaker 1: I think no human should have more than ten million dollars in assets, and I don't even think it should be like Oh, well tax you above that.
Speaker 1: I think it should be a felony to be caught having that many assets.
Speaker 0: Sure, whatever.
Speaker 1: anyway It's time for things of the day.
Speaker 1: So the other day I was in a private discord Looking to respond to someone with a meme because someone quoted the the transit Advisor from SimCity 2000 who is iconic if you've never seen this guy and I wanted to post a meme of that guy.
Speaker 1: So I looked for a SimCity 2000 like meme generator.
Speaker 1: like you do.
Speaker 1: That's way easier than photoshopping it.
Speaker 1: someone did the work and what I discovered is a website called death generator calm.
Speaker 1: It has like it has generators for So many old video games that it died about an hour and a half of just great fun using this thing last night.
Speaker 0: And I did.
Speaker 0: I did.
Speaker 0: it was two nights ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was two nights ago.
Speaker 1: But this thing is super fun if you want to make like Oregon Trail or Legend of Zelda or Doug memes like This meme generator is just a plus.
Speaker 1: It's well designed.
Speaker 1: It's elegant.
Speaker 1: It just works props to at food.
Speaker 1: who made this thing?
Speaker 0: Yeah, what a horrible night to have a meme generator.
Speaker 1: Are you a bad enough dude to post topical appropriate memes and their respective channels?
Speaker 0: Are you a bad enough dude to go from a serious topic about the you know end of human society to then talking about video game memes?
Speaker 1: Ah, but I uh, if there's one thing that keeps me sane throughout the hellscape of my adult life It is the fact that I have computer still works.
Speaker 0: You have your you have your foot bread and your circus.
Speaker 0: It's it.
Speaker 1: I have my bread.
Speaker 1: I have my circus but more importantly I have a very dark sense of humor that That's not even festival from hell world.
Speaker 0: That's for when I was a target to help you.
Speaker 0: You got a scary clown circus.
Speaker 1: not a fun clown circus, yeah, but I go to the scary clown circus and I'm kind of into it.
Speaker 1: That's the difference.
Speaker 0: I like the good clown circus.
Speaker 1: I like both.
Speaker 0: I like both scared of clowns.
Speaker 0: I like both happy clown and terrifying clown equally and as long as the clown is here for me It's all about where the clown is talented.
Speaker 0: right an untalented clown is sort of just really sad and disappointing.
Speaker 0: But a really talented clown is like whoa, right?
Speaker 1: They've got the juggling and their magic And unchallenged clown is actually scarier than a scary clown because an untalented clown is Someone whose life is probably also very sad and you can feel that sadness.
Speaker 0: They got the mime skills.
Speaker 0: a clown just got so many skills, right?
Speaker 0: You look at someone like, you know, Charlie Chaplin with like all the physical humor.
Speaker 0: That's like a -.
Speaker 0: that's what a talented clown is right.
Speaker 0: only live.
Speaker 1: All I get it now is that that tweet from space twigs doctor.
Speaker 1: The treatment is simple.
Speaker 1: go see Orville.
Speaker 1: very funny clown Pagliacci.
Speaker 1: what about Pagliacci doctor Pagliacci, man, I could not name a more suck-ass clown.
Speaker 0: just Haven't heard that one.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's a good.
Speaker 0: That's a good Pagliacci remix if I ever heard.
Speaker 0: Okay, so one thing a clown might do is jump rope, I'm actually becoming a fan of jump rope lately Cardio.
Speaker 1: like you think running's hard.
Speaker 1: try jump roping at speed for ten minutes.
Speaker 0: Good God I can't even.
Speaker 0: I couldn't even jump rope for five minutes.
Speaker 0: So Yeah, jump ropes are real cheap - I got one for a few bucks, right?
Speaker 0: And it's just like yeah It's other than biking.
Speaker 0: jump roping is fun Yeah, you know and you can exercise and fun or even a fake jump rope with this.
Speaker 0: There's that app on the switch.
Speaker 0: You can just fake jump rope with two Two joy cons with no string.
Speaker 0: jump roping is getting a whole body workout.
Speaker 1: And it's also.
Speaker 1: it's difficult It's not easy to do.
Speaker 0: Well Yeah, you'll I mean I can do it.
Speaker 0: I just can't do it super well But you get but you get better very quickly with.
Speaker 0: so it's a weird aside But it's not like ping-pong where you try a hundred times and you still can't you know, even get it.
Speaker 1: In my elementary and middle schools on the playground we would often get engaged in jump rope offs and the way they would work is two people start jump roping and Basically, whoever can go the longest wins.
Speaker 0: That was it We would do the.
Speaker 0: you know, we would do the three people write two people on the ends hold the big one.
Speaker 0: You know whenever that happened usually the turn turning around, you know doing it, you know, I could do a flip.
Speaker 1: It's what you were doing more freestyle and we were doing technical.
Speaker 0: some people could you know do the switch feet like left right left Right, some people would do like jump once but make the rope go under them like three times before they land.
Speaker 0: I could do it two times before I land but not three time I could.
Speaker 1: I never successfully did the two jump ropes at the same time ever.
Speaker 1: I fell on my face 100% of the times I tried that.
Speaker 0: Oh the double dutch.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can't do.
Speaker 1: I can't do it at all.
Speaker 0: I just but here in this thing of the day They're doing a shocking number of jump ropes at the same time.
Speaker 0: In fact, it is a dangerous number of jump ropes at the same time so dangerous that there are two spotters Watching the person jumping.
Speaker 0: I don't even understand really how this works.
Speaker 0: Is this fake?
Speaker 0: I don't know what it is, but it's worth looking at and that's why it's a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: So the top posts under this are that would fuck you up if you miss the jump the next place.
Speaker 0: it would instant bondage.
Speaker 1: Yes, it would Imagine failing a jump and being strangled right there in front of.
Speaker 0: how do they even make the ropes for this fucking thing?
Speaker 1: Imagine failing a jump and being just strangled there right in front of everyone by everyone.
Speaker 0: Well, that's what it's two people to Russian and save you just standing there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I hope those two people have knives on them.
Speaker 0: I think they probably.
Speaker 0: I assume they do otherwise But you never know cuz this is like how I think really the impact of getting hit is really what's gonna mess you up?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, especially cuz those jump ropes are so long And there's so many of them right?
Speaker 0: It's like imagine you get whipped by one whip.
Speaker 0: It's like ow, right?
Speaker 0: You know if it's and these aren't getting whipped hard like someone's trying to you know, give you lashes, right?
Speaker 0: They're just sort of going a little bit but it.
Speaker 0: so it's sort of like a weak whip but a weak whip times that many Right plus the leverage of a long rope.
Speaker 0: You know, there's a lot of leverage in there in give me a rope long enough and I'll move something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so in the better moment, we will not be at PAX West which is ongoing this weekend.
Speaker 1: This is the first PAX Anywhere in the United States?
Speaker 1: We have not been to and presented at.
Speaker 1: says it's happening physically since we started in 2008.
Speaker 1: We've also presented at every virtual packs.
Speaker 1: So Thus ends the streak officially as of today.
Speaker 0: It's an arbitrary streak.
Speaker 0: No, my health is more important than and even if the streak was a meaningful thing and not an arbitrary thing.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, no regrets.
Speaker 0: It is more important by like a billion.
Speaker 1: Don't get me wrong though.
Speaker 1: I broke the streak a year after you really when we didn't keep going to PAX Australia every year because I had ridiculous.
Speaker 0: I have.
Speaker 0: no I have like, you know, you think oh you have this big long streak.
Speaker 0: you think I'd be like upset about it.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 1: no I had a streak of over a decade.
Speaker 1: go to Wildwood every year and I broke that streak for good reasons.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just you know, it's like, you know, it's not a big deal arbitrary numbers and things don't mean any.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: what means something, you know, it means something being healthy.
Speaker 0: No one that I know and care about I mean some people I know and care about got COVID, right?
Speaker 0: But you know for the most part the damage that I and people I care about have suffered has been way less than what other People have done for which I'm thankful.
Speaker 0: I'll give up fucking PAX forever in exchange for that.
Speaker 0: So I don't give a shit.
Speaker 1: Yep, our last PAX panel, which was a PAX East Online 2021 Camp PAX Atari game design is just on YouTube slides and notes.
Speaker 1: Everything is just there.
Speaker 1: You can just watch it.
Speaker 1: You don't have to wait for PAX to post a VOD or whatever.
Speaker 1: They're gonna do.
Speaker 1: Book Club book is still the tale of Genji.
Speaker 1: I haven't read any since the last show we did but that was only two days ago, so hey, but uh, I think definitely gonna finish it within a month or two because I'm steamrolling along.
Speaker 0: and Well, I guess I guess I'll start reading.
Speaker 0: I think the thing the thing that's actually motivating me is like there's these other books I've discovered that I want to read but I feel guilty reading a book that's not good.
Speaker 1: Oh the book I picked for the next book is you pick Genji.
Speaker 0: I know the book you pick for the next book is a book that I very badly want to.
Speaker 0: yes Wait, I wanted to wait to read it until it's series that it is in is completely done.
Speaker 0: No, I'm just gonna be the boys.
Speaker 0: You know, I hate.
Speaker 1: Yeah, though if you the thing is this author we know we'll finish what they start quickly.
Speaker 0: Well, oh, yeah, and he will end in our you know, hopefully right?
Speaker 0: Well, we are Scott backer.
Speaker 1: Well, what's going on, buddy?
Speaker 1: Nothing ever come on, buddy.
Speaker 0: I assume it's done.
Speaker 0: I assume that's it.
Speaker 0: We're not getting anymore buddy You got it.
Speaker 1: you got a good I got it.
Speaker 1: you got to explain.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm a piece of the fact we're not getting any.
Speaker 1: I am confident that Cal moments with a C and Cal moments with a K. that is not a coincidence.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna die on that hill and The only way you can prove me wrong is to publish a goddamn book or I guess come on the show and tell us what?
Speaker 1: The ending was gonna be otherwise.
Speaker 0: while we're talking about books just real quick I want to call out the shenanigans that Amazon is doing, you know, they're doing lots of shenanigans.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but If you add a book to your wish list on Amazon, right which I have done What they'll do is sometimes they'll send you this email.
Speaker 0: That's like, hey, I see you got the book on your wish list.
Speaker 0: All right, you want to buy the Kindle version of the book?
Speaker 0: I know you do.
Speaker 0: you got on your wish list?
Speaker 0: I know you want to read it.
Speaker 0: I know Here's five dollars.
Speaker 0: if you buy that book within the next seven days We will discount the price on the e-book by five dollars.
Speaker 1: That's like the Sunday super shopper special, right?
Speaker 0: But it's like specifically for you because it was on your wish list.
Speaker 0: in seven days You have to and it's like.
Speaker 0: it's like fuck.
Speaker 0: I do want to read that book.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna read it one day or at least I think I am.
Speaker 0: if I don't buy it now.
Speaker 0: I'm losing five bucks.
Speaker 0: I'm just giving Jeff Bezos five.
Speaker 1: Don't buy now don't buy something unless you're imminently about to use it.
Speaker 0: That's of course my policy and that is of course why I'm not buying it.
Speaker 0: But that's an evil.
Speaker 0: whoever came up with that evil dirty trick I got a guess at Amazon that person probably got promoted like ten times for that trick And that trick should be illegal.
Speaker 1: also My guess is that someone in Amazon just took some training on modern pricing methodologies.
Speaker 0: Whoever I'm saying whoever implemented that system that does that should go to jail and it should be illegal.
Speaker 1: That doesn't bother me nearly as much as gacha mechanics in games and pay-to-win.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying is bad.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm more mad that Pokemon unite is a terrible game because of pay-to-win than I am about that.
Speaker 0: I'm listening.
Speaker 1: It's just another thing In the world someday, we'll get power and we'll break Amazon into a million pieces.
Speaker 0: What the book?
Speaker 0: one will still be doing?
Speaker 0: the evil shit the book company.
Speaker 1: But if they were just a book company, they would.
Speaker 1: the other book companies could compete with them maybe.
Speaker 1: Well, we could probably see.
Speaker 1: here's the other thing.
Speaker 1: Remember my my praxis and I haven't talked to this a lot on geek nights, but I'm not gonna derail this.
Speaker 1: we're getting right into the main bed, but Here my main thing is we can't just become communists like.
Speaker 1: there's no non-violent way to make that just happen.
Speaker 1: I mean as much as I want that.
Speaker 1: the pragmatic for approach is You make public options.
Speaker 1: you start with things that make a lot of sense to a lot of people like oh, yeah Public utility public health care, whatever, but then you start edging into.
Speaker 1: there's the government game company.
Speaker 1: There's the government silverware company government streaming service Free markets.
Speaker 0: welcome to compete with that government option have a government streaming service.
Speaker 0: It's called library.
Speaker 0: That doesn't let you that doesn't stream you on a public platform that the library There are the library has like a thing that you can log into and watch a fucking ton of movies.
Speaker 1: No, no, I'm talking publishing streams not in this case Me making a stream out to the world.
Speaker 0: Oh, I Was.
Speaker 1: that was what I was referring to?
Speaker 1: Otherwise, yes, you were correct if you think about the opposite end of that.
Speaker 1: But yeah If thanks, there should be a public out the public bookstore.
Speaker 1: Amazon has to compete with the government.
Speaker 1: one and guess what the government won't.
Speaker 1: let you say our books are free We just pay the authors and we give the books away for free.
Speaker 1: Fuck you Amazon.
Speaker 1: That's how you get to communism.
Speaker 1: Anyway, anyway Genji continues to have no job other than sleeping with ladies after telling them poetry.
Speaker 0: What a job though.
Speaker 1: of everything I've read up to this point the funniest moment still is from Moderates like it's still in the first third of the book But it just stands out of the moment when he's trying to woo that one woman and he's incognito and then he sees someone else in the area who's also incognito and he Realizes that that dude is trying to woo the same woman and then they bump into each other and they're both like what the fuck?
Speaker 1: Are you doing?
Speaker 1: what the fuck are you doing?
Speaker 1: Nobody can see either of us here and they sneak back into the court and pretend they'd been there the whole time Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I think that's the funniest thing that's happened in the book so far.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not exactly a comedy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but funny things like that happen.
Speaker 1: So Outerwear, I heard you had some trouble with your rain jacket yesterday.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, so my strategy because I was going to the tennis and didn't know the situation there.
Speaker 0: apparently You know, I could have.
Speaker 0: just you know, I was like, well, let's not bring any bags Let's not even bring a camera with a big lens.
Speaker 0: Who knows what they're gonna let me do, right?
Speaker 0: Let's go with as minimal things as possible.
Speaker 0: I know it's gonna rain Yeah, but I'm not gonna bring an umbrella because I know you're usually not allowed to open it at the tennis because it blocks people's.
Speaker 0: Let's not even bring umbrellas.
Speaker 0: Let's just wear our raincoats.
Speaker 0: They'll keep us dry if we get rained on.
Speaker 0: well, we don't have anything on us.
Speaker 0: So who gives a shit if we get wet?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: We'll just.
Speaker 0: we'll just walk home wet and then change we get home And well, you know in a raincoat will keep us dry enough that it won't be intolerable.
Speaker 0: So my raincoat that I wore was basically, you know this $20 effectively sheet of plastic.
Speaker 0: ish It's like a synthetic cloth and inside the synthetic cloth is basically like a rubbery coating.
Speaker 0: You know, I got a Uniqlo for like 20.
Speaker 1: so I have one question for you is it slightly stretchy Or is it completely rigid?
Speaker 1: Can you stretch it a little or not at all?
Speaker 0: I Don't know I had to go.
Speaker 0: I'm just curious.
Speaker 1: go look is that sounds like cheapo soft shell?
Speaker 0: So, you know, we went to the tennis and surprisingly didn't get really wet at the tennis And then we went out to eat dinner with some friends, right?
Speaker 0: We got a little bit rain on the way when we were walking to the food place to the restaurant.
Speaker 0: But you know, it was fine walking into the restaurant.
Speaker 0: But when we were at the restaurant outdoor dining, but with a roof over us right to keep us dry, but still outdoors It was so, you know acceptable.
Speaker 0: That's when the big rain came.
Speaker 0: And you know, we waited to leave the restaurant until the raid died down a little bit and then we left.
Speaker 0: But of course on the walk the rain picked up Came down.
Speaker 0: We basically got completely soaked and my shoes are completely soaked.
Speaker 0: I expected that I knew that was gonna happen Short-soaked.
Speaker 0: I expected that before I left the house.
Speaker 0: I was okay with that.
Speaker 0: You know, it's just fine with all those situations.
Speaker 0: but while I'm walking My shirt not that not the raincoat thing the shirt that was completely covered by the raincoat I felt water going down my back and I'm like how the fuck is this water getting in there?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Yeah water has gotten in there all I've been in the ring already.
Speaker 1: The answer is from the very beginning when you said that.
Speaker 1: when you said the words, I'm gonna quote you.
Speaker 0: Yeah Somehow my shirt was getting wet.
Speaker 0: even you know, it didn't it?
Speaker 0: this thing kept me dry for quite a while But not forever.
Speaker 0: eventually I was getting wet.
Speaker 0: So what happened is when I got onto the train.
Speaker 0: finally when we were nice and dry on the subway train I Realized hey because it's a blue.
Speaker 0: It's a blue coat.
Speaker 0: There were like these blue specks on my hands and I'm like, what the fuck is this?
Speaker 0: Thing was like fucking disintegrating from like the inside into little bits and then the water was getting through.
Speaker 0: I was like this thing is totally shot.
Speaker 0: I just got to throw it out.
Speaker 0: It's useless now.
Speaker 1: Yeah Like it sucks that.
Speaker 1: the reality of the world is this.
Speaker 1: but especially with outerwear like sports outerwear or weather protection outerwear The more expensive ones are better but not just are they better up to a certain point.
Speaker 1: up to a certain point obviously but they are better to a Shocking degree like So for example, I I wear like a couple hundred dollars ski jacket a hard shell like serious a normal price.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that is not.
Speaker 1: it's not waterproof at all.
Speaker 1: You want an actual waterproof ski jacket.
Speaker 1: You're spending middle 500 plus now 800 just for the top and it's uninsulated.
Speaker 1: Then you have to buy all the other layers separately and then buy the bib and the overall separately as well.
Speaker 1: it's like the Gulf between pretty good and Actually, like fully good is so wide with this kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: Well also what's you know?
Speaker 0: good it's you know Good enough right for what you're doing.
Speaker 0: It's like you can pay for more and more levels But really the $200 level for walking around is gonna be perfect for anybody.
Speaker 1: Yeah But like for skiing.
Speaker 1: if you're skiing like a lot or doing like out like backcountry skiing.
Speaker 1: That's $200 is not good enough because it's dangerous to use something so weak compared to a quote.
Speaker 1: real solution.
Speaker 0: So yeah, it really depends on the more you pay the more you pay right you get.
Speaker 0: a you're warmer Yeah, B your dryer.
Speaker 0: Yeah C you're gonna be less like sweaty and shit cuz you're gonna get like some nice, you know, like Breathe more.
Speaker 1: it's like design better.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's breathe.
Speaker 0: it breathes better or wicks or who knows what it's.
Speaker 1: usually but not always it'll last longer because I can talk about.
Speaker 1: one Of the jacket I own is extremely expensive.
Speaker 1: It's also extremely fragile But it serves a very different use case because it weighs nothing and I can get arrested.
Speaker 1: I can compress it into a ball about the size and shape of my cell phone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, when you pay more you're getting more durability, right?
Speaker 0: You're getting more comfort.
Speaker 0: You're getting better Design, it looks cooler right more fashion.
Speaker 0: You're getting you know possible, you know crumple ability like rim just said.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're also getting lighter, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you could pay, you know, like get a really warm coat that for really cheap.
Speaker 0: That's gonna keep you nice and toasty all winter and but it'll be like big puffy boy like poof poof.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can also get something that's like ultra thin and weighs nothing.
Speaker 0: It feels like I'm wearing nothing at all But somehow it's keeping you warm like it's a big puffy coat or a blanket.
Speaker 0: like how the hell is it doing?
Speaker 0: well they They Filled it with u.s.
Speaker 0: Dollars, that's what's happening.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's right.
Speaker 0: You're insulating with with pictures of dead.
Speaker 1: the listener chimed in like Scott strikes me as a raincoat kind of guy which is true.
Speaker 1: cuz what my first reaction when you said oh, I got wet my raincoat is that I Personally hate raincoats.
Speaker 1: like the idea that I would wear a coat to keep myself dry just seems silly.
Speaker 1: I had to use an umbrella or I get wet and raise my umbrella - No, well because I grew up in a place.
Speaker 0: you see you you changed your mind.
Speaker 1: Yeah you know why.
Speaker 1: cuz I live in a place where I walk everywhere and I live in New York.
Speaker 1: when I used to not live in New York when I lived in Michigan or even when I lived in the suburbs, I Never needed to go outside in the rain.
Speaker 1: And when I did I only really needed to get to my car.
Speaker 1: I just run for it Like I wouldn't get that wet not wet enough to matter.
Speaker 1: when I grew up like no one ever used an umbrella they Someone would like drop you off in front of the mall and then like one person in the family would have one giant umbrella just To get themselves in.
Speaker 1: no one else have had an umbrella or even owned one half the time We had umbrellas.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we didn't.
Speaker 1: it's just a thing in Michigan I guess.
Speaker 1: but I guess my point is a raincoat that Sands umbrella can keep you connects.
Speaker 0: Thursday umbrellas.
Speaker 0: All right next keep going seems.
Speaker 1: Oh, I got opinions on umbrellas.
Speaker 1: They got that fancy when I imported.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll do it.
Speaker 1: Not now That umbrella is so good.
Speaker 1: But yeah, not now.
Speaker 1: Restrain how it's how much I love that fucking umbrella that I paid $100 to import from Europe.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I was hundred dollars in import plus what it actually cost.
Speaker 1: It was a. this was a expensive of a brand Mm-hmm, and it's the second one because the first one I bought got stolen anyway, so If I wear a coat that in driving rain would keep the top of me dry but the rest of me gets wet I feel like there's zero value in that.
Speaker 1: if my pants are wet, I don't care if the rest of me is wet and rain gear that would keep my body effectively completely dry is Stupid unless I'm out in the backcountry hiking.
Speaker 1: We're away from civilization.
Speaker 1: Like I'm not willing obviously because Gear that can keep you completely dry.
Speaker 1: It kind of like the security paradox of more security means more pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: More dryness means less comfort.
Speaker 1: That's just how it works.
Speaker 1: You want to be completely dry?
Speaker 1: You're wearing something that hermetically seals your body.
Speaker 1: Guess what that shit sucks to wear.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I wasn't interesting on you Really interesting to being completely dry.
Speaker 0: that's not right.
Speaker 0: It's like I bet you like I said when I left the house I sacrificed my shoes socks.
Speaker 0: I wore shorts because I knew that jeans would get soggy and uncomfortable even though a little bit cold.
Speaker 1: So you understood your threat profile like what you were seeking here?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like I just need enough of me to be dry.
Speaker 0: Right, you know so that I can you know walk around if I'm.
Speaker 0: just if I was just out there with you know Nothing, it would be like that would be horrible Uncomfortable and Cold.
Speaker 1: and because that then it gets into because outerwear from one definition could just mean whatever the furthest out layer of clothes you have on is and If you go to any clothing store.
Speaker 0: if you click on the outerwear section You're gonna see raincoats.
Speaker 0: winter coats had a little like jackets hoodies Or outerwear hoodie some.
Speaker 0: sometimes you'll see hoodies in there.
Speaker 0: Sometimes you'll see it in a different section But usually when they say outerwear they mean jackets and occasionally it'll be something like snow pants depending on the website.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that might qualify but usually it's various jackets for different situations, right,
Speaker 1: but I guess what I'm getting out there is that I Wear if I'm gonna get wet like if I go outside hiking like I don't bring rain gear Even if I'm going on a very long hike or camping expedition.
Speaker 1: What I bring is I wear outerwear and clothes that are themselves expensive and beyond the scope of the show That are wicking and designed to get wet and dry quickly and I just let myself get wet.
Speaker 1: But if I were not wearing that specialized clothing Which I don't want to wear in normal circumstances Like I wouldn't wear that at a pecs because that kind of clothing has other problems.
Speaker 1: It smells bad way earlier than normal clothes.
Speaker 1: Like it's harder to wash.
Speaker 1: It's more expensive.
Speaker 1: It wears out faster.
Speaker 1: It's not that fashionable like.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of other reasons there.
Speaker 1: But if I was wearing like a packs t-shirt and jeans and I got soaked.
Speaker 1: Absolute misery.
Speaker 1: that is that is one of the most miserable situations you can be in.
Speaker 0: I mean forgetting, you know the current world situation where you know A lot of jackets are like inherited from the sporting outdoors world and brought down into the fashion world.
Speaker 0: You look at how many people in you know, New York City the fashionable thing is to wear a Canada Goose jacket Which is originally meant for like trekking around in the Arctic.
Speaker 0: $500 like a fashion statement.
Speaker 1: Yeah 500 but contrast that because the jacket is still aimed as a fashion accessory.
Speaker 1: $500 doesn't even buy you close to the jacket.
Speaker 1: You need to go trekking around in the Arctic.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean people did go trekking around the Arctic with those jackets.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah company the same jackets.
Speaker 0: But obviously if you're doing it now you would buy a higher-end model from that company.
Speaker 1: Like I. just it's a thought that runs through my head every time I ski because I put on all this outerwear like jackets and gloves and everything and I Just and I don't even have the most expensive stuff.
Speaker 1: Like I said, I use a normal ass ski jacket I use like crappy.
Speaker 0: you have better.
Speaker 0: you have better than what rich people had last century.
Speaker 1: Yep like I have better equipment on me to walk through the snow to buy groceries in the winter than Anyone in the HMS Terror and Erebus expedition had when they went to the pole and died.
Speaker 0: Yep, pretty much but yeah, you know forgetting about that sort of jacket, right?
Speaker 0: there's all kinds of other kinds and the purpose of most jackets really if you think about it is Temporary shirt.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's like you put a shirt on your body to you know Just cover your torso when you're going outside because that's a normal thing to do and you can't really take that off.
Speaker 0: But sometimes right you're gonna be going you're gonna be leaving your clear wardrobe behind and venturing into the world And you're going to encounter Different temperature.
Speaker 0: right if you're just going to a single place with one temperature, right?
Speaker 0: I'm going for a walk outside You know then you can you could.
Speaker 0: you don't need a jacket like this temporary shirt.
Speaker 0: You could just shirt yourself appropriately with permanent shirts or at least, you know the kind you're not gonna take off While you're on that walk and then come home.
Speaker 0: The jacket is because I'm going to go outside and it's gonna be cold.
Speaker 0: So I'll put this extra shirt on but it has a big ol zipper in the front or buttons or something.
Speaker 0: And then when I get where I'm going, I'll take it off and that won't be getting naked.
Speaker 0: And when I leave but it's like people, you know, it's something everyone just inherently knows But you don't really think about it in terms, you know in that in that way because it's such a natural thing You know examine it closely.
Speaker 0: But like that's what a jacket is the temporary like plus shirt that you you know can take on and off Appropriately at different locations to adjust your temperature level.
Speaker 1: Hmm our case in point.
Speaker 1: But it can be inverted like so I Pat and a PAX.
Speaker 1: the jacket is just like PAX East.
Speaker 1: in the winter It's just to get me to that building and then the jacket is just a liability.
Speaker 1: I don't want to carry it with me so I can hang it up somewhere I can leave it somewhere and come back to it.
Speaker 0: The coat hook was invented.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the coat hook or the coat check.
Speaker 1: I I always I do actually really like using coat checks and I find a lot of people avoid them.
Speaker 1: but the caveat is Any large event the coat check is more trouble than it's worth.
Speaker 0: It depends on how the coach at PAX that coat check is a fucking nightmare.
Speaker 0: I'm so always if I if I'm thinking about a coat check if I see one and it would be advantageous to me I scope it first to see how it's operating and I try to predict like is it going to be a shit show?
Speaker 0: when I Try to leave, you know, then I that and I make my decision, you know How shitty will it be if I have to hold on to this coat the whole time?
Speaker 0: Etc.
Speaker 1: And then also there's another point here.
Speaker 1: This is a very different situation from the things that I usually do of going out to the wilderness or doing some crazy sport where it's all about layering like.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna layer to a PAX with like multiple different levels of like shirt outer shirt fourth shirt jacket because I don't need that many levels of clothing and comfort to switch between.
Speaker 1: and The key of a jacket is that it's very easy to take on and put it to put on and take off Compared to like a secondary base layer that I have to like peel up over my head or deal with in some way.
Speaker 0: I get to think about.
Speaker 0: think about the layers when it comes to not outdoors enos, right?
Speaker 0: But think about the layers for formal wear, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like you got a shirt right.
Speaker 0: the dress shirt That's the.
Speaker 0: that's the thing.
Speaker 0: The dress shirt is the thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you usually have an undershirt under the dress shirt to protect the shirt, right?
Speaker 0: It's a shirt that makes you look good But you put a shirt under it so that you a can't see through the dress shirts material to your hairy body or whatever Your body looks like and B to keep your sweat from messing up the dress shirt.
Speaker 0: It's a dressy shirt.
Speaker 0: Then you got a dress coat that goes over the dress shirt.
Speaker 0: You can take it off and you will usually but it looks a lot nicer if you have that coat on right like your tuxedo Coat or whatever.
Speaker 0: so, you know, you'll have that on during your ceremonies and whatever.
Speaker 0: But you might take it off when you're sitting down to eat dinner.
Speaker 1: Go to any wedding, but it's everyone all the all the all the people who wear suits are wearing suits And once they sit down for dinner 90% of those suits get unbuttoned and they're hung over the back of the chair.
Speaker 1: and now you only got a vest on Exactly, and then let's not even talk about the vest right?
Speaker 0: But here's the thing.
Speaker 0: What are the kind of bonds?
Speaker 0: Well, that's not a part of the jacket.
Speaker 0: So the jacket right, but this is a dress jacket.
Speaker 0: It's like a sport jacket or a suit coat or who knows we all tuxedo coat something like that.
Speaker 0: That is not.
Speaker 0: I mean it does keep you pretty warm.
Speaker 0: And if it's a little chilly outside like in the fall, that's perfect.
Speaker 0: That's sufficient.
Speaker 0: But if it's gonna rain or something, well you this is such a dressy coat.
Speaker 0: It's not just a coat That's.
Speaker 1: you can't let water touch that thing.
Speaker 0: So now you need like the trench coat or something now right to go over that shit.
Speaker 0: Right and that trench coat is what the coat check was for.
Speaker 0: Yeah So that when you show up at the Broadway show or the dinner party or whatever the fuck it the concert at the opera Whatever the fuck it is, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you're gonna be wearing your fancy jacket while you're sitting and watching or doing or whatever because that's what looks good.
Speaker 0: But you had to wear this raincoat that protected your dress coat and you don't want to bring that around with you.
Speaker 0: It's all soaking wet and they didn't have better technology than trench coat in 1940 50 something.
Speaker 0: but also that is what you give to the to the coat check.
Speaker 1: so less fancy jackets like a sport jacket or A blazer blazer or the top of a leisure suit like that kind of stuff Partly because of my job and also just because I like them.
Speaker 1: like I wear those a lot in my daily life like when I'm Like pre-covid times like when I'm going out.
Speaker 1: But those are different because they're designed to be worn every day.
Speaker 1: So Until it's too cold to do this usually in the winter.
Speaker 1: I don't wear a coat.
Speaker 1: I just wear a heavy sport jacket on my way to and from work with like Scarf and that's it.
Speaker 1: Like I don't actually wear like a coat.
Speaker 1: I actually don't own that many coats.
Speaker 1: Like if I look at what I own I have one Insulated trench coat.
Speaker 1: that is my winter coat.
Speaker 1: I fucking love that thing.
Speaker 1: trench coats long coats are the best if you're not doing a sport Because they keep your legs warm too.
Speaker 1: They hold in so much heat like.
Speaker 1: it's hard for me to imagine not living my life without a long coat in the winter.
Speaker 1: It's my favorite kind of coat.
Speaker 1: I used to wear dusters, but that's cuz.
Speaker 1: I was awesome in high school.
Speaker 1: I do like dusters, but the long insulated jacket is what I actually need.
Speaker 0: Let's talk about some like different coat styles, right?
Speaker 0: So one coat style.
Speaker 0: I actually like a lot Is like the bomber jacket style where it's like, oh, I like those in middle school.
Speaker 1: I'm not a big fan anymore.
Speaker 0: It's a little bit insulated, right?
Speaker 0: It's kind of styling.
Speaker 1: you can really puffy like.
Speaker 1: you have a big puff around you.
Speaker 0: Sometimes they're puffy, but sometimes they're not so puffy.
Speaker 0: It depends on which one you get.
Speaker 0: There's various levels of puff.
Speaker 0: They have those like a ribbed sort of cuffs around the arm the arms usually in the waist area.
Speaker 0: It's sort of keep it tight.
Speaker 0: So winds not coming in there and stuff.
Speaker 0: the thing I don't like about those is Pulling up the sleeves is kind of meh on them.
Speaker 0: Some of them have zip-off sleeves actually, but not too many.
Speaker 1: the only bomber jackets I actually did really like and still kind of like are the ones that look like what they came from an actual bomber jacket.
Speaker 0: Yeah, most of them look like that.
Speaker 1: There seemed to be a whole bunch of fashion jackets called bomber jackets that look nothing like bomber jackets.
Speaker 1: Lot of people are calling things bomber jackets.
Speaker 1: that I would not consider a bomber jacket Usually.
Speaker 0: what the the one that William Gibson made famous is the one that you know is really popular and then most people are modeling it After that one, right?
Speaker 1: So but now I'm talking about the ones like the traditional.
Speaker 1: one is Brown with fur or fake fur around like the cuffs and around the neck and it zips up in the front and it's puffy and A lot of leather and that's pretty much it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the fur Is optional sometimes right.
Speaker 1: the fuzzy ones Yeah, not that I would ever wear a ferg like don't get me wrong, right?
Speaker 0: But the thing is it's sort of like it.
Speaker 0: those are sort of like these in-between Kind of jackets, right because you know, you can actually keep that one on as long as you're not, you know Sweating like crazy, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you can you know, keep that on and it's almost occupying the sort of sport coat zone right where it's it's as opposed to the You know hang up zone but for normal everyday stuff and not for fancy stuff.
Speaker 0: Yep, right There's a few other coats that sort of occupy that same space like like some parkas and stuff.
Speaker 0: You can wear them right and just keep them on all the time and it doesn't look like why are you wearing your coat?
Speaker 0: Even though we're inside now It's like it's.
Speaker 0: you know It's almost like a hoodie where it's still acceptable to keep wearing it Even when you're in the thing.
Speaker 0: There's other coats.
Speaker 0: if you wear like one of those big old pea coats and you show up and you don't take it off And you're sitting in the restaurant with your pea coat on without like those big buttons with the anchors on Even if you unbutton it It's like you look really silly.
Speaker 0: if you keep that shit on you get your North Face coat.
Speaker 0: if you sit down at the restaurant Or in the theater and you still have that on and you haven't taken it off people would be like, are you cold?
Speaker 0: Are you all right?
Speaker 0: What's wrong?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I Have worn my North Face ski jacket indoors at conventions in the past because sometimes that AC is sometimes it's cold.
Speaker 0: Yeah, then you'd be like, yeah, it's cold.
Speaker 1: People are constantly being like why you were in your winter coat.
Speaker 1: It's like what the fuck is wrong with you.
Speaker 1: Do you not feel this?
Speaker 0: Yeah, there are some but there's other kinds of coats right that you can that you can keep wearing and it's like Oh, that doesn't look.
Speaker 0: you don't look ridiculous keeping that on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so Interestingly is because I wear blazers and sport jackets so much.
Speaker 1: I don't own a single one of though what you would want that kind of coat that you described not one.
Speaker 0: See the problem I have is actually I own a couple.
Speaker 0: I think I got like one or two, right?
Speaker 0: but the problem is is if I want to wear it as a You know inside coat like not take it off Then you could end up looking silly if say you go to you're going to work in the year 2021.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you went to work every day and you changed all your clothes every day But you had like some bomber jacket and you just wore it all day every day at work It'd be like why you always wearing the same.
Speaker 1: and the difference is I can wear the same blazer for weeks on end Because people don't notice that it fades into the background.
Speaker 1: the shirt under it changes every day.
Speaker 1: the pants combined with it change every day So it's.
Speaker 0: you can also see the shirt a lot more through us Big the deep V going on in the front, right?
Speaker 1: Exactly So.
Speaker 1: so but yeah, I don't own anything like but my but I go straight.
Speaker 1: I go between hoodie and above hoodie.
Speaker 0: It's like I don't have anything until I get to but to which I Several different coats that are appropriate for wearing and not taking off Right is a lot of money and a lot of closet space.
Speaker 1: that Actually is what I was about to say because that is why I don't own any of the coats you described like not one.
Speaker 1: I have so many highly specialized like sporting outdoor coats that I don't really have room to have more.
Speaker 1: So I try to use those instead of what you described as a more normal jacket.
Speaker 1: So I go from my coats.
Speaker 1: go from lightest to heaviest Summit jacket, which I'll get back to after that.
Speaker 1: It's hoodie or fleece like but you're just like me my base layers for skiing and stuff.
Speaker 1: the next step after that is like when my ski jacket and the next step beyond that is my Fully insulated trench coat and I got nothing else.
Speaker 0: His is the list of coats I got right.
Speaker 0: actually actually I might have more coats than you.
Speaker 1: Oh, you definitely have more coats than me because my coats are few and expensive and bulky.
Speaker 0: Some of mine are at least a little bit expensive not now and probably I don't.
Speaker 0: probably don't have a single coat That's more expensive than your most expensive coat, but I have several hundred dollars.
Speaker 1: I one way I can cheat my most expensive coat.
Speaker 1: I paid very little money for because it had a slight defect and I got it for like nothing.
Speaker 0: clearance sale Good deal Yeah, so assume forgetting the things that I have abandoned and don't wear anymore, right?
Speaker 0: That I might still have somewhere like packs hoodies I've abandoned.
Speaker 0: right?
Speaker 0: I have two hoodies now that I actually wear.
Speaker 0: They're basically the same hoodie, but one is lighter than the other for different seasons.
Speaker 0: So there you go.
Speaker 0: I got two hoodies, right?
Speaker 0: I then I have.
Speaker 0: I guess I'm gonna have to rip.
Speaker 0: I had two raincoats.
Speaker 0: I had the one that died the pla- it was basically just a sheet of plastic for 20 bucks And I had like a real kind of raincoat.
Speaker 0: the problem with my real kind of raincoat is it's still pretty good But it hasn't like an insulating layer which works very well.
Speaker 0: But sometimes it rains and you're not it's not cold and then it sucks to wear that coat because way too hot in it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, also the sleeves on it are too short and you can't make sleeves longer and my arms are long.
Speaker 0: so I think I'm gonna abandon the broken plastic sheet and donate the good raincoat and Just get something that's a raincoat that fits and have that be the raincoat.
Speaker 0: So raincoat.
Speaker 0: then I Have a special like ultra thin, you know Plasticy raincoat that is only good for biking if you wear it when you're not biking you look like a dingus.
Speaker 0: But if you're biking in the rain, it's incredible.
Speaker 0: like you'll you can actually bike in the rain with this thing.
Speaker 1: I've been thinking about getting something like that because it wasn't cheap.
Speaker 0: It wasn't the cheapest.
Speaker 0: It's just like a sheet of plastic kind of situation, but I assume it's gonna last my whole life and it's amazing Biking stuff the same way.
Speaker 1: I approach my ski stuff.
Speaker 0: It sounds like I have a second biking only coat.
Speaker 0: It is for biking in the cold.
Speaker 0: I can't bike in like fucking snowy winter with it But like I can bike in like, you know close to freezing as long as it's not snowing or anything.
Speaker 0: It's not like ultra below zero if it's that warm.
Speaker 0: if you wear this while biking and the problem is most coats You wear while biking you start to get all sweaty inside this one.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: You feel great while biking if it's cold.
Speaker 1: That's what that's actually what I do with biking.
Speaker 1: I don't have a biking specific one, but guess what, but all the kit I use for skiing.
Speaker 1: not the pants obviously But like the top part Perfect for biking except it's less aerodynamic than a bike specific solution, but it's perfectly comfortable.
Speaker 0: Yeah, alright, so then so I got the two biking coats one for just it's wet out But it's warm and the other four it's cold, but it's not wet.
Speaker 0: I don't really have a cold.
Speaker 0: if it's cold and wet I don't bike so I don't have I don't need a third biking coat and I don't have to combine the two either.
Speaker 1: The listeners are also.
Speaker 1: they've all devolved into still suit.
Speaker 1: That's the way to go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have a bomber ish kind of jacket that I can wear.
Speaker 0: You know when it's like a little bit cold like you're going maybe apple picking or something, right?
Speaker 0: It's not too cold out You know, you're not freezing but obviously it's too cold to go with no coat.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know kind of in-between deal Right see in that situation.
Speaker 1: I either wear a hoodie or wear my hiking gear.
Speaker 0: Yeah, then I got two more.
Speaker 0: I got two wintry coats I used to have in the old back in the day.
Speaker 0: I used to always buy a North Face kind of thing, but I got tired of that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so what I have.
Speaker 0: so what I have now is I have one that's sort of like a pea coat kind of ish situation.
Speaker 0: You know what the buttons as zipper end, you know, whatever in a hood that you can detach, you know It's that same kind of material and basically it doesn't matter if it's cold as long as it's not snowing because obviously there's no real Waterproofness to it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's right.
Speaker 0: But as if it's just cold, it's great It keeps you way warm in there right deep pockets nicely It's you know great, but then I have another one that's basically the it's snowing jacket Which is actually two jackets one that goes inside the other one so I could separate them and use just half for half.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all ski jackets are like that.
Speaker 1: Usually the ski jacket is just a shell and you zip an insulator into it and then you do more and more layers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is I think it's the one this is technically called like a three-way jacket But I pretty much only wear if it's cold and snowing.
Speaker 1: Yeah it's well because what I found is those jackets like my ski jacket.
Speaker 1: I can wear the whole thing or I can unzip the insulating layer out of it and wear it just as a shell or Yeah
Speaker 0: The problem even if I tip thing is this one Even if you know there are ones where the insulating layer is like where all the insulation is this one.
Speaker 0: Some of the insulation is in both layers.
Speaker 0: if I just try to wear the outside only it's like you're still pretty warm.
Speaker 0: Right, if you wear the inside only it's like well, why don't I just wear the bomber jacket?
Speaker 1: Yeah, my jacket cuz it's fancier.
Speaker 1: The outside is completely on insulated.
Speaker 1: I can just use it as a shell and mix and match what I want to use inside.
Speaker 1: But the inside part is also a jacket that is perfectly capable of being worn on its own and it's actually great for That mid-tier situation.
Speaker 1: The only reason I don't use it for that purpose and and fill that gap in my wardrobe is that I use this jacket to ski and I ski a lot and it It looks grody as shit from the grease of my body and the sweat and just mess of skiing.
Speaker 1: And I mean when I went to her I'm cleaning we'll make that thing look like I'm not a hobo.
Speaker 0: so that is When we went to college, I knew it was gonna be snowy in Rochester.
Speaker 0: That's what I brought with me freshman year.
Speaker 0: I bought like the fanciest Gore Tex like outer shell and I got the fanciest inside I mean for Rochester.
Speaker 1: that might not save your life on the quarter-mile.
Speaker 0: But that's that's what I had for years at RIT and I you know I only did died because I buy it was killed by Rochester.
Speaker 0: I had the fanciest thing that you know, but I realized when I left Rochester I don't really need that anymore.
Speaker 0: That was that's not necessary now.
Speaker 1: Yep So yeah, you have way more jackets than me, but we both have a lot of highly specialized jackets.
Speaker 0: Cuz yeah, I mean if you do specialize I guess I you know, I'm not even counting like.
Speaker 0: I have one suit.
Speaker 1: I was about to say I have more jacket.
Speaker 0: I have one jacket.
Speaker 0: That's not a part of a suit.
Speaker 1: I have more jackets than you if we count Blazers and like leisure suits and all that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I have one two, three, four five two.
Speaker 1: I have 11 sport jackets That I wear regularly and in the non-covid times, obviously, I might have two suits, but only one of them I think is wearable.
Speaker 1: I have 11 sport jackets and I have three dress jackets.
Speaker 1: I Also have a seersucker that don't wear much anymore.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I guess I'm gonna downsize raincoats.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna get rid of two and add one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that'll be good.
Speaker 1: So the jacket I have that you don't have is the one that it look Marmot made it but they don't make it anymore.
Speaker 1: I'm actually googling around this.
Speaker 1: so I got this.
Speaker 1: I was in Salt Lake City years and years and years ago I was actually out in Park City like the ski resort But I was there to mountain bike in the off season.
Speaker 1: long story short I had a whole day with nothing to do and nothing was open before I could fly home.
Speaker 1: So I wander around this town and I find this sport shop.
Speaker 0: No, these are reasonable prices Marmot.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Marmot is.
Speaker 1: Marmot is not to turn this into an ad but Marmot is The best like jacket where you're gonna get for a price that you Scott would consider reasonable.
Speaker 1: That is comparable in quality to the Arcturix stuff.
Speaker 1: That is just insane quality.
Speaker 0: Let's see rain rain.
Speaker 1: I mean where I every Marmot Outerwear item I've ever bought has been utterly phenomenal for the dollars.
Speaker 1: I paid.
Speaker 0: All right, let's check out these raincoats.
Speaker 1: So the thing I have they don't make anymore.
Speaker 1: They haven't made it for a long time.
Speaker 1: I bought it from this shop that had a like discount rack of Clearance items that were unsaleable or had defects or things like an outlet store and I paid $80 for this thing.
Speaker 1: it retailed for four or five hundred dollars, but It is so it's that that's that tiny jacket.
Speaker 1: I described it's so small.
Speaker 1: It's the size of my cell phone.
Speaker 1: I can just wad it into a ball.
Speaker 1: It's sort of.
Speaker 1: it's waterproof But that's not what it's used for.
Speaker 1: like you couldn't use this raincoat because the underarms are completely vented So you can just like vents your sweat out of them.
Speaker 1: these jackets are used for exactly two things.
Speaker 1: It's a highly specialized piece of basically outdoor survival gear.
Speaker 1: you carry it in your pack and you put it on when you're summiting a mountain Not a not a like super high mountain like Kilimanjaro, but like a normal moderate-sized mountain.
Speaker 1: It's just this extra layer you put on only at the top when you're making your summit approach.
Speaker 1: It's too much to wear on the whole trip But it's like a windbreaker you put on at the very end and the other use for it is it's an emergency layer That weighs nothing that you can whip out if you suddenly need a jacket and you literally have no Room weight space or anything to carry a jacket.
Speaker 1: like.
Speaker 1: I could put this jacket in my back pocket out of packs and just whip It out if suddenly it gets too cold late at night.
Speaker 1: You've seen me wear it.
Speaker 1: It's that shiny blue shirt.
Speaker 0: Oh the show's gone on way too long Yes, but I guess the final word on jacket is that one day we'll have some awesome cyberpunk.
Speaker 0: You know you'll just you'll just right you'll just have.
Speaker 0: you'll have cyber skin And you'll just change the fucking skin and you want to worry about that.
Speaker 0: and then your clothing can just be all style if you Even have clothing.
Speaker 0: so and that'll be great.
Speaker 0: yeah Until then you got to own a hundred different jackets to shift your form.
Speaker 1: yeah Alright, and if it is watching the stream.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna see.
Speaker 1: if anyone wants to play quick one.
Speaker 1: tonight I will probably be around and I'm happy to play quick one with a bunch of you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm gonna eat food, and maybe I'll also play quick one.
Speaker 1: We've got some people to play quick one.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website At front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night
Speaker 1: and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are How do you mean uncle Ellen shows and gives you adrenaline trimmer Chris Reimer Clinton Walton Dex Finn?
Speaker 1: Just like a dude guy.
Speaker 1: kashaya 85 Rebecca done review medical 34 powers Ryan parents that marriage and Shervin on her old Taylor Brown.
Speaker 1: Under program law ad pours ad threat open seed.
Speaker 1: right you hold the key to my heart and a bunch of people who do not Want me to say their names?
Speaker 1: Yeah, playing some quake as soon as I finish editing the show together.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: What can I say?
Speaker 1: I got a long weekend.
Speaker 1: I took a day off because I long ago planted for packs.
Speaker 1: I didn't go to pack.
Speaker 1: So I got a long weekend and we're gonna some geek night stuff gonna play some quake with all of you.
Speaker 1: and Yeah, I will let you all know if I get mega team fortress specifically to work with multiplayer in quake one.
Speaker 1: because if I can make that work, uh We'll see.
Speaker 1: This is actually very important to a panel.
Speaker 1: I'm working on that.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty excited about but it's gonna take a while.
Speaker 1: It's a panel I might do solo because it's a topic Scott doesn't seem to have a lot of thoughts on but we'll see.
Speaker 1: But anyway for now I leave you with.