Speaker 0: It's Tuesday April 6th 2021.
Speaker 0: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We are talking about JRPGs the genre.
Speaker 1: let's do this.
Speaker 0: So we didn't want to review the game.
Speaker 0: We just played and actually I'm looking at the Final seconds of this game, but we're playing another train game right now called 1828.
Speaker 1: Let's just become train nights.
Speaker 1: forget this geek nights business
Speaker 0: I mean, I feel like a big reason why we're playing so many train games is because we're stuck inside at home all day while we're working and Like this website
Speaker 1: happened to come into existence at the exact right time
Speaker 0: we happen to have a group of people who already knew the deal with train games and They really suit themselves to asynchronous play far more than a lot of other types of games for a lot of reasons We talked about in a recent episode on asynchronous play.
Speaker 0: So, you know, but all I want to say is if I guess it we could be a geek bite this 1828 one Intrigues me quite a bit and I think it's equal in my eyes now to 1817 in terms of want to play it again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this 80 this is a good one.
Speaker 1: This 1828 I would recommend.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like I think the and well 12 reviewed at some point.
Speaker 0: We just don't want to do a million train reviews all in a row and I've got to play it again.
Speaker 0: But the thing I'll say is that the sign one of the signs we've noticed of a good train game compared to a mediocre one Or just an okay one is if after the first play We all go whoa, and then the next time the same group of people play we play it radically differently.
Speaker 0: That's usually a sign that it's one that's got some staying power.
Speaker 0: Mmm, if there's one like 1889 I like but every like second time I played it I did the exact same thing.
Speaker 0: I tried to do the first time just better third time fourth time every time it almost always goes the same basic way, but this one looks like it can go in a lot of different directions.
Speaker 0: and Like going back through my early moves in this game.
Speaker 0: What the fuck was wrong with rim?
Speaker 0: Why did he?
Speaker 0: why did he wait to par Michigan Central?
Speaker 0: Like that was a mistake?
Speaker 1: This one I mean how I didn't understand what the I didn't realize the 8e wasn't just an eight train.
Speaker 0: I love how you looked at in a 3d and thought oh that D. Yeah, you understood the D. That's a big deal.
Speaker 0: We talked a lot about the D But at no point where you were like, why does that other train have any?
Speaker 0: I guess it's not.
Speaker 1: I did.
Speaker 1: I said why I thought to myself why is there an e that must mean something?
Speaker 1: and I'm like, yeah I'm not gonna look it up.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 1: I'll just do play the game and then it's like oops Actually, it was a big deal.
Speaker 1: I messed it up.
Speaker 0: Well, not like the 1817. we played with the listener where I literally just forgot that outstanding market shares dropped stock price at the end of the SR in that one and made a catastrophic error.
Speaker 0: Yep, what I should have done is mutually shorted and that would have been fun.
Speaker 0: But instead I was like, oh, I'm fine.
Speaker 0: He can't rust any trains.
Speaker 0: This is gonna be fine.
Speaker 0: And then when the OR starts and I saw that stock price drop.
Speaker 0: I was like, oh, yeah 1817 fuck.
Speaker 0: Anyway Anyway, there is a decent amount of gaming news But we're gonna start with.
Speaker 0: is that PAX East?
Speaker 0: this is officially announced.
Speaker 0: There is gonna be no PAX East this year as we assume.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: I didn't see that coming.
Speaker 1: Whoa, what a surprise.
Speaker 0: Better call James Randi.
Speaker 0: We got an Nostradamus here But uh, you're gonna need an Nostradamus to call James Randi.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Rest in peace.
Speaker 0: You were a cool dude, but pexis.
Speaker 0: There's gonna be no pexis this year because April May probably June like.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna speculate about the rest of the year in terms of like odds of a convention happening, but Spring and early summer is just off the table.
Speaker 0: Like it is too soon Like things there's things are still evolving.
Speaker 0: I applaud packs for making these decision and they have a statement that we'll just link to.
Speaker 0: But also they're gonna do another packs online because it actually went really well and whatever that looks like we're gonna be there for it.
Speaker 1: All right, sure.
Speaker 0: Maybe we'll do a new panel.
Speaker 0: I got I got a panel.
Speaker 0: I've been working on It's in the.
Speaker 0: I've actually I've done some research.
Speaker 0: I've got a little bit of data, but I got to get more.
Speaker 0: the problem is to get more data.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I got to do.
Speaker 0: I actually have to go record myself playing Team Fortress 2 with randos.
Speaker 0: Okay, like I literally need a few hours of footage of me earnestly trying to play Team Fortress 2 online against real people trying to win and I need to do it with every single character class.
Speaker 0: So I need like two hours of my own play for every character class as Data for this panel.
Speaker 0: Thankfully.
Speaker 0: I already have more than that for overwatch because that's almost all I play these days.
Speaker 0: But I look forward to a packs online, I think it's the right decision.
Speaker 0: We'll see if packs West happens.
Speaker 0: I think that's iffy because even if September like a miracle happens and the world is way safer My suspicion is it's gonna be too late to plan September cons, especially cons that involve big industry presence.
Speaker 0: So we'll see.
Speaker 0: I feel like packs unplugged is the first big Convention that has a chance of happening.
Speaker 0: that I would like
Speaker 1: it has a chance But I'm not even gonna give it a 50% chance No, but it's
Speaker 0: one where if I was in a casino when I saw those odds I might throw a little bit of money at it
Speaker 1: if you have to bet on one, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's like if the gate if you made a game and the game was okay.
Speaker 1: Here's a list of all packs is for the next three years.
Speaker 1: Right put a token on the first packs that will happen without going over.
Speaker 1: That's it's either that one or soon after is where it's either that or it's like.
Speaker 0: I don't even know about South because the whole Texas situation.
Speaker 0: so it might be East if it's not unplugged.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all right.
Speaker 1: It's like that's the area where the tokens car with the current odds are likely to lay, right?
Speaker 1: So yeah.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So III the horrible conferences existed our whole lives which is it had such a mystique like before?
Speaker 0: we knew what it was like like In those early internet days like early petty arcade days.
Speaker 0: there was a weird mystique like everyone wants a mistake even in the 90s.
Speaker 1: Yeah because it was like hey all the video game all the big video game companies get together in this place once a year and show off all the new video games before anywhere else and there weren't really like Big fan cons like you know them today.
Speaker 0: that were gaming company, right?
Speaker 1: That were all you use.
Speaker 1: the only thing you you could only experience e3 through the pages of a video game magazine.
Speaker 1: Right, like someone telling you I went to this amazing Holy Land.
Speaker 1: Let me tell you about it with some photos and some text and it's like Holy.
Speaker 0: I see a photo and be like wait, are they playing a prototype of hardware that didn't come out yet?
Speaker 0: I would like salivate over those images.
Speaker 1: Right and there was like these mysterious was like Hall E or something Like.
Speaker 1: there was supposedly this hall that had like, you know, the small time Rondo stuff that we write.
Speaker 0: that was like Not to be confused with the special hall at the San Diego comic-con.
Speaker 0: That's a whole other thing.
Speaker 0: Hall D I forget which one's which that all blurs together, right?
Speaker 1: The San Diego comic-con one is just.
Speaker 1: that's just a big panel room that has the big lines and the big celebrities.
Speaker 1: the one at the E3 is like the secret room where the small time places are showing off these, you know rarity games like hey kid Here's the good stuff Right exactly.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the point is obviously e3 is you know, it's gone up.
Speaker 1: It's gone down up and down all over the place.
Speaker 1: bad good getting their lunch eaten by packs Who knows companies have left saying we don't need you.
Speaker 1: We'll do all our own thing.
Speaker 1: Oh wait We'll come back and we'll work with you.
Speaker 1: We're gonna not happen.
Speaker 1: We're gonna happen.
Speaker 1: Pandemic reasons.
Speaker 1: other reasons what's happening with e3 this year?
Speaker 1: e3 is not only happening this year.
Speaker 1: It's an online only deal and all the big companies seem to be going in on it.
Speaker 0: Nintendo's like yeah Okay III will come and do your online e3 and then such and such so make sense because they need There's that you need to tie your buzz to a broader buzz or have earth-shattering news to get noticed.
Speaker 1: I know they got their Nintendo direct today.
Speaker 1: What do they need e3 for?
Speaker 1: but I guess they're going in on it.
Speaker 0: So What was the next buzz Nintendo was gonna have until they announced dates?
Speaker 1: for breath of the wild - I Don't know the point is be on the lookout for Big hot news is from all the video game companies all at once in a blob around.
Speaker 1: the time actually happens.
Speaker 1: There's a split.
Speaker 0: so Nintendo Microsoft Konami and Ubisoft are like doubling down on e3 online.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Activision and Sony are not going to be included at this time, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah And you know not every company's.
Speaker 1: it's gonna be June 12 through 15.
Speaker 1: So in early June look for big video game news.
Speaker 1: Yeah You can expect you know April May to actually be a dry spell for big triple-a video game news because they're gonna be holding their cards until e3.
Speaker 0: Yeah Okay, so in some other news this happens often, but it's happening again for another platform.
Speaker 0: So it's worth sort of just pointing at.
Speaker 0: but PS Vita or Vita games.
Speaker 0: I never had one but there were a lot of games that were released on that thing that were exclusive to it Like they were developed for it.
Speaker 0: They only came out on it.
Speaker 0: It wasn't like a piece.
Speaker 1: there are a lot of games that were exclusive to PSP, you know PS Vita whatever all the portable PlayStations of which there probably will never be another one.
Speaker 1: I am not I guess I can't guarantee that but it seems likely.
Speaker 1: Yeah and You know there were a lot of some of the.
Speaker 1: there were some good games on there some exclusive ones and Some of them got ported to other systems and some of them didn't.
Speaker 1: I think us the switch is like a really good destination.
Speaker 1: Any developers or publishers that put games out on those platforms Would do well to just shove them in the switch.
Speaker 0: Esha hundred percent.
Speaker 0: The tricky part seems that a lot of the companies that made these things are either gone or have changed radically Don't have the resources to do a port and probably couldn't make enough money to justify the port.
Speaker 0: So there's sort of a race to preserve these games somehow.
Speaker 1: Right, you'll probably see things like I remember there being like a PSP contra or something.
Speaker 1: That wasn't anything else.
Speaker 1: That's like.
Speaker 1: that's how old my memory is.
Speaker 1: that was when I was in college.
Speaker 1: But it's like yeah, you can see.
Speaker 1: probably, you know, maybe it was re-released and I didn't notice.
Speaker 1: but you could probably be like in the Future like, you know PSP mega pack.
Speaker 1: and it'll be like, you know, 10 bucks 10 PSP games.
Speaker 1: You know some bundle running on who knows what platform.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well just like on the switch We have these compilations of like.
Speaker 0: here's a bunch of old arcade games in a package every Mega Man game.
Speaker 1: You know 50 bucks what I like.
Speaker 0: those are still my weakness.
Speaker 0: whenever there's a package of like.
Speaker 0: hey Here's every game in some series that you've played.
Speaker 0: a little bit of part of my brain says oh I should just buy that.
Speaker 0: So I have it.
Speaker 1: good thing.
Speaker 1: I have my policy now.
Speaker 0: Yeah I have implemented the similar policy of I only buy a game if the price it's on sale to the point that arounds down to zero or I am going to play it as soon as it finishes downloading.
Speaker 1: Like I'm gonna sit there and wait for it to download and unless it's litter even if a game is I don't see mine is Even more strict even if it's one penny.
Speaker 1: I won't buy it unless I am going to install it and play it immediately.
Speaker 1: If it's zero dollars, okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, then I will.
Speaker 1: then I'll just whatever it cost zero.
Speaker 0: now I did at the last second by any that Mario 3d compilation the anniversary one.
Speaker 1: No, I had no need for that.
Speaker 0: I bought it in cartridge for me.
Speaker 1: I have all the games in the compilation.
Speaker 1: What do I need?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't cuz I was sponging off at your we and your gamecube for many years I'd ever owned either of those consoles myself.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Well, but yeah, the all these games are disappearing.
Speaker 0: same old story.
Speaker 0: I got a link to it right here.
Speaker 0: I got a little news.
Speaker 0: This is you might have seen this.
Speaker 0: it kind of made some.
Speaker 0: it made the rounds on like the reddits and everything.
Speaker 0: But you don't know.
Speaker 0: Magnus Carlsen is the reigning chess world champion Like just gay.
Speaker 0: yeah the chess champion in a recent game against Hikaru Nakamura During a tournament.
Speaker 0: He did something that the internet noticed and by the internet I mean even the non chess internet.
Speaker 0: He played an opening.
Speaker 0: that is kind of a joke on the internet.
Speaker 0: That is specifically known as the bong cloud.
Speaker 0: It is a the best way I can describe this.
Speaker 0: I'll link to this.
Speaker 1: you can watch a video.
Speaker 0: a great What a great name, you know what this opening is.
Speaker 0: do fucking Ridiculous nonsense and try to put the game in such a broken state that both players are just lost in a fog And may the best player win.
Speaker 0: Okay, break the game and see what.
Speaker 1: he just be just bored doing the same old same old.
Speaker 1: So he went.
Speaker 0: now it's it let loose the bong cloud, you know, yeah Apparently this opening was like known among like people who play chess online But like no one played it in like a super serious tournament and the internet like noticed that this was happening.
Speaker 0: There was a whole thing around it.
Speaker 1: He probably learned about it from the internet.
Speaker 1: people are on the famous people on the internet to yep He can read reddit, right?
Speaker 0: you know like Justin Bieber big Leafs fan like talks about them a lot just randomly online like Probably on leaves to reddit or at least Twitter, you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like people who are famous like things that are fans of other people who are more or less famous Yeah, they're reading the same shit.
Speaker 1: You're reading.
Speaker 1: They know what's going on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there isn't like a secret to it.
Speaker 1: I'm just calls and probably knows it's called the bong cloud.
Speaker 1: He's like, you know what?
Speaker 1: It is like if I lose this tournament, that's not a big deal.
Speaker 0: It's not Magnus Carlsen's tiny thumbnail I can barely see just from the news page I got up.
Speaker 0: I see a stream and it looks like both of the players are like like like One of them is laughing and the other one is clearly like trying to stifle a laugh as the opening.
Speaker 1: But they probably both know about the bond cloud, right?
Speaker 0: But it also speaks to something we've talked about a lot not as much on geek nights But we talked about this a lot in panels we do Around.
Speaker 0: how chess has this endgame where all the attractors in the like the math of chess are draws like Gay like yeah, a eyes are pushing chest to the who won.
Speaker 1: the who won the bond cloud game?
Speaker 0: I don't actually know and I'm gonna find out later cuz I didn't actually do it.
Speaker 1: So I've always been sort of mad on chess.
Speaker 1: cuz I don't like to memorize openings and stuff But the fact that there's an opening called the bunk.
Speaker 1: Maybe I should maybe I should memorize that Opening and not learn anything.
Speaker 1: I'm not interested in learning anything more about chess than I already know, right?
Speaker 1: You know, I just sort of play naturally like I look a few moves ahead.
Speaker 1: Okay, I'll kill two of your guys And you'll kill one of mine.
Speaker 1: That seems good.
Speaker 1: That's how I play.
Speaker 0: playing the epon first is a very natural opening in chess But moving the king up to e2 is essentially always a terrible second move.
Speaker 1: The point is I should learn The the the bond cloud and just play until the openings over and then from there just play naturally just you know.
Speaker 1: However, I feel like yeah, I don't even ever have to play shit.
Speaker 0: I can't imagine what the endgame looks like for the bond cloud.
Speaker 0: I'm actually there's a Early game looks like I have not watched the full video.
Speaker 1: This is the first.
Speaker 0: this is the first I've heard of it Like ooh, I'm gonna start with the Polish opening and then the other Scott's across from me and he just smiles that King moves forward.
Speaker 1: It's anyway I gotta talk about a geek bite this little game here.
Speaker 1: So I don't know how I remember how I found this game.
Speaker 1: It's on Steam.
Speaker 1: It's 10 bucks, but you can play a free demo.
Speaker 1: You don't need to pay the 10 bucks.
Speaker 1: It's still early access.
Speaker 1: You might want to wait for like the full version if you do want to pay the 10 bucks.
Speaker 1: I did pay the 10 bucks because I did install it and play it immediately and I've played it Once it once in a while, you know every few days I'll open it up and play it like one time and the game is luck be a landlord Obviously named after the Frank Sinatra song luck be a lady.
Speaker 1: I don't know if that came from somewhere before Frank Sinatra.
Speaker 1: it may have and I'm just not aware of it But yeah, so what this game is is something very clever.
Speaker 1: It is Sort of a deck building game in a way right and where you start with five Symbols it was a Robert Alda first performed it.
Speaker 1: Okay, and you start with five symbols and then after every spin of a slot machine You add a symbol to the slot machine.
Speaker 1: So it starts out with like a cherry a cat a coin and a couple other thing, right?
Speaker 1: And it's like, okay, you spun the slot machine.
Speaker 1: You got this many coins.
Speaker 1: What do you want to add to your slot machine?
Speaker 1: a dwarf?
Speaker 1: Like a goose a clam or a goose, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, okay I guess I'll add the goose and each thing you add to the slot machine has different rules Surrounding it right?
Speaker 1: So if a dwarf it stops and he's adjacent to meaning in the eight spaces You know.
Speaker 1: next not just orthogonally adjacent just adjacent to the dwarf.
Speaker 1: if any of those contain an alcoholic beverage The alcoholic beverage will be removed and the dwarf will give you a whole bunch of coins Cuz he you know to pay for the beer.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, this sounds good.
Speaker 1: There's also like a bartender.
Speaker 1: the bartender has like a 10% chance of creating an alcoholic beverage.
Speaker 1: If you have a key and it ends adjacent to like a safe or a lockbox The key and the lockbox both go away and a bunch of money comes out, right?
Speaker 1: So, you know, there's all these sorts of synergies between symbols.
Speaker 1: The best the thing is no matter what symbols you get.
Speaker 1: I have not found anything better than cultists.
Speaker 1: It's like a cultist is one coin.
Speaker 1: two cultists means two coins each.
Speaker 1: They don't need to be adjacent.
Speaker 1: three cultists three coins each.
Speaker 1: four cult is four coins each.
Speaker 1: you get it.
Speaker 1: Cultists are just the best.
Speaker 1: I'm the only time I've gone deep in this game with huge payouts is with a lot of cultists.
Speaker 0: Well, the game is early access.
Speaker 1: Maybe they'll nerf the cultists Maybe but this game is actually updated rather frequently with significant updates.
Speaker 1: It's even a timer on the bottom left of the main menu that tells you how long until the next update launches.
Speaker 1: Whoa There's real fun.
Speaker 1: There's also Items.
Speaker 1: so like you key after every.
Speaker 1: basically the it's called luck be a landlord because this the story of this game is That you move into an apartment and you got to pay the rent and the rent starts out at $25.
Speaker 1: So and you have I think six spins of the slot machine, right?
Speaker 1: It's like we put.
Speaker 1: don't worry We put a slot machine in your apartment to help you pay rent.
Speaker 0: So I feel like that's gonna move from satire to truth within a decade, right?
Speaker 1: But you get you get a certain number of spins before you have to pay rent and you start with five symbols.
Speaker 1: So you're gonna get the rent on the first rent payment no matter what unless you really eff it up, right?
Speaker 1: But then you have.
Speaker 1: then as soon as you pay rent you get an item.
Speaker 1: you get to choose an item Which is like a permanent ability sort of like a relic and slay the spire as opposed to a card Right, and then it's like, okay well Your next rent payment is even bigger and you have this many spins to get to that next rent payment and you keep doing this Until eventually you pay the seven seven seven rent.
Speaker 1: as soon as you pay the triple seven rent You've won the game and then you enter endless mode.
Speaker 1: if you would like to enter endless mode and keep paying Exponentially higher basically a deck builder, but the deck is a slot machine.
Speaker 1: It's a solo deck builder.
Speaker 1: but you don't draw hands or play hands.
Speaker 1: your entire deck gets shuffled on a slot machine and 25 of the symbols in your slot in your The available ones you have appear in a random arrangement on the grid and then score Appropriately and sometimes get consumed meaning, you know, they get they're removed from your deck for the next spin.
Speaker 0: Well, I see one like coal after 20 spins turns into a diamond.
Speaker 1: Diamonds are pretty great because they're sort of like cultists in which their cultists are won by default.
Speaker 1: diamonds are I think five by default And the more diamonds you have They all increase each other's value similar to cultists.
Speaker 1: So Diamonds are like the ultimate thing.
Speaker 1: just a screen full of diamonds I think might be the highest possible payout you could get because it would be five times 25 plus Some.
Speaker 1: you know the math on that.
Speaker 1: It's yeah.
Speaker 1: But yeah There's a lot and the thing is a lot of the symbols and the interactions between the symbols and the items are just a whole lot Of fun and are really cute and wholesome.
Speaker 1: Most of the time like you have a thief the thief every time he shows up takes a coin from you.
Speaker 1: but when you catch the thief either with a banana peel or With the bounty hunter or with like general zaroff who kills all humans Then you'll get every thief the coin stole.
Speaker 1: you will get back times four.
Speaker 0: Oh So apparently also very important news.
Speaker 0: There's a dog and you can pet the dog.
Speaker 1: Yep, there's a lot of stuff going on in this game.
Speaker 1: So it's a really cute fun single-player like very brief thing to do and it changes every so often.
Speaker 1: So like every day or two, I'll open it up and play it one time Usually while I'm waiting for something else like a geek nights to start or something of that nature, right?
Speaker 1: I'll just open it up Like if I've got steam and we're gonna play sieve and everyone's still chatting I'll just open it up play it one time and then up the sieves ready.
Speaker 1: Okay, close my slot machine.
Speaker 1: So I recommend this and it's still early access $10 game.
Speaker 1: I recommend it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, nice and cute but anyway things Of the day.
Speaker 0: so check this.
Speaker 0: this is a video from 2018.
Speaker 0: I didn't know this was at the Met But basically this is the oldest piano in the world from the early 1700s like it's the oldest one that exists.
Speaker 0: Not only does it exist, but it's playable and This is a video of someone playing the oldest piano in the world.
Speaker 0: That is pretty fascinating in and of itself And there's a little bit of explanation about Like how it was built and where it came from and how the guy who made it wasn't actually trying to invent the piano.
Speaker 0: He was actually trying to do something else.
Speaker 0: and if you're interested in this the rabbit hole you can follow on the origins of the piano and Where like the clavichord and like what happened to the harpsichord?
Speaker 0: There is.
Speaker 0: there is so much nonsense there That is way more complicated than you would ever expect But sounds pretty good for an instrument from the 1700s that is still working and not just like a brass instrument.
Speaker 0: Mmm, imagine if your job was to maintain this thing though, like don't break it.
Speaker 0: I think there's a little bit of ship of Theseus going on But it is like the original keys as far as I've read like almost everything on it is original Except I think they've replaced a lot of the strings of these as they've broken over the years.
Speaker 0: Okay, probably some of the pads - I assume.
Speaker 0: So what do you got?
Speaker 1: What do I have as my thing of the day?
Speaker 1: Let me see.
Speaker 0: I know you're trying to run that train.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Okay, so I haven't.
Speaker 1: This is fanfiction that someone posted to an archive of our own.
Speaker 1: I don't think I've ever done a fanfictions thing of the day before because I don't read fanfiction.
Speaker 1: I read, you know, I know of it.
Speaker 1: I respect it, but I don't.
Speaker 1: it's not my thing, right?
Speaker 0: Last one I was at RIT when we read Sailor Moon saves the furries out loud at in capstone that one - okay But yeah, someone named I guess mewd M-e-w-d.
Speaker 1: I think that's the author's name there.
Speaker 1: I saw this on Twitter.
Speaker 1: someone linked to it and it's the name of the Fanfiction really caught me.
Speaker 1: and then I read the summary and that caught me.
Speaker 1: and I read the first page slash chapter And that was enough for me to know that I could make this a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: I haven't read the whole thing.
Speaker 1: So let me just read you this summary and the title in the summary.
Speaker 1: The title is Daisy and Waluigi dream star wannabes by mewd.
Speaker 0: I'm already intrigued.
Speaker 0: just that it's Daisy and Waluigi summary princess.
Speaker 1: Daisy and Waluigi team up to upstage Mario and become big shot heroes and destroy and/or save the world in the Process and maybe fall in love if there's time after that.
Speaker 1: Wow a sprawl.
Speaker 1: a sprawling Novel length romantic comedy action Nintendo adventure where Daisy confronts her past her feelings of self-worth and her feelings for Waluigi.
Speaker 0: I'd I'd Sprawling novel leg.
Speaker 0: Okay this so there's a lot of.
Speaker 0: There's a lot here.
Speaker 1: It's a lot.
Speaker 1: I mean Just have the summary be the thing of the day.
Speaker 1: I don't know and I can't tell you if you should read on beyond the chapter one But like, you know, there are 38 chapters in this thing.
Speaker 1: If you are gonna write a fan fiction That is the bar for a compelling summary to get people to care about it, right?
Speaker 0: Um Have a go I'm just skimming it.
Speaker 0: Mouser fry guy claw grip and try Clyde are all in it.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Those are some of my boys.
Speaker 0: In the moment, I'm still stuck inside.
Speaker 0: like that much is happening.
Speaker 0: You'll see us probably in some packs online like whatever that looks like.
Speaker 0: We'll probably be on that.
Speaker 0: We have a sprawling internet presence.
Speaker 0: So check us out at all the places we exist.
Speaker 1: So and I've been working on a thing because I want to make it you know, we keep saying this I'm making a thing where all of the places that geek nights has an online presence I'm gonna make one page somewhere that you can go to that just has links to every place geek nights exists on the internet and Sort of organizing all those places in a spreadsheet.
Speaker 1: So let me just list for you the 30 Almost 29 places so far that I've.
Speaker 1: we've discovered online presence.
Speaker 0: There's definitely more.
Speaker 1: So we have a website.
Speaker 1: right you can email us.
Speaker 1: You have Twitter the geek nights Twitter, but there's also my Twitter and rims Twitter, right?
Speaker 1: We have three YouTube channels mine rims and an official geek nights one that was barely used that we don't really use anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah for reasons we haven't about we have a discord.
Speaker 1: We have our old forum, which is archived in read-only mode and a new forum, which is active.
Speaker 1: We are on Spotify.
Speaker 1: We're on iTunes.
Speaker 1: We have a geek nights email newsletter.
Speaker 1: I should write one of those.
Speaker 0: Those are very good.
Speaker 1: It's been a while.
Speaker 1: We have a Facebook page that we don't post to.
Speaker 1: I guess it's a Facebook page slash group.
Speaker 1: Who knows we got the patreon that you shouldn't give money to.
Speaker 1: We have an Instagram.
Speaker 1: We have a geek nights twitch and there's also my personal twitch.
Speaker 0: now I guess I say me I actually don't have a twitch channel.
Speaker 1: Okay We have a code of conduct.
Speaker 1: I guess slash github kinda, you know, I don't know That We have a geek nights reddit that no one uses.
Speaker 1: We have it.
Speaker 1: there is.
Speaker 1: you can find this on board game geek.
Speaker 1: There is a listing for our podcast as well as rim.
Speaker 1: whenever we do Board game reviews right rim makes a YouTube video.
Speaker 1: That's just the review and then attaches it to the board game.
Speaker 1: So if you go to board game geek and you find a game there in the video section on the game on board game geek You may see a geek nights YouTube video there.
Speaker 0: Yep Surprising amount of traffic gets comes from that.
Speaker 0: like you'd be surprised.
Speaker 1: We have a steam group and steam curator page.
Speaker 1: So those are sort of the same thing.
Speaker 1: one and a half things right?
Speaker 1: We have our official RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We have many of them, you know, you can.
Speaker 1: I don't know how many of them still work, but you know, they're there.
Speaker 1: We are on Google podcast run Amazon podcasts.
Speaker 1: Rim made a LinkedIn page when he treated me.
Speaker 1: He said that he basically Instead of a company page He made geek nights as a company on LinkedIn that someone could theoretically be an employee of.
Speaker 1: yeah I guess maybe I should attach myself to it.
Speaker 0: I forgot about it until Scott was asking me to like find places We're not thinking of and I bump into it by accident.
Speaker 0: I made that so long ago because like real talk I put geek nights on my actual resume like I like when I got my current job I like.
Speaker 0: they asked me about it and I was like, yes, this is this thing I do.
Speaker 0: It's a whole big thing.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna keep doing it or I'm not gonna work here.
Speaker 1: the point is is that the final one that we know that we've managed to list so far is Amazon.
Speaker 1: we have an Amazon fashion page where you can buy a nice t-shirt directly from Amazon and I'll spoil it.
Speaker 0: now There are more gig nights t-shirts with our new logos coming there.
Speaker 0: They are like I am work.
Speaker 0: I have been working on things for ten years from now.
Speaker 1: Yep We had an IRC channel at some point.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it still exists, but there are logs of that IRC channel.
Speaker 1: And also this doesn't include all of our.
Speaker 1: this only includes things that I consider to be like, you know geek nights things Right, like, you know a geek nights listener.
Speaker 1: follow me on Twitter.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: alright, you know, but like I guess I have a personal Instagram.
Speaker 1: you can find it.
Speaker 1: You know what my internet name is, right, but it's like.
Speaker 1: that's not a geek nights thing.
Speaker 0: Like I like her.
Speaker 0: It's public but it's not the geek nights flicker.
Speaker 0: Like if I take a bunch of photos for geek night, I'm gonna publish them somewhere else where you'll all see them, right?
Speaker 1: But my personal YouTube my personal Twitter those have the.
Speaker 1: those are more geek night.
Speaker 0: See, we're like my personal YouTube.
Speaker 0: right effectively is the geek nights YouTube?
Speaker 0: just because that exactly.
Speaker 1: so some.
Speaker 1: so not there are some things that are my Personal thing or rims personal thing that are also a geek nights thing kinda and some that aren't right.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, so Take that as you will.
Speaker 0: Yeah, otherwise we're.
Speaker 0: uh, we're reading the tale again G Sure, so read along with us.
Speaker 0: It's the first novel.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: read the first one, right?
Speaker 0: You gotta read the thing.
Speaker 1: if before you read Daisy and Waluigi Dream star wannabes right the newest greatest novel in the history of humans, right?
Speaker 0: You got to start with the first novel in Genji's just kind of going like Just gets into trouble gets out of trouble.
Speaker 0: Consequences happen mostly to other people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's what I've taken away from this so far.
Speaker 1: Okay, so let us go to the main bit and then I need dinner.
Speaker 0: All right, let me jump right into that.
Speaker 0: There we go.
Speaker 0: Okay so JRPGs, we've never really talked about like that on geek nights except tangentially.
Speaker 1: Well, I think what happened is Tuesday is a day where we all we're always playing games more often than other things.
Speaker 1: We always have a game to talk about usually or a convention.
Speaker 1: Well, at least refresh the pool and so we haven't had to resort to like, you know more generic sort of Conceptual show ideas for Tuesdays as we do on other days.
Speaker 1: but also we have done a few Tuesday shows on like shmups or Things that right like more just targeting a whole genre at once.
Speaker 1: but we haven't done a lot of those.
Speaker 1: So we're like, well, we haven't actually both played a new game.
Speaker 1: You know that we haven't done a show on recently.
Speaker 0: who new FPS is.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna try out this weekend.
Speaker 1: Okay, and there are a lot of games coming up soon that I think will both play like that one that I linked to.
Speaker 1: that I discovered today, that's like a Like an our xcom plus slay the spire combo possibly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm worried about that.
Speaker 0: one Might be too good for me exactly.
Speaker 0: We're playing a lot of games we've played before and already reviewed on geek nights - like right.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna do this big show or another train game show.
Speaker 0: Wait, let's talk about hearts of iron or still are.
Speaker 1: so I was like, hey, let's just do a genre show.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about a whole genre of games in general, which there are many genres.
Speaker 1: You haven't discussed pick one pick JRPGs.
Speaker 1: Okay, let's talk about JRPGs.
Speaker 0: Yeah now full disclosure.
Speaker 0: I Don't like JRPGs anymore like for the most part.
Speaker 0: like I don't play modern ones I keep an eye on them like I learn about them, but I tend not to play them.
Speaker 0: But at the same time as much as I want to say I can't deal with those mechanics I am playing Final Fantasy 4 randomizers for some reason right also.
Speaker 0: Sometimes I feel this urge to go level up in a JRPG like just poke it Final Fantasy 1 in an emulator.
Speaker 0: It's weird.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it's very strange how you know, you know, we had the D&D right the pen and paper RPGs.
Speaker 1: Yeah predating for example the piece, you know the RPGs that were on various PCs Right and they varied Spectrums and Commodores and Amigas and DOS.
Speaker 1: and you know all those old PC platforms Commodores apples, right?
Speaker 1: There were all cars RPGs on those platforms.
Speaker 1: and then Once you know in Japan you had them on you know The MSX or the FM towns or the PC 9, you know all kinds of different platforms.
Speaker 1: And there's
Speaker 0: all these different lineages of these games like we get into that history like From a very different world from some of these other games,
Speaker 1: right but that core mechanic there right of you know, the the the combat of D&D was just brought over to Video games right in this sort of fashion where it's like you're still calling it an RPG When this like the role-playing element is like, where is it?
Speaker 0: You know You're not that's that was our first facts panel that beyond D&D the original version of that where we talked a lot about It's a role-playing game.
Speaker 0: But what actual role-playing are you doing?
Speaker 1: Right or even if you are, you know It's like you're limited to just like this subset of actions, right if you play like a gold box game or you know A shadow gate.
Speaker 1: those aren't JRPGs obviously, but there's still computer Versions.
Speaker 1: right because computers are so limited then they still even today still are quite limited.
Speaker 1: right You know when you're playing a tabletop RPG Even if it's just a dungeon crawly one where you fighting monsters and traps and doing all these things Your you know human brains you affect you have a human GM possibly Depending on the game.
Speaker 1: He said this wealth of basically infinite possibilities It's like you know what I could do all this stuff with my 10-foot pole.
Speaker 1: What if I poke the bee's nest with it, right?
Speaker 1: It's like whereas in a computer game even today It's like if they don't program in that specific Possibility.
Speaker 1: it's not a possibility Right, you know, so The JRPG is like comes out of the fact that they were even more limited in those days.
Speaker 1: they wanted to translate that tabletop D&D experience to the computer.
Speaker 1: and You know the American peep game developers and you know British game developers did it in certain ways and the Japanese game developers did it in the Dragon Quest?
Speaker 1: Final Fantasy way.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's interesting because at the same time the actual Japanese role-playing game space at the time was a lot broader than what Americans recognized and Back then no one called those JRPGs.
Speaker 0: They were just RPGs and The most popular RPGs in America at the time Ended up being the ones that were mostly on the NES and SNES Just due to like.
Speaker 0: that was when gaming started to become more mainstream.
Speaker 0: That was a very accessible popular affordable console.
Speaker 0: for a lot of people those two consoles.
Speaker 0: so That was right around when Final Fantasy and Dragon Quest were also available in the US.
Speaker 0: so a lot of people like.
Speaker 0: the term JRPG came way later to try to differentiate one subset of Japanese RPGs that are themselves together a subset of like digital RPGs.
Speaker 0: and right term is Not like the fact even though it stands for a Japanese role-playing game.
Speaker 0: It's not really a useful or accurate term because Japanese role-playing games are far more diverse than most people would like.
Speaker 0: hide lied Arguably comes from that same lineage, but no no one who played hide lied today in America would say oh, that's a JRPG Right.
Speaker 1: the common, you know the common tropes of a JRPG right is that there's some sort of overworld right that you walk around on And there's random encounters right and then there's gonna be some sort of turn-based Combat where you know positioning usually doesn't matter too much.
Speaker 1: It's usually you're choosing just an actions per character right fight run.
Speaker 1: You know Magic spell special ability of some kind right you know like steel or something.
Speaker 1: You know the bad guys go you go you have hit points.
Speaker 1: You don't want to die.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you go to towns you talk to people you go to dungeons you walk around There's random encounters in the dungeon, but also boss battles, but also treasure chests full of items.
Speaker 1: And then you know through talking to the characters And also cutscenes and dialogue and boss dialogue and things of that nature.
Speaker 1: There's usual, and there's usually this really very involved.
Speaker 1: You know sort of epic Fantasy story usually a fantasy or sci-fi story.
Speaker 1: yeah that unfolds sometimes with cutscenes and cinematics and all sorts of other embellishments usually Fantastic music of some kind.
Speaker 1: And you know those elements together is usually what makes a JRPG versus?
Speaker 1: yeah, you know Like in a Skyrim, which is definitely a computer video game RPG that doesn't really have all of those elements.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but at the same time while we're calling the show JRPGs, and we're gonna talk about these same kinds of games I don't think that term is useful because even like game nerds all Disagree on exactly what it means.
Speaker 0: if you say it means any role-playing game made in Japan.
Speaker 0: Most of them are nothing like what we're describing.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: it's useful in Action JRPG and AJ RPG like that.
Speaker 0: there is not.
Speaker 1: there's no consistency in this nomenclature The way I use it and I think the only useful way to use it is you're basically a short way of saying a game.
Speaker 1: That's very similar to Dragon quest Final Fantasy yep chrono trigger Etc.
Speaker 0: that's what we're going with.
Speaker 1: but even there's a game along those lines.
Speaker 0: So I pulled up a Wikipedia page that is interesting because it's a listen Oh blade.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Lunar is kind of right in our games that we know some people are obsessed with right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know all those he's wanders from years and all that or wise yeast is more of an action one.
Speaker 0: Yeah They're actually all kind of different because there was the one that a lot of Americans were familiar with on the SNES Which was luffia.
Speaker 0: yeah luffia breath of fire.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I said breath.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I wasn't listening to you.
Speaker 0: I was looking at this page.
Speaker 0: I got this list here.
Speaker 0: It's a Wikipedia page of the best-selling Japanese role-playing game franchise Pokemon earthbound.
Speaker 0: yep, so this is fascinating.
Speaker 0: This is franchise base.
Speaker 0: These are the best-selling Japanese Role-playing game.
Speaker 1: Pokemon is number one.
Speaker 0: Pokemon is number one by like double.
Speaker 1: Of course.
Speaker 0: number two is Final Fantasy.
Speaker 0: so take every Final Fantasy anyone ever bought on any platform and The Pokemons have sold about double.
Speaker 0: Okay Dragon Quest is about half again down, and then there's a long tail.
Speaker 0: and it's interesting because it's like Monster Hunter Kingdom Hearts Souls.
Speaker 1: Monster Hunter is an action.
Speaker 1: You know Right it is a Japanese role-playing game franchise, so there's nothing role-playing about it really.
Speaker 1: It's an action game action RPG like let's not random encounters.
Speaker 1: You're not walking around the map.
Speaker 1: You're not.
Speaker 0: This is why I wouldn't class Not like.
Speaker 1: it's not like Final Fantasy or like, but that's just you're like are?
Speaker 0: the two are working definition Useful definition of.
Speaker 0: I just really want to drive home.
Speaker 0: the fact that the concept of JRPG uses as a genre is Silly and if you're gonna have a conversation like this you actually need to describe what you're talking about Because no one's gonna agree with you like clear at all.
Speaker 0: But the funniest thing about this is that one of the franchise is listed.
Speaker 0: It's like 15 down like.
Speaker 0: it's very high on the list.
Speaker 0: It's just called chrono because it's chrono trigger which consists of two games One of which was bad.
Speaker 0: in my opinion Chrono cross chrono cross was not a good game.
Speaker 0: I did not even finish it.
Speaker 0: I could not stand it and radical dreamers is not listed because that's yeah anyway.
Speaker 1: So let's talk about games like Final Fantasy Dragon Quest etcetera.
Speaker 1: So I first when I was young Right when I was young I actually didn't have Games like that, right Those were not the games that I would buy for the consoles that I had.
Speaker 0: those are the games I was the most obsessed with as a kid like I got fight like.
Speaker 1: I think I think Had I bought a Super Nintendo?
Speaker 1: I probably would have had Final Fantasy 6 and chrono trigger earlier and then play them.
Speaker 0: See I started way earlier on the NES when I got my NES.
Speaker 0: So I upgraded from the Atari to the NES.
Speaker 0: Final Fantasy 1 was one of the first games I got.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see I didn't play Final Fantasy Anything until I basically had emulators in the later 90s like 90s.
Speaker 0: So I played Final Fantasy 1 and I was enough of a nerd.
Speaker 0: So when the SNES came out, I got Final Fantasy 2 and 3 and I was obsessed with them.
Speaker 0: It's scary to think that I was playing cuz I have this vivid memory.
Speaker 0: I was playing Final Fantasy 4 which I knew is 2 on the Super Nintendo when I was home from a lot from school for lunch in Elementary school Mmm, and I have this memory of I got as far as the antlion.
Speaker 0: I hadn't saved my game and my mom said it was time to go back to school But I had to beat the boss as you wouldn't let me and I had to do that whole fucking dungeon again.
Speaker 0: I was mad about it for like Probably an hour and then I forgot but it feels like I was mad for years.
Speaker 1: Yeah So at the time that I really started playing them right those late 90s.
Speaker 1: I was like, whoa these games?
Speaker 1: I've seen them in magazines, right, but I finally understood like ah, that's what these games were I you know because I was somehow despite not having really played them that much all those tropes, right?
Speaker 1: I I already somehow had learned those from somewhere like I knew how to play them even though I hadn't right.
Speaker 1: The first time I opened Final Fantasy 1 in nesticle, right the emulator, right?
Speaker 1: I knew exactly how to play it like everything in there was completely familiar to me cuz it's a well-designed game like it the There was not any game that I had the NES cartridge for that even remotely resembled it right in any way.
Speaker 1: And I don't.
Speaker 1: it's not the kind of game that you would play at a friend's house.
Speaker 1: Now what's definitely is a long single-player deal.
Speaker 0: the problem I ran into is that on the NES?
Speaker 0: Ultima Exodus and Ultima avatar To a kid who doesn't know better in an era where there isn't an internet they just looked like RPGs.
Speaker 0: I was like, oh I bet it's like Final Fantasy and in a lot of ways they are like.
Speaker 0: I'd argue they're in the same genre but those games were just inscrutable Impossible nonsense to me as a kid.
Speaker 0: I could not like Final Fantasy 1 like Despite kid brain.
Speaker 0: I played it with the aim of beating it Like.
Speaker 0: I knew there's something to beat and I like tried but when I played like Ultima Exodus at the same age I was just like water on the world and at no point.
Speaker 0: I have this concept of.
Speaker 0: this is a game that I could be.
Speaker 1: Well, I think that comes down to the linearity, right?
Speaker 1: We sort of view linearity as like a negative in some ways, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you want this open-ended game.
Speaker 1: We can do what you want.
Speaker 1: It's like the dream and it's like you have like something like an Ultima and it's like alright and it's like What the hell do I do with you that you need?
Speaker 0: There's a very specific like path to win that game you can just approach in any order.
Speaker 1: the problem is not it's not clear it's not.
Speaker 0: the game doesn't tell you shit and Like, you know in it like in Final Fantasy or like even Simon's quest like as another example Even if the characters like the translations bad and the characters don't say useful things You can figure out on the puzzles pretty intuitively.
Speaker 0: in Ultima the puzzles are things like yeah, if you talk to these ten villagers across these ten different places You'll eventually figure out that in this one map when the moon is a certain way Walk forward three spaces left two spaces and search that empty spot.
Speaker 0: That doesn't look any different from any other spot in the world and you'll find a game necessary item Like very different philosophy of design even though superficially they were very similar.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So in the with the or the JRPG side, it's much more linear.
Speaker 1: It's like you can only go one place or you can go maybe sometimes places You've already been or you can
Speaker 0: get to places that are a little too dangerous and you kind of avoid them or you figure out A way to do them, but you're always gated like the scope of your world Expands and expands and a lot of them especially the Final Fantasy is this trope.
Speaker 0: I know is in a lot of other games.
Speaker 0: They open up after they have taught you like what's going on usually by giving you effectively the airship.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like that was a trope for so long.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Now I got the airship.
Speaker 0: now I can go anywhere.
Speaker 1: But even if you are opened up It's like most of the places you can go are all the old places and one new place.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right and it's like there's always some sort of gating either by danger of random encounters that will just kill you if you go to the wrong place.
Speaker 1: or You literally can't go to a place or you went to a place, but it's not the time to go to that place yet.
Speaker 1: So you're just sort of seeing that this town exists, but it doesn't matter You're just here whatever.
Speaker 1: and when you come back to the town later as like ah now this town does something.
Speaker 0: But I do think a lot of them do have a moment where they get a little bit rudderless on purpose Like the game has gated you for so long and then finally it's like alright now you can just go anywhere and suddenly you find all.
Speaker 0: you explore the world and find all these interesting things to poke at and Usually that's when there's a lot of side quests and things that aren't strictly necessary to win.
Speaker 0: you can do But eventually even if you don't try to beat the game You'll poke at everything and the game sort of like guides you back toward the critical path to actually beating it Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Well, I think it's part.
Speaker 1: usually the games will do that because most of them, you know, really confer like this sort of.
Speaker 1: You know, you don't see a lot of small JRPGs, right?
Speaker 1: They're long and big right?
Speaker 1: So you're you can't really confer that sense of big and epicness to the player Without sort of opening the world to them in that way, right?
Speaker 1: So it's sort of you do the timing and fashion in which that is done.
Speaker 0: like Final Fantasy 1 you walk around the bridge.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you get the bridge this bridge and then these credits play like to do.
Speaker 1: Okay now the world.
Speaker 0: But then you go you're thinking okay the world.
Speaker 0: and then you find a ship and then you're like, oh the world.
Speaker 0: But then if you try to go north There's a whole continent that doesn't have a single port and you're like wonder what's up with that?
Speaker 0: And then when you get the airship, you're like, oh I'm going up there.
Speaker 0: I've been waiting to get up there my entire childhood.
Speaker 1: here I come Yeah, or you know.
Speaker 1: sometimes, you know, there's usually also Some point in most of them where it's a common trope to go to like a different world, right?
Speaker 1: it's like and you go to the moon or You know some sort of hell or magic land or a world of ruin Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, sort of it's like a terrible secret of space that you've discovered in the plot, right?
Speaker 1: Here's the truth and that's why there's always like a we call it a square boss named after the company square.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this the bad guy that you've known the whole time that's the main bad guy Right.
Speaker 1: That's the.
Speaker 1: you think they're gonna be the final final boss.
Speaker 1: you beat them.
Speaker 1: It's like aha It was actually to do and there's an even bigger boss and Mega Man 2 does the same thing.
Speaker 0: Fuck you, golly.
Speaker 0: Wait Zemus.
Speaker 0: What's that?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like you beat Wiley and then it's like another skull and then you fight this robot alien Wiley spoilers for Mega Man 2.
Speaker 1: It was Exactly while he was controlling the alien robot with remote control anyway And almost all the JRPGs do a very do that same exact thing.
Speaker 1: where it's like it's this bad guy.
Speaker 1: No, it's actually this like god.
Speaker 1: That's the bad guy.
Speaker 1: Some guy, you know from more some elder, you know thing from another dimension.
Speaker 1: Yeah, true evil, but another very true evil is just a guy.
Speaker 1: It's like actually he had this much power and possessed by ten demons.
Speaker 0: But there's also epic ending these games because they're not usually real time or time like like.
Speaker 0: there's no dexterity component to them sometimes like obviously a lot of exceptions and but There's grinding and leveling up as a mechanic and especially the early ones.
Speaker 0: for a long time That was a primary mechanic and this is where like as a reviewer on one hand Like I don't got time for that shit in my adult life.
Speaker 0: But on the other hand, I cannot ignore the fact that that was Extremely satisfying to me when I was younger.
Speaker 0: Like if you got I'm I would like not you haven't become bored of it yet Yep, I would like walk back and forth next to elf land like fighting trolls to get that silver sword.
Speaker 0: I was enjoying every second of that like I can't pretend I didn't.
Speaker 0: it's not like I sprang forth from Zeus.
Speaker 1: knowing that grinding is bad For me, it wasn't that I enjoyed the grinding is that I was more tolerant of it in those days.
Speaker 1: And then the reward of getting the silver sword finally affording it and then just mowing down people with the silver sword Yeah, that reward was so satisfying.
Speaker 1: It was worth.
Speaker 0: it was almost like the pain.
Speaker 0: We've talked about this in panels before.
Speaker 0: a certain amount of pain like say a super meat boy Increases the pleasure of completion.
Speaker 0: the pain just can't be too deep but when we were young we had an infinite capacity for that kind of pain.
Speaker 1: exactly You know, but yeah, it's like that mechanic of random encounters as bad and lazy as it is now.
Speaker 1: It's like there is Something to it, right?
Speaker 1: You know to sort of fill if you you know, it's like if you just took that out completely.
Speaker 1: Right, it's like okay.
Speaker 1: Well now if there's no random encounters then the fun parts I like for example like getting items Right going shopping learning magic spells.
Speaker 1: Those have lost all meaning now.
Speaker 1: It's like who cares?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't want to learn I don't want to get items anymore.
Speaker 1: I don't care about getting gold because there's no random encounters - right.
Speaker 1: It's like They put this bad thing in the game That's unfun in order to make it fun to get things to make the unfun part Go away.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like, you know, it's like the goal of capitalism is to escape capitalism.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: The goal of the JRPG is to escape the horrible random encounters that they're not a problem anymore.
Speaker 1: earthbound I think did really great where if you bump into a bad guy, that's too easy.
Speaker 1: You just automatically win.
Speaker 0: Yeah I think it should have been a little more liberal with that because its rule was if that enemy could not hurt you in any Way if it could possibly do even one damage you have to fight it Exactly, but you could usually kill it in one shot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was the case.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was really weak Yep But some of them like Final Fantasy 4 was always interesting to me in that the random encounters Was what was a resource game?
Speaker 0: Like do I have enough resources to get to the next like checkpoint, but then the boss fights were actually kind of like serious puzzles More so than a lot of other JRPGs I had played and that is a common theme of.
Speaker 0: the bosses will have Complexity that is a combination of knowledge and skill of how to deal with them based on what level you're at and what you've got and I always found that really satisfying.
Speaker 0: like I think the reason Final Fantasy 4 has such a relatively large Randomizer scene like as small as it is like it's the biggest of the RPG randomizer scenes that I can see.
Speaker 0: I think it's because it's basically a boss rush and the bosses in Final Fantasy 4 were really interesting Especially compared to other similar JRPGs from the era Final Fantasy 4 came out The the better JRPGs definitely, you know have more complex or interesting combat systems.
Speaker 1: To you know, some of them good some of them bad, right?
Speaker 1: Everyone's different and I can get into all the different ones like.
Speaker 0: honestly Maybe I'll complain about Final Fantasy 8 but Combat I didn't find fun.
Speaker 0: I liked everything else about that game.
Speaker 1: But the point is the good ones usually have some sort of Puzzly element where it's not just do your highest DPS attack heal when you're low repeat and Usually they'll be structured in such a way to where you know.
Speaker 1: sure they're all.
Speaker 1: if it has leveling up Mathematically, it's always going to be possible to grind and level up so much given enough time to blow past any amount of puzzles And just beat every guy right that which it's always a way possible in Final Fantasy 6.
Speaker 0: That's what I did.
Speaker 0: my endgame and I'll add Final Fantasy 6 was just four characters casting Ultima constantly.
Speaker 1: right You know, it's like.
Speaker 1: that's always gonna be possible as long as leveling up as a thing.
Speaker 1: But the good JRPGs the ones that are better will have some sort of way where if you're clever and you figure it out Then you can with much less resources with much less grinding Find a way through right?
Speaker 0: Oh if I'm clever and I use this You know and sometimes it's like He's healing herself serious boss late-game keeps healing herself cast wall on her Like yep, that's a clever bit.
Speaker 0: I remember I didn't figure that out on my own.
Speaker 1: someone told me Now some of that stuff I think a lot of it actually ends up just being Knowledge and not really skill like I said.
Speaker 0: someone told me I didn't figure it out.
Speaker 1: It's like did you?
Speaker 1: if you know it then you know it.
Speaker 1: it's not are you good enough, right?
Speaker 1: It's like just do you know a thing?
Speaker 1: It's like a not, you know, if you have some knowledge well now you can grind less because you know a secret, right?
Speaker 1: It's like okay great, you know, it's not very satisfying.
Speaker 1: Yeah But at least it's better than just yeah, the only way through is grinding, right?
Speaker 1: You know, it takes this many hours to beat this game.
Speaker 1: the end Yep.
Speaker 0: But it also points out something about the way like we and like game reviewers talk Think again about like Final Fantasy 1 and like when you like you even said when you finally pick those games up They were very intuitive even though you'd never really played them before that that linear grindy relatively simple mechanism in a game Even if like say rumin Scott have outgrown it.
Speaker 0: it's worth noting that for a young rumin Scott.
Speaker 0: Those were killer mechanics Unbelievable game.
Speaker 1: like if I had those games like some years sooner, I would have been like, oh my god This is the greatest game.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I was like Ridiculously obsessed with min maxing my Final Fantasy and Dragon Quest games.
Speaker 0: I played all those Final Fantasy legends that ever like I just I played every RPG I could get my hands on even though really pay for me It was really just.
Speaker 1: I wanted to know the frickin story right because they had such good.
Speaker 1: You know music and characters and stories and I wanted to you know.
Speaker 0: But I also I really wanted to know like who the were sword.
Speaker 0: What does that actually do?
Speaker 0: I want to go find a werewolf now and hit it with it and see what happens.
Speaker 0: Like I would want to see what things did in the game.
Speaker 0: But there was also an element that that was the era where I started to become aware that wait This is Final Fantasy 2.
Speaker 0: But why did that nerd I met on Prodigy say it was Final Fantasy 4 And I wasn't able to figure that out until the internet either.
Speaker 0: I learned it relatively early.
Speaker 0: I actually hosted in In the early geocities days.
Speaker 0: I had a video game magazines did not tell the secret Hosted a site that had a partially translated Final Fantasy 5 ROM.
Speaker 0: Okay, I was really proud of that when I got it.
Speaker 0: but Those like that era for me.
Speaker 0: What the moment that I remember and this gets back to these games are often a little glitchy and buggy and had weird stuff That wasn't well explained at least for kids like me.
Speaker 0: It was exciting to uncover to discover them and try to solve that mystery because I got a summon That you're not supposed to be able to get in Final Fantasy 2 because it's part it was removed into.
Speaker 0: it was only in four But in an SNES cartridge, there's glitches and things where you might get some of those summons for Rydia and I got it and I had friends who literally did not believe me that I had this summon and I'd like show it to them and they were Like amazed by it and it got into sort of that like creepypasta Unknown exploration like no one can explain this to me, which no kid today could ever experience because they were just looking up.
Speaker 0: There's no way to bring that era back.
Speaker 0: I don't think.
Speaker 1: no, I don't think so either.
Speaker 1: You need a frog fractions frog fractions.
Speaker 0: Just go down.
Speaker 1: The frog fractions person recently tweeted that like they put frog fractions for inside of it's like what it's like.
Speaker 1: We can just decompile it though and take a look at the code.
Speaker 1: Yeah We don't need to trust them at their word.
Speaker 1: Just try to mess with us.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't really play any modern what we would call a JRPG.
Speaker 1: No, I don't.
Speaker 1: I just don't have time for that.
Speaker 1: It's - what I really like and we've talked about this a bit.
Speaker 1: when I talked about I think I geeked by did cloudpunk And I all.
Speaker 1: we also did a show recently on heavens heavens vault.
Speaker 0: Yeah, don't waste.
Speaker 1: much is Right.
Speaker 1: It's like you can get the stir games now that are giving you parts of the RPG the parts that I like at least Right the explore the world talk to people epic plot sometimes multiple endings Right the same a chrono trigger head, right?
Speaker 1: So your choices matter some person replayability or look at a very different genre.
Speaker 0: Now they aspire.
Speaker 0: gives me the.
Speaker 0: here's a bunch of complicated bosses and I got to figure out how to fight them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like just that, you know, whichever part you want don't you know, I always made this analogy.
Speaker 1: So I'll make it again where.
Speaker 1: imagine you went to the movie theater to watch Lord of the Rings and you're right or some epic movie and you watch it for like five minutes, right?
Speaker 1: And that was the intro.
Speaker 1: that's just like you'd even press start.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: and then you know you're watching like the first scene right and then the.
Speaker 1: suddenly it pauses and In front of you there pops up like, you know, they give you like a little tablet and it's like on the tablet.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, here are some trivia questions.
Speaker 1: Answer them correctly, right?
Speaker 1: Or wait ten minutes and then if you answer them correctly or wait ten minutes Then we will let you watch the next scene.
Speaker 1: Otherwise watch this death scene where the and that's the end of the movie.
Speaker 1: the end Frodo dies, right?
Speaker 1: And then go back to the to the quiz again, right after you're watching the death scene.
Speaker 1: And it's like if you had to watch a movie like that.
Speaker 1: It's like you wouldn't watch the fucking movie You'd be like.
Speaker 1: what the fuck is this bullshit?
Speaker 0: Let me watch and that's I was always annoyed like that concept of there's nothing different.
Speaker 0: Failure just prevents you from proceeding.
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 0: as an adult and as someone who introspects why I enjoy games I realize that that is.
Speaker 0: I'm not here for that But I do recognize that for other types of gamers, especially younger gamers those mechanics that I despise Still hold value to them and that's why there's such a thriving ecosystem of fairly grindy JRPGs that even today Aren't substantially evolved from Final Fantasy 6.
Speaker 1: I mean they're evolved but they're not.
Speaker 1: you know, I think the fundamentals are still are still there.
Speaker 1: They've just really polished a lot of the outer edges, right?
Speaker 1: But yeah, it's like sometime around the college times, you know, thanks to playing Mudds in high school Right and learning things there about grinding When Wow came out and I saw people grinding there and the MMO RPGs That's when I sort of realized like hey, why can't I just play Final Fantasy 6 without this fucking ground bullshit?
Speaker 0: That was that was my moment too when I bounced off a Wow and I was like, wait a minute.
Speaker 0: Wait a minute Fuck this.
Speaker 1: No, I refuse and my opinions basically been the same since then which is like just let me fucking watch the rings.
Speaker 0: I
Speaker 1: wanted to stop and answer your goddamn quizzes right
Speaker 0: before that like right before I went to RIT I was playing the realm and like grinding out like killing imps to get to experience points for hours and hours and hours at a time to make a number grow up and There was nothing wrong with that in my eyes for some reason.
Speaker 0: and when I hit Wow I bounced off of it and then remember you a bunch of us at RIT got into.
Speaker 0: uh, oh god, what was that?
Speaker 0: MMO that we got it.
Speaker 1: I mean I played puzzle pirates.
Speaker 1: That was pretty grindy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was pretty good.
Speaker 1: It's not a J. Not a JRPG.
Speaker 0: Yeah But now we play.
Speaker 0: we played a couple of like.
Speaker 0: we played a Korean RPG at one point.
Speaker 1: No, Ragnarok Ragnarok.
Speaker 1: That was the one and I just hit slimes for like a week.
Speaker 0: And yeah, we we both we were all grinding it.
Speaker 0: and then we all together was like wait a minute This grind is just gonna unlock a Slightly different grind and we I think we all have a girl grind rats instead of slimes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I tried to run to the end of the game and it was just a bigger numbers grinding out bigger numbers.
Speaker 0: There wasn't anything else there.
Speaker 0: Yep, so yeah You know, that's That's just our thoughts on this.
Speaker 0: I
Speaker 1: think you know, I think JRPGs these days I think what they've done especially we talked about the most popular one Pokemon Is that to sort of you know Alleviate, I don't know necessarily alleviate but to sort of appeal to a broader audience of people who may not just want to grind and Level up is they add all sorts of other things?
Speaker 1: Dragon Quest does this also.
Speaker 0: Well, we're a lot of grinding mechanics that are not game necessary.
Speaker 1: Right this fashion and this side game.
Speaker 0: go grow your berries and breed berries or whatever.
Speaker 1: All sorts of other things going on in the game.
Speaker 1: Just all sorts of systems that may or may not interact with the combat system.
Speaker 0: Look at the game of the year.
Speaker 0: Look at Hades dating sim dialogue tree unlocking relationships plus like action RPG.
Speaker 1: Right exactly, you know They just put lots and lots of systems in there So that there's something for you to be interested in something for you to spend your time in something for everyone to you know do And yeah, you know eventually uncover the plot of some kind right.
Speaker 1: so?
Speaker 1: And I do think you know regardless of any other negative things about them.
Speaker 1: game wise, you know the plots characters You know stories of a lot of JRPGs are still really kind of epic and awesome.
Speaker 1: a lot of the time not all the time But a lot of the time and I really enjoy those kinds of stories and I'd love to like watch them on YouTube As opposed to playing them.
Speaker 1: Yep, right because then I can get that story while without wasting such a large portion of my life Just pushing a and waiting for the next, you know to get to the next town.
Speaker 0: Yeah What I wonder?
Speaker 0: I suspect we wouldn't feel differently because if we didn't have jobs But somehow didn't need money.
Speaker 0: I think we would fill that vacuum trivially, but I do wonder if we had a lot of free time Would we be more tolerant?
Speaker 0: I think the answer is no.
Speaker 1: I might be more tolerant in that, you know, as long as it was a You know an easier one right one.
Speaker 1: that didn't, you know, it depends on exactly how long it takes, right?
Speaker 1: It's like I might be able to get through.
Speaker 1: You know cuz like.
Speaker 1: I've played a Pokemon games recently and I usually get like a few gyms in and then stop, right?
Speaker 1: I haven't beaten one since like Maybe.
Speaker 1: well
Speaker 0: like they're not that long ago like during kovid I just like fired up Final Fantasy 1 in an emulator because I was trying to test something and Before I knew it I'd beaten garland and the bridge appeared and I was like wait wait rim you're actually playing stop.
Speaker 0: I had to catch myself.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I played final fantasy 7 came out on Steam Maybe a few years ago because I and I went and I played that like alright I'll give this game one more shot, right and I went and I played it and I got through.
Speaker 1: I was having a good time going through seeing stuff I'd already seen before going through and then Suddenly I got farther than I'd ever gotten before and the world like opened up into this enormous world outside the town And I didn't even know the game got that big And I was like what the fuck is this?
Speaker 1: I don't have time for this.
Speaker 1: And then I stopped playing as soon as that.
Speaker 1: that was just so overwhelming to have that such big world open up and Realize the game was gonna be that long and that made me stop playing.
Speaker 0: Well, that's that that rudderless moment assumes that you have like gotten invested in the game enough to where you're.
Speaker 0: like Hooked you before that rudderless moment.
Speaker 0: I think that's the moment.
Speaker 0: Most people would just bounce off of a game Like if you weren't feeling Final Fantasy 1. as soon as you get that airship, you'll be like, oh, there are way too many things up North.
Speaker 0: I'm done.
Speaker 0: I'm out.
Speaker 1: Yep All right.
Speaker 1: So yeah the future of JRPGs.
Speaker 1: I think they're just.
Speaker 0: you know, I keep on evolving.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm not paying enough attention to the scene to know like what the developments are and what.
Speaker 0: I don't even finish Pokemon games these days right as an outsider Right.
Speaker 1: It just looks like they sort of keep doing You know the same old same old only, you know freshening and advancing and expanding but not really Revolutionizing, right?
Speaker 1: It's like here's another Final Fantasy.
Speaker 1: It's a lot like the other Final Fantasy's only better graphics bigger fancier new combat system more things to do Etc.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: This one is different because it's what dudes pushing a car or something, right?
Speaker 1: Who is that was one of the recent ish ones?
Speaker 1: I guess that one's probably old by now right knowing how old I am You know.
Speaker 1: and then they just they do how they do it.
Speaker 1: I guess there's still an audience for it And it's you know, it's just not it was.
Speaker 1: it sort of is and isn't for me at the same time, right?
Speaker 0: Yep, that's part of why I'm playing these randomizers because I get to scratch that itch that's still there buried But it's a very concentrated experience that ends quickly and it's just like I'm mainlining.
Speaker 0: the part of those games that I like the most which for Final Fantasies was Especially Final Fantasy's foreign earlier was the boss rush as of Andy like looting more so than the plots Really?
Speaker 0: It was Final Fantasy 6 and chrono trigger where I was more invested in the characters than I was in the game mechanics.
Speaker 0: Mmm, this has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and make comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate.
Speaker 1: Thursdays Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geeknights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Heidi We nickel Ellen Joyce link easy dread Lily Tenebra Chris Reimer Clinton Walton Finn Graham Finch just like a dude guy.
Speaker 0: now go through the last year or so podcast and make room saying Ryan from New Zealand Review mad bull 34 cowards Ryan Perrin Sam Erickson Shervin vulnerable Taylor Braun.
Speaker 0: You hold the key to my heart and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Speaker 0: just watch the Rangers completely blow the Penguins out of the water.
Speaker 0: and now I leave you with.
Speaker 1: Get down on that fizzy Oh.