Speaker 1: It's Thursday, October 28th, 2021.
Speaker 1: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We are reviewing the 2021 movie Dune.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: so, uh Biking home from work today.
Speaker 1: Like I do want a city bike.
Speaker 1: I Had two things happen.
Speaker 1: They're both minor.
Speaker 1: They were just notable.
Speaker 1: One of them's funny and one of them was just weird.
Speaker 1: So It's hard to get a city bikes lately, like they're just like people are biking like crazy, especially in Midtown.
Speaker 0: So let's get a little colder.
Speaker 0: So and the thing is the the city bike usage does go down when it gets colder But not as much as you'd expect not as much as you would think.
Speaker 0: people keep going even in the cold Right, and it's not that it's.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's cold right now if you ask me, but it's not that cold, right?
Speaker 0: It's not like.
Speaker 0: yeah, like.
Speaker 1: I just bike home in like a dress shirt and a blazer and I was fine.
Speaker 0: It's it's below 60 Fahrenheit, so I'm cold, but it's like I could bike if I was outside.
Speaker 0: I could use city bike.
Speaker 1: So I'm at a dock where there's only one bike like left and I'm just walking toward it And I I stand next to it and I pull my keys.
Speaker 1: someone runs up and grabs it before you know I'm about to put my keys in and this dude from behind me just says that's my fucking bike and I turn around.
Speaker 1: He's ready to fight me.
Speaker 1: So I was just like what.
Speaker 1: I just walked away.
Speaker 1: dude was like willing to do violence.
Speaker 1: All right, well you can have it bro for his city bike.
Speaker 1: so I just walked away and let him do his thing.
Speaker 1: Weird dangerous looking dude who seemed to have problems.
Speaker 1: So whatever I walk like a block over to another doc.
Speaker 1: There's plenty of bikes and I'm fine.
Speaker 1: So I'm biking home and I'm on what?
Speaker 1: in Midtown There's a lot of like cross streets with a narrow bike path like a one-way really narrow bike path.
Speaker 1: and as I'm biking There's two women running in the bike path side by side completely blocking it and there's a baller that a lot.
Speaker 1: It's fine bollard on the left sidewalk on the right with a big curb and like ours and stuff.
Speaker 1: So I come up behind him.
Speaker 1: It's a city bike.
Speaker 1: I'm going real slow.
Speaker 1: So I'm like, excuse me, pardon me Like.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to be nice.
Speaker 1: They don't respond at all.
Speaker 0: So they got headphones in or something?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: So I ding the city bike little bell once like dick and immediately a Laurel and Hardy routine ensues.
Speaker 1: the woman on the left like immediately just likes pan.
Speaker 1: It like startles and turns to the right.
Speaker 1: the woman on the right panics and turns to the left.
Speaker 1: They bounce foreheads against each other and fall over in a tangle Like I stop and I'm like, are you okay?
Speaker 1: And neither one of them would talk to me and they were just.
Speaker 1: they were unhappy With the situation and I decided just let them be.
Speaker 1: they did not want assistance of any kind But I had to wait.
Speaker 1: but I had to actually wait for them to get out of the way so I could bike past them.
Speaker 1: So I'm just standing there like pardon me.
Speaker 1: Just trying to get by.
Speaker 0: I find the problem.
Speaker 0: You know the.
Speaker 0: the culprit there really is simply that you know, the sidewalks are too narrow.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like.
Speaker 1: I will never run in bike lanes, but I see a lot of people running in them and I understand I don't agree, right?
Speaker 0: It's not their fault.
Speaker 0: It's like they want to run.
Speaker 0: Okay, the sidewalk is too narrow.
Speaker 0: They should take away a lane from cars to make the sidewalk wider.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then on top of that It's like there's just not like, you know green space in that, you know, you I notice a lot more.
Speaker 0: if you see that happening It's probably because that area doesn't have like a park.
Speaker 0: You don't see people running in the bike lane at a story apart because there's a fucking track there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like there's no reason that you know.
Speaker 1: I read up the east side path and I run.
Speaker 0: I run loops on Randall's Island and I Had and it's like where can you run in Manhattan if you say side west side, there's an apart, right?
Speaker 0: There's an enormous park in the middle and there's things on the edge.
Speaker 0: if you're in the middle part That's south of Central Park or north of Central Park too far away from it.
Speaker 0: Are you gonna take a subway ride to then run?
Speaker 0: It's like no.
Speaker 0: No in this case the like the tiny little park and run in a tiny circle.
Speaker 1: It so happens that in this particular place the sidewalk was wide and completely open.
Speaker 1: There were no people anywhere.
Speaker 1: The only people on this whole street were these two women running in the little narrow bike lane.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess they just you know, yeah, but I to my credit I did not laugh out loud because I because it was really like.
Speaker 1: it's hard to describe how funny it was How quickly the situation people turn and bonk?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can imagine.
Speaker 0: I'm already laughing it just my imagination.
Speaker 1: So there's so much big news that happened today that we're only gonna cover a couple of things cuz there.
Speaker 0: really I don't think there's That much.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of political news that you probably didn't pay attention to.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's.
Speaker 0: it's probably just more of the same news is continuing and you're like you make a big deal out of some Development.
Speaker 0: that doesn't actually mean anything.
Speaker 1: Wasn't talking about US politics.
Speaker 0: But anyway Say, you know the same thing around the world.
Speaker 1: one thing I can.
Speaker 1: so one thing that happened in the cryptocurrency world Which is a scam just to be sure.
Speaker 1: So there's a situation right now.
Speaker 1: I am NOT giving investment advice of any kind.
Speaker 1: This is my person.
Speaker 0: I am.
Speaker 0: don't buy any crypto anything at any No matter what it costs no matter what.
Speaker 0: avoid all crypto nonsense.
Speaker 0: Do not touch.
Speaker 1: all I will say is that Scott is a very intelligent person and I trust his judgment generally on things.
Speaker 0: So no matter what happens don't touch it.
Speaker 0: So don't let anyone you know touch it.
Speaker 1: There's a couple things going on I want to highlight cuz it's a weird situation.
Speaker 1: It's the kind of thing that is specifically like there are laws and regulations to make this not happen In real finance, so there's a fair shit coin Which is what Wall Street actually calls most crypto currencies anything like doge and shiba.
Speaker 1: You'll see people literally just call them shit coin in professional settings Which is really funny sometimes when it's like an old trader guy being like, oh, yeah, I got options on this shit coin.
Speaker 0: Yeah, man, it's pretty much, you know, this Bitcoin and there's the etherium one and everything else a shit coin.
Speaker 1: So I also will make it clear.
Speaker 1: I am merely stating opinion and other people's reporting and I am not necessarily saying that I That's not to say the Bitcoin and a theory of aren't also shit, which they are Yeah, but they're not shit coins as a term.
Speaker 1: That is kind of a for real term.
Speaker 1: So yes, there was a shit coin that you have all heard of called the doge coin Which was made as a joke, but now people are all made as a joke.
Speaker 0: Well as a single one of them they made it in the good.
Speaker 1: They didn't even make it to make money.
Speaker 1: They made it to be funny, but then people started using it.
Speaker 0: So they made a theory him too because they were mad about World of Warcraft.
Speaker 0: So someone is true.
Speaker 0: That's not an exaggeration.
Speaker 1: I mean, wait till people find out what mount gox came from.
Speaker 1: so Anyway, there's a coin a shit coin called Shiba Inu.
Speaker 1: It is just this garbage coin that is just a picture of a Shiba, you know, and there's like trillions of them.
Speaker 1: They're worth like nothing individually.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you make up your own coin, you can mint as many as you want.
Speaker 0: So this coin suddenly you make the rules got it.
Speaker 1: so many people bought this coin like just now That it is in the top 10 cryptocurrencies on earth.
Speaker 1: It has more capital market value on paper than like Pinterest or Etsy does.
Speaker 1: it is like huge now top 10, right?
Speaker 0: But that capital market value is calculated by saying, okay Well the most recent person to buy this for real money paid this much for one coin Multiplied by the number of coins that exist.
Speaker 0: and the number of coins that exist was what did you say?
Speaker 0: trillions like?
Speaker 1: Yeah, right, but people selling paid.
Speaker 0: So someone paid a penny a real US penny for one of these coins.
Speaker 0: Then the total market value would be a trillion divided by a hundred right, which is still enormous.
Speaker 1: so it is Skyrocketing right now and people keep buying it so you could sell it for those prices at least.
Speaker 1: right now People are not buying these coins with actual money.
Speaker 1: They're buying them with another crypto currency Called tether.
Speaker 1: like more than 80% of all the purchases of this coin are using tether a different coin.
Speaker 1: That coin is pegged to the US dollar.
Speaker 1: So theoretically one tether coin is always worth exactly one US dollar.
Speaker 0: So if I want to go buy some tether, right?
Speaker 0: Like I give a US dollar to someone and I get a tether Right, so I could be buying that from someone who has a tether already.
Speaker 0: Yep, right, but I at some point they need to mint more tethers Right.
Speaker 1: Oh, so the way they did this was by saying they will hold dollars for every tether coin that exists Like a go like there's a backing to the.
Speaker 0: so I could go to the main bank of tether And if I give them a US dollar and they'll put it in their vault and mint a tether and give it to me.
Speaker 1: So that's what they said.
Speaker 1: Turns out and there's a ton of reporting on this.
Speaker 1: the feds are investigating them.
Speaker 0: So what dollars are they using to pay their bills if they're keeping them all in the vault?
Speaker 1: So they do not appear to actually have the dollars that they said they have don't say yeah surprise.
Speaker 1: So people are using the pegged back Chip coin that's probably fake to buy the sheep coin that is currently pumped.
Speaker 1: and All of this leads to the third factor that makes this ridiculous 70% of all the Shiba Inu coins are owned by Ten people.
Speaker 1: well ten wallets ten wallets could be one person could be one person and no more than ten entities.
Speaker 0: Oh, it could be more than ten entities because they could like share the wallet number with each other Like, you know a married couple or something?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that get.
Speaker 1: that gets weirdly complicated because of the way the habit wallets I'm just saying technically right but what that means is that Most of those coins are owned by probably the people who are doing the pump and dump.
Speaker 1: and if those people sell even a tiny Fraction of their coins they'll cash out and everyone else.
Speaker 1: It'll drop down to zero basically, right?
Speaker 0: So the point all you have to do to avoid this scam is don't buy crypto currency Don't buy the coins right because that person cash.
Speaker 0: in order for that person to cash out and be wealthy They need to actually at the end of the day convince real people.
Speaker 0: they had to be like, okay I'm ready to sell all these coins in this wallet this trillion coins.
Speaker 0: You'd actually need.
Speaker 1: I checked it's.
Speaker 1: it's now 78% of all sheep coins are held by like 10 people.
Speaker 0: Right, but you need to go and find someone to actually buy those coins from you.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter what the number says on the Market website or whatever.
Speaker 0: if you can't find people to who will actually buy them from you It's like I'll be a billionaire.
Speaker 0: You have to find people who will collectively give you a billion dollars.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like it.
Speaker 0: that's not gonna have.
Speaker 1: there's this concept of a limit order book and liquidity.
Speaker 1: if there's a really liquid stock There's tons of people buy it and sell it it.
Speaker 1: if it's not that liquid You'll see a book where there's a ton of people willing to sell it and there's like one weird nerd willing to buy it.
Speaker 1: And what's that?
Speaker 0: We're you got all you got.
Speaker 0: imagine the gathering black Lotus right which is tech, you know back in my day It was worth $300.
Speaker 0: I don't know what it's worth now according to you know, the price guys.
Speaker 0: It was worth $300 back then.
Speaker 0: I'm sure it's worth much more now But if you had one It's like.
Speaker 0: in order to get the $300 you had to find a human being with $300 who would Agree to the exchange.
Speaker 0: it wasn't like cash where it's just guaranteed $300.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, of course, it wasn't hard to find such a person But it you know, it wasn't like a guarantee.
Speaker 0: But if you want to sell a million crap coins that are technically worth a dollar each to get a million dollars You have to find someone who has a million dollars.
Speaker 1: All right, so in January a black Lotus sold for five hundred and eleven thousand dollars.
Speaker 0: I Just robbed that fucking kid who had a whole binder full of them in.
Speaker 0: Literally in 1993 I was at a table and at the same table as me with someone with one of those binders where there's you know Nine cards per page and they had several pages of just black lotuses.
Speaker 1: I was in a tournament where they had a Contest where if you had a chaos orb, which is also a valuable magic card It was a card with a gimmick where you'd like throw it at the table.
Speaker 0: I know I had.
Speaker 0: we had that card.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's that car.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I still have it, but I might have.
Speaker 1: it was moderately valuable at the time and the contest was you had to have What at least one of those cards?
Speaker 1: You could enter the contest as many times as you wanted once per card and the contest was who can throw their chaos orb the furthest And the winner got a black Lotus Mmm, but you're risking damaging your all at the time also relatively valuable chaos orb.
Speaker 0: Well, a chaos orb is the same as any other magic card, so what a practice throwing forests.
Speaker 1: And yeah, you don't fight like you get one shot with the real card, right?
Speaker 0: If my once I got my forest throw real down pat and I was sure I was gonna win then I would enter.
Speaker 0: But if I couldn't get the forest throw down then I wouldn't enter.
Speaker 1: All right pass orbs today are worth like three grand.
Speaker 0: All right, maybe I got one.
Speaker 0: if I got one I'll sell it.
Speaker 0: What's?
Speaker 0: I know I have a demonic tutor.
Speaker 0: What's that worth?
Speaker 1: Uh, I feel like that's though.
Speaker 1: I think that was actually only an uncommon card.
Speaker 1: Technically.
Speaker 1: I have a bunch of them Let's see.
Speaker 0: I got a copy artifact.
Speaker 0: Maybe what else do I have?
Speaker 0: soul ring?
Speaker 1: I mean, I have a complete revised set.
Speaker 0: Doesn't have moxes and black lotuses.
Speaker 1: No because boxes and black lotuses were they Unlimited was the last set.
Speaker 1: those were in.
Speaker 1: yeah demonic tutor three grand for a high quality one 40 bucks 40 bucks for ours.
Speaker 0: Yeah, mine mines the the used one ours are worth about.
Speaker 0: he actually tutored a card with it.
Speaker 1: What value my tutor was in every fucking deck I made cuz.
Speaker 0: of course it is.
Speaker 0: It's actually a good card.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So speaking of financial shenanigans This is another story that's nuts and I actually kind of approve of what they did.
Speaker 1: This is cool.
Speaker 1: So there's an Andy Warhol pen drawing Of fairies, it's good was called.
Speaker 1: what fairies?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I've never.
Speaker 0: I didn't see it until today.
Speaker 0: Yep, but it's a Original Andy Warhol artwork.
Speaker 0: He the actual Andy Warhol held a pen drew this artwork on a piece of paper.
Speaker 0: It's a physical artifact.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not a bullshit NFT.
Speaker 0: It's a real one.
Speaker 1: Yeah It was valuable because Andy Warhol physically touched it.
Speaker 1: we know for a fact it is the original.
Speaker 1: Absolutely, the chain of Providence is unbroken and It's sold recently to a group for a reasonable size of some of money.
Speaker 1: They bought they paid 20 grand for it.
Speaker 0: That's for an Andy an original Andy Warhol.
Speaker 0: That's okay.
Speaker 1: Yep So then they used they analyzed it they scanned it they used printing materials and like a machine that will draw with a pen to make Extremely high quality forgeries of this drive.
Speaker 0: But but the thing is those forgeries even if you so I think the technique they used was like, you know They had like a robot.
Speaker 0: He'll hold a pen and move it around a piece of paper, right with more.
Speaker 1: I look.
Speaker 1: they actually did more than you think they did.
Speaker 0: they get the exact right paper and the that's only got the right Exact.
Speaker 0: they got right ink.
Speaker 1: So it looks like they got correct ink.
Speaker 1: They also got correct old ink.
Speaker 0: Yeah, apparently Otherwise because the idea is that no one should be able to tell right.
Speaker 0: but you could tell with some aging Techniques if you didn't use old paper and old pen.
Speaker 0: Yeah You could also.
Speaker 0: they might did.
Speaker 0: the specialist might be able to detect when the ink dried and then you'd be in.
Speaker 0: they'd get you.
Speaker 1: so part of what they did too is that the robot actually Recreates the like the strokes of the pen in the right order and the depths and everything.
Speaker 1: so Supposedly so far they've had a lot of experts examine these and nobody can tell the difference.
Speaker 0: Nobody can get it Right, I think you would need to use like, you know, you couldn't do it with like your magnifying glass.
Speaker 0: You would need to do it with like, you know Some kind of science like, you know, take a piece of the paper and you know, so we don't know We don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't know what kind of stuff they do.
Speaker 1: So we don't know if someone will ever prove which one is the original again.
Speaker 1: So now they're selling all Thousand of these for $250 each.
Speaker 1: so basically you can pay $250 for a one in a thousand chance of having an original a war haul.
Speaker 0: That's the same as when they sell, you know expensive raffle tickets for a luxury car.
Speaker 1: Yeah, same deal, but there's more to it than that.
Speaker 1: They have themselves Shall they?
Speaker 1: they randomized it such that they don't know which one is the original anymore either?
Speaker 0: How do you know that they did that?
Speaker 0: That's the best the thing.
Speaker 0: they could have made a thousand forgeries and lock the real one Just and left.
Speaker 1: so it's.
Speaker 1: I hope that they have not cheated this and that they honestly don't know because that makes us a thousand times funnier.
Speaker 1: You'd read the article because it's either.
Speaker 0: the point is the profits on this right minus the cost of them to make the reproductions, right?
Speaker 0: $250 times a thousand is 250 grand.
Speaker 0: They made a profit of 230 grand.
Speaker 1: Yep, and even better Think about what this does on one hand protect Assume they did it right and no one can tell and the chain of Providence is broken Which is what they are trying to do.
Speaker 1: They just turned and they destroyed the idea of their being an original and there are now a thousand functionally identical originals.
Speaker 1: Good the argument being do you appreciate the art or are you paying for the fact that this one human touched this?
Speaker 1: And my argument is that here's the real question Is a stupid thing to care about right?
Speaker 0: if you appreciate the art then you should be fine Buying one that is known to be fake.
Speaker 0: just get a print.
Speaker 0: and if you if you're okay getting a print You can get a print for less than 250 dollars.
Speaker 1: I mean we have a painting in the bed.
Speaker 0: anyone pay.
Speaker 0: anyone spending the 250 is not someone who only Appreciates the art.
Speaker 0: right because you could just if you only wanted to have this particular artwork You know to in a physical form to hang on your wall or something you could get it for less than 250.
Speaker 1: Yep In fact high quality prints like you can get painting prints that also have the 3d texture like other that know.
Speaker 1: only an expert is Gonna even notice that it's not identical to the original.
Speaker 0: Well, I think they'll know because it's the Mona Lisa and your house is not the Louvre.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you come over.
Speaker 1: It's like rims that a new Picasso Like.
Speaker 0: Right, it's we know because we're in your apartment and your We know but it's not the other.
Speaker 1: the other cool thing about this is basically what it did.
Speaker 1: is it turned this one work?
Speaker 1: Into a thousand shares of this work.
Speaker 1: You're almost buying one thousandth of the original work and then you get a token that is the work itself to appreciate.
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 1: it's just an interesting art project as a whole like the thing.
Speaker 0: I do appreciate it as a Commentary on you know, the the art world and also the you know, the very present NFT world.
Speaker 0: Yep so laughing in their face, so I hope I Really?
Speaker 1: Hope no one ever figures out what the original one was ever.
Speaker 0: I hope it is actually impossible I bet they you know, the other thing is they could have like destroyed after scanning.
Speaker 0: They could have just gotten rid of the original.
Speaker 1: that would have been a pro move.
Speaker 0: No the pro No one can tell because they're all actually identical because they're all fake ones.
Speaker 0: The real one is somewhere, you know.
Speaker 1: Well the probe.
Speaker 1: you know what I would do if I was running this company.
Speaker 1: I'd sell a thousand fakes and the original would just be in my house and I would never tell anyone.
Speaker 0: Well, someone would find out when you died or whatever.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, I'm dead at that point.
Speaker 1: Who cares?
Speaker 1: Oh In my will my will will literally just be fuck you.
Speaker 1: I had the original bury with me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I want to be able to.
Speaker 0: I want to go.
Speaker 0: the laugh from the afterlife continued at.
Speaker 0: my continued scam Continues to scam.
Speaker 1: be right before you die you launch it into space in a low-earth orbit.
Speaker 1: Yeah Anyway anyway in the final big news we should.
Speaker 1: well one big news recently talked about Facebook as was rumored changed his name officially to meta and they're doing a whole thing.
Speaker 1: We'll probably talk about that more on Mondays and Tuesdays where it's more relevant.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there can as everyone predicted.
Speaker 0: They're trying to basically, you know Fulfill some dystopian cyberpunk dream and they're probably gonna fail.
Speaker 1: What I hate is that a lot of these tech bros when they think about the metaverse They're trying to recreate like the libertarian dystopia aspect of it with like property ownership and real estate and NFTs and bullshit instead of just a creative place for people to interact.
Speaker 1: We'll see how this goes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think they read too much snow crash.
Speaker 0: It's like we need to get them watching more ghosts in the shell, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, cyber space should be this place where you know information is Granted.
Speaker 1: what happens in ghost in the shell?
Speaker 1: because in standalone complex and second gig Every time the major goes in spies on regular like not police cyber ninjas doing shit.
Speaker 1: They're all just sharing ridiculous Conspiracy theories and being wrong about stuff.
Speaker 0: and for my call but I'm saying but that's the button goes kind of like the real world.
Speaker 0: Most of the message of ghosts in the shell isn't about the cyberspace It's about the you know, the the combination of you know, your body with with technology man machine interface.
Speaker 0: What is man wise machine since we're not since we're not cyborg ng at least we are cyborg ng, but we're not you know Robot brain cyborg in our lifetimes.
Speaker 0: most likely right that if you just look at the cyberspace In the ghost in the shell world on its own It's a lot more like the real one.
Speaker 0: It's just like a place of free information sharing Yeah, and it doesn't.
Speaker 0: there's no ownership in cyberspace.
Speaker 0: There's power because you might have more computing power at your disposal Or you might have control over information if you have large computing systems You know or satellites or who knows what hardware you own in the real world.
Speaker 0: But there's no ownership in the cyberspace itself and that's yeah the correct way.
Speaker 1: But I am regardless of the technology and what they're trying to build.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about that another time.
Speaker 1: I am so confident.
Speaker 1: the reason they are changing their name is not because of the new project but because they have fully internalized that the brand.
Speaker 1: Facebook is Permanently poisoned and toxic to anyone who is not wearing blinders and over the age of like 50 at this point.
Speaker 1: Well, I think it's also like young people like Facebook is what old people use to like buy horse paste.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, you know Google right they got their alphabet thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like but that was clearly just a corporate like shell company to be able to be flexible for like Corporate governance and like finance reasons and regulatory.
Speaker 0: I think that that's also a reason that Facebook is doing this also, right?
Speaker 0: You know Facebook is just one product that of what of the many things that meta will.
Speaker 1: but here's the difference.
Speaker 1: Google kept the Google brand on almost everything.
Speaker 1: No one talks about out the brand on.
Speaker 0: they're gonna eat the Facebook brand on Facebook.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but meta doesn't have the Facebook brand on it because they got to get rid of that Facebook brand.
Speaker 0: The alphabet doesn't have the Google brand on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz Google doesn't have the alphabet brand on it either It doesn't.
Speaker 1: Facebook isn't gonna have the meta brand on it Yeah, but I'm pretty sure Facebook is going to be in a long decline to eventually being destroyed or merged.
Speaker 0: Well, there have been many many rumors, you know of and and you know some people with pretty good, you know takes Showing like yeah, you know, why is Facebook doing the things it's doing is because it's just not doing well.
Speaker 0: But you know long-term financially it's like yes social networks.
Speaker 0: That's how they do.
Speaker 0: they rise and then they fall that the young people are not using the Facebook.
Speaker 0: It's they got this large group of old people and Facebook Recognizes that even if it has such a large user base that it will last for quite a while It only sells so much horse pace to so many QAnon.
Speaker 0: All the kids all the kids are using something else, right.
Speaker 0: so that's why Facebook acquired the Instagram and the whatsapp.
Speaker 0: But you know those things too, right?
Speaker 0: It's like they'll fade just like myspace faded right everything over time.
Speaker 0: It's like here's a user base and then the new people use something else and they recognize.
Speaker 0: if they just stay as Facebook with that Social garbage social network as their primary business that at some point, you know could be a decade could be who knows?
Speaker 0: It's just gonna go downhill and that's gonna be it and that that time would be within Zuck's life.
Speaker 0: He's not that old.
Speaker 0: So he has in personal incentive since if he was really old He might not do this because he'd be dead by the time Facebook died, but you know, he's unlikely to die soon.
Speaker 0: So he needs to make sure that you know, if the Facebook dies within his life that the company he's still CEO of something important.
Speaker 1: Now the other thing going on here is remember those all the whistleblowers and all those Facebook papers leaked recently in Congress investigating and Yeah, there's a lot of risk involved.
Speaker 0: They might you might lose the Instagram and the whatsapp if there's any trust that breaks them up.
Speaker 1: Well in the last ten days We've seen revelations that as bad as we thought Facebook was as bad as I talk about Facebook being it is It did things that are so much worse than I even imagined.
Speaker 1: and this stuff Imagined all those things, you know, I did not specifically but in general Yeah, but the worst part is you can see clear evidence that every smart person inside of Facebook was Constantly raising the alarm.
Speaker 1: people were quitting over this stuff.
Speaker 1: people are constantly raising ethics complaints and it was all ignored in the name of engagement and protecting the User base of primarily angry conservatives.
Speaker 0: there were you know, I'm not gonna say that like this, you know There were many many instances of what you just described.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there were.
Speaker 0: if you read all the documents I didn't read all of them, but I read the handful.
Speaker 0: I guess there were a few instances where they did take the advice and made things better that is
Speaker 1: true
Speaker 0: but those happened to be cases where Taking the advice and making things better was not a severe, you know damage to the to the bottom line Yep,
Speaker 1: and that Facebook still needs to be broken up and literally shut down.
Speaker 1: It is a material threat to modern democracy, right?
Speaker 0: But Facebook is wasn't you know, anyone who's like all Facebook is being evil for the sake of being evil.
Speaker 0: No, they're starting anybody, you know, they figure it out.
Speaker 0: It's only for the sake that capitalist.
Speaker 0: You know motive is the motive right?
Speaker 0: They're not like hey, hey, hey, let's have people die and spread, you know vaccine misinfo Like hey if you if you stops people from spreading vaccine misinfo they stop using Facebook.
Speaker 0: shit Yeah, and then we make less money on ads.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, so last there's two other little newses.
Speaker 1: in our hometown of New York City in Queens in Astoria We won a fight like the people of Astoria to not put a big Basically gas-powered plants right in the middle of popular air in our neighborhood.
Speaker 0: There's already two Generation lance.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're not like the main power plants.
Speaker 0: They're you know, those the ones that turn on and help out when the you know, we're all got our air conditioners.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right and it's you know.
Speaker 0: They actually call it asthma alley.
Speaker 0: because what do you know?
Speaker 0: the largest public housing project in the world is right next to one Yep, and there's another.
Speaker 0: there's two more right in between in the in the in the space between the two different power plants.
Speaker 0: Not only is my apartment but two more so three.
Speaker 1: So they only put these power plants where poor people live.
Speaker 0: three total large public housing projects including the largest in the nation.
Speaker 0: So It's called asthma alley because guess what kids who grow up in this particular area?
Speaker 0: They have more asthma than the highway higher significantly higher rate than kids who live and I don't know a green Rich people mansion full of trees and yeah with no power plants nearby because nimby's won't let it a power plant now.
Speaker 1: We do need power plants But they not yet built in places that make sense from a scientific and social perspective Not from a where rich people want them to go.
Speaker 0: perspective, right?
Speaker 0: So they were basically, you know planning to you know, sort of stem the tide or whatever and you know upgrade Add another.
Speaker 0: you know Power plant on the north end that was going to burning like fracked gas gas that was obtained via Fracking which we shouldn't be fracking in the first place but it's you know natural gas power plant and the people got together and We nimby'd that.
Speaker 0: yeah, I'm right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it wasn't a wrong nimby.
Speaker 1: Well what I've read I was like grades were unnecessary and all they do is continue to invest in fossil fuels rather than alternatives Right, so I was.
Speaker 0: I was like, hey listen, you know Feel free.
Speaker 0: I wasn't nimbying.
Speaker 0: I was like look feel free to build a power plant build.
Speaker 0: You could build two power plants.
Speaker 0: You know the power plant Right next door to my fucking house as long as it's like a solar plant or a wind plant Yeah, or some kind of geotherm.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: nothing does something that doesn't fucking burn.
Speaker 1: Yeah, put up a thorium salt.
Speaker 1: put a thorium salt reactor right next to my apartment.
Speaker 1: I would pray I would fly would crowdfund that shit nuke.
Speaker 0: Oh, you could put the nuclear one there I don't care because remember kids coal power plants.
Speaker 0: Well modern good kind and not the old shitty kind.
Speaker 1: even the old shitty kind is.
Speaker 0: I'd take over any coal plant coal over over Yes, but I would if there's that's.
Speaker 0: that's something that if they were gonna build the old shitty kind I'd go out there with a protest sign say yeah, please build the newer better kind.
Speaker 1: But that's that's something that a lot of environmental activists like to forget.
Speaker 1: like they'll they'll point out the damage and danger Of like a second generation nuclear power plant like one of the old light water reactors.
Speaker 1: But it's not light water reactor or nothing.
Speaker 1: It's light water reactor or coal or oil or something equally shitty.
Speaker 1: or worse coal power plants release more new radiation into the atmosphere Than all nuclear power plants combined ever have including Chernobyl and three-mile island.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so how did we stop this?
Speaker 0: Well, there were a few Like.
Speaker 0: that's the reason I want to talk about.
Speaker 0: it is because it's like hey a bad politics was gonna happen and we stopped it.
Speaker 0: So looking at how we stopped it is important if a bad politics is gonna happen near you and you live in a democracy Right, so there are three three key things that we did to stop it, right?
Speaker 0: Well, I guess I guess a few.
Speaker 0: They're all kind of related.
Speaker 0: But the number one thing to stop it was that we got lucky and changed the governor at the right time.
Speaker 0: The governor the old governor would have done it and we that governor got booted.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we got a new governor who didn't do it.
Speaker 0: That's the main thing.
Speaker 1: new governor has actually been pretty stand-up so far to be a new governor wants to get reelected very badly Yeah, so there If competition as good as she is we're still gonna primary from as far left as we can Probably yeah.
Speaker 0: So that's that's the key number.
Speaker 0: second key Obviously, you can't replicate the first one unless you go hire private investigator to spy on the governor.
Speaker 0: Granted bad politician find a skeleton in their closet.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: the more conservative a politician is the more skeletons tend to be in their closets.
Speaker 0: So harder to get those skeletons that is harder to get heart and harder to get anyone to care about those skeletons.
Speaker 1: Yep I mean Half the Republicans out there.
Speaker 1: their skeletons are like out paraded around on a daily basis and they still get really good.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean compare right?
Speaker 0: Anthony Weiner skeleton came out career over.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not.
Speaker 0: not that he's good.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying he was a Democrat and his skeleton there are out and his career was over.
Speaker 1: skeletons only.
Speaker 0: What about the comedy guy who was the senator at Franken?
Speaker 0: right out?
Speaker 0: skeleton out career over, right?
Speaker 0: But then what do you got in the Republican side with the gates guy?
Speaker 0: tell a thousand six-foot skeletons?
Speaker 0: They're like five.
Speaker 1: they're dancing around doing the xylophone thing in his front yard Exactly.
Speaker 0: So the second thing that we did is not just did we protest and organize and do all those normal protest things that you Right, but our local politicians were on our side helping us organizing.
Speaker 0: So that was good.
Speaker 0: that helped as well.
Speaker 0: but the in during those protests activities there were two main activities that helped the most because Number one they had to take by law.
Speaker 0: Public comments there was not like some change org bullshit, right?
Speaker 0: We're talking, you know Agency that was in charge of this had to have a public comment period.
Speaker 0: then we submitted official public comments that go in the record and 85% of those comments are saying what the fuck are you doing?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: and the second thing was they had to have a public hearings Right where people actually were.
Speaker 0: they were digital because it was the zoom times and you go to the public hearing and make a public comment in person and Pretty much 99.9% of the people who bothered to go there which was quite a few people because they were organized Went there and went to their face and said you're the person who can decide to do this or not.
Speaker 0: I live here don't do it and That was pretty significant.
Speaker 0: right, you know your change that org ain't gonna do nothing, but your your official Public comment will do something.
Speaker 0: So if something's happening and you don't like it and you wanted to stop from happening You should find out if there is official public comment or public hearing and Organize to spam that shit and that will have an impact of some kind and prevent you from going up from two power plants to three.
Speaker 1: Last last little thing so Not to belabor the point but the state of Texas in the United States has basically been speed running Destroy democracy lately.
Speaker 1: like they have done so many egregious things as a state that We literally could not list them in a reasonable amount of time.
Speaker 0: It is several other states are watching that speed run on state Whatever and and they're gonna.
Speaker 0: they're learning all the strats and they're gonna copy whatever works democracy.
Speaker 0: They're all in the same discord channel working with each other.
Speaker 1: So Texas has done so many bad things that like like I'm boycotting Texas personally I will not do.
Speaker 1: I will not visit Texas.
Speaker 1: I will not do.
Speaker 0: I mean I wasn't even happy too happy about going to Texas before nope.
Speaker 1: We went to Texas for packs.
Speaker 1: That was the only times I ever Another way over the line.
Speaker 1: Yep Like I would I if there even is a pack South which I doubt Considering some of the things Texas did might literally prevent there from being a pack South like banning vaccine mandates for events.
Speaker 1: But it's gotten so bad that today the NAACP Has called for a very targeted boycott of Texas will likely see them call for more.
Speaker 1: They issued a very long Very powerful statement.
Speaker 1: They're basically Urging all Professional athletes who are in free agency meeting if I mean this varies depending on the sport, but basically they could switch teams.
Speaker 1: There's no there's no like contract preventing them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, free agency means, you know, you can go to any team you want that you agreed to sign a contract with yep.
Speaker 1: So they're basically urging any athlete in any professional organ is sports of any kind To refuse to take free agency for any team in Texas until the voting laws the anti LGBT laws the I mean, there's like ten different things.
Speaker 1: the abortion laws are over peeled Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I urge you to boycott Strategy, I don't know how many people are gonna listen if it'll matter but it's like yeah You you probably shouldn't go to work in Texas if you're a professional athlete.
Speaker 1: Yeah About this an individual person Has especially someone who is in a position of do I take a job in Texas or do I take no job?
Speaker 1: It's hard to blame a person for taking the job when the alternative is nothing and they're fine.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's several people I know who are considered good friends and they live in Texas.
Speaker 0: But it's like, you know, I can't be like, you know, it's like I would like them to leave, Texas They might even want to leave or you know, they're not able to afford to right.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know and as bad as Texas is.
Speaker 0: it's like I don't blame the people of Texas for what is happening in, Texas Right, I blame 44% of the people of Texas, right?
Speaker 0: It's like the.
Speaker 0: you know There's a large number of people close to half even that are good people who don't like this or is half of the voting people.
Speaker 0: and You know, it's just the people who are causing the bad thing.
Speaker 0: Those are the you know, the politicians who run, Texas Those are the ones who must be you know be harmed, right?
Speaker 1: Yep, but basically the but the argument is that one if an athlete does this it's highly visible like it'll make up news And that person is not risking their personal livelihood the way that like some schmuck work in minimum wages.
Speaker 0: Nope, and also there are people in Texas who may be bad people but also sports fans.
Speaker 0: Right if an athlete does this to them They'll obviously hate that athlete forever and have them on their shit list and boo them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're forced to play away games in Texas, by the way They should boycott away games in Texas.
Speaker 1: I think the NFL should just refuse to allow Texas teams to compete.
Speaker 0: Well, NFL is not gonna do that.
Speaker 0: I know they're not But I don't think you'd be able to go that far, right?
Speaker 0: You'll probably have to play away games in Texas if you're playing against a Texas team.
Speaker 1: well at some point we might have to because part of what the NAACP is arguing is that What's happening in Texas right now is the first domino of a very rapid destruction of democracy in America?
Speaker 1: And their argument is basically that we have to use every available tool even with collateral damage and harm as fast as possible to stop Texas from continuing down this path or Everyone in America is at extreme risk.
Speaker 0: We are been at extreme risk.
Speaker 1: Yep That's why I heard like if Pac South happens don't fucking go to it.
Speaker 0: I would not unless it's not in Texas.
Speaker 1: if they move it to like, Georgia or like a place that we might be able to You know the greatest but Georgia Georgia's do it.
Speaker 1: Okay, Georgia is fighting the fight a little bit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'd go there right now I would go to.
Speaker 1: I would go to Georgia.
Speaker 1: I would not go to Texas.
Speaker 1: Not gonna Florida's in the shit list - yep, or bring it to Detroit the the most non-white big city in America.
Speaker 1: That would be the most accessible packs that America wouldn't get any money.
Speaker 1: No one Yeah, but it would also be the packs that the most disenfranchised people and the most underprivileged I bet they could a lot of gamers with the ticket price, uh, you could run it pretty cheap in Detroit with I Bet the game.
Speaker 1: I mean the game industry showed up to Texas to a degree.
Speaker 1: I feel like to really just be easier barely anyway.
Speaker 1: but anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: so uh You ever wonder you know, most people drive manual transmissions.
Speaker 1: I would argue that in the modern world Automatic transmissions charges the default and it's weird to have a manual transmission like just get rid of them.
Speaker 1: They're done that ships.
Speaker 0: You might need it for racing or for some other Specialized cars for specialized a big truck, right?
Speaker 0: So, you know, yeah
Speaker 1: God double clutches anyway, I do not miss manual transmissions, but You ever you know as a kid with the manual transmission and even with an automatic always thought about like hey What if I just fucking put this thing in reverse while I'm on the freeway,
Speaker 0: but of course It'll stop you from doing that.
Speaker 1: Yeah automatic transmissions won't let you do that.
Speaker 1: But this video asked the question what if you just take a manual transmission car like a bog standard one and Just put it in reverse while you're going at speed and it is not.
Speaker 1: what do you expect?
Speaker 1: Spoilers.
Speaker 1: Yes, you can do it, but you gotta muscle it You gotta.
Speaker 1: it's actually physically hard to do but the car doesn't stop you from doing it if you make it work.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, and in this video the gentleman is able to make it happen at At a pretty high speed on a highway and it is really funny.
Speaker 1: Okay, and I'll leave it at that.
Speaker 1: You can skip through the video to find the good part.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, there's 10 minutes of a start YouTube comment that has the timecode in it to click on.
Speaker 1: Nope There but the guy spends 10 minutes talking about transmissions and honestly if you don't know anything about cars You'll probably learn a lot from this guy.
Speaker 0: should watch my thing of the day from a week or two ago with the guy who?
Speaker 0: Takes apart transmissions.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but manuals.
Speaker 1: manual transmissions are way simpler than automatic transmission.
Speaker 0: He does he did a manual at least once.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's just so few people have manuals.
Speaker 0: So he did right.
Speaker 0: so it's like he's in a transmission shop.
Speaker 0: He's showing you what he's working on.
Speaker 0: It's like people come in for transmission repair.
Speaker 0: How many people come in with manuals not too many.
Speaker 1: So the last time I drove a manual transmission was in the year 2000 and Five.
Speaker 0: I Don't remember what probably last I probably last run.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was it.
Speaker 0: I think I haven't driven a real manual transmission since like so other than that truck the previous time before like 2005.
Speaker 1: ish that's your plenty of manuals though.
Speaker 0: Lots.
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 1: Yeah was uh, it was the year When I borrowed my mom's Jeep Cherokee or yeah Jeep Wrangler Jeep Wrangler.
Speaker 1: that was manual.
Speaker 1: And uh, yeah, I stalled it out like five times.
Speaker 1: cuz I don't really drive manual transmissions.
Speaker 1: Even then I hadn't done it in a while anyway, so Nothing in the day here.
Speaker 0: We got this website.
Speaker 0: So the World Series is going down between two piece-of-shit teams.
Speaker 0: We got let's see.
Speaker 1: We've got the team with the racist tomahawk shot.
Speaker 0: We got the.
Speaker 0: we got racist Atlanta versus cheating, Texas actual cheating.
Speaker 1: go read about it Like we're not.
Speaker 1: even this is even worse than the whole like deflate gate thing, right?
Speaker 0: So basically no no good no good results here in the World Series just ignoring that garbage Garbage fire by the umpires.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so there's a website here that I didn't know about and a Twitter account called ump scorecards and what they do is really fascinating.
Speaker 0: I didn't realize they were collecting all this data and you know visualizing it and all that.
Speaker 0: but it's just what it sounds like.
Speaker 0: they watch pretty much every pitch in baseball and They look at who the ump is look at whether they called a ball or a strike and then Looked at what the computer said.
Speaker 0: It should have been And say oh was that you know, how often does the ump get it wrong, you know, do they get it wrong?
Speaker 0: Are they really good up right?
Speaker 0: which ump's are better than others, you know Our.
Speaker 0: this is ump like biased towards like, you know high and inside or stuff like that.
Speaker 0: And I'm sure this is not only useful to fans of baseball who love this shit But also I wouldn't be surprised if like teams are looking at this and saying all right, who's the ump today?
Speaker 0: Oh, you know that guy, you know He'll call you strikes if you even if you throw it a little low the pitcher knows that that can help you out.
Speaker 0: Yeah And this is all publicly available Very well organized and very well visualized data.
Speaker 1: Imagine doing that for hockey like.
Speaker 1: ah We got the guy who never calls cross-checking And you can even like organize.
Speaker 0: it's like the least accurate.
Speaker 0: ump's are getting it right only like 91 percent of the time.
Speaker 0: it's like that means nine percent of almost one out of ten pitches.
Speaker 0: They're getting wrong That's.
Speaker 0: yeah, I think that's really.
Speaker 0: that's really bad, right?
Speaker 0: The best ump gets it right 96 percent of the time.
Speaker 0: so that's that's not too bad, right?
Speaker 1: Yep computers can get it right like a hundred percent of the time.
Speaker 1: They just don't fully look at the tennis thing.
Speaker 0: The tennis thing always gets it right The eagle whatever.
Speaker 0: I don't know what they call it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I met a moment geek knives book club book tale again.
Speaker 1: Gee, we're reading it.
Speaker 0: Uh, check this out.
Speaker 0: Check this out.
Speaker 0: I got the new that I guess the light is gonna make it see count.
Speaker 0: There you go.
Speaker 1: No, that's the new paper wide.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got the new.
Speaker 0: you know, cuz I had a Kindle, you know way back in the day.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the fuck happened to it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I've been using the Kindle app on my phone when I was on the train.
Speaker 0: But you know how to read on your phone if you don't have to know and I'm not not on the train anymore.
Speaker 0: So I was using the Kindle app on my iPad, but I have a giant iPad and as a keyboard attached to it.
Speaker 0: So like reading laying down was holding this heavy iPad up in the air for an extended Genji.
Speaker 0: You're reading for an extended period not a short period.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it's like and also, you know the beach, right?
Speaker 0: So I would have bought the paper white earlier and it taken it to the beach this year.
Speaker 0: But I realized wait a minute.
Speaker 0: The Kindle paper white is like a several year old device That's got to be getting updated soon, right and sure enough it was.
Speaker 0: so yeah this I literally got this Yesterday and it was released yesterday.
Speaker 0: So hopefully this will last me many years.
Speaker 0: go to many beaches.
Speaker 0: That way I don't take my iPad to the beach.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, because I guess that will help me I already read some Genji.
Speaker 0: just cuz you know, you're a nerd You're excited to use your new technological do dead.
Speaker 1: Haha, so we'll get ready to do it.
Speaker 1: Well, really briefly talk but assume we're gonna spoil some doing stuff.
Speaker 0: so if you've never did a book club episode on dune the book.
Speaker 0: So if you haven't read doing the book you could.
Speaker 0: if you have you can go listen to that episode.
Speaker 0: if you haven't Yep, read the book right or I guess you could just watch this movie and listen to this episode.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I would not say it's bad.
Speaker 1: Like if you watch this movie It's pretty good at like conveying what the book conveys Like it's.
Speaker 1: you could do fine by just watching.
Speaker 0: but we're gonna spoil, you know, I guess book and movie But they're almost the same so it's not really any different.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there is having read the book Nothing in the movie was out of place, right?
Speaker 0: It's like I was effectively a hundred percent spoiled on it.
Speaker 0: Yep, so But yeah, we're gonna spoil the book and movie of do and there's no point.
Speaker 0: it's a really old book.
Speaker 0: It's older than me.
Speaker 0: I think you're as old as me at least.
Speaker 1: so so all over the main I'll say before we will just start spoiling stuff about Duncan Idaho is that the movie is really good and you should see it.
Speaker 0: I just watched an HBO max.
Speaker 1: No problem Yep, it just worked.
Speaker 1: It was perfectly fine quality.
Speaker 1: My sole complaint was that the dialogue was in many scenes a little bit hard to hear because there was way Low in the mix compared.
Speaker 0: Well, that's because right.
Speaker 0: so that's a common problem.
Speaker 0: I've noticed I don't.
Speaker 0: I'm sure I'd love to talk to like a Hollywood audio expert to find the reason for this.
Speaker 0: But I've noticed this pattern Pretty much like especially with like blu-ray rips or pretty much anything that has like a surround Hollywood movie theater mix.
Speaker 0: if you take that mix and just play it in your home without remixing it somehow It's like even on sometimes.
Speaker 0: they'll have a 5.1 surround system and like the voices will be on the center channel where they belong but they'll just be so much quieter than the explosions and the music and the Everything else.
Speaker 0: and it's like in the movie theater.
Speaker 0: I guess that's not a problem because there's a ton of speakers behind the screen But for some reason at home It becomes a problem and I'd love for someone who knows a lot about that to explain what the deal is.
Speaker 0: But I've noticed that a lot for the past 20 years.
Speaker 1: I've also noticed it more with the so-called prestige movies than with like every other regular old movie.
Speaker 0: Just not any yeah, but it's like even if I take like a Star Wars, you know Obviously not the ones that I'm watching which are you know, the the special?
Speaker 0: Despecialized editions, but if you get a Star Wars bureh, it's like.
Speaker 0: it's like actually the you know, the voice is too quiet Yep, but it's visually stunning like the acting is great the story is really stunning But the colors are.
Speaker 0: it's like it's either brown or gray.
Speaker 1: I think that works though considering what's going on.
Speaker 1: And also it is when you get shots of Caledon.
Speaker 1: It's very it's more colorful, but then we don't go back barely Barely, yeah, it's an austere future.
Speaker 0: It's not brown.
Speaker 0: So it's a contrast.
Speaker 0: Yeah you know just like the the Harkonnen plan it's black.
Speaker 0: Well, it's like very it's not.
Speaker 0: it's never multiple colors at once.
Speaker 1: if you haven't read the book or Seen the movie stop listening cuz we're gonna spoil a bunch of stuff.
Speaker 1: and if you only saw the movie Also, we're gonna spoil some stuff because the the movie stops kind of in the middle of the book right before things get weird.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they broke.
Speaker 0: they broke.
Speaker 0: So that's something they broken in two parts, right?
Speaker 0: That's a common complaint nerds have when a nerdy book gets turned into a movie is all the stuff that gets cut out because books Are fucking long.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I made a movie that had everything in the book.
Speaker 0: It would be forever.
Speaker 0: You'd be in the theater for 10 hours, which I'm fine with but not everyone is right.
Speaker 0: So then what they did in this case rather than cut things they did cut a lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean they didn't cut nothing but they didn't cut anything that was that significant.
Speaker 1: They cut the concept of men tats.
Speaker 1: they showed it and they implied what it was, but they didn't like explain it at all That's your.
Speaker 0: but yeah, it wasn't isn't?
Speaker 0: Hawaii's the mentat right and DeVry.
Speaker 0: I Guess DeVry didn't appear did they?
Speaker 1: Yeah, they died right away anyway.
Speaker 0: Hey What was I saying?
Speaker 1: well, yeah, whatever.
Speaker 1: so when you may when you adapt something like this, you can either cut a ton out or Make like split it up and make multiple movies.
Speaker 1: You can go too far.
Speaker 1: movies like the hobbit stuff where they they made way too many hours of movie.
Speaker 1: for how long that book Actually is?
Speaker 0: well the hobbit also changed way too much stuff.
Speaker 1: It was too significant a change and the hobbit got like 80% through the book at the end of its first movie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't even watch past the first time.
Speaker 1: I watched the second one.
Speaker 1: it was bad and I didn't watch anything after that.
Speaker 1: I never even saw smog.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway, anyway, so there's doing movie that just came out.
Speaker 0: So first of all, I Don't think it's like a masterpiece five-star movie.
Speaker 0: It's not like fucking Seven samurai or some, you know rear window or some shit, right?
Speaker 0: It's not like.
Speaker 0: but in terms of take a nerdy book and turned it into a movie I Don't know how you can do better.
Speaker 1: No, it didn't Do.
Speaker 1: the casting was great if like Emily has not read the book.
Speaker 1: I've read the book.
Speaker 1: We watched it together.
Speaker 1: We both reacted to it about the same level because knowing things Makes some like minor elements pop more or be interesting.
Speaker 1: but not knowing things in no way takes away From the story.
Speaker 1: that's being told.
Speaker 0: and in fact the movie spoilers.
Speaker 0: spoilers didn't spoil didn't they huh?
Speaker 0: Well, that's a thing I guess.
Speaker 1: well now because in this case I was mostly I go to a movie like this Primarily knowing what's happening.
Speaker 1: I'm just curious.
Speaker 1: How are they gonna do it?
Speaker 1: How are they gonna portray this?
Speaker 1: What is this mentat gonna act like?
Speaker 1: Oh, they did an eye thing.
Speaker 1: That's cool.
Speaker 1: I Do like the eye thing.
Speaker 1: they do okay, but The visual storytelling is really good.
Speaker 1: But really it's that it actually Tells you what's happening much more directly than the book does.
Speaker 1: in that the book like.
Speaker 1: if you read it closely It's obvious what the Emperor's plan is.
Speaker 1: But a lot of people like don't get it and it was surprising at the end of the book.
Speaker 0: The book is never saying like the.
Speaker 0: you know, the book is like.
Speaker 0: alright, you know, something's happening.
Speaker 0: Why you know, why is the the Emperor removed telling the Harkonnens to leave the spice?
Speaker 0: And bring you know, the the the Atreides in.
Speaker 0: why are they doing that?
Speaker 1: wait, why are there Sardar car there?
Speaker 1: That's weird.
Speaker 1: I thought the Emperor is on the Atreides right?
Speaker 0: Whereas this one is like Yes The Emperor is doing it because he fears Atreides is getting too powerful.
Speaker 0: more patent might overtake the Emperor.
Speaker 0: Therefore he is doing this to kill off the Atreides in a way that they can get away with it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they just spell it out for you, but they're also spoon it right in.
Speaker 1: It's also doing a really good job of spelling out the Chekhov's things that are critical to the second movie Like for example, they bring up in the movie multiple times that this there's no satellites around Dune.
Speaker 1: Well now around Dune around Arrakis - uh.
Speaker 1: But they make it clear that that is why the Emperor was able to send the Sardar car in there Because there'd be no record of it because everyone who saw them would be dead.
Speaker 1: But as you know if you've read the book the fact that there's no satellites.
Speaker 1: there is a big part of what the Fremen are up to and Also a big part of what the Emperor's up to and also a big part of how the entire plot evolves in the end.
Speaker 0: Yep But yeah, it's like, you know, I'm sure if you do I only read the book once when we did the book club.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I attempted to read it in my youth and wasn't a fan then.
Speaker 0: and um, I mean, I guess it's okay.
Speaker 0: now I'm not like a huge Dune fan.
Speaker 1: I like that book a lot But I like the prince of nothing books a lot - it's about on that level of like how much I like.
Speaker 0: There's nothing way more than we're doing.
Speaker 1: I guess the thing about dude The only problem with people I was about to say the prison nothing.
Speaker 1: The problem is the later books aren't quite as good.
Speaker 0: but dude Yeah, well, I didn't.
Speaker 0: I only ever read one Dune book.
Speaker 1: I also only ever read one.
Speaker 0: So Was it.
Speaker 0: but you know dude, I guess even if I'm not like a huge fan of it, right It's still a bunch of fun, right?
Speaker 0: Cuz you got all these proper nouns you get worms, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah It's it's just fun to do.
Speaker 0: doing stuff is fun.
Speaker 0: That's why there's so many doing me up.
Speaker 1: also, I gotta say the casting and the acting was like Absolutely.
Speaker 1: Perfect.
Speaker 1: They made Duncan, Idaho So absolutely likable.
Speaker 1: when he shows up you're like that guy's awesome.
Speaker 1: And then when he dies, you're like what the fuck you killed my favorite character right away.
Speaker 0: I knew he was gonna die though because I read the book.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's funny because everyone who has not seen Dune or red Dune like even those people have heard of Duncan Idaho because that name's ridiculous.
Speaker 1: and Yeah, Duncan, Idaho is the best character because he does come back and like almost every Dune book, right?
Speaker 0: It's like that's.
Speaker 0: I haven't read any other Dune book But I know that there's like clones of Duncan, Idaho and shit something like that.
Speaker 0: There's something along those lines In Idaho and bringing him back because even in universe too cool and fun and awesome.
Speaker 1: Yep, even in universe people are like, oh, yeah that Duncan, Idaho gotta get me some of that Give me give me a done bring me another.
Speaker 1: I broke mine.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, but people watching this movie who don't know anything about Dune are like, oh that's Duncan, Idaho I see why everyone and then he's dead and they're like, what the fuck?
Speaker 1: He's not coming back in the second movie guys He's gone right.
Speaker 0: so for me the a big complaint I have with a lot of things, right I make this complaint actually a lot about all those superhero movies.
Speaker 0: Right because like you read like a superhero comic and there's this surface level story.
Speaker 0: Let's say x-men for example, right?
Speaker 0: There's like a surface level story in x-men of oh, yeah There's bad magneto and he's gonna do something bad and these guys fight and most people will go see the movie and though That's what they'll take away from it.
Speaker 0: Right good guys bad guys fighting but x-men has a deeper story.
Speaker 0: Sometimes that deeper story is or deeper message will be you know, yeah Genocide against you know, this minority mutant people discrimination, etc.
Speaker 0: But there'll be even more layers to that.
Speaker 0: You know, like I think I've made the Claremont Twitter account a recent thing of the day, right?
Speaker 0: You can go They get pretty deep in the comics but then and there are movies that go deep.
Speaker 0: But the movies based on the written material don't go.
Speaker 0: they remove the depth right.
Speaker 0: a lot of times you know, you'll see you know a Movie based on a book and the movie is just the shallow part and they cut out the deep part Because it's a Hollywood blockbuster.
Speaker 0: So this one that is what I expected.
Speaker 0: So in Dune right the big You know from my reading of Dune and I definitely said this in the episode we did on the book.
Speaker 1: I'll link to it.
Speaker 0: yeah, the The deep parts of Dune the most the most significant part is the ecological message, right?
Speaker 0: It's mostly a story about the ecology of the planet.
Speaker 0: right the spice You know is some kind of worm jizz or some shit like that, right?
Speaker 1: Water the the fact that the Lifestyle they live there is almost a form of ecological terrorism by the colonial powers.
Speaker 1: It could have been a paradise planet.
Speaker 1: it by all rights should be a paradise planet, right the Fremen, right?
Speaker 0: They they you know, they don't try to change the planet, right?
Speaker 0: They live in harmony with their environment, right?
Speaker 0: Instead of coming in and messing it up and stealing and pillaging right that whole thing going on and I'm like Well, that's the deep message.
Speaker 0: I guess this movie is gonna cut that part out and you know what.
Speaker 0: they fucking didn't cut it out.
Speaker 0: They left.
Speaker 0: how long did they not cut it out?
Speaker 1: It's driving straight at it at lights.
Speaker 0: Yeah, as as the movie goes on they zoom in on it and I'm like they're more.
Speaker 0: it's like it's there and they keep you Know they don't let it go.
Speaker 0: They're like, yeah, it's this is gonna be a focused important thing.
Speaker 0: We're not letting go of that message and I was like, oh golf clap golf clap.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll go.
Speaker 0: also keep that shit.
Speaker 1: Liat Keynes or kinds like the the the imperial judge of whatever like.
Speaker 1: they're not, you know, the whole plot around that character.
Speaker 1: Yeah the casting for that character like changing it from a man to a woman getting the perfect actress to play that character and That character really really driving home the ecological message and then going out in a perfect blaze of glory Like that was just such a great set of scenes right there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now there were some changes but none of those changes were changes that were like Significant in terms of making dune not dune anymore, right?
Speaker 1: They left out like a bunch of extra desert scenes that didn't matter.
Speaker 1: We're like Jessica gets buried in some sand.
Speaker 1: They left out all the like dinner parties and like local political intrigue that led up to the attack.
Speaker 1: The movie starts Harkonnen attack like basically two days later.
Speaker 0: Yep What they a good example of a positive change they made right is in the book.
Speaker 0: You know The Baron Harkonnen is a sort of a fat phobia thing going on there.
Speaker 0: body shaming I mean, he's still large and I guess they didn't.
Speaker 0: but it's like, you know, I don't know They did.
Speaker 1: they made it like you look at his neck.
Speaker 1: They made him more Deformed and less just a fat person like he was often portrayed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean it's still there.
Speaker 0: But they also in the book Baron Harkonnen was like a gay pedophile, right?
Speaker 0: So it was homophobic yeah and such and that aspect completely removed.
Speaker 0: which is that right?
Speaker 0: good That was.
Speaker 0: that's unnecessary, right?
Speaker 0: We don't need the bad guy to be the.
Speaker 0: you know You make the only gay person a pedophile and also the big villain.
Speaker 0: It's like what message you sending there, right Frank Herbert was sending that message, but we don't need to spend that message anymore We'll just get that one out of there.
Speaker 0: It does not harm the story in any way.
Speaker 0: He's still the bad guy, right?
Speaker 0: You know, he's the bad guy because he's in this place.
Speaker 0: That's all black and he's killing people.
Speaker 1: The way they make him float is hyper Menacing in a very Darth Vader way and I appreciate much much better that scene where he just like floats up over the table Was perfect.
Speaker 1: It's like I got a little movie.
Speaker 0: way of floating was was much not as good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or wait or when he comes out of his vat.
Speaker 1: That was a lot like when the shell opens around Darth Vader when the Admiral comes in to report to him
Speaker 0: All right, and then you know, he's actually kind of like a scary dangerous, dude Which you see in the scene where the the poison gas comes out of the tooth, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, like, you know.
Speaker 0: So he's day.
Speaker 0: he's dangerous and capable.
Speaker 0: He's not just like a you know, an evil blob like a crang the brain from Ninja Turtles or something.
Speaker 1: But that was another good change of.
Speaker 1: they didn't leave in the fullness of the plot around the doctor and the conditioning and like the the entire convoluted plot that led up to the assassination attempt on the Baron the all they just distilled it down to.
Speaker 1: Dude knows his wife is dead.
Speaker 1: He's pertaining to go along with the Baron and betray them and he's actually betraying a trade ease.
Speaker 1: But he's actually doing all of it to assassinate the bear.
Speaker 1: They just distills it down to that essence.
Speaker 1: It doesn't get into all those other details that frankly weren't that relevant to the story And that and that aspect still like resonated really well.
Speaker 1: those scenes were great.
Speaker 0: Hey, what else is there to say about this movie?
Speaker 0: the whole time?
Speaker 0: I was watching the movie because I've read the book.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was thinking about the final scene of the book, which is You know sort of a big at the end of the book is like this big climax of awesomeness, right?
Speaker 0: And I know exactly what happens in that scene.
Speaker 0: Hopefully they don't change it because that would be very.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 1: They did in the very in the very beginning when they come in.
Speaker 1: He's like, what's that?
Speaker 1: Oh, that's the shield wall.
Speaker 0: It protects the entire city okay, but So hopefully they don't change the ending.
Speaker 0: but while I was watching it it made me Excited right, you know had positive anticipation for like ooh The final scene of this book is awesome.
Speaker 0: I Want to see that final scene at the end of this movie, right?
Speaker 0: I got.
Speaker 0: I want to see it play out on the screen even though I know what happens.
Speaker 0: Yep, right.
Speaker 0: So which means I was enjoying what I was watching.
Speaker 0: Simple as that, right?
Speaker 1: The I guess.
Speaker 1: the other thing I can I can point out is that one thing I like is a big theme in the book like the secondary theme other than the ecology and also other than the whole like Transhumanist.
Speaker 1: what are the Bene Gesserit everyone else actually up to with the breeding programs?
Speaker 1: It did a good job of like weaving that in without focusing on it.
Speaker 1: But I appreciate a big part of the book was the fact that the religion of the Fremen was fake.
Speaker 1: It's a generic religion that the Bene Gesserit seed all throughout the galaxy or the universe.
Speaker 1: even Just in case a Bene Gesserit ever gets like stuck on a planet or has a problem They can like figure out what aspects of that core religion Like how it got integrated in local society and then use the local superstitions and religion to get their way.
Speaker 1: It very subtly Does that in the movie when you see Jessica like?
Speaker 1: Talking to the Fremen and when they're like out for the first time in the desert you see the her and Paul sort of interact until they figure out like how much the religion is there and then they just dive into it.
Speaker 1: and I like how you see Them like bickering with each other with their sign language the whole time Like.
Speaker 1: I thought it did that well and it Didn't lose the idea that the Bene Gesserit planted the religion in the first place while also showing that Maybe the religion was planted there for more than one reason or maybe no one anticipated that Paul might Use it more than they expected to like that
Speaker 0: whole element Right.
Speaker 0: so the reason the religion is planted right it sort of depends the level of the perspective of how much spice and how much into the future a Person sees right.
Speaker 0: so it's all zero.
Speaker 0: You can't see into the future at all.
Speaker 0: It looks like a legitimate religion.
Speaker 0: That's what they believe right now.
Speaker 0: the next level right like Bene Gesserit level.
Speaker 0: You know they can.
Speaker 0: it's like okay like what you said.
Speaker 0: they plan it there.
Speaker 0: You know in case they might need it in the future and they're planning for the long haul, but it's like step three.
Speaker 0: Ha you know Bene Gesserit right full plan.
Speaker 0: It's like ah we knew that exactly this would happen and therefore we plant this seed Thousands of years ago in the Fremen people just for this moment.
Speaker 0: We know it's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was all set in advance and now the dominoes are falling right.
Speaker 1: finally But then you go even further.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, maybe Paul spice too much and saw beyond what you saw and now it's not your plan anymore.
Speaker 0: The K came before.
Speaker 0: yeah Darkness Spice me up.
Speaker 0: So the worm right.
Speaker 0: the thing with the worm.
Speaker 0: On the one hand I kind of you know The worm is still a pretty good design for the scenes in the movie because there's a lot of scenes like you know The worm comes straight up and it becomes like a big hole sort of like the Sarlacc.
Speaker 0: So visually for the scenes they were going for in the movie the design of the worm works, but just personally aesthetically I like the worm.
Speaker 0: that's like the head.
Speaker 0: the tip is split into three flaps.
Speaker 0: You know that style that you've seen a lot of illustrations.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty a little it on that piece.
Speaker 0: Oh, I mean, it's really minor right, but I just like the three flap worm, right?
Speaker 0: But in addition to that in the book from what I remember is Sort of like when they make Paul ride the worm spoilers for part two.
Speaker 0: Yeah When Paul rides the worm like that's I didn't if there was any instance of anyone riding a worm Before then in the book.
Speaker 0: I didn't see it.
Speaker 0: I must have missed it.
Speaker 0: So When Paul rides the worm, it's sort of like simultaneously like you can ride a worm Right, you're getting hit with both of those at once whereas in this book and in this movie.
Speaker 0: There's a scene where Kinds right holds up the two hooks and I'm ready to ride the worm and then right at the end of the movie They show you in the distance someone riding a worm.
Speaker 0: So it's like, you know, someone can ride a worm.
Speaker 0: now before Paul rides a worm.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: I Just at least I don't know if that was different because a I don't remember the book or B It was different from the book.
Speaker 1: Yeah I don't remember exactly how that scene went down But I love when Lee but it's just right pounding the sand with her fist to make sure the Sardar cargo down with her.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but yeah, it's a right because riding a worm is pretty significant.
Speaker 1: So in terms of I like how the movie did not explain how the shields work at all.
Speaker 1: But no the way they were visually portrayed makes it extremely clear the important parts about those shields except for the laser gun thing Which didn't come up yet.
Speaker 0: I mean, that's really most of what making the movie is Right, you know it since they didn't really change too much plot.
Speaker 0: Most of the decisions and the artwork of making this movie was okay.
Speaker 0: Here's what happened, right?
Speaker 0: Here's the here's the world.
Speaker 0: But what does it actually look like?
Speaker 0: All we have is a description of words.
Speaker 0: That description isn't like some rock-solid Like description where you could go to a CNC mill and create the world of dune, right?
Speaker 1: Or you've got a long dialogue of someone explaining this is how a shield works and you don't want to do that in a movie
Speaker 0: Right, you need to look at those words and be like, okay They just described what this room looks like and so you imagine the room in your head and now you need to get you Know the people who make the set the people who make the props the actors the costume people the cameras, right?
Speaker 0: this the shots everything to Make a vision image a 2d image that matches that text Right, and then since someone watching it, you know understands the story as if they were reading it.
Speaker 0: and they accomplished that very Very well, right.
Speaker 0: nothing that you saw on screen like didn't match it.
Speaker 0: you know, there's not like.
Speaker 0: oh those those ships don't look like that.
Speaker 0: or You know, that's not what a shield a shield should look like this.
Speaker 1: It's like but like the way it like turns red when something gets too close to the skin and how it's something moving slow like it Conveyed what was paragraphs and paragraphs of explanation into the book Visually simply and it worked and not not with any incorrectness.
Speaker 1: Yep I also do like the casting of Paul because he's basically just a mumbly teen Who is very rapidly outstripping his mother's powers, and I think he's just he's playing it really well Like he's just a mumbly angsty teen.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, they casted everyone really well, I think you dirty is grating the book.
Speaker 1: is there anything I don't like?
Speaker 1: no not one.
Speaker 0: but they could have.
Speaker 0: uh You know, it's like they could have gone harder right in terms of like, you know, they could have made a treatise not white You know, I mean, yeah, they could have made.
Speaker 0: you could have made Paul a woman, right?
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you could have flipped.
Speaker 0: you could have flipped it like Bene Gesserit or dudes every height and Everyone else is ladies or whatever, you know, at least I'm glad with Lea They made that was a really good casting choice at a really good character.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there were some issues though in terms of a lot of those characters that were not the white people right were killed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know you get your the doctor, you know kinds all these You know choices to go with not white people and those people all sort of died.
Speaker 1: better have more non-white people in book two Don't write Right.
Speaker 0: So it's like, you know, they did more than nothing.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't think we know who's playing the Emperor yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I do suspect the Emperor might be a black person.
Speaker 0: I really hope so especially Considering lead and like the Imperial is based also based on the Imperial stuff that you saw Like during the opening scenes, I think it could be likely.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: That's what I hope.
Speaker 0: Maybe someone out there already knows who's playing the Emperor.
Speaker 0: It's been announced or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just I don't pay that much attention.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they did only just announce that like we assumed part two is coming But they only just now firmly a hundred percent confirmed.
Speaker 0: They're gonna make the part two.
Speaker 0: So yeah But that wasn't much of a confirmation.
Speaker 0: It's like tell me something I don't know now.
Speaker 1: what I wonder is if they if they make part two and now we've got the first dune book Either they keep going They don't And even so I wanted to keep going red.
Speaker 1: I want to just go crazy.
Speaker 0: So that's the thing is not having read any book beyond book one.
Speaker 0: I still know enough to know those books are out of control.
Speaker 0: Yeah, bring me some Bennett Alaxu tanks, and I want to see what the fuck these all these They did sort of show you the you know a tank a little bit.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it's not a
Speaker 1: yeah show show me the second like the third dunk in Idaho
Speaker 0: Right, so it's like if they keep sticking to those books as they have now even if they keep putting in the same budget, it's like it's gonna fall apart because The books it's like.
Speaker 1: well if you or or here's something that can happen.
Speaker 1: Dune because the P. all the reactions I saw from people who had never read dune or just saw the movie were mostly like Wow, that went really hard.
Speaker 1: That was way more intense than I expected.
Speaker 1: Oh, it was all crazy.
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 1: I don't think they realized that maybe 10% of the crazy shit happens in what we've seen so far.
Speaker 1: Like what's gonna happen in the second movie is way off the rails of what most people are expecting if they make more of the movies.
Speaker 1: this might be a way to Like remind people that movies can be fucking weird and still be good and open the door to more me.
Speaker 0: I don't think they have the courage.
Speaker 0: I don't think they have the courage to do that?
Speaker 1: I don't either and we won't know until after the second movie is done.
Speaker 1: if they announce a movie.
Speaker 1: three I'm gonna be unreasonably excited because I want to see triple-a Blockbuster big-budget big director movie.
Speaker 1: that is as weird as what I know happens in the fourth and fifth dune books.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like the stuff that I know that happens in those books is way out there stuff That is possibly not great as a story a lot of people say unfilable similar to like the culture books, right, but I You know, even if I agree with that not how.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I agree with that cuz I've read them.
Speaker 0: But even if I believe them then that means that a I'm not gonna be too interested in those books.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but B Well, I love seeing Fucked up nonsense on movies, right?
Speaker 1: I look like fucked up Trippy space shit, that's four hours long like hook it into my veins.
Speaker 0: end of Eva end of 2001 Space Odyssey all that I love that kind of like Abstract.
Speaker 1: you want to get Scott to watch the MCU go hard into the weirdest space shit and Scott watch those movies.
Speaker 0: It's right abstract art.
Speaker 0: It's like a Picasso, right?
Speaker 0: So when you get sort of that abstract nonsense in text form, right?
Speaker 0: It's not that abstract because you're right but like we read 2001 for the book club Right and that ending was not as abstract as the movies ending even though they were pretty close to each other.
Speaker 0: Right because the movie doesn't say words.
Speaker 0: You're just showing you images.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like you look at a Picasso and you're like There's no context.
Speaker 0: There's no what you just you know, it is what you see.
Speaker 0: so you could take some nonsense book like Oh, yeah, the dude's a worm.
Speaker 0: God see in the future.
Speaker 0: Who knows what the fuck's happening?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and if you just show that while no one's talking It's like that suddenly makes it good Even if you don't change anything else.
Speaker 1: if they do make the more books I trust that they would do it the right way.
Speaker 1: because the final thing I would say is that what that were the biggest success of this movie is Not explaining things with words and just trusting the audience to fucking figure it out.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: That is I did.
Speaker 1: that is the primary strength of this movie.
Speaker 0: So one other one last thing I guess because we're getting I'm hungry.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah same The a lot of times that you see in series in general what matter the medium Even if they're not super long series is that they'll start off one way and switch things up, right?
Speaker 0: It's like Adventure Time starts, you know.
Speaker 0: season one Eh, but then season two onwards is like, you know, what Adventure Time really is Or you know, but in this case Dune is like the flippy floppy.
Speaker 0: it's like season.
Speaker 0: the book one is the Good part and then Oh goes later on leave right?
Speaker 0: Where's adventure time, you know?
Speaker 0: or some other things you might tell someone Oh get past the beginning Get past the grinder and suddenly you're gonna care a lot about these characters right where this is, you know?
Speaker 0: Yeah, just read the first one and stop.
Speaker 0: Yeah opposite deal.
Speaker 0: It's not like they learned as they went on it's they messed up more as they.
Speaker 1: So, uh, yeah, hopefully we'll find out what the Emperor's deal is.
Speaker 1: We'll see a second movie someday in the future because they're definitely making it.
Speaker 1: They've announced it like five times.
Speaker 0: that they're making the sequel You know I guess just the final thing is I'm encouraged that someone was able to take an old nerdy book and Translate it into a movie, you know So accurately, but I'm disappointed and that they did it to an already popular old nerdy.
Speaker 1: But we know broken like shattered earth is getting this treatment.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's true.
Speaker 0: But I would love to see a lot more doing it to newer Right, not ultra popular books or even just fucking original stories that don't already exist in a medium You know.
Speaker 1: But you want you want to get me excited.
Speaker 1: do this for the prince of nothing.
Speaker 1: do it for any culture book.
Speaker 1: I don't even care which one Those might actually be.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying go find some fantasy novel series.
Speaker 0: That's only read by like, you know Not white not dude.
Speaker 0: people right and you know do that, right?
Speaker 0: Don't be going for the.
Speaker 0: you know The popular mega hits always.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but at least they're.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: Conserve their monies because it's this ain't cheap.
Speaker 1: but dune has enough cultural cachet to where it might open the door on studios being more willing to take a risk on weird stuff again because Also that ebbs and flows in Hollywood in terms of will they make a weird movie or will they make extremely safe movies?
Speaker 0: It might also maybe teach at least one Hollywood executive if we're lucky a lesson of yeah You don't got to keep fucking changing shit.
Speaker 0: Just let just follow the book and you'll be alright.
Speaker 1: But isn't it too weird that that like that the reason like the assassination plot with the Baron like isn't that?
Speaker 1: No, just throw it in.
Speaker 1: It'll be fine.
Speaker 1: You get a cool weird scene where he's hiding on the ceiling and it's awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was a good scene.
Speaker 1: when they come in like the tasmid suits like oh no Everyone got assassinated and he's up there just barely alive coughing and pissed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you know that he is pissed.
Speaker 1: He's not afraid.
Speaker 1: He's just angry.
Speaker 1: Mmm, this has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights Our Heidi McNichol Alan Joyce link eg dread lily to the brain a bunch of people who don't want me to say their names Chris Robert Clinton Walton Dex Finn just like a dude guy Chi 85 Rebecca done review mad bull 34 cowards Ryan Karen Sam Erickson Sure Ron hurl Taylor Braun the iron front.
Speaker 1: you hold the key to my heart and a whole bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Speaker 1: We do and I look forward to doing too, but for right now.
Speaker 1: I leave you with magic liquid sunlight Drenching your body like a mental golden shower.
Speaker 1: Observe the power within you and let it bring your intentions into reality and then fucking focused dipshit.