Speaker 1:
Speaker 0: It's Wednesday, December 7th, 2022.
Speaker 0: I'm Rym.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, we are reviewing the anime Spy X Family.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So yeah, something amazing happened.
Speaker 0: Something that hasn't happened in many years for some reason.
Speaker 0: Scott and I were at a gaming convention, simultaneously to do a panel, and we played at least one tabletop board game at said convention.
Speaker 1: And then we left.
Speaker 0: Yep, then we left.
Speaker 0: It was a fun time, but still not at the point where I'm gonna go to a con for a whole weekend.
Speaker 0: Even when I was out in Seattle, we spent a lot of time outdoors and tried to limit the amount of time we spent indoors at the con for all the reasons you might be able to imagine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think the biggest problem is that like, you know, back in the day, we used to go to cons and everyone we knew at first, everyone we knew was going to all the cons.
Speaker 1: It was a big party, right?
Speaker 1: And then we were going to cons to do geek dice shit.
Speaker 1: And some people went with us, but, you know, it was less and less people going with us, right?
Speaker 1: And those people who were going, a lot of them had their own shit to do.
Speaker 1: They weren't going to hang out with us the whole time, right?
Speaker 1: They had to artist's alley table or their own panels or who knows what, right?
Speaker 1: Or a staff, right?
Speaker 1: So we were going to cons, especially Anime Boston was the one where this happened the most.
Speaker 0: I was about to say there's a big dichotomy between the gaming cons on this factor and all other kinds of cons, partly because gaming cons have a default of play a board game or know a lot of people who aren't in like the core circle who are likely to be at that con in normal times.
Speaker 0: Anime cons, I didn't have as much of that.
Speaker 0: And the people we knew are people who, uh, what are you going to do with the anime con?
Speaker 0: I'm going to sit next to like my tool and watch something like.
Speaker 0: that's fun, but that's not as fun as other things we could do, like talk, right?
Speaker 1: So like, you know, what happened to Anime Boston is many times you would go there and other than when we were doing our panels or going to the concerts or a few other, go to that one Godzilla panel that one time.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: A few other things on the schedule that stood out to us.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And then we go to the dealer's room once to go to the artist's alley once.
Speaker 1: And then we had a bunch of time to do nothing.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So we take a long breakfast and a long love, you know, and so go to Pax Unplugged here after so many years.
Speaker 1: And, you know, it's it was Pax Unplugged is like they rearrange the layout a bit, but it was.
Speaker 1: it was a happening, you know, in terms of we went on Sunday and one panel at like eleven thirty a.m.
Speaker 0: on Sunday completely filled the room in and mostly filled the room.
Speaker 0: It filled the room.
Speaker 0: The official email I got there, they turned several people away.
Speaker 1: But anyway, the the con was pretty happening and the expo area was bigger than I'd ever seen it at Pax Unplugged, having only really missed one unplugged.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: We'll get to that on a Tuesday show.
Speaker 0: There's some interesting trends in what.
Speaker 0: what the booth were at this Pax, actually.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But anyway, the you know, for the only thing that would have told you that this was a Sunday was the fact that it ended early instead of going midnight.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So I imagine it had to be even bigger on Friday and Saturday.
Speaker 1: So it was.
Speaker 1: it was happening.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was a full a full pax.
Speaker 1: Nothing at the pax itself was lacking.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But, you know, because we did not have a whole bunch of people, RP, at least our people there.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: There are obviously a bunch of people there, but they weren't our people.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Only some of them were our people.
Speaker 1: It's like if we had been there for more than the one day.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: There was still.
Speaker 1: there was stuff I was not able to do.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I didn't get to look at the first look area.
Speaker 1: I didn't go to the classic cardboard area.
Speaker 1: I didn't go to any panel other than my own.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I didn't you know, there was.
Speaker 1: there was more con provided content that I could have done had I been there an extra time.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But even if I added all of Saturday, just one more day, I would have run out of things to do if I didn't have people to play games with.
Speaker 1: I would have had to play games with strangers in a normal pre covid pax situation or in or join the enforcers again.
Speaker 0: But even if no one else we knew would come except the people who we knew and we were hanging out with on Sunday were there in a pre covid pax.
Speaker 0: I would not have run out of stuff to do, but I do a lot of things you don't do.
Speaker 0: Like I will go hang out at bars and after parties to meet people and I will.
Speaker 1: That's not that's not a pax activity.
Speaker 0: It's the activity that only happens because those people are at.
Speaker 0: and I'm also talking about.
Speaker 1: I'm talking about things to do at the pax.
Speaker 0: Also, I will often at pre covid paxes also then arrange in the convention to meet up with those people and play games and do things.
Speaker 0: The people that I met sometimes at the external event.
Speaker 1: And that's something that's having your people there.
Speaker 0: But I seek out more people.
Speaker 0: And one thing I noticed about this pax specifically was because I'm in a mask and everyone else in the mask, I was losing my voice quickly because I was basically yelling the whole time.
Speaker 0: And also, I wouldn't necessarily recognize people right away.
Speaker 0: Like I walked past our friend Pat and I realized afterward I walked past him.
Speaker 0: I didn't recognize him at first.
Speaker 1: So the thing is, I guess like, you know, over a week ago now, like last Monday, I got some kind of sniffly cough cold deal and I tested is definitely not the sea.
Speaker 1: I don't have the sea at the same thing.
Speaker 1: Sam Rosen got, I don't know, it could be RSV.
Speaker 1: Who knows?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It could be cold.
Speaker 1: And I was like, well, I'm going to.
Speaker 1: am I going to go to this pax or not with this cold?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I probably shouldn't be going if I'm not feeling good.
Speaker 1: And so I was 50 50 the night before, like legitimately 50 50.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, well, you know what?
Speaker 1: If I wake up, because basically almost every morning I would wake up and have like a coughing fit situation.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So I'm like, well, I'll just wake up tomorrow.
Speaker 1: I'll set this alarm for the be in time to get the train.
Speaker 1: And if I have a coughing fit and if I feel mad, I just won't go because it was covered.
Speaker 0: I could do the panel anyway.
Speaker 0: Like I've done three paxes by myself and one with Emily.
Speaker 1: But I woke up and I and I honestly felt 95 to 99 percent recovered.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Like there was only the tiniest tickle remaining.
Speaker 1: And you were with me all day.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: How much you were basically all day from before we got on the train.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, you're like me on a normal day because I'm non covid.
Speaker 0: I get allergies and I'm just kind of confidence in my way through life.
Speaker 1: It's like at the pax.
Speaker 1: Did I cough at the pax?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: But like a handful of times, like I didn't cough during the panel.
Speaker 1: I did a whole panel with no coffin and a cough on the train.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, I coughed a handful of times.
Speaker 1: It definitely was.
Speaker 1: it felt like, you know, the day after you've definitely recovered from something as a minor remnant.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: So I was like, good.
Speaker 1: I luckily healed just in time for pax.
Speaker 1: It was it was a sign.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know that the timing was so perfect and that.
Speaker 1: and then I went to bed after getting home from pax and I wake up the next day and I'm caught.
Speaker 1: I've been coughing all over the place again.
Speaker 1: It's already the pax was Sunday.
Speaker 1: We only went one day.
Speaker 1: It's currently Wednesday and I'm still caught.
Speaker 0: And one thing I can say is in my normal life, like it came right back in old days when I go to a con, like I would get a scratchy throat and be coffee after every con just because I mean, you know me, I just talk constantly.
Speaker 0: It's never shut up.
Speaker 0: So eventually, you know, I learned to not lose my voice by doing radio voice like all the time and like being quiet like we had to do with voice protection.
Speaker 1: This is illness.
Speaker 0: But I'm saying in normal times, I'll just get a cough after pretty much any con or any major thing.
Speaker 0: I'd even get that after like major work events just in my normal life.
Speaker 1: Definitely the same exact cough that I had before.
Speaker 1: That is just.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: No, I'm not talking about your cough.
Speaker 0: Talking on my own third situation because no one cares about your throat because one thing I've noticed is all the mast paxes I've been to.
Speaker 0: I even if I'm barely in the con, I just I talk so loud and I talk so much and I have to talk louder to hear myself and for other people to hear me that my throat feels at the end of these after like one day what normally three or four days of cons is.
Speaker 0: how like that's that's how many days of convention yelling it takes to get me to that point.
Speaker 1: You know, other people can hear you even if you can't hear yourself.
Speaker 1: You don't have to be that loud.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: But I found people repeatedly at all the at all these mass cons.
Speaker 0: I often have people ask me to repeat myself.
Speaker 0: It's been it's been a thing.
Speaker 0: So I find myself just talking louder anyway.
Speaker 0: But I'm pretty much still not dive in a while for the foreseeable future, but we'll probably be at PAX East doing some panels.
Speaker 0: But again, I don't think we're going to hang out at PAX East the whole time.
Speaker 0: Still, it's still probably a little too soon for that.
Speaker 1: Who knows?
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So I'm sure there's news, but I want to talk about something.
Speaker 1: right as I finally got Saga trade paperback volume 11.
Speaker 0: I forgot Saga existed until you were like, oh, hey, I'm going to get by Saga.
Speaker 0: There's more.
Speaker 0: there's more issues.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, because we talked about it, I think rim red volume like one and we did a show on it and we never talked about it again.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But Saga ran from twenty twelve to twenty eighteen.
Speaker 1: So there was six years and sixty fifty four issues.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So there are fifty four individual floppy comics in nine volumes of Saga that came out over those six years.
Speaker 1: And then it was a major, major ending that rim hasn't reached yet in that night.
Speaker 1: End of that ninth volume issue.
Speaker 1: Fifty four had a major ending like a big time ending.
Speaker 0: We reviewed Saga in twenty thirteen.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: When it was about like one volume was out.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: And we reviewed the six volumes.
Speaker 1: The six issues came out in twenty twelve, but like late twenty twelve.
Speaker 1: And then the first the cop, the trade paperback for the six issues came out in twenty three.
Speaker 0: For whatever reason, we reviewed it alongside also reviewing the Star Wars comic like we did two reviews in that show.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Well, that was around the time when, you know, Marvel Disney bought Marvel.
Speaker 1: And then so the Star Wars comics moved from Dark Horse to Marvel.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: So Saga, after a hiatus since September twenty eighteen or whatever, I guess, you know, effectively a four year, three or four years hiatus.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Saga came back in January with issue number fifty five.
Speaker 1: And it's still going.
Speaker 1: It's every month.
Speaker 1: there's another issue of Saga is going again.
Speaker 1: And trade paperback number ten was recently ish released like a month or two ago, I'd say.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: That contains issues fifty five through sixty.
Speaker 1: So five more issues combined.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, you know, Saga was, you know, like S tier graphic storytelling.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Already.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But it's like what what could go away for four years, three or four years, have already this ending beyond belief.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And then come back and immediately remain at S tier.
Speaker 1: It's like has anything ever gone away, come back and not been, you know, way different, way worse, way, you know, maybe it's like I can't think of any serial storytelling thing ever that like had a hiatus that was that long and came back and was as good as if it was never gone.
Speaker 0: Ah, how long was it between some of those Venture Brothers seasons?
Speaker 0: That might be like one of the only things on the Saga level.
Speaker 1: I would say I would say so.
Speaker 1: See, I would say that, you know, in terms of just English language, right, graphic storytelling, that Saga is probably the best that has been created this millennium.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So are you going to say that Venture Brothers is the best English animated storytelling this millennium?
Speaker 1: No, I don't think so.
Speaker 0: It might be up there.
Speaker 0: I think it's a contender.
Speaker 0: You don't know.
Speaker 0: You don't watch anything.
Speaker 0: Spikes family is definitely not.
Speaker 0: It's good, but it's not.
Speaker 1: So, yeah.
Speaker 1: So Saga is back.
Speaker 1: If you have never read Saga for some reason, because, you know, you've never been listening to Geek Nights for, I don't know, nine years.
Speaker 0: I'll let you do a review, because if I recall correctly, our review is basically, "Oh my God, it's so good.
Speaker 0: Oh my God, just read it.
Speaker 0: When the thing happened, oh my
Speaker 0: God.".
Speaker 0: And we were talking about like one or two trades.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think, you know, we need to definitely, you know, read.
Speaker 1: Well, I've read everything.
Speaker 1: Rym needs to read a whole bunch and then we could actually talk about what's happening in this story.
Speaker 0: I should catch up.
Speaker 0: My interest is rekindled, especially now that I know it is coming out again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just to give you an idea of like how good I think Saga is, right?
Speaker 1: At some point, I don't know if it was moving or on vacation.
Speaker 1: I had all the original nine volumes.
Speaker 1: They're gone.
Speaker 1: I don't know what happened to them.
Speaker 1: I lent them to someone.
Speaker 1: They didn't give them back.
Speaker 1: Someone stole them.
Speaker 1: I lost them.
Speaker 1: I left them somewhere.
Speaker 1: I don't fucking know.
Speaker 1: They're gone.
Speaker 0: Just buy them again.
Speaker 1: So I went.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I ordered.
Speaker 1: They have a box you can buy that has the nine volumes in a single box.
Speaker 0: I see that box.
Speaker 0: It's on the website right there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just bought that box to replace the nine I had lost.
Speaker 1: And then I ordered volume ten.
Speaker 1: And that so I have all of it except for the few issues that have been out.
Speaker 1: If you really want to, they do sell a deluxe hardcover set.
Speaker 1: And instead of buying nine volumes, you can buy three deluxe hardcovers that will cover the nine volumes.
Speaker 1: So basically three trades per hardcover.
Speaker 1: They also sell the saga compendium paperback, which is one mega book that has issues one through fifty four.
Speaker 1: So nine volumes in a single.
Speaker 0: Well, like like one of those old like the years they had, sir, that would fall apart, that had an inch and a half thick binding.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So there are four different.
Speaker 1: And then I guess I don't know if you can buy it digitally or not.
Speaker 1: Let me check.
Speaker 0: It was on Comixology, but Comixology, of course, has issues.
Speaker 0: And we've talked about that.
Speaker 0: And it doesn't really work that well anymore in the whole Amazon.
Speaker 1: Who knows what's going on with that.
Speaker 1: But I'm sure there's a digital way to read it.
Speaker 0: Oh, Comixology and Kindle are still listed.
Speaker 1: In fact, if you have Kindle Unlimited, you can get volume one for zero dollars on Kindle.
Speaker 0: That's definitely worth it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So there you go.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So in some news, you may remember a while ago that Funimation, there's a whole situation where basically Funimation, which is Sony, bought Crunchyroll away from AT&T.
Speaker 0: It's still bad that that list of nouns is together in one big corporate merger acquisition situation.
Speaker 0: But that happened and people kind of wondered how this would go.
Speaker 0: We're starting to see the early glimmers of how this is going to go.
Speaker 0: So there's a. there's a story, but then there's a buried lead in the story.
Speaker 0: The story is now Crunchyroll and Funimation.
Speaker 0: They're basically replacing all their SKUs.
Speaker 0: So all the old Funimation SKUs are being retired and all the things that Funimation put out are going to have new SKUs through Crunchyroll, confirming that they are keeping Crunchyroll as the primary brand for this stuff going forward.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's like you have basically two streaming services that are both streaming anime owned by the same company.
Speaker 1: It's like the only real decision of which one to choose is which one has more users and which one has a brand that people know.
Speaker 1: And I definitely feel like Crunchyroll has the better brand in the English speaking world than Funimation does.
Speaker 0: I think so.
Speaker 0: I would not disagree.
Speaker 1: It doesn't really matter to them which one of them is the winner because they're the same fucking company.
Speaker 1: Just like Grubhub Seamless.
Speaker 1: It's basically the same exact website only with a different skin.
Speaker 1: It's like they keep them both because both brands have cachet in different areas.
Speaker 1: But it's literally the exact same website just with two different skins on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Like you can see lately, there's a few restaurants near us where the same restaurant is listed with two different names and two different menus.
Speaker 0: But it's the same address.
Speaker 0: It's the same kitchen.
Speaker 0: It's literally the same restaurant.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So I wonder why I thought that they might have gone with that kind of strategy of keeping both Funimation.com and Crunchyroll.com.
Speaker 1: But no matter which one you go to, it's the same exact website.
Speaker 1: It just has a different logo at the top.
Speaker 0: Never mind the things they sell.
Speaker 0: Funimation had DVDs and stuff, but I guess those are going to all be Crunchyroll SKUs going forward.
Speaker 1: Crunchyroll has a shop.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: But yeah, the Crunchyroll brand is stronger.
Speaker 1: So it's also a valid business choice.
Speaker 0: But they warned everyone.
Speaker 1: The Funimation brand and go with the Crunchyroll.
Speaker 0: Many titles may be unavailable to purchase until the SKU migration is complete.
Speaker 0: Like things that had the old SKU won't be able to be purchased by anyone until the new SKU comes online for the same thing.
Speaker 0: And they won't give a timeline on that and they won't say which titles are affected and when.
Speaker 0: But there's going to be like an ongoing thing for possibly many months.
Speaker 1: Who cares?
Speaker 0: So that was the article buried in.
Speaker 0: this news article was a very, very important piece of news.
Speaker 0: So the entire world right now has generally been moving toward ads.
Speaker 0: So services that previously would just have a pay option like say Disney Plus are moving toward also having a cheaper tier where they shove ads in your face.
Speaker 0: But then they charge you less money.
Speaker 1: I read an article actually about the Disney CEO change.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: It was on the verge.
Speaker 1: And one of the things in that article that they mentioned was that the CEO of Disney who just got ousted, one of the things they did was promised to Wall Street like big, big numbers for Disney Plus.
Speaker 1: And those numbers were sort of unrealistic and hard to reach.
Speaker 1: And so the reason that Disney did the ad supported thing was it's a way to boost the numbers.
Speaker 1: They were basically just doing everything they can to meet the number that they had told to Wall Street a too big a number.
Speaker 1: And rather than pull the number back, they would do the ad thing.
Speaker 1: Whether or not the ad thing was a good business decision, it was that they had a different goal in mind in doing it.
Speaker 1: So the fact that you would see crunchy roll, right, getting rid of the ad, you know, support free tier, right?
Speaker 1: It's like they're.
Speaker 1: only they don't have that kind of Wall Street, you know, motivator or other reasoning, right?
Speaker 1: So this must be for them what they believe to be a good business strategy up.
Speaker 0: So the new strategy is actually, I think, pretty good.
Speaker 0: So here's the deal.
Speaker 0: Starting with the spring 2022 season, like that was already up and out there on Crunchyroll in March, they will no longer have ad supported viewing for any titles going forward.
Speaker 0: Full stop.
Speaker 0: Like it is over.
Speaker 1: So but for titles going forward.
Speaker 1: But what about existing titles that already are ad support?
Speaker 0: Existing titles will be dropped at some point probably next year as well.
Speaker 0: So there will be no shows that are just free to watch on Crunchyroll with ads.
Speaker 0: Gotta have a real account.
Speaker 0: that costs money.
Speaker 0: However, they said that the plan is to have every single show have the first three episodes be available for anyone to watch with ads, which is a really good idea.
Speaker 0: That sort of gives one.
Speaker 0: people could check out a show.
Speaker 0: You know, we always said from RIT anime onward and even geek nights, four episodes of an anime 99.9% of the time.
Speaker 0: That is enough to figure out if you want to watch the rest of that show.
Speaker 0: Three episodes, probably 90%.
Speaker 0: Like that's still probably enough episodes to figure it out.
Speaker 0: So that means anyone who wants to try out a show could just watch it.
Speaker 0: Even if they if they if they like the show and they want to watch more, if they're hooked, they got to pay.
Speaker 0: If they don't watch anymore, well, they still.
Speaker 0: Crunchyroll still got some money because that poor kid watched a bunch of ads while they were watching the first three episodes that they blocked them.
Speaker 0: I don't can block those ads easily.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can block everything.
Speaker 0: I have found that ads within streaming services are increasingly difficult to block and a lot of services just fail when the ad block kicks in anyway.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I think this is, you know, when you look at like the video game market, right, where you have share wares and you have demos, it's been shown that like people play a demo of a game or a shareware of a game like, you know, the first few levels.
Speaker 1: And even though they beat the game, they're like, OK, I learned, you know, I got enough of an experience from that game.
Speaker 1: And they actually don't feel the need now to buy the game and beat the whole frickin thing.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like they had enough.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like they beat the demo.
Speaker 1: It's like that's the that's an ending.
Speaker 1: It's like, OK, good enough.
Speaker 0: I mean, think back to Castle Crashers.
Speaker 0: You play the first two levels.
Speaker 0: That's the whole game.
Speaker 0: You're done.
Speaker 0: You're good anyway.
Speaker 1: So the so it's shown that like if you don't have a demo for your video game, you'll actually get more sales.
Speaker 1: You're better off having a trailer.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: There's a trailer shows someone that it's the kind of game they want to play.
Speaker 1: They're enticed.
Speaker 1: They see that they can't play even one minute unless they pay money.
Speaker 1: and then they pay the money.
Speaker 1: And even if they quit after three levels, you got the same amount of case in point.
Speaker 0: call to the lamb.
Speaker 0: A lot of people bought it.
Speaker 0: And I think a lot of people didn't realize it's basically Binding of Isaac and not the farm like the town building being.
Speaker 0: they thought it was.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, but with anime, it doesn't work that way.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like you see three episodes of an anime.
Speaker 1: It's like if you don't like the anime, OK, sure.
Speaker 1: You're probably not getting past what it says.
Speaker 0: You say it's a show that you say you don't like.
Speaker 0: And then the fourth of the third episode, in our case, the fourth episode, that talk to me guy like they don't actually finish the race.
Speaker 0: You don't know if you want or not.
Speaker 0: You're curious.
Speaker 0: You want to know if you won.
Speaker 1: It's like if you like an anime, it's like you got to watch the whole thing.
Speaker 1: You can't stop in an episode three.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And so that's a good way, you know, to entice people because it's not like people are out there watching anime trailers.
Speaker 1: Anime trailers are not very convincing.
Speaker 0: I mean, if anything, what I used what I used to do back when I watched a lot more anime is I'd watch AMV's and almost treat those like trailers.
Speaker 0: If I'd like a show or not.
Speaker 1: I mean, if I was an anime maker, I would make AMV's of my own anime as the trailer.
Speaker 0: Oh, hell yeah.
Speaker 0: And you know what anime they actually did that for?
Speaker 0: Escaflowne.
Speaker 0: There are official music videos to Escaflowne that are out there.
Speaker 0: So in some other news, so Makoto Shinkai's new film, Suzume, the one with the door and the hot boy and the clouds.
Speaker 1: The guy turns into a chair.
Speaker 0: I was going to say that in a second.
Speaker 0: The show that is about clouds and colorful skies and girls with long dark hair who tie their back with long red ribbons and hot guy.
Speaker 0: And I guess the guy turns into a chair and there's a cuba.
Speaker 0: And this this movie looks like it's all over the place in the kind of way that we it's been out for a while.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Japan.
Speaker 0: We now have the dates April 12th, 13th and 14th.
Speaker 0: There will be theater screenings everywhere in the world outside of Asia where there's a market.
Speaker 0: So April 14th is the day for the United States and the United Kingdom.
Speaker 0: You can check this website to figure out if your country is covered.
Speaker 0: So April 14th, there will almost definitely be multiple screenings of Suzume at theaters in New York City.
Speaker 0: I'm just going to put a note in my calendar and remember, I assume we're all going to go see this movie on April 14th.
Speaker 1: Despite the fact that, you know, Shinkai has not been, you know, he had the year name, which was the global sensation.
Speaker 0: One of the most popular animated movies ever.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Despite the fact that we, you know, we don't we personally don't put him as good as, you know, some of the other contemporaries right now.
Speaker 1: You know, still going to go see it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And other news of movies coming to the United States.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Shin Ultraman, which came out in Japan earlier this year, much earlier this year, is finally going to be in theaters in the U.S.
Speaker 1: in on January.
Speaker 1: So they had to wait for a whole year.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I see Astoria Kaufman, January 11th, January.
Speaker 0: So January 11th, 2023.
Speaker 1: There'll be a subtitled, you know, screening.
Speaker 1: And January 12th, there'll be a dubbed screening.
Speaker 1: So perhaps some of the time it took to bring it over was because they really wanted to make that dub.
Speaker 1: And you got to presume that, you know, after this movie comes out, you know, in the theater in January, there's going to be all kinds of, you know, streaming and DVD, Bure and all that.
Speaker 1: You know, you're going to be able to watch Shin Ultraman.
Speaker 1: So I really want to watch it and I'm probably going to go on January 11th.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: So I cannot stress enough, Disco Elysium is one of the best single player games I've played since Breath of the Wild.
Speaker 0: It's just that good.
Speaker 0: Now I'm going to dive into Pentiment, which is in many ways, mechanically and thematically similar, though they are very different games.
Speaker 0: So most likely our next Tuesday show, we're going to review Pentiment, but I like Disco Elysium enough.
Speaker 0: I'm playing it through a second time.
Speaker 0: And my thing of the day is a little animatic music video someone made to Disco Elysium, but it's to a song.
Speaker 0: And this one, this video is great.
Speaker 0: Like this is really funny.
Speaker 0: If you haven't played the game, it's still funny.
Speaker 0: You played the game.
Speaker 0: It is extremely funny and extremely poignant.
Speaker 0: However, the song, if you just watch this, you might think clearly some nerds made this song to go with this video to make fun of Disco Elysium.
Speaker 0: It's too on the nose.
Speaker 0: It's too close to what happens, like what the actual game is about.
Speaker 0: So my thing of the day is not so much that video.
Speaker 0: It is the band that made the song.
Speaker 0: The song is called Party Time by the Northern Boys and they actually have a music video.
Speaker 0: And the Northern Boys are basically three old men who sing about how deeply sad sack their lives are.
Speaker 0: And it is fantastic.
Speaker 0: It is really funny.
Speaker 0: I recommend this band.
Speaker 0: It's actually a pretty good song, but the lyrics are, this is, this is extremely dark humor and we'll leave it at that.
Speaker 0: So what do you got?
Speaker 1: So recently I was talking with someone about some, you know, old vinyl records, right?
Speaker 1: And they were, they were talking about how like they had Sesame Street vinyls and you know, and I was like, well, I didn't realize the C is for cookie came out on vinyl.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: Uh, and then I remembered when I was a kid that I had a Pac-Man vinyl record of some kind.
Speaker 1: And I remember when I got it as like a gift, I think, and it was just so weird to me because up until that point, every vinyl record I had ever seen was just some sort of like actual album by a band of some sort, right?
Speaker 1: Like, you know, Rolling Stones, something album, right?
Speaker 1: Like I'd never seen a vinyl album.
Speaker 1: that wasn't, you know, something else.
Speaker 1: I had seen cassette tapes that were like, you know, listen and read, you know, with a book for it.
Speaker 0: Cause you're a kid.
Speaker 0: My childhood was filled with vinyls that had like coloring books and activity books with them.
Speaker 1: Not all the ones that I had.
Speaker 1: that were some sort of kids thing that weren't, you know, a, an album where cassette tapes for my Fisher Price cassette player, even though I had a big bird record player, I had that big bird record player, the big bird record player played, you know, queen or whatever.
Speaker 0: It's like, what's the player for 45?
Speaker 0: Like, I feel like it was small.
Speaker 0: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: Now you could put, you could put either one on there, but yeah, it was the, if you put on a full size vinyl, it would sort of hang over the edge, but it worked anyway.
Speaker 1: So this, I had this Pac-Man album when I was a kid and I looked it up.
Speaker 1: It's called the amazing adventures of Pac-Man.
Speaker 1: It was put out by kids stuff, records and tapes.
Speaker 1: And was it rare?
Speaker 1: Was, was I, did I experience some album that like no one's ever heard of?
Speaker 1: And I had like an ultra rare thing and it's gone now.
Speaker 1: Absolutely not.
Speaker 1: It was common as dirt.
Speaker 1: Everyone's heard this fucking thing.
Speaker 1: It was all over the place.
Speaker 1: Kids in the eighties had this thing all over.
Speaker 1: So it's on YouTube.
Speaker 1: You can just listen to it.
Speaker 1: It's really bad and painful.
Speaker 1: It's narrated by, you know, people who think that this will be entertaining for children.
Speaker 0: The seven minute and nine second mark is where do you think it's as dire as it could be?
Speaker 0: And it's somehow worse after that point.
Speaker 1: And they want to make money cause it's 1980 something and Pac-Man is like a huge craze right now.
Speaker 0: Like if you think a white knuckle scoring was a cynical cash grab, it's got nothing on this Pac-Man thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So go on, if you got some minutes, go on YouTube and listen to the vinyl album, the amazing adventures of Pac-Man.
Speaker 1: I want to sort of point out one thing.
Speaker 1: I actually learned something about Pac-Man that I did not know.
Speaker 1: I was under the impression until just now when re re-listening to this album, right?
Speaker 1: At least a few minutes of it, that the names of the Pac-Man ghosts were Blinky, Pinky, Inky, and Clyde, right?
Speaker 1: Those are the names.
Speaker 1: I've always called them those four names.
Speaker 1: And that's not wrong, but apparently the truth is that their actual names are obviously Japanese names, right?
Speaker 1: Oikake, Machibuse, Kimagure, and Otoboke.
Speaker 1: And those translate to chaser, ambusher, fickle, and stupid.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: This is according to Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: ABC News has an article that explains this, actually, weirdly enough.
Speaker 1: Okay, I'm ready to get into Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: But on the album, they call the ghosts Shadow, Speedy, Bashful, and Pokey.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, whoa, did they just get the names wrong on this album?
Speaker 0: It sounds like they took the Japanese and just translated it themselves badly.
Speaker 1: That's not true at all.
Speaker 1: What happened is that Midway Games, when they brought Pac-Man to the United States, they changed the names of the ghosts to Shadow, Speedy, Bashful, and Pokey.
Speaker 1: And then if you actually look at a Pac-Man machine and actually pay attention to what's on the screen, which I've never done, apparently, it actually says on the screen of Pac-Man, you can go to Wikipedia for ghosts Pac-Man.
Speaker 1: They have their own page, right?
Speaker 1: Just for the ghosts.
Speaker 1: And sure enough, their real names are, at least in English, according to Midway, are Shadow, Speedy, Bashful, and Pokey.
Speaker 1: And Blinky, Pinky, Inky, and Clyde are their nicknames in the English canon.
Speaker 0: That's a fairly elegant way around that.
Speaker 1: So I just never realized that those were nicknames.
Speaker 1: I thought that those were their real names in English.
Speaker 1: And I was wrong, and the album actually got their real names right-ish.
Speaker 1: I mean, I guess the only way to be more right would have been to call them Oikake.
Speaker 1: I don't think they're going to be doing that.
Speaker 0: I love these track names too.
Speaker 0: We've got Pac-Man Theme, we've got Take the Fruit and Scoot, Slightly Lazy Crazy Day, and The Chase.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I also like that.
Speaker 1: on the cover of the album, there's this rat guy who's not a character in Pac-Man at all, but they needed more characters because just Pac-Man and four ghosts.
Speaker 0: Also, what's the ghost doing with that fruit in the background?
Speaker 1: Well, in the story is that they're all in Pacville, and Pacville is all about fruit and also pretzels.
Speaker 0: Yep, as we know from the NES game Pac-Man, that is not the Pac-Man you all know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess Dig Dug must be digging under Pacville, that's why.
Speaker 0: Ahh.
Speaker 1: Where does the Galaga Ship come from, though?
Speaker 0: Don't go too deep into that, Laurie, you'll go crazy.
Speaker 0: In the meta moment, the Geeknides Book Club book is Alif the Unseen.
Speaker 1: I read a few chapters.
Speaker 0: I expect in January we'll do an episode on it, it's not gonna be a super long read, but it's not gonna be as fast as Binti.
Speaker 1: I read a few chapters, stuff's moving along, it's all, you know, you got a cyberpunk dude, he's hacking and he's getting in trouble.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: We were, of course, just at Pacs Unplugged 2022, we did a panel, why does the game take four hours to play?
Speaker 0: If you've somehow missed it or you're curious about the topic, there's video of a similar panel we did at the last Pacs Unplugged before.
Speaker 0: Covid called Take Your Fucking Turn, which is on YouTube, you can just watch.
Speaker 0: I also posted a link to the slides we used from the panel at Pacs Unplugged on Sunday.
Speaker 0: I've been trying to post the slides more and more because I found that people do actually go look at them.
Speaker 0: I even left one of them with comments on and people were like leaving comments, like it was, there were some interesting insights that people like added or asked questions, so I might see if that's a thing we could engage with in some fashion down the road, like sharing the slides more directly and openly.
Speaker 1: Anyway, yeah, the next convention that we have any chance of going to is going to be Pacs East.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The dates are announced, they're what?
Speaker 0: Oh, Pacs East is going to be, the panel submission is just open too, and I got to tell you, they've now migrated the rest of their stuff to Growtix.
Speaker 0: For the first time since 2008, when I've submitted panels to every Pacs forever, it's a different website now, it's that Growtix backend, the same one we used to use at Kineticon.
Speaker 0: Well, so we'll see how that goes.
Speaker 1: But anyway, March 23rd through 26th, 2023, it's still four days, and if you don't know, if you didn't hear the news already, the policy for Pacs East is going to be, they're not going to check the VACs, but they're going to require the mask, right?
Speaker 1: Pacs Unplugged did check the VACs, Pacs East is not going to check it, and that's that.
Speaker 1: Yep, so like I said, you have to decide on your own if you're going to go or not go.
Speaker 1: If that is a factor in your decision.
Speaker 0: I significantly expect for us, we, or possibly, depending on the pain in the ass of doing this, just me, will show up just to do a few panels and hang out.
Speaker 0: It is highly unlikely we will be there the entire Pacs East.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so Spy X Family.
Speaker 0: This show, among our friends, like people I talked to online, like all the anime people, they were like really into this show after it came out.
Speaker 1: Like this appeared- This show is clearly just based on, you know, the buzz of being connected to the internet, right?
Speaker 1: Is a popular, very, very popular show, right?
Speaker 1: Around the whole anime communities, right?
Speaker 1: People love this show.
Speaker 1: I don't think people were like coming off like.
Speaker 1: this is like the greatest show ever.
Speaker 1: It weren't coming off like.
Speaker 1: this is a masterpiece.
Speaker 1: It was just coming off like.
Speaker 1: this is really popular, like the same- You know what it is?
Speaker 0: This is the kind of show like straight up, and Scott and I actually said the same thing kind of at each other when we first watched it.
Speaker 0: This is the kind of show, when we were running the RIT Anime Club, when we found out what it was and watched a little bit of it, we would have instantly just made it the next screening at the anime club.
Speaker 0: because this is the kind of like basic, solid B-level, like B-tier anime.
Speaker 0: that's pretty good.
Speaker 0: People enjoy it.
Speaker 0: It would definitely get the crowd riled up.
Speaker 0: We already can see like specific characters and specific things that would get quoted by the nerds who would watch a show like this.
Speaker 0: It's just a solid, overall okay anime.
Speaker 0: that's kind of funny, kind of serious, well animated, like it checks all the boxes, but it's not great in any particular domain.
Speaker 1: Well I think what it is is that it's a crowd pleaser, right?
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: it's just, you know, it's not fan service-y in a sexual way.
Speaker 1: There's nothing sexual about this show pretty much whatsoever, right?
Speaker 1: But it's fan service-y as like playing to the crowd, like just like, you know, having cool anime people doing cool anime stuff, right?
Speaker 1: And they've got every different flavor of cool anime stuff going on.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So if you're an anime fan or just, you know, I think even a non-anime fan, it's like it's just kind of fun, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, it's not gonna, it doesn't challenge the audience or anything like that.
Speaker 1: It's just a whole lot of fun.
Speaker 1: It's a perfect anime club kind of show.
Speaker 1: I don't, I can't imagine someone watching it and like disliking it or not having a good time or not being, you know, happy or entertained.
Speaker 1: That would be weird, right?
Speaker 1: Cause it's just like, you know, it's like, it's like sugar, right?
Speaker 1: It's like cookies.
Speaker 1: So what's the deal with this show?
Speaker 1: Well, the title sort of gives it away, right?
Speaker 1: You gotta imagine from the title, there's a spy and the spy has a family or it's like, one of my guesses with the spy has to make a family for a mission.
Speaker 1: It's like, yes, that's exactly what it is.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much that.
Speaker 1: And there's a guy who's a spy and for some, you know, uh, generic European ish country, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: There's what there's, there's basically, there's two countries, west and east and it's vague and they are, it's obviously west and east Germany without saying Germany.
Speaker 0: And there's definitely a cold war going on and there's spies all over the place.
Speaker 0: You get the impression that this place is just lousy with spies.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And there's, this guy's the best over, he's the best spy, right?
Speaker 1: Like the absolute best spy, like, you know, anime, you know, ridiculous levels of power at spying.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Agent Twilight.
Speaker 0: He's like the hot anime guy, master of disguise.
Speaker 1: Like an absolute genius, perfect skills, perfect disguises, never fails, right?
Speaker 1: It could take anyone.
Speaker 1: It's just like, even better, like James Bond like gets beat up.
Speaker 1: It's like, this guy doesn't really know.
Speaker 0: This guy takes out what he fights those goons in the art theft thing that he's doing a few episodes in and he's just like, I can't spend more than 10 seconds per guy that I'm about to beat up.
Speaker 0: There's 38 of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like Kenshiro levels of power, but obviously a different, much different personality and tone than this to the North star.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And so this guy has a mission, but in order to do the mission, he has to write, there's a prestigious boarding type, you know, school, which reeks of like a princess tutu tena kind of place.
Speaker 0: There's no allegory.
Speaker 0: It's not going to do anything clever with this.
Speaker 0: Like don't misinterpret what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's just a rich, it's just a really, really high brows, snooty, rich people's school.
Speaker 0: But to an insane anime degree, like it is, if the spy stuff is unrealistic and the fights and things are unrealistic in an anime way, the university is like double unrealistic in terms of how it's portrayed and how it's structured.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: And he has to basically, you know, it's a contrived scenario, right?
Speaker 1: We has to get into this school, which means he needs a child and, you know, possibly a spouse, right?
Speaker 1: To sort of, you know, go to the school interview, get the child accepted to the school.
Speaker 1: The child has the past, the, you know, the, the very, very rigorous, you know, examinations and application barriers, right?
Speaker 1: Him and the spouse have to, you know, pass muster and convince the school that they are of, you know, high class, right?
Speaker 1: Individuals.
Speaker 1: And he doesn't have a spouse or a child, right?
Speaker 0: Nor is he interested in one at this point.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: So I guess spoilers for the earliest parts of the show, right?
Speaker 1: It kind of needs to spoil this to talk about anything.
Speaker 0: Because there is a little twist to this concept because he finds a wife, a fake wife and they get together.
Speaker 1: First, he goes to the orphanage to get a child and he ends up with this very cute daughter who, unbeknownst to him, and I still don't know if or when he ever finds out, the daughter is literally telepathic, like literally.
Speaker 1: She could just hear everyone's thoughts, right?
Speaker 1: She can't go to crowded places because it's too, you know, too many thoughts, right?
Speaker 1: And she's really cute and she's not that smart, but she has telepathy.
Speaker 1: So that makes up for not being so smart.
Speaker 0: And they animate, like she's just adorable.
Speaker 0: They animate her great.
Speaker 0: She's a really funny character.
Speaker 0: Like, it's all very well done around her.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And then it's like, okay, what about the spouse?
Speaker 1: So there's this, you know, this woman and she's working in some kind of government office or something, right?
Speaker 1: And she's very serious and separate from all the other coworkers, but secretly she's an ultimate badass assassin.
Speaker 0: She just murders people.
Speaker 0: It is implied she has killed a lot of people.
Speaker 0: And what's funny is up until the point where you see her doing her job, you don't really see people like dying in the show.
Speaker 0: Like it's kind of like off-screen stuff.
Speaker 0: She shows up and just stabs like eight people in her opening scene almost.
Speaker 1: She's like, she's literally ultra dangerous assassin.
Speaker 1: She's as good at assassinating as the spy dude is at spying.
Speaker 1: Just ultimately unbelievable, right?
Speaker 1: But you know, at work, she's very serious and boring, when she's assassinating, she's ultra badass.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And then, you know, when she's just hanging out, she's kind of cute.
Speaker 1: So you sort of get this, you know, appealing character through having wildly divergent personalities at different times.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: I didn't expect that was interesting is they, they made her like, not just an assassin, but like extremely obsessed with and enamored with the artifacts of violence.
Speaker 0: Like she almost seems like horny for a sharp knife or a photo of a guillotine.
Speaker 0: Like it is, that's her thing.
Speaker 0: Like she is, she's just mega assassin.
Speaker 1: And so they mysteriously, you know, uh, she takes orders from her brother.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And she basically goes only into assassin mode.
Speaker 1: when, you know, the brother sends some orders and, you know, she, it's like they get into other situations.
Speaker 1: Um, but they're not related to her mission.
Speaker 1: So she just goes along with, you know, right.
Speaker 1: The spy dude who doesn't know she's an assassin and she doesn't know he's a spy.
Speaker 0: So the little girl, that's neither of them.
Speaker 1: No, the girl is.
Speaker 0: And that's the twist that makes the show actually pretty funny and like makes it work is that it's not the, it's not like the true spies movie.
Speaker 0: where they like.
Speaker 0: the plot is when do they figure it out about each other?
Speaker 0: and what are they hiding or all that kind of nonsense.
Speaker 0: This is more like they are actually completely hiding it from each other.
Speaker 0: They both have the other one completely fooled.
Speaker 0: And meanwhile, the little girl knows the full deal with both of them, but simultaneously doesn't want them to know she's psychic.
Speaker 0: So she doesn't let on.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And then of course the final thing, which, you know, this isn't a spoiler because I don't know, I've only seen five episodes, but you would have to be really bad at, you know, looking for, you know, uh, uh, oh, their mission definitely overlaps.
Speaker 0: They're the same guy, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, her, they keep, you know, whenever they show her brother, it's always like, she's talking to him on the phone and they'll cut to like a photo of the brother, but his face will be like hidden, like some, you know, some someone's wiener,
Speaker 0: telling
Speaker 1: you and a cucumber,
Speaker 0: right?
Speaker 0: Standard anime doing all that like basic shit.
Speaker 1: It's obvious that the main spy dude's mission is to get the brother.
Speaker 1: And at the end of the season or whatever, there's a conflict where he's trying to get the brother and you're right.
Speaker 1: And now he's a, you know, they have to fight with each other and sort things out.
Speaker 0: I imagine the psychic girl is going to be the one who like allows them to sort this out.
Speaker 0: Like that's clearly where the show is going.
Speaker 0: The only thing I can't predict.
Speaker 1: the fact that the plot is so transparent doesn't matter because that's not why you're watching the show.
Speaker 0: That is just a vehicle for like scenes where they go to apply to the university and an utenna like animal stampede happens and the headmaster is secretly watching them to decide if their child deserves to be in this prestigious academy for six year olds.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the reason you watch this show is because every episode they've got to take the next step in, you know, their mission or whatever.
Speaker 1: And they come into some ridiculous circumstance that's truly off the wall and wild.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And they comedically and entertainingly, you know, overcome all these various challenges in ridiculous and entertaining anime style.
Speaker 1: Like when their clothes get dirty three times, it's like, aha.
Speaker 1: But they brought a third set of clothing.
Speaker 0: And then Mr.
Speaker 0: Elegant is like, oh, that's beyond elegant.
Speaker 0: That's terrifying.
Speaker 1: I got to get this girl in the anime face like, oh, you know, right.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I'll tell you, if we showed this, if you showed this to any anime club for at least two weeks, you're going to have kids running around to your club going elegant, elegant and yelling at each other.
Speaker 0: That's just how it's going to go down.
Speaker 1: So it's like, you know, the scenario.
Speaker 1: anime is kind of thing as we go on for a while.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But this particular scenario is somewhat unique and clever and well thought out.
Speaker 1: And I think that helps it a lot.
Speaker 0: It's legitimately funny.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: And then despite being very cliche and leaning heavily into the anime tropes, it executes them very well.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's not, you know, it's not.
Speaker 1: it's well animated, at least for what it is.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You know, it's doing the thing with like a bunch of.
Speaker 0: there's a set of side characters and you get the impression they're introduced more of them as time goes on, like not just Mr.
Speaker 0: Elegant, but like the fuzzy haired sidekick to the fuzzy haired spy guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: They got like the weird looking background characters that younger anime fans like to low key obsess over, which is the thing anime fans have always done in America.
Speaker 1: And I think that's another strength of this show is that, you know, you see a lot of anime where there's a whole bunch of characters and it's typical, I think, for main characters to sort of be boring.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And not have a lot of, you know, wild, different personality or anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Like supposed to be ultra relatable, like blank slate kind of deal.
Speaker 1: And all the side characters are interesting and awesome.
Speaker 1: Whereas in this show, every character is interesting and awesome and some and different in it.
Speaker 1: It's like all side characters, basically.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Like you get the jerk guy who works for the school, who's like, I don't like these people because they're young and hot.
Speaker 0: So fuck them and make sure the kid doesn't get into the school.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: But the kid gets in anyways.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You did.
Speaker 1: I, this is not a show where you're watching it because you don't know what's going to happen.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, what's going to happen from episode one if you're an adult.
Speaker 0: And the other thing, you know, we've seen things, it really does check all the boxes of a solid, typical upper echelon, but not great or memorable anime like the opener.
Speaker 0: Fantastic.
Speaker 0: Like as a really good opener, the closer is cute.
Speaker 0: The opener and closer are like stereotypical standard anime opener and closer for this kind of show.
Speaker 0: It is just everything is done adequately, but nothing is done to any sort of like, um, like S tier or memorable degree.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So I think like if you're a younger anime fan or you're an anime fan who has someone to watch the show with, you should definitely do that.
Speaker 1: If you're an older anime fan, I guess, you know, you don't have to run out and need a show to fill some time.
Speaker 1: You could do a lot worse because it's scratched.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to, I don't think I'm going to watch it all anytime soon, but I might occasionally watch an episode and kind of go a little bit beyond where I watch because it scratched an itch.
Speaker 0: that hasn't been scratched for me in a while because now we're older.
Speaker 0: We don't watch as much anime.
Speaker 0: We're much more selective about what we watch.
Speaker 0: And the thing that this show did for me is I watched one episode and it's scratched that itch of, Hey, you want to watch an anime?
Speaker 0: Like, Hey, want to see some anime kid?
Speaker 0: It just scratched that.
Speaker 0: It should felt like how I felt when I watched a typical anime a long time ago when I was younger.
Speaker 0: Cause usually when I watch a show, I'm only watching a show that like has accolades or like there's some specific reason to watch it.
Speaker 0: Like cyberpunk is going to be very different type of show and type of review.
Speaker 0: And I'm going to watch it, approach it and enjoy it in a very different way from like this kind of show.
Speaker 1: Now I am curious about the manga for this, which I believe still going, I guess, and is still going.
Speaker 1: And the show is now going to have a second season.
Speaker 1: So I'm curious if a, is the plot resolution going to be resolved at the end of season one?
Speaker 1: Will there be a new plot, right?
Speaker 1: Like what's going to happen?
Speaker 1: I'm just guessing here, right?
Speaker 1: Not, it's not a spoiler.
Speaker 1: if I'm just guessing based on common logic, uh, you know, they realize they, everyone realizes the truth and that, you know, they started out doing this as a business arrangement, but actually, uh, they end up loving each other and wanting to stay together as a family.
Speaker 1: And season two is what they're the awesome family who now knows everything.
Speaker 0: Now, if I had to guess, I would guess that they figure out the girl is psychic as part of the resolution of the first plot, which if I would assume is going to be the end of season one.
Speaker 0: And then season two probably picks up with.
Speaker 0: the three of them know each other's deal.
Speaker 1: And now it's against the world, but openly, like they're all now, now they're no longer just, I think like in their minds in the, you know, in the first season, right.
Speaker 1: It's like they entered into this relationship with each other for their own reasons.
Speaker 0: Oh, they already gave us the scene in episode like two or three where Twilight like watches the two of them interacting.
Speaker 0: And he just has this moment where he's like, ah, and he like looks at another family that are being happy.
Speaker 0: And you can see a hundred percent where the show is going from that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like he did this just for his mission.
Speaker 1: She did this for what?
Speaker 1: Like, you know, because she had trouble with her friends at that party or something.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: The coworkers, he needed to bring a boyfriend to the party to show them what to what for.
Speaker 1: And obviously the girl is doing this because, you know, she doesn't go back to the orphanage.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And she likes them as parents.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Finally got some good parents.
Speaker 0: I got cool parents.
Speaker 0: One of them's an assassin.
Speaker 0: One of them's a spy.
Speaker 0: Fuck yeah.
Speaker 0: Cause she's into spy shows.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And so, you know, everyone's in this arrangement for their own reason, but obviously, you know, they're going to grow into actually all loving each other as a family and staying together.
Speaker 1: Surprise.
Speaker 1: That's a hundred percent guaranteed to happen.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So if all that stuff happens in season one and the manga keeps going and the anime keeps going, right.
Speaker 1: You got to presume that either a not all of those things happen so quickly or B they go onto some other, you know, plot where the family is together.
Speaker 1: They all understand each other and they have another challenge.
Speaker 1: Some conflict.
Speaker 0: I feel like getting you.
Speaker 0: that point would be important because then that unlock, like right now there's a lot of jokes around.
Speaker 0: You've got a tall little girl, a precocious little girl.
Speaker 0: Who's honestly kind of like, she's, she's dumb like a kid.
Speaker 0: That's why your kids because he has stupid, but because she's psychic, she can kind of fake it.
Speaker 0: And like her interactions with adults because of the fact that she's psychic are actually surprising and funny.
Speaker 0: But I think the next evolution of that is the parents know she's psychic.
Speaker 0: How the fuck do they parent her now knowing this?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, I think it helps that she's kind of, she's not bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: She's definitely not bad.
Speaker 0: She's, she's, she's a good girl.
Speaker 0: Do it, do it.
Speaker 0: Trying to do good.
Speaker 1: I think it would also be kind of awesome, right?
Speaker 1: It's like once they know it, they'll do some kind of spy mission and they'll be like, Hey, go listen to that guy's thoughts.
Speaker 1: Tell me what you think.
Speaker 0: You imagine the loss of situations.
Speaker 0: Like, Hey, we're, uh, we're a husband and wife and we figured out our deal and we want to go have some, some alone times, but we can't think about that while our daughter's within like a kilometer of us,
Speaker 1: you know, they could make another, they could make a biological baby between them.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And then, uh, you can get some pregnant assassin action and you could, you know, uh, uh, you know, what season two might be, no blood.
Speaker 0: It might be figure out the origin of her psychic powers to protect her from the plot that predates the show of, you know, she was part of an experiment.
Speaker 0: Like where did she get her powers from?
Speaker 0: Whereas, and there was a character who looked like a redheaded woman, I think in the opener who was stylized that looked like she was spying on the family.
Speaker 0: I wonder if that's her real mom or like the scientists that made her or like, there's, there's something there.
Speaker 0: If that's in the opener that might come up in season one.
Speaker 1: The point is it's not hard to carry this scenario on for quite a while, as long as they're still making money and their show is making money, they're selling mangas, they're selling merch.
Speaker 0: I mean, I can't stress enough how this show flooded my social media, like for a couple months after it came out and I still see random people just talk about it.
Speaker 1: I see fan arts, I see, you know, I see memes and you know, so yeah, it's, it's a, it's a hot new, new, not too new, newer anime manga.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's from 2022.
Speaker 0: It's, uh, it's new to geek nights.
Speaker 1: It's a, it's a fun time.
Speaker 1: Um, it's just not a legendary great anime of all time.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So if you already got a crunchy roll account, there's no reason not to watch a few episodes of this.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I would not buy a crunchy roll account just to watch this, however.
Speaker 1: But if you buy a crunchy roll account to watch something else, watch this also.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Sci-Tech Mondays, gaming Tuesdays, anime comic Wednesdays, and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a creative comments attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And the patron patrons for this episode of geek nights are Alan Joyce, the Kiji dread, Louis Tenebrae, a happy communist, Chris, the dog, Chris Reimer, Clinton, Walton decks, Finn, Joel Hayes, Rebecca Dunn, Sam Erickson, Shervin von Horrell, stop all the downloading and several people who are giving less than $5 because that is wise and prudent, but I will not say your names.
Speaker 0: It was pretty much 50/50 which of the two clips I recorded for this stinger was going to be and I did literally flip a coin.
Speaker 0: so enjoy.
Speaker 0: Sin and no chasing.
Speaker 0: I know it sounds amazing to hear your Pac-Man say that I'd love to play on this slightly crazy lazy day.
Speaker 0: Stop those ghosts.
Speaker 0: They're stealing them.
Speaker 0: Hey you, come back with that fruit.