Speaker 1:
Speaker 0: It's Monday April 18th 2022.
Speaker 0: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We are talking about video cables.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: so, uh got real warm got like 70s warm and I did a bunch of bike like about Five hours couple days.
Speaker 0: It was like upper 60s that second day.
Speaker 0: So I've learned that with clay in the era of climate change He even like in New York City.
Speaker 0: the forecast for the next day will be radically different by the time that next day comes.
Speaker 0: so Anyway, I got a whole ton of biking in.
Speaker 0: it was a fantastic weekend.
Speaker 0: I get up this morning thinking maybe I'll bike to work.
Speaker 0: It's like 40 degrees.
Speaker 0: I still bikes but It was not as pleasant as say Biking over the new Brooklyn Bridge bike path, which I did for the first time with Emily over the weekend.
Speaker 0: Mmm, it's it's I'd never been over.
Speaker 1: It's a path.
Speaker 0: Yeah completely separate.
Speaker 0: biking on that was interesting because I saw that the Pedestrian slash tourist part of it was completely packed with people who couldn't even walk.
Speaker 0: It was so crowded And there was like two or three other bikers on the bike path.
Speaker 0: Everyone's just flying.
Speaker 0: It was a good time But it's gonna be cold I think for the rest of this week.
Speaker 1: It's annoying.
Speaker 1: it's like it's like we're gonna have climate change right.
Speaker 1: at least just give me the one upside Which is it's supposed to be warmer, right?
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: The problem is it's gonna be warmer, but it's also gonna be more variable.
Speaker 0: So our winters will be colder and worse.
Speaker 0: our summers will be hotter.
Speaker 0: But also worse.
Speaker 0: It's gonna swing a lot more.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be less.
Speaker 1: thing is hotter and worse.
Speaker 1: hotter is better.
Speaker 0: I'll tell you hit that wet bulb temperature and the human body just literally dies.
Speaker 1: I If I literally die, you know, at least I'll die warm.
Speaker 0: But in more exciting news if you haven't noticed The price of video cards is slowly but surely Approaching reasonable prices again for a bunch of reasons.
Speaker 1: It's going down a little bit.
Speaker 1: It's actually going down hurt.
Speaker 1: Actually, I heard the prices are actually not bad in the UK.
Speaker 0: I saw oh, they're not bad in the u.s.
Speaker 0: So I died.
Speaker 0: so I looked again.
Speaker 0: I actually bought.
Speaker 0: now we bought a 3080 tie Titanium the fancy one.
Speaker 0: The big thing I noticed was the biggest price discrepancy is still the 3080 because if you look at MSRP The the GTX 3080 is the absolute sweet spot of dollar for performance like bard.
Speaker 1: No, what's the?
Speaker 1: what's the MSRP?
Speaker 1: 700 bucks?
Speaker 0: No, I got to look it up again.
Speaker 0: It's really it's shockingly low.
Speaker 0: Let's see MSRP 3080.
Speaker 0: I live in share my browser.
Speaker 0: So the stream guy can see seven months.
Speaker 1: That's what I just said.
Speaker 0: yep, so 700 bucks is a fantastic price for a 3080 but the actual price even if you buy it direct from a store is About double that or more because they're in so much to me.
Speaker 1: So you get it.
Speaker 0: but I've seen him for like a thousand eleven hundred give or take but very rarely and usually those require Being in a weird line being in a lottery All sorts of nonsense.
Speaker 0: and Meanwhile, if you go up to the 3080 tie or the 3090 the MSRP is higher and the performance per dollar Like there's diminishing returns obviously, but if you buy these cards right now the price that you actually pay from a non scalper the difference in price between MSRP and The overcharge from lack of supply is way lower.
Speaker 0: You're paying a way closer to MSRP, but you're still paying an above.
Speaker 0: so I ended up getting a 3080 TI that cost about the same as what a 3080 is going for right now and Put in Emily's computer with the i9 and that thing one.
Speaker 0: It is huge.
Speaker 0: It is absolutely huge Which is terrifying to me because it is still significantly smaller than a 3090.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's you know, I mean that's the thing is that you know people keep comparing right, you know The Apple computers to write PCs as they should right and you Even if I buy a PC and I pay the overcharge for the 3080 3090 whatever right and it's like, you know You're gonna beat you the Apple computer right?
Speaker 1: Even that new Mac studio.
Speaker 1: You're gonna beat it It's gonna be faster, right?
Speaker 1: But what you're not counting taking into account is I think I've said this on the show probably a million times is It's?
Speaker 1: you know, it's basically using ridiculous amounts of power and generating ridiculous amounts of heat.
Speaker 1: It's like it's not efficient.
Speaker 1: What's a whatsoever?
Speaker 0: Well case in point.
Speaker 0: so the price difference between MSRP an actual price right now for the 3090 is Approaching actual MSRP and I thought about buying a 3090 because of that.
Speaker 0: but when I looked at it So Emily's computer has an i9.
Speaker 0: It's a super powerful computer.
Speaker 1: The i9 is also sort of you know in that nonsense zone.
Speaker 0: Well, what Emily does is kind of diminishing return it is but for what Emily does?
Speaker 1: it actually does make a significant difference like you think I Don't know if there would really be a significant Highest and i7 and an i9.
Speaker 0: so an i9 with a The recommendation is the minimum.
Speaker 0: PSU is an 850 watt the absolute minimum And a lot of people report significant instability Which I think is because people buy GPS use that say 850 but are a little bit dodgy if you're pushing them that hard.
Speaker 1: so Over overheating probably also So.
Speaker 0: but also the 30 like generally the 60 is like the normal card for normal gamers.
Speaker 0: The 70 is a weird card.
Speaker 0: usually that's faster But maybe like I can't imagine any who actually needs it The 80 is like the sweet spot.
Speaker 0: The 80 TI is usually the like the one a professional would get because it's sometimes even as a slower clock.
Speaker 0: But it'll have like more cores or more RAM.
Speaker 0: It'll run cooler use less power for performance Gets using less power more less power per performance.
Speaker 1: I don't think usually the differences between that's what.
Speaker 1: the other thing that surprises me, right?
Speaker 1: Is it you know, the marketing difference right is like oh, yes this, you know, 30 70 38, right?
Speaker 1: It's like Megato make it time.
Speaker 1: I make it too, right but it's like the actual difference between them is So scant, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know the 99% of the time, you know.
Speaker 1: Would you ever notice the difference between the 3080 and the 3090?
Speaker 1: No, there would be no Perceptible difference.
Speaker 1: So mean them.
Speaker 0: there are other than if you're making games working in unity working in Maya working in like ZBrush and all these other tools the thing the 3090 has the Two things that has that don't apply to anyone who's playing games.
Speaker 0: These only apply to professionals.
Speaker 0: like a 3090 is worthless for gaming.
Speaker 0: even an index VR can run at Absolute max specs on a regular ass 3080.
Speaker 0: So the 3090 has double the video RAM and Way more coup de corps.
Speaker 1: But would you?
Speaker 1: Used if you're working this out for making how much time?
Speaker 1: how much time is it at real-world time?
Speaker 1: Is it actually saving when you push the render button versus the cheaper the one?
Speaker 0: This is like real-time editing and what happens is if you don't have enough RAM like video RAM Then but isn't you know, but is it half as much still enough?
Speaker 1: No, it's absolutely not.
Speaker 0: Like some of these applications.
Speaker 0: remember, they're not great.
Speaker 0: Remember how Adobe products used to be like.
Speaker 1: then how does it make these applications?
Speaker 1: What computers did they use to make them?
Speaker 1: if they've right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, if the majority of your customers do not have.
Speaker 0: No, they all have cards possible.
Speaker 0: It's a big problem in the video game industry last year was that people needed these new cards and literally couldn't get them.
Speaker 1: Well hat that's what I understand.
Speaker 1: It's like if you're making software, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, okay, you know You can't make software that at that demands, you know Some rare piece of hardware equipment that none of your customers have.
Speaker 1: you have to make your software run on The average hardware that most of your customers are going to be using.
Speaker 0: your customers are professionals.
Speaker 1: Then obviously that level is going to be much higher.
Speaker 1: Right, you know, but you can't like be like, oh, you know We know that the 3080 has what 12 gigabytes of Video RAM or something right and the 3090 is 24.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, it's like a 3080 has to be enough to run your software.
Speaker 1: You can't be writing software.
Speaker 1: That's like actually no you need the 24.
Speaker 1: We're gonna make unique get the 3090 or a software is gonna run poorly.
Speaker 0: Well, it depends bad.
Speaker 1: That's really bad on the side of the whoever's making the program.
Speaker 0: I mean you say that but that's like for example Monitoring software in capital markets takes about four times the performance of the software actually doing the trading.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: It's poorly written software.
Speaker 0: No, that's that's that the problem is actually more complex.
Speaker 0: It's way more work to make the thing than the final like rendered in-game real-time version of it is nobody Obviously, that's true.
Speaker 1: But the point is is that you still You know you cut.
Speaker 1: you have to consider no matter what software it is You have to consider what the customer is, you know, who's running the software is gonna have yeah, right?
Speaker 1: You can't set your system requirement too high if you want customers.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is these are happy are pretty reasonable for VR development.
Speaker 0: And the only problem is we've had this weird from weird video card crush because of cryptocurrency.
Speaker 1: well, there's also the Yeah, but it's just like what I was saying before, you know, these video cards is basically you know, it's like a hot rod.
Speaker 0: Some ridiculous car Reviews because you know, I decided against the 3090 for all the reasons we both talked about.
Speaker 0: but the best review I saw was this thing is a toaster oven that you put in your computer and turn on and never turn off Right.
Speaker 1: It's like oh you want to make your car faster, right?
Speaker 1: It's like well, you know You could cleverly engineer it and come up with better new radical designs that are more efficient and whatnot, right?
Speaker 1: which is the Apple way.
Speaker 1: or Just take the old shitty design.
Speaker 1: We've always had and just more power more heat sinks, right?
Speaker 1: Just like Duct-taped something on there, you know put so hands on it Do you know?
Speaker 0: on fighter jets, you know, you hear the term afterburner like.
Speaker 1: that's what that is.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, do you know how they actually work?
Speaker 1: It's even more ridiculous than you just think don't they just ignite the exhaust fumes to me?
Speaker 0: I hope they thrust.
Speaker 0: it's even worse than that.
Speaker 0: They basically spray fuel Past the original jet to cause a further set of fire and explosions among the exhaust.
Speaker 0: They're spraying fuel and f-16.
Speaker 0: I went to Starbase like this program that was obviously in retrospect trying to get kids to join the Air Force and indoctrinate them.
Speaker 0: but an f-16 can run its afterburner for like Seven minutes and then the whole planes out of fuel.
Speaker 0: it has to go land.
Speaker 1: Well, usually you have in air refueling, right?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but six or seven minutes of burning that thing because you're literally just spraying fuel out the back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what an Nvidia 3080 3090 is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, but it's like, you know as fast as it is Right and is you know, it's like I don't I'll probably get a new video card, you know, 50 80 something right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, see 80 something like that.
Speaker 0: So there's a reason.
Speaker 0: this 3080 TI is an Emily's computer because she needs it for work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can play overwatch just fine with my 1080.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna wait.
Speaker 0: either 3080 is MSRP or a 4080 comes out.
Speaker 0: or honestly I can't upgrade this computer to Windows 11 because it's the.
Speaker 0: the CPU is too old.
Speaker 0: So in 2025, I might just build a brand new workstation.
Speaker 1: I mean my.
Speaker 1: my 1070 runs both monitors at 4k and any game I've ever played in any Adobe app I've ever used in any program.
Speaker 1: I've ever tried to write.
Speaker 1: I've never had any slowness of any kind anywhere.
Speaker 1: The only thing I can do settings or anything with I can't do so with the 1080.
Speaker 0: I can't do index VR in full settings I don't do that.
Speaker 0: I do.
Speaker 0: and also I can't live stream myself doing VR while doing VR.
Speaker 1: Well, that's you know, this goes back to my other point I keep making which is like yeah VR is not for the people yet if it requires some kind of ludicrous machine to do it.
Speaker 0: But that's not consumer VR.
Speaker 0: That's the weird edge case.
Speaker 0: VR most VR is computerless mmm, anyway.
Speaker 0: So in some fantastic news, I haven't actually read the full Court ruling yet because it's recent.
Speaker 0: It's actually from today.
Speaker 0: There was a case a while ago that I think we even talked about on geek nights.
Speaker 1: Well, there have been several cases.
Speaker 1: I think this is the latest in a short line of them.
Speaker 0: This was the LinkedIn one.
Speaker 0: seems to be the one yeah that caused this ruling in the 9th Circuit Court Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So favorite one.
Speaker 0: Yeah The 9th Circuit Court if you're not a US Ian is basically like the one court district in our complicated in Southern, California.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that almost always makes the right decision compared to most of the other districts in the US like if there's ever a really good court decision in the US it almost Definitely came through that circuit court For reasons related to how fucked up America is.
Speaker 0: but anyway all these cases but this one in particular Boiled down to one fundamental question Can you take data that is visible on someone else's website and download it?
Speaker 0: That's actually what these cases are about Which if it sounds stupid because I'm looking at a web page meaning I have definitely already downloaded this In fact, I'm live streaming the web page that I downloaded to you right now on YouTube.
Speaker 0: So, why would that possibly be illegal.
Speaker 0: well lots of people have tried to make that illegal over the years.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, you know because people don't understand Right, like, you know that the two things look different, but they're not actually any different, right?
Speaker 1: It's like oh, you know you view sourced and you hacked our website.
Speaker 1: There was that situation.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, this is web scraping.
Speaker 0: What if I?
Speaker 1: so it's like, okay, you let me download a web page.
Speaker 1: All right, so I make a web page.
Speaker 1: I make a program that just downloads lots of web pages over and over again.
Speaker 1: It's like what's?
Speaker 1: it's?
Speaker 1: all I'm doing is visiting web pages real fast.
Speaker 1: It's not any different than visiting it in my browser.
Speaker 1: It's not doing anything different.
Speaker 1: It's just doing it a lot and doing it fast.
Speaker 1: It's like is it legal for me to go and go into a store and buy something?
Speaker 1: Yeah All right.
Speaker 1: Well go into the store and buy something and check out a million times really fast.
Speaker 1: It's like is that illegal?
Speaker 1: I guess not.
Speaker 0: Well, that's the old argument with Google Maps.
Speaker 0: when they added the street view first It was all right.
Speaker 0: Is it illegal to walk down a sidewalk and look at someone else's house?
Speaker 0: Like just look at it from the sidewalk?
Speaker 0: Absolutely not.
Speaker 0: That's perfectly legal.
Speaker 0: Is it legal for me to take a picture of that house?
Speaker 0: Perfectly legal.
Speaker 0: Is it legal for me to share that picture with other people also legal?
Speaker 1: So Google said, all right We'll do that to every single house in America Right now what you just do it computers allow doing things that Individually right are perfectly legal You know.
Speaker 1: whether those individual things are should be legal is another question.
Speaker 1: That's not important right now, right?
Speaker 1: And then they allow you to do those things at scale which does Create some sort of meaningful difference on the impact of that, you know a particular activity, right?
Speaker 1: you know, but You know, the court shouldn't be shouldn't be saying well doing any legal activity doing a legal activity Many times really fast should not turn it into any legal activity and so therefore web scraping should be legal and it is a Court.
Speaker 0: confirm that and the court basically like.
Speaker 0: I'm summarizing and paraphrasing and oversimplifying because we're not lawyers And this is not legal advice.
Speaker 0: You can read these articles.
Speaker 0: they link to the rulings.
Speaker 0: But what it came down to was the case was around a company mass scraping data out of people's LinkedIn profiles And those are public LinkedIn profiles.
Speaker 1: They aren't like, you know accessing so they weren't hacking into LinkedIn or or you know getting secret info.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and we didn't said that's against our terms of service and the court basically said so what?
Speaker 0: Your terms of service are your terms of service.
Speaker 0: You're welcome to block them.
Speaker 0: You're welcome to make that information behind some sort of paywall or gateway.
Speaker 0: you're welcome to throttle your website But if it's if you can see it you can scrape it and like, you know Now what they might do with the scraped information?
Speaker 1: right might might cause a problem, right?
Speaker 1: So for example, there might be a Website that has I don't know some Sports sports statistics, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I pay for access to get those statistics because I'm gonna be doing some sports broadcasting.
Speaker 1: No, right, so I pay for the what the Elias Sports Bureau, right?
Speaker 1: I pay for an account there and I I now I paid for this service.
Speaker 0: I'm legally allowed to see all this data But you're also legally bound with an asterisk because TOS or their own Can of worms we're not gonna get into.
Speaker 0: you're bound by the terms of service of that contract, right?
Speaker 1: So I go and I scrape all the data and now I have it, okay I was legally allowed to see the data with my eyes and access it with my computer cuz I paid for it.
Speaker 1: No problems, but now I go ahead and I open up Scott Sports Bureau.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Well now I'm in trouble.
Speaker 1: right now that I can't do.
Speaker 0: That is a huge part of my day.
Speaker 1: job industry is but I just keep it on my computer or use it for my own Purposes within the license that I'm you know, use it for my broadcast or whatever.
Speaker 0: But you just said use it, you know you license.
Speaker 1: Okay, I put it up on Pirate Bay to forever other people to download it.
Speaker 1: Oh, I'm in trouble But that's it.
Speaker 0: you license this data meaning you sign some sort of contract with this company to get the data.
Speaker 0: LinkedIn.
Speaker 0: I can go to LinkedIn's website from an incognito browser in a library.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't sign shit.
Speaker 1: You could just make up any old LinkedIn account and start browsing around and looking at people's resumes and shit.
Speaker 0: So the this was appealed.
Speaker 0: and now the decision.
Speaker 0: this was the second pass at this.
Speaker 0: they went further.
Speaker 0: They live relied on some old Supreme Court thing and they basically said the only time any of this is applicable is if the access to the data was clearly unauthorized and Access by illegal means.
Speaker 0: and I'm gonna quote the article because it says it best quote Using a gate up gate down analogy.
Speaker 0: The Supreme Court said that when a computer or websites gates are up and therefore information is publicly accessible No authorization is required period hmm.
Speaker 0: And I think that's the exact right call.
Speaker 1: as the technologist They got it, right Yeah, meanwhile, they went you know, Aaron shorts killed himself, right because they went after him for trying to download all those journal articles.
Speaker 0: You know how many people's lives especially Teenagers in the 90s who accessed government websites and then got like literally the FBI would go after them for Violating laws that were poorly written or didn't even exist.
Speaker 0: This is not a new problem and people's lives have been ruined But at least we know for sure scraping websites is perfectly legal.
Speaker 1: So scrape on But you know what you do with that.
Speaker 1: scrape data that might.
Speaker 1: that's questionable.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if I scrape location data and use that to make a hitman database and put hits on P there's laws I'm breaking.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, uh and some other news.
Speaker 0: a very bad man has tried to buy the very bad company.
Speaker 0: Elon Musk keeps trying to buy Twitter And he seems to have tried to buy it.
Speaker 1: He tried to buy it once then he gave up.
Speaker 0: He seems to have.
Speaker 0: it's not clear if he gave up or if he fucked it up so badly that now he can't buy it Because I want to get the.
Speaker 1: if you want the full details You're gonna read them online, but he has the vague outline right step one right is.
Speaker 1: he was unhappy with Twitter, right?
Speaker 1: You know because he's one of those, you know, lack of doodles.
Speaker 0: Well, there's a buried lead there He doesn't.
Speaker 1: who hasn't read the XK CD comic about what free speech means?
Speaker 0: even worse.
Speaker 0: So I found a totally separate article I'm gonna I could use for news today.
Speaker 0: It's too much but it was an analysis of tweets that speak favorably about Tesla vehicles and it found that a huge percentage of all tweets about Tesla vehicles that are positive Come from a very small number of accounts and a large percentage of them appear to be bots.
Speaker 1: So but the point is is that he's had a long history of getting in trouble for tweeting things and the SEC getting mad at him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's also periodically mad about people making fun of him on Twitter.
Speaker 1: Well anyway, so You know, he's got enough money.
Speaker 1: you could just do whatever he wants, right because that's how this world works right now And it's not good.
Speaker 1: So anyway, he's like in.
Speaker 1: the stock price of Twitter is low because it doesn't make any money.
Speaker 1: So he's like, you know what?
Speaker 1: I'll just buy this fucking thing, right?
Speaker 1: So he bought a large percentage of it like, you know, so I think he's now the largest single shareholder Although it's like what.
Speaker 1: eight or nine percent something like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah some percentage, right?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Maybe it was six whatever some number but a significant amount.
Speaker 1: and Then that number was supposed to get him a board seat, right?
Speaker 1: If you have that much shares in a company you can basically vote yourself into a board seat.
Speaker 0: All right immediately not to get into the nuances of boards, but right it's close enough.
Speaker 1: Yes, so he was gonna get a board seat But then he didn't because there was something about a. you know, there were some rumors swirling.
Speaker 0: No, all we know info all we know is he no longer sought the board seat.
Speaker 0: No one's game.
Speaker 1: there were some rumors about like a background check or something.
Speaker 1: who knows if that's true or not.
Speaker 0: But you know, we know he.
Speaker 0: we know he did not submit to the background check that was required by Twitter.
Speaker 0: That's all we.
Speaker 1: but anyway, the board seat thing didn't happen.
Speaker 1: So now he went for plan B or C or whatever plan.
Speaker 1: it was plan X. He's like, you know what I'll offer 50 something dollars a share.
Speaker 1: right and I'll you know, I'll offer that as a hostile takeover.
Speaker 1: So anyone who wants to sell me your Twitter shares, I'll pay way over what they're actually worth.
Speaker 1: Yeah Which is still Sun on a number he could at least buy.
Speaker 1: his net worth could afford.
Speaker 1: Who know?
Speaker 0: there's a lot of.
Speaker 0: there are multiple articles talking about how at the time that he made this supposed offer He did not actually have liquid assets arranged to be able to execute it, right?
Speaker 1: He would have had to secure financing or sells sell stocks and Tesla or something like that in order to get the money to buy the shares.
Speaker 0: if Which you know stating this publicly without having that lined up edge is potentially into malfeasance.
Speaker 1: But I'm sure the SEC is looking into it.
Speaker 0: Oh, the SEC has already issued some statements about all this.
Speaker 0: It's real funny, right?
Speaker 1: So anyway, so he says he's gonna.
Speaker 1: so if people had said, you know If the people who already had Twitter shares had said, okay I'll just cash out and take a bunch of money Twitter's going nowhere.
Speaker 1: He would have you know ended up owning 51 at least 51% of Twitter and then been Been able to turn it into a private company again and do whatever he wants, but that didn't happen because the board of Twitter Was like, you know what?
Speaker 1: We don't want that to happen.
Speaker 1: We don't like you even though you're our largest single shareholder.
Speaker 1: We're gonna do some shenanigans.
Speaker 0: They put a poison pill.
Speaker 0: my favorite thing.
Speaker 1: It's right.
Speaker 1: The bylaws of Twitter itself, right because they're the board they vote on those things like Common example.
Speaker 0: say I had a little company and I was gonna.
Speaker 0: I might sell it to someone.
Speaker 0: We might in our incorporating documents or bylaws or whatever make a rule that says if the company is sold Then anyone who works at the company as of the date of the sale cannot be fired for 10 years.
Speaker 0: Mmm, that's an example a fast I'll example of a poison pill.
Speaker 1: Right, so I believe I'm not a hundred percent sure what this one says but it says something along the lines of if this dude tries to come and buy us then Everyone who's already got shares can buy up a bunch of shares right in advance to sort of block him
Speaker 0: out.
Speaker 0: Okay, so I found Matt Levine tweeted Twitter's poison pill is I'm quoting?
Speaker 0: I haven't even read this yet.
Speaker 0: an exercise price of $210 allowing each shareholder to pay $210 to acquire stock having a then current market value of twice the exercise of god damn it.
Speaker 0: This is complicated.
Speaker 0: They basically made it to where if he tries to buy them out the people who are already on the board and existing shareholders can Unbuy it out.
Speaker 1: Yeah They could just acquire a bunch of share.
Speaker 0: the more I'm reading.
Speaker 0: It's market.
Speaker 0: It's too complicated.
Speaker 0: to summarize I got to read a deeper article.
Speaker 1: they can block him out face.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's all you need to know.
Speaker 0: He could get around this possibly but with more money.
Speaker 1: right with more money You know anyway, so he's not being able to buy Twitter.
Speaker 1: Twitter is still yep.
Speaker 0: To the two Twitter's boards credit because Twitter has made a series of terrible decisions over the years, but at the same time Letting this particular human being own Twitter and direct it and make it private Would possibly be the worst possible outcome.
Speaker 1: anyway, I mean it would just be a tumbler situation.
Speaker 1: It would just die.
Speaker 0: yep.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so the final news is that Jack the previous Twitter CEO who's not there anymore?
Speaker 1: I think he's on the board, but might leave the board soon or something.
Speaker 1: I don't know what his deal is now?
Speaker 1: who cares about that jerk?
Speaker 1: any yeah But he was like yeah, you know the the Twitter board is dysfunctional something something right.
Speaker 1: so he you know and Basically his complaint which is somewhat valid Depending on your perspective right from the perspective of someone who is you know got a capitalist motivation?
Speaker 1: It's like well if you own Twitter shares that aren't worth very much You want to accept that offer and cash out for 50 something bucks a share, and you'll make a ton of money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's you know.
Speaker 1: the fact that the board turned that down is like not in the interest of purely capitalist Shareholders.
Speaker 1: and his criticism was that hey those board members of Twitter act.
Speaker 1: They don't actually own that many shares themselves.
Speaker 0: Yep, right.
Speaker 0: There's a screenshot here where someone showed that the top 12 like owners of stock Whoa go.
Speaker 0: there's a great quote here.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure he's prepared to take on a couple PhDs a few MBAs and a Baroness who use Twitter once a year and collectively own 77 shares of the company.
Speaker 1: Yep, I mean the board.
Speaker 1: the people who do own the shares voted those people onto the board.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but those people on the board don't own that many shares themselves.
Speaker 1: So they don't give a crap.
Speaker 1: if it's you know what the.
Speaker 1: if you know then turning that down doesn't hurt them.
Speaker 1: No, right very much at all.
Speaker 1: So it's kind of a good thing in one way for Twitter to have people in charge of it who don't have a capitalist interest But it's also not a good well because they they are ultimately beholden to the fiduciary duty to the actual shareholders.
Speaker 1: right But it's also not a good thing because technically they're supposed to be capitalist or whatever, right?
Speaker 1: Theoretically, but anyway, so that's what happened there.
Speaker 1: I you know.
Speaker 1: Personally, you know, I'm just using Twitter less and less all the time.
Speaker 0: It's funny I actually use Twitter a lot and there's a but it's there's specific people.
Speaker 0: I talked to a lot on Twitter because I just don't have any other good way to talk to those specific people.
Speaker 1: but I mean if I like you I really need to talk to someone and if I were to stop using Twitter all together and I really needed to talk to someone who was only on Twitter.
Speaker 1: I'm sure I could talk to them.
Speaker 1: No problem.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no It's more than I have like semi public conversations with this like group of people on Twitter who really don't have a good forum To do that.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, but like you made some blur died.
Speaker 1: those people went somewhere, you know myspace died.
Speaker 1: Those people went somewhere.
Speaker 1: Facebook dies.
Speaker 1: people went somewhere, right?
Speaker 0: It's like there isn't really anywhere for that kind of conversation though cuz Mastodon sucks.
Speaker 1: I mean this play though something will arise.
Speaker 1: people will go somewhere, right?
Speaker 1: but really I'm not gonna.
Speaker 0: my main use of Twitter anything dies is as a publishing mechanism and That as long as the audience is there I will continue to publish stuff to Twitter.
Speaker 0: pretty much as much audience.
Speaker 0: They're Right, it's like, you know, I mean my biggest my biggest platform is one lips in and to YouTube.
Speaker 1: But yeah So that's that.
Speaker 1: that's a full drama that played out there.
Speaker 1: You know, I'm more and more.
Speaker 1: I just see myself, you know Retreating from the like the public, you know social networking places.
Speaker 0: Oh The semi-private curated places are the place to be and always have been the private g-chats the discords the geek nights Forum could see a renaissance.
Speaker 1: I don't know maybe but I'm just using those places as Sort of, you know a broad like you said a broadcast mechanism, right?
Speaker 1: Like I uploaded a YouTube video Okay, I guess I'll tweet about it and post about it here and post about it there So that you know, cuz other people I'm not here to decide what you know.
Speaker 1: What other people should use is their platform of choice, right?
Speaker 1: People have their reasons for staying on Facebook or using Instagram or whatever.
Speaker 1: So it's like, okay I'll meet you where you are.
Speaker 1: If I want to share something I made or thought so badly Right, then I should go to where you are to tell you about.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: My philosophy is put it put my stuff everywhere.
Speaker 0: That's why I get All these platforms.
Speaker 1: as long as they exist I'll go to them and I'll post on them, you know to announce whatever.
Speaker 1: But it's like, you know in terms of having a conversation or communications or oh I don't have conversations on Twitter other than with my friends.
Speaker 0: Like I post something and if people want to discuss it I tend to just block all.
Speaker 1: I don't need to use any of those sites for that You know, even though I might from time to time right?
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: I'll just bring all that stuff You know back to whatever right even if I have to go back to IRC or who knows dark dark recess over the internet.
Speaker 0: I have to go if I want to see people talking about my work.
Speaker 0: They're coming to my own forum my own discord and I'm not really looking anywhere else.
Speaker 1: Anyway, you know, but even if discord goes away it's like I'm okay with that.
Speaker 1: So we don't.
Speaker 1: I'm not too upset when I see when I see stories about the collapse of a website, you know platform sites Yeah, I guess what I find interesting is that the world might be better if they all died.
Speaker 0: Twitter unlike all other social media platforms it happens to do a fairly unique thing and everyone who's tried to make a clone of it or Take its ideas and do something similar have failed.
Speaker 0: And I think it's mostly because of the critical mass of people who are on Twitter.
Speaker 0: Facebook had a long hemorrhaging of people but Twitter seems to Maintain its audience in a way that other platforms haven't.
Speaker 1: because well I don't Twitter doesn't have the largest audience in terms of number of people who are like active all the time.
Speaker 1: But I think what keeps Twitter specifically afloat is its connection to news and journalism.
Speaker 0: a lot of people Without right using.
Speaker 0: like my mom She's like.
Speaker 0: she follows me on Twitter only Recently as she started like really like engaging with people on Twitter for most of the time.
Speaker 0: She's on Twitter.
Speaker 0: She just read it like a new site.
Speaker 1: It's not right, but it's not just reading it as a news site But also you go to right.
Speaker 1: it's like, you know a news site.
Speaker 1: like you watch a TV news We'll report on so and so tweeted this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that right will be but you don't see news.
Speaker 1: So-and-so Facebook posted that.
Speaker 1: why cuz?
Speaker 1: Facebook posts aren't some public linkable thing exactly?
Speaker 1: so You know, that's how that works.
Speaker 1: Yeah, journalists also go on Twitter and find out the news the same way that we will and then report on it.
Speaker 0: You know as secondary I can say one interesting fact this for the first time ever Twitter.
Speaker 0: like when the Ukraine war actually happened.
Speaker 0: like when it actually started Twitter told me it was happening before Fark did.
Speaker 0: I have never had Fark not be the first way I found out about fucking anything in my life before Twitter's that Twitter's.
Speaker 1: you've been the fastest for a long time.
Speaker 0: Yep, though Fark had way more Information than Twitter way faster.
Speaker 1: Well, you got a. you know, it's harder to put the information together on Twitter.
Speaker 1: It is far more organized.
Speaker 0: Yep, Fark still hanging on.
Speaker 0: I still pay for Fark.
Speaker 0: Fark's gonna someday.
Speaker 0: I think I paid for Fark for a long time.
Speaker 0: Fark's great.
Speaker 0: So anyway Things of the day.
Speaker 0: so check this out Really tiny little thing.
Speaker 0: Uh This is there's.
Speaker 0: this is almost environmental storytelling.
Speaker 0: My thing of the day is just a tweet that was making the rounds.
Speaker 0: See my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: I'll tweet.
Speaker 0: This is how deeply infested we are with Twitter.
Speaker 0: but this tweet was an image and all it said was New at the local game shop from a verified account.
Speaker 0: a lot of people retweeting it lots of conversations Multiple reddit threads about this image.
Speaker 0: The image was an opened and defaced Copy of a Super Nintendo game called demons crest which not rare like don't is not a rare game.
Speaker 0: And the two notable things about it were one it has Written badly on it in marker and I'm just gonna read what is written on this cartridge.
Speaker 0: Fucking mine.
Speaker 0: You can only fucking borrow this game and It has a price tag of a thousand US dollars.
Speaker 0: So I saw a scary number of people freaking out like there's no way that games worth a thousand dollars and others Trying to rationalize it like but what if this was a rental only copy?
Speaker 0: because there's a third long story short.
Speaker 0: Nobody knows who wrote that text on it.
Speaker 0: It was probably kid some kid who lent this game to a friend and made it clear that it's fucking his and he's gonna get It back because he's exactly 13 years old.
Speaker 0: He owns a game called demons crest and he's an edge Lord The gate.
Speaker 0: the story is the game.
Speaker 0: store owner thought this was really funny and just put this thousand dollar price tag on it Just for a joke and took a picture of it.
Speaker 0: and that picture is online and everyone's freaking out about this and all these Conversations about it.
Speaker 0: It's just a joke guys.
Speaker 1: And in fact, if you don't give the context then people start, you know thinking, you know.
Speaker 1: try to imagine things except the context was trivial.
Speaker 0: discover by clicking on the tweet and Scrolling down in the people.
Speaker 0: don't do that.
Speaker 0: The guy who posted it was like FYI.
Speaker 0: Here's the entire story and somehow everybody missed it and there's even people don't do that.
Speaker 1: Did you see the picture?
Speaker 1: Yeah, how many and how many people copied that picture and pasted it somewhere else without you know?
Speaker 1: Even if people set posted a bedded a link to the tweet that doesn't include the whole thread It just includes the tweet itself, you know.
Speaker 0: so if there's probably some kid out there who has a ti-85 calculator where the name rim and I don't remember what I believe I wrote like property of rim and some other stuff with a knife on the back of it And I'm sure
Speaker 1: sure that's probably in a landfill.
Speaker 0: The fives are pretty good if you replace the batteries anyway, what do you got?
Speaker 1: so another social platform right.
Speaker 1: read it for the April bullshit day Which was you know a couple weeks ago, they do this thing.
Speaker 1: They've been doing it for a while now called our place Which is basically the way it works.
Speaker 1: is they open up a big white canvas And if you have a reddit account You can go to that big white canvas and you can select one pixel and change the color of that pixel.
Speaker 1: And I think there's like maybe 16 color 32 not that many colors to choose from very small number of colors to choose from But it's you know, a full Crayola set right?
Speaker 1: You're not you're not gonna be like, oh no, there's no red.
Speaker 1: It's like they got red.
Speaker 1: It's like come on And you set a pixel and then you think you have to wait five or ten minutes and then you can set another Pixel.
Speaker 1: or you can get multiple reddit accounts and start doing lots of pixels Or you can get a large subreddit of coordinated people to do a lot of pixels And of course you can overwrite other people's pixels, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, I could put down a black and rim can just be like come right on top and turn it white again.
Speaker 0: It's like why you've got to have some amount of community power to do anything interesting here.
Speaker 1: Well read it happens to be a social network built around communities, right all these different subreddits.
Speaker 1: So you get all the people of your subreddit together.
Speaker 1: now, it doesn't just matter how many people are in your subreddit It matters how many of them give a shit?
Speaker 1: How many of them have time for this?
Speaker 1: Right how many of them care?
Speaker 1: and you can go and onto this big canvas.
Speaker 1: you can draw things and sort of claim.
Speaker 1: So it's sort of a game of claiming territory via social influence, but also you know, it's a Artwork thing right where you know, what do we draw?
Speaker 1: Where do we draw it?
Speaker 1: trying to integrate with the things that are drawing nearby right lots of integration going on?
Speaker 1: You know, there's just so many dynamics and at the end right when they when they turn it off the end result is Usually I don't want to say picture of the internet But it's basically a picture of the communities of reddit and like, you know You can see like that year at that exact moment, you know, what was big what was not so big, right?
Speaker 0: Fascinating to dig through this especially because there's a lot of one-off pixels that are the wrong color because it's a battle.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I'm very pleased that you know, fuck cars got a really big spot.
Speaker 1: So that Kennedy the anti car movement is growing.
Speaker 1: You can see that like lots of country flags are large right because you know, like Turkey's got a pretty large right, you know You know, he's really did a lot of this.
Speaker 0: There's like multiple whole areas that were done by Turkish reddit.
Speaker 0: Yep, there's a picture of out of Turk.
Speaker 1: There's a giant Turkish flag the out of Turk at the top.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's also the Turkish flag with the Istanbul cityscape.
Speaker 1: Yep, you got there's all kinds of stuff on here and you know, this is only the end picture.
Speaker 1: But the website that's actually my thing of the day is the reddit place atlas for 2022.
Speaker 1: And what this is is they took the final image.
Speaker 1: You see you don't get to see the evolution of it which is sad but They have sort of gone over the image and carved out Every single different piece of it and sort of given you a label so you can understand what everything is Like.
Speaker 1: it's like you see some guy's face and you're like what the hell is that and you hold your mouse over it.
Speaker 0: and it's like Oh, oh, it's about show a Turkish rock musician.
Speaker 1: It's a total biscuit tribute that guy who died.
Speaker 1: Here's a whole bunch of paragraphs about him.
Speaker 1: I forgot.
Speaker 1: Oh, what's this over here?
Speaker 1: Oh, it's kpop alley.
Speaker 1: These are all these different kpop groups that all put their shit near each other.
Speaker 0: Battle of the heroes a mural depicting the duel between obi-wan Kenobi and Anakin Skywalker, right?
Speaker 1: Here's a Star Wars poster and then even within the Star Wars poster.
Speaker 1: They're like, this is the Death Star.
Speaker 1: This is yeah Yeah, so you can learn a lot about the culture of you know, the people of the internet of you know 2022 and Reddit by going over this image and hovering over things and being like what the hell is.
Speaker 1: you know, you know What is that?
Speaker 1: Why would enough people get together to fight for space to draw that image there and then defend it to the very end, right?
Speaker 1: Why would they care enough to do that?
Speaker 1: You know if there were that many people who put that effort forth whatever that image is Must have some significance to enough people on this earth that maybe it's worth knowing what the image is and what it stands for.
Speaker 0: So yeah from crosscode the main protagonist of the action role-playing game crosscode released in 2018 From Austria.
Speaker 0: The other thing that I think is really striking about it is how extremely non?
Speaker 0: u.s.
Speaker 0: Centric it is.
Speaker 1: Yeah You know those Pete, you know people from those countries have a lot more pride, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know they you know I mean, there's a lot of other and I would not be putting a very super pro-american thing on this thing.
Speaker 1: American flags in the bottom right?
Speaker 1: That's what the pro-america stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah But you know for example, right, you know a good example of how like the numbers don't line up right the the Vancouver Canucks right.
Speaker 1: their logo is somewhere on here and it's actually pretty significantly large and fancy.
Speaker 1: and You know somehow the people of Vancouver like they had that thing in there early and they held it like for a long time.
Speaker 1: It's a pretty sure it's in the final image, right?
Speaker 1: Meanwhile, the Rangers right?
Speaker 1: We have way more fans.
Speaker 1: Our subreddit is way bigger, right?
Speaker 0: And the workers would have time for that shit.
Speaker 1: I'm like exactly the best.
Speaker 1: the best the best we could do is Right, we could.
Speaker 1: we tagged along the Colorado Avalanche put like a whole, you know Pretty fancy looking full logo there and we have like a sad looking like Hank.
Speaker 1: It says Hank 30 like a blurry like we had to like team up with them to get some space Because so few Rangers fans gave a shit.
Speaker 1: Better things to do.
Speaker 0: this is this is not a representation of the biggest internet communities.
Speaker 0: It's the most online Internet communities.
Speaker 1: Well the most caring about this particular thing on reddit.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's it's still really fascinating to browse through it and look around it and see what you know, five things.
Speaker 1: See things you recognize don't recognize learn about stuff You know, maybe and a lot.
Speaker 1: the really useful thing is like you'll see some image and you're like.
Speaker 1: I've seen that around I've seen that but what is it?
Speaker 1: you hover over it now, you know what it is, you know quack And that's nice.
Speaker 0: Oh Is that marks?
Speaker 0: is that marks?
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yes, it's Carl Marx.
Speaker 0: Good job Okay Anyway in the matter moment the geek nights book club book was NK jemisins the city we became.
Speaker 0: we read it We did a show on it.
Speaker 0: That book is fantastic.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna read the sequel Basically instantly when it comes out But it won't be a book kind of like how I read the entire wheel of time.
Speaker 1: The next book club selection.
Speaker 1: the current book club selection is listener choice Nine Fox gambit not ten boxes not eight, but nine nine foxes.
Speaker 1: So Listener got their way there where we rims gonna.
Speaker 1: I already read the book rims gonna read the book the listener Some point and then we'll do an episode a few months probably.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll give you time to read it.
Speaker 0: I feel like I'll read.
Speaker 1: hopefully I don't forget it all.
Speaker 0: there is a chance We will record the episode earlier like as soon as I finish it, but not a bad idea.
Speaker 0: But we'll make sure we don't like the.
Speaker 0: it's not official.
Speaker 0: We're not gonna put it in this in the.
Speaker 0: we might livestream it if we do that But we won't like put it in the feed until you've had enough time to read it So you can still actually follow along.
Speaker 0: it is a book club.
Speaker 0: Not everyone reads entire books over the course of like a week like we do Yep.
Speaker 0: So I yeah, it's got right into it.
Speaker 0: There was a tweet that caused us to think of this idea and the tweet was a an image Posted by YouTube gaming and it said in which era of video cables.
Speaker 0: Did you start your gaming journey and anyone?
Speaker 0: Who is older than like being a tiny child?
Speaker 0: immediately took issue with the fact that It did not cover most of the cables that were used for gaming over the years And it didn't even have the cables.
Speaker 0: that is showed in the right order.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we've done.
Speaker 1: we've done shows on like monitors and other things of that nature, but we never did a show I think on video cables specifically and video cables are interesting in that There's sort of this unique kind of cable right.
Speaker 1: most other cables like power cables.
Speaker 1: It's like they send power.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like, you know, there are some differences.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know some that I I work with.
Speaker 0: I used to work with I don't anymore with DC driven data centers.
Speaker 0: so our power cables were Giant bars of exposed metal behind glass plates.
Speaker 0: do not touch them.
Speaker 1: That's a power cable?
Speaker 1: Yeah, sure.
Speaker 1: You've also got data cables which send Data, right?
Speaker 1: But video cables, right?
Speaker 1: Are sending a specific kind of data and they under very specific circumstances right that you have.
Speaker 1: you're sending data that will represent an image that will be displayed on some sort of monitor of some kind some display device projector or something right and You need to send not only how many different colors the device can display but also You know enough data so that it can render all the frames that it's going to be sending and Consistently so that the frames are displaying, you know at even intervals, right?
Speaker 1: So there's like a video cable is like a unique thing in the world of cables and that it has completely different requirements from all others.
Speaker 1: and on top of that over the years the Devices on both ends of a video cable have changed Significantly in how they work and thus the video cables have had to change significantly to meet the requirements on both ends.
Speaker 0: and also about the most fascinating part the Signaling over these cables was analog analog for a long time.
Speaker 0: digital video over cables for anything other than extremely niche or like professional use cases was Practically non-existent until and now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it seems like a good time to talk about video cables now because what we're seeing in the present time is USBC becoming at least that the physical structure of USBC Regardless of what's going over the cable might be DisplayPort or Thunderbolt or whatever, right?
Speaker 0: It's the cable to rule them all.
Speaker 1: it's the cable that is now replacing all other cables including video cables.
Speaker 1: I think in within Definitely within five to ten years for sure.
Speaker 1: I think just everything that's going to connect to anything else with any kind of data whether it's video data or otherwise is going to be that shape of cable and Any other kind of cable is going to be slowly made obsolete.
Speaker 0: I mean networking will remain like that's not going to change.
Speaker 1: Right now I could see a world in which well, first of all people are mostly networking wirelessly, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so, you know then in the in the data center at the office probably still gonna be Ethernet, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, well because USBC has a very short range remember.
Speaker 1: Yes, but I could see a world in which you get a router from Your ISP right in 2020.
Speaker 0: Oh We've already had that.
Speaker 0: my my router at the right beacon had a USB port on it and you could plug a computer Directly into that.
Speaker 1: No, I thought those USB C ports that are on those That was regularized USB right goes were for plugging in Storage devices that would then become networks.
Speaker 0: there were routers You could directly plug a computer into.
Speaker 1: I've there may have been but I've never seen that in my life.
Speaker 0: I've seen them I've used them.
Speaker 0: They were slow as shit because USB direct networking sucked shit.
Speaker 1: Well, but the point is I could very well see ISPs soon putting giving people routers in their homes that have Wi-Fi and Like a single USB C connection if you really want to connect your device,
Speaker 0: I won't - my rationale is Anyone who thinks about that is the kind of person who would never use a wired connection anyway.
Speaker 1: Well, because I think what you're getting right someone has like a MacBook Pro, right?
Speaker 1: It's like why should they go out and buy some USB C to use?
Speaker 0: the router is almost definitely not gonna be where their Mac Book is and you can't make a long USB C cable.
Speaker 1: You don't know.
Speaker 1: You can make something that you absolutely cannot.
Speaker 1: this I could very I I could see very much.
Speaker 1: No, not too distant future.
Speaker 1: No more Ethernet in people's houses.
Speaker 1: So yes, but I think it's replaced except for nerds who have it on purpose.
Speaker 0: I think it's replaced by all wireless.
Speaker 1: I think there would.
Speaker 1: you know, there might be replaced by all wireless.
Speaker 1: But if it's not I think there might be a USB C on the.
Speaker 1: I don't think so because nothing in the USB C Physical you're also gonna see like a cable box that has USB C to go to the television.
Speaker 0: You'll see that.
Speaker 0: you'll see that easily.
Speaker 1: It's all the same, right?
Speaker 0: You'll just get now, but it's your range There is.
Speaker 0: you have you ever read the specs for a physical USB C cable.
Speaker 0: There is no provision for long.
Speaker 1: I got one really long one and it does work really long.
Speaker 0: How long Ethernet can go a kilometer.
Speaker 1: It's not that long.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we don't need it to go a kilometer though.
Speaker 1: It's not across the living room.
Speaker 0: One thing I've seen is a lot of people and this gets back to that YouTube tweet because knowledge of old cables is lost Coaxial RF cables The same cables used for old TV signaling were used for cable modems and to this day are used even my FiOS.
Speaker 0: It's FiOS into my front like the front of the apartment and then there's a device there that has coax that goes through the apartment into the computer room where the router is.
Speaker 0: a Lot of people don't know that those cables are dirt cheap Trivial to run and they pay a lot of money to get Verizon or something to run that cable for them through their own house.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so the the oldest video cable will go back to the beginning because you guys do it.
Speaker 0: That would be proprietary Soldered or twisted on RF cables because right?
Speaker 0: So was transferred from any device like early gaming devices.
Speaker 0: early everything they had to connect to existing TVs and existing TVs were designed to be connected directly to a 300 ohm RF antenna connection.
Speaker 1: exactly so you had this antenna on your roof and it was picking up signals from the air from some broadcast antenna wirelessly and then Just like a radio that signal went into your television and that was the only input the television had.
Speaker 1: So what you would end up having to do to send some other thing into your television?
Speaker 1: That wasn't from an antenna.
Speaker 1: is?
Speaker 1: you would basically have to Broadcast television right only instead of broadcasting it on an antenna, right?
Speaker 1: so the whole world you would broadcast it over a wire and Which I want to point out TV That is all.
Speaker 0: cable TV is the signals going over like cable TV when it first was introduced.
Speaker 0: Same signals that are going over the air just on a cable instead of in the air.
Speaker 1: Yep, just the exact same broadcast.
Speaker 1: You could take like a VCR, right?
Speaker 1: So what is a VCR?
Speaker 1: It's a magnetic tape and on the tape they've recorded the RF signal and you play it back again just as it was.
Speaker 1: It's not converting it to other it's just writing it down and playing the signal back again.
Speaker 0: Well, even worse consent tape records FM, you know It's encoded in this complicated spiral slant way because you don't there isn't enough bandwidth on a VCR tape a VHS tape.
Speaker 0: But
Speaker 1: regardless you could if you could take a VCR with the VHS tape Right, and if you had a big enough antenna and a big enough amplifier You could broadcast directly over the air and some old TV with an antenna could then watch what the videotape you were playing.
Speaker 1: Alright, that would totally work.
Speaker 1: So an old Atari or an old Nintendo right would just create TV signals.
Speaker 1: You could hook up an NES or an Atari 2600 to a giant antenna and the whole world to be watching combat.
Speaker 1: Pat man, right you could do it and then you would connect it to the back of the TV where the antenna goes and Usually it was in the form of these two prongs because the antenna is always connected with these little forks.
Speaker 1: Right, you would put the screw in the middle of the forks, right?
Speaker 0: So yeah.
Speaker 0: So the funny thing is I needed a picture of that and I discovered something terrifying.
Speaker 0: By and large the internet doesn't even know that the twin lead RF existed.
Speaker 0: I found and I googled for it.
Speaker 1: That's how old we are.
Speaker 0: Nobody knows what it's called and I found mostly people posting questions asking what the fuck are these two?
Speaker 0: Screw things in the back of this old TV.
Speaker 0: What do they do?
Speaker 0: What's this called?
Speaker 0: What can I plug into it?
Speaker 0: Nobody knows but it's twin lead RF or 300 ohm RF designed to be plugged in directly to an antenna The coax cables that come out of cable boxes or cable TV.
Speaker 1: that is RF But it's exactly the same as the two forks only it's 75 ohm.
Speaker 0: There's multiple differences.
Speaker 0: You actually have to convert that signal if you want to plug it into a TV That does not have a coaxial input.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: It came way later Yep But yeah So the had that.
Speaker 1: and then what you would have to do with those that was a lot of fun back in the day is It's like well, I want to plug my Atari into my TV.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I also want to plug the TV into the antenna.
Speaker 1: still I still want to watch TV sometimes.
Speaker 1: So you would have an RF switch and you would go behind your TV and flick the switch.
Speaker 1: yeah, so and you would plug the antenna into the switch and the Atari into the switch and then the switch into the TV and You would switch between the two just like an HDMI switch nowadays.
Speaker 0: and that switch it would basically the art.
Speaker 0: Ari would send its T It's RF signal through that box.
Speaker 0: on the frequency.
Speaker 0: that happened to be US channel 3 but it was different frequencies in other countries, right?
Speaker 1: So you had to turn in the United States.
Speaker 1: you have to turn your TV to channel 3 to watch What was being broadcast by the attack.
Speaker 0: when I was a kid the two greatest mysteries in my life?
Speaker 0: Where?
Speaker 0: why channel 3?
Speaker 0: and why isn't there a channel 1?
Speaker 0: because there wasn't an internet to look that up on and you know.
Speaker 1: Only now to literally this moment.
Speaker 1: I realized you know what they could have done if they had a more powerful, right?
Speaker 1: You know Atari back in the day.
Speaker 1: You could have broadcast different parts of the game on different channels and you could have had like you could have had the Atari sending Out, you know data on like seven channels and you flip between them like channel 2. is the map?
Speaker 1: channel 3 is the right You know, they could have done that if they had enough power.
Speaker 0: There's lots of nonsense you could have done But yeah, pretty much no one did that ever.
Speaker 0: but in terms of video cables that consumers used in their own homes.
Speaker 0: Twin lead RF was it for most of the history of video existing in homes?
Speaker 1: Yep, the coax RF came around when cable TV became a thing And they still had switches for those.
Speaker 1: but the switches were like they had.
Speaker 1: the NES came with like an automatic switch.
Speaker 1: You didn't have to go back and flick it yourself.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like if you turn this gray box, right?
Speaker 1: It automatically detected when you turn the NES on and then would turn off the TV antenna and then when you turn the NES off The TV would come back.
Speaker 0: But also that NES device.
Speaker 0: I want to say it took.
Speaker 0: it only took in 75 Ohm.
Speaker 0: So if you had an old 300 ohm antenna, you still needed a converter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you had the twin lead you needed a special extra thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah that TV we had up until beacon had twin lead on the back.
Speaker 1: So Atari, right?
Speaker 1: So Atari was twin lead NES was coax, but also the NES did have at the Famicom didn't have it.
Speaker 1: But the NES actually had one advantage over the Famicom and that it did have component RCA.
Speaker 1: It didn't have stereo sound.
Speaker 1: It just had a red and a yellow and a white or a white whatever Yellow and it just had one video and one audio and that was it.
Speaker 1: But if you had a TV that took RCA in that was definitely preferred.
Speaker 1: Do you use that?
Speaker 0: but TVs that could take RCA in were?
Speaker 0: Extremely rare.
Speaker 1: for until the later 90s at least mid mid to late 90s, I'd say yep I didn't really see too many.
Speaker 0: now This is where it starts to get a little complicated because what signal is going over?
Speaker 0: a cable is not necessarily like one-to-one related to what kind of cable you're losing and it gets more and more complex into the future, but RCA is what most people call it.
Speaker 0: some people call it component RCA But a lot of people who call it that think that that is component Which is no component is different.
Speaker 0: and also component was rarely used by any Consumer except nerds and it only was really popular for a very brief period of time.
Speaker 1: Though it's the best option.
Speaker 0: if you have a Wii, I hope you have a Wii or like a Gamecube That is the best possible.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: It was so much better than using RCA, but yeah RCA Basically became the defacto standard for video for a long time in the US and It was a standard that included video and audio which was made it easy, but the signaling over that thing It wasn't RF.
Speaker 0: It was something completely different.
Speaker 1: And this yeah, I never really I never fully understood it how it worked.
Speaker 0: It just sent two components basically.
Speaker 1: Yeah But the main thing the main significant difference for the the RCA over the RF right was that number one?
Speaker 1: It was much easier to figure out how to set it up, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah Switches there were standardized colors yellow red and white.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now the video was separated from the audio.
Speaker 1: So now you could send the video to the television and the audio to a receiver Separately without having to have the TV get involved and you could now suddenly do you know?
Speaker 1: Hook up sound systems and things to your television more easily with RCA.
Speaker 1: Also, you didn't need this external switching thing to go behind the TV or whatever because now your TV could just have like five sets of RCA inputs and In this is when the first TVs instead of turning to channel 3 or something You would just push the input button on your remote control.
Speaker 0: TVs didn't have the input button before RCA really and in fact a lot of TVs they had a big switch to flip between VHF and UHF.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but now once you had RCA It's like okay.
Speaker 1: now the TV has an input button and one of the inputs is the antenna which is could be cable TV Or could be an antenna, but then there'll be other inputs, which are the RCA input.
Speaker 1: So now your VCR eventually DVD players when they came out right all video game consoles for a long time all Used RCA as the way to plug into the television even up to Gamecubes.
Speaker 0: PlayStations right now Is an ancient standard that predates any of this.
Speaker 0: it just wasn't used in console a lot of consumer technology.
Speaker 0: It was used heavily in audio, but not commonly used in video until way later, but the other I mean, yeah There were plenty of audio devices.
Speaker 1: I've seen that just like I have cables that go from like, you know headphone size to just red and white.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's unbalanced like.
Speaker 0: it's not the best way to send audio but it works.
Speaker 1: And it was.
Speaker 1: it was the most friendly, you know, you didn't need a screwdriver You didn't need to know what the hell's going on.
Speaker 0: Oh, you want to hear about.
Speaker 0: you want to know.
Speaker 0: you know, like my stalagmites might hang from the ceiling But they don't mnemonic.
Speaker 0: I have an equally terrible red is on the right side, right?
Speaker 1: White is on it.
Speaker 1: White is on the left side.
Speaker 0: Right is red and left is white.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's how I used to remember it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know and I want to say it Craig.
Speaker 0: I might be wrong.
Speaker 0: it's been a long time because the official rule is If you only plug in the white one Then the device is supposed to assume you're sending an analog signal and send that audio to both speakers.
Speaker 0: But nothing modern does that Mono, yes, it's supposed to assume its mono and send it to both speakers But I don't think any modern device does that.
Speaker 1: but the other problem is RCA was the cable from all the way from like the NES and even the Commodore 64.
Speaker 1: I remember the Commodore 64 monitor had RCA on the front of it as the way to plug your Commodore into it.
Speaker 0: Oh, I had.
Speaker 0: there were devices that used RCA connectors, but they sent RF signals over them.
Speaker 0: This is where RCA gets complicated.
Speaker 0: RCA is just a cable specification.
Speaker 0: There's lots of different ways to use those connectors.
Speaker 0: So if you heard about component with the three different colored things, I think it's like green blue there.
Speaker 0: yet Yeah, but that's RCA.
Speaker 0: That's also RCA.
Speaker 0: It's in the same specification Yep.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so though that was this.
Speaker 1: that was the way to plug things into a TV from.
Speaker 1: you know Commodore 64 up through I mean ps2 still used it, right?
Speaker 1: I guess until you know HD was a thing.
Speaker 0: My TV still has a yellow white and red in the back and also another white and red for audio in the back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my TV.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So while during that long period where RCA was the thing for televisions Computers had all kinds of different shit going on.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: All these old computers had all kinds of different weird things that they used.
Speaker 1: you had Frickin the Apple computers all had like RGB cables and all kinds of weird things going on.
Speaker 1: PCs had VGA cables then they had DVI cables.
Speaker 1: All right, they had the S video cable.
Speaker 1: the S video cable is really weird as video.
Speaker 0: when I when I first encountered it I thought wow, that's amazing It's just is it's just a better cable.
Speaker 0: and then I discovered rapidly that almost nothing supported it by the time It was widely available.
Speaker 0: It was already obsolete and now it's gone.
Speaker 1: Yep, so as video was this inch.
Speaker 1: it was interesting though in that there was enough Deployment of it that you could use it like TVs had an S video in for the most part during that time period.
Speaker 0: why?
Speaker 0: During that period TVs had it but no devices had it.
Speaker 0: No VCR fight.
Speaker 1: There were devices that had Video cards that had it.
Speaker 0: almost every device that had it was a was either a camcorder.
Speaker 0: That's the place.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's right.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yep, and a handful of video cards.
Speaker 1: I think there were some game consoles to where it was possible to have a game console.
Speaker 1: Maybe a dreamcast could had one.
Speaker 1: maybe I want to say I'm not a hundred percent sure I have.
Speaker 0: anyway, I'm actually unaware of any game console that had S video.
Speaker 1: I think there were some that you could have as video but regardless it was all as video was sort of a like.
Speaker 1: it never got fully adopted I think because Even if it was deployed somewhat significantly, it was never alone, right?
Speaker 1: you were never in a situation where like that was what you had to use.
Speaker 1: because like if If a device had an S video out it had another video out besides as video.
Speaker 1: Oh TV had an S video in.
Speaker 1: it had plenty of RCA ends and other ends.
Speaker 1: So you were never in a situation We're like S video was the one you were gonna use And it wasn't.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it was different or not, but it definitely wasn't significant.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's what I was gonna get to.
Speaker 0: so as video is one cable But all it sends is Luma and chroma The same fucking Luma and chroma that we send over that yellow cable at RCA.
Speaker 0: It just has more grounding like it's.
Speaker 0: it's better designed, but it's not better.
Speaker 1: Yep Okay, so all those computer cables right the VGA VGAs and DVIs right those were basically like, you know breaking things down into tons of.
Speaker 1: you know Separation right a bunch of a little wires all on separate pins But also what.
Speaker 1: that's also where we started to move to digital signaling because VGA was analog signaling still Yep still but there was a VGA still has a digital signal for like the v-sync, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, one of the some of those pins because that's the one difference with a computer versus a television right the television Like, you know what the the frame rate is on the television at least in those days, right?
Speaker 1: It was locked in whereas with computers right your vertical refresh rate was could be anything and your resolution could be different as well.
Speaker 1: So a lot of those pins on VGI and DVA were to synchronize the clock DVA VGA DVI whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah But a lot of those pins were there to synchronize the clock so you could get the frame rate and resolution Correct, right the horizontal sync but all the data was just pure analog RGB HV, which was literally red green blue.
Speaker 0: Horizontal sync vertical sync and all the other pins are just in support of those.
Speaker 0: Yep, there's also some data pins power pin and there were some data pins that I don't think were ever used by anything ever.
Speaker 1: We had a recent thing of the day Ben eater.
Speaker 1: He has a video where he shows you how to basically make a VGA display video card, right?
Speaker 1: It's like world's worst.
Speaker 1: It calls the video like world's worst video card to something and if you watch that video, you'll understand how VGA works.
Speaker 0: Yep, but VGA for all these pins It's not really that different from component which used RCA.
Speaker 0: But instead of having one for video one for left channel one for right channel It had three video pins and VGA actually very similarly just has three video pins for the three colors.
Speaker 1: But but due to the vertical and horizontal syncs being in there It supported a wide variety of resolutions and frame rates that the other cables couldn't do.
Speaker 0: And VGA was the standard for computers for a long time and D long time Didn't actually replace it.
Speaker 0: It just coexisted alongside it because it added some things.
Speaker 0: but it also wasn't Super universally adopted and it starts the company.
Speaker 1: I did have some other features that but like those features never really got used.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: if you could well DVI you could run VGA signaling over some of the pins.
Speaker 0: on DVI you can have analog and digital signals coexisting.
Speaker 0: on DVI You could drive two monitors from the same DVI cable and yep.
Speaker 0: Very little of this was ever used.
Speaker 0: DVI was kind of over engineered and ahead of its time.
Speaker 1: And then HDMI came.
Speaker 0: Yep, and HDMI rapidly became what I'm basically at.
Speaker 0: from HDMI onward We are at the basically pure digital signaling.
Speaker 0: These are just digital cables.
Speaker 0: It doesn't really matter.
Speaker 1: once we went into the HD realm It's like okay this that's the end of all those other things, right?
Speaker 1: Everyone has an LCD panel, right?
Speaker 1: That's HD at least.
Speaker 1: so we can all use HDMI now, right?
Speaker 0: Well, so there are two.
Speaker 0: there's HDMI and DisplayPort are basically the two right now and most video card report is really only used by computers.
Speaker 0: Yep, so most computer like we just got a 3080 a TI right?
Speaker 0: It's got three display ports and one.
Speaker 0: That's kind of the default right now.
Speaker 1: Yep, that's just about any video cards gonna have that Yeah days.
Speaker 1: and at this point if you get if you get you know The thing is DisplayPort right is there even if you don't realize it's there at the start of the show.
Speaker 1: We talked about USB C. Yeah Like ah, that's.
Speaker 1: but USB C is just display port only on a different to a degree display port.
Speaker 0: It's just USB C because these.
Speaker 0: this is where we have completely disentangled the physical spec of the cable from what the fuck you're doing over it.
Speaker 0: and DisplayPort and USB C as cables can both do basically anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much DisplayPort has the added bonus of it can ruin your computer.
Speaker 1: Well only in that one weird case that's largely solved now.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah largely solved because devices had to protect themselves from the fact that most of the cables are still broken to this day.
Speaker 0: I encountered a broken cable recently.
Speaker 0: They're out there still Sure.
Speaker 1: Something else is that you know these cables since they can do just about anything, right?
Speaker 1: We're seeing them do more things at once right but much like DVI We're not seeing those things really used thoroughly.
Speaker 1: so like DisplayPort you can daisy chain DisplayPort.
Speaker 1: you can go from your computer to a monitor and then from that monitor to a second monitor with two DisplayPort cables and That's supposed to work, but it only works if everything is super great and it supports things properly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a lot of times it doesn't and it's not you know, it's like come on just make it work people, right?
Speaker 1: You could theoretically put like networking.
Speaker 1: I have HDMI cables that are ultra thick.
Speaker 1: I got rid of it though But I had one that was Ethernet over HDMI.
Speaker 1: so you could theoretically get a monitor or a TV and plug it in to a device and Then that device could provide the TV.
Speaker 1: Let's say it was a smart TV because you were a fool and you were gonna use.
Speaker 1: You could let the smart TV get its internet over the HDMI cable.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: have I ever seen that working?
Speaker 1: The only time that's probably ever worked is in like some commercial setting.
Speaker 1: right where they're they have networked Paddles for displaying things like an airport or some shit like that, you know advertising displays or something.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's ever gonna work in anyone's house.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, I get.
Speaker 1: there are ways I think of sending power over certain HDMI cables.
Speaker 1: I've never seen that work if that exists.
Speaker 1: I think I've seen it.
Speaker 1: I think I've seen it like mentioned but I've never seen it working in person, right?
Speaker 1: But that would be cool because you could have a display with no power cable just one cable the end, that'd be nice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think we'll get there.
Speaker 0: I think we'll see.
Speaker 0: you just plug your computer into your monitor via a USB C cable and everything just works.
Speaker 1: Yep, that'd be good.
Speaker 1: Another table are we gonna see another cable after USB C at any point?
Speaker 0: Yeah, what most of the research right now that is around?
Speaker 0: Doing increasingly complex things over the existing physical cable standards.
Speaker 0: So the physical cables are evolving but also reaching sort of upper limits of what you can do with them without like novel materials.
Speaker 0: And it's the signaling standards and the specifications of how they're used.
Speaker 0: the auto Negotiation between devices like in the old days if you use USB a there was a way to send video over that and do sorts of nonsense but weak though, yeah.
Speaker 0: also Cables like look think about old computer cables even old video cables Really easy to break stuff and cause problems or things just don't work.
Speaker 0: or the negotiation you plug a newer device into an older device The auto negotiation fails and everything breaks.
Speaker 0: we're getting to the point to where any modern device can just plug USB C cable into any other modern device and They'll figure out what they can even do with each other if I plug.
Speaker 1: I've been reading a lot of articles from people who are Like, you know really sticklers for specifications Laining.
Speaker 1: they're all complaining like ah USB C is a mess.
Speaker 1: Everything's wrong.
Speaker 0: It's less of a mess than DisplayPort or HDMI, right?
Speaker 1: They're like.
Speaker 1: this doesn't work with that.
Speaker 1: You know the.
Speaker 1: the Mac says it supports this but it doesn't right.
Speaker 1: and I'm like and they're showing like these Weird edge cases.
Speaker 0: and I'm like, oh you're trying to do firewire over USB C. who cares about that?
Speaker 0: But you I really don't right.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: let's talk about real practical examples, right?
Speaker 1: Here's a real practical example.
Speaker 1: I can go and buy a generic USB C device that on one end has USB C a cable and on the other end has an HDMI output and an SD card reader and I can plug that one generic device into a MacBook, right my PC and the bottom of a Nintendo switch.
Speaker 1: and on all three of those devices And a phone and a phone an Android phone or an iPad also right five different devices that have USB C holes.
Speaker 1: I can plug that same generic thing into all five devices and in all five of them The HDMI port will work and the SD card reader will work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: so Practically speaking in terms of you know an everyday person, right?
Speaker 1: I don't give a shit if there's like these Spec problems that some people are complaining about where this device doesn't work with that one or that person.
Speaker 0: people like that How you get all as the OTG.
Speaker 0: rest in peace, right?
Speaker 1: It's like the it.
Speaker 1: it works enough that it's a miracle for people's lives that they could buy one Adapter and use it with every fucking thing they own and don't have to buy a second one and it works Properly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so that's what counts.
Speaker 1: Rest in peace.
Speaker 1: RF cable.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek knives are Heidi McNichol Alan Joyce.
Speaker 0: I think it's you try to listen to braid a bunch of people who don't want me to say their names.
Speaker 0: Chris the dog Chris Rhymer Clinton Walton Dex Finn help computer because shy 85 Rebecca done review.
Speaker 0: review.
Speaker 0: mad bull 34 cowards Sam Erickson sure about her.
Speaker 0: Taylor Braun.
Speaker 0: The next station is Queen Queen station and like 60 people who do not want me to say their names Yeah, we're back.
Speaker 0: That was a pretty long episode.
Speaker 0: I hope you enjoyed it.
Speaker 0: We're gonna review that one-off by the mangaka of chainsaw man on Wednesday.
Speaker 0: We'll see what we do next week.
Speaker 0: And for now I leave you simply with.