Speaker 0: It's Tuesday, December 13th, 2022.
Speaker 0: I'm Rym.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, we are talking about playing on teams.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So, I'm pretty sure I told the story on the show where that old car that we have, like, basically had a problem and overheated and low-key exploded on the GWB at midnight, coming home from a family thing on Thanksgiving.
Speaker 0: So, the saga has ended.
Speaker 0: Today, I picked the car up from the garage where I normally keep it to give it to a guy who is going to tow it away.
Speaker 0: They're going to figure out how much they can scrap it for, and it's going to be a charitable donation.
Speaker 0: I did not donate it to the evil Cars for Kids.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, you know, what they're doing is they give the money to, you know, to run, like, their Hasidic schools in the Jewish neighborhood, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, it's like, oh, it's for kids.
Speaker 1: And it's like, you know, but they didn't say which kids or what.
Speaker 1: It's not like, it's like, they're just like, for kids, which kids?
Speaker 1: Kids in a hospital, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, they're funding their schools, right?
Speaker 1: And it's like, okay, you know, if it was like, you know, a Catholic school, right?
Speaker 1: You know, it's like, but Catholic schools go around and say, hey, give money to the Catholic school.
Speaker 0: They're at least up front about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And it's like, and the problem is, it's like, okay, you have a religious school, right?
Speaker 1: You know, whether I believe in your religion or not, right?
Speaker 0: I wouldn't even be that opposed, you know, as much of an angry atheist as I am.
Speaker 0: I am not even opposed to that.
Speaker 0: It's specifically that is for schools primarily in the areas that are basically under apartheid rule in Palestine.
Speaker 1: No, it's for schools in Brooklyn.
Speaker 0: No, I just read a thing on this.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the point is, is that, A, there's the deception, right?
Speaker 1: But the real problem is that those schools, right?
Speaker 1: Unlike, you know, not trying to give credit to Catholic schools here because they don't deserve it.
Speaker 1: They got a lot of problems.
Speaker 1: But those schools basically do not teach the children properly, right?
Speaker 0: Oh, right.
Speaker 0: There was that New York State huge report that just came out talking about the city.
Speaker 1: Maybe it just came out.
Speaker 1: This has been going on for decades.
Speaker 0: No, but there was a giant investigative journalism thing that dropped this year.
Speaker 1: The investigative journalism has been ongoing.
Speaker 1: It's not like something that just happened.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, this was not unknown, but this report was huge.
Speaker 0: It was like 30 pages long and had all this data.
Speaker 1: There's been many, it's just one in a line of many things, right?
Speaker 1: But the point is, is that basically they run these schools and they don't teach, you know, math, English, you know, the required subjects, right?
Speaker 1: They'll just, there have been videos showing like schools, like just cheating, like to make sure the kids pass these tests.
Speaker 1: Kids who were not, you know, because basically they only teach the kids what they want to teach them.
Speaker 1: Imagine if someone went to Catholic school and they only had religious class and didn't have a math class at all.
Speaker 0: In fact, you know, as an elementary school, I went to a Catholic school and the math classes were better than the public schools.
Speaker 0: Basically everything was better except, and it's sad, but I hate to say this, the science classes were actually religiously bullshit, right?
Speaker 1: But the point, you know, there's a state laws that say, you know, federal laws even, right?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't know what the laws are specifically, but there is a legal standard of you.
Speaker 1: No matter if you're going to have a home school, a private school, whatever, you have to teach these things to this level, right?
Speaker 1: There are these standardized tests and the, you know, overall the, you know, sure.
Speaker 1: Some kids might fail, some kids might get an A, but it's like if everyone fails, clearly the school is responsible.
Speaker 1: They didn't teach it, right?
Speaker 1: So these, some of these schools, there are yeshiva schools that are teaching properly, right?
Speaker 1: But then there are some that are not and they're, you know, and the cars for kids money funds those schools to raise the children of very religious Jews in a way that is not legal, but they get away with it due to politics, but the pressure has been mounting and continues to mount, but still has not cracked.
Speaker 0: The most fascinating thing that came out of that big investigative journalism thing was the test scores.
Speaker 0: The girls' schools actually have way better test scores in secular subjects than the boys' schools.
Speaker 1: Because the girls aren't given the religious education.
Speaker 0: So where I donated the car was actually the New York, WNYC, like the New York City radio station.
Speaker 0: They have a more generic, we'll take a car and deal with it charity.
Speaker 0: But the funniest thing is I donated it and they were shocked that it moves, that it drives, that it has an engine.
Speaker 0: They were like, this might be the best car anyone's ever donated to us.
Speaker 0: They were really funny about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I imagine most people donate a car, donating cars that don't move, right?
Speaker 0: While this car moves, for those of you who know cars, the rear seal is blown out.
Speaker 0: The car has no oil in it.
Speaker 0: I have driven it like five times with no oil in it.
Speaker 0: It still goes.
Speaker 0: It feels like it's fine if you don't know there's no oil in it.
Speaker 1: Why didn't you just buy an oil at the gas station and just pour it in?
Speaker 0: Because it would spurt right back out.
Speaker 0: The rear seal is blown because it overheated catastrophically.
Speaker 0: I'm real lucky it didn't catch fire.
Speaker 1: But the point is, even if it comes back out, it'll at least lubricate the insides a little.
Speaker 1: It's not like all of it would just fall out the bottom, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, there is residual oil in the oil pan and in the engine itself, but the dipstick will show zero.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's going to happen.
Speaker 0: But it doesn't matter because they took it.
Speaker 0: But the opening bit, the part that was interesting is the tow.
Speaker 0: truck driver was super cool.
Speaker 0: He comes over.
Speaker 0: I drove the car to a place that would be easy for him to get it and he was very appreciative of that.
Speaker 0: Because if you don't live in New York City, like you imagine a tow truck and you think, yeah, it could just pick up a car.
Speaker 0: New York City does not have a lot of places a tow truck can maneuver, especially like outside of big roads, like where the car is normally parked.
Speaker 0: I don't think a tow truck could even get in there easily.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but despite that fact, right, you know, trying to tow one car in a crowded, tight place with a giant tow truck, right?
Speaker 1: But whenever New York wants to tow, right, it's like, oh, a marathon's coming through.
Speaker 1: We're going to tow every car in the street.
Speaker 1: Oh, we're going to pave this road.
Speaker 0: Suddenly those cars disappear faster than you can imagine.
Speaker 0: It's like magic.
Speaker 1: Somehow they managed to make that happen.
Speaker 1: When they really want to make it happen.
Speaker 1: Oh, parade.
Speaker 1: Got to tow all the cars.
Speaker 1: Guess what?
Speaker 1: Overnight, every single car will be gone, right?
Speaker 1: So when they want to tow, the city can tow, right?
Speaker 1: And I'm like, just deploy that towing power all the time, right?
Speaker 1: Double parked, tow, right?
Speaker 1: Beat up car that's not starting, tow.
Speaker 0: The car that was stuck at an angle outside your apartment for several days.
Speaker 1: For almost a week?
Speaker 1: Tow.
Speaker 1: I think it did get towed eventually, but it's like, they should be, the aggression with which the energy they put into towing for a parade is the energy they should put into towing on a non-stop basis, right?
Speaker 0: But the guy was just really appreciative that I put the car somewhere easy so he didn't have to get out.
Speaker 0: What he said was the weird stuff, to like get it out of a garage or something.
Speaker 0: But then we were talking, I kind of explained what happened.
Speaker 0: We were just hanging out a little bit.
Speaker 0: And, you know, I almost broke down on the GWB like during heavy traffic.
Speaker 0: And the guy was basically like, whoa.
Speaker 0: And what he told me was if you had actually broken down, one, it would have been like a $700 tow truck job to get your car off of that bridge.
Speaker 0: And two, they probably would have ruined the car even more because if you break down on one of the New York City bridges, they don't just send a normal tow truck.
Speaker 0: They want to get that thing out of there.
Speaker 0: They basically push it off the bridge with something that kind of looks like a bulldozer and often damage the car in the process.
Speaker 0: And that's on you.
Speaker 0: They do not care.
Speaker 1: So if you have a Ferrari and it breaks down on the bridge...
Speaker 0: You're in trouble.
Speaker 0: Granted, if you're the kind of person who has a Ferrari and also maintains that Ferrari to such a poor degree that it breaks down in the like 45 minutes to 3 hours that you are on the George Washington Bridge, that's on you.
Speaker 1: At least me, it's a shitty... The point is I've seen very expensive cars on New York City bridges and tunnels.
Speaker 0: Yet somehow my car that spewed all of its oil out over the span of a couple of minutes and overheated catastrophically, somehow I was able to keep driving it to get over the bridge and ditch it in the Bronx and deal with it the next day.
Speaker 1: That reminds me, I learned a new slang term-ish, right?
Speaker 1: The slang term is B&T, meaning bridge and tunnel.
Speaker 1: And basically, to use it in a sentence, you might say, "Ah, there's a lot of B&T in this restaurant right now," right?
Speaker 0: I've heard bridge and tunnel.
Speaker 0: I've never heard it shortened to B&T.
Speaker 0: It's the people who come into the city on bridges and through tunnels.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: When you say B&T, you're talking about like North Jersey people as a group, right?
Speaker 1: So those people, as a collective, you would refer to them as B&T.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, if you take a subway that connects to The Path in Manhattan on a Thursday or Friday night, the people on that train are almost exclusively those people, mostly drunk.
Speaker 0: Alright, it's gaming day and the gaming news.
Speaker 0: That Dwarf Fortress, the one with graphics, came out.
Speaker 0: It's on Steam.
Speaker 0: It did.
Speaker 1: We waited.
Speaker 1: We waited a long time.
Speaker 1: And finally, after 20 years, Dwarf Fortress, that isn't ASCII text.
Speaker 1: I mean, there have been mods and hacks and things, but the official Dwarf Fortress that isn't ASCII text, it has graphics and you can buy it on Steam for 20, 30 bucks, something like that, 30 bucks.
Speaker 0: I'm buying it.
Speaker 0: I don't even know how much I'll play it, but I gotta say...
Speaker 1: It's legally available.
Speaker 1: If you missed all the news stories, if you look in the Steam reviews, you know, a lot of people are like, you know, basically people who love Dwarf Fortress were like, you know, instant, just like five-star, right, reviews, a hundred thumbs up.
Speaker 0: Oh god, I just imagine, imagine if you don't know the deal about Dwarf Fortress and you see this on Steam and you just buy it and try to play it.
Speaker 1: Somebody made a comment in the reviews and the comment became semi-famous.
Speaker 1: This person making the comment clearly knew about Dwarf Fortress because they're like, "Hey, why does this game have so many just instant thumbs up?
Speaker 1: It's been out for like five
Speaker 1: minutes.".
Speaker 1: People just waiting 30 years or 20 years to pay $30.
Speaker 0: Oh, I saw that thread.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and so their replies were just like,
Speaker 1: "Yes.".
Speaker 1: People have been playing this game for free.
Speaker 1: They love the shit out of it and they waited and waited and waited.
Speaker 1: It's like, all right, now you could pay money for the thing that you've been able to get for free.
Speaker 1: only it has graphics.
Speaker 0: I don't think it has a lot of other quality of life improvements.
Speaker 1: It has a lot of the user interface improvements I played at the beginning of a fortress and as a tutorial and there is significant quality of life improvements in terms of user interface.
Speaker 1: It's like, you don't do anything different in terms of what you have to do, the effort required to play Dwarf Fortress, but I guess figuring out user interface parts is significantly less difficult.
Speaker 0: Which is good.
Speaker 0: You've got Apocalypse and Doctor Doom are both coming at you and Apocalypse is busy now, so you only have to fight Doctor Doom to play this game.
Speaker 1: But one of the people did the math and they're like, "Well, it sold about this many copies at 30 bucks each,".
Speaker 1: but they had to share the money with the publisher.
Speaker 1: It's a good publisher, by the way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think the people who also publish Boyfriend Dungeon, it's a good publisher.
Speaker 1: But anyway, and they're like, "Yeah, I guess they probably brought in like six million dollars-ish,".
Speaker 1: but they had to split it and Steam took a cut, we know what that is, but we don't know what the split is between the Dwarf Fortress guys and Kitfox.
Speaker 0: Never mind, Dwarf Fortress, we discovered it in like 2006, 2007?
Speaker 0: We interviewed Tarn Adams on Geek Nights in 2008?
Speaker 1: The point is people are like, "Whoa, millionaires now,".
Speaker 1: but Tarn Adams was basically like, "Yeah, I've probably got some millions now, but we've been working on this 20 years,".
Speaker 1: so it's like basically if I had a tech job, a normal tech salary for 20 years, and then got paid all at once.
Speaker 0: It's like that scene in The Simpsons where the kids find out how much Seymour Skinner gets paid and they're like, "30,000 dollars a year?
Speaker 0: He's a
Speaker 0: millionaire!".
Speaker 0: So there's an uncredited quote that was making the rounds today.
Speaker 0: that sort of sums up Dwarf Fortress in a really funny way.
Speaker 0: "Dwarf Fortress is good.
Speaker 0: Game of the year.
Speaker 0: Game of the century.
Speaker 0: Love to make a bunch of little guys who slowly and tragically die because they need God to tell them to make their own pants or something, and that God does not even know.
Speaker 0: that's a thing he can
Speaker 0: do.".
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Well, we'll review this in detail after we play it.
Speaker 0: I'm definitely playing it at some point.
Speaker 0: There's the Holiday Geek Nights hiatus coming up before too long.
Speaker 0: In some other news, so in full disclosure, as you know from previous Geek Nights, I own a good, good amount of Activision Blizzard stock.
Speaker 0: This is not investment advice, but just full disclosure, I do own a significant amount of Activision Blizzard stock.
Speaker 1: So if it gets bought, you stand to, uh...
Speaker 0: Break even, 'cause the stock price pretty much got locked in at the price it was when this deal was put in place, and it was gonna be worth it.
Speaker 1: You bought it for less than that.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, I bought...
Speaker 1: Presumably.
Speaker 0: I, despite many ups and downs, made a not-insubstantial amount of money with my investments in Activision Blizzard over the years.
Speaker 0: It has been pretty profitable.
Speaker 0: I will, I have to, I should disclose that because we're talking about a bunch of news, you know, journalism, ethics and all.
Speaker 0: So the FTC now is suing to block Microsoft's acquisition of Activision Blizzard on antitrust grounds.
Speaker 0: And all I have to say, despite being a shareholder...
Speaker 1: Why haven't they, they gotta do this a lot more often.
Speaker 0: Yeah, why, this is what bothers me.
Speaker 0: On one hand...
Speaker 1: Yes, it's like, yes, I agree, this is an antitrust ground, good job.
Speaker 1: You should be starting with NBC, Universal, Comcast, a hundred other companies, whatever the fuck that is.
Speaker 0: This is a pattern.
Speaker 1: Start at the top and then work your way down.
Speaker 1: What are you doing starting in the middle?
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I know why.
Speaker 0: Because at the top, they got lawyers and they own politicians.
Speaker 0: At the bottom...
Speaker 1: Microsoft doesn't have lawyers?
Speaker 0: Come on.
Speaker 0: Compared to the top?
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, also, Microsoft, this acquisition is relatively small in the grand scheme of things for Microsoft.
Speaker 0: It's a bigger deal for Activision Blizzard, frankly.
Speaker 0: But on the bottom end, the low tier, there ain't no money there, nobody cares.
Speaker 0: The middle tier of acquisitions are the sweet spot of not so big.
Speaker 0: someone's gonna like pull rank on a senator with their money, but not so small that literally no one cares.
Speaker 0: So I feel like certain sectors get more antitrust enforcement because it's easier.
Speaker 0: It'll make the right amount of headlines, but it's like the minimum effort to make that headline.
Speaker 0: It's like shooting for the low B at RIT where they didn't have pluses and minuses.
Speaker 0: So I am one.
Speaker 0: I'm hugely in favor of this, even though I do stand to lose money if this goes through, because I really want to see more companies broken up just across the board.
Speaker 0: I don't care if it's a company I like.
Speaker 0: I don't care if it's a game I like or a product I use.
Speaker 0: Too many companies are too big and capital is a threat to humanity.
Speaker 0: But that said, I'm gonna quote from this CNBC article, which is quoting one of the players here, arguing against this specific action.
Speaker 0: Microsoft faces huge challenges in the gaming industry.
Speaker 0: The Xbox console is the third place console behind both the Sony Playstation and the Nintendo Switch.
Speaker 0: Microsoft has "no meaningful presence in the mobile game
Speaker 0: industry.".
Speaker 0: He pointed at Apple and Google, saying that while mobile games are fast-growing and high-revenue segments, those who store operators take a significant portion of those earnings through their own fees on developers.
Speaker 0: And he basically makes an argument that, yeah, you could go after Microsoft, but if this is the threshold, you have to go after 90% of the rest of this industry, too.
Speaker 1: I agree.
Speaker 0: I agree as well.
Speaker 0: Now, I don't think they should give up on blocking this acquisition.
Speaker 0: I always think to that old penny arcade where Bungie is coming out of the burning building and the fireman's like, "Are you
Speaker 0: safe?"
Speaker 0: and Bungie tries to get back in, and the fireman's like, "You can't go back in there.
Speaker 0: It's a death
Speaker 0: trap.".
Speaker 0: But you don't understand, Blizzard's still in there.
Speaker 1: One thing you could say, right, is it might be a clever-- It could-- It's a possibility-- I doubt this.
Speaker 1: Is that a precedent?
Speaker 1: I highly doubt-- Right.
Speaker 1: That basically, by making this case, right, you could set the bar.
Speaker 1: If a judge says that this is antitrust, then it should be-- You can basically go to anything bigger, right?
Speaker 1: You could be like, "The judge said-- That other judge, we went all the way, we finished all the court cases, and they said this was too big, it was anti-trusty, right?
Speaker 1: Therefore, look at-- We're bringing Apple to court.
Speaker 1: They're bigger than that was.
Speaker 1: So therefore, they're also anti-trusty, right?
Speaker 1: It should be-- And hopefully-- And then, I guess, I don't know, those cases should be faster, easier, 'cause you can just keep pointing to the one that you already did.
Speaker 1: that was smaller, right?
Speaker 1: Like, if I went to go to Judge A, and Judge Solomon says, "10 is too big for a baby.
Speaker 1: You gotta cut it in half,".
Speaker 1: and then I go, "Well, that lady's baby's 11 pounds.
Speaker 0: That lady's baby's 12
Speaker 0: pounds.".
Speaker 1: I just show up to Solomon with all the giant babies, right?
Speaker 1: And he's like, "Well, I already said the 10-pound baby was too big, and it had to be cut in half, so I'm either gonna be really the inconsistent King Solomon, or we gotta chop up all the 11, 12-pound babies
Speaker 1: too.".
Speaker 0: And in mythology, King Solomon was definitely not known for being inconsistent.
Speaker 0: But that is actually a way this could go, and that's partly why, even if that is not a strategy, which it may be, like, that may well be a strategy, and why-- I don't think so.
Speaker 1: I think the chances are almost nil.
Speaker 1: It's hard to say, because games-- Gaming is also-- I think they just really love going after Microsoft.
Speaker 0: I would say gaming is a pretty small chunk of any industry they could go after.
Speaker 0: I mean, look at Disney right now.
Speaker 0: Look at entertainment.
Speaker 0: Look at news.
Speaker 0: There are other industries that are so much bigger than gaming, that they alone should probably warrant almost all of the antitrust work.
Speaker 0: But I will take any win right now.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter where any antitrust success is a step in the right direction, so I absolutely applaud this personally, even though I personally stand to lose, possibly, a significant amount of money if this is blocked.
Speaker 1: In related Blizzard news, just tiny note, right?
Speaker 1: The Diablo 4 is coming soon.
Speaker 1: A, I'm not gonna lie, you know, Diablo is not a good game.
Speaker 1: I mean, in some senses, it's a great game.
Speaker 1: In some senses, it's not, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, sometimes, like eating a McDonald's burger, sometimes you just want to click on devils and eventually click on Satan.
Speaker 1: It's a game where you click until Satan dies, right?
Speaker 1: But it's, you know what?
Speaker 1: I enjoy all the other three Diablos, one, two, three.
Speaker 1: I clicked until Satan died, and then I stopped playing, and I was not upset.
Speaker 1: I would click Satan to death again, right?
Speaker 1: And they're coming, and they're like, you know what?
Speaker 1: Would you like to click Satan to death for a fourth time?
Speaker 1: And I'm like, you know what?
Speaker 1: I wouldn't mind, right?
Speaker 1: I would.
Speaker 1: Why not, right?
Speaker 1: Might not run out and do it immediately, but I would.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: But A, there are many reports that they are crunching and mistreating the Diablo Satan makers quite horribly.
Speaker 1: And of course, you know, you've got to consider all the things that have already happened over there, not just with the Microsoft department, but also the, you know, the sexual harassment department, right?
Speaker 1: That sort of started this whole shenanigans.
Speaker 1: And then, you know, the money-grubbing, right?
Speaker 1: Who knows what kind of microtransactions it's going to be, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've already seen a lot of chatter and conversation and reports that the monetization is demeaningly aggressive.
Speaker 1: I'm sure the monetization will be demeaningly aggressive, but I know that me, the kind of person that I am, is that, you know, I'll pay the base price for the game, right?
Speaker 1: And even though I might end the game with, like, shitty-looking equipment, and not- Oh, I play Fortnite.
Speaker 0: I have one skin.
Speaker 0: I bought Overwatch 1.
Speaker 0: Overwatch 2?
Speaker 0: I haven't spent one cent, nor will I ever.
Speaker 1: I'll have, like, no fancy items from the real money auction house.
Speaker 1: I'll have, like, you know, no special anything.
Speaker 0: Marvel's death.
Speaker 0: I'm using the default avatar and the default deck.
Speaker 1: If for some reason the base price of the game does not allow you to click Satan to death, then I won't play.
Speaker 1: I won't play it, right?
Speaker 1: But it's like, I can't imagine that.
Speaker 1: It's like, if you pay the 40, 50, 60, whatever they want to charge, just to get the game, unless it's a free-to-play game, And all bets are off.
Speaker 0: Free-to-play is the biggest red flag there is.
Speaker 1: I have a free-to-play Diablo.
Speaker 1: It's the mobile one, right?
Speaker 1: But they're going to charge 40 to 60 bucks for the game, and then if you pay that and do not pay a dime more, I'm 90% confident that they will let you click until Satan dies and then stop playing, which is what I plan to do.
Speaker 1: Any kind of microtransaction bullshit they put in, cosmetic or pay-to-win, it's a single-player game, so pay-to-win, who cares?
Speaker 1: I'll just win without paying more.
Speaker 1: But I don't know if I will, because they mistreated all the people who made it.
Speaker 1: I really wish the Torchbearer people -- not Torchbearer, Torchlight people -- had not fucked up, and Torchlight 3 was actually something worth playing, and the drama there didn't happen.
Speaker 0: Well, it's tricky, because there are -- no large game studio does not mistreat its workers right now.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But it's like, hey, somebody make -- You just rotate.
Speaker 0: who is getting attention for mistreating and how egregious is the mistreating at any given week.
Speaker 1: Now, there are a lot of action RPGs out there with the loot and everything, but none of them are Diablo-like, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you've got to think, why haven't more people copied?
Speaker 1: -- just literally rip off that formula, don't change a fucking thing, right?
Speaker 1: Just put different skin on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: How many games try to rip off Zelda?
Speaker 0: How many games try to rip off Metroidvania?
Speaker 0: There's a million clones.
Speaker 1: The Metroidvania ones, though, were kind of successful.
Speaker 1: The Zelda ones, that's tarred, because you need so much polish to succeed with that.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 0: There's a reason nobody's ripped off Advance Wars, except maybe one game, because you really can't.
Speaker 1: No, there have been quite a few that have tried.
Speaker 0: None of them are good, except Wargroove.
Speaker 1: Eh, anyway.
Speaker 0: And Wargroove is alright, but it doesn't have the polish of Advance Wars.
Speaker 1: But you could make a Wargroove of Diablo.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you absolutely could, if someone was willing to put that level of effort and polish in.
Speaker 0: In yet more Blizzard news, World of Warcraft, which is extremely popular in China, is going to disappear from China.
Speaker 0: Because Blizzard contracts with NetEase to offer World of Warcraft in China, and these two companies appear to have had a significant falling out, where there is continuing new reporting on the details.
Speaker 0: Like, no one's sure exactly what went down.
Speaker 1: Don't they have an existing contract that they have to abide by?
Speaker 1: Unless the term's expired and it's time to renew, in which case it makes perfect sense.
Speaker 0: Yep,
Speaker 1: but
Speaker 0: some weird statements came out around this, and there's been a lot of updates to the stories, where Weipo obtained some emails from Blizzard's president, who apparently said that there was a mismatch in values, and that there were some direct conflicts that led to them not wanting to work with NetEase in China specifically.
Speaker 0: There's also NetEase.
Speaker 0: actually, while they officially declined to comment on that, they issued some other statement basically saying, there's a quote that's like, "A jerk is the reason we're not doing
Speaker 0: this.".
Speaker 0: They seem to be referring to one individual, who they're calling a jerk, who is responsible for this.
Speaker 0: And this is all with the backdrop of the Chinese government over the last few years, heavily cracking down on gaming across all of China.
Speaker 1: I mean, if China doesn't want World of Warcraft in their country, then they won't have it.
Speaker 1: Except for people who have a VPN and a US account.
Speaker 0: Yep, VPNs are less and less reliable in China over the last year and a half as well.
Speaker 0: So gamers are of course panicking, because a lot of them have highly leveled up characters, who they're afraid will just get deleted, and it's not clear what's going to happen to them.
Speaker 0: Blizzard appears to be trying to give them a path to migrate their characters to non-Chinese servers, so the characters will continue to exist, but it's not clear if the players could play them, and this is sort of an ongoing story, where we're not really sure where it's going to go.
Speaker 0: There was an update right before Geek Nights that I haven't fully read yet.
Speaker 1: See, what I don't understand is that, you know, China's... It's like, they have these, you know, undersea cables connecting them to the actual internet, right?
Speaker 1: And then they have the Great Firewall, whatever.
Speaker 1: You know what you could do, that would save you a lot of money and a lot of work on this Great Firewall, is, you don't want to cut the undersea cables, because obviously your industrial sector still needs access to the real internet, right?
Speaker 1: So, what you would do is you just set up internet service providers that have, you know, the real internet for business, right?
Speaker 1: And you could maybe keep your Great Firewall on that, or, you know, for each individual business that signs up, you sort of do a reverse firewall, where it's like, "Okay, your business needs this real internet thing.
Speaker 1: That's the only thing we're going to let you have access
Speaker 1: to.".
Speaker 0: Notching it into the details, but that is, to a large degree, how a lot of this works.
Speaker 0: There are just places, pops, data centers, and industries that just have access to the real internet.
Speaker 1: All over the regions of China.
Speaker 1: The blocking aspect, right, is you would set, you would go to, let's say, a factory.
Speaker 0: Oh, if you're in those zones, like, you just have the full internet.
Speaker 0: It doesn't even go through the firewall.
Speaker 1: Right, but what I'm saying is what they could, if they really wanted to crack down, right, they could go to each business, figure out what internet, real internet, that business needs, and limit their internet to just that at the ISP level.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because then it's just TLS, so they'll have to man in the middle of it to make sure they can actually look at the content.
Speaker 0: The content is more what they care about than the services.
Speaker 1: You don't have to look at the content.
Speaker 1: You could be like, "Oh, your business needs, like, this one
Speaker 1: website.".
Speaker 1: It's like, right, well, any traffic-- No, historically, what they really do is just arbitrarily block things and just-- But that would not serve any purpose for them.
Speaker 0: That reduces the control they have.
Speaker 0: By being arbitrary and making it hard, it forces businesses to look inward wherever possible, which is probably part of a long-term strategy.
Speaker 1: The point is, what they could then do is for any ISP that's serving not a business that has a reason to access the real internet, like, there just is no physical path to the real internet.
Speaker 1: Those ISPs would be entirely internal to the country.
Speaker 1: You don't need to great firewall the individuals because there is no router that will route them to the US, like, period.
Speaker 0: The great firewall is a little more complex than you're sort of making it out to be.
Speaker 1: No, what I'm saying is, like, that's what, like, you won't need the great firewall if you do what I say of just don't-- people who live at home can't access the United States, period.
Speaker 0: That is largely how the great firewall operates in practice.
Speaker 1: Pretty sure it looks at, like, all the actual, like, it's, like, it looks at all the, you know, the content.
Speaker 0: It's not just the content.
Speaker 0: They also block entire routes, entire networks.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of the physical routing.
Speaker 1: But you won't need to block anything if there is no route at all.
Speaker 1: If there just is no wire connecting to the real internet from someone's house.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: So, you know, lately, if you use TikTok or, like, you look at Google Shorts, there's a particular format of video.
Speaker 0: They're, like, 30 seconds long.
Speaker 0: And they're, like, this very specific kind of life hack that are often extremely simplistic.
Speaker 0: Half the time, they're just wrong.
Speaker 0: But they're out there.
Speaker 1: A lot of the time, they're lies.
Speaker 1: I think a lot of them are lies on purpose.
Speaker 1: To be funny or impressive or to trick people or, you know, just to get clicks.
Speaker 0: Some of them are seeking clicks.
Speaker 0: Some of them are seeking ad revenue.
Speaker 0: Some of them are parodies.
Speaker 0: Some of them are just--.
Speaker 1: They've been around for, they've been around for a long time.
Speaker 1: I think as long as, like, Instagram Stories, I think that's when they really started.
Speaker 0: But they've sort of settled over the last several years into a particular format.
Speaker 0: To the point that they all kind of follow the exact same pattern.
Speaker 0: So my Thing of the Day is I just encountered a 30-second short on YouTube.
Speaker 0: That is a very apt, straight-faced parody of these together about how to remove potatoes from your knives.
Speaker 0: And it is expertly done and hilarious.
Speaker 0: And if you watch this, you never need to watch any other parody of these things.
Speaker 0: And probably you don't need to watch these things.
Speaker 0: Because most of them, at best, will not work and more likely might hurt you.
Speaker 0: But if your potato is stuck on your knife and the shoes aren't doing it, this is how you get a potato off a knife.
Speaker 0: So yeah.
Speaker 1: So usually, if you want to attend, you know, a fancy business conference, right?
Speaker 1: You got to travel and/or pay a bunch of money, right?
Speaker 1: And even if they put their shit online, it costs money, right?
Speaker 1: It's like usually only for the people who bought real tickets can access the whatever, right?
Speaker 1: If there's a live stream, you got to pay for that.
Speaker 1: And usually people pay the large amount of money because, you know, the company pays for it.
Speaker 1: Not the person, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a reason nerd conventions cost like 100 bucks for a badge, but like an industry conference is like $5,000.
Speaker 1: But the space is the same, right?
Speaker 1: So anyway, the Seattle Kraken, the newest NHL hockey team, had a conference called C-Hack, the Seattle Hockey Analytics Conference.
Speaker 1: And they held it like, you know, in their arena, right?
Speaker 1: And they had all kinds of basically people from all across the ice hockey analytics world, right?
Speaker 1: Students, researchers, industry people, right?
Speaker 1: People who work for teams, teams other than Seattle, right?
Speaker 1: You know, the GM, I think, of the Seattle Kraken, all kinds of people, right, talking at this conference.
Speaker 1: It was like eight hours long, like a real, a whole day deal.
Speaker 1: And they just put that shit, it was live on YouTube, just for free for anybody on the official Seattle Kraken YouTube channel.
Speaker 1: Not on some special conference one, not, you know, and the live stream video is just still there, just recorded.
Speaker 1: You can still watch it on YouTube.
Speaker 1: It didn't go anywhere.
Speaker 1: So, you know, even if you're not interested in ice hockey or, you know, it's like, you know, there's so many components here, right?
Speaker 1: The computer aspect, right?
Speaker 1: The hockey aspect, the analytics aspect, the math aspect, so much going on.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of people who might be interested.
Speaker 1: I watched some of the talks there and I learned quite a bit from quite a few of them.
Speaker 1: And yeah, it's just there for free.
Speaker 1: And it's unusual and good.
Speaker 1: More people should be doing shit like this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, Kraken in general, the hockey team has done a good job of leveraging social media and streaming and things as a new franchise.
Speaker 0: And I applaud it.
Speaker 0: Like, what else can you say?
Speaker 0: This is cool.
Speaker 0: So, the thing is that there are conferences that are really big that, despite having tons of attendees, also have huge ticket prices.
Speaker 0: I used to go to trade tech every year in Paris.
Speaker 0: Like, that's why I used to go to Paris.
Speaker 0: So, for some perspective, it's like a three-day conference, so comparable to a PAX.
Speaker 0: The turnstile attendance is 1.2 million.
Speaker 0: And the cheapest regular badge is 4,300 euros.
Speaker 0: And that only gets you onto the main show floor.
Speaker 0: That'd be like an expo hall only pass.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would never, ever go to trade tech on my own dime.
Speaker 0: But if a company's paying for it, maybe I'll go next year.
Speaker 1: It's like GDC costs an arm and a leg unless you get some sort of, you know, in or dollars or whatever.
Speaker 0: GDC I might actually just pay for.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But, I mean, it's still expensive, right?
Speaker 1: And the quality of the content is very good.
Speaker 1: And they were lucky.
Speaker 1: They released some of the talks for free over a long period of time, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, they've also got that package where you can basically buy access to those archives.
Speaker 0: And it's honestly a pretty good deal if you need that content.
Speaker 1: I mean, the quality of the content is astronomical.
Speaker 0: Like DEFCON, I don't ever need to actually go to DEFCON.
Speaker 0: I can watch all the panels from DEFCON.
Speaker 0: That's the only reason I'd be there.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: In the meta moment, the Geek Nights Book Club book, Alif the Unseen.
Speaker 1: I'm making a good progress.
Speaker 1: I think I'm like 30% done here.
Speaker 0: I imagine we'll do this show before the end of January or like early February at the latest.
Speaker 0: I expect a lot of rapid reading during the holiday times.
Speaker 1: I'm rapid reading right now.
Speaker 1: I'm zooming along here.
Speaker 1: We'll see what Alif is up to.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: He's unseen.
Speaker 1: So far, he's very seen.
Speaker 1: So I'm not sure what the unseen part... Everyone can see him.
Speaker 0: Well, do they see...
Speaker 1: If he gets the invisible powers at some point, I don't know what the unseen part is.
Speaker 0: I'd say right now I'm leaning toward "unseen by whom" is one angle I'm thinking about.
Speaker 0: Who is unaware of what the unseen is up to?
Speaker 0: But more importantly, I'm also thinking about are there aspects that are not seen that are the real story that are going to come out later?
Speaker 0: This feels like a book that has multiple levels of allegory rolled into the title itself.
Speaker 0: Never mind the plot.
Speaker 0: This is going to be a good one to talk about.
Speaker 1: The main character is named Alif.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, we were just AdPax Unplugged.
Speaker 0: If you didn't see us there, the room was full.
Speaker 0: A very similar panel we did at PAX Unplugged right before.
Speaker 0: COVID is already on YouTube.
Speaker 0: I posted the slides that were updated from the new one.
Speaker 0: You can just go see them.
Speaker 0: They're just online forever.
Speaker 0: If you didn't fill out the PAX feedback form, please do so.
Speaker 0: PAX was really bugging people to do it.
Speaker 0: They did tell me that apparently people who went to our panel were filling it out in high numbers.
Speaker 0: So good job.
Speaker 0: We will very likely do a panel or two at PAX East.
Speaker 0: We'll very unlikely be at PAX East for all four days.
Speaker 0: I just don't see that happening.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, we'll probably not do a ton of shows in the coming weeks because this is the time when disruptions happen and geek nights will resume like normal at some point in January.
Speaker 0: I don't know what else we need to cover right now in the meta moment.
Speaker 0: Follow me on Mastodon because I ain't using Twitter anymore.
Speaker 1: I'm still setting up a new internet regime and I'm in no particular hurry because... I
Speaker 0: did see really specifically in the last 48 hours I personally hit a critical mass on Mastodon where suddenly dozens of people all followed me just over the last two days with clearly new accounts and for the first time this morning I looked at my Mastodon feed like the actual feed of people I follow and there was a reasonable amount of content in there.
Speaker 0: There's people posting.
Speaker 0: It's not just.
Speaker 0: everyone has the new account and no one's using it yet.
Speaker 0: So we'll see how this goes.
Speaker 1: The approach I think I'm going to take is I'm going to set up... We already talked about this on a Monday show but I'm going to talk about my publishing.
Speaker 1: It has nothing to do with anybody else but me.
Speaker 1: I publish what I want in a way that I want and it has nothing to do with anyone else.
Speaker 1: so I'll just decide that independently.
Speaker 1: And then in terms of intaking I think what I'm going to do is independent of any services or platforms.
Speaker 1: I'm going to write down who and what do I actually need to know about and follow closely and then seek each of those things out individually.
Speaker 0: Funnily enough I made a Google spreadsheet and I've been doing an audit myself.
Speaker 0: I have a list of like 30-ish entities right now where it was like.
Speaker 0: this is a thing I actually read every day and care about.
Speaker 0: And I haven't decided what to do with that yet.
Speaker 1: It matters to my life.
Speaker 1: It's a person I'm close to or a topic that is real important.
Speaker 0: Right now my list is like a handful of feeds, a few specific journalists, like Pope Hat is something that's on that list.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: I'm not listing YouTube channels.
Speaker 0: YouTube's not going anywhere anytime soon but nothing lasts forever.
Speaker 0: Do not trust that YouTube will continue to exist.
Speaker 1: Alright, so.
Speaker 0: Teams!
Speaker 0: Playing games with teams!
Speaker 0: A generic broad topic that is often a launching point into future shows and maybe panels but it's something we've never actually talked about as a topic on Geek Nights except in the context of other conversations.
Speaker 0: And we both realize there's a lot to talk about here.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean the fundamental thing is a team is, right?
Speaker 1: When you combine multiple humans into a single player in the context of a game, right?
Speaker 1: You have a game, maybe it's a three-player game but you got nine people.
Speaker 1: so you have three teams of three, right?
Speaker 1: Most often a team game is gonna be two teams because, you know, any sport, any game of any kind that has more than two, you know, participants, players.
Speaker 0: Two participating entities with agency.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that is not a pure race, like a hundred meter dash or something like that.
Speaker 0: Meaning completely non-interactive.
Speaker 1: It's going to be political.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, imagine American football if somehow there were three teams and they were just all fighting over touchdowns.
Speaker 1: Right, it's like, it becomes a political game.
Speaker 1: So you want to remove politics to become a test of skill, right?
Speaker 1: And you're not a pure race because there's some interaction that's going on between the two parties involved.
Speaker 1: So, but you don't want to just only have two literal human beings.
Speaker 1: So you form two teams of human beings and there you go, right?
Speaker 1: Problem solved.
Speaker 1: Because like one-on-one-- And that's the most common implementation of teams.
Speaker 0: Like one-on-one basketball, one-on-one hockey, those are fine fun things to watch and find fun things to play, but a lot of aspects of those games can't exist.
Speaker 0: There's nobody to pass to.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's just, there's no passing.
Speaker 1: It's like you lost the whole aspect of the game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like imagine, imagine a one-on-one counter-strike.
Speaker 0: It is literally just hide and seek and then who can click on the other person's head first.
Speaker 0: That's the whole game.
Speaker 0: Nothing else matters.
Speaker 0: Which actually would be kind of fun.
Speaker 0: Also, total aside, I just imagined American football, but there's three teams.
Speaker 0: And when you're on offense, you pick which lane you want to fight in.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so as a kid, like as a kid playing team sports and team games, sports are a good angle for this analysis.
Speaker 0: It's interesting because when I was young, there really wasn't real competition.
Speaker 0: Like unless you go to a weird school or your parents are a little bit overzealous, you are not, like when you're six, you're not playing a sport competitively.
Speaker 0: Like your kid brain probably wants to win, but like there are zero stakes and half the kids probably don't even realize they're playing a sport.
Speaker 0: So I remember very distinctively, my school had a thing where at the end of the school year, every year, there was a school-wide tournament across all grades, K through five.
Speaker 0: And the way it worked is every kid was given a color and there were four colors and the entire school was sliced vertically into four teams.
Speaker 0: And we had a day long like outdoor Olympics of team sports.
Speaker 0: And within the field day, yep.
Speaker 0: And within those team sports, you'd rack up points and one of the colors would win.
Speaker 0: And it was entirely arbitrary and random who won in the end.
Speaker 0: But as a kid, I was oddly invested in making my team win in a way that I would not have cared about were it not for that structure of a team that in my kid brain depended on me to do well.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, there's a huge psychology, you know, when you're just on your own competing in some sort of game or even just playing and not competing.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like you're just doing whatever for your own reasons, however you like, and you get.
Speaker 1: the result is entirely on you or mostly entirely on you.
Speaker 1: There could be luck or other factors.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But, you know, you're not beholden to anyone else or anything.
Speaker 1: But once you're on a team.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, well, now there's people that are like depending on you.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: their result depends on what you do and your result depends on what they do to some extent.
Speaker 1: And you'd like you have this now positive like relationship with these other people.
Speaker 1: You want to help.
Speaker 1: you want to help each other out.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like there's no helping in a game when there's no teams.
Speaker 1: It's like there's only hurt, you know, hurting and conquering and defeating as soon as you have teams.
Speaker 1: It's like, yeah, you still have the conquering and the beating of the other, you know, your opponents.
Speaker 1: But you now have brought in the positive emotion of there are other human beings who you are helping, supporting, boosting.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Which does not exist in a non team sport.
Speaker 1: I'll go play non doubles if you go play singles tennis.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, no, no one's boosting you except that you're maybe a fan or something.
Speaker 0: But but another aspect of that field day type competition or kid teams is that they're usually formed randomly.
Speaker 0: So as a result, a randomly formed team is a very different situation from an actively formed team.
Speaker 0: And that is a that is a topic that could probably be an entire goddamn lecture series.
Speaker 1: I was going to say formation of teams could probably be, you know, the different ways to form a team and what that means.
Speaker 1: But it's like that could be a whole episode.
Speaker 0: I remember on the as a kid, you know, you go to gym class in elementary school and a lot of times the way a team is formed is the teacher just randomly splits kids up because they don't want to deal with drama.
Speaker 0: But then you're on the playground.
Speaker 1: Take the two kids who are the best at the sport.
Speaker 1: Everyone knows who they are.
Speaker 1: And they take turns picking kids.
Speaker 1: And then the kids who are the worst feel bad.
Speaker 1: They get picked last.
Speaker 0: That is how it often went on the playground when the teachers weren't around.
Speaker 1: I mean, we had.
Speaker 1: I mean, I when I was kid, teachers would tell us to do it that way.
Speaker 0: Oh, wow.
Speaker 0: I you know, weirdly, I died after elementary school.
Speaker 0: I never took a gym class in school again.
Speaker 0: So I didn't experience that was required.
Speaker 0: Anyway, a band counted as gym.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the point is right.
Speaker 1: That's one way to choose teams.
Speaker 1: But, you know, pro sports.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You have a draft and you have.
Speaker 1: you know, it's labor.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Choosing the teams is like a labor issue.
Speaker 1: You're hiring and firing people.
Speaker 1: You can waive people.
Speaker 1: You can trade people.
Speaker 1: You could force someone to go move their life to a different city.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Or, you know, loan someone from one soccer team in one country to another.
Speaker 1: And like upend this person's life and change who they're playing with.
Speaker 0: Well, that gets to the point where independent of all that team formation now expands the scope of the game.
Speaker 0: The game is not just how did you do in the game?
Speaker 0: The game started when you started forming or messing with the team.
Speaker 0: Just like making a deck and magic is part of the match of magic you play.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You could be a college coach.
Speaker 1: It's like, OK, you can choose any of the eligible players who are students at the school right now.
Speaker 1: Choose the best one.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: And then you have to think about the goal of the team.
Speaker 0: is the goal of the team.
Speaker 0: Like, imagine an intramural or a junior varsity sport or like the gaming club at your school.
Speaker 0: It's not professional.
Speaker 0: It's competitive because you want to have this competitive, fun, test of skill.
Speaker 0: But the stakes are low.
Speaker 0: So as a result, the teams may be formed based on what is the most fun or what helps the members of the team grow the most.
Speaker 0: But a professional sport or a sport or a game where the stakes matter, the formation of the team kind of has to focus on the health of and performance of the team, possibly to the detriment of the members of that team individually.
Speaker 0: It starts to get into a really complex and interesting space when you look at what teams actually mean in the real world.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But yet the way you form the teams can cause a lot of competitive imbalances.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: All sorts of you know, or it can make a lot of good balances.
Speaker 1: You form the teams in a good way.
Speaker 1: But I think one of the things that's exposed by team formation the most are those imbalances.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Because, you know, you might have an individual who might be extremely good at something right on a team and the rest of the team isn't good enough.
Speaker 1: And while that person might be like an all star.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: They never the team never wins.
Speaker 1: Or you could have someone who sucks ass.
Speaker 1: They're not any good, but they're there.
Speaker 1: You need to fill the roster and not everyone on the team is an all star.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So they could play basketball and you have 10 people.
Speaker 1: And five people warm on the bench and they all suck.
Speaker 1: And five people are legendary and they win the championship and they never get injured or tired.
Speaker 1: And the five bench warmers sit and don't do a damn thing.
Speaker 1: And then our NBA champions.
Speaker 1: It's like it happens.
Speaker 1: There are people who are NBA champions who haven't really did not.
Speaker 1: Well, I literally if I had been paid to sit in their seat, I would be an NBA champion.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Because the five people who did most of the playing right were, you know, carried everything.
Speaker 1: It's like and that's, you know, is that fair?
Speaker 1: Is that right?
Speaker 1: Is a lot of questions.
Speaker 1: But it's like we just sort of look at.
Speaker 0: look at online video games.
Speaker 0: like I play a lot of team Fortnite.
Speaker 0: I play a lot of team Overwatch.
Speaker 0: Most of my Overwatch playing these days is with randos.
Speaker 0: It's me and five other random team.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So winning or losing, like I'll play my best and I'll try hard.
Speaker 0: Sometimes the DPS just garbage, like nothing you can do.
Speaker 0: Like you're going to lose them.
Speaker 1: Sometimes people say sometimes people complain that they lost because their team sucks and they're salty.
Speaker 1: And it's like, but sometimes that's true.
Speaker 1: You did lose because your team suck.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like, how can you tell the salt from the truth?
Speaker 0: And you know, this is known because if you look at what Overwatch, I know I'm sure other games do this, too.
Speaker 0: But Overwatch does it very directly.
Speaker 0: If you come into the matchmaking queue in a group, it tries to match you against teams that have groups of the same size.
Speaker 0: So if I have a group of three and they're going to put two randos in my team, it tries to put me against another team that has a group of three and two randos.
Speaker 0: Because team cohesion and team structure and the existence of a team versus a team that existed versus a team that was instantiated has a huge impact on how well the game will go.
Speaker 0: Five people who talk a little bit in voice chat are almost definitely going to beat five people who do not talk in voice chat if skill is similar.
Speaker 0: I've played on teams over the years, but they're in a lot of different contexts.
Speaker 0: I played off and on in Quake 1 days on some CTF teams that would meet and practice and play arranged matches.
Speaker 0: And honestly, it was super fun and I missed that.
Speaker 0: That is a height of game playing that I would seek out if I had more free time.
Speaker 0: A lot more than I do now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well there's two other types of teams I want to discuss.
Speaker 1: So the first type of team is you see this happen a lot at family board game night where it's like, you know, the game doesn't support enough players and it's like, oh, we'll be on a team, right?
Speaker 1: Or, you know, you play...
Speaker 0: That's code four, alright little buddy, we can pretend that you're participating most of the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or you have a co-op game, right?
Speaker 1: And presumably you're playing Hanabi, right?
Speaker 1: But I guess Hanabi is a real team game, but Pandemic kind of mostly isn't, right?
Speaker 1: Sort of.
Speaker 1: And it ends up being a situation where... It's PVE.
Speaker 0: It's Team PVE.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: What's actually happening is you're playing Solitaire, right?
Speaker 1: And even though you have a team, not everyone is contributing, right?
Speaker 1: If you play soccer, right?
Speaker 1: You have 11 people out there.
Speaker 1: Someone might just stand still and not do anything.
Speaker 1: I guess that's possible, right?
Speaker 1: But the point is everyone is contributing.
Speaker 1: If someone just stood there, that would detriment your whole team, right?
Speaker 1: In order to win, you need all of the 11 people to contribute the effort, right?
Speaker 1: One person can't do it all alone against 11, right?
Speaker 1: Assuming it's not like a superstar against children or something like that, right?
Speaker 1: That doesn't count.
Speaker 0: Now imagine a board game, like chess as an example.
Speaker 0: If you and I are playing chess and I just said, hey, Joey Jojo, be on my team, we'll play together.
Speaker 0: Well, now, one of us, either me or Joey Jojo, is better at chess, and that's probably the only person who matters in that game now.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: If me and Rim join, you know, what's the dude's name, Max, whatever, the legendary, the guy who wins all the chess?
Speaker 0: Matt Carl...
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever, uh...
Speaker 0: Magnus Carlsen?
Speaker 1: Yes, not Max, Magnus, yes.
Speaker 1: Right, so if me and Rim join Magnus' team, his team is the same as it was before, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, we're contributing nothing, absolutely nothing to that team, and we can't contribute anything to that team.
Speaker 1: It's basically not a team.
Speaker 1: We'd be lying to yourselves if you said that that was a team, you're an individual.
Speaker 1: So that, it's like, that's the same thing as when you're like, okay, we'll be a team and play Monopoly, we'll both be the top hat.
Speaker 1: It's like, no, you're not.
Speaker 1: One person knows how to play Monopoly better than the other person.
Speaker 1: If you let a child actually do physically move the hat, it's like, that's nice, right?
Speaker 1: The kid will learn how to count, but the kid is not on the team.
Speaker 0: One could argue, in a more complex game that's still structured like that, you could divide up duties that not one player... Imagine a train game where one person calculates and thinks about stock rounds and the other person runs the trains because one of them's good at one and one of them's good at the other.
Speaker 0: I could see some edge cases, but they're so rare and so contrived that I don't think they matter in any real conversation.
Speaker 0: Unless a game is so complex that it's already getting to the point to where multiple people forming a team could do it better objectively.
Speaker 0: Like, four people playing American football against three people are probably just gonna do better.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So, the other kind of team is basically a team where you're not actually on the team together, right?
Speaker 1: You're just sort of cooperating and working together, right?
Speaker 1: So, a good example might be like a boxer, right?
Speaker 1: Boxing is an individual sport, right?
Speaker 1: Or a golf.
Speaker 0: Purely individual sport when you're a golfer.
Speaker 0: By a team of people.
Speaker 0: Look at a hockey team!
Speaker 0: The equipment manager, the coach, the assistant coach, the goalie coach, board games.
Speaker 0: You could imagine a competitive board game team having the strategy coach separate from the drilling coach.
Speaker 1: Well, but it might not just be the coach.
Speaker 1: It might be that you have a boxing gym or a golfing club and there's the people that you golf with, right?
Speaker 1: And even though you're all individually golfing, no one hits your ball for you, right?
Speaker 1: But all four of you are driving the golf cart around individually golfing together, talking about golf together, watching each other, giving each other's tips, right?
Speaker 1: When it comes time for a golf tournament, you all enter individually.
Speaker 1: But you might have some camaraderie with each other, right?
Speaker 1: And be happy if the other people win because those are your people who you golf with.
Speaker 0: That is actually specifically the plot of Queen's Gambit, which is a really good show and you'd probably like it.
Speaker 0: It's about board games, basically.
Speaker 1: People who play chess together, but they're individual.
Speaker 0: It's about a person who becomes a chess master and joins the world of professional chess.
Speaker 0: And I guess low-key spoilers, over the course of it realizes that despite being a genius at chess, she will do better if she talks to other humans about chess instead of just being by herself.
Speaker 0: Spoilers.
Speaker 0: Don't say.
Speaker 0: Also drug abuse and other things going on, but it's a good show.
Speaker 1: Well, don't do that.
Speaker 1: That's bad.
Speaker 1: But, you know, the point is it's a kind of team, but like the game itself doesn't care about that kind of team, but the humans care about that kind of team a lot, right?
Speaker 1: It can make a huge difference from the human perspective to play individual games with some sort of team-like structure.
Speaker 0: Well, also you'll get situations that blend that where you practice and scrimmage as a team or you play games as a team.
Speaker 0: But then when there's a competition, a subset of your team goes to play as a team in the competition.
Speaker 0: In high school, Quiz Bowl was like that.
Speaker 0: We had like 15 people in the varsity team and they would choose usually with an internal tournament within the team that practice together.
Speaker 0: We do many tournaments to decide who represented us on the five person team at the regional tournament.
Speaker 1: This does remind me of a somewhat recent ish thing of the day where there was the the jigsaw puzzle turn.
Speaker 1: And you could see that some people went to the jigsaw puzzle tournament as a team, like all wearing the same T-shirts coming from the same country.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But there were multiple different rounds and events.
Speaker 1: There were individual events, two player events, two puzzle events, the two people events and a four people event.
Speaker 1: And some people teamed up, you know, they formed different teams for those different events, like four people went.
Speaker 1: They all competed individually in the individual round.
Speaker 1: They formed two teams of two and in the dual and the doubles round.
Speaker 1: And then they they combined for a team of four and the four people round.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So they sort of were having every different kind of team.
Speaker 1: All in one, you know, set of tournaments at one event.
Speaker 1: Mm hmm.
Speaker 0: I got to say in general, because obviously there's a I think we've already come up with like four episodes of Geek Nights and at least one panel out of this conversation so far.
Speaker 0: But I got to say, the times I have played on competitive teams in any domain, like, you know, varsity things in high school, the handful of proto esports teams I played on for small amounts of time.
Speaker 0: I've loved it.
Speaker 0: It's fun.
Speaker 0: It just takes a lot of investment.
Speaker 0: I feel like I should, you know, fuck it.
Speaker 0: I'm going to form an Overwatch team.
Speaker 0: Who's in?
Speaker 0: Geek Nights listener, join me.
Speaker 0: We can be bronzed here together.
Speaker 1: I think the biggest problem, the biggest thing that hurts a team is when people on the team aren't aligned in their goals and attitudes.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's one thing when in a game that's competitive, not all the players want the same thing.
Speaker 0: Some people are trying hard, some people aren't trying hard.
Speaker 0: But if you're on a team and for like an Overwatch team and four of the players practice and try to get better and like show up and play regularly and the fifth player is flaky and doesn't actually care that much if they win.
Speaker 0: That's almost worse.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You could imagine a high school sports team, right?
Speaker 1: And one kid is like, he really wants to get noticed by scouts and get like a college scholarship because he's right.
Speaker 1: And then another kid is just doing this for fun.
Speaker 1: They don't care.
Speaker 1: Another kid, their parents made him do it.
Speaker 1: Another kid, right?
Speaker 1: It's like there could be so many different motivations and reasons and attitudes of the different players on the team.
Speaker 1: And if they can't align, there could be lots of drama and it will be a negative team experience.
Speaker 1: This is why I like.
Speaker 1: This can happen in professional teams too, right?
Speaker 1: You can have.
Speaker 1: one person is an old player who's retiring and just wants to finish out their contract right year, you know, and then retire.
Speaker 1: And then they just want to not get hurt.
Speaker 1: Another player is a young player.
Speaker 1: They want to, you know, they're.
Speaker 1: another player is a, uh, they're in their free agent year.
Speaker 1: They're playing really hard.
Speaker 1: They want to get a, you know, get a big deal next year to get paid.
Speaker 1: Another person just got their contract.
Speaker 1: They're getting paid.
Speaker 1: They don't give a shit anymore because they don't actually, for some reason they're not competitive.
Speaker 1: They don't care about winning.
Speaker 1: They just care about money.
Speaker 1: Someone else actually does care about winning.
Speaker 1: They want to win, but the team doesn't care about winning.
Speaker 1: They just care about, there could be conflicts there as well.
Speaker 1: Just because it's a professional type organization doesn't mean everyone's going to be in alignment.
Speaker 0: And in gaming, like this is something I really applaud.
Speaker 0: And we've seen this in a lot of online video games already.
Speaker 0: They're starting, they increasingly sort players by what they want out of the game or what they're trying to do rather than just sorting them based on skill.
Speaker 0: Like the difference between like, instead of calling it competitive and casual, you have, you have to click, I'm a tryhard versus I just want to have fun.
Speaker 0: And you play with different groups of people.
Speaker 0: At least the people who say they want to be tryhards will be grouped together separately from the people who say they don't want to try that hard.
Speaker 0: They want to have fun.
Speaker 0: Now, self-reporting, obviously this isn't perfect, but we're seeing this more and more.
Speaker 0: Fortnite does this very well.
Speaker 0: All the different modes in Fortnite have very clearly different motivations for the players.
Speaker 0: And it keeps teams from forming among randos who are going to do radically different things in the course of the game to their team's detriment.
Speaker 1: So yeah, there's a lot of stuff going on with teams.
Speaker 1: You could probably have a whole, you know, not just, you know, several panels, but like a whole podcast that's like team dynamics, the pod.
Speaker 1: I bet there's people who probably just study this as their whole life.
Speaker 1: There's experts on teams, right?
Speaker 1: Not just, you know, game teams, like teams at work, jobs, and, you know, just human cooperation just as a subject matter, right?
Speaker 1: So, it's particularly noteworthy for games.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And the Patreon Patrons for this particular episode of Geek Nights are... Alan Joyce, Linki G, Dreidel, Lily Turner, Chris Hadad, Chris Reimer, Clinton Walton, Dex Finn, Joel Hayes, Rebecca Dunn, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Hurl.
Speaker 0: Stop all the downloading and many, many people who wisely give us just one dollar.
Speaker 0: Holidays are coming up.
Speaker 0: As you know, Geek Nights goes on unexpected hiatus pretty regularly this time of year.
Speaker 0: But I don't have any work.
Speaker 0: travel until January, February.
Speaker 0: So we'll see.
Speaker 0: We'll probably do a show on Thursday.
Speaker 0: I expect we'll do shows next week and we'll see what happens.
Speaker 0: But for now, join my Overwatch team and I simply leave you with...
Speaker 1: Ladies and gentlemen, make some noise for the richest man in the world.
Speaker 0: Cheers and boos, I say.
Speaker 0: Smithers, are they booing?
Speaker 0: No, they're saying boo-erns.
Speaker 1: Boo-erns.
Speaker 0: Are you saying boo or boo-erns?
Speaker 1: I was saying boo-erns.