Speaker 1: It's Thursday, January 20th, 2022.
Speaker 1: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight we are talking about greeting cards.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So I am continuing my odyssey and I've turned this into an actual challenge.
Speaker 1: My goal now, like what am I just low-key goals in my life?
Speaker 1: Lower priority than Genji because I'm rapidly approaching the finish line.
Speaker 1: I don't think Genji's got much longer to live.
Speaker 1: He's uh, anyway.
Speaker 1: So, uh, I'm trying now.
Speaker 1: My goal is to beat every single song in DDR on every difficulty, nine feet or under, not like max 300 legend of max.
Speaker 1: Like, cause that did, that shit didn't even exist until like six.
Speaker 0: So basically you said a line, you said, this is the difficulty of DDR song that I'm capable of beating and I'm going to beat every song that's that level or easier.
Speaker 1: So it's a little more than that because.
Speaker 0: That's like saying I can lift a hundred pounds.
Speaker 0: I'm going to lift every rock on earth that weighs less than a hundred.
Speaker 1: Actually, you know why I picked?
Speaker 1: I actually did not pick that line for that reason because as of now, there are several songs I cannot pass following my rule.
Speaker 0: And you set the bar a little bit higher to level up.
Speaker 1: And in fact, uh, before recently, most of the songs that I've passed in this challenge, I passed for the first time in the last two or three weeks.
Speaker 1: And it was never able to pass in my life up till this point.
Speaker 0: Is that because you had never done them before in your life?
Speaker 1: Some of them I'd never done before.
Speaker 1: Some of them I had tried to do.
Speaker 0: I could do a song on basic and be like, wow, I've never been able to beat that before.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, I'm only talking about nine footers.
Speaker 1: Most of the nine footers I have passed in my life, I have passed for the first time in the last month.
Speaker 1: The majority of them, in fact.
Speaker 1: But the reason I chose nine feet is actually a reason you would appreciate, uh, up until eighth mix DDR dance, dance revolution for you kids who've never heard of this, has a foot rating from one to nine.
Speaker 1: And nine was the maximum difficulty.
Speaker 1: Like when we were playing DDR at RIT, Scott and I got to the point we could do seven footers like reliably, like, like no chance of failure.
Speaker 1: That's like music.
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 1: that's about the level we were at.
Speaker 1: Eight footers were the hard songs and nine footers were like the Orion dot 78 bullshit.
Speaker 1: I could barely pass most nine footers that I could even pass back then.
Speaker 1: But I picked nine feet because that was the maximum difficulty of DDR until max 300 appeared in six mix.
Speaker 1: That was the first 10 footer.
Speaker 1: And up until eighth mix, there were only a few 10 footers and 10 footer basically just men.
Speaker 1: These are the weird, special bullshit songs.
Speaker 0: I mean, I always enjoyed that those existed, but I like, I didn't play DDR to play the, you know, I just never interested in like, you know, raising the difficulty level.
Speaker 1: It's like, oh, I never wanted, it was always like a sticker ad.
Speaker 0: If I saw other people trying it, you know, it's like, I played songs and it's like, okay, this song doesn't have enough arrows to even be interesting.
Speaker 0: I'm like going step step, right?
Speaker 1: And then it's silent Hill, the Christmas song basic.
Speaker 0: And I guess, you know, judging by the fourth mix measurement, right?
Speaker 0: The harder trick, easier maniac songs, like a six, seven foot, six, seven, eight is like the sweet spot of like super fun.
Speaker 0: Sweet spot where there's enough arrows that it's interesting.
Speaker 0: It's still challenging, but you're, you're can still dance.
Speaker 0: You're not just sort of like, right.
Speaker 0: You know?
Speaker 0: And it's, you know, it's like, yeah, there were some harder ones that I could do, you know, but it's like, I just, it wasn't fun to do those.
Speaker 0: Cause it became a, you know, not only was it harder, but it was actually a different game at that level, right?
Speaker 0: It wasn't the same.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like, no longer is it about right.
Speaker 0: It's about something different.
Speaker 0: You know, it's not just like straight.
Speaker 1: We would get like that's the seven footer, the same game, just harder.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Like most of how we played DDR was, Hey, let's do this song and have fun and try to show off.
Speaker 1: and Hey, I'm going to try to do a spin like that kind of nonsense.
Speaker 1: But so as of now, I have passed every song on DDR on every difficulty through up to eight feet all the way through the end of seventh mix.
Speaker 1: And I'm halfway through eighth mix.
Speaker 1: Uh, nine feet, uh, I have two nine footers to go in six mix and I currently can not pass either of them.
Speaker 1: Uh, one of them I'm real close to passing.
Speaker 1: It's one of the weird orions.
Speaker 1: Like if I try it one more time, I'll pass it.
Speaker 1: But flash in the night, the fuck that song is weirdly hard for a nine footer.
Speaker 1: Like compared to any other nine footer I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: I haven't heard of that one.
Speaker 1: It's a six mix song.
Speaker 1: You probably only ever saw it at, uh, remember there was a six mix machine at the bowling alley.
Speaker 0: I played six mix a few times because I was the machine, the head of the bowling alley.
Speaker 1: But, uh, the things, I guess the things I've noticed is I have added some techniques now to my repertoire that I never did before.
Speaker 1: Like rocking a foot between heel and toad and Nintendo foot because 40 year old rim cannot mash his foot that fast.
Speaker 1: Like directly.
Speaker 0: I got, I wasn't a fan of arrows that made me do that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I also noticed that I can do seven footers without dancing adjacent, but it's that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: But, uh, yeah, this is actually a super fun thing that's pretty low effort.
Speaker 1: And my goal is just to be able to pass every song that existed in the ecosystem of DDR that existed up until like after eighth mix.
Speaker 1: Like when we really weren't paying attention to DDR anymore.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm spending my time doing a lot of reading because it's cold outside and I don't have to read the tale again anymore.
Speaker 0: So I read and I'm reading all kinds of stuff and I'm reading it way faster.
Speaker 0: It's like, oh, yes, reading words.
Speaker 1: Well, it's not because it's the words were written in the past few decades.
Speaker 1: There's it's like the difference between when we read Emily Wilson's translation of the Odyssey versus the last time before that that I read the Odyssey.
Speaker 1: It is the actual.
Speaker 0: how to say it is difficult to read.
Speaker 0: Well, not the actual Odyssey in Greek.
Speaker 0: No,
Speaker 1: I mean, I know some translation
Speaker 0: who
Speaker 1: have read that thing in Greek and I know a guy at work who can recite it in Greek because that's a thing that a lot of people in the UK just do as part of college is learn enough ancient Greek to read the classics.
Speaker 1: So there's a guy at work who literally can recite the Odyssey in Greek, mostly from memory.
Speaker 0: Uh huh.
Speaker 1: He's still like, pull this out and just do it at a party.
Speaker 1: Like I've seen him do it.
Speaker 0: That's that guy.
Speaker 1: I know that's the Odyssey guy.
Speaker 1: Hey, that's like two steps above the person who you see very, like, very ostentatiously like making the mouth movements of the soliloquies when they're watching Shakespeare to make sure everyone around them knows that they memorized it.
Speaker 0: That's you.
Speaker 1: That is not me.
Speaker 1: I know I know two soliloquies from Shakespeare still.
Speaker 0: That's two more than anyone who's not that guy knows.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's just because I played those parts in high school in like dump ass productions of Hamlet and Macbeth.
Speaker 0: You were in dump had more dump ass productions than anyone who's not that guy.
Speaker 1: That was that you realized that was required in AP English.
Speaker 1: You had to perform in the in the Shakespeare stuff.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Unless you got a note.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I played, I played, I played Laertes once.
Speaker 1: I played, I did.
Speaker 1: I get to get to get to be actual Macbeth once, which was annoying.
Speaker 1: Anyway, got any news?
Speaker 0: Uh, do we have?
Speaker 1: I got a bunch of news.
Speaker 1: Did you not actually come up with the news?
Speaker 1: Do I have to go through all mine in a row?
Speaker 0: Is there anything?
Speaker 1: I don't think you sent me a link?
Speaker 1: I don't think you had a news.
Speaker 0: I think I forgot.
Speaker 1: I ain't stopping the show is about.
Speaker 0: Let's go see what's what's going on.
Speaker 1: Cause I got it.
Speaker 1: I'll start with a few.
Speaker 1: So, uh, this is, this is something that is important, but it's also not something that is like as scientific as some people make it out to be.
Speaker 1: But it's something that I think people should pay attention to.
Speaker 1: Partly because I started to realize just talking about this and poking at it recently because it made the news again, that a lot of younger people sort of lost the context for what this is.
Speaker 1: The thing I'm talking about is the doomsday clock.
Speaker 1: The doomsday clock has existed for a long time and it actually was invented and publicized during the cold war.
Speaker 1: The goal of it, uh, was to have a, a pseudo objective, but mostly qualitative measure, agreed upon by a body of experts.
Speaker 1: that is roughly just an analogy or a arbitrary metric, like a baseline to say, how close is humanity to destroying itself by its own hands?
Speaker 1: Like, are we close to doing this?
Speaker 1: Have we backed away from doing this?
Speaker 1: Like what's a relative measure of the danger of humans to themselves on a global scale?
Speaker 1: Like that's the intent of it.
Speaker 1: And it really existed to highlight the fact that nuclear weapons for the second time in human history, cause I have a point to make here.
Speaker 1: Where, where there was a second time humans made something that we could theoretically destroy our entire society with if we chose to.
Speaker 1: I say second time because fossil fuel and the way we use cars is the first time.
Speaker 1: we just didn't recognize the danger of that at the time.
Speaker 0: And no one recognizes the slow roll.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Like nuclear weapons, uh, the doomsday clock was cool, was less close to destruction of during at any point in the cold war than it is now.
Speaker 1: And it is where it is now primarily due to climate change and the global rise of fascism and the dysfunction of global governments.
Speaker 1: We are so among experts who's basically entire professional identities are around thinking about existential crises to humanity from our own hands have agreed pretty much unilaterally that climate change is a bigger risk to humans than nuclear weapons ever were at any point and likely ever will be.
Speaker 0: That is obvious to people, but also nuclear weapons are still a threat.
Speaker 1: Nuclear weapons are not less of a threat, but we are closer to crisis due to climate change than we are due to nuclear weapons.
Speaker 0: In fact, there could be many, you know, uh, combinations of the two, right?
Speaker 0: You know, some, you know, are the three, right?
Speaker 0: Some, uh, you know, uh, dilapidated government somewhere here that has nuclear weapons and is being, you know, ravaged by climate crisis might end up using them.
Speaker 0: If it's a strong government that is in good shape and isn't facing crisis, I mean, it's less likely to news.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to talk about just because, uh, it's moving rapidly and you should just read the real news about this and we'll talk about it later.
Speaker 1: But, uh, there is a, there is a very significant likelihood there will be war in Europe with Russia and Ukraine in the nearing future.
Speaker 0: I don't know why Russia wants to invade Ukraine so bad.
Speaker 0: Uh, one thing I don't understand.
Speaker 0: Just let it go.
Speaker 1: A light, a light stroll to Wikipedia actually answers that question pretty directly.
Speaker 0: Uh, just let it go.
Speaker 1: But, uh, to agree, you are making an obvious smart point, but, uh, same thing with China and all those islands.
Speaker 0: Let them go.
Speaker 1: Just like what Emily, I talk about politics.
Speaker 1: Like, yeah, everything you're saying is 100% to 100% reasonable objectively.
Speaker 1: Like people aren't reasonable, but the people in the position of making decisions here have different motives and their motives are stupid and evil and wrong.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the funny, you know, it doesn't mean, you know, there's no point in focusing on the, you know, solving the new thing, right?
Speaker 0: Or the climate change thing.
Speaker 1: We need to solve the, some people are real bad, but, uh, you know, so to give you some perspective, because the, the, the clock was kept at 100 seconds to midnight, which is the closest it's ever been to the theoretical destruction of human society by human hands.
Speaker 1: Uh, and it moved there actually pretty recently and it basically, they're keeping it there.
Speaker 1: Uh, the least close to doom it ever was, was during the fall of the Soviet Union.
Speaker 1: And then it rapidly started ticking back up because the states that emerged out of that crisis were basically hyper capitalist, uh, disaster states.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I highly recommend you go read about why the clock was set to 100 seconds to midnight recently.
Speaker 1: And I just point out that one of the people who spoke at the, uh, the ceremony, because this has been going on for 75 years, uh, was Hank Green, the V of the vlogger guy, the YouTube, the YouTube guy, the YouTube guy.
Speaker 1: Uh, he's actually pretty close to this organization.
Speaker 1: Uh, and I'll just, as you know, I, I'm a fan of the, the green brothers.
Speaker 1: I have been pretty much from the beginning.
Speaker 1: Like, I just love those two, but Hank is really like grown as the one I paid the most attention to.
Speaker 1: And I really like, he's very insightful and I like what he has to say.
Speaker 1: And I think you will be interested in what he had to say about why the doomsday clock is set, where it's set.
Speaker 1: Was that enough time for you to come up with the news or I got to keep going?
Speaker 0: No, I didn't really see anything that interesting.
Speaker 1: So I got another little news.
Speaker 1: Uh, it's one of those things that's not news to anyone, but it is always valuable to look at case studies.
Speaker 1: If there's something you care about, like look at individual actual concrete, non hypothetical examples of something you're mad about or interested in, uh, independent of looking at actual data about behavior and aggregate.
Speaker 1: So this is a story on vice, really short, really simple, but it's journalism in that it follows a handful of gaming NFTs.
Speaker 1: Uh, specifically like, like it follows like who bought these things?
Speaker 1: What happened to them?
Speaker 1: Like, let's talk to the person who owns it to see what their deal is.
Speaker 1: And it is fascinating because the story here seems to be the people they talk to who actually for real have an NFT and are not just an NFT scammer selling NFTs kind of bottom out of vague curiosity at best.
Speaker 1: Don't give a shit about NFTs, barely understand them.
Speaker 1: And like it is the most interesting one was the person who bought one because they were themselves doing journalism on what it's like to buy one.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, this isn't anything new.
Speaker 0: We talk about this all the time.
Speaker 0: That's how, you know, we're the kind of people where any decision we make in life, even the simplest thing, like I'm going to go to the grocery store and buy some fucking, I don't know, uh, dishwashing detergent.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: That's me and Scott spending like hours reading about different chemicals in dishwashing detergents, trying to figure out which brands are all actually the same brand.
Speaker 0: Like trying to find, trying to find a bootleg access to consumer reports, figuring out, you know, the tabs, the powder, the liquid with, you know, which with our, our type of dishwasher, which mode to use, what, you know, it's all.
Speaker 1: There is a, there is a, there's a, there's a YouTube video that goes deep into how you got to use that.
Speaker 0: I'm aware of, I've seen the same YouTube video.
Speaker 1: Did you see the followup that had several retractions and updates?
Speaker 1: That's even longer.
Speaker 0: I mean, which of the several followers?
Speaker 0: Anyway, the point is we're the kind of people we think really hard about everything, you know, and we, you know, we research and whatnot.
Speaker 0: A lot of people just sort of coast through life, right?
Speaker 0: You're not thinking too hard, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, if they need to buy some pad of paper, right?
Speaker 0: They'll just go to Staples or a drug store and just grab the cheapest one.
Speaker 0: Whereas I'm like, what's the nicest paper?
Speaker 0: What kind of pen do I have?
Speaker 0: What do I should get the lines?
Speaker 1: How far apart should I even need a pen or paper?
Speaker 1: Like, do I, do I really actually need this?
Speaker 1: A lot of my research when I think I'm buying anything is, do I need a thing to solve this problem at all?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And not even just buying things, just doing things, right?
Speaker 0: Ah, I have to cut up this onion.
Speaker 0: What cutting technique should I use?
Speaker 0: Which, which of the knives I already bought should I be using?
Speaker 0: What, you know, it's like techniques, you know, all these things.
Speaker 0: We're thinking really hard.
Speaker 0: And even if we're not thinking hard about a particular problem we have right now, I just constantly read things all over all the time.
Speaker 0: I spend most of my time just reading things all over and learning techniques, information about things.
Speaker 0: So I think most people don't do that or don't do it to the same extent that I do.
Speaker 0: Now, therefore it's like, if they open, they're playing a video game, they open it up and it says, Hey, buy this NFT skin.
Speaker 0: It's like, all right.
Speaker 0: You know, they're the kind of person who doesn't think too hard about that then.
Speaker 0: And they got money and they want the thing.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: They just do it.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: You know, they're not like necessarily an NFT believer or, you know, something like that.
Speaker 0: They might be.
Speaker 0: Um, but it's like, they're just going along with life.
Speaker 1: Not, you know, but it's also, I mean, not that everyone does that for everything.
Speaker 1: Like for all the research I do for like, there's a certain type of purchase.
Speaker 0: I do.
Speaker 0: I don't think there's anything I don't like in terms of anything I do in life.
Speaker 0: I think I've researched the techniques and equipment.
Speaker 1: But in terms of there, there are classes of completely fungible consumer products where I literally do not care and buy whatever the generic option is.
Speaker 0: But that is such a, I think the it's, if anything in my life that I don't like heavily research.
Speaker 0: the right way or the best way of doing a thing is, uh, or like any, like even minor life decisions or major ones, the only times I don't do extensive research investigation.
Speaker 1: I'll give you an example.
Speaker 1: I bought a battery for my car.
Speaker 1: I did zero research.
Speaker 1: I just bought an equity, the cheapest battery from a brand that appeared to be a real brand.
Speaker 0: that was the only time I don't do that is if it's something I've decided I'm just not going to do that way.
Speaker 0: I don't have to, you know, it doesn't matter what choice.
Speaker 0: Cause I just, I chose not to, but, uh, it's really funny.
Speaker 0: I do have a goal of just, you know, minimizing life, right?
Speaker 0: Do as few things as possible.
Speaker 1: But at least in the NFTs, like fake space where, you know, NFTs are just a scam.
Speaker 1: It is the media.
Speaker 1: like landscape around NFTs acts like they're a thing because the most of the conversation about NFTs are from the people who are running NFT scams and Astro turfing everywhere they can Astro turf.
Speaker 0: But I mean, a large, a large part of media is not at, you know, a very small part of media is journalists who think hard about a thing.
Speaker 0: And even if they do think hard about a thing, they write about the thing from within its own context and not, you know, I think about almost everything I ever encountered, like case in point, I consider it with a global context.
Speaker 1: Like a good journalist would literally point out that the Republican party in America is engaged in fascist voter suppression, but no, they're going to talk about them as somehow being an equal entity to other political parties.
Speaker 1: And they're going to have this very neutral, simplistic, like dialogue about it.
Speaker 0: That's not about shrinking the context.
Speaker 0: That's just.
Speaker 0: that's just about being wrong.
Speaker 0: But it's like I'm talking about, like, you know, someone might be discussing like a game and they talk about it within, you know, these with these assumptions already existing, right?
Speaker 0: Like, you know, whereas I'm going to look at like, OK, you're playing this game in the world, right on Earth.
Speaker 0: And the only assumption I have is the conservation of matter and energy.
Speaker 1: So the listener pointed out your extensive research.
Speaker 1: Does this apply to decisions you make in games, which I know that you often do not do any research on how, say, work arts work in civilization sex?
Speaker 0: Oh, well, that's just because it's a pain, too much of a pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: But no, I'd also don't like it when I am unable to do the right.
Speaker 0: I don't enjoy the games that require too much research into useless minutia.
Speaker 1: So so in one last news, you can watch it if you want to.
Speaker 1: It's 11, almost 12 hours long because they tried their best.
Speaker 1: So last night, the Democratic Party of the US basically forced the issue through a somewhat complicated and weird Senate procedure to force a floor vote.
Speaker 1: Basically, in the Senate, you can't like force a vote without weird shenanigans because of how broken that chamber of the American government is.
Speaker 1: So because, you know, we need to pass voting rights legislation or huge numbers of non white people basically lose access to the vote in the United States, mostly in Republican controlled states.
Speaker 1: This is all common knowledge.
Speaker 1: But one of the avenues, one of the few avenues we have to stop this is to pass a specific bill in our Senate, which has passed our house and is ready to be signed by our president.
Speaker 1: And because of the obscure rules of the Senate, basically you need 51 people to vote to proceed or the bill is just dead.
Speaker 1: And basically what the Democrats did is pull the shenanigans to actually force that vote.
Speaker 1: Up until this point, nobody actually had to say they were against the voting rights.
Speaker 1: They only had to just not show up, let the filibuster happen and kind of get away with it.
Speaker 1: So they basically exercised their final power to make it clear that there is no possible way to pass a bill like this via legal channels in the Senate.
Speaker 1: Whatever we do about the 2022 elections, there is no way to solve it via the existing Democratic process in the United States Federal Congress.
Speaker 1: They forced the issue.
Speaker 0: Following the rules that exist, yeah?
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, the rules that exist can only be changed by the exact same vote of that body.
Speaker 0: But I mean, you only need to change the rules if you've already decided to follow them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't think there's any world where the Senate just passes a bill not following Senate rules.
Speaker 1: that somehow becomes law.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying you only have to change rules if you already have decided to follow rules.
Speaker 0: If you're not following rules, doesn't matter what the rules are.
Speaker 1: So this is the interesting thing.
Speaker 1: It's worth watching the end of it, because what is interesting is that they basically went as hard as possible in the actual debate.
Speaker 1: And it was one of the first times in my life I've seen an actual, serious, no punches are pulled, real discussion of an issue like this.
Speaker 1: Like they went as hard as you can imagine going and they made extremely succinct, simple points.
Speaker 1: They made it very clear that the vote is literally just to protect the voting rights of non-white people.
Speaker 1: And 52 senators said, yeah, fuck that.
Speaker 1: I'm going to vote no on the record.
Speaker 1: Fuck you.
Speaker 1: It's over.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's, you know, because they're bad people.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So nothing was learned or gained.
Speaker 1: No, actually, one thing was learned because this is actually something that's moderately important.
Speaker 1: A big, false and honestly ridiculous argument that a lot of leftists and progressives in America have been making in public channels and even pundits have been making is they try to make a case that even if you got these two shitbag, like, traitor senators to vote on this bill, other Democrats wouldn't let this filibuster go away.
Speaker 1: Like there's other people.
Speaker 0: That's not true at all.
Speaker 0: It's just two shitbags.
Speaker 0: We know that.
Speaker 1: No one could prove that.
Speaker 1: No one believed that.
Speaker 0: You know, in case you weren't on the same page that we've been on.
Speaker 1: If you believe that ridiculous talking point, that's what happened.
Speaker 0: I never I haven't heard of anyone who said that.
Speaker 0: But that is extremely widespread, Scott.
Speaker 1: Even among some of our friends, it is.
Speaker 0: Well, if you didn't realize it was just two shitbags holding up the entire country.
Speaker 0: Now, you know.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But it is.
Speaker 1: But that argument is absolutely false because 48 Democrats voted right then and there to end the filibuster.
Speaker 1: It would have happened instantly if these two shitbags or if any two Republican senators who are also shitbags had voted.
Speaker 1: So fifty two human beings who represent roughly twenty five percent of the American population have an absolute veto on all legislation.
Speaker 1: And forty eight senators representing a actually terrifyingly small percentage, terrifyingly large percentage of the population have zero recourse.
Speaker 0: And nothing new was learned or gained.
Speaker 1: The thing we just said was learned because a lot of people.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess someone needed to learn that, but nothing new was learned.
Speaker 1: I guess the point is a scary number of people needed to learn that there are actually 48 senators willing to overturn the filibuster for this.
Speaker 0: I think the only thing that was gained is that you made all those old white guys sit there for that many hours.
Speaker 1: The only possible thing that Democrats could do now in the Senate is something that they started to do last night.
Speaker 1: My wonder is the threat or whatever.
Speaker 1: But there is one other thing is kind of obscure.
Speaker 1: There is the concept of a reverse filibuster.
Speaker 1: It was used in like 2003 by the Republicans once.
Speaker 1: I don't know of any other instance of it happening, but basically what you do is you bring a bill to the floor, OK?
Speaker 1: You vote to make it pass.
Speaker 1: The Republicans then filibuster filibuster you at the last second.
Speaker 1: You make sure that your majority leader votes last.
Speaker 1: You vote no against your own bill.
Speaker 1: So it gets pulled from the floor without like.
Speaker 1: if you vote yes for it and it fails, you can't bring it back to the floor.
Speaker 1: But if you vote no and pull it from the floor, you can theoretically bring it back to the floor.
Speaker 1: So you bring it to the floor.
Speaker 1: All the votes come in.
Speaker 1: If it didn't pass, you vote against it.
Speaker 1: Bring it back from the floor.
Speaker 1: You immediately raise a point of order and bring it back to the fucking floor and you start over.
Speaker 0: OK, so but they're happy to do that because that what does that get you?
Speaker 0: They don't want anything to pass ever.
Speaker 0: So if you keep doing that and you keep repeating it, so I think they'll get what they want, which is you just write this.
Speaker 1: You can do one thing because the thing the reason the filibuster is so broken in America is that for most of its history, it was a talking filibuster.
Speaker 1: If you wanted to filibuster something, you had to actually stand up there and piss your pants.
Speaker 1: Keep talking.
Speaker 1: Read the phone book.
Speaker 1: So when they change that rule, you can do nothing and filibuster.
Speaker 1: Filibusters are just automatic.
Speaker 1: The thing you could do with the reverse filibuster is force all those old men to sit there and they literally cannot leave.
Speaker 1: If once you start this process, if they leave, the bill passes, they would be forced to sit there and wait you out.
Speaker 1: And you could force a ridiculous public spectacle and also block all other Senate business.
Speaker 1: That's basically the last holy grail.
Speaker 0: Problem is, is you still need even if you, you know, OK, you avoided this filibuster thing and now you're actually voting on the bill itself, whether it will become law.
Speaker 0: You still need 50 votes and a tiebreaker to pass the law.
Speaker 1: Which could happen.
Speaker 0: But do you think the two shit bags who are going to vote for the law?
Speaker 1: So it's like there's more complication.
Speaker 1: I'm skipping, but I think one of those two shit bags could be brought enough to ship.
Speaker 1: The problem is one of them seems to just be a plant like she is just like working with Republicans openly at this point.
Speaker 0: So so it won't really matter even if you get past the filibuster and then.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: OK, let's say you get this thing past the filibuster.
Speaker 0: You pass this law.
Speaker 1: It's instantly law.
Speaker 1: Biden signs it that day.
Speaker 1: He has said as much.
Speaker 0: that is true.
Speaker 1: Already passed the House.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: Here's what's not true.
Speaker 1: The Supreme Court could just overturn it immediately if they wanted.
Speaker 0: Well, that but not overturn it.
Speaker 0: But OK, so some red state is still conducting voter suppression against the law.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You have to now sue that state in a court and then you have to fight in the court.
Speaker 0: And then even if the.
Speaker 1: Oh, do you actually know what's in the John Lewis voting?
Speaker 1: That voting rights act is watertight, trivial to enforce, almost impossible to pull up into the courts or the Supreme Court.
Speaker 1: And more importantly, you know what it does.
Speaker 1: It basically gives the Department of Justice, which is way less constrained by rules than Congress, the ability to enforce.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, you're definitely going to get some enforcement, but, you know, it's not.
Speaker 1: Also, honestly, we really only need this bill for a couple of swing states for the short term.
Speaker 1: Like it only needs to really be enforced in like Georgia and a couple other places.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, because I mean, it doesn't matter if that, you know, OK, voter suppress all you want in Utah.
Speaker 1: It's the West Virginia is 98 percent white.
Speaker 1: No statewide election goes toward the Democrats in that state under any circumstances.
Speaker 1: But the other new piece of information that we get to the rest of the show, that's actually very important.
Speaker 1: There is a way forward if the Democrats hold the House in 2022, which is not impossible.
Speaker 0: It seems unlikely.
Speaker 1: It's less unlikely than it was a few weeks ago because the gerrymandering the Republicans were doing wasn't actually as effective as people expected because they're running out of room to gerrymander.
Speaker 1: They've gerrymandered so much.
Speaker 0: The only hope that I have is enough Republicans died of covid.
Speaker 0: That's my hope.
Speaker 1: I was I was actually about to bring that up.
Speaker 1: That is what I look.
Speaker 0: But I did some cursory research on that at one point.
Speaker 0: I was like, all right, how many people died of covid in Florida?
Speaker 0: total?
Speaker 1: Oh, no, you don't need Florida.
Speaker 0: Where the margins on like, you know, I looked at them.
Speaker 1: I don't even need Florida.
Speaker 1: All that matters is like Arizona, Michigan, Ohio, Wisconsin.
Speaker 0: I think I looked at also at like Texas.
Speaker 0: But it's like.
Speaker 0: even it was like even if every person who died of covid in Florida was a Republican and all, you know, it's like it wasn't enough to make up the margins on any of the statewide elections.
Speaker 0: So I don't think that's going to remember.
Speaker 1: All we have to do theoretically is win what we like, win things that like things we've won very recently.
Speaker 1: It's not impossible.
Speaker 1: It's actually it's plausible.
Speaker 1: But mostly Republican seats are up for election in the Senate in twenty twenty two.
Speaker 1: Very few Democrats are up, meaning they're mostly playing defense because forty eight senators, none of whom are likely to lose their seats, are have voted yes for this and would vote yes for it again.
Speaker 1: If we pick up even two seats, we can immediately pass this bill.
Speaker 1: if we hold if we hold the House by even one seat.
Speaker 0: Well, which two seats do you think you're going to get?
Speaker 1: There are several that I think talking about.
Speaker 1: that's out of scope for the show.
Speaker 1: You could join us in the angry politics section of the discard board.
Speaker 1: We're talking about this constantly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no, there's no, but I'm saying I don't know what you're talking about.
Speaker 0: To simultaneously talk about a hopeless and free to serve.
Speaker 1: Picking up two Senate seats makes it actually for real possible to pass this bill.
Speaker 1: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 1: So check this out.
Speaker 1: This I found this video as part of a conversation I was having about old commercials.
Speaker 1: And this is a compilation of a bunch of commercials for dot com companies during the late 90s, early 2000s dot com boom, which was like Mike.
Speaker 1: That was like Scott and I were already nerds.
Speaker 1: And this was like before the Internet existed.
Speaker 1: in the way that you know today, like this is Web 1.0 Internet ads.
Speaker 1: Mm hmm.
Speaker 0: It is paperweight paperweight style.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is amazing.
Speaker 1: Like just what some of these are selling, especially when you see screenshots of what websites look like back then, like I know what websites look like back then.
Speaker 0: I made those websites and use those websites.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I made and use those websites.
Speaker 1: This was an era when most online shopping meant mail a check or money order in the via the U.S.
Speaker 1: post office to a company after you bought something on their website.
Speaker 0: Or type your credit card number into an unencrypted Web form and make an HDTV post.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Very few websites could accept credit cards back then.
Speaker 1: Very few.
Speaker 0: And they weren't accepting them the way they are now, where like a transaction happens.
Speaker 0: You were basically just posting and then it was going into a database or a file and someone at the other end would then look in that file and then process your order manually.
Speaker 0: It'd be like it'd be like if I sent you an email with my credit card number and said, I'd like two pizzas, please.
Speaker 0: And then someone opened the email, looked at it, then charged my card using their point of sale system and then started making the pizzas.
Speaker 1: That is, I'm pretty sure how that one experimental online pizza delivery website at RIT worked.
Speaker 0: I mean, I worked at broa.com for many years before that, before I got there.
Speaker 0: Well, before I got there.
Speaker 0: But when that business was new in the late 90s, it was literally just email these two and they would run down physically to the theater and buy the tickets and then they would get your money and then you would show up to New York and then you'd come to the office and they'd give you the tickets from the safe that they bought.
Speaker 1: So I just scrolled down and I saw the top YouTube comment on this video and it hit me right in the old.
Speaker 1: I'm just going to read this.
Speaker 1: It's one sentence quote.
Speaker 1: I never knew Amazon was originally a book only website.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: People don't know that they just sold books.
Speaker 0: The first thing I ever bought on Amazon was a copy of catch 22 a book.
Speaker 1: So what do you got?
Speaker 0: What do I have?
Speaker 0: So, uh, we love the go, the old factory videos, right?
Speaker 0: Anytime you see the inside of a real factory making some, you know, common everyday goods, right?
Speaker 0: Really fascinating stuff, really satisfying, especially a lot of the processes.
Speaker 0: Here's one that is not just interesting for the process and how shockingly manual a lot of it is.
Speaker 0: I think a lot more could be automated in this factory, even with my limited factory knowledge.
Speaker 0: But what's really fascinating is just, you know, the, I guess, eco friendliness in this factory in South Korea where golf is pretty popular.
Speaker 0: It's one of the golf playing nations.
Speaker 0: They are taking old golf balls, which usually go to the driving range and then go to the mini golf and then go to the garbage.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And basically, if you think about a golf ball, it's like, yeah, you use it.
Speaker 0: You know, and for like a round of golf, maybe you lose some in the woods, right?
Speaker 0: And they're still good.
Speaker 0: But if they don't lose them to the woods, they're not really good to use again.
Speaker 0: The next game of golf, they've gotten beat up and damaged and whatnot, but it's only really the outside shell that's damaged from flexing and getting smacked.
Speaker 0: The inside is largely just fine, um, you know, and could see a lot more use than the outside could see.
Speaker 0: And what they do in this video is they basically get old golf balls.
Speaker 0: They cut the outside off and throw it away.
Speaker 0: And then they make new outsides and they're reusing golf balls, which is very economic, ecologically good, not wasting so much plastic and rubber.
Speaker 0: So that's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: And in general, the the actual reality of how physical things and physical labor get done are way more important to society than the tech stuff that we're doing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, if all golf balls were, you know, made this way, like reused in this fashion, instead of just being thrown out or lost in the woods, that would probably have a pretty significant impact.
Speaker 1: So in the moment, getting used to the book club book, The Tale of Genji, Scott has reached the end.
Speaker 1: I am rapidly already a third into.
Speaker 0: I'm a 33 percent done with the next book club.
Speaker 1: I feel like we'll do that next book club book inside of a couple of weeks tops after we finish this one.
Speaker 1: But I'm steamrolling ahead.
Speaker 1: I think Genji is about to die.
Speaker 0: I feel like I think you are not that close to the end that you got a ways to go.
Speaker 1: I think he's going to die like next chapter, which means you better read some more.
Speaker 1: Well, that's the I know.
Speaker 1: I know the historical context of the chapter chapters that follow at least more so than I know about the other part.
Speaker 0: They are easier to read, but they are not.
Speaker 0: you know, they're going to take you some time still.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But I also when I'm reading this book, I read it pretty fast, but partly because every time I read the chapter where Genji dies, that one's going to take you.
Speaker 0: You're going to read that one real fast.
Speaker 1: Oh, I looked ahead and I saw.
Speaker 1: I saw that one.
Speaker 1: I saw that chapter.
Speaker 1: That's that's cool and clever.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I also learned something about the chapters that come after that.
Speaker 1: And there's a lot of debate over the intent around them.
Speaker 1: There's even some debate around who wrote them, apparently.
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but also Genji is only like 40.
Speaker 0: So people didn't live that long back then.
Speaker 1: And Turnabout's fair play.
Speaker 1: Some of the things that happened to Genji in the last few chapters are a lot like the things that Genji was doing to other people in earlier chapters.
Speaker 1: You see the cycle there.
Speaker 1: I got things to say about like the.
Speaker 1: the structure of these books get more and more like modern novels the further you get into them as you see her clearly refining her technique.
Speaker 1: And that's the thing that is standing out the most to me as I get near the end.
Speaker 0: It's like reading a webcomic.
Speaker 0: It gets better as the time goes on.
Speaker 1: Like if you just grab the Tale of Genji and read one of the later chapters, you'll understand it a lot better than if you read like the second chapter.
Speaker 0: And it's it's not just your understanding of it that improved because I went back and tried to read an earlier chapter and it was still hard to know.
Speaker 1: There's a lot more context in the text.
Speaker 1: There's a lot more like of the way we expect books to be written in the text.
Speaker 1: It's it's fascinating.
Speaker 1: That's I'm taking more away from that than I am from anything else in these books anyway.
Speaker 1: Well, this book, these chapters anyway.
Speaker 1: So we'll be doing that.
Speaker 1: We'll be finishing that show up in the next couple of weeks.
Speaker 1: And then we'll be Steve Rollin ahead with a bunch of book club books.
Speaker 1: And I have a pile of nonfiction.
Speaker 1: I've been really, really itching to read.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, PAX East.
Speaker 1: Most likely the best is either us or likely just me.
Speaker 1: We'll be there for one day to do one or two panels like I did for PAX Unplugged.
Speaker 1: I feel like that's the extent.
Speaker 1: But Tracy, see if if he's going to do a panel, I'm going to a panel.
Speaker 1: See if we can arrange them on the same day and maybe we'll do a panel together.
Speaker 1: If you don't want to go.
Speaker 0: Not going to Boston just to do a panel.
Speaker 1: I'll go to Boston.
Speaker 1: I work in an industry where pre-COVID I would just go to Boston for the day, like kind of commonly as part of my job.
Speaker 1: Like I'd literally just get up, get out in a cellar, go to Boston, work there all day and get out in a cellar home.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no, not doing it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll see.
Speaker 1: April is later than other PAXes.
Speaker 1: So I'm less hesitant about.
Speaker 1: I hope the COVID situation is way better in April than it is now.
Speaker 1: But mostly having been to PAX Unplugged for a few hours, the thing I would be most worried about at a gaming con now is even if it was safe to go, I discovered what it's like to be at a table with four people trying to talk to each other in masks in a place that is as echoey and loud as a gaming space at a con like PAX East.
Speaker 1: I don't think most people can understand each other well enough to play an RPG.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: Like that.
Speaker 0: That isn't playing RPG under normal circumstances in a non-COVID time.
Speaker 1: There is nothing obstructing the words coming out of my mouth.
Speaker 1: Us playing an RPG at PAX East is us yelling at each other for hours at a table and constantly repeating ourselves.
Speaker 0: You need the quiet room, right?
Speaker 0: The quiet room is the way.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And if we're going to just go to a hotel room, why even go to the con?
Speaker 1: Let's just all meet in one of our apartments and play an RPG.
Speaker 0: Yeah, why don't we do that?
Speaker 0: Let's do that.
Speaker 1: I actually do want to start off that Blades in the Dark game in Queens like as soon as I unbubble again.
Speaker 0: I want to play other games.
Speaker 1: Like what game do you want to play?
Speaker 0: I mean, I have a huge pile of indie tabletop RPG PDFs.
Speaker 0: I want to play each one one time.
Speaker 0: I'm not really interested in.
Speaker 1: I'm honestly, right now, I'm mostly interested in taking a game I've never played and doing a full campaign to really explore it.
Speaker 0: Full campaign means, you know, I got all these games.
Speaker 0: Just eat the same burger every night?
Speaker 0: It's like, I want to try everything.
Speaker 0: I want to go to the buffet and feast upon all the different games.
Speaker 0: And then maybe after I've tried all these different games, maybe then I'll be like, that one was the real good one.
Speaker 0: Let's play a campaign of that.
Speaker 1: Thing is, I know, I know mostly how these games will go just from reading the rules and having a lot of experience with them.
Speaker 0: I haven't even read the rules yet.
Speaker 1: I did too.
Speaker 1: I did stop reading the rules to indie RPGs that have come out in the past couple of years because I have read a lot of indie RPG rules over the years and not played those games yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 0: I want to play all these games, one time each at least.
Speaker 1: I guess the thing I'm most interested in in RPGs, now that I've played a campaign for a while again, is that that is what I've always loved.
Speaker 1: the most about RPGs is playing long form, not the one offs.
Speaker 1: The one offs are just like hollow appetizers compared to campaigns.
Speaker 0: Me, I don't really care for the campaign.
Speaker 1: I mean, my whole life, most of the D&D I played, the vast majority of all role playing I've ever done in my life was from a grand total of five campaigns.
Speaker 0: It's, you know, because with the campaign, it's always more of the same.
Speaker 0: I need the novelty.
Speaker 0: I want to try to explore the same.
Speaker 1: You're doing different things.
Speaker 1: We are taking out the Denver Sisters.
Speaker 0: Okay, whatever.
Speaker 1: Okay, I guess we will play RPGs.
Speaker 1: I'll go run campaigns with everybody else.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so greeting cards.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're going to do a bunch of shows on different kinds of cards, so stay tuned for that.
Speaker 0: Well, I've wanted to do a YouTube series about cards.
Speaker 0: I've had some, you know, but it's a project shit talk situation.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: We thought about doing a meta show on Geek Nights, and we just recently did one.
Speaker 1: So greeting cards or just cards, the kind like Hallmark cards, the card you send to someone for an event based reason, like a birthday, a death, a graduation, a funeral.
Speaker 0: It could also just be a greeting like, hi, I was thinking of you, you know, you also might not send it.
Speaker 0: You might like tape it onto a gift or true, you know, hand it to someone.
Speaker 0: These are especially in the US because I know that I don't know what the culture of greeting cards is in other countries.
Speaker 0: They're very different everywhere.
Speaker 1: I have encountered the equivalents from various countries over the years in my professional career, getting professional gifts.
Speaker 1: And yeah, I actually had like a coach at my old company who would like help us, help me and help us as a company respond to or proactively do whatever the equivalent culture is in the countries we were doing business in, because this culture is radically different everywhere.
Speaker 1: So everything we're talking about is going to be primarily from a US-centric perspective because we're US-ians and really in the forum, like let us know what it's like in your country.
Speaker 1: Like this is I am very interested in that.
Speaker 0: I want to know.
Speaker 0: But anyway, so in the US, when I was growing up, I don't know what the history was because I never researched it.
Speaker 0: I'm sure I could look it up.
Speaker 0: But when I was young, basically, if there was a special occasion, usually in accompanying a gift, but not always, not always, you would you would go and buy a card, which is either made by.
Speaker 0: there were basically two companies that sort of have Monopoly, American Greetings and Hallmark and American Greetings, made famous by Penny Arcade and Hallmark, made famous by capitalism.
Speaker 0: And you would go to either a Hallmark store that was like a store that just sold cards and gift shit or, you know, the grocery store, the drugstore.
Speaker 0: They always had a section of them, you know, needed one quickly.
Speaker 0: And you'd you'd pick one out.
Speaker 0: And there were all these licensing deals so you could get Snoopy's and Garfield's.
Speaker 1: It was organized.
Speaker 1: And it was always like they were like literally organized by topic alphabetically.
Speaker 1: So you're like funeral function, like you're just looking down the list until you find like 40th birthday.
Speaker 0: That's the one.
Speaker 0: But right.
Speaker 0: So first it's by topic, but then it's by audience.
Speaker 0: It's like, OK, birthday, but is an old person's birthday, a young person's birthday?
Speaker 0: What gender is the person that you're giving the birthday card to?
Speaker 0: Or a, you know, a gender neutral one.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Or, you know, is it is it gonna be a funny one or a serious one or a sentimental one?
Speaker 0: Or, you know, every different flavor for each event was or circumstance was available.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And then.
Speaker 0: That there was licensing deals and there were some that weren't licensed.
Speaker 0: Some of them had words in them.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Like.
Speaker 0: and some of them were just blank and you had to write your own words.
Speaker 0: Some of the words are minimal, but you could add your own words in the other space.
Speaker 1: So I don't know about you, but I at least, you know, we talked about this.
Speaker 1: We did all the shows around our childhoods in history.
Speaker 1: I grew up in like like very young childhood Detroit.
Speaker 1: But most of my like post kid brain childhood was in the most suburban suburbs to ever grace Midwestern suburbia like pop generic Americana and greeting card like cards like this were such a fixture of life.
Speaker 1: And there were such like specific and simple rules about them that literally like kids would all almost even get the exact same card for their birthday.
Speaker 1: Like as time went on.
Speaker 0: Like that's something I didn't notice until more, you know, maybe the past decade or decade and a half.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Is that the quality of cards and variety of cards back then was much lower.
Speaker 0: Number one, making your own cards was like much more difficult back then.
Speaker 0: You know, even if you had a printer, it wasn't a high quality printer.
Speaker 0: You were using Microsoft Publisher and getting some clip art.
Speaker 0: You didn't have Photoshop.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You know, now anyone can make any card.
Speaker 0: So computers helped a lot.
Speaker 0: There have been a lot of advances in terms of cutting machines that are available to industry as well as home people and basically just, you know, the technology of cards and also, you know, the art of cards, Hallmark and American greetings.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: We're only making cards and like a certain amount and a certain spread of ideas.
Speaker 0: And they were really staying in their lane.
Speaker 0: Whereas once that opened up to other companies, butting in the monopolies long over and people making their own cards, the range of expression on cards expanded, you know, massive.
Speaker 1: I've seen in drugstores sections like big congratulations versus just a regular congratulation or like work anniversary versus significant work anniversary, like different levels of condolences.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, I'm talking more like, OK, so there's a company, Papyrus with the overpriced cards or whatever.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I think they might have gotten bought by so I don't know.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but their cards are like extra fancy with like materials.
Speaker 0: And right.
Speaker 0: And then you've got some like the love pop ones which came out, which are like these pop up cards.
Speaker 0: And it's like, you know, they're really fancy.
Speaker 0: You open it up and like there's a pop up scene.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, and then the way those have like an insert that you write on and there's no words.
Speaker 0: you have to write everything yourself.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So those are pretty good.
Speaker 0: And then, you know, in Astoria here, we've got like, you know, the local, you know, we've got local shops and they've got like some hyper local cards going on right from companies you never even heard of that are like making greeting cards and selling them a whole bunch.
Speaker 0: But only, you know, in in more indie stores.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like the indie greeting card market, because now the, you know, the technology to make design cards with Photoshop and then print them, you know, got democratized.
Speaker 0: You didn't have to have a giant, enormous printing press like Hallmark had in the 80s or whatever.
Speaker 0: And, you know, anyone could do it now, but also an Etsy.
Speaker 0: You could make you could design a greeting card, go on Etsy, sell it, and people will buy it and use it for their occasions.
Speaker 1: You know, so when I was a kid, as a result of, you know, before all of that, there weren't that many different greeting cards and you'd all get the same one.
Speaker 1: And the other thing I always remember is that there were just sort of like these social rules of sending them where you were like as a kid, like we're obligated to send them even if we didn't care about people, like they were just a thing.
Speaker 0: Every relative said, well, it's not like you could email someone and phone calls were long distance cost money.
Speaker 0: So like, you know, you would send someone, you know, it's like someone's birthday.
Speaker 0: You sent cards.
Speaker 0: If it's your birthday, you got cards.
Speaker 0: You know, but what's interesting now, you just text someone when it's their birthday.
Speaker 1: If I wanted to communicate, I would like.
Speaker 1: back then, I was like, sometimes I would write a letter like that was the thing.
Speaker 1: You know, we're very old.
Speaker 1: I would write letters to people.
Speaker 1: Sometimes people like relatives read letters to us.
Speaker 1: We do a phone call, which for was a big deal in the era when long distance was the thing.
Speaker 1: like couldn't call.
Speaker 0: People who went on vacation would send you a postcard because it's not like they could call you or anything from there.
Speaker 1: I remember when my grandparents were in New Zealand, we we did one phone call with them and it was late at night.
Speaker 1: And that was like the biggest fucking deal.
Speaker 1: Like we're going to do this phone call.
Speaker 1: It's going to be really expensive.
Speaker 0: We just sent postcards when someone was in an island or something.
Speaker 1: But what I also what I remember as a result of that is that most of the cards I received and most of the cards I sent, we had and there was I would not write a message in them.
Speaker 1: I would just sign them.
Speaker 1: They had a canned message and almost every greeting card I ever received just had a canned message, even within the family.
Speaker 1: It was mostly just canned messages, except the handful of people both in the family and just friends and people I knew who were like the greeting card people who would always get a blank one and completely fill it with a letter.
Speaker 1: But that was the exception.
Speaker 1: Like there was one on who would do this, one grandma who would do this, the mom of the one friend who would do this, the one family who would get a custom card with their own photos in it and send like the same card to everyone over Christmas.
Speaker 0: Oh, you got to talk about the holiday card thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I noticed, at least in my family, it really dropped off once the Internet started to take off and we started to email each other.
Speaker 1: And there was a period when I just stopped like middle, late middle school.
Speaker 1: I stopped doing cards of any kind.
Speaker 1: I would give no one a card.
Speaker 1: I would only email people.
Speaker 1: And I noticed that I stopped getting cards from anyone who wasn't old around that time as well.
Speaker 0: Yeah, everyone just sends a Facebook, you know, post on their Facebook wall on your birthday or whatever, you know, no one send in a car.
Speaker 1: They started to come back around later.
Speaker 1: But I think that's partly an artifact of my less online contacts and less online relatives.
Speaker 1: Like my mom just watches the stream.
Speaker 1: She's really watching this right now.
Speaker 1: Like some of my distant friends and family follow me online or we interact online.
Speaker 1: But then there's the subset who aren't as online and I interact with them much more via cards than I do everyone else.
Speaker 1: Not that I don't talk to them outside of cards, but those are the people who tend to send and receive cards with me more so than people who are online enough to just text me on like my birthday.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, the card nowadays is really, you know, when I was a kid, it was common probably because, you know, you're getting birthday gifts constantly, you know, holiday gifts constantly.
Speaker 0: So there's cards attached to them in some way.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Or, you know, there's relatives, you know, you don't see or talk with often enough.
Speaker 0: You know, there's a special event, but nowadays it's like, OK, I'm only really using the card and getting the card when it's like a special situation like, OK, I'm coming to your wedding and I'm giving you a gift.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And I'm putting the gift in this card.
Speaker 0: I can't just.
Speaker 0: it would be weird if I just handed you a check on its own.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So I got to put it in a card.
Speaker 0: It's almost, you know, or I'm getting you a gift for the holiday.
Speaker 0: I will.
Speaker 0: it would be weird if I just gave you the gift and just a blank just wrapped and that's it.
Speaker 0: I have to take a card and tape it to the outside of the package for years now.
Speaker 1: What we've been doing is Emily would do this a lot.
Speaker 1: Her family does it.
Speaker 1: So we started doing it just generally is if we have a gift, we'll wrap it in some sort of towel, like a nice cloth of some kind and reuse that for future gifts.
Speaker 0: We you know, there's the gift bags for people who don't want to wrap anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we we have the gift bags and then we just save them and use them again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we just use the fancy cloth.
Speaker 0: You just put tissue paper to hide what's inside so no one goes to the top.
Speaker 0: And then you next year you just look and you go look in the closet and see if you have a bag that's the right size.
Speaker 0: And you know, you only have to use the wrapping paper if it's, you know, a more serious biz deal.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The other thing I remember is some the holiday cards were a special thing because many families, not every family, not every part of every family, like even in my family orbit, some like a subset of them would send a very long like card that was really just a letter or just really honestly, and
Speaker 0: I don't have anyone who did that.
Speaker 1: We did, but it was mostly that like really disappeared from my entire life around the time that the Internet really took off in that those letters were mostly just like, here's an update on all the things that happened to us because we don't talk often because you live really, really far away.
Speaker 0: You don't know because there's no such thing as Facebook.
Speaker 0: And the thing as a kid, like the cards that we don't talk on the phone regularly, but I still think of you.
Speaker 1: I always hated the the cards that they made us do in school.
Speaker 1: Like, all right, it's Valentine's Day.
Speaker 1: You have to make a card for everyone in your class.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, I thought that I like those because I only like getting the candy that would generally come along with it.
Speaker 0: But you would get the box that was full.
Speaker 0: That was designed for school.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: The one that's like, hey, it's Zelda cards.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: And it would you get a cool one like, you know, Ninja Turtles or something.
Speaker 1: But I was the nerd who gave the cool Nintendo one and the non nerds thought that stuff was lame as hell.
Speaker 0: I mean, there were enough nerdy people.
Speaker 0: I got some good ones and then you got some normal ones to choose, you know, whatever.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But, you know, you got it was like getting a goodie bag.
Speaker 0: It was fine.
Speaker 0: You know, it's fine.
Speaker 1: One class had a rule.
Speaker 1: You had to write something in every card, which was rough because I didn't even know half of these kids and the other half of them.
Speaker 1: I avoided on purpose.
Speaker 0: I just wrote Happy Valentine's Day.
Speaker 1: One year in third grade, they were like, it can't just be Happy Valentine's Day.
Speaker 1: You have to write something personal.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 1: I was right.
Speaker 0: I'll write the word something personal.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I don't remember what I did.
Speaker 1: I remember being mad about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Pretty much only use and get the cards in the special occasion times.
Speaker 0: Especially if I have to put money or a check in something.
Speaker 0: Or if it's like, yeah, you got to give a gift to the door people at the end of the year.
Speaker 0: Super.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You put that in a card.
Speaker 0: You can't just give some Benjamin's like, there you go.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But I think that, you know, the purpose of the cards is not just this sort of physical gift vehicle.
Speaker 0: You know, since the letter purpose is, like we said, gone, it's also sort of like this social lubricant for people.
Speaker 0: You don't want you feel awkward or you feel uncomfortable, right?
Speaker 0: Expressing heartfelt, you know, sincere heartfelt sentimentality.
Speaker 1: Either because that's difficult or because you don't have anything in particular to say.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of reasons that could be the case.
Speaker 0: Like face to face, right?
Speaker 0: Like you're going to go to the doorman, right?
Speaker 0: And be like, you know, I really appreciate, you know, you work hard, right?
Speaker 0: You know, you think, you know, I see you here every day.
Speaker 0: You know, my life is a lot better, you know, than it would be if you weren't here.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You're doing a great job.
Speaker 0: You know, imagine, imagine all my packages would be stolen if you didn't come and do this job, right?
Speaker 0: It means a lot to me.
Speaker 0: It's like, that would be awkward to actually say that to the doorman, even though it's true.
Speaker 0: And that's what you feel, right?
Speaker 0: It's like giving a card is like, aha, a non-awkward way to express those feelings to especially someone you're not super close with.
Speaker 0: It's also, if you are close with them, right?
Speaker 0: It's, you know, it's very important.
Speaker 1: I don't know how long it'll remain this way for people to ping people who are not online in their lives.
Speaker 1: Because in fact, like a lot of people you pay, you either have the mutual social media stuff or you use email or some technology to occasionally ping people that you want to stay in touch with, but don't have anything particular to say to like, hey, I recognize that we still know each other, us too.
Speaker 1: Like, hey, I point out, I note that you still exist.
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 1: I've clicked on you.
Speaker 1: I poked you on Facebook or whatever, but not online people.
Speaker 1: The card is like the only way to do that because those people aren't going to SMS you.
Speaker 1: They're not going to text you.
Speaker 0: I don't think there's any such people anymore.
Speaker 1: I still encounter people like that.
Speaker 1: And also those are the people who you don't often necessarily want to call them because you don't have a lot to say to them.
Speaker 1: Even if you care about call would be awkward.
Speaker 1: Like I said, so the generic card with a little bit like a little note is a really good way to stay in touch with those people.
Speaker 0: So let's talk about the thing I mentioned before.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: The holiday card.
Speaker 0: There is a tradition that I didn't do because we're Jews.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But in the
Speaker 0: U.S.,
Speaker 0: especially Christmas, people will make a holiday card usually with like a family photo or a pet photo.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: They'll have them made and they'll send one to literally everyone they know, every family at every other house in their family, every address in their contact list.
Speaker 0: That's someone who is close enough relation to them.
Speaker 1: Everyone had like the one extended family relation who did that.
Speaker 1: And you get it every year.
Speaker 0: Like who's the friend, family, coworkers.
Speaker 0: And they would send the card like to everyone, like holiday greetings from our family.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Here's a photo of us this year.
Speaker 0: And just, you know, make a huge pile of them, like a little project every year.
Speaker 0: And, you know, on the one hand, it's sort of like, eh, you receive one of those and you're like, eh.
Speaker 0: But on the other hand, it's like if I'm on the sending end, it's like, eh, you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, it's all right.
Speaker 0: It's like I could have fun doing that, especially, you know, when you're getting creative with it.
Speaker 0: Especially nowadays with your photo shops and your printing skills.
Speaker 1: You know, you can make a lot of the artist friends we have do a Chinese New Year card where they put some of their own original art on a card and like do a little thing.
Speaker 0: That's one thing I do know is that in Japan, the manga artists all make a and all the animators, they'll always make like a New Year image.
Speaker 0: They'll draw a New Year's picture.
Speaker 0: And I think they, you know, in the past, they may have put it on cards, but now they'll like like.
Speaker 0: I think even like Miyazaki drew a picture and then he just posts it on the posted on social media or whatever.
Speaker 0: Like, here's my New Year's image that I drew.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And that's, you know, that's nice.
Speaker 0: I like that.
Speaker 1: But yeah, it's this industry definitely got largely altered by the fact that technology exists, but it moved in.
Speaker 0: It's in a really good place right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Apparently, there still are really only two major producers of them in the globe.
Speaker 0: It's still weird that there's still two major producers even.
Speaker 1: But like, I think what's happening is most people do not put as much thought into this topic as we just did doing a podcast about it.
Speaker 0: So echoing back to the first part of the show, I feel like for the past decade, though, I was like, I haven't bought a Hallmark or an American.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, I've ever if I've ever gotten one, it's either been a local indie, you know, one or the the love pop ones.
Speaker 0: I like a lot the pop of ones.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Although they may have that company may have been bought by one of the bigger companies.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: But even if they did, I was buying from them when they were still small.
Speaker 1: Well, I remember once when I was young, like late middle school, we got Christmas cards from like a family that was friends with our family.
Speaker 1: But it had photos of them in it, which at the time was very expensive and not easy for normal people.
Speaker 0: Film photos.
Speaker 0: You're going to go to get them developed and print out a whole bunch of them.
Speaker 0: And you can't just see photos on Facebook, right?
Speaker 0: It was like that.
Speaker 0: They were they were having this person in months.
Speaker 0: Oh, I can see what they look like now.
Speaker 1: And that was another, you know, another function that disappeared was.
Speaker 1: that was the only way I would see what people who didn't live near us.
Speaker 0: I didn't see selfies of them every day on Instagram.
Speaker 1: So like I didn't have a digital image of myself that I could do anything with until eighth grade when I scanned a photo of myself in the computer lab at our at in my middle school.
Speaker 1: And then I had that photo on a floppy disk.
Speaker 1: It was like a couple hundred pixels, probably.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And I remember I photoshopped another earring onto my will not photoshopped.
Speaker 1: I think I used MS pain to see what an earring would look like to decide if I should get a second earring like.
Speaker 1: that was the extent.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, I think that was a show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got a. you know, I got a. I basically say every greeting card that I've gotten, I have in a drawer over there.
Speaker 1: But I started drawing old ones.
Speaker 1: I keep them for like a year and I purge.
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 0: The thing is, I don't have that many because at a certain point they stopped coming.
Speaker 0: So it's like that's all I've ever going to get pretty much.
Speaker 1: I think I have a pile of them back at home.
Speaker 1: Like my mom probably has a pile of old ones.
Speaker 0: My mom definitely has a huge pile of them.
Speaker 0: But I've only got the ones that I've received directly since leaving home.
Speaker 0: So and I'm not receiving any more.
Speaker 0: And I guess if I have a special event, I can't imagine what special event would result in getting a bunch of cards.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Maybe if I get sick and I get get hopefully that doesn't happen.
Speaker 0: I could get well soon.
Speaker 1: I mean, the truest gift for a friend in the modern era is an old copy of EGM, which there are rituals and how that's delivered.
Speaker 1: And this has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of Geek Nights are Heidi McNichol, Alan Joyce, Link Iggi, Dread Lillie, Tenderbrain, a bunch of people who don't want me to say who really don't want me to say their names.
Speaker 1: Chris Lidad, Chris Reimer, Clinton Walton, Dex, Finn, Kishaya85, Rebecca Dunn, Revue, MadBull34, Cowards, Sam Erickson, Shervin, Mount Horrell, Taylor Braun.
Speaker 1: The next station is York Mills, York Mills Station and several people who I will not reveal in this current stinger to this episode of Geek Nights because they have asked me not to.
Speaker 1: So, uh, yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: Let me know what color you want me to make my rim light and I'll change it for the next stream.
Speaker 1: How's that?
Speaker 1: I'll see who's actually listening to this stinger for right now.
Speaker 1: I simply leave you with Earlier.
Speaker 2: this evening, one of my colleagues from Crossy Isles said, why are we going down this road?
Speaker 2: And there have been similar questions.
Speaker 1: Why is this so important?
Speaker 2: Why is this bill so important?
Speaker 2: And I'll answer simply this, that dark money corrupts elections.
Speaker 2: If you and I donate more than $200 to a campaign, we are recorded.
Speaker 2: But if extraordinarily wealthy individuals donate hundreds of millions of dollars, they can do it with no attribution, corrupting the elections across this country.
Speaker 2: Gerrymandering corrupts the system of equal representation.
Speaker 2: From the earliest debates in this chamber, it was recognized that each of us has a stake in the integrity of the elections in other states so that the people of the United States experience equal representation.
Speaker 2: We do not have equal representation in the House today, and the gerrymandering going on now will increase that corruption.
Speaker 2: And third and most importantly, the power to vote is the most significant right guaranteeing each citizen a voice in the direction of our democracy.
Speaker 2: It is the soul of what it means to be a democratic republic.
Speaker 2: And that power to vote is also the most important check in our system of checks and balances.
Speaker 2: With rigged elections, leaders leaning towards autocracy can keep themselves in power.
Speaker 2: But with fair elections undergirded by a free press, the people can vote out those autocratic leaders who ignore laws and undermine our institutions.
Speaker 2: It's the most important check in maintaining the integrity of our beloved republic.
Speaker 2: Let's go back in time.
Speaker 2: The rules of the Senate were forged in the Confederation Congress experience.
Speaker 2: Our founders were engaged during the time they were writing our Constitution and participating in the Confederation Congress.
Speaker 2: that required a vote of 9 out of 13, two-thirds plus a bit, in order to pass any law.
Speaker 2: And it prevented them from being able to pay the pensions of our veterans.
Speaker 2: And it prevented them from raising money for Shea's Rebellion.
Speaker 2: Our founders participating in that process said this supermajority has paralyzed our ability to act.
Speaker 2: And with that in mind, they wrote our Constitution so that legislation would be passed by simple majority.
Speaker 2: That at the end of the debate, when all perspectives were duly considered, the perspective favored by the larger number would be accepted rather than the perspective favored by the smaller number.
Speaker 2: And so our founders, leaving nothing to chance, warned us in their writings, "Never adopt a
Speaker 2: supermajority.".
Speaker 2: They said, and I will quote James Madison, that when the general good might require new laws, the principle of free government would be reversed.
Speaker 2: It would no longer be the majority that would rule, it would be the power transferred to the minority.
Speaker 2: And he went on to say the result would be particular emergencies to extort unreasonable indulgences.
Speaker 2: Hamilton said many similar things.
Speaker 2: If a pertinacious minority can control the opinion of the majority, the result will be tedious delays and continual negotiation and intrigue and contemptible compromises.
Speaker 2: He noted the supermajority's real operations to embarrass the administration and destroy the energy of government.
Speaker 2: And anyone who has seen the energy drained out of this chamber by nothing happening, day after day after day when we have important issues to face, can understand just how right the founders were.
Speaker 2: So in writing up the guidelines and the vision for the initial Senate, our leaders came up with a Senate code.
Speaker 2: And that Senate code was here.
Speaker 2: all perspectives, in fact, guaranteed in rule four of the original rules that every senator will have the right to speak twice to a question.
Speaker 2: In addition, they put into the rules a previous question just in case they couldn't get the debate to wrap up so they could get to that all important vote to determine where the greater number stood.
Speaker 2: And Thomas Jefferson put into the rule book the manual for the rules.
Speaker 2: in 1801, no one is to speak impertinently or beside the question, superfluously or tediously.
Speaker 2: Hear the debate, consider all perspectives, and take the option the greater number favored.
Speaker 2: That Senate code endured in a powerful fashion for a very long time.
Speaker 2: In 1806, Aaron Burr was rewriting the rules and he said, you know, we've never needed to use the previous question rule in the book because we hear everyone, we hear those perspectives, we take a vote, and we go forward, so we don't need the previous question, and it was dropped from the rule book.
Speaker 2: And when I hear folks say the Senate never had a simple majority to close debate, they had the Senate code, and they had a rule, and then they said we don't need the rule because we have the Senate code.
Speaker 2: And that code continued to endure, which the full understanding of the members of this chamber was.
Speaker 2: they had no right to prevent the Senate from getting to a final vote.
Speaker 2: That code was so powerful that in the mid-1800s, when senators started to speak at length in order to make it very difficult to get to a final vote, the press called it piracy.
Speaker 2: You may wonder, where did that term filibuster come from?
Speaker 2: That term is a corruption of the term freebooter, the term for piracy.
Speaker 2: The piracy was senators breaking the Senate code.
Speaker 2: That was the piracy.
Speaker 2: But still, it happened on rare occasion, and the code was stretched, but not really broken through the 1800s, except on civil rights.
Speaker 2: And what happened in our history on civil rights?
Speaker 2: Well, you had John C. Calhoun leading the nullification movement that said, hey, states don't have to accept any given federal law.
Speaker 2: They can choose and pick which ones they want.
Speaker 2: And initially, that nullification movement was in order to block laws that put tariffs on imported products that strengthened the North and cost more funds to the South, increased the prices of goods.
Speaker 2: But then it turned to the question of protecting slavery, and nullification continued and even went so far as to say states should have the right to succeed if they don't like those federal laws.
Speaker 2: And then we had a civil war over that question, and that was the end of nullification.
Speaker 2: But it was not the end of attack on civil rights.
Speaker 2: So what did we see after the Civil War?
Speaker 2: We saw a group of states make it harder for individuals to register to vote.
Speaker 2: We saw a group of states make it hard for black Americans to get public accommodations.
Speaker 2: We saw a group of states make it easier to re-enslave black Americans under the black codes utilizing the slavery clause of the 13th amendment.
Speaker 2: And Congress responded.
Speaker 2: The House responded.
Speaker 2: This Senate responded and said, no, we are here to defend the Constitution, that every person is created equal, and every person's rights must be protected.
Speaker 2: That's what this chamber of the Senate did in 1875.
Speaker 2: The House passed the Civil Rights Act on public accommodations, guaranteeing access to all public accommodations for all Americans.
Speaker 2: The House voted 152 to 99, and it came to the Senate, and the Senate voted 38-26, simple majority.
Speaker 2: Although there were senators here who desperately hated public accommodation bills, because it would end discrimination in the South, they did not filibuster because the Senate code said after all views are heard, you can hold a simple majority vote.
Speaker 2: The Senate code held.
Speaker 2: But it didn't hold in 1891.
Speaker 2: In 1890, Henry Cabot Lodge, down the hall in the House, introduced what became known as the Lodge Bill, and it said, in order to protect the foundation of
Speaker 0: our nation, there
Speaker 2: can be federal supervision upon request to make sure registration is fair, to make sure the voting process is fair, and to make sure the counting process is fair.
Speaker 2: And the bill came here to the Senate, and a bipartisan group filibustered that bill of Southern Democrats and Western senators known as the Silver Senators, and they were anxious to get on to a bill about silver coinage, support the silver mining in the West, and that bill was eventually tabled.
Speaker 2: 1891, the Senate code was broken on civil rights and continued to be broken through.
Speaker 2: 1922, the Dyer Anti-Lynching Act, it was filibustered.
Speaker 2: 1934, the Cossack and Wagner Anti-Lynching Act, it was filibustered.
Speaker 2: 1942, the anti-poll tax bill that put a price on being able to access the ballot box, it was filibustered.
Speaker 2: And on and on.
Speaker 2: With the exception of a one-week delay in a bill for arming commercial ships in 1917, virtually every filibuster was to deny black Americans the right to vote, because in lieu of nullification, there had to be a strategy for certain senators to make sure that black Americans didn't get their civil rights.
Speaker 2: That is the sorry chapter of that part of our American history.
Speaker 2: Three generations through 1965 paid the price of denied opportunities.
Speaker 2: The Senate code on every other issue essentially survived until 1971 within our lifetimes.
Speaker 2: 1975, '71, we started to see the filibuster go to not just one or two filibusters a year, but to 12, a dozen, imagine that.
Speaker 2: And 1974 to '32, and that was just so outrageous, because each one takes up a week, and so this Senate said that is unacceptable, so we must reform the rules, and it led to the March 1975 rule reform where they went from two-thirds of those voting to 60 members voting.
Speaker 2: Well, the result is that law backfired.
Speaker 2: To quickly look at it, cloture on amendments, each one taking up a week, expanded from some six times an entire decade in the 1960s to 143 times in the 2010s.
Speaker 2: From motion to proceed, which is the ability to prevent debate from ever happening.
Speaker 2: So the filibuster promote debate was used to kill debate on the motion to proceed.
Speaker 2: It was used ten times in the 1960s, 175 times in the 2010s.
Speaker 2: And on nominations, it went from once in the 1960s to 545 times in the 2010s.
Speaker 2: And how did it happen that it expanded in the 2010s?
Speaker 2: Well, it happened because the Republican majority, Republican minority, decided that they were going to obstruct as many of President Obama's nominations as possible.
Speaker 2: And the Democrats did the same thing to President Trump.
Speaker 2: Each one of these takes up a week, an intervening day, 30 hours of debate, another hour of debate for every other senator who wants to speak.
Speaker 2: who didn't get to.
Speaker 2: Every single one.
Speaker 2: So when you have over 100 of these a year, it is impossible to have a Senate that works.
Speaker 2: The Senate has been broken.
Speaker 2: And perhaps the top champion of breaking the Senate is a minority leader who has engaged in the tactic of delaying obstruction, arguing.
Speaker 2: he wanted to make sure his top priority was making sure President Obama was never reelected and stopping him from having an agenda and stopping him from putting people into office was the strategy.
Speaker 2: And Democrats took much the same approach to President Trump.
Speaker 2: So we have both done it, but the Senate is blowing up now.
Speaker 2: You know, that original Congress, the Senate, first term, it said there were about four cabinet members to confirm, plus ambassadors and some judges, four.
Speaker 2: We have over 1,000 positions now.
Speaker 2: It's completely out of sync.
Speaker 2: The gears don't match.
Speaker 2: And every time there's a filibuster or a nomination, it's another week lost.
Speaker 2: So the Senate is now paralyzed.
Speaker 2: Because here is the interesting prospect and the unfortunate reality of 60 votes.
Speaker 2: The interesting prospect is that a majority of less than 60 has to reach out to the minority to get something done.
Speaker 2: And that sounds like it's going to increase cooperation and negotiation.
Speaker 2: But the unfortunate reality in our tribal partisan politics is the minority looks at that and says, if we can hold 41 senators from agreeing to close debate, we can paralyze the majority.
Speaker 2: That is the overwhelming impact is paralysis and accentuation of partisanship of our current filibuster.
Speaker 2: Today's debate, it's not about a filibuster versus no filibuster.
Speaker 2: It's about fixing a broken Senate.
Speaker 2: It's about the difference, as my colleague from Virginia has said, from the secret no show filibuster to the public talking filibuster.
Speaker 2: Before 1975, people who wanted to extend debate had to actually debate.
Speaker 2: what a notion they had to show up.
Speaker 2: And that is painful and difficult to maintain continuous debate.
Speaker 2: And so there's an incentive to negotiate.
Speaker 2: But when there's a no show, no effort filibuster where those who say they want to debate are off on vacation because 60 votes is required with or without them, there's no incentive to negotiate.
Speaker 2: So if you believe the Senate should be a place that encourages negotiation, we need a public filibuster, not a secret, silent filibuster.
Speaker 2: If you believe that the public should be able to participate in our process, we need not a secret, silent filibuster, but a public filibuster.
Speaker 2: We're here, day after day, week after week, we're debating the issue, we're raising amendments, we're considering amendments.
Speaker 2: And what is the result?
Speaker 2: The citizens weigh in, they say finally they're considering it.
Speaker 2: Finally, they're debating it.
Speaker 2: Finally, they're going to take a debate.
Speaker 2: Now we can weigh in effectively in this moment.
Speaker 2: So this is about restoring, reinvigorating debate, restoring the public role, creating an incentive to negotiate, creating an incentive for both sides to work to reach an accommodation.
Speaker 2: Now, my Republican friends have made much today of Democrats signing a letter saying that they are determined to, quote, preserve the ability of members to engage in extended debate -- interesting.
Speaker 2: Preserve the ability of members to engage in extended debate.
Speaker 2: The ability to preserve the ability to engage in extended debate means we need the talking public filibuster, not the secret, silent filibuster, which requires no debate at all.
Speaker 2: So to my Republican colleagues who signed this letter, this is your opportunity to do what you said -- vote for the principle that the majority leader is going to be laying out forthwith.
Speaker 2: So colleagues, if you believe in the Founders' vision of this Senate, of hearing everyone and hearing everyone well, but eventually getting to a final vote, if you believe in the Senate code, which stood up for so long, not even needing a rule to enforce it, except for civil rights, it held up through 1971, if you want more debate, and you want people who want to debate to have to show up to debate, support the talking filibuster.
Speaker 2: If you believe there should be an incentive for both the majority and the minority to negotiate, support the talking filibuster.
Speaker 2: If you believe the public should have the ability to see us debating issues, then support the talking filibuster.
Speaker 2: And my colleagues have said we must defend the minority leverage.
Speaker 2: Amen to that.
Speaker 2: That is why in 2011 I put forward in this chamber the talking filibuster and said we need to defend the minority's right to participate.
Speaker 2: Today we have another opportunity to defend the minority's participation, to speak at length for at least twice on any given question on through a complex bill.
Speaker 2: But that, colleagues, depends upon ending the era of the secret, silent source of partisanship and paralysis that we currently have and replacing it with the talking public filibuster.
Speaker 2: I encourage you all to stand today for the Senate to work and for the Senate, most importantly, to defend the fundamental rights of every American to access the ballot box.