Speaker 0: It's Monday, June 27th, 2022.
Speaker 0: I'm Rym.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight we are talking about refrigeration technology.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: And finally, we are free.
Speaker 0: Hockey is over.
Speaker 0: I don't have to think about, "Oh, when's the next hockey
Speaker 0: game?"
Speaker 0: Until, uh... For a little while.
Speaker 1: Four months?
Speaker 1: Three or four months?
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: And all I'll say is, you know what, I was rooting for the Avalanche because, one, they were gonna win anyway.
Speaker 0: Like, that path was determined.
Speaker 0: Round one showed me the way.
Speaker 1: I mean, I thought they were gonna win since early in the regular season.
Speaker 1: But, on the other hand, it's like, you know, none of these, either team, neither one was a team that I hated or had bad people on it.
Speaker 1: You know, that I was aware of or anything.
Speaker 0: Though, what's funny is, right around this time, you see that ESPN has that big documentary about, basically, the hockey era of my childhood, the Red Wings-Avalanche rivalry.
Speaker 1: Yeah, 'cause they've went against each other several years.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: But it's no longer a rivalry.
Speaker 0: Like, the teams don't give a shit about each other.
Speaker 0: Like, the hockey's very different now, but...
Speaker 1: Well, divisions change and all sorts of stuff, right?
Speaker 0: But, I'm very happy that the Rangers made it as far as the conference finals.
Speaker 0: Nothing to cry about.
Speaker 1: They did not think we were gonna make it there.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And now, this is one of those teams, Rangers have got a few years of "stay this good and just keep trying for a
Speaker 0: cup.".
Speaker 0: And maybe it'll happen, maybe it won't, but...
Speaker 1: The problem is, is like, the Rangers are quite good, you know, but you look at these teams, like the Avalanche specifically, right?
Speaker 1: And it's like, you could just see, they're so far ahead of the other teams.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, if the average team is a strength of five, right?
Speaker 1: The Rangers might have a strength of seven and a half or eight.
Speaker 1: And there's a lot of teams with a similar strength of seven and a half, eight, nine, right?
Speaker 1: But the Avalanche have a strength of like, eleven or twelve.
Speaker 0: Well, I think, so I read a bunch...
Speaker 1: And nobody else is like, you know, up there.
Speaker 1: It's like, well...
Speaker 0: I read a bunch of analysis of people trying to say like, what's the deal?
Speaker 0: Like, what exactly is happening?
Speaker 0: And there actually are pretty common themes, even among a bunch of people who normally disagree with each other.
Speaker 0: But they seem to come down to more depth in the team, like better coordination among the lines, like really just basic stuff.
Speaker 0: But also, everyone made the point that they are proof that you do not need a good goalie to be a good NHL team.
Speaker 1: Well, you have to have an okay goalie.
Speaker 0: Oh no, but I saw people pointing out that people making an argument that they didn't even need a good goalie.
Speaker 0: Their goalie didn't even actually have to deal with that many shots.
Speaker 1: I mean, yeah, that's definitely part of it, right?
Speaker 1: You know, but he did, he was slightly subpar, right?
Speaker 1: I think he let in like a few over expected, but it's not like he was awful or terrible or anything.
Speaker 1: If you had a terrible goalie, so many more, you know, he did make saves, they would have gone in if you had a terrible goalie, right?
Speaker 0: But look, Vasilevski and Shasturkin, two of the best goalies in the game right now.
Speaker 0: And yet, I think we have discovered, as we talked about before when we were in for this matchup, we were about to see the immovable object versus the unstoppable force.
Speaker 0: Turns out an unstoppable force will beat an immovable object every time in hockey.
Speaker 1: Right, because even the greatest goalie, they're not a superhuman who can just stop every single shot no matter how ridiculous, right?
Speaker 1: So therefore, it's, you know, it's like if you have the best goalie in the universe, but the rest of your team isn't good enough, the other team is going to get a million shots.
Speaker 1: And even though only 0.05% of them go in, it's like they just make enough shots.
Speaker 1: and they make good enough ones, they're going to go in.
Speaker 1: And if your team can't get into the offensive zone, you can't score goals and the other team could just beat you 1-0.
Speaker 1: It could happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I did see one argument though that Colorado has the extra X factor of their high elevation team.
Speaker 1: So I think that's, I think there's some, you know, it's not completely without merit, but I think it is nonsense because if that was the case, we would see Colorado teams in all athletic sports winning more often on average.
Speaker 0: Not necessarily because that type of, like, the equivalent of doping, it's basically natural doping.
Speaker 0: Doping meaning putting extra red blood cells in, essentially.
Speaker 0: That only primarily benefits you in extreme endurance sports, but not in, like, other kinds of explosive action sports.
Speaker 0: The point, we don't see people who come from higher elevations doing better on average in, like, foot races and many types of track and field events.
Speaker 1: The best track and field people are all from, like, you know, Nigeria.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but statistically, of course, there are individuals who can overcome anything like that, but overall, high elevation training is effective at certain kinds of sports.
Speaker 0: But anyway, hockey's done.
Speaker 0: Don't have to worry about hockey anymore.
Speaker 0: I heard you got a plant.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, so I had, you know, I had a lot of house plants, right?
Speaker 1: But the thing with the house plants is that, you know, it's hard to, if you just, you know, buy plants and it's, like, at a random place, you know, just say, "Oh, that plant looks nice.
Speaker 1: I'll buy
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 1: You don't know, A, what kind of plant it is specifically, how to take care of it.
Speaker 0: Maybe at best it's got that little card that gives you vague instructions that assume you know a lot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then it's, like, if you don't have, you know, a garage or a yard, it's, like, it's hard to take care of plants just in a pot in an apartment.
Speaker 1: It's, like, what are you going to do?
Speaker 1: You buy a bag of dirt?
Speaker 1: Where are you going to put a bag of dirt in an apartment?
Speaker 1: You don't have a, it's, like, We have a container.
Speaker 0: Remember the old Geek Nights container?
Speaker 0: That is currently on the balcony, and in that container is the bag of dirt and a bunch of other stuff like that.
Speaker 1: You have not wasted my balcony space on bag of dirt.
Speaker 0: Our balcony's huge, so it doesn't really take up any material about a space.
Speaker 1: The point is, is that it's a pain in the ass to do things like repotting plants or whatever.
Speaker 1: You know, there's nowhere to go to do that, right?
Speaker 1: So, uh, one of the things I planned to do during my time of not work, which has got a couple more weeks left, uh, was go take care of the houseplants because they're all alive, but some of them were falling over because they were too big for the pot.
Speaker 1: Some of them were alive but sad, you know, so I took them to this plant store, and the plant store was basically the ideal retail establishment, right?
Speaker 1: So, you know, we always talk about just buy shit online, it's cheaper, right, you know?
Speaker 0: Well, what we always say, we always said, unless you need to talk to an expert and the store you're going to will have an expert.
Speaker 1: Right, retail stores usually don't have experts, don't have good selection, don't have good prices, don't offer anything, right?
Speaker 1: But this particular plant store, I go in, and I, you know, I went up to the counter where, you know, this woman was sitting, and I, you know, but she, you know, didn't seem like she wanted to help me.
Speaker 1: She seemed like she was, right, like working and cashiering and that sort of thing, and like she didn't want a customer service very much.
Speaker 1: And it turns out this other person in the store, this broey dude, who I didn't, who I just thought was a customer, was actually the owner.
Speaker 1: And he was, you know, it's like you look at this guy, and if you had seen this dude in any other setting, the street, you know, the park, anywhere, you'd think he was just some broey dude who was, you know, gonna get drunk, party, drive a fart car, right?
Speaker 0: And he might be.
Speaker 1: Right, in New York too.
Speaker 1: But this dude was the owner of a plant store and an enormous plant nerd, like plant nerd the way that we're a computer nerd, right?
Speaker 1: And he was so happy, right?
Speaker 1: It's like what he was doing would have normally counted as mansplaining, if not the fact that I was specifically asking for the explanation.
Speaker 0: It's funny, we had the same experience recently.
Speaker 0: There's a little plant store that has a lot of succulents near us, like by the huntress.
Speaker 0: Same deal, the people in there know everything.
Speaker 0: They're like mega plant nerds.
Speaker 1: Right, this dude is a huge plant nerd, you know, and he repotted my plants, and he's like, "Oh, you gotta get some fertilizer for this
Speaker 1: one.".
Speaker 1: And he's like, "You should get this
Speaker 1: kind.".
Speaker 1: And I'm like, "Do you sell
Speaker 1: that?".
Speaker 1: And he's like, "No, I don't sell
Speaker 1: that.".
Speaker 0: That's the surest sign of a real expert in a store, if they will recommend things that they don't even sell.
Speaker 1: And I was like, "Yeah, this plant came with this kind of dirt, but I had to switch it to this kind of dirt because I couldn't find the kind of dirt it came
Speaker 1: with.".
Speaker 1: And he's like, "I make my own
Speaker 1: dirt.".
Speaker 1: Alright, but he repotted my plants, and I bought a new plant there, and I got some newer pots, and now my houseplant situation is all very nice now.
Speaker 0: I think there's something to this ongoing belief and assumption and pop culture idea that millennials are obsessed with plants.
Speaker 1: Houseplant popularity is actually way up, which is probably why stores like that are successful.
Speaker 1: People got plants in their houses, you know.
Speaker 1: They want more, you know.
Speaker 1: People want plants when they had offices.
Speaker 1: You know, every office I've ever worked in, people are always having plants at the desk, right?
Speaker 0: I wonder if we're allowed to have plants that are desks.
Speaker 0: I've never seen one at anyone's desk.
Speaker 1: Really, never?
Speaker 1: I've never not seen one.
Speaker 0: I mean, our desks are tiny at work.
Speaker 1: I guess my past three jobs, which is going back, you know, a long time because I kept the jobs for a long time each, but that's like 15 years' worth.
Speaker 1: People always had plants.
Speaker 0: The only thing on my desk is one little goomba.
Speaker 1: The only thing on my desk now is nothing.
Speaker 1: I don't have an office desk anymore.
Speaker 1: I just have this.
Speaker 1: This is my only desk.
Speaker 1: I got one.
Speaker 0: Get in the news.
Speaker 0: One non-tech news, but we can't not talk about it.
Speaker 0: Of course, go read Real News to find out more.
Speaker 0: If you're hearing about this from Geek Nights, once again, I don't know what to say except go read something.
Speaker 1: Maybe they're from another country or something.
Speaker 1: You know, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you're in the US and you're hearing about this from us, shame on you.
Speaker 0: But if you're outside the US, this has grave portents for other countries, too.
Speaker 0: This is a big problem.
Speaker 0: Basically, of course, the US Supreme Court has been compromised because the traitor guy who took over our government in an illegitimate election in 2016 cheated and appointed a bunch of people to our court.
Speaker 0: If you're not familiar with the American courts, basically our Supreme Court is invincible.
Speaker 0: The people on it are appointed for life and there is zero accountability and supreme power.
Speaker 0: And we're kind of screwed right now because there's no way to kick someone off the Supreme Court.
Speaker 1: You can impeach them, but it's basically impossible.
Speaker 0: It requires a supermajority in our Senate, which is 50% controlled by the fascists and unable to be changed significantly for reasons.
Speaker 1: So we're in deep shit and they've basically- At least if you agree to follow the rules that are written in the Constitution.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which that would be a coup.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying- Which we're still doing.
Speaker 1: We're still doing for now, right?
Speaker 0: To a degree.
Speaker 0: The Department of Justice and the military effectively said that they're going to ignore state laws and make sure that service members can get whatever health care they need, which is a start.
Speaker 1: But if it's on federal land, then there's nothing they could do.
Speaker 0: But basically what this means is about half of the American states either have now or will imminently ban basically all abortions.
Speaker 0: And the other half of America's states are enshrining the right to abortions in their own constitutions.
Speaker 0: And the Republican Party in our country has said pretty much straight up that if they take back the government, they're going to ban it nationally.
Speaker 0: They're going to pass a law that just bans it in all 50 states.
Speaker 1: So the only way- Oh, but we could just filibuster that forever the same as they do.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: If they pass it, they could overturn the filibuster because you only need 51 votes to overturn the filibuster and change the rules.
Speaker 0: Well, we don't have 51 votes.
Speaker 0: We have 48 Democratic senators and two traitors.
Speaker 0: So basically the only legal thing you can do if you're not down for a coup, other than protesting and harm mitigation, is effectively in the
Speaker 0: U.S.,
Speaker 0: we got to pick up at least one net seat in the Senate in the 2022 election.
Speaker 0: Because a lot of people on the left who are screaming and freaking out are also kind of yelling at the wrong people in one specific regard.
Speaker 0: Our Senate voted in May to overturn the filibuster and enshrine a basic form of abortion rights nationally, which would undermine this rule.
Speaker 0: That bill went down 49 to 51.
Speaker 0: One piece of shit.
Speaker 0: Democratic senator, Joe Manchin, voted against it.
Speaker 0: Meaning if we pick up even one seat, we should be able to do the exact same vote and it would get through the filibuster on a technicality.
Speaker 0: So that's what we can do.
Speaker 0: And the most likely one is Pennsylvania, where the cool guy is running.
Speaker 0: Betterment.
Speaker 1: But even if we do that, you know, we have to keep that because at any moment, if the other side takes over the government, they could just pass the opposite law.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Well, once we get that, the other next step is we got to either pack the court or abolish the Supreme Court or do something.
Speaker 0: We got to do something egregious, which is possible.
Speaker 0: Packing the court is something FDR threatened to do.
Speaker 0: It's doable, but it requires getting rid of the filibuster.
Speaker 1: FDR was not a perfect individual.
Speaker 0: Not saying he was, but in that regard...
Speaker 1: He had guts to tell you.
Speaker 1: this is what I want to happen and he made it happen, right?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So we'll see.
Speaker 0: At least one more Democrat has to be in the Senate for anything to happen.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, it's just, you know, the same crisis that's been happening for a long time continues to happen.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: The American population is concentrated into a handful of states and the rest of the empty land gets overrepresented in our government because our Constitution is...
Speaker 1: It's been this way since before we were born and we're still alive and...
Speaker 0: Our Constitution is old and crufty.
Speaker 0: And if you notice, we haven't amended it in a long time, except for trivial stuff.
Speaker 0: It's starting to run out of steam, that thing.
Speaker 1: Oh, what are we going to do?
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: So I encourage you to read more about this and look at what options you have for doing something about it.
Speaker 0: And if you're against abortion, I don't know what to get.
Speaker 0: Stop listening to geek nights.
Speaker 0: Like, what are you even doing here?
Speaker 0: So in other news that is not that, you know, Geek Nights Monday technology, Google is actually both of our newses.
Speaker 0: Google is shutting down hangouts, which I feel like they have announced...
Speaker 1: That's not news.
Speaker 1: We knew this was announced a long time ago.
Speaker 0: I feel like this has been announced at least half a dozen times in some form.
Speaker 1: They keep, you know, changing their fucking minds over there.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like it's bad enough to start things and then, you know, get users and then turn them off.
Speaker 1: It's another thing to like, you know, not just turn something off, but to like transition to other products and change branding.
Speaker 1: And because now not only are you hurting people by turning off a thing that they've come to depend on, but you're now also confusing people, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, having allo and duo and chat and we are we are.
Speaker 0: we are terminally online technologists who have been doing a podcast for like 15 years on technology.
Speaker 0: And yet I have to go look up what the fuck Google is doing and what app does what in this ecosystem.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It seems like they're finally getting everything in order and that I don't know what the time frame on this is, but when all is said and done, they are going to have all of the text chatting consolidated into Google Chat, which will be a product that is somewhere in between like a Slack and a, you know, Hangout DM thing.
Speaker 1: But no one's really going to use it, basically.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't even use Hangouts or any of this anymore.
Speaker 1: We used to use it, but then, you know, I stopped using it years ago when they basically fucked it up.
Speaker 1: And then that was it.
Speaker 0: I moved everything into Discord.
Speaker 1: I don't know anyone who.
Speaker 1: the only time I've seen it used recently is that, you know, if you were from working at companies, the companies I've worked for recently have used, you know, the Google Chat.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, as sort of like the backup if Slack goes down.
Speaker 1: So even if the companies have Google, you know, workspaces, you know, for their email, it's like they're only using that for email.
Speaker 1: They're not using that for chatting on a regular basis.
Speaker 1: They have Slack, right?
Speaker 1: My ring light is having a problem with USB cable.
Speaker 1: USB cable is flaky.
Speaker 0: Basically, when Google Hangouts started like breaking and all the problems happened, that's basically when I jumped ship to Discord.
Speaker 0: Today, I'd say that 80 percent of the people who want to talk to me just DM me on Discord or talk to me in a Discord.
Speaker 0: Another like 10 percent still SMS me.
Speaker 0: A handful of people, including my mom, Twitter DM me and everything else is email.
Speaker 0: And that's it.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's this is a sort of a fundamental thing.
Speaker 0: I guess I roll SMS and signal together because they work the same way.
Speaker 0: Like it doesn't matter which one's which when someone messages me.
Speaker 1: The point is, is that any service in which requires any platform in which users make accounts.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It becomes basically trivial for that service to add a feature which allows users to direct message each other.
Speaker 1: And even if that service is not a messaging service, that is, you know, where that is the primary use of it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It becomes also a necessary and helpful feature.
Speaker 1: So let's say you have, I don't know, eBay.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: eBay's primary feature is buying and selling shit.
Speaker 1: But if you're going to have a transaction with someone, it becomes useful and necessary to have some sort of way to message that person and come and converse with a person that you were having a transaction.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Like Uber.
Speaker 0: All the problems with Uber.
Speaker 0: None of us said you got to be able to chat with the person who's picking you up in case like, wait, what intersection are you at?
Speaker 0: You know, confusion.
Speaker 0: Airbnb.
Speaker 0: Like there are good reasons for this in terms of if you have a conversation through the Airbnb platform, then the company has a record of that in case there's fraud or malfeasance.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of reasons why this makes sense.
Speaker 0: But now to your point, I have all these like messaging systems that each have a very specific purpose.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, it's like.
Speaker 1: so what happens is there's all these DM platforms everywhere and people will just start using one and the platforms that used to exist that whose sole purpose was text messaging.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Other than SMS, all the other ones have really kind of bitten it right in favor of things that are also something else.
Speaker 1: You know, even your even your WhatsApp apps and things of that nature, it's like they're also sort of like a group chat thing.
Speaker 1: And they all right.
Speaker 1: Or, you know, it's like.
Speaker 1: Facebook is also Facebook Messenger and Instagram as DMS.
Speaker 1: And even though it was primarily a photo thing originally, at least, you know, it's like so those end up getting all the users.
Speaker 1: And then, you know, things like Google Hangout is right falling over.
Speaker 0: So, yep.
Speaker 0: So along those lines, even in more news, Google is combining duo, which I guess somehow still existed.
Speaker 0: I remember I installed duo.
Speaker 0: It didn't work with domains at the time.
Speaker 0: So I never.
Speaker 0: I never used it even once.
Speaker 1: I mean, that was the last time they tried to do this.
Speaker 1: They made that aloe in the duo and were like, OK, I forgot about aloe.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It lasted five minutes.
Speaker 0: You know, whatever they launch them at like the same time.
Speaker 0: And I did.
Speaker 1: That was the idea is that that was the original attempt was to replace hang out with aloe and duo.
Speaker 1: And now they're basically they're going to have chat and they're going to have meat, which already meat is the only thing that Google has.
Speaker 1: I think that's going to actually have sustained usage because any company that even a company that uses Google workspaces and pays for it is going to be using Slack or Microsoft Teams or something.
Speaker 1: They're not going to be using the Google chat.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But the Google meet companies use that except for companies that might pay extra and use Zoom instead.
Speaker 1: The actual the best ones.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Still, to this day, I still believe that I message and especially FaceTime are the best as a product.
Speaker 1: But they only work if everyone has an Apple device and therefore they're never going to be a solution for pretty much anyone.
Speaker 0: I used I only recently got an Apple device.
Speaker 0: And even today, the vast majority of people I interact with online do not have even one Apple device.
Speaker 1: But even if they do have an Apple device, it's like as soon as you have one person who doesn't.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So it's like maybe the only people you talk to in your life are your family and they all have Apple devices, in which case it's going to be fantastic for you.
Speaker 1: It's going to be amazing.
Speaker 1: Maybe every single friend you have, you're a high school student and all of your friends have iPhones, literally everybody.
Speaker 1: And you don't have a single person who doesn't have one.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's going to be fantastic for you to use iMessage and FaceTime.
Speaker 1: Life is going to be great.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But if you have just if you have online friends, if you're a connected person or if you're if you have friends in the community.
Speaker 1: You go to say, I don't know, a club or a volunteer group or a religious organization or a city council community or any kind of social group that you interact with.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: A bowling league.
Speaker 1: There's going to be at some point along the way, there's going to be people who are not using it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And it ends up being that the universal platforms that work, no matter what computer or device someone has.
Speaker 1: Even if they're shittier.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Zoom is shittier.
Speaker 1: And FaceTime, it's going to win.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And so Google Meet is really good.
Speaker 1: If you have a company and everyone's using Google Workspaces, everyone can use Google Meet and it works for in company stuff.
Speaker 1: But as soon as you have to interact with another company at that company is not using Google Workspaces also.
Speaker 1: Guess what?
Speaker 1: Now your company is also going to use Zoom to interact with the other companies.
Speaker 0: I haven't at least found that Zoom has displaced almost everything else.
Speaker 0: And I find that every professional interaction I have is Zoom now.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And then your company is going to be like, well, we have to interact with people outside the company and use Zoom.
Speaker 1: Then why the fuck are we going to use Google Meet for internal and Zoom for external?
Speaker 1: Let's just use Zoom for everything.
Speaker 1: That way we're using less things.
Speaker 1: And then you're not using Google Meet anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So I think that's the fundamental thing Google has to do.
Speaker 0: The sad thing, though, is...
Speaker 1: It's products out there.
Speaker 1: I think it's sort of lost because, like, you know, it's like this.
Speaker 1: Are people even using Gmail anymore?
Speaker 1: Like who need email?
Speaker 0: Well, because no one sends emails.
Speaker 0: I increasingly find that and not from an old person complaining if you should use email for everything, that's ridiculous.
Speaker 0: But email is good if you want to send someone like a whole ass page of text.
Speaker 0: And I have people who will like SMS me a long thread.
Speaker 0: that could have just been one email.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: But I'm saying it's like, you know, if there are people who are new... You know, we have Gmail because... Right.
Speaker 1: Like if I had to start using email today, I wouldn't choose Gmail.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Not a chance.
Speaker 1: The reason I use Gmail is because back in the day I had college email.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And at the time, everyone using the email their ISP gave them, whether that was the college or whatever, AOL or, you know, something.
Speaker 1: And then we entered the next period where it's like you weren't dependent.
Speaker 1: Your ISP could no longer give you services.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Because they couldn't compete with the services like the ones that were provided by, you know, web apps.
Speaker 1: So people moved to Gmail.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But now it's like, you know, at the time, Gmail was the only one.
Speaker 1: That was the game.
Speaker 0: I would probably still use Gmail today because I'm thinking about all the alternatives and I would probably just get a Gmail account.
Speaker 1: I would use maybe the iCloud email or there's some other ones out there that are that are good options also.
Speaker 0: Not a ton though.
Speaker 0: You start scraping the bottom of the barrel pretty quick.
Speaker 1: If I only had to choose between Microsoft, Google, Apple, I guess Facebook doesn't give out email.
Speaker 0: In that situation, I guess I might go with Microsoft.
Speaker 0: if I didn't go with Gmail.
Speaker 1: I would choose the Apple one.
Speaker 1: Of those three choices, I would choose the Apple with if I didn't have any existing anything.
Speaker 1: The Apple one is the easy choice for sure.
Speaker 0: Of course, I didn't have an iPhone until recently.
Speaker 1: I'm just you know, even if I had no devices at all.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Just choosing only the email app and not any.
Speaker 1: nothing else is set yet with the Apple one.
Speaker 0: But I got to say, good lord.
Speaker 0: Now that not that Covid is winding down, but as I've interacted with humans again a little more frequently, I am reminded that outside of my close circles, if you ask someone how you can get in touch with them, I have found that a lot of people don't actually have a good answer anymore.
Speaker 0: Like non-online people aren't really sure and they'll mumble something about Facebook or maybe they have a cell phone number.
Speaker 0: They'll give you a text and that's about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because like they're really only, you know, communicating frequently.
Speaker 1: You know, they don't have an online presence where they're communicating with lots of people.
Speaker 1: It's like they only.
Speaker 1: it's like how did they communicate with their family?
Speaker 1: Maybe they are one of those Apple only families that all FaceTimes each other.
Speaker 1: But it's like, how do I get in touch with you?
Speaker 1: Well, they're not going to give you their fucking FaceTime.
Speaker 1: That's not how it's going to.
Speaker 1: you're not going to.
Speaker 1: you just have to send them a quick message.
Speaker 1: They don't have a personal email that they're checking right constantly.
Speaker 1: They're not an online person.
Speaker 0: I mean, I give people my direct Discord, but a lot of people don't.
Speaker 0: Discord is terrifying and confusing to them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're not going to make and they have to make an account for it.
Speaker 1: Which they're not going to do just to talk to one person.
Speaker 0: I would advise everyone.
Speaker 0: as a total aside and related to the first news we talked about.
Speaker 0: I would suggest installing Signal and just setting it up even if you don't use it.
Speaker 0: Signal is...
Speaker 1: I have it.
Speaker 1: I have it set up and never use it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you set it up and never use it, it will.
Speaker 0: If you message someone else who has Signal, then you'll have end to end encryption.
Speaker 0: Like it's it's legit and it works.
Speaker 0: And that might be useful depending on how things go.
Speaker 1: I don't think that.
Speaker 1: I don't think that works like that.
Speaker 1: If you just use the iPhone messages app, it's not just going to be like...
Speaker 0: I use the Signal app.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I use the iPhone messages app.
Speaker 0: No, you got to use the Signal app or it doesn't do shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, that's that's that's not.
Speaker 1: and, you know, I installed it and I don't use it.
Speaker 0: No, see, I installed it and I actually do use it.
Speaker 0: I use it.
Speaker 0: I replaced SMS with it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, iMessages is also end to end encrypted.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: So I'm linked to a tweet because the tweet links to a video, but the tweet also gives some context.
Speaker 0: The video is in German.
Speaker 0: It won't matter that much.
Speaker 0: It doesn't actually matter what they're saying.
Speaker 0: It looks like there's subtitles in multiple languages.
Speaker 0: But my thing of the day is a video where there is a 15th century bath house in Germany and it has been restored.
Speaker 1: So a late medieval bath house.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it has been restored and renovated to be fully functional and period correct.
Speaker 0: And it's a museum.
Speaker 0: And this video is two naked German guys taking you through the full experience.
Speaker 0: And I got to tell you, bath houses are something super cool that I wish Americans respected more.
Speaker 0: And I wish we had destroyed all of them at the end of the 20s and 30s.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So I think we've done an episode on sound cards a long time ago, but for people who aren't aware.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, computers originally all the only sound they had was beep beep.
Speaker 1: And then, you know, the motherboard didn't have any sound audio facilities on it.
Speaker 1: You had to put a card in your computer that had synthesizers and other sorts of audio chips on it.
Speaker 0: You probably got an ad lib card.
Speaker 0: Maybe you got a sound blaster.
Speaker 1: And so, you know, right.
Speaker 1: So some, you know, when it comes to playing record, fully recorded audio samples like MP3s, WAV files, anything like that.
Speaker 1: It doesn't really matter what sound card it is because you have the exact wave that is going to be played is recorded and then played.
Speaker 1: But the earliest computers and consoles could not do that because the amount of memory it would take to store a high fidelity audio sample of any length before we invented MP3s and processors fast enough to decompress them quickly, you know, was vast.
Speaker 1: And you didn't have a lot of storage space in early computers.
Speaker 1: And so that didn't work out.
Speaker 1: So what you do is put a synthesizer in your computer and then it took a very little space to just basically have the equivalent of digital sheet music or even just, you know, a program that would generate, you know, sheet music effectively in, you know, as it processed to instruct the synthesizer.
Speaker 1: Basically, it's like a keyboard without any keys.
Speaker 1: And there's a processor that pushes the keys electronically.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And because of that, every computer and every sound card sounded differently.
Speaker 1: The Commodore 64 sounded great.
Speaker 1: You know, some old Apple computers could really just go.
Speaker 1: You know, but there are people with nostalgia and there are people with preservation interests and people with, you know, various reasons would want to have, you know, those exact or as close enough to it.
Speaker 1: The exact synthesizers that were in those old sound cards so that they could, you know, use old software and hear exactly what it sounded like back in the day.
Speaker 1: Create music that is retro.
Speaker 1: So many reasons that you would want an old sound card and old sound cards.
Speaker 1: Not necessarily easy to acquire.
Speaker 1: There just might not be a lot of them.
Speaker 1: They might not be a lot of them that work.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: They might not.
Speaker 1: Even if you buy a Sound Blaster 16 and you find one that inbox mint inbox.
Speaker 1: Guess what?
Speaker 1: That shits an ISA card and your computer does not have an ISA slot.
Speaker 0: Your computer doesn't even have a PCI slot.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So, yeah.
Speaker 1: So it's like, well, how are you going to hook that up to your computer?
Speaker 1: You probably could find a way, some sort of adapter, some and write a bunch of drivers or get an old computer also.
Speaker 1: But that sucks.
Speaker 1: So here we have somebody who in 2019 compiled this forum post, the comprehensive list of all modern reproductions of vintage sound cards.
Speaker 1: And it's exactly what it is.
Speaker 1: It's a comprehensive list of modern reproductions of classic sound cards.
Speaker 1: And they've updated this list as recently as May 2022.
Speaker 1: So just, you know, last month.
Speaker 1: So they just been updating this forum post.
Speaker 1: And it's like, yep, you can get some creative music system, Yamaha, YMF262.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Sound Blaster's crystal, whatever is all kinds of different, terrifying urge to spin up the old Sound Blaster all 32.
Speaker 1: But, you know, here are, you know, some of these are actually people who have produced boards for sale.
Speaker 1: Some of them are plans for boards that you can like put together yourself, all sorts of things here.
Speaker 1: But if you're interested in, you know, replicating the sounds of old computers with new computers, this is the link for you to click on.
Speaker 0: In the moment, the Geek Nights Book Club book, Nine Fox Gambit.
Speaker 0: We're done with it.
Speaker 0: The only reason we didn't do a show on Thursday is because we were busy.
Speaker 0: So and I think we're going to be busy on Wednesday.
Speaker 0: So no show on Wednesday this week.
Speaker 0: But next week on Thursday, even recorded in advance, that will be the Nine Fox Gambit show.
Speaker 0: We're done with the book.
Speaker 1: That'll be the last show before I have to start another job.
Speaker 1: Unless they decide to unhire me before I start.
Speaker 0: Exciting times.
Speaker 0: Legitimately exciting.
Speaker 0: But Nine Fox Gambit's real good.
Speaker 0: I got a lot to say about it.
Speaker 0: And we're not going to talk about the second book in that book club book episode.
Speaker 0: But I will say that having read most of the second book in the series, I'm going to finish the series.
Speaker 0: I mean, granted, I think you always finish the series.
Speaker 0: I was about to say, I don't think that was your rim series finisher.
Speaker 0: The cost.
Speaker 0: I was about to say, Scott was probably going to point out that with one exception, I've never not finished a series.
Speaker 0: I fucking read all four.
Speaker 1: Every single time I've made a book club selection, that was the first book of a series.
Speaker 1: Rim has gone on to finish that series and I have usually not done so.
Speaker 0: Wheel of Time, you followed a little further than I expected.
Speaker 1: I read, I don't know, it might have been four or five wheels of time.
Speaker 1: I don't know how many.
Speaker 1: There's at least a few.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, a month later, I was like, hey, I'm on book 13.
Speaker 0: And you were like, what?
Speaker 1: I've read every published Prince of Nothing book.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And I doubt there'll be any more, which I highly doubt there'll ever be any more.
Speaker 0: Little troublesome because I would like to know.
Speaker 0: But anyway.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: But I'm enjoying the Nine Fox Gambit.
Speaker 0: By Thursday, I got to pick what the next book club book is.
Speaker 0: I got a few ideas.
Speaker 0: As much as I want to pick it, I'm not going to pick Emily Wilson's newer translation of a different work.
Speaker 1: Because, well, I mean, yeah, it's like, you know, that's.
Speaker 1: I'm going to read that for sure.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm going to read that.
Speaker 1: The point is, is like, stop just picking sequels and things related to existing book club books.
Speaker 1: You know, it would be preferable to get variety.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: If every book club book was something, you know, going down a new road and not rehashing an old road.
Speaker 0: I will resist the urge, at least for one more cycle, to pick a nonfiction book, though.
Speaker 0: But I'm going to warn you now.
Speaker 0: My next book club book after this one will very likely be nonfiction.
Speaker 0: I love me some nonfiction.
Speaker 0: Don't worry, this will be fiction and maybe pulp.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm thinking.
Speaker 1: I'll just I'll just pick some computer book.
Speaker 1: That's not fiction, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, you could just read anything you pick.
Speaker 0: Just gives me the opportunity if I so be if I feel that it is justified to bust out my favorite count, the count.
Speaker 1: It's like, can I can I take structure and interpretation of computer programs as a book club book?
Speaker 0: I mean, if you do count of Monte Cristo is going to be the next book club book.
Speaker 0: And that book.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't know if you would understand what.
Speaker 1: the art of programming by Newt this book.
Speaker 1: Is that even going to work?
Speaker 0: If you pick that, what you know what?
Speaker 0: I could do some technical like Newton, NATO doctrine book or some bullshit.
Speaker 0: The stuff that I read for fun.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying you wouldn't understand it.
Speaker 0: I just don't think you'd like it.
Speaker 1: I'll be.
Speaker 1: you know, just, you know, if you want to humor me, I guess I'll just ask you to do this.
Speaker 1: I can't make that right.
Speaker 1: But go S.I.C.P.
Speaker 1: You can just read it for free.
Speaker 0: I wrote it before.
Speaker 1: Go try to read the first chapter.
Speaker 1: It's doubt it'll end with some.
Speaker 1: it's a textbook.
Speaker 1: So it'll end with some quiz questions, I guess, in the first chapter.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And just see if you can even understand what the fuck is going on.
Speaker 0: It's tough because I am a computer professional and a technologist, but I am an information technologist.
Speaker 0: I am not a computer scientist.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, Pax West, there will very, very likely be at least one gig nights panel there.
Speaker 0: But the odds are it'll be either just me or just me and Emily.
Speaker 0: Emily will be there for some other professional reasons.
Speaker 0: I can't say that we'll be at any specific cons beyond that.
Speaker 0: I feel like Scott and I might do a panel together at Pax Unplugged, even if we don't want Pax Unplugged to happen.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: We've reached the point where where I was just like, you know, yeah, cons are going to happen or not.
Speaker 1: And the answer was not.
Speaker 1: But yeah, now we're at the point where it's like, listen, you know, I don't know if I'm going to go to Pax Unplugged.
Speaker 0: I'll say this of all the Pax's Pax Unplugged requires the least advanced decision from me and Scott to decide if we're going to go.
Speaker 0: It's the least planning.
Speaker 0: It can be a day trip very easily like that's a short trip.
Speaker 0: There's a lot.
Speaker 0: it's a lot easier to plan a Pax Unplugged to the last second for us than literally any other Pax.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But, you know, we're at the point where it's like, I really would like to go to Pax Unplugged.
Speaker 1: You know, I hope other people I know would go there to play games with.
Speaker 1: But who knows what's going to happen.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But I can at least say that I will almost definitely be presenting at least one panel at Pax West.
Speaker 0: But I cannot promise that you will see me at the con at any other point than the panels, because I'll be in Seattle for other reasons and probably not hanging out mostly alone in the convention center for four days.
Speaker 1: The website is coming along very nicely.
Speaker 1: I'm just about done with the part of the website that you won't see, which is the tooling that will let rim upload episodes easily and completely.
Speaker 1: It took a long time because I was getting really fancy in terms of the.
Speaker 1: I discussed this before we sorted out the ID three chapters and all kinds of other fancy features.
Speaker 1: So that seems to actually all be coming together.
Speaker 1: The next part I have to work on is basically getting all the data from the old website over to the new website with some sort of ETL process.
Speaker 1: And once that's in place, the the finish line isn't close, but the the the the first finish line, I guess, of take down the old website and put up the new website becomes pretty close.
Speaker 1: Only, you know, a small pile of small tasks to accomplish to make that happen.
Speaker 1: You know, verifying all the redirects are correct.
Speaker 0: I don't want to take a moment to highlight and praise Scott here, because gig nights as a philosophy from the beginning, one thing that we were both like really, really mad about is when links break and people don't follow the basic contract of the Internet.
Speaker 0: And this would all be a lot easier if we didn't insist on never breaking a URL and never taking down content we have published.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, you got to realize, like the geek nights website was at first a WordPress, I think.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And so if you have some link to some old WordPress posting, it's like it's.
Speaker 1: I believe it would still work now.
Speaker 1: And I'm going to make sure it continues to still work and redirect to.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, it's like never mind the cruft of.
Speaker 0: we were using the advanced features of Libsyn when Libsyn launched.
Speaker 0: Those features are no longer the advanced features.
Speaker 0: They are charitably called the legacy features.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: I think we are literally their oldest customer.
Speaker 1: It's quite possible we could be.
Speaker 1: But yeah, so, you know, sorting out all that shit will replace the old website with the new one as soon as the new one achieves feature parity.
Speaker 1: And then at that point, the website, the new website will be open source on GitHub and you will be able to watch the progress and also submit, you know, if you want to help out, if you have the skills to do so.
Speaker 0: And, you know, if you're trying to start a podcast, guess what will be a really cool framework you could use?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it might be difficult to just copy the website and deploy it yourself.
Speaker 0: Because it is it is made for the kind of thing that we do.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You know, but regardless, you know, the progress has been happening, especially since I haven't had any work to do, but I haven't done any work on it in, say, three or four days because I've been doing other stuff.
Speaker 1: But I'm going to, you know, this week.
Speaker 1: there's going to be some more progress happening, you know, tomorrow.
Speaker 0: And the thing is, once the new website is live, that lights a fire under both of us for a lot of the like new kinds of content and experimental stuff and like other projects we want to do.
Speaker 1: So there's already a long list of features to be added to the website.
Speaker 1: So we got to work on those also, but prioritize them and whatnot.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, let's just get right into it with a show that we came up with because our friends are currently arguing about the nature of refrigerators for a bunch of reasons.
Speaker 0: So I realize we've.
Speaker 0: we have talked about cooling PCs.
Speaker 0: We've also talked about PC cooling.
Speaker 0: One of the rare instances where I think I snuck in an episode twice.
Speaker 0: We've talked about server rooms.
Speaker 0: We've talked about HVAC.
Speaker 0: Never talked about refrigeration.
Speaker 0: Like as a technology, arguably.
Speaker 1: I mean, we don't need to explain how refrigeration works with compressors and whatnot.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You can look that up on YouTube and find better visualizations of it.
Speaker 1: I think even RIM's favorite technology guy, whatever, has a video or two on it also.
Speaker 0: Suffice it to say, the only thing you need to know if you don't know is that all refrigeration is a concept.
Speaker 0: It does one of two things and that's it.
Speaker 0: It either removes heat from an environment into a medium in some fashion, like, say, dry ice in a room.
Speaker 0: It's pulling heat into something to cool the space or it is actively pumping heat out of a space into the broader environment.
Speaker 0: It's just a heat pump.
Speaker 0: You Google for heat pump.
Speaker 0: There are plenty of people, like Scott said, who will explain it to you.
Speaker 1: So there's many different methods.
Speaker 1: There's many different methods of doing this that vary sometimes in big ways, sometimes in small ways.
Speaker 1: But, you know, regardless, like that's what you're doing.
Speaker 0: Less than 200 years ago, the primary way a lot of people in America got things like ice was harvesting it from rivers in the winter and storing it under, like, bales of hay.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: I didn't even know where the hell they got dry ice.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to think about, I know about methods from the 1900s to make dry ice.
Speaker 0: I don't know if and how dry ice might have been made before that, actually.
Speaker 0: I don't know the history of dry ice at all, I realize, other than that one thing.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: I do remember, though, my grandfather talking about how back in the day, it's like you look at today and people drive food around and other things that need to be cold in refrigerated trucks.
Speaker 1: Just a big truck that has a refrigerator attached to it and the inside of the truck is cold and now you can drive meat around town in the summer.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But he said back in the day, all they would do is just have a truck and throw a piece of dry ice in the truck and maybe put a fan near it.
Speaker 1: And that was it.
Speaker 1: And the truck would be cold as hell.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Dry ice was observed and documented in detail in the 1830s.
Speaker 0: And it looks like in the early 1900s is when manufacturing processes that are not that different from what we do today were invented.
Speaker 1: And Rym has read Wikipedia to you as a service.
Speaker 0: Yup, because I was curious.
Speaker 0: I did not know if they were able to make dry ice in the late 1800s and the answer seems to be sort of.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Regardless, all the ways of keeping things cold back in the day, meaning up until relatively recently in terms of human history, was get cold shit and put it near the shit that needs to be cold until it runs out and then get more cold shit.
Speaker 1: Even in the 20th century, right?
Speaker 1: You had the icebox, right?
Speaker 1: They didn't have refrigerators in houses.
Speaker 1: You would have someone deliver fucking ice to your house.
Speaker 1: You'd put the ice into the bottom of the fridge, right?
Speaker 1: The fridge would be cold until the ice melted and then they would deliver more ice.
Speaker 1: And that's how you kept food in your house from spoiling.
Speaker 0: So, my grandparents had, when I was a kid, I might have talked about this on Geek Nights more than a decade ago, they had a general electric refrigerator from the late 1940s.
Speaker 0: And it wasn't their primary fridge.
Speaker 0: They had a more recent fridge in the main house.
Speaker 0: But in the furnace room, they had that old late 40s fridge and it still worked.
Speaker 0: And they were still using it because they thought it was neat.
Speaker 0: It never had any maintenance other than some lubrication at any point.
Speaker 0: And as a kid, I was vaguely obsessed with it.
Speaker 0: And all they stored in there was soda pop.
Speaker 0: It had this really cool chunky latching mechanism to open it.
Speaker 1: Yep, that's how they do.
Speaker 0: Yep, and you had to manually defrost it.
Speaker 0: But yeah, so early refrigerators that plugged into an outlet and used electricity, like my grandparents...
Speaker 1: Hold on, there's one thing for the ice boxes, right?
Speaker 1: There's one thing about the ice box that I never knew and still don't know, but I only have a guess.
Speaker 1: Which is that, you know, the ice cube would melt, the big ice cube, right?
Speaker 1: Then they'd bring a new one.
Speaker 1: Did you just drain the water down the drain?
Speaker 1: Or drink the water?
Speaker 1: Because the old ice cube melted into water.
Speaker 1: It didn't disappear.
Speaker 1: What did they do?
Speaker 1: Did they pump it out?
Speaker 1: What did they do with the water from the old ice cube?
Speaker 0: So the Wikipedia page doesn't actually say much about it, except it talks a lot about how all nice ice chests had spigots to drain it and catch pans and holding tanks.
Speaker 1: Okay, so you would drain it and it would go down the drain into the sewer?
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 0: I doubt people...
Speaker 1: Like down the sink, basically?
Speaker 0: Unless you lived somewhere where... That was my guess.
Speaker 0: If you lived somewhere where you didn't have running water in your house, which, frankly, in the early 1900s in the US, not that uncommon.
Speaker 1: But if you lived in a place without running water, are you really going to be in range of an ice delivery man?
Speaker 0: Might have.
Speaker 0: Small town.
Speaker 0: A lot of houses in the 20s did not have...
Speaker 1: Since it's just water, it is safe to just drain it out into the backyard or some shit, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: As long as you don't drain it on your kitchen floor.
Speaker 0: But we had a beefy dehumidifier in the basement when I was a kid, and we would actually take that water and use it to water the plants in the house.
Speaker 0: Just, why not?
Speaker 1: Yeah, why not?
Speaker 0: But yeah, refrigeration.
Speaker 0: I talk about this a lot on Geek Nights, but in general, one of the most important things you can do if you care about technology is not to just focus on the bleeding edge of the cool new stuff we can do, but to think about technology that works and how it can be distributed more equitably, used more efficiently, etc.
Speaker 0: Refrigeration is one of the most important things humans have ever invented.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you play Civilization, it gets a whole spot on the tech tree.
Speaker 1: I think in every Civilization game that I'm aware of, refrigeration has its own item.
Speaker 0: It's like, "Oh yeah, double food from all your shit
Speaker 0: now!".
Speaker 1: Yup, exactly.
Speaker 0: Your cities can just grow like crazy.
Speaker 0: See, also, sewers.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: Hospitals.
Speaker 0: that comes after hospitals.
Speaker 1: After plumbing, I think refrigeration is the next most important invention for human society.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's to the point to where...
Speaker 1: It's dependent on electricity, which at least kind of, right?
Speaker 1: Mostly.
Speaker 1: There are plenty... So I guess you could rank electricity higher, kind of.
Speaker 0: But there are plenty of cooling mechanisms that are as effective as modern day refrigeration that uses electricity that do not require electricity.
Speaker 0: There's lots of ways to do it.
Speaker 1: That is true, but the vast majority of refrigeration around the world is the electric kind.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: But I think the most important thing about it is just that it allowed perishable food to be stored with relative safety.
Speaker 0: Like, beyond everything else.
Speaker 0: Because even in a modern world, in the year 2022, where I have a refrigerator and a freezer, I still have to put a not insignificant amount of mental effort into thinking about the safety of various foods and what should be stored where.
Speaker 0: And can this be frozen?
Speaker 0: Can this be refrigerated?
Speaker 0: Should this be refrigerated?
Speaker 0: Some foods shouldn't be refrigerated, like tomatoes!
Speaker 1: But I mean, think about this.
Speaker 1: Back in the day, before refrigeration, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, okay, you either had to get everything fresh, or, right?
Speaker 1: You store some food, okay, well then what if, you know, you might have to like... I mean, any food you want to store, you don't have to do some sort of preservation work, right?
Speaker 1: Like, you know, maybe can it, or, you know, what's it called?
Speaker 1: Like, you know, you can't just save the beef for tomorrow, you gotta make some beef jerky instead, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, stuff like that.
Speaker 0: Like, leftovers were difficult.
Speaker 0: Leftovers like we know them today are basically impossible without refrigeration.
Speaker 1: Right, it's like, okay, then you get, it's like, okay, you have this sort of battle going on.
Speaker 1: It's like, do I save food?
Speaker 1: Do I eat food, more food than I can stomach?
Speaker 1: Do I go hungry?
Speaker 1: You know, do I eat, do I, the food's older, but do I eat it anyway and risk getting sick?
Speaker 1: Do I even know that the food will make me sick?
Speaker 1: Just have warm meat lying around.
Speaker 0: Yup, and while there are a bunch of adjacent technologies that have achieved similar results, like to keep things cool, like evaporative coolers, like those have existed since ancient times, they are much less reliable, and they're not as controllable.
Speaker 0: The big thing about the refrigeration we're talking about, like a modern fridge, is that you pick a temperature, and it is at that temperature.
Speaker 1: Also, you know, you talk about, you know, food traveling, right, so it's like you'd have to eat food that came from somewhere close.
Speaker 1: You couldn't eat a food that, you know, wouldn't, a spoilable food, that came from far away, you know, like, you get a fruit from another country, it's like you couldn't have that.
Speaker 1: It would be disgusting by the time it took a boat over, or even if it took a plane.
Speaker 1: somehow, you know, I guess planes and refrigerators were invented around, you know.
Speaker 1: But, you know, it's like before the, you know, you'd have to take a boat, and it's like it would be rotten.
Speaker 1: It's like you would never be able to eat that unless you went to the other place, then you could eat the food from there, but you couldn't have brought the food from home, right?
Speaker 1: It would be disgusting by the time you got to the other side, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, on boats, it's like the navies would be bringing around live animals on the boat, because otherwise, it's like if you just had all the animals pre-butchered, it's like guess what, you're not going to make it across the ocean.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: Similarly, most of the food they brought was all the food you imagine on a Napoleonic era ship.
Speaker 0: Weevils.
Speaker 0: Weevils and hard bread and salt pork.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, refrigeration was huge.
Speaker 1: So, modern day, right, you go and you probably just buy a fucking refrigerator, but there's so many different ones now.
Speaker 1: When I was a kid, everyone I knew just had the standard refrigerator, which was just freezer on top, fridge on the bottom.
Speaker 0: When I was a kid, there were exactly two kinds of fridges.
Speaker 0: Everyone, with a handful of exceptions, had what you describe, and there were a handful of kids whose parents were rich, who lived in the nicer houses and the newer developments in the suburbs.
Speaker 0: They had the early versions of those modern fancy refrigerators with a bunch of features on them, like an ice thing and a water thing in the front, and the doors that opened to the sides.
Speaker 1: I feel like I didn't see any of those until the mid to late 90s.
Speaker 1: They probably existed earlier, but I didn't see any.
Speaker 0: I saw them in the houses of a handful of kids I knew in middle school, who were way richer than us and lived in way nicer suburbs than we did.
Speaker 1: What I did see were people who had, you know, larger houses, they had garages and large basements.
Speaker 0: Oh, we had a beverage fridge, we had a fridge in the kitchen, and we had a, basically, when we bought that new fridge, the old fridge wasn't that broken, it was just like old and inefficient.
Speaker 0: We stuck it in the garage, and that became the soda fridge.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we might have done that if we had had such a space, right, in our house, but we also didn't drink soda, so it wasn't really a thing.
Speaker 1: But people had chest freezers.
Speaker 0: We also had a chest freezer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the people with the chest freezers, for example, right, I remember you'd buy your turkey on Thanksgiving, and you'd go to the person's house who had the chest freezer, and leave it in there until Thanksgiving.
Speaker 1: Then you would go there the day before Thanksgiving.
Speaker 0: If I had enough space for it, I would 100% have a chest freezer today.
Speaker 1: Because we didn't have room in our regular fridge to store a whole fucking turkey.
Speaker 0: I would absolutely have a chest freezer if there was anywhere to put it in this apartment.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: There's also those cool, there are the Peltier, like there's chest freezers and chest refrigerators that are designed for long-term storage to be energy efficient, and they tend to have a really weak-sauce Peltier device instead of the more traditional cooling.
Speaker 0: And they basically take a long time to get cold, but if you don't open often, they just stay cold using almost no electricity.
Speaker 1: I mean, the best memory I had of chest freezers was the people across the street had one in the garage, and that's where they put the popsicles.
Speaker 1: It was like, you didn't have to go in their house to go and get a popsicle.
Speaker 1: You could just be like, "Bam, you're already outside having a good
Speaker 1: time.".
Speaker 1: Just like, boom, popsicle right there.
Speaker 0: I remember going into random friends' parents' garages and just taking ice cream and popsicles out of their chest freezer, probably without permission, because the kids would all just kind of do this.
Speaker 1: It was equal opportunity, except for our house, because ours were in the freezer.
Speaker 0: Though, what I do, the thing that always did bother me is every fridge I've ever seen that has an external port for water and ice, that shit never works.
Speaker 1: Okay, well, first of all, it works sometimes, right?
Speaker 1: The thing that bothers me is, A, inconsistent design.
Speaker 1: A lot of times, I try to use it, and the design of what I'm supposed to do is not obvious.
Speaker 1: Some of them, there's the plastic thing, you push your cup into it, and it's like, "Ah, that should make water come
Speaker 1: out.".
Speaker 1: And some of them, that makes the ice come out, and some of them makes the water come out.
Speaker 1: Some of them don't even have that.
Speaker 1: Some of them, you gotta push buttons on the face of the thing to make stuff happen.
Speaker 0: A lot of times, they have a dial and a switch, and you set it to what you want to happen when the plastic thing gets hit.
Speaker 1: And there should only ever be two buttons.
Speaker 1: Spit out water and spit out ice.
Speaker 1: Some of these things have more buttons.
Speaker 1: What the fuck are those buttons for?
Speaker 1: Like, seriously?
Speaker 0: Crushed ice versus chopped ice, even though they end up being kind of the same on most of these things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't give a shit.
Speaker 1: If you give a shit about that, you got problems, right?
Speaker 1: And then, the other thing is, I guess if you're extra fancy, I imagine, I've never seen one, there must be one out there that will carbonate the water, right?
Speaker 1: Which I don't drink, but, you know, okay, if that's the case, I could make, you know, if you're that person, I could maybe say the third button is okay.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess I'm always, I never like when a half-assed version of a feature is put into an inappropriate device, as opposed to, most people probably don't need this feature, and if people who really want or need it get a dedicated, specialized device to do that thing.
Speaker 0: Like, if I were that guy, I would have a specialized ice maker, like, in my bar.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, if you are in a place where, you know, let's say, you know, the water is not so drinkable from the tap, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And you want to filter it and keep it cold.
Speaker 1: Even for me, like, my water is drinkable from the tap.
Speaker 1: I'm in New York City, like, the best water, among the best waters, right?
Speaker 1: But, a lot of our fridge space is taken up by water pitchers, water bottles, right?
Speaker 1: Things of that nature.
Speaker 1: If we had the spigot on the front of the fridge, right, then I could save a lot of space in the fridge by not having all this water, like, saved up and all the time.
Speaker 1: It's like, yeah, I could drink from the tap, but the point is to make it cold first.
Speaker 0: At least our tap is shockingly cold, even in the dead of summer, for some reason.
Speaker 0: Sometimes, sometimes.
Speaker 1: But it is a useful feature to have for space savings, right?
Speaker 1: The ice that goes right into the glass, eh, okay, me, eh, you know.
Speaker 0: I just find that most of the times, when I try to use one of those things at someone else's house, or, like, in an Airbnb, or anywhere that I encounter one, they fail in some way.
Speaker 0: Even the last time I visited my brother, I go to use the ice maker, and suddenly he's like, "Ah, the ice maker doesn't really work, don't do it, don't touch
Speaker 0: it!".
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: I just feel like they're cheap and they tend to break.
Speaker 1: Our fridge has the kind of ice maker I like, which is the one where you can turn it on and off.
Speaker 1: Right now it's on, because I just used a bunch of ice, but I turn it off soon once the bucket fills up.
Speaker 1: But basically, there's a bucket in the freezer, and you just turn it on, and you wait, and eventually the freezer bucket is full of ice, just tons of ice.
Speaker 1: And I like this because, A, you know, ice cube trays, I used to use those, and it's like you had to fill them, carry them to the freezer full of water.
Speaker 1: You can't really have that many trays in the freezer because there's not enough room, and you don't have that much ice, and then it sublimates if you don't use it quickly enough, and then you don't have ice when you want it.
Speaker 1: The bucket full of ice in the freezer is just like, "Yep, there's just a fucking bucket full of ice, you can go wild with the
Speaker 1: ice.".
Speaker 1: It's like, oh, you want to, you know, you can put a couple cubes in a glass, you're like, just dip your glass in there like you're scooping.
Speaker 1: You just scoop it all the way full, right?
Speaker 1: Take a water bottle, just jam it with ice all the way to the top.
Speaker 1: You don't get to give a shit, you get so much ice, and you don't have to, you know, you don't have to work.
Speaker 1: You don't have to like, you know, remember to manage the ice, or to make cubes, or to fill anything, it's just, it's always there.
Speaker 1: And if it ever runs low, you push the button until it's full again, and then when it's done, you push the button one more time.
Speaker 0: Now for whatever reason, I don't use ice, like, I almost never use ice in my day-to-day life.
Speaker 0: So all I have is one little silicone tray that makes four giant ice cubes with a cover on it so they don't sublimate.
Speaker 0: And anytime I use two of them, I put some water in there, so I always have ice cubes.
Speaker 1: I mean, this time of year, you know, I'm filling coolers, I'm filling water bottles.
Speaker 1: Coolers!
Speaker 0: I just go to the bodega and buy a bag of ice for a dollar.
Speaker 1: That costs money, and you gotta carry the ice, and...
Speaker 0: Bodega's right there!
Speaker 1: It's still, it's work, right?
Speaker 0: Also, our freezer's usually pretty much full of food.
Speaker 1: Yeah, ours is not that full of food.
Speaker 1: There's only two people living here.
Speaker 1: Why would you have that much food in there?
Speaker 0: Well, we keep a lot of stuff in there.
Speaker 1: Eat it!
Speaker 0: Yeah, then we kill it with more!
Speaker 0: But living in an apartment is a little annoying because there are better fridges.
Speaker 0: Like, I get a much better fridge than what we have, but I don't own this place, the building owns the fridge.
Speaker 1: Yeah, when you rent, you don't have a choice of fridge, so I've never bought a fridge in my life.
Speaker 0: Yup, as much as I would want to.
Speaker 0: And, what's funny is a lot of people, even now, I see our friends still debating fridges.
Speaker 0: A lot of people have a lot of shocking misconceptions about, like, how different configurations of fridges being more or less efficient, and it's almost all aesthetics and style, and very little of it affects the efficiency.
Speaker 0: But, from what I do know, a handful of things that people would think would be more efficient end up being way less efficient.
Speaker 0: Like, case in point, the drawer freezer, those things just jettison cold air compared to a regular one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, well, people, I don't know how many people realize that, like, you know, you have a fridge, the cooling is all happening in the freezer, right?
Speaker 1: The fridge, part of your refrigerator, is actually just getting, sort of, you know, the cool air left over from the freezer, sort of goes into the fridge by, like, a vent, and that's what makes the fridge cold.
Speaker 1: All the actual active cooling is happening in the freezer zone.
Speaker 1: So, the classic style with the freezer on top, you know, cold air goes down, warm air goes up, is much more efficient than the freezer on bottom kind, right?
Speaker 1: Because the cold air from the freezer just naturally goes down into the fridge on its own.
Speaker 1: If you had to make the cold air go up, well, now, you know, it's not so simple, right?
Speaker 1: You might have to have a little fan in there, who knows?
Speaker 0: Now, I will admit, if I owned a place and I were rich, I would be really interested in one of those integrated refrigeration systems, where you don't have just one big fridge, you just have some of your cupboards are just refrigerated to different temperatures.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I mean, as inefficient and wasteful as that is, the convenience and amazingness of, like, you know, "Hey, next to your cabinet full of glasses is a refrigerated cabinet full of
Speaker 1: beverages.".
Speaker 1: And then, you know, next to where the cutting board is, right, in your work area, well, that's where the vegetable fridge is, right?
Speaker 0: But also, depending, that could be more efficient if done in a nuanced way around things, like, not everything needs to be cooled to the temperature of a refrigerator.
Speaker 0: Then we pick that temperature because that is safe for pretty much anything for a short amount of time.
Speaker 0: Like, that is a food safety temperature we've chosen.
Speaker 0: But, like, a lot of vegetables, they'll keep on— Humidity also could be customized per fridge, yeah.
Speaker 0: If they're just—they just need to be kept at a consistent temperature.
Speaker 0: that's slightly lower than room temperature, so a really weak-sauce Peltier system for the vegetable crisper could mean you don't have to waste all this energy cooling all your lettuces to 40 degrees Fahrenheit.
Speaker 0: Like, you could have—you could actually probably save energy.
Speaker 0: But, it's hard to calculate that because those are bespoke systems.
Speaker 0: Like, that's not something you just go and buy.
Speaker 0: That's something a rich person gets installed into their house.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, well, I mean, there are non-rich people who do have multiple fridges for other reasons, right?
Speaker 1: Most notably, people who keep kosher, and they gotta separate their meat fridge from their dairy fridge.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: I used to have because it was a gift, and it was actually really useful.
Speaker 0: I had a wine fridge that—all it did was chill wine, but it—you know, wine doesn't need to get that cold, so it saved energy because it just kept the wine at the temperature.
Speaker 0: you would drink it.
Speaker 0: You type a number in, it just keeps it—but when that broke, I did not replace it because now I live in a tiny apartment.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I guess there's, you know, the last thing I guess would be the other arrangements of fridges, right?
Speaker 0: A lot of people seem to have strong opinions about, like, the doors, whether you should get the splitting doors or— Well, my only preference is there is anything where there's a divider between the two left and right side of the fridge seems just a complete waste of space.
Speaker 1: Yeah, mine has the top doors split in the middle, but the inside of the fridge is one cavern.
Speaker 1: It's not—there's no split in the fridge.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I like just one big cavern, and then a smaller one big cavern for the freezer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, I really don't care too much about the—people have such strong opinions, like, I don't care about the doors, right?
Speaker 1: I care about the efficiency, and I care about how much space is inside to store food as long as it's enough for the food I have, and I care that it fits in the kitchen and, you know, fits nicely and doesn't stick out too far.
Speaker 0: Which again, living in an apartment, like, one minor annoyance of our fridge, you know, our apartment's big, but it's still— It doesn't swing out and hit things or block the way or, you know.
Speaker 0: There is no way to remove the left bottom crisper drawer from our fridge without removing the entire refrigerator door.
Speaker 0: Because you cannot open the fridge door all the way around because it's up against the wall.
Speaker 0: And that's just an annoyance, there's literally no way around that, and that is not a concern for pretty much anyone who lives in a house, but if you live in an apartment—
Speaker 1: That is a chore I do, like, once a year, is take all the things out of the fridge and clean them, all the shelves and the drawers and everything.
Speaker 0: That one shelf, what I do is, when it's time to clean it— Yep, I open the fridge door, and then I clean it as fast as possible.
Speaker 0: Like, I'm in and out of there so quick.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It is nice to have a rearrangeable shelf, you know, and such and such.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Oh, the one other feature that our current fridge has that actually I do like is that if you accidentally leave the door open, it'll start beeping at you.
Speaker 1: Ooh.
Speaker 1: It would have been a great help earlier in life, but our fridges did not do that when I was young.
Speaker 0: So once, one time, I think I talked about this in Geek Nights, we lost everything in the fridge because the door, like, a pressure thing happened, and the door popped open a tiny bit.
Speaker 0: There was this, it was opened by, I think, the tiniest bit.
Speaker 0: And actually, a lot of the fridge, especially the lower part, still stayed, like, pretty cold.
Speaker 0: But it was just open wide enough to where the light bulb in there turned on.
Speaker 0: And that light bulb was an incandescent bulb pumping out 20 to 40 watts of heat, and it basically cooked everything in the top of the fridge.
Speaker 0: So I had to throw out everything.
Speaker 0: Had it not been an incandescent bulb, we probably would have lost almost nothing in that incident.
Speaker 0: So I did replace both bulbs in our fridge with fridge-safe, cold-temperature-rated LEDs, and they output basically zero heat.
Speaker 0: Like, it's kind of amazing.
Speaker 1: My previous fridge, my previous apartment, I replaced the bulbs, but in this current fridge, I just have whatever it came with.
Speaker 1: I don't even know, I guess if they die, yeah, I'm gonna replace them with the best possible LED.
Speaker 0: Does he gotta get an LED that's designed for fridges?
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, obviously you always put a fridge-specific bulb in there.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: But, uh, yeah, refrigeration.
Speaker 0: Super important to humans.
Speaker 0: I camp and hike, I like camping and hiking and all that stuff.
Speaker 0: And, uh, can't just bring a fridge with you.
Speaker 1: I guess the last thing is that, you know, a lot of other features have been added to fridges these days.
Speaker 1: They're trying to, you know, like, they get some fucking computers in there, and like, things to tell you how much food is left, or, you know, do some smart fridge bullshit.
Speaker 1: All that stuff sucks, get that shit out of here.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Do not connect your refrigerator to the internet.
Speaker 1: I don't want a fridge with a screen on it.
Speaker 1: No, I don't want none of that shit, get that out of here.
Speaker 0: Yup, unless the fridge were smart enough to, on its own, without me having to do anything, know an inventory of everything that's in it, and provide that to me via an open format.
Speaker 1: That's what they say they can do, but, uh, no.
Speaker 0: Yup, call me when they do that without me having to configure anything, and without me having to connect it to the internet.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: I simply leave you with...
Speaker 1: (singing in Italian).
Speaker 0: (singing in Italian).