Speaker 0:
Speaker 1: It's Thursday, February 3rd, 2022.
Speaker 1: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight on the Geek Nights Book Club, we review the first novel, The Tale of Genji.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So I think more so than other book club books, this one deserves a little bit of a meta preamble.
Speaker 0: Well, so first of all, according to the Geek Nights website database, we announced that this was the book club book on June of 2019.
Speaker 1: June 20th, 2019, which 2019 was a thousand years ago.
Speaker 1: 2019 was a different world.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So basically, you know, the world went to poop and also the book itself is hard to read and lots of things happened.
Speaker 0: It was interesting.
Speaker 1: I didn't actually like we'd announced it in June and usually when we start a new book club book, like I don't actually start reading it right away.
Speaker 1: Like I'd wait a few weeks.
Speaker 1: I started reading it and we'll talk about like what that was like.
Speaker 1: But in terms of just the meta part and I was plugging along, I was like seven or eight chapters in like slow and steady.
Speaker 0: I was enjoying it, but I had 50 some odd chapters, so that's not bad.
Speaker 1: And I was reading it mostly like when I was commuting or like sitting at a restaurant, like at lunch, like at work, like I'd sit at a restaurant for an hour having my lunch and I'd read for an hour.
Speaker 1: And then we'd go on trips.
Speaker 0: I was reading it mostly.
Speaker 0: I had the Kindle app on my phone and then I would open it on the subway.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: That was one, especially early chapters of Genji, two subway trips.
Speaker 1: You could finish a chapter actually.
Speaker 0: But that's also why I hadn't start reading it right away because in June I was biking to work.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Same.
Speaker 1: So I started reading it on the subway toward the end.
Speaker 0: I didn't start reading it until like September 2019.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: But then, as you all know, in March the world shut down and everything changed and for about a year I didn't read a lot.
Speaker 1: Like we talked about this on Geek Nights a bunch, but it was this weird situation I'd never been in in.
Speaker 1: like my life up to this point where most of the time I would spend reading was like traveling or like laying on a beach.
Speaker 1: Like all the all the context I had where I would generally sit down and read for a long period of time fiction, all those activities disappeared from my life because of COVID.
Speaker 1: Plus the world was weird and stressful, especially in those early days.
Speaker 1: Like it's it's easy to not really internalize how stressful those first like six months were when none of us know knew how this was going to go.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, a lot of things got in our way of reading this book, not just the book itself.
Speaker 0: You know, a lot of times you see like professional athletes give interviews like I don't want to make excuses, but here I'm like, let's make some perfectly valid excuses.
Speaker 0: You got a valid excuse?
Speaker 0: You know, don't give me invalid excuses.
Speaker 0: But listen, if you have valid excuses for things, use them as long as they're valid.
Speaker 0: It's like, OK, like valid excuse.
Speaker 1: This book would have taken us a while without COVID.
Speaker 1: It wouldn't have taken us this long, but based on the based on the trajectory we had before COVID, we would have done this show probably like summer of 2020.
Speaker 1: Like, really?
Speaker 0: That's what it would be more like late.
Speaker 1: If there had been zero COVID by August 31st, I think it's plausible.
Speaker 1: we would have done the show definitely by the end of the year 2020.
Speaker 0: But anyway, now that I finished it, my appetite for reading has returned voraciously.
Speaker 0: The next book club book, which I guess we announced at the end of the show as per usual.
Speaker 0: I'm already 80 percent done.
Speaker 1: Well, because you seem to have thought that I had already read it, but no, Emily read it and I was really excited to read it.
Speaker 1: And I bought it.
Speaker 1: I read one chapter and thought, holy shit, this is the next book club book.
Speaker 0: The prologue or the first chapter?
Speaker 1: Well, the prologue.
Speaker 1: I didn't actually even get to the first.
Speaker 1: I read the prologue and based on what I do from Emily, this book is so up our alley.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so tale again, gee, we finally read this whole damn book.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is the first novel ever written by any person.
Speaker 0: There were many long forms of literature, both of fictional literature before the tale of Genji, such as like, I don't know, the Odyssey, which he already did the book club on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the Odyssey.
Speaker 0: Odyssey is an epic poem.
Speaker 0: It's like a novel.
Speaker 1: Also, it was not written as a book.
Speaker 1: It was an oral tradition later transcribed.
Speaker 0: Yep, exactly.
Speaker 1: And also it was, what's really fascinating is it was like the Odyssey was around 725 BC and the tale of Genji is around 1000 AD.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So 1700 years apart.
Speaker 1: But meanwhile, Rome didn't fall until about 400 years after the tale of Genji was written.
Speaker 0: So did Rome have novels or did they not receive the invention of the novel yet?
Speaker 1: Well, that's something that it's an aside that I think about a lot and I wish history books did, like history classes did more was sort of always zoom out from any zoomed in lesson to just talk about the state of the entire world at some time.
Speaker 1: Like America's cowboys were a very short time, but like what was going on to the rest of the world?
Speaker 1: Not what a lot of people think.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so the tale of Genji is extremely notable and important for a lot of reasons.
Speaker 1: And honestly, it should be studied in school all around the world, as it often is.
Speaker 0: I'm kind of annoyed that people whose entire job, including like, you know, the translator and many other people, where all they do is study the tale of Genji, you know, the same way that like, you know, rabbis study the Torah.
Speaker 0: They just have this is like they're a significant portion of their lives is studying, you know, this single book, and not just the story itself, but the entire context around it, you know, historically, culturally, etc.
Speaker 0: Because you have this extremely long book, written by a person at a time in history, right further in the past than any other such work.
Speaker 0: And just by your by reading it, and you know, looking at other physical artifacts surrounding it, you can learn a whole lot about, you know, that era and what was going down.
Speaker 0: And that's actually how I decided to make this the book club book is.
Speaker 0: I went there was a I had heard of the book.
Speaker 0: And I had a general idea of what its deal was.
Speaker 0: But then they had an exhibit at the Met Museum over in Manhattan.
Speaker 0: And since I live in New York City, one morning, I think I woke up on like a weekend.
Speaker 0: And Twitter was like, I had known the exhibit was there.
Speaker 0: But I think Twitter or something reminded me that like, it was the last weekend for the exhibit.
Speaker 0: So I'm like, I got nothing to do.
Speaker 0: And you want to just go over there.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Just got on the train and went over there.
Speaker 0: Just check it out.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: We went, you know, and I checked it out.
Speaker 0: And I learned a lot of things there.
Speaker 0: that will probably be discussed if, you know, in the second episode about this book.
Speaker 0: But after doing that, going to that exhibit, I was like, well, I guess I should make this the book club book.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: We can read this and I need to choose one.
Speaker 0: So, you know, I don't remember what the previous book club book was.
Speaker 1: Actually, so we have done a grand total of.
Speaker 1: I was looking at our book club book history, trying to remember.
Speaker 1: We've done 29 books.
Speaker 1: And the one we did before this was Pages of Pain, it looks like.
Speaker 0: Oh, OK.
Speaker 0: So I mean, on the one hand, that's more books than I thought.
Speaker 0: But on the other hand, in 15, that's two books a year.
Speaker 0: That's not a great rate.
Speaker 1: We did a lot pretty quickly.
Speaker 0: Let's get it up to four books a year.
Speaker 1: I feel like four is a good.
Speaker 1: We did a lot like densely for a while.
Speaker 0: I don't mean I don't mean getting the average up to four books a year.
Speaker 0: That'll mean we'll have to do eight books a year for a while.
Speaker 0: I mean, just get the rate from here on out up to four books a year.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because part of the joy is reading a book like together, like we're assuming you read the book, too.
Speaker 1: If you didn't, you're going to have no idea what we're talking about coming soon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, spoilers.
Speaker 1: Genji dies like two thirds of the way through this thing, like both.
Speaker 1: later than I expected based on.
Speaker 1: I learned that he dies in the middle of the book early on.
Speaker 1: And I was kind of waiting.
Speaker 1: When's he going to die?
Speaker 1: But also there is more book after he dies than I expected there to be.
Speaker 1: But yeah, lots of spoilers.
Speaker 1: But also we're like one, I have to refer to notes to really remember which character is which.
Speaker 1: And I frequently was mistaken about who someone was.
Speaker 0: And the only way you're in the book.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the only way I was able to avoid that was that after the first like ten chapters, every time I finished a chapter, I would stop.
Speaker 1: And the next day, I would read a summary of that chapter, like from an external source, like a cliff note type thing, just to see if that lined up with what I got out of the chapter.
Speaker 1: And usually it was really spot on, but every now and then something, like I just missed something completely.
Speaker 1: Like something stupid obvious in retrospect.
Speaker 1: And it's partly just an artifact of the writing style and the language and partly the translation, but I think I was thinking about a lot.
Speaker 1: I was mentioning this to Scott before we started the show.
Speaker 1: We recently read The Odyssey, which had a very modern, fantastic translation by Emily Wilson.
Speaker 1: So the interesting thing about that translation was that it took the text and modernized it that made it easier to consume, understand, and enjoy to a modern audience.
Speaker 1: The Tale of Genji would be harder to do because the things that are missing from the book, especially in the earlier chapters for me as a modern reader, those words are not there.
Speaker 1: They're only inferable from the text and from context.
Speaker 1: A translation that did what Emily Wilson did to The Odyssey would actually have to add a lot of context and words that are not there.
Speaker 1: And I don't know if that still counts as a translation or if that gets into full on adaptation territory.
Speaker 0: It would have to be like a Talmud situation.
Speaker 0: I don't know if people know what the Talmud is.
Speaker 0: It's a Jewish book.
Speaker 0: It's a Jewish set of books.
Speaker 0: And basically if you ever open one up, it's like these huge red books and in the middle of each page will be a section of the Torah or the Old Testament.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And all around the edges in the margins, there's these different sections and it's basically different comments from different rabbis throughout history.
Speaker 0: Explaining what it means or what they thought about it.
Speaker 0: And they're like getting in the margins.
Speaker 0: It's like all these.
Speaker 0: So the majority of the book is notes telling you that the real original text is in the middle and everything else is like, you know, so it's sort of like reading a newspaper article and putting the comments all around the sides.
Speaker 0: From all the other people.
Speaker 0: So I think if you want to make the tale of Genji more readable, right, you would do something like that.
Speaker 0: But then how long would it take you to read that fucking thing?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You would read a page and then you read all these comments from all these different scholars telling you what, you know, explaining what the heck that was.
Speaker 1: That's something I gave up on early on the first few chapters.
Speaker 1: I would click on footnotes to like get the context.
Speaker 1: But there are so many footnotes that was so interruptive to my reading process that I just gave up on that.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So we're going to spend this episode from here on out talking about just the story, pretending that this was just like a book we just read.
Speaker 0: Just like any other book.
Speaker 0: And then we'll do another episode where we talk about all kinds of meta stuff, history stuff.
Speaker 0: Stuff about the author.
Speaker 0: Stuff I saw at the museum.
Speaker 0: Stuff about novels as a form.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: That one we'll probably either do the next Thursday episode or the following one, just because I'm going to brush up a little bit.
Speaker 1: Read some Wikipedias on Heian Era.
Speaker 0: I'm just going to talk about stuff that I know and not research additional things.
Speaker 0: Because it's like, what's the point?
Speaker 0: If someone out there wants to know those additional things, you can go research them on the internet yourself.
Speaker 1: I guess not just to regurgitate on the show.
Speaker 0: There are people who are professional scholars about this.
Speaker 0: If you really want to know, you can find them.
Speaker 0: I'm happy to tell you.
Speaker 1: The part I want to read about specifically is the debates over all the college years chapters of this book and who actually wrote them.
Speaker 1: Because there's one chapter in particular.
Speaker 0: I got the gist.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But there's one chapter in particular where I clicked on a footnote.
Speaker 1: Which one was it?
Speaker 1: It was near the end of Genji's life.
Speaker 1: He dies.
Speaker 1: And then I think it was the second or third chapter.
Speaker 1: Whichever one it was, I just remember the footnote basically said that this chapter may be an ahistorical forgery for political reasons.
Speaker 1: Like, written later and inserted.
Speaker 1: And there was a whole thing that I'm just curious about now.
Speaker 1: But yeah, we're going to treat this like it's just a book we read.
Speaker 1: And I don't regret reading this.
Speaker 1: I enjoyed it.
Speaker 1: The only thing that really stands out to me that's hard to reconcile is that on one hand, the last part of the book was easier to read and easier to understand.
Speaker 1: But the story was both more compelling and less compelling in that it almost felt more like a modern novel.
Speaker 1: But the story felt a little more contrived.
Speaker 1: Like it was, "I'm going to figure out a way to make drama happen with a narrative on
Speaker 1: purpose.".
Speaker 1: Whereas most of the tale of Genji up to that point was more like, "Here's a bunch of characters.
Speaker 1: What would
Speaker 1: happen?".
Speaker 1: It just sort of follows what would logically happen based on the story that was presented.
Speaker 1: And it kind of just flows and then just sort of peters out.
Speaker 1: But the drama feels way more constructed after Genji dies.
Speaker 0: Well, I think, you know, the first, before Genji dies, the form of the novel is there is a narrator who is basically telling you, "Oh, this happened, then this happened, then this," right?
Speaker 0: And then the narrator breaks the fourth wall on a very few occasions and they say things like, "Oh, but yeah, I don't remember all of
Speaker 0: that.".
Speaker 1: Genji said heartfelt words that it would be improper to repeat to you here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, stuff like that, exactly.
Speaker 0: But yeah, after Genji dies, I think, you know, it's still a third-person narrated book.
Speaker 0: So-and-so did this, so-and-so did that.
Speaker 0: But I think the presence of that narrator is sort of gone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, it's replaced by.
Speaker 1: there's a lot more "he said, she said" paragraph explaining where the fuck someone is.
Speaker 1: Like, where are we?
Speaker 1: That was not in the first part of the book, really.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's very different.
Speaker 1: Like, way early on when a ghost shows up and murders someone Genji's having sex with, which, like, that happens way early and it's not the first ghost murder.
Speaker 1: But it surprised me that I had to back up and reread that section again.
Speaker 1: One, to figure out, no, literal ghosts is what they're talking about.
Speaker 1: And two, wait, where are they?
Speaker 1: They went to some abandoned house, like, just somewhere.
Speaker 1: Like, they just fucking snuck away to an abandoned house.
Speaker 1: And it was not clear.
Speaker 1: I did not get that in my first reading.
Speaker 0: Alright, so basic plot summary, right?
Speaker 0: Because, despite being fucking long, obviously, not that much happens in these books.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You could list the things that happened and just very quickly, right?
Speaker 0: So, it's really separated into three sections, if you think about it.
Speaker 0: And the first section is like young Genji, right?
Speaker 0: Where he's, you know, rim, rim, he's like, oh, yeah, he's coasting through life or whatever, right?
Speaker 1: Sleepwalking through life, no real responsibilities.
Speaker 0: He's a teenager of great privilege and talent and skill and beauty and he's taking advantage of it.
Speaker 0: and he's horny and he's, you know, his dad's the emperor, so he's just, you know, doing his thing, right?
Speaker 1: It's almost even better because his dad's the emperor, but he's not the heir.
Speaker 1: So, he's almost like, has all the wealth of the emperor's son, but none of the responsibilities.
Speaker 0: Right, so then, the second part is like, okay, Genji's sort of an adult now, so he's not the emperor, but he does have a lot of responsibilities, even though the book never talks about those responsibilities, but he's like, you know, a chancellor or a counselor or all kinds of different government positions.
Speaker 1: But you see, he's also, that's the point where he's, the story, like, it's almost like he fucked around and he starts to find out, like, that's where suddenly, one, there's a bunch of times where consequences happen, which wasn't happening in the earlier parts of the books, or two, something he did before.
Speaker 0: He's much more restricted because he can't get away with stuff that he got away with when he was a kid.
Speaker 1: Stuff he did before it catches up with him.
Speaker 0: He also cares about things more than he did before, you know.
Speaker 1: I remember there was one chapter then, right before he goes on exile, where he's just like, The exile is sort of the transition point.
Speaker 1: Yeah, for a bunch of things, but like, he's about, he could just run away, like, he's about to get caught fucking around, and he's like, I'm gonna rock and run away.
Speaker 1: And then he's like, you know what, no, that actually isn't gonna work out.
Speaker 1: I gotta be an adult here.
Speaker 1: I can't just run away.
Speaker 1: They're gonna catch me anyway.
Speaker 1: I've gotta deal with this.
Speaker 1: It was a significant transition that happened over the course of one paragraph.
Speaker 1: And then he goes on exile pretty soon after.
Speaker 0: So that second part, where Genji's an adult, it really slows down and zooms in to this status quo scenario where Genji lives in this house, right?
Speaker 0: With his ladies and all his staff and servants and all these goings on at his house.
Speaker 0: And the court drama, since he's now such a significant person, and also the drama of the people that are close to him and related to him.
Speaker 1: But the part that I thought most interesting about that part of the book was that...
Speaker 0: I think that's the significant famous part of the book.
Speaker 1: It's the most interesting by far, because the court drama...
Speaker 0: Even if something was the first novel technically, it wouldn't have been such a significant, studied, historic thing if there wasn't any sort of merit to it.
Speaker 0: I think most of the merit of the story is in that middle section.
Speaker 1: Absolutely, because what I like is that in the first part, there's no real undercurrent.
Speaker 1: It's just, yeah, there's political drama, but Genji's so beautiful, it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: He's a child, who cares?
Speaker 1: But he's just hanging out with his friend, the captain, and everything's great.
Speaker 1: But in the second part, especially when the court turns against him, and there's a lot of background chatter about these evil times.
Speaker 1: And it's interesting because the book doesn't actually explain specifically what is happening in the court.
Speaker 1: It just shows that the displeasure of individuals that are part of that has cast him out of polite society for a while.
Speaker 1: But it's definitely implied that there is danger there, that the government is not stable, that the times are changing.
Speaker 1: There's an undercurrent that Genji's job actually did matter at that point.
Speaker 1: A lot.
Speaker 1: And everyone's jobs mattered a lot because there's political upheaval.
Speaker 0: Well, you can also see that political upheaval is reflected in the story in the forms of what activities all these nobles are partaking in.
Speaker 0: So before the darker times, they're all having parties and festivals.
Speaker 1: A lot of music, a lot of poetry contests.
Speaker 0: And then later in the story, they keep talking about how no one plays the music like they did before.
Speaker 0: It's just the level of festivity and luxury that's happening significantly decreases over time amongst the noble family.
Speaker 1: That's the other thing I want to read about because I wonder if in Heian era Japan, there was an era of conservatism and asceticism that set in in the government that this book was mirroring while also having Genji's fortune sort of follow that same path.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Well, I think also part of it is that if you didn't already know this, you can tell from the book that women, especially noble women in that era, were very cloistered, secluded, treated as objects as a very patriarchal, misogynist society.
Speaker 1: Like literally, Genji doesn't even see the face of half the people he has sex with.
Speaker 1: One of the chapters is literally he's trying to figure out which daughter of this guy he actually slept with the previous night because he's not sure.
Speaker 0: But this book is written by a woman of that time who was like, you know, the daughter of like some like governor or something.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I think that's what the name Murasaki Shikibu.
Speaker 0: I think what they said that it means is like Murasaki, that's the name of like a flower and it's the name of one of the characters in the book that sort of like her, you know, self insert.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And then Shikibu means like like like like masks, like ceremonial something.
Speaker 0: And it's like that's like her dad's job.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: That's that they don't know the real name of this person.
Speaker 0: Much like we don't know the names of a lot of the characters because he wasn't polite to refer to people by their actual name at the time, which honestly gave me the most struggle reading this book.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But this author.
Speaker 0: You know, was similarly much like the characters was similarly sequestered.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: In society.
Speaker 0: Hidden from view.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Not a lot.
Speaker 0: Not just walking about town, seeing what's going on.
Speaker 0: So I think, you know, my guess would be why didn't they write about like what's going on in the government?
Speaker 0: And because because the person writing didn't know.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: Yeah, they either didn't know what they knew, but it could also know about goings on in up in the palace.
Speaker 0: That's that's the things they wrote about were things they knew.
Speaker 0: They didn't write about anything else.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Though two two things that stand out to me around that are the other thing that could be going on is the depending on the time the author may have avoided the topics that could have gotten them in trouble.
Speaker 1: That could have happened.
Speaker 1: But to true, I'm curious about why some of those things were left out, because there are a few points where there is dialog from commoners.
Speaker 1: It happens once early on, but it happens a couple times later, like pretty rare.
Speaker 0: But it's in there.
Speaker 1: It happens a little bit when Genji's in exile because he's like not in the court town.
Speaker 1: Like he's.
Speaker 1: basically it's funny.
Speaker 1: He's like, I'm in the fucking booties in the middle of nowhere.
Speaker 1: It's like I got forced to forced to move to like upstate New York and this shit sucks.
Speaker 1: But then you look at the map at the end of this goddamn book.
Speaker 1: He didn't go that far.
Speaker 0: It's like it's not like you had cars.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: You know, someone pulled him in like a wagon or carried him and, you know.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: But you can't go that far.
Speaker 1: There's a few points along the way where you get dialog from regular ass people.
Speaker 1: And every time that occurs, those characters talk like normal human beings.
Speaker 1: And that really doesn't happen at any other point until the college years.
Speaker 1: Part of this book where there's a lot more like structured dialog than there was in the beginning.
Speaker 0: And I could have just been, you know, I don't know if that's an artifact of the original text or the translators did that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: On purpose.
Speaker 1: That's what that's one of the things I don't know.
Speaker 0: So second part of the book, right, is the court drama of, you know, Genji and all his people.
Speaker 0: They live in, you know, in the in the city next to the palace.
Speaker 0: How things go on.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And Genji finally dies.
Speaker 0: Because you don't live that long in that era.
Speaker 1: Like they don't make it that far.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: No one no one lives that long.
Speaker 0: They're like, oh, man, I'm 50.
Speaker 0: I'm really it's almost more than like 40.
Speaker 0: Like they're considered like old retire.
Speaker 1: I mean, look, his half brother, the guy who was emperor briefly, he has to abdicate because he's dying.
Speaker 1: Like he's sick.
Speaker 1: Well, Genji is still actually doing pretty well.
Speaker 1: Like we get to get another emperor while Genji is still just fine.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The guy goes up to the mountains.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But yeah.
Speaker 0: So then after Genji dies, the focus shifts to these other two characters.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's his grandson.
Speaker 0: Well, Kaoru is not his grandson.
Speaker 0: Well, Kaoru is basically.
Speaker 1: Let me pull up that chart of the characters again.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Kaoru is, I guess, legally Genji's son.
Speaker 0: But what actually happened was Genji's the wife of one of the wives of Genji that was Kaoru's mother actually got it on with, you know, the intended.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: No, I love this because in the first part of the book, this is like a major part of the story, the Kashiwagi thing.
Speaker 0: It's like it takes like two chapters.
Speaker 0: It's like the biggest chapter in the book is like all about this this one drama.
Speaker 1: It's like what I love about that drama is how much it parallels the very beginning of the tale of Genji with the.
Speaker 1: There's the relationship that was expected, the relationship that wasn't expected.
Speaker 1: Genji gets bored, whatever.
Speaker 1: But then you get the point where Genji is sleeping with the wrong person and the emperor's son is actually Genji's son.
Speaker 1: And now the same thing sort of happens to Genji.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So anyway, but yeah, so Kaoru, who is, I guess, legally Genji's son, but, you know, probably Kashiwagi, almost definitely Kashiwagi's biological son.
Speaker 0: And then there's this other guy.
Speaker 0: I forget his name.
Speaker 1: Oh, Kuimo Nakahara, the friend guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the friend guy.
Speaker 0: But basically it's like, you know, here you see a lot of tropes.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You see in this story, you got these two guys and there's a lot of tropes that I think have carried to the present day.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You've got the one dude who's like, you know, buff and, you know, sexy and, you know, naughty, you know, get, you know, just like raping people and whatnot.
Speaker 0: And then you got, you know, Kaoru who's like, you know, he's very, you know, religious and, you know, reserved.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And, you know, uptight.
Speaker 0: And you got the parallel between these two dudes.
Speaker 0: and they basically fight over the daughters of this dude who lives in the mountains or lives, you know, in a village.
Speaker 0: And they just fight over his daughters for like several chapters and then the ends, abruptly the end.
Speaker 1: And it escalates.
Speaker 1: The thing is, unlike all the stuff that happens in the first part of the book, that conflict escalates rapidly to a faked death, an attempted suicide, and they lose, like they both lose in the end.
Speaker 1: Like it's a radically different ending from how those dramas ended in the first part.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like, but on the one hand, it does keep escalating, but also the fundamental drama doesn't change.
Speaker 0: It's like they're still fighting over these two, these ladies.
Speaker 0: They're still fighting over these ladies.
Speaker 0: Okay, things, something happened, but these two dudes are still fighting over these ladies.
Speaker 0: It's like, it just stays that way.
Speaker 1: But I like how in the end, she's basically like the one girl is just like, fuck it.
Speaker 1: I'm going to be a nun and fuck both y'all.
Speaker 1: Like, I'm not even going to respond to your letters.
Speaker 0: A lot of people throughout the entire book go off to become nuns or monks when they're done with noble biz.
Speaker 1: I mean, Genji kind of does that.
Speaker 0: But I assume that's something you can do as a luxury of being noble.
Speaker 0: is that you can afford to just go into the, you know.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, that's the CEO in Roman history.
Speaker 1: Like there's the same thing of fuck the Roman empire.
Speaker 1: I retired.
Speaker 1: I'm going to take care of my turnips.
Speaker 1: This is your problem now.
Speaker 0: Like I'm not going to go be a hermit.
Speaker 1: I can appreciate that desire.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: So we'll zoom in a little bit more in part one, right?
Speaker 0: So part one, you got Genji and his mom is like a concert of the emperor, right?
Speaker 0: The Kiritsubo concert, right?
Speaker 0: Uh, but, uh, and like the emperor like totally thinks she's awesome.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And thinks Genji is awesome too.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But technically this other concert of the emperor, the Koki Den concert, right?
Speaker 0: Is like the more important one.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So the Koki Den concert's son, Suzaku is going to be the next emperor, not Genji.
Speaker 1: And Suzaku is okay.
Speaker 1: Like he's not a bad person, but, uh, that drama kind of drives everything that happens to Genji in the second part like that.
Speaker 0: So, right.
Speaker 0: So since Genji is not the heir, he goes around, you know, doing all sorts of shenanigans.
Speaker 0: But meanwhile, Genji is the most beautiful, the most perfect, the most talented, the most beloved, the perfect, you know, like everything person, right?
Speaker 0: It's like when he dances at the festival or sings or poetries or anything, he's like the best.
Speaker 0: It's like, this guy's the best at everything, right?
Speaker 0: You know, just the perfect dude, except for all the bad things he does.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So Genji goes around sleeping with all kinds of ladies.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And it's, it's interesting how some of them are super dramatic, like the ghost murder.
Speaker 1: Some of them are just absolute shit shows that are just hilarious.
Speaker 1: There's a big mix of what happens, but it's interesting in terms of his taste because he doesn't seem to care that much who he actually has sex with for most of the first part, because the only
Speaker 0: person he
Speaker 1: actually wants to have sex with all the time is the woman who reminds him of his own mom.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Well, I think all of it is having to do with his mother issues.
Speaker 1: His mother issues are such a big part of Genji's life.
Speaker 1: It is sad and funny and it stands out a lot to a moderate audience.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So one of the emperor's other consorts, right?
Speaker 0: Wives is Fujitsubo, who is extremely significant in the book, right?
Speaker 0: And that's like, so Genji gets with her and she has a baby and that baby is actually the third emperor, Reizei, who everyone, basically, you know, it's a very small number of characters who know that that is not the emperor's son.
Speaker 1: The funniest scene in the whole goddamn book is they think they got away with it.
Speaker 1: And then like a few chapters later, like the kids a little older and the emperor Reizei is just like, hey, uh, or is that?
Speaker 1: no, uh, Susan.
Speaker 1: God, I forget their fucking name.
Speaker 0: Well, because the reason that, you know, the hint that gives it away to the cat, like, you know, because you're reading the book as the reader.
Speaker 1: Well, the hint is he looks exactly like Genji.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like he's way hot, just like Genji.
Speaker 1: But the emperor invites Genji over and they're like hanging out and Genji shows up and he sees the kid for the first time in like a little while.
Speaker 0: And it looks like him.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: He's just like, fuck shit.
Speaker 1: How do they not know?
Speaker 1: They're going to find out.
Speaker 1: And the emperor is very, very like.
Speaker 1: there's a whole scene where the emperor is like talking to Genji and the whole time Genji's quietly panicking that he's about to be executed.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But yes.
Speaker 0: But I mean, after getting with Fujitsubo, right.
Speaker 0: You know, Genji, like, you know, is like.
Speaker 0: that's like his number one.
Speaker 1: He's like he's obsessed with her to the point that even she is like, dude, like, you've got to calm down, kid.
Speaker 0: But he can't like, you know, their relationship from then on out is very, you know, distant.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like Genji keeps trying to like, you know, like, you know, talk to her more.
Speaker 0: It's like he just, you know, because of the way the society is and whatnot, he just, you know, he sort of forced away from her.
Speaker 0: She becomes a nun at one point.
Speaker 1: It's interesting because she is not stupid and she is like, Genji.
Speaker 1: Yeah, sure.
Speaker 1: We could like I wouldn't mind.
Speaker 1: But you realize how much shit we're in.
Speaker 1: Like this is a dangerous situation.
Speaker 1: You've got to just like not bother me for a little while.
Speaker 1: And he is incapable of this.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So that's that's the first most important, I guess, person that Genji is getting with.
Speaker 0: The I guess it's worth mentioning, Genji has this legal wife, Aoi, who only shows up like two and a half times.
Speaker 0: And she dies very young, which Genji, I guess, you know, doesn't really like her or care about her.
Speaker 0: And that's sort of convenient for Genji.
Speaker 1: There's a whole chapter that really paints her as being extremely angry and difficult, which take with a grain of salt because Genji was ignoring her.
Speaker 1: Her whole of all her fortunes were ruined by being married to Genji.
Speaker 1: The whole like left of the palace is angry at the fact that she was basically forced into a marriage with Genji instead of the real crown prince.
Speaker 1: So like there's a lot of drama that comes out of that relationship.
Speaker 1: But basically the only time she appears is what?
Speaker 1: She forces the other woman out of the way with her carriage and causes a bunch of drama that Genji has to go apologize for.
Speaker 1: And then she has Genji's kid and dies.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So then...
Speaker 1: And then Genji ignores the kid for like a year.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So now you've got, I guess, the second most important character, right, which is where the author's name comes from, who's Murasaki.
Speaker 0: So Murasaki, and this is where Genji the creep enters the scene.
Speaker 1: Well, Genji the hebophile creep as opposed to just Genji the creep.
Speaker 0: It's borderline there.
Speaker 1: It's pedophile at this point.
Speaker 1: The only saving grace is Genji does not appear to actually do anything until she's a little older.
Speaker 0: But... But anyway...
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I guess to her credit, when he finally does, she is like, "What the fuck,
Speaker 1: dad?".
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: There's a whole chapter where she is like, "Uh, this is not what I signed up for.
Speaker 1: WTF.".
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So anyway, Genji finds this girl, Murasaki, somewhere, right?
Speaker 0: And he's like, "Holy
Speaker 0: shit.".
Speaker 0: And I guess, you know, the girl reminds him of his mom, right?
Speaker 1: This is where it's both kinds of creepy.
Speaker 1: He's like, "Well, I want to continue to have sex with my pseudo mom, but I can't because I'll get in trouble.
Speaker 1: So I have found a girl who I can groom to be just like
Speaker 1: her.".
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: He finds this like very young girl, extremely young, Murasaki.
Speaker 0: And he basically keeps trying to pressure and convince, right, the girl's guardians to like, you know, "Listen, I'm basically, the emperor is my dad, right?
Speaker 0: I'm a super rich, noble dude.
Speaker 0: You know, let me have this girl.
Speaker 0: I'll raise her as my daughter.
Speaker 0: I swear to you that my intentions are pure,
Speaker 0: right?".
Speaker 1: And to their credit, they are basically like, "Lol, there is no way we're giving this girl to
Speaker 1: you.".
Speaker 0: Even in the year 1000, they're like, "What the fuck is wrong with
Speaker 0: you?".
Speaker 1: One of the lines I mentioned, I think, when we were doing a meta moment like a year ago, because this is still really early in the book, but it was something like, "This Genji certainly has modern
Speaker 1: tastes.".
Speaker 1: Like, I guess this is what nobles are like today.
Speaker 1: It's a conversation, I want to say, between like the woman who's her guardian and that guy who's there, like the two people who are sort of taking care of her.
Speaker 1: It's like just a side conversation that happens.
Speaker 1: But he just fucking kidnaps her, and hides her at his house, and ploys her with toys, and it is 100% creepy groomer, like the whole time.
Speaker 0: He grooms Murasaki basically through her entire childhood.
Speaker 1: To be exactly like his mom, or his mom fetish, and to like get, like he tricks her into sitting on his lap, like even through the translation, and the history, and thousand years of humanity.
Speaker 1: You read this today and you're like, "Yeah, it is as creepy as it feels like it
Speaker 1: is.".
Speaker 0: Yup, it is creepy AF.
Speaker 0: Genji is no good.
Speaker 1: But what the fuck Genji?
Speaker 1: He finally like convinces her to marry him, despite the fact that it's a bunny drop, or even she is like,
Speaker 1: "No.".
Speaker 1: And then he immediately cheats on her.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, it is bunny drop, isn't it?
Speaker 0: Only it's a forced bunny drop.
Speaker 0: The bunny drop guy, right?
Speaker 0: It landed on him, whereas Genji went out and tried to get it on purpose.
Speaker 1: Yep, Genji bunny dropped on purpose.
Speaker 0: It's even worse than bunny drop, somehow.
Speaker 0: But the worst thing, the thing
Speaker 1: that actually like made me really not like Genji, because up to this point, not like Genji was funny, even if he's kind of a bad person, but as soon as he actually marries her and it's real, he immediately cheats on her, and actually just kind of ignores her for a long time.
Speaker 1: Like he doesn't give a shit about her anymore.
Speaker 0: Yep, so he's got, you know, he grooms this girl.
Speaker 0: Right, well, okay, so hold on.
Speaker 0: So he got, Murasaki is so important, right?
Speaker 0: It's like basically the focus of most of the book, right?
Speaker 0: So he grooms this girl all through her childhood, but then when you get to the second part of the book, she's basically like the perfect heroine.
Speaker 0: Like Genji did such a good job grooming her, that she became the most amazing woman that everyone loves, who is perfect and smart and wonderful and is the greatest.
Speaker 0: And, you know, everything about her is amazing.
Speaker 0: And that's why she's sort of like the author self-insert deal.
Speaker 1: Yep, she is like literally perfect in every possible way.
Speaker 1: And it is telling.
Speaker 0: And she's absolutely the one that Genji actually loves the most.
Speaker 0: that's still alive.
Speaker 0: But it was interesting how- When she dies, there's like a whole chapter of people crying, whereas other people, like an emperor dies in like a sentence, like a middle of a paragraph, when Murasaki dies.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, there's more text for Murasaki's death than there is for Genji's death.
Speaker 0: Yep, but- There's just so much mourning and wailing and whatnot.
Speaker 1: But Genji definitely does not like fully appreciate her until it's too late.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like he gives up.
Speaker 1: He doesn't interact with her that much.
Speaker 0: No, but he's also a jerk to the very end because even at the end, right, she really wants to go, you know, become a nun or whatever, and Genji is like,
Speaker 0: "No."
Speaker 0: He doesn't let her until, you know, basically ever.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Even though that's what she really wanted.
Speaker 1: She's very clearly trying to be a nun to kind of get away from his crap.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, Murasaki, you know, the author is named after her, right?
Speaker 0: You know, extremely important part, this whole grooming thing is like, I guess like it's almost like the main thread of the whole first two parts of the book, right?
Speaker 0: It's, I guess, bigger than any other threads.
Speaker 0: All right, so one more to get the Akashi lady, right?
Speaker 0: So Genji's like out in this, I guess, place called Akashi, I guess, I don't know.
Speaker 1: And he gets with this Akashi lady- That was when the after exile, he went with that captain, right?
Speaker 0: It was hard to follow.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And it was so early in the book, I read it like at least a year ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I want to say he goes out there with her, with him, and that dude is just like, "Holy shit, Genji's perfect, and I think he has the hottest of my daughter.
Speaker 1: I have to make sure they have
Speaker 1: sex.".
Speaker 0: But anyway, the Akashi lady, right?
Speaker 0: You know, Genji likes her, I guess.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: And she ends up, you know, moving to his house, but she sort of just like lives in the house quietly on her own, off in a corner somewhere, and doesn't get a lot of attention from anybody.
Speaker 0: She's just sort of like, "Well, I guess, you know, I got with Genji once, and now I live here, and I guess I'm living comfortably.
Speaker 0: Okay.".
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But that's his father.
Speaker 1: The father was, I'm pretty sure it was her father, was just really trying to get them together, vaguely hoping Genji would marry her, just to give her wealth and a better life.
Speaker 1: There was definitely a sitcom plot around them conspiring to get Genji to like her enough to maybe marry her.
Speaker 1: It was like this long shot.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the Akashi lady's daughter ends up being a huge plot point in the second half of the book, because this whole thing of Genji trying to set her up with a good life and get her married to the right person, right?
Speaker 0: He ends up being able to get her married to the emperor, ends up being the fourth emperor, right?
Speaker 0: He basically sets her up with the heir, while the third emperor, Reize, is the emperor.
Speaker 0: He gets her set up with the heir, who's still a kid at the time.
Speaker 1: Reize, remember, is Genji's actual child with his fake mom.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: So when Genji's biological son is the emperor, he gets the Akashi lady's daughter, hooked up with his, I guess, his grandson, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, because the fourth emperor would be... Oh no, because the fourth emperor isn't the son of Reize.
Speaker 1: No, the fourth emperor is the child of the second emperor, Suzaku.
Speaker 1: Let me find that fucking chart that you sent me before.
Speaker 1: I got a tab open here somewhere.
Speaker 0: The second emperor's son is the fourth emperor.
Speaker 1: Yes, Suzaku emperor married someone on the right, and then that is the emperor that the Akashi princess.
Speaker 1: That's sort of what I meant about a sort of constructed feeling that maybe we'll talk about more in the meta show, where the first two-thirds of this book is almost like the map of relationships just centers around Genji directly, because that's what's driving the story.
Speaker 1: But the last third of the book almost feels like the author took those relationships and constructed the drama they wanted from all the characters that were available from the first part of the book.
Speaker 1: That's just kind of how it felt to me as the reader.
Speaker 0: And so then you come to, I guess, in the second part of the book, where Genji's got the house and everything, there's a major drama that develops with regards to Suzaku's daughter, So Suzaku has a bunch of... The second emperor, Suzaku, has a bunch of daughters.
Speaker 1: The one who was emperor when Genji was exiled, partly because of drama from his own family.
Speaker 1: He liked Genji.
Speaker 0: His half brother.
Speaker 0: So his half brother has daughters, but the half brother is going to go into the mountains to live.
Speaker 1: Well, because he had to advocate because he was probably sick.
Speaker 1: He couldn't do his job anymore.
Speaker 0: And so he's trying to get these daughters set up with good lives before he leaves.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So someone can support them.
Speaker 0: And he's basically Hemen and Haag.
Speaker 0: And the daughter he cares about most is the third one.
Speaker 0: He's got these other ones, but he cares about the third one the most.
Speaker 1: Well, because she's the daughter of the Fujitsubo.
Speaker 1: Like that line.
Speaker 0: Well, but she was the daughter.
Speaker 0: I forget if that was the... I forget which daughter is the one that like, you know, hangs a piece of paper on the post when they move out of the house.
Speaker 1: Oh, God.
Speaker 0: There was like a whole big thing about that.
Speaker 1: I think that was her.
Speaker 1: I always get confused with Fujitsubo.
Speaker 1: The Fujitsubo princess.
Speaker 1: Fujitsubo something happens a lot in that part of the book.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of names that are reused.
Speaker 0: For example, right.
Speaker 0: You know, Genji lives in a house called Rokujo.
Speaker 0: What is Rokujo?
Speaker 0: It's literally, you know, Hachi Roku, like Initial D. It's 6th Street.
Speaker 0: His house is on the 6th Street in the city where the palace is.
Speaker 1: Which was very obvious when I saw the map at the end of this book.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's another house called Ichijo.
Speaker 0: That's on the 1st Street.
Speaker 0: There's a different, like, noble house on each street.
Speaker 0: And the people, because it's, I guess, impolite to refer to them by name, they'll be like, oh, you know, when they talk about, like, you know, the Koki Den concert, that's like the concert that lives in the Koki Den.
Speaker 1: It's like I'm the Crescent Street podcaster.
Speaker 0: Like an area in the palace, the areas of the palace, the wings, have different names, and people get named after the wing that they live in or the house that they live in.
Speaker 1: Oh, Scott, I heard the Packard Square podcaster is talking about the tale of Genji with the Astoria podcaster.
Speaker 0: Right, exactly.
Speaker 0: That's how they're referring to people, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, oh, yeah, the Queens boy and the Texas boy, right?
Speaker 0: The Madison Avenue guy and the Times Square guy, you know, that's what's going on here.
Speaker 0: So that's why it gets confusing when people move, because people move, their name fucking changes, and it's some name someone else had before.
Speaker 0: They'll be like a Rokujo lady, and then there'll be another Rokujo lady who's not the same one as the last Rokujo lady.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: In fact, the Rokujo lady had a daughter that married, that was the daughter that married the emperor that was Genji's son, the Reizei emperor.
Speaker 0: So, the second emperor is trying to figure out, you know, I gotta give this third princess that's my most important princess, I gotta get her the best husband, who do I give her to?
Speaker 1: The best person I know, Genji.
Speaker 0: Right, he's like, he thinks about all these other options, he doesn't like Genji.
Speaker 0: You can tell he recognizes the reasons not to go for Genji, which there are many.
Speaker 0: But when he looks at everyone else, he's like, I guess it'll be Genji then, right?
Speaker 1: I got the impression he had mixed feelings, because he liked Genji in some ways.
Speaker 1: He's actually pretty nice to Genji, considering what he knows Genji did.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: But anyway, so, Genji ends up sort of being forced to marry this princess that he's not really interested in.
Speaker 1: Well, the emperor publicly asks him, meaning, he can't say no, there's no consequence of saying no except personal ruin.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: And so the book portrays this third princess, right, basically as an annoying child, right, that doesn't, you know, she's not very talented, whatever, but Genji's forced to spend a lot of time with her, even though he doesn't want to, just because he has to, right?
Speaker 0: And then Murasaki, the groomed wife that he actually likes, you know, is upset about that.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: Why aren't you spending time with me?
Speaker 1: Why are you spending time with this annoying- You spent all this time grooming me, and now you're not even gonna hang around with that brat?
Speaker 1: Great.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna go be a nun.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: So, you know, Genji doesn't, you know, actually seem to like the third princess, but he's sort of forced into it, he doesn't have much of a choice.
Speaker 0: And so now he's got like four ladies living in his house, all in different wings, all with different names, but, you know, basically this third princess and Murasaki are the ones that matter in terms of the plot the most.
Speaker 1: Now, one thing that I thought was really interesting about that, as like the house in particular, was that throughout the book, you get glimpses of, like, all the women are cloistered separately from the men, obviously, and when we're zoomed in, we usually see all the men talking to each other, or Genji talking to, like, a woman through a screen.
Speaker 0: Well, they're usually also talking to people, not directly, but through messaging.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, like through Yu Gao.
Speaker 1: Yu Gao is like Genji's go-to, like, get a message.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like they, you know, they talk to someone, and then the person goes and tells, you know, it's like a little back and forth with their servants sharing the messages between them, or always writing letters all the time.
Speaker 1: But it always, every time those things happen, it's clear that in the, like, on the side of the screen that the book doesn't portray, where all the women are hanging out, the women, like, all read the love letters together, and, like, they all know what's going on.
Speaker 0: It'll be like a woman with, like, all of her, you know, I guess maidens and all sorts of, you know, retainers, and all these, like, a whole group of people.
Speaker 0: You're not just talking to this one person, right?
Speaker 0: It's like they always have people near them.
Speaker 1: Like, when Genji writes some letters, the women are like, "You've got to respond to him, otherwise we look bad.
Speaker 1: Like, go have sex with him.
Speaker 1: Seriously, come
Speaker 1: on.".
Speaker 0: They're like, "Oh, this dude's so hot.
Speaker 0: Why don't you want to bang him?
Speaker 0: I'll bang him for
Speaker 0: you.".
Speaker 1: "Can I bang him for you?
Speaker 1: He won't even
Speaker 1: know.".
Speaker 1: That happens, like... But, uh, so, it felt like there was tons of drama just behind the screen that was, like, not really portrayed directly during those chapters of the book.
Speaker 1: Like, you get the impression all the women of the house were having all this drama around, like, the Genji situation, but that was just an undercurrent because the books... I don't think the books really ever go behind the screen except the one time where Genji's back there and he gets caught during that storm in, like, the 18th or 19th chapter.
Speaker 0: I mean, there are times where they talk about, like, "Oh, yeah, the people were busy and were elsewhere, so someone was able to get around and make
Speaker 0: mischief.".
Speaker 0: And so that is actually one of the most important parts where Kashiwagi, right, who's this guy?
Speaker 0: the Intendant, right?
Speaker 0: The Intendant is, like, sort of like a lesser Genji.
Speaker 0: You know, he's a talented... He was Genji's friend.
Speaker 0: He's a talented, wonderful dude, right?
Speaker 0: But he's actually in love with this third princess that Genji has been forced upon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but he marries the other princess.
Speaker 0: Right, he's legally married to the second princess, but he doesn't really like her, and she, you know, is like... Right?
Speaker 0: He likes the third princess.
Speaker 0: And the third princess is legally married to Genji, but doesn't really...
Speaker 1: Well, she's just annoying and a problem generally.
Speaker 0: Right, but Kashiwagi actually loves the third princess, and so he eventually finds that, you know, he keeps going there and calling on her and finding excuses to get closer to her and whatnot, even though she stays so distant from him.
Speaker 1: Kind of like what Genji was doing in the entire first third of the book.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: He just keeps trying, and, you know, Genji's friends with him.
Speaker 0: Genji likes him, so it's not that, you know, awkward for him to be around, hanging around his house, you know.
Speaker 1: But then his daughter is Kaworu.
Speaker 1: Son.
Speaker 1: His son is Kaworu.
Speaker 0: Right, so he gets, finally, you know, the right timing, right, when there's not a lot of ladies behind the screen, besides that third princess.
Speaker 0: And he goes in there and makes his non-consensual move, right, as is so often in this book.
Speaker 1: It was... The thing that was interesting is, in the earlier parts of the book, the less consensual and non-consensual sexual encounters were much more, like, vaguely described.
Speaker 1: This one was very much more, like, "Now's my
Speaker 1: chance!"
Speaker 1: and he, like, storms in.
Speaker 1: Like, it was much more abrupt and it felt more violent the way it was written.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, this book will never say, like, in it, like, "They fucked," but the book will be like, "Ah, yes.
Speaker 0: They, uh, you know, he stayed there
Speaker 0: late.".
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: It's like, "Wink,
Speaker 0: wink!".
Speaker 0: You know, it's that kind of deal.
Speaker 0: But this scene was, like, yes, he stormed through the curtain and carried her, you know.
Speaker 0: It's, like, up.
Speaker 0: He's, like, picked her up.
Speaker 0: He's got his hands on her and they actually said that.
Speaker 0: It's, like, up.
Speaker 0: They did it.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: They made babies.
Speaker 0: And sure enough...
Speaker 1: They made one baby, at least.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the baby that they make, the Intendant and the Third Princess, right, is Kaoru, who's the main character of the final part of the book.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Who is, you know, I guess legally Genji's son, but biologically almost definitely the Intendant Kashiwagi's son.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: Oh, and so in this chart...
Speaker 0: That's the major drama of the second part.
Speaker 1: ...in this chart I'm looking at to remember the names of all these characters.
Speaker 1: So, this chart is great because it has a line for formal marriage, a line for child of doubtful parentage, which is what they use for that.
Speaker 1: Then there's a line for sexual relations without issue, and a line for sexual relations with issue.
Speaker 0: Mhm, mhm.
Speaker 1: And that describes the tale of Genji more than anything.
Speaker 1: It's those four types of relationships.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: So that's pretty much the plot of, you know, all the significant plot points.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of other little tiny side stories here and there that are brief or whatnot.
Speaker 1: There's one chapter that's basically just like... There was a chapter that really confused me.
Speaker 1: It was around a little bit after the exile time, but reading, skimming over some footnotes, apparently that one was mostly allegory to well-known Chinese literature that anyone reading this book in a contemporary time would have known.
Speaker 1: We just didn't know.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: So, that's the plot, right?
Speaker 0: As a plot goes, there are some parts of it that are interesting or compelling or dramatic, but overall, it's not like trying to say anything like a lot of modern novels do.
Speaker 1: I think the third bit, like the college years after Genji dies, it might have been trying to say a little more, because think about how it actually ends.
Speaker 1: It ends with the...
Speaker 0: Abruptly.
Speaker 1: But it ends abruptly with these sort of pseudo-Genji, like the cycle repeats, similar stories keep happening, but the difference is, he goes to like do the grand gesture to get the woman back after he uncovers that her death was faked and she's actually like okay.
Speaker 1: And she's just like, nope, fuck you.
Speaker 1: And then it ends.
Speaker 1: Like, nope, this isn't going to keep happening.
Speaker 0: Alright, so, just other things about the story itself, right?
Speaker 0: So, you get this plot, and even though you could talk, you could describe the plot in much more detail, there are more things going on, but the ratio of words to things that happen is really low.
Speaker 1: Especially considering the words don't often describe anything in particular, they tend to just set the mood for a scene.
Speaker 0: Well, set a mood for a scene or describe in ridiculous detail everything, like things that don't matter, right?
Speaker 0: So they'll be like, if there's a festival going on, you could have several pages where they're like, this song was sung, and this person played this instrument, and they sounded great, and this person played this instrument in this mode, and they weren't as great, right?
Speaker 0: And these flowers were blooming and they smelled like this.
Speaker 1: But then one sense in the middle of that will be like, oh yeah, this person's dead now.
Speaker 1: And you're like, wait, wait, what?
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're literally, it can't get over that like, oh yeah, this emperor died and the next emperor took over, and fast forward, like in a paragraph, in the middle of a paragraph.
Speaker 0: Like events, significant events in the world, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you got a chapter that took you an hour to read, you know, and half of it was just incredibly detailed descriptions of flowers or poems or whatever, right?
Speaker 0: And nothing happening, nothing advancing, none of the dramatic, you know, current circumstances being addressed, maybe not even any dialogue happening at all.
Speaker 0: And then maybe something will happen, right?
Speaker 0: So if you just, I think, you know, there is an abridged edition, which we declined to read, and I guess that's good.
Speaker 1: I'm glad we read the unabridged version because I feel like we would have lost, like there's a lot of just mood and feeling that I could have internalized reading something so old.
Speaker 1: I'm glad I did it.
Speaker 0: But if you want just the plot, you can cut this book down a lot.
Speaker 0: The plot could probably be, if you just tried to write the plot only, think, you know, characters doing things, things happening, and you use modern language even, you know, you could chop this thing down.
Speaker 0: 80% or more could just be done.
Speaker 1: This is something I actually don't want to dwell on because, one, we've gone almost an hour already and I want to save this for the more meta show, but something that struck me, there was a specific moment, again, around The Exile, because the writing style changed.
Speaker 1: Like a lot of things shift around that time, not just the plot and the characters like Genji growing up, but I think that around that is the first time a chapter ends and the next chapter just picks up where the previous one left off.
Speaker 1: Like it's the same contiguous story.
Speaker 1: A lot of the earlier chapters, like a chapter ends and the next chapter is like three years later and Genji's with a totally different set of people.
Speaker 0: Well, there's also times where it's like you'll have a chapter and they'll be like, this chapter covers from when Genji's 23 to when he's 24.
Speaker 0: It's like, okay.
Speaker 0: And the next chapter will be like, oh, this chapter covers from when Genji's 22 to 25.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like, yeah, there'll be like.
Speaker 0: on a modern book, what you would do is you would keep things quite often, you know, sometimes unintentionally, you know, you would unintentionally.
Speaker 0: or sometimes in a modern book, you'll intentionally, you know, not be chronological, but in a clever way.
Speaker 1: Like the best example of this I've seen in my modern reading of anything is that one culture book, Use of Weapons.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So imagine, think about this in my life, right?
Speaker 0: So imagine I was still commuting to work, right?
Speaker 0: So I have my work life and then I have podcast convention life, right?
Speaker 0: So if you were going to write my life as a book, you'd be like, chapter one, Scott goes to work.
Speaker 0: Chapter two, Scott comes home from working podcasts.
Speaker 0: Chapter three, Scott goes back to work.
Speaker 1: Chapter one, the paxes Scott went to for these four years.
Speaker 1: Chapter two, Scott's job for these four years.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So it's like it becomes really hard to tell, like, well, at the third pax in chapter two, it's like, was that like before or after the drama at Scott's work in chapter four?
Speaker 1: But I think part of that is that those worlds rarely intersect in this story.
Speaker 1: The things that happen in two different threads do not affect each other.
Speaker 1: That breaks a little bit in the last third, though.
Speaker 1: And that's sort of the stuff we want to talk about in the meta episode, because those later chapters, there's so much more like this character went here and did this and is talking to this person sitting in this place.
Speaker 1: And then you get a bunch of dialogue that is like way more modern dialogue.
Speaker 1: It goes longer.
Speaker 1: It's structured more like a modern novel.
Speaker 1: If you read chapter one of Genji and then chapter like forty eight of Genji back to back, they would not feel like they're the same book or the same author.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But I guess in the case of Genji, you know, this sort of split up will be like, OK, Genji was courting three ladies at once.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But we're going to have one chapter that's going to tell you all the instances of Genji courting Lady one.
Speaker 0: And then the next chapter will be all the instances of Genji courting Lady two, even though those things were happening concurrently.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: There are two separate plots.
Speaker 0: We're going to tell them to you in separate chapters.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: And so it becomes confusing, though, when you're trying to follow the sequence of who's who, what's happening, et cetera.
Speaker 1: But it almost like to read this book to enjoy if you're listening to this, but you chose not to read the book for whatever reason, we were alluding to this in our meta moments along the way.
Speaker 1: If you just sort of roll with it, it is actually an enjoyable read if you're just willing to not fully understand exactly what happened when.
Speaker 1: Like the story of all his interactions with Fujitsubo, really compelling story like this is an adult and a man child having drama and it's a pretty good story.
Speaker 1: But if you try to like chronologically remember exactly how that lines up with him going after Mers, just don't don't do not try.
Speaker 1: It's not worth the effort unless you're doing lit crit on this book.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I think the only reason to read the unabridged as we did is if you want to get all of that historical context, you know, poetry, all you want to get all those extra meta bits in there.
Speaker 0: If you just want to enjoy the story that is happening here, I would strongly recommend going for an adaptation.
Speaker 0: I'm sure there's a manga that I've heard is good.
Speaker 1: Emily's read a bunch of it because she's been doing Japanese lessons online for a long time.
Speaker 1: And what they do is like read this manga together and talk about it in Japanese.
Speaker 1: Like that's a good way to brush up on your Japanese.
Speaker 1: But I kind of want to read this manga.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's translated anywhere.
Speaker 0: Oh, OK.
Speaker 1: I feel like that would clarify some of the nuances that I probably missed.
Speaker 0: But also just being able to see people's faces would help with the name issue.
Speaker 1: You know, it'd be really funny if the manga is just Genji sitting in front of various differently drawn blinds for the entire thing.
Speaker 0: But then you could remember which curtain was which based on what's drawn.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But also, if you just read it, like just rolling through it, there are so many legitimately really, really funny scenes.
Speaker 1: There's the scene where he's having said they're having sex secretly and like the servants are right outside.
Speaker 1: Remember, like their beds are so like this woman is in a bed that is surrounded by curtains, that is itself surrounded by blinds, that is itself in a room that has windows that are covered by their own blinds with guards outside.
Speaker 1: Genji is in there.
Speaker 1: They're having sex.
Speaker 1: And then a thunderstorm happens and the captain of the guard runs in to check on the women because he's one of the few men allowed to go to that room.
Speaker 1: Guess who's hiding?
Speaker 1: Like that whole scene is really funny.
Speaker 1: or the old lady he's having sex with where the husband finds out and it's just like, "Yeah, I'm too old for this shit.
Speaker 1: You were welcome to sexually pleasure my wife, like by all
Speaker 1: means.".
Speaker 1: And if you read the like read the Tale of Genji to get those scenes, I feel like it's better to enjoy them in the utter bridge version just because you're almost reading and it takes you a minute to realize what's actually happening.
Speaker 1: And suddenly it's really funny when you realize like, "Oh, oh shit, he's actually in that room right now.
Speaker 1: Oh, I get it.
Speaker 1: I get
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like somehow if you just read and read and read and don't stop, don't try to go back and understand the sentence.
Speaker 0: It's like that barest hint of what happened that you smelled from afar, even though there's no clarity.
Speaker 0: It's like a blurry haze, but you can sort of make out a little bit what happened.
Speaker 0: If you just keep going, when you reach the end of like a big long paragraph, it'll still be a fuzzy picture, but it'll be enough.
Speaker 0: And you'll understand enough to enjoy and follow.
Speaker 1: He's trying to have sex with, I think he was trying to have sex with Fujitsu Bo early on, and he fucks up and ends up in like the wrong servants quarters.
Speaker 1: So he basically just has sex with this random woman who's just sleeping there like quietly.
Speaker 1: And later on, he's like, "Oh shit, I don't want to know who that
Speaker 1: is.".
Speaker 1: There's another time where he has sex with that woman, he doesn't know what she looks like.
Speaker 1: And then he does shenanigans to figure out who it is, and he sees her, and she's really ugly, and he's mad, and you go.
Speaker 1: Loki makes fun of him for a while about it.
Speaker 0: I guess I get.
Speaker 0: one last thing is that the book has, surprisingly, a lot of supernatural stuff going on.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, so it's not that first ghost murder I talk about a lot just because that's really early on, but Genji's wife was murdered by the spirit of another character who is still alive, and that is treated as absolutely real in this story.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's people who are sick, Buddhist priests, monks come in and try to pray the spirits away, and then people who are sick will suddenly rise up and start talking because the spirit that was possessing them and making them sick is trying to tell you what they're mad about.
Speaker 0: That happens at least twice, I think.
Speaker 0: That kind of thing.
Speaker 1: Yep, there are just ghosts and spirits.
Speaker 1: Genji has a vision right before he goes out of exile where the dragon turtle king is like, "Hey, I got a daughter," and Genji's like, "I gotta get the fuck out of
Speaker 1: town.".
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And the other thing is that there's a lot of disease going around.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, I mean, look, how many emperors abdicate because they're dying in their 40s of malaria?
Speaker 0: Right, well Genji, that's basically the thing, Genji lives as long as he does despite having malaria.
Speaker 0: But it's like, other diseases are not so specific, you probably couldn't figure out what they were without, maybe you could never figure them out, because there's not enough information in the book, or some scholar knows,
Speaker 1: but
Speaker 0: you can see a lot of people get sick with various things at various times, their medical technology is not great.
Speaker 0: There's just lots of sickness and unwellness is a frequent plot point amongst many people from Genji's legal wife, the Aoi, that he was forced to marry when he was young that he doesn't care about, up through everybody.
Speaker 1: But I guess what I'd leave you with on this is, the plot by itself, like if you read a summary of the plot, there's not much there and it's not that interesting.
Speaker 1: It's only interesting to read summaries of the plot after you've read a bunch of the actual text to sort of bring it together, because the value, like what I enjoyed about this was reading the actual original text translated, and trying to just get myself into the mindset of this book from the year 1000-ish.
Speaker 1: So, if you didn't read it, honestly, you can find copies of it, just read the first four or five chapters, just read a little bit of it, even if you just listen to this whole thing, you'll find something to enjoy.
Speaker 0: I think you should only read it if you have some interest, some reason to be interested.
Speaker 0: If you're just a person who likes to read a book and you pick this up as a book, you're probably not going to have a good time.
Speaker 0: But if you care about history or poetry or culture or anything like that, then you're going to get the extra value from reading the actual text.
Speaker 1: I have this old book, I think I got rid of it eventually, I think we gave it away or I donated or something, but I had this book that I got at Atlantic Books long, long ago, and it was a collection of essays from Japanese authors in various ancient times.
Speaker 1: It was that kind of book, the kind of book Rim would buy in Wildwood.
Speaker 1: But the first essay in that book, because I didn't read beyond that, this book was thick, was this guy from 1200s Japan, and he was reading ancient Chinese literature and his essay, he was sort of musing on how amazing it is to read the words a person from a thousand years ago wrote a thousand years later.
Speaker 1: And that stuck with me, especially because I was reading someone who himself had written that many hundreds of years before I came in, and humans have been doing this forever.
Speaker 1: So even if you don't do it with the Tale of Genji, do it with something.
Speaker 1: Read an old book.
Speaker 0: We read The Odyssey.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like read something old at least once.
Speaker 1: And honestly, The Odyssey, the Emily Wilson translation, it is really, really accessible, like way more than you'd think from a book written in BC.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So yeah, we're going to do one more.
Speaker 0: Since we put so much effort into reading this incredibly long book over such a long period of time, we are going to do at least one more episode.
Speaker 0: We're going to talk about not the actual content of the story, but all sorts of meta stuff around the book.
Speaker 1: I got so much to say I've been holding back on in this episode.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So we'll let that all out because clearly we need to, and we need episode ideas, especially for Thursday.
Speaker 0: So you might as well.
Speaker 0: But we've also, Rym, selected another book.
Speaker 0: And this book is a S-tier book that is very, the opposite of the Tale of Genji.
Speaker 0: And relatively speaking, it is like, you know, extremely new novel.
Speaker 0: And I, when I knew that it existed, I said, "I am reading the fuck out of
Speaker 0: that.".
Speaker 0: Even before Rym selected it as the book club book, I knew I was going to read the fuck out of it.
Speaker 0: But I said, when I, when I heard of the book's existence, I thought to myself two things.
Speaker 0: The first thing I thought was it's going to be a series.
Speaker 0: It's the first book in a series.
Speaker 0: Therefore, I'm going to hold out and not read it until that series is done.
Speaker 0: Rym foiled that plan by selecting it as a book club book.
Speaker 1: Because I learned, Emily read it, so I got a lot of like, "Rym, you should read it.
Speaker 1: Here's a thing about the book that will intrigue
Speaker 1: you.".
Speaker 1: And everything Emily said was very much, "Hey, Rym, we have to read this
Speaker 1: book.".
Speaker 0: I knew I had to read this book.
Speaker 0: I just wanted to wait to read the book.
Speaker 1: So the next book club book is?
Speaker 0: Wait, wait, wait.
Speaker 0: So then the second thing that I thought to myself was we should not select this as a book club book.
Speaker 0: Because I don't want to keep doing authors.
Speaker 0: We already did.
Speaker 0: I like, we got to mix it up.
Speaker 1: You are Scott Becker.
Speaker 1: You've, uh, you're, you're, you have decelerated at a rate that is worrying to me.
Speaker 0: But anyway, this is Rym's choice.
Speaker 1: The City We Became by N.K.
Speaker 1: Jemisin.
Speaker 0: I am already, so it took us two and a half years, however long, since June 2020 to read the Tale of Genji.
Speaker 0: I started reading this book this year and it's only February 3rd.
Speaker 0: I am 80% done with this book.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Partly because you were under the misa- The day it was announced, I'm 80% done already.
Speaker 1: You were under the misapprehension that I had already read it and we could knock out a book club book.
Speaker 1: I have not read this book yet.
Speaker 1: I read the prologue and then I stopped on purpose because I was going to, I committed to finishing Genji.
Speaker 1: I finished fucking Genji.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So we have the opposite problem now where we need to give the listener time to read the book if they haven't already.
Speaker 0: So listener will probably do an episode on this book in, I guess, March, April at the earliest, right?
Speaker 0: Give you some time to get the book and read it.
Speaker 0: Of course, it didn't take me that long at all.
Speaker 0: I'm going to be done probably in two, three sittings more at the most because it's easy to read.
Speaker 0: Compared to Genji, oh God, it's easy to read.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It is.
Speaker 1: It is kind of like how we played some PUBG the other day.
Speaker 1: And then when I played Fortnite the next night, it was like, wow, this is just such a breath of fresh air.
Speaker 1: Like it does not take effort.
Speaker 1: I can just enjoy this.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Also, now that I don't have any guilt of like I'm reading, you know, because I felt guilty whenever I read something that wasn't Genji.
Speaker 0: Like I should be reading Genji.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: I've got this great book that is like the history of liberalism as a concept in human history.
Speaker 1: And I forced myself to stop reading it because I wanted to finish Genji.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But now that that guilt is gone, I am like reading, you know, not just this book, but like all reading like, you know, comics and also like voraciously like, ah, I don't, I can't, I don't have to feel guilty reading this other stuff.
Speaker 0: I'm just reading up a storm now.
Speaker 0: So, uh, you know, and I already got some good ideas for a book club book after we read this one.
Speaker 0: I guess that would be the summer reading book, right?
Speaker 0: So we'll see.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: We're finally, we're finally halfway done with this Genji.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: And the Patreon patrons for this much awaited episode of the Geek Nights Book Club are... Heidi McNichol, Alan Joyce, Lynn Geegee, Dread Lily Tenerbrait, and a bunch of people who really don't want me to say their names.
Speaker 1: Chris Addad, Chris Reimer, Clinton Walton, Dex, Finn, Kishiai85, Rebecca Dunn, ReviewMedBull34Coward, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Horl, Taylor Braun.
Speaker 1: The next station is Davisville, Davisville Station, and several people whose Patreon names I will not say.
Speaker 1: It took us a while, like Scott said.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we got some excuses.
Speaker 1: Only about 20% of that delay was intrinsic to us.
Speaker 1: The rest was due to circumstance.
Speaker 1: But anyway, for now, I simply leave you with...