Speaker 1: It's Thursday, May 12th, 2022.
Speaker 1: I'm rim Scott's yawning.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is gig nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We are talking about swimming.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So, uh, I was involved in a biking incident on my way to work this morning.
Speaker 1: a minor one But there's a. there's a light getting into biking incidents a minor one, but on the way home I I was not involved in any biking incidents.
Speaker 1: However, I Witness One of the bigger bike dramas I have ever seen like on my commute.
Speaker 1: It was seen a few.
Speaker 0: how big could it be?
Speaker 1: It was moderately big because it kept escalating and as I was biking home I'd get to the next red light and encounter more of the like follow-up of this drama.
Speaker 1: Okay, so, uh on the way to work pretty straightforward I was biking to work and a cab Cut across two lanes suddenly and just went straight across the bike lane Hit the front of my city bike and then like screeched to a halt like right then.
Speaker 1: So they bonked the city bike and there's a little dent in their hood.
Speaker 1: I was fine.
Speaker 1: The city bike weighs 50 pounds.
Speaker 1: I'm just sitting there and then the cab rolls down his window and he starts yelling at me Like it's my mate.
Speaker 0: So there's wait.
Speaker 0: so they cut across two lanes.
Speaker 0: They're making a left.
Speaker 1: they were making a left like but not from the left most not from the left most from the leftmost lane.
Speaker 1: and With a the bike.
Speaker 1: there was one of those bike Greenlight saying bikes had the right-of-way and the red left turn.
Speaker 1: the light for red for left turns for cars was red.
Speaker 0: So you see you bonked into the side of the cab like a tee like the fronts like a very no left.
Speaker 0: You were going straight.
Speaker 1: I was going straight left.
Speaker 1: He went left.
Speaker 1: if it been a car it would be like a t-bone accident probably and I saw him coming.
Speaker 1: but city bikes Can't stop that quick.
Speaker 0: Even if you're going to jump off that you could always jump off the back.
Speaker 1: I thought about it, but he was already like tires were screeching.
Speaker 1: There was a little bonk and a little dent.
Speaker 1: so he starts to yell at me.
Speaker 1: So I just looked at him and I kicked the side of the cab and I put a dent in his door.
Speaker 1: I just biked away.
Speaker 1: Okay, that was the end of that.
Speaker 1: like city bike was unharmed.
Speaker 1: But on the way home, so I'm biking and I get past Really aggressively by this fixie guy.
Speaker 1: He whistles at me and like passes.
Speaker 1: He's just weaving like crazy.
Speaker 1: Whatever people like that all the time.
Speaker 1: so There's a red light up ahead and a ton of bikers are just stopped at the red light in that tiny little narrow bike path.
Speaker 1: I'm like First Avenue and I'm pulling up.
Speaker 1: I'm slowing down ready to just stop and wait for the light
Speaker 0: and
Speaker 1: The fixie guy is stuck in this group and he starts kind of shoving his way through the people like he's albowing people out of the way Physically gets his bike to the front and then he just like runs through the red light in front of some cars and keeps going.
Speaker 1: Whatever that happens.
Speaker 1: So light turns green.
Speaker 1: I go with all the bikers I see I up ahead.
Speaker 1: that guy is now again at the next red light and he's already.
Speaker 1: It's clearly like trying to get through the red light.
Speaker 1: He does that bike maneuver.
Speaker 1: that always annoys me.
Speaker 1: that fixie people do the most where they don't want to run the red light directly.
Speaker 1: so they kind of turn onto the street and Like the cross street and they go down it and do a little loop and come back up the other side to just sort of Skip the red light.
Speaker 1: so he does this and on his way He his handlebar clips a scooter guy on his backpack pulls him off his bike and like he falls over And the guy's like, ah, hey and the fixie guy turns around flips him off and keeps biking.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So that is that is not even worthy of being a geek.
Speaker 1: I like an open ebit.
Speaker 1: so far Here's where it gets fun.
Speaker 1: So Scooter guy like gets up dust himself off and light turns green.
Speaker 1: He goes off ahead and I go off ahead and now we're just biking straight.
Speaker 1: I see the fixie guy.
Speaker 1: then behind him is scooter guy and behind scooter guy is me.
Speaker 1: We're just going.
Speaker 1: Scooter guy goes to the right a little bit Speeds up and gets ahead of fixie guy and then rams him from the side.
Speaker 1: Fixie guy flips over his handlebars goes spinning the his front tire is like bent.
Speaker 1: his phone Shatters on the ground and he's bleeding and I stopped to help him like dude.
Speaker 1: Are you okay?
Speaker 1: He gets up and he doesn't want to help.
Speaker 1: He's like chase that guy.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna beat the shit out of him.
Speaker 0: So I'm just like dude, honestly is already a violent and there's already a violent angry dude Beforehand, so I'm just like.
Speaker 1: so I just look at him.
Speaker 1: I'm like, you know what fuck you.
Speaker 1: I'm on scooter guy side I tell him that and I bike off.
Speaker 0: So then I mean, I'm not I'm not an either of those people side, right?
Speaker 0: They're violent aggressive people who deserve each other.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, it's like if that you know, if that dude was driving a car, he'd be a road rage dude, right?
Speaker 1: That's like and I'm of you feel like with cars One road rage should be a one strike and you never drive again Like you are too dangerous to be in charge of a vehicle ever.
Speaker 0: I think you would be.
Speaker 0: you're definitely a borderline road rage person.
Speaker 1: I have never in my life Never once never even Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Honestly, why would you?
Speaker 1: I would even say something like that.
Speaker 0: I uh-huh Why are you kidding?
Speaker 0: Why are you kicking some guy's door putting a dent in it?
Speaker 1: Cuz he was yelling at me.
Speaker 1: He almost hit me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well you caught your wave your middle finger at people all the time.
Speaker 1: But that's New York That's just a friendly.
Speaker 1: Hello.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I See if I'm in any of those situations, I just go.
Speaker 0: yeah, I know calmly calmly go out my way.
Speaker 1: So it's just like all right, so Fixie guy eventually passes me.
Speaker 1: cuz he's chasing scooter guy And he catches up to him and tries to fight with him and scooter guy.
Speaker 1: at this point It's just like like he kind of shrugs and just feeds off and they were racing and I finally lost sight of them After they both almost got hit by a truck because they ran a red light while they were fighting with each other mmm, and Then at the very end of all this there's an old guy who'd been puttering along kind of next to me the whole time on a city bike same as me and he Pulls up next to me and he just turns to me and says that was really funny And I'm just like
Speaker 0: kind of was.
Speaker 1: and then he laughs and then I bike tell me here I am.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, I feel like.
Speaker 0: You know, there are definitely people in society who for whatever reason me not being a psychologist or anything.
Speaker 0: It's like I. just what the fuck Do I know right?
Speaker 0: It's like they're looking for a fight like there are clearly people who are Permanently or temporarily angry and not the kind of angry that that you know, I have.
Speaker 0: we're like, I'm angry at an unjust society.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'm not like the sharp anger of like say you're driving a car and you did just get t-boned by someone around a red light You would justifiably be very angry about that situation.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't be angry.
Speaker 0: I'd be like, oh my god I want don't want to die.
Speaker 1: I mean after like say you're fine and it happened I'd be angry that well be late to wherever I was going because somebody broke the law and assaulted me.
Speaker 0: Well, I'd be angry at the unjust society for being car centric, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, of course Anger already exists.
Speaker 0: I'll be like.
Speaker 0: well another example of the thing I'm already justifiably angry about but this is the road rage kind of anger, right?
Speaker 0: You're a person who yells you're a person who is trying to hurt other people.
Speaker 0: You're a person who will Physically, you know, you know yell or worse act aggressively, you know in a disproportionate Response to things that happen near or adjacent to you or within your vision, right?
Speaker 0: You know those sort people who behave in that way Right certainly exist In some quantity and They act in that way some percentage of their lives.
Speaker 0: That is more than average.
Speaker 1: Well, it's There it's the disk.
Speaker 0: and in response in that way in acting that way Those people are you know harming?
Speaker 0: Society right that society is less healthy the more people are doing that right.
Speaker 1: so we need Demick society level interventions to try to understand this and stop it.
Speaker 0: Yes There needs to be something that's like, you know Hey, even if you haven't, you know fucking murdered anybody or beat anyone up or anything like that, right?
Speaker 0: It's like if you're an angry kind of person Right, who's?
Speaker 0: you know acting this way and you know causing angry scenes or you know, whatever It's like you're not a person that you know should be allowed to say operate heavy machinery or That's why so much on children.
Speaker 1: It's three factors.
Speaker 1: the factors are a disproportionate response to a situation repeatedly having these disproportionate responses.
Speaker 1: and the disproportionate response is in the context of something like You're in control of a multi-ton death machine or you are a cop with a gun.
Speaker 1: Because like a proportionate response like, you know you see two people and they like they almost hit each other with their cars and they both go fuck you and they honk their Horns and then they drive away.
Speaker 1: That's very different from up.
Speaker 1: someone gets cut off and then they like Follow someone else's car all the way home and get out screaming at them which happens kind of often actually in society.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, you know, there's the intersection of the T intersection out my house.
Speaker 0: They changed it, you know years ago right to make one of the streets a two-way street And it's very poorly designed.
Speaker 0: all kinds of accidents.
Speaker 0: one time a car crashed into the brick wall.
Speaker 0: It was you know, wow But you know, I've seen some.
Speaker 0: you know So little fender benders out there and most of the time you hear like screech bump, right?
Speaker 0: You look out the window and there's two people and they pull over Right and then they get out and they go mumble mumble mumble mumble insurance insurance insurance back in the car, right?
Speaker 0: Maybe there's a tow, you know, but you know, it's it's not it's not common But it does happen where one person gets out and it's like they're gonna you know They're gonna like be try to fight the other person, right?
Speaker 0: And it's like that's a person who needs some kind of help and that help should be forced upon them gets Interesting and trick for the benefit of society.
Speaker 0: This might be a topic for another show because Unrelatedly Emily I haven't read that's a topic for a show that should have a Psychologist or a psychiatrist.
Speaker 0: you get a guest.
Speaker 0: Oh cuz what the fuck do we know?
Speaker 1: Well, no, cuz.
Speaker 1: so Emily and I've randomly we've been reading a lot about road rage and those kinds of things.
Speaker 1: because uh-huh related to all this.
Speaker 1: well now because There was a bunch of studies many years ago.
Speaker 1: They're starting to add up that you know the lead poisoning I bought this is people who have lead poisoning have Objectively like this is a measurable effect Reduced impulse control increased anger and violence responses just across the board in their lives.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Yeah, that's well known.
Speaker 1: everyone in America who lived in America Especially in cities or near roads older than us has some amount of lead poisoning.
Speaker 1: We're one of the first generations when the lead atmosphere levels were lower.
Speaker 0: I mean, we might have lead poisoning from all those painted glass cups.
Speaker 1: but to Deficiencies in B vitamins like not not not not supplement nonsense, but more like Your diet is so bad that you are not getting enough B vitamins.
Speaker 1: It's also very strongly correlated to violence and poor impulse control Mmm, and third and this was the tricky one There is some emerging evidence that there is that if you look at broad populations There is one cluster of genes and people.
Speaker 1: it's not that people who have that cluster of gene variants are gonna be violent But a very high percentage of people who are in prison for violence have that gene cluster compared to other populations.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, there's a very thorny and complex conversation around all that could be a causation correlation problem, too.
Speaker 0: Right something about prisons causes people's genes to change, you know, who knows?
Speaker 1: Yep There's that.
Speaker 1: well So this even tracked kids in school who are?
Speaker 0: or hey The people who putting people in prison tend to put black people in prison.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, it does so.
Speaker 1: these gene clusters do not correlate to any physical demographics.
Speaker 1: Not like aid they correlate differently between men and women so far but not like black people versus white people versus Asian people Etc, but it's also could be it could be you know Low-income people tend to make babies with low-income people and in their neighborhoods.
Speaker 0: are you know, you know, oh, yeah but but what this all leads to is Suppose we discover that us some percentage of that's who police go after police don't that rich people in jail that often?
Speaker 1: so suppose we in?
Speaker 0: we discover that there is an environmental cause for some subset of violence in society in that we can say whoever whoever created that Environmental problem is a murder company put polluted.
Speaker 1: the polluting company should be held responsible But also crimes the people who were impacted by that where their crimes were likely caused by that Arguably less culpable in the crimes they committed.
Speaker 0: Yes The company that poisoned them should be to take that culpability.
Speaker 0: exactly.
Speaker 0: And did the P?
Speaker 0: in fact, you know the people who were poisoned should sue and get.
Speaker 0: you're right All right, you poison you.
Speaker 0: if so if I came along and I Poisoned you right with a poison that makes you rob a bank right on your own That sounds like a really good K drama to make poison that makes you rob banks, right?
Speaker 0: It's like I poisoned you and then you rob a bet.
Speaker 0: the poison makes you rob a bank.
Speaker 0: It's one of those mind-controlling fungus boys, and I'm not guilty of any parasite.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: it's like well rim wouldn't have robbed the bank if it wasn't for the parasite.
Speaker 0: So the parasite did it but Scott knowingly had the parasite and in knowingly put it on the rim.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or even if I negligently produced the parasite and put it on the rim, right?
Speaker 0: It's like I'm some I'm responsible for the bank robbery in some large sense more so than rim is right, right Alright, so in the news there is actually so.
Speaker 1: remember when kovat first hit like those early terrifying days and there was a meat shortage during that.
Speaker 1: Like there was a meat shortage.
Speaker 1: It was in the news.
Speaker 1: the government like the federal government everything shortage.
Speaker 1: well so that that's the news.
Speaker 1: and the federal government actually took a bunch of measures to Like.
Speaker 1: let meat packing companies Continue to operate despite the risk of kovat and reduce safety controls and all this stuff to like.
Speaker 1: get the meat supply going again.
Speaker 1: bad choices, uh, so It turns out this is actually pretty breaking news from today.
Speaker 1: There's a really big expose and Rolling Stone We now know there was never a meat shortage at any point.
Speaker 1: All of that was fabricated by the meat industry and they paid Lobbyists to bribe the US federal government and Trump and the Republicans to basically use this as an excuse To get rid of a bunch of OSHA controls and get and avoid all the kovat controls and kill a whole bunch of their very Low-income workers.
Speaker 0: that no surprise.
Speaker 1: There was never at any point a meat shortage during kovat.
Speaker 1: That was a Republican lie?
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course.
Speaker 0: No surprises.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And this article is a pretty in-depth expose of all of this.
Speaker 1: There's gonna be hearings now.
Speaker 1: There's a house select committee.
Speaker 1: that is like we might be criminal charges.
Speaker 1: This is all unfolding right now.
Speaker 0: I Mean, you know the problem is is you know again, how many times can we talk about this?
Speaker 0: Right if a company commits a crime basically nothing happens, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you need to have a situation where for companies commit crimes The CEOs go are the ones who.
Speaker 0: you know, it's like I'm all for abolishing prisons.
Speaker 0: But if we're gonna have prisons They should be filled with CEOs and not with someone who robbed a convenience store for a pack of gum, right?
Speaker 0: Oh or someone who robbed the drugstore for baby formula because there's a baby formula shortage It's real and their baby is starving.
Speaker 1: Oh, I did.
Speaker 1: Yeah that baby for formula shortage I don't think we have time to talk about it tonight.
Speaker 1: And also if you just heard about that from us, that's just a shame Goddamn, you're not reading news.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you heard about it here first Yeah, baby that point is a shortage is a big fucking deal and a lot of kids are gonna die.
Speaker 1: This is actually a huge crisis.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, it's been a crisis for a while, you know, even before that the current shortage It's like they're.
Speaker 0: you know, baby formula is real expensive and they weren't making enough of it.
Speaker 1: But now it's way like there isn't enough and there won't be for a long time now.
Speaker 0: anyway, the point is is that you know, you could see you could be a CEO and have a company that steals a billion dollars and Basically, you know not face any really life-changing consequences.
Speaker 0: and you can be you know a poor homeless person and rob a drugstore for $20 and at least spend a night in jail or something.
Speaker 1: well the salient line of always not if not worse the the line that gets repeated like the most succinct point is if a crime Has a punishment that is a fine Then that is actually simply a price tag.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like if you were I speed in a car.
Speaker 1: we could we could both pay any speeding ticket And it wouldn't even hurt us that much.
Speaker 1: But if a poor person gets pulled over for even speeding a little bit.
Speaker 0: They're fucked.
Speaker 0: We don't get.
Speaker 0: some countries scale it we don't we should.
Speaker 0: but even scaling it is not solving the problem.
Speaker 1: Nope well, the problem is cars.
Speaker 1: but Yes You got some news.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so there's that I talked about this in the night's forum.
Speaker 0: It's a kpop news, but it's it's actually not entirely kpop news.
Speaker 0: This is girl Alexa, right?
Speaker 0: That's you know, I think her real name is.
Speaker 0: I could look it up on Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: you can too.
Speaker 0: so go ahead but her stage name is Alexa and She's from Oklahoma.
Speaker 0: so she's a Korean American from Oklahoma and By you can read the whole story online of by circumstances, right?
Speaker 0: Similar to like the otaku dream that many nerds lived of like, you know going to Japan and you know Making animation like Stevie B or whatever, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah She ended up in Korea right as a kpop star in Korea despite being from Oklahoma And that you know.
Speaker 0: and was she super popular?
Speaker 0: not really right.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: she was on you know One of those competition shows and she got almost no screen time and did not win.
Speaker 0: and then a company Believed in her because she was quite talented and invested money in her and produced music for her and she was on the music shows.
Speaker 0: She didn't have a ton of fans, right, but she wasn't like, you know Absolute no one right?
Speaker 0: She was sort of I'd say if you had to rank kpop popularity from like what one being Someone you never heard of and had to disband immediately with no money and five being BTS She might be like a two or two and a half, right?
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So but you know, she was.
Speaker 0: you know, people who really followed kpop a lot could see her right, you know Recognize her and especially in the english-speaking kpop community international kpop community Knew her because she could speak fucking English right cuz she's from.
Speaker 0: So her content online was very accessible to people around the world.
Speaker 0: It didn't have to wait for it to be subtitled or anything like that.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: So she was getting around, you know, and Somehow in the United States they decided like the United States always foolishly does to try to take something that was popular in another country and Remake it in an American way And make it worse.
Speaker 0: right and you know, they did that with the mass singer show, right?
Speaker 0: Which is a Korean show and they did it with Eurovision, right?
Speaker 0: And so they remade Eurovision in the US.
Speaker 0: they called it American song contest and they had a competitor from each state and Thanks to Alexa's agent And I guess their quality business skills.
Speaker 0: They got her to be the representative from Oklahoma, huh?
Speaker 0: So this this kpop girl basically is representing Oklahoma really in musically nothing, Oklahoma.
Speaker 0: You would expect a country music right from Oklahoma.
Speaker 0: All right, nothing country going on here whatsoever.
Speaker 0: So it turns out that that show Was not a popular show.
Speaker 0: right people it was not killing it in the ratings Exactly, right.
Speaker 0: The mass singer thing I think ended up being more popular than than this one, right?
Speaker 0: Regardless She won because why a bunch of kpop people voted for her.
Speaker 0: That's why It's the power of kpop Right, even if they weren't like number one Alexa fans like, you know, she's their favorite person ever.
Speaker 0: It's like There.
Speaker 0: it's like there's a any kpop related person could have gone into this contest And as long as there was no other more popular kpop person the kpop community that you know Spoke English was gonna go and vote for them, right?
Speaker 0: And so she won the whole thing, right?
Speaker 0: And in fact, I think she broke that it was funny.
Speaker 0: I think she broke the trophy when she would.
Speaker 0: It was very funny.
Speaker 0: But it's just really interesting right to point out how Right, you know for all that there's many negative things to say about kpop.
Speaker 0: We can go on all day about that but this is an example of one of kpop's positive traits the industry's positive traits in that sort of positive trait right and that they just want to be successful and make money right.
Speaker 0: and Because it's an entertainment business, right?
Speaker 0: They don't give a shit if you're from Oklahoma, right?
Speaker 0: It's like if there's a way they can make money on you.
Speaker 0: It's like come on in right they'll accept.
Speaker 0: They got kpop people coming from, you know, all kinds of countries Thailand Japan Korea us, right?
Speaker 0: It's like they don't give it.
Speaker 0: You don't have to be Korean, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you don't speak Korean All right, you know just you know, well you learn enough words to go on TV, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you.
Speaker 0: as long as you can sing a dance All right, you can.
Speaker 0: you learn to sing the song and you don't know any other words.
Speaker 0: great It's like just come on.
Speaker 0: I think Alexis speaks better Korean than that.
Speaker 0: I'm not you know.
Speaker 0: I've seen her speak Korean on TV, right?
Speaker 0: And I guess I don't speak Korean so I can't judge.
Speaker 0: but She's not someone who learned just a few words, right?
Speaker 0: She's been living there like four years or something.
Speaker 0: There was like a video like, you know, she like got to see her parents in Oklahoma after like so many years Right not seeing them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like the you know, the the accepting of anyone, you know, and then also, you know At least the international fans right of kpop, you know.
Speaker 0: accepting anyone right, you know Is it's cool to see and I think you know this even though the show was not popular You know, I like some of her music right?
Speaker 0: She's talented and I'm sure that you know She'll.
Speaker 0: you know, just having this thing on her resume, right?
Speaker 0: It's probably gonna help her become, you know She's definitely upgraded from you know, two star.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, at least three or three and a half star here out of the five.
Speaker 0: so That's it's something.
Speaker 0: it's interesting story right?
Speaker 0: Not the usual just normal kpop stories.
Speaker 1: Yep, so in another actually breaking news We have learned that you know do not the dune movie that was actually pretty good.
Speaker 1: part two is of course coming.
Speaker 1: It was announced and this is a newer dune movie.
Speaker 0: Not the the old one.
Speaker 0: Yeah It was announced that the Emperor Who was not in this spoiler?
Speaker 0: Emperor who did not make an appearance in dune to dune part one.
Speaker 1: In dune part two the Emperor is going to be played no joke by Christopher Walken Which is the kind of casting that nerds always say?
Speaker 1: Oh, they should make Nick Cage and Christopher Walken play.
Speaker 1: It's that kind of casting but that is actually the casting.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's not a joke.
Speaker 0: It's not a prank It's not April Fool's that really is who's gonna play the Emperor.
Speaker 0: on the one hand I don't you know my vision of the Emperor having red dune see book club book episode about dune, right?
Speaker 0: It's not a Christopher Walken type character, right?
Speaker 0: It's a serious, you know dark you know dude, right like You know Like a Roman Emperor, it's you know, only not not insane.
Speaker 0: Yeah But and Christopher Walken, you know, he has that, you know slight, you know goofy quirkiness to him Of course, I guess like he I remember in a suicide Kings.
Speaker 1: He's a little more restrained and terrifying.
Speaker 0: Right is is but he has that sort of You know Somewhat, you know easygoing humorousness and not the completely, you know Seriousness at all times.
Speaker 0: but you know, it's a still even so right.
Speaker 0: that doesn't matter, right?
Speaker 0: It's not about my what I imagine the dune Emperor to be like, right?
Speaker 0: It's not like the dune Emperor her last that long anyways.
Speaker 0: But This news though.
Speaker 0: Usually I don't give a shit about you know, casting news has come out all the time.
Speaker 0: I usually don't give a shit.
Speaker 0: This actually makes me really want to see.
Speaker 0: I mean I already was gonna see it.
Speaker 0: This makes me really.
Speaker 0: this really makes me want to see cuz what?
Speaker 1: Way more Christopher Walken.
Speaker 0: I wanted to see it already.
Speaker 1: either He is unexpected in the way He plays this character and it's amazing or he's expected in the way We think he'll play this character and I feel like that will still be amazing.
Speaker 0: I don't see any way that this is bad.
Speaker 0: This can only be.
Speaker 0: this is they're basically just announced like let me translate the announcement, right?
Speaker 0: It's basically like doing.
Speaker 0: part two is coming.
Speaker 0: You were already gonna see it and the news today is it's gonna be more entertaining than you already thought It was gonna be.
Speaker 0: yep.
Speaker 0: That's the new.
Speaker 0: raise your expectation without concern.
Speaker 1: It's like, okay I've raised my expectation without concern, but also we know for a fact That he knows how to walk without rhythm so as to not attract the worm.
Speaker 0: I Don't think does the Emperor ever actually have to walk without rhythm.
Speaker 1: I don't think the Emperor ever actually has to walk.
Speaker 0: That you're thinking of the other.
Speaker 1: not only I'm.
Speaker 1: I feel like the Emperor might just get wheeled around too.
Speaker 1: So I thought the Emperor was a guy who could walk Absolutely, but I feel like he's the kind of person who had servants to walk for him if he wanted to.
Speaker 1: Anyway, anyway in one last little news.
Speaker 1: I got two minor convention news.
Speaker 1: is that are funny because they're both.
Speaker 1: They are both two sides of the same problem.
Speaker 1: that happens with a lot of nerdy conventions in that the kinds of people who attend a lot of nerdy conventions bring their own unique problems and challenges to the venues that may normally be used to Regular boring people doing regular normal hotel stuff.
Speaker 0: I mean, that's true, right?
Speaker 0: Most of the conventions and conferences are really quiet, you know.
Speaker 0: They're usually companies of the vendors and those sorts of things like this.
Speaker 1: The reason the escalators break at every convention because no convention is ready for nerd conventions, right or their academic conferences Right, but there are can.
Speaker 0: there are conventions and conferences that are way way way worse.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah The young Republicans convention is the worst one as far as I can tell.
Speaker 0: anything that has a frat like Atmosphere right is going to be if we we've.
Speaker 0: we know this from talking to many Hotel convention center staff over decade plus.
Speaker 1: go find old geek nights episodes about katsu khan.
Speaker 1: we interviewed like random maintenance people and they Shared some terrifying shit mostly about the concierges.
Speaker 0: you talk to hotel housekeeping, right?
Speaker 0: You talk to these people, you know, and you know security guards at convention centers things like that.
Speaker 0: You know and you learn stuff and it's like yes The worst absolute conventions are the ones that have some sort of frat like atmosphere a bunch of white boys getting drunk being bad.
Speaker 0: Those are the ones that destroy everything.
Speaker 1: Nerds kind of problem, right?
Speaker 0: The nerds are better than that but a Problem compared to the normal quiet business things.
Speaker 1: So first colossal con.
Speaker 0: I've heard of that.
Speaker 0: I don't know what kind of con it is But I've heard is one of those generic cons.
Speaker 1: as far as I can.
Speaker 0: I don't know where it is either.
Speaker 1: You know a bunch of people who go.
Speaker 1: it's at the Kalahari resort.
Speaker 1: I don't actually know what state that's in.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's not a con will go to pretty sure.
Speaker 1: they just announced they're not masking or something.
Speaker 1: But that's not what I'm talking about.
Speaker 1: They sent a warning To the guests of colossal con About a potentially disruptive event that will be held in the convention center during those dates.
Speaker 1: But the event they warned the colossal con attendees about is colossal con What.
Speaker 1: so they put a warning out?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna read the exact who put the warning out the the hotel the Convention Center hotel Sent a warning to the regular guests saying warning.
Speaker 1: a note if you choose to stay Specifically anytime during June 1st through 5th.
Speaker 1: There is a unique private event throughout the resort called colossal con consisting of anime gaming and Japanese culture.
Speaker 1: In an effort to accommodate our non convention guests We are enforcing a pg-13 rule.
Speaker 1: nudity adult behaviors are banned.
Speaker 1: all these rules Under 18 people are not allowed to go anywhere near the waterpark.
Speaker 1: all these rules and this seems like it was written aimed at Regular people who happen to be staying at this resort during colossal con.
Speaker 0: So they probably sent it to everyone who had a room booked that wasn't in the room block But they also sent it to the room block for colossal con.
Speaker 0: Okay, so some hotel person who sends an email and it isn't some technologically advanced person just you know sent the email out Thinking too hard about it not understanding or whatever.
Speaker 1: But what they have actually banned is they're saying the entire resort has to be a pg-13 rule and it says specifically Nudity and adult behaviors are banned in guest rooms private spaces.
Speaker 0: How can you even do that?
Speaker 1: I have no idea.
Speaker 0: Are they cameras and all the guest spaces don't stay at this hotel?
Speaker 1: Yeah So, uh Meanwhile, there's another convention the Motor City furry con and they had to post.
Speaker 0: I wonder where that is.
Speaker 1: There are actually a Huge number of furry conventions and gaming conventions in Michigan that basically nobody has heard of outside of Michigan.
Speaker 1: It might be the densest other than North Jersey.
Speaker 1: It might be one of the densest places for like very small nerdy gaming conventions.
Speaker 1: Just anyway, so They sent a letter that has gone out in the past from many other conventions many kinds of conventions But they sent a very very long letter that was like look Everyone who went to our con last year.
Speaker 1: You got to stop leaving vomit everywhere.
Speaker 1: You got to stop leaving diapers everywhere.
Speaker 1: You got to stop sleeping in your cars.
Speaker 1: They're gonna ban us if you stay if you don't stop this shit.
Speaker 1: and it is a very long and terrifying letter detailing Everything that the attendees of this convention did that are pushing the hotel to the point of possibly not letting them ever return.
Speaker 1: You can read it if you enjoy.
Speaker 1: I enjoy convention drama just because it's it's like watching a car wreck in the distance.
Speaker 1: It's just fascinating to behold but anyway things Of the day.
Speaker 1: So, uh t-pain seems like a stand-up, dude.
Speaker 1: He He succeeded in opening a restaurant.
Speaker 1: he's really excited about it.
Speaker 1: it's cool thing.
Speaker 0: He's got enough money.
Speaker 0: He can buy a restaurant just pay people to run it.
Speaker 1: if I like.
Speaker 1: it'd be pretty fun to run a restaurant Like listen if I had there's a restaurant you.
Speaker 0: Staten Island is the worst place.
Speaker 0: We've talked about this at length.
Speaker 0: But yeah in Staten Island there is right.
Speaker 0: everyone has this idea.
Speaker 0: They don't realize it actually exists.
Speaker 0: It's existed for many years.
Speaker 0: There is a restaurant in Staten Island Completely operated only by grandma's of various nations who make grandma food.
Speaker 0: How good is that?
Speaker 0: It's really insane.
Speaker 0: There's a real place right, you know?
Speaker 0: So it's like you want to open one of those?
Speaker 0: well you know it's.
Speaker 0: you got to do all the work of running a restaurant or Just be wealthy enough to buy to pay rent and buy food and have grandma's do all the work You know,
Speaker 1: I mean I would love to just retire and be like look I Run a nerdy bar Like that would be a really fun thing to do.
Speaker 1: if that were somehow a sustainable achievable thing that would survive capitalism I would run a nerdy Jewish deli.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but t-pain did it.
Speaker 1: You hope he's open in his restaurant.
Speaker 1: He's really excited about it, but he posted a photo to sugar.
Speaker 0: Where is it?
Speaker 0: Can we go?
Speaker 0: is in New York?
Speaker 1: I don't actually know California so we are.
Speaker 1: so I have the key to it.
Speaker 1: We could go.
Speaker 1: we could break in if we could just open the door.
Speaker 0: He's changed the locks by now He hasn't yet.
Speaker 1: So, uh, the story is when he tweeted about the fact that he's opening the restaurant.
Speaker 1: He posted a picture He was holding up the key like the master key to the building.
Speaker 1: now Nerds always especially lock picking.
Speaker 1: nerds always like to point out whenever someone does this.
Speaker 1: Hey, someone could someone's gonna copy your key.
Speaker 1: You're fucked and that is true.
Speaker 1: But my thing of the day is a video that deviant olam a guy who's famous in the lock picking community.
Speaker 1: He's the guy who did those elevator hacking talks at conventions over the years.
Speaker 1: This video is only six minutes long and he actually does make t-pain ski Directly, but he shows you Exactly step by step what it takes to do that.
Speaker 1: Like every step.
Speaker 0: did he go to t-pain's restaurant and open the door?
Speaker 0: He did not and he that would make an s-tier video.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying go open the door just like, you know surreptitiously I'm saying like go there You know with t-pain in the video.
Speaker 0: I'd be like hey t-pain watch this.
Speaker 1: So and he posted this video and and then t-pain and that would.
Speaker 0: and that video would help t-pain.
Speaker 0: Right, it recruit him to educate the people, you know to not take photos of keys.
Speaker 1: So it looks like t-pain saw this video because he had a follow-up thread where he was like, yeah I saw like.
Speaker 1: I saw I understand.
Speaker 1: Alright, what are you gonna do?
Speaker 1: break in and steal the bar stools that we're throwing away?
Speaker 1: We're renovating the place.
Speaker 1: Like I'm gonna change the locks guys.
Speaker 0: I'm not stupid I'm just saying you know, you at least t-pain understands.
Speaker 0: You shouldn't take photos of keys now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: So the two things I will say is one watch the video because you know what tools you need to do this yourself.
Speaker 0: website a blank key Something to grind away at it.
Speaker 1: Oh, you can just buy a key punch like a stencil a piece of paper.
Speaker 0: It's you know, it's way easier than that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he actually so deviant even like shares these things.
Speaker 1: He just takes the photo into Photoshop and he has templates with vector graphics of lines for different kinds of keys.
Speaker 1: He just lines it up on the photo.
Speaker 1: It's really straightforward like, okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they prints it out.
Speaker 1: Yep, you follow
Speaker 0: that if the pencil paper
Speaker 1: Cuz keys are just passwords from the photo and
Speaker 0: we just has the numbers and
Speaker 1: the templates It's really easy to figure out the numbers which are basically the password because a key like a residential key is Actually just a five or six digit Numerical password.
Speaker 1: your key to your house is literally just a basic ass password.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's why lock picking is so easy because they're just really simple passwords.
Speaker 1: So if you ever post a photo of your keys your dad is the equivalent of typing your password into Twitter and just hitting send.
Speaker 0: If you find someone's keys and you want to share a photo of the keys to be like hey who lost their keys?
Speaker 0: Come and get them.
Speaker 0: You should hold your fist over the bottom the spiky part of the keys and just show The key chains and the tops of the keys that you know where the the ring is and that would be enough for someone to identify.
Speaker 0: That's my keychain.
Speaker 0: Those are my keys without revealing their actual keys.
Speaker 1: Yep God, if I lost my keychain, that would be a big fucking problem because my yubi key is on the keychain.
Speaker 0: I have two yubi keys.
Speaker 1: I have one but then I have the backup codes for everything.
Speaker 0: But I have backup codes for everything also, but I put.
Speaker 0: I put all everything I put on one yubi key.
Speaker 0: I also put on the other yubi key.
Speaker 1: I thought about doing that and then I didn't.
Speaker 1: probably should.
Speaker 1: next time I do the refresh I probably will but that's why I made this my thing of the day because a lot of people talk about Copying keys from photos this video.
Speaker 1: if you watch this video, you will literally be able to do it.
Speaker 1: It is so easy and so simple.
Speaker 1: All you need is Photoshop or something.
Speaker 1: That's Photoshop enough.
Speaker 1: I Don't think you could do it in the GIMP that easily though.
Speaker 1: Honestly GIMP doesn't have layers the right way.
Speaker 1: Anyway, what do you got?
Speaker 0: so We talked about the anime.
Speaker 0: keep your hands off eyes.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: There's also a manga.
Speaker 0: It's great And the opening song for that anime is easy breezy by Is it?
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's Chelmeko or Kelmeko but the group that made that song is called Chelmeko or Kelmeko because Right one of the persons in that group is Rachel And the other person in the group is Momiko, right?
Speaker 0: So it's Rachel plus Momiko is.
Speaker 0: I guess it must be Chel because it's Rachel right Chelmeko, right?
Speaker 0: Anyway, I if that's your you know, only exposure to that musical group.
Speaker 0: Let me tell you right they are really something and What's even more than them being really good at music is their music videos are like S-tier music videos.
Speaker 0: They're all have like these original.
Speaker 0: even the easy breezy one is like it's really.
Speaker 0: That is not the music video.
Speaker 1: I expected to go to that song Easy.
Speaker 0: the easy breezy music video, you know, I think goes along really well with the the anime, right?
Speaker 1: Oh, absolutely.
Speaker 0: But They have a new music video.
Speaker 0: it came out like Pretty recently, right like a couple weeks ago, I guess right?
Speaker 0: I don't know how recently was it?
Speaker 0: 29th.
Speaker 0: Okay, sure And the song is may die may right?
Speaker 0: I hope I'm pronouncing that properly.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the songs about.
Speaker 1: I played it for a second.
Speaker 1: I had it muted.
Speaker 1: So I thought I had assumed this was a music video to easy breezy.
Speaker 1: I just saw the music video and I see that it is a different song.
Speaker 0: Now easy breezy is a different music.
Speaker 1: I clicked around in the video and I saw the images from the music video and I thought easy breezy what what?
Speaker 0: What I see this is their new song.
Speaker 0: This is not an old.
Speaker 0: Well, this isn't the newest song, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, I guess it's the newest music video, but I've been hearing this song on Spotify for at least a while, right?
Speaker 0: So it's not the.
Speaker 0: you know, it's not like the song just dropped Right, but the music video just dropped.
Speaker 0: and the music video is extremely creative in that it's some sort of like Parody of like, you know horror movies, right and you know the song has verses right and you know verse chorus kind of structure.
Speaker 0: and Every time the song comes around to the next, you know verse chorus.
Speaker 0: the music video sort of starts again But this time plays out similarly but differently and sort of a time loop sort of thing going on While keeping the horror theme and then on the final I think it does it two or three times and on the final one Obviously, it's very different right and that's you know, how things how you how stories are told How good stories are told.
Speaker 0: so St.
Speaker 0: Music video we got here.
Speaker 0: I looked up the music video director and the only real information I could find about them was that they also were making the directing most of Kari Pommie Pommie's music videos.
Speaker 0: So this is like, you know very prolific high quality Japanese music video director person, so Yeah, if you aren't checking out chamico, right Their music and music videos are really good Thing of the day worthy.
Speaker 1: All right in the meta moment.
Speaker 1: The geek nights book club book is nine Fox Gandit.
Speaker 1: We're gonna do the show within a month.
Speaker 1: Cuz I'm Steamrolling through it.
Speaker 1: It's real good.
Speaker 1: It's a dense dense sci-fi with abstract concepts and violent calendars.
Speaker 0: No, the violent calendars have appeared.
Speaker 1: Oh the violent cow in.
Speaker 1: the violent calendars are referenced very early on but I did not a regular calendars.
Speaker 1: I did not appreciate the extent of the violence of the calendar.
Speaker 0: Yeah, calendars came up in like the first chapter, but you didn't realize the whole book was about calendars.
Speaker 0: main focus of the book was calendars.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, it's.
Speaker 1: uh This book is real good to me.
Speaker 1: But my advice to you just like with the Prince of Nothing books If there's up too many proper nouns in a row Just go with it and it'll make more and more sense if you just keep reading.
Speaker 1: But at least the characters are very straightforward in terms of who they are.
Speaker 1: Compared to the Prince of Nothing books were like one character has ten different names depending on who's talking about them And there were a few characters early on.
Speaker 1: I wasn't didn't realize for the same character until later.
Speaker 1: I did not have that problem with this book.
Speaker 1: This book is just dense sci-fi dense abstract and violence.
Speaker 1: Alright, definitely gonna read the rest of these books.
Speaker 0: I think In another meta moment if you're somehow not aware, right?
Speaker 0: We have a presence in many online places Even places that we don't actually Inhabit ourselves, right?
Speaker 0: We still have geek nights still has a page or an account or a something, right?
Speaker 0: It's like there's a geek nights Facebook page and you know what.
Speaker 0: there they it was.
Speaker 0: first We had a feature that was automatically posting episodes there.
Speaker 0: Then it broke.
Speaker 0: then I turned it off because it wasn't worth the effort.
Speaker 0: then Facebook added a podcast feature.
Speaker 0: So I'm like, okay, why not?
Speaker 0: Here's our RSS feed Facebook.
Speaker 0: Go ahead post our episodes on our page be my guest.
Speaker 0: And now Facebook says guess what?
Speaker 0: We're getting rid of the pot.
Speaker 0: We failed at our podcast.
Speaker 0: We're giving.
Speaker 0: we're giving up on that right Google style and we're getting rid of that feature.
Speaker 0: and I'm like, okay, so If Facebook is how you follow geek nights, I'm sorry You might want to change to something else.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna delete the page or my account But I never use it and I'm probably not gonna go and do something about this for a very long time.
Speaker 0: It's like it's on my list, but it's like the last item on the list, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, we have an Instagram account.
Speaker 0: We don't use it really right especially not without any conventions.
Speaker 1: We got Twitter which we're outside of conventions pretty much just tells you when episodes are happening.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know we got accounts all over but the most interactive places are most happening of all places are our forum Which is on our website, which the website is being redone.
Speaker 0: We're making a lot of progress imminently.
Speaker 0: and The forum which is linked to the website.
Speaker 0: There's an old forum That's a read-only archive from back in the day but there's a current forum and is also a discord server that we have right.
Speaker 0: so Join those places if you want to interact with us and you might see benefit from doing so.
Speaker 0: for example Listener.
Speaker 0: the only listener dazzle 369 I think is the numbers on there dazzle something.
Speaker 0: dazzle 369 gave us the idea for today's Thursday show.
Speaker 0: We had no fucking idea for today's Thursday show.
Speaker 0: We're probably close to bailing on it just because we didn't have an idea.
Speaker 0: and then we looked in our forum and we clicked on The ideas thread and we scrolled up and in July of last year Dazzle 369 suggested to do a show on swimming and swimming pools.
Speaker 0: That is a show that we can do with no research.
Speaker 0: It is something that where we definitely have 20 to 30 minutes of material to discuss Without preparation and we have not done a show on that already and therefore it is prime material for a show.
Speaker 0: So that's what we're gonna do.
Speaker 1: We do have a plan for a future show while we're in the metamoment before we get into it.
Speaker 1: So I'm just gonna ask all of you if Scott and I were to at some point in the nearing future rewatch an old James Bond movie that we probably only saw on TV with ads as kids and have not watched since
Speaker 0: and Might have been censored even who knows for TV, right?
Speaker 0: Like what aspect ratio it for TV?
Speaker 1: what James Bond movie?
Speaker 1: Would you want us to both watch with modern adult eyes and do a review of?
Speaker 1: I'm just curious.
Speaker 1: if anyone has strong Preferences they're not even gonna tell you which ones I've seen recently and which ones I haven't because I'm just curious which ones you recommend.
Speaker 0: We did a show on James Bond show recently.
Speaker 1: We did so.
Speaker 1: you can get a sense of our sensibilities around James Bond.
Speaker 1: you know that I'm a I'm a big Daniel Craig fan and it's not gonna be one of those because I've seen all of those and With I guess two of them are great.
Speaker 1: Anyway, maybe three.
Speaker 0: Let's talk about swimming and swimming pools.
Speaker 0: So I lived a very Swim privileged youth Oh sent white middle-class living in a suburb.
Speaker 1: We both had a very similar upbringing in this regard.
Speaker 0: It was a you know, I guess I was born in New York City.
Speaker 0: But then you know, you know, I guess then my parents we moved to Connecticut.
Speaker 0: But then this you know House we moved into after like when I was.
Speaker 0: I guess maybe two or three two or three Is still the house my mom lives in today.
Speaker 0: and that house had an above-ground pool in it when we moved into it And that pool was not torn down until after the children had gone to college and such and no one was using it anymore And it was just a pain in the ass to maintain and it was taking up space in the backyard.
Speaker 0: So the kid I don't vary.
Speaker 0: and in addition in addition to that pool that was in my own backyard We would frequently in the summer Right go to the town public pool that you could only park your car at if you had a sticker that proved You lived in the town and you had a driver's license that Indicated you lived in the town and aren't the town we lived in the suburban town Had like two or three such public pools to go to.
Speaker 0: yeah And on top of that, right?
Speaker 0: The town also had a leak that nowadays you can't swim in that lake anymore.
Speaker 0: It's but it you could when when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: That's Yeah, and then well, I think it overrun by algaes and you know all kinds of climate change.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then on top of all that I frequently attended summer camps and various summer programs and went on Vacations to beaches and things of that nature.
Speaker 0: and it's you go to a summer camp.
Speaker 0: It's like you're swimming every day.
Speaker 0: It's like even if you went to summer camp at the YMCA that the you know at the Jewish Community Center in town.
Speaker 0: It's like swimming was a daily activity there, right?
Speaker 0: For everybody.
Speaker 1: so my house was similar, but we were you know in Detroit We did not have a pool because our backyard was about the size of the room I'm recording geek nights in right now.
Speaker 1: Like it was a tiny house in Detroit.
Speaker 1: In fact, it was so tiny There was no grass.
Speaker 1: It was pea gravel.
Speaker 1: When we moved to the suburbs One of the first things my parents saved up for it.
Speaker 1: It was a big goddamn deal.
Speaker 1: We got a small above-ground pool But one of those ones that has like the metal sides like a really really like built up one and We were obsessed with it.
Speaker 1: We swam in it all the time, but it wasn't really a pool you could swim in.
Speaker 1: It was just like a kid jump around.
Speaker 0: See ours was.
Speaker 0: ours was the same kind of construction.
Speaker 0: is that?
Speaker 0: you know, it's four feet deep metal sides, right?
Speaker 0: But you could swim in it like around in a circle, right?
Speaker 0: But mostly what I would do is come home from school or whatever Yep, splash it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, please all get your.
Speaker 0: you know, super soaker battles in there, you know pool basketball.
Speaker 1: We would jump out of the garage into it when our parents weren't watching.
Speaker 0: it wasn't close ours wasn't close enough to the house for jumping but our A Family friend's house.
Speaker 0: They also had a similar pool and They had one of those, you know decks those porches because it was one of those You know Right the houses that were like the.
Speaker 0: the land they were on was high in the front and sloped downwards in the back.
Speaker 0: So the porch was you know, like, you know, even though it was at the same level as the first floor It was like a ranch with a basement.
Speaker 0: You know, the basement was just like it's in the back of the house.
Speaker 0: You could just walk right out, right, you know straight with a normal door, you know, and the porch was above that.
Speaker 0: So in the backyard, the porch was real high up and they they they basically had the porch.
Speaker 0: They built it outwards to go down to the pool so you could get to the pool without having to go on to the ground and Then that provided many opportunities for jumping.
Speaker 1: We had nothing like that because it wasn't really the burbs.
Speaker 0: many many opportunities Jumping into that pool.
Speaker 1: This was actually like One of those old brick row houses like in the outer rings around Detroit like in Grosse Pointe Park like that kind of place.
Speaker 1: So the pool was illegal because it was too close to the garage.
Speaker 1: It was too close to the house.
Speaker 1: It was too close to the problem.
Speaker 1: Every side of this thing was illegal in some fashion, but who's gonna do anything about it?
Speaker 1: So but Most of my swimming swimming was another thing that white middle-class kids, especially in the Midwest do is Get swimming lessons.
Speaker 1: a lot of schools just have pools and it's just a class.
Speaker 1: Sometimes it's not even like you're forced to.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's swimming lessons.
Speaker 0: So many times right?
Speaker 0: Not only did we have Swimming lessons at the public pool swimming lessons at the summer camps.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's it, right?
Speaker 1: It's like I Learned like full formal swimming.
Speaker 1: We had to do races in the classes.
Speaker 1: Like I know a bunch of strokes Like swimming was just this assumed thing and being a privileged middle-class white kid at the time I didn't realize that not everyone learns how to swim when I was a kid.
Speaker 1: I Just assumed like that everyone knew how to swim and I remember I was.
Speaker 0: I was getting swimming lessons with all the kids I knew.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's like something like I didn't feel like anyone wasn't getting them But actually no a lot of people.
Speaker 0: just you know, it's like wait a minute now that I think about it.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah, there were this many kids in school But when I went to the public pool only some percentage of those kids were coming to the pool.
Speaker 0: The rest of them were somewhere else.
Speaker 1: And it wasn't until middle school when I went to some friends house because they had a. they had an in-ground pool.
Speaker 1: Like they were the richest people I could imagine when I was in middle school.
Speaker 1: So, uh, you know, they just had a nice house but they had a like a smallish in-ground pool.
Speaker 1: and I remember going to a birthday party at this house in like sixth grade and A bunch of the kids like wouldn't get in the pool because it had a deep end.
Speaker 1: they just like would not get in.
Speaker 1: and I started to realize really quickly that a lot of those kids like Just couldn't like if you threw them in they would just think to the bottom and die Like they could not even keep their head above water if they were.
Speaker 0: why we put fences around pools?
Speaker 1: because people die and in my subdivision Multiple kids died because they would break into other families houses Like they break into other families backyards swim in the pool and drown.
Speaker 1: That happened multiple times when I was a kid Yeah, and the homeowners got sued because anyway, that's a whole separate conversation.
Speaker 1: But that was the moment I started to.
Speaker 1: that was one of the first times I started to internalize How radically different some aspects of my childhood were from the average childhood in America.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean the answer right and then we can just talk about water anecdotes after this, right?
Speaker 0: But the answer is that obviously Swimming lessons should be as mandatory as math lessons for all humans in the society, right?
Speaker 1: Every majority of the have enough money to have a pool.
Speaker 0: if a spot majority We're not putting enough money into that public school or you could take the kids to the town pool or whatever, right?
Speaker 0: It's like doesn't matter your town, you know There should be a pool close enough to where everyone has pool access no matter where they live, right?
Speaker 0: As long as he's not in a drought place, but that's a waste of water.
Speaker 0: But it's like, you know, most of the earth is covered in water.
Speaker 0: unless you live in Oklahoma And never leave you're in your life you are likely to encounter a body of water right intentionally or unintentionally and You should.
Speaker 0: it's like yeah, you know since I left, you know The suburbs it went to college the swimming opportunities have been much less.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much like when I can go to the beach and that's it.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, like why?
Speaker 1: like watch me or Scott's swimming today.
Speaker 1: Our form is atrocious our speed.
Speaker 0: I pretty much Yeah, I pretty much swim at the beach in a relaxing swim to stay afloat and not die and that's that's the level of swim I have now.
Speaker 0: right but You know, it's like I don't drown if I go in the water But I still know how to swim if I fell off a boat and I didn't you know And it wasn't like a mega boat where I die hitting the water or something, right?
Speaker 0: It's like I could probably I give a fell out of rowboat or a kayak I could get back in or you in the very least you could tread water until you got help Or I could.
Speaker 0: I could.
Speaker 0: if I can't get back in the boat I could get near it and hold on to it.
Speaker 1: Yeah I think I think any like you me Emily like most of like we could all if we had to we could probably swim across the East River like if there's like not that I want to At the problem the distance.
Speaker 0: I think I could make it with difficulty.
Speaker 0: I think the problem is that depending on you know, assuming that where you land on either side you is like, you know I'm assuming I'm gonna be Flat.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a flat wall And then you had the current I'd.
Speaker 0: if I tried to swim across the East River from where I live in Queens I'd probably I'd be lucky if I didn't go past the bottom of Manhattan by the time I got across right.
Speaker 0: but in terms of The difference I think you could do if I don't if I don't make it to the battery It's like I can't make it to Jersey.
Speaker 0: It's like I bet I'd be screwed.
Speaker 0: I'd maybe I get.
Speaker 0: maybe it would push me to Staten Island.
Speaker 0: There is a beach there.
Speaker 1: Well one to one.
Speaker 1: thing though that I think a lot of people don't super realize is
Speaker 0: Swimming fast
Speaker 1: is takes a lot of practice and skill and physicality and it's really good exercise and it's hard but knowing how to swim enough to Tread water not drown and slowly make your way in a particular direction That
Speaker 0: is
Speaker 1: one day's worth of instruction.
Speaker 0: It is not hard depends depends on the person.
Speaker 1: Yeah, unless you have some people got some.
Speaker 0: some people have aqua phobia, right?
Speaker 0: You know, they have issues.
Speaker 1: some people's bodies are different, you know There's nothing physical preventing you from doing it and there's nothing psychological or otherwise preventing you from doing it reasonably healthy reasonably fit.
Speaker 1: the motions like the mechanics of it come pretty much just come down to.
Speaker 1: You're sort of moving your arms left and right when angling your hands and that's pushing water down keeping you up and your legs.
Speaker 1: You're just kind of kicking them.
Speaker 1: Just kick them a little bit and that'll keep my head above water, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, it's the thing is right is every human who has legs at work You know learns to walk right, you know.
Speaker 0: somewhat somewhat sort of without really even any instruction.
Speaker 0: so much, you know.
Speaker 1: I mean horses come out walking Immediately, but some babies also come out Naturally being able to swim like they will kind of just swim.
Speaker 1: They'll keep their heads above water when they get older.
Speaker 0: They lose that right, but the you know, there's swimming, you know, this.
Speaker 0: we need swimming lessons because You know, you're not swimming constantly, right?
Speaker 0: You're not in the water every day unless you live in like a fishing village or something, right?
Speaker 0: Where you probably don't need swimming.
Speaker 1: But also the mechanics of swimming with speed are not actually intuitive to just a human who doesn't have specialized knowledge Right, but the thing is, you know, right it swimming with speed is like running, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you you don't need to do that.
Speaker 0: Actually, right?
Speaker 0: it's like this kind of swimming lessons you got are basically teaching you to walk in the Right.
Speaker 0: It's like to walk in water not on water like Jesus.
Speaker 0: in water.
Speaker 0: We got we got all we went from basically walking like you like if you are in a free in a in a body of water Submerged and not holding on to any objects and you're not near any surface, you know, can you move around?
Speaker 0: According to your will at any speed?
Speaker 0: right walking in the you know in water That's that's the kind of swimming that everyone needs to learn.
Speaker 1: Yep I mean what I can do like I can do like most of the basic front strokes I can do the backstroke really easily.
Speaker 1: I can I can do a really shitty looking breaststroke, but like it works.
Speaker 0: dog paddle, of course Yeah, that's a dog paddles enough, you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just can you get in a body of water and enjoy it and not die Danger to yourself and others.
Speaker 1: when I think back to my young childhood like early like kindergarten early to mid-elementary school Video games were a big part of my life, obviously Anime was a big part of my life at that time obvious like it later like as well like fourth grade onward.
Speaker 1: but the two things that I was sort of I guess three things that was sort of the most obsessed with as in Activities I wanted to do every day, but could not do every day.
Speaker 1: We're in order one ride rollercoaster Yeah to be in a big pool with a deep end.
Speaker 0: That's the thing is like if I think about you know, what was I interested in when I was you know At any any age right?
Speaker 0: What were my hobbies and primary interests?
Speaker 0: swimming never makes the list ever, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, what did I care most about?
Speaker 1: More like.
Speaker 1: I want to be in a deep pool because there's lots of fun things.
Speaker 0: Swimming was never the primary interest even if you asked me at the time I was swimming the most like what my favorite thing was like video games.
Speaker 0: It's like swimming would never come up right?
Speaker 0: But if you would ask me what would you like to do right now?
Speaker 0: Right and swimming in the pool was an option.
Speaker 0: It would frequently make the top of the list.
Speaker 1: When we had an above-ground pool as small and crappy as it was Every single day after school, I would come home and just like put in my swimsuit and jump in the pool like immediately.
Speaker 0: Yep, on the home Saturday home from school is the forget.
Speaker 0: home from school is the pool open?
Speaker 0: Yeah, is the pool ready?
Speaker 0: is the weather good?
Speaker 0: I'm going to be in the pool until dinnertime and possibly after dinner.
Speaker 1: Yep, my friends might just show up and get in the pool with me and we're gonna play tag in the pool.
Speaker 0: Say it's walking around the neighborhood.
Speaker 0: Hey who wants to come in the pool?
Speaker 1: Yep Saturday morning.
Speaker 1: I'd eat my frosted flakes I'd watch some cartoons open and I would be watching out the window Waiting watching to wait for my dad to get up Go outside and do the pH test and the chlorine stuff and come back and say it's okay to go in the pool And that would drop everything and go jump in the pool.
Speaker 0: Did that?
Speaker 0: did that all myself?
Speaker 1: I started doing that when I was older, but our parents did it when I was in like first grade.
Speaker 0: All right, so Anecdotes of things that happened while swimming.
Speaker 0: so at the town pool Right when the town pool that we had was an L shaped pool Oh fancy that the long part of the L had obviously lanes, right?
Speaker 0: And then the the the curved part was like a little square Right and it got deeper as it went.
Speaker 0: as the long part The shallowest part was the farthest away from the square right.
Speaker 0: as you went down the lane it got deeper.
Speaker 0: But in the square right there's a rope separating the square of the L from the long part of the L. That was the mega deep end right like, you know, like way deep right and that was the basically the diving area.
Speaker 0: There was a regular old springboard like you do.
Speaker 1: Oh, did you have an actual high dive?
Speaker 0: and then there was the high dive?
Speaker 1: I assume it's liability reasons why those are gone.
Speaker 1: But as a kid Diving was my favorite thing and that's why I was so obsessed with the deep pools because I couldn't dive at home.
Speaker 0: That would literally kill me Yep, and then there was the high dive.
Speaker 0: So, you know, I ever jump off it.
Speaker 0: At the time that the high dive was in operation.
Speaker 0: I was not yet old enough to go on the high.
Speaker 1: I went up there when I wasn't Right off of that thing before anyone could stop me as a kid.
Speaker 0: I was still doing the low dive.
Speaker 0: I was not allowed to do the high dive but at this time that the high dive still existed The pool was like super popular right and all kinds of people.
Speaker 0: it was busy.
Speaker 0: There's a kiddie pool off to the side also, but it was popular and busy right.
Speaker 0: and the bet the funnest times Were you think when they call adult swim?
Speaker 0: That's not the fun time when you're a kid because that means get out of the pool, right?
Speaker 0: But actually the tap the pool was so busy and popular that during adult swim the kids would go to the deep end diving pool area and we'd sit on the the edge of the pool with our feet in the water right next to the high dive and Basically all the biggest dudes in town Would come and cannonball.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like a cannonball contest like every day in the summer Right and we'll be all like get us wet Even though they were diving so far away from us.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right we would get mighty wet When these kids.
Speaker 0: it was, you know.
Speaker 0: But then over time it was sad because a the high dive went away and was replaced with the second low dive.
Speaker 1: Yep, so I found a whole bunch of articles talking about.
Speaker 1: there are a lot of people ask this question Why did all the high dives disappear?
Speaker 1: What the fuck they were.
Speaker 1: ability when I was a kid another all gone.
Speaker 0: People got hurt actually.
Speaker 1: No, that doesn't seem to be the main reason people were not getting heart at a high rate.
Speaker 0: I mean, I never saw anyone get hurt, but I assumed there was liability reasons and people were getting hurt.
Speaker 1: so it seems like they're actually very safe and Most of the reason they went away was a fear of people getting hurt.
Speaker 1: That was mostly unfounded.
Speaker 1: Aha the other part of it is that New safety regulations came in place in a lot of places Where insurers would say oh if you got a high dive, you can't just have a teenager's your lifeguard You need a certified diving instructor.
Speaker 1: and every pool said well fuck that.
Speaker 1: I'm not paying more than minimum wage Yep.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yep It's kind of hard to hurt yourself off a high dive if you're the kind of person who would jump off a high dive in The first place.
Speaker 0: I mean the real danger of the high dive is, you know Besides the drowning if you can't swim or maybe landing on someone kids are fucking around under it, right landing on someone.
Speaker 0: Somehow be you know, the dive causes you to lose consciousness or get disoriented and then you drown.
Speaker 0: or Hitting the board itself right with your jump is the other major danger.
Speaker 0: Or slipping and falling off of the board like sideways or something I did see.
Speaker 0: a lot of people fuck but it's sticking out so far into the water and it's the water is so deep You're still just.
Speaker 0: you're not gonna.
Speaker 0: you're not gonna like hit the concrete, you know when you fall off.
Speaker 1: So Olympic coaches are actually.
Speaker 1: I found an article on Weibo talking about this.
Speaker 1: They're all kind of mad and there's a bunch of anecdotes of them saying yeah It really hurt diving as a sport because when the high dives disappeared, nobody got interested in diving Or we couldn't find any divers.
Speaker 0: The thing is I always assumed that you know, the high dives are removed from the public pools.
Speaker 0: But I assumed that like people who are swimming seriously for sport Like those those pools still have all kinds of dives the mega high dives.
Speaker 1: it seems like it was more that it meant.
Speaker 1: most people never encountered a high dive and Thus didn't think about it and didn't like try to learn how to.
Speaker 0: but if you're a kid who goes to a swim meet You're then you're gonna see one.
Speaker 0: you're gonna say, you know what?
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll try that instead of swimming back and forth.
Speaker 1: true the kid But the kid who's going to the swim meet?
Speaker 0: probably definitely.
Speaker 0: if I had ever, you know If I had ever done competitive swimming, which I never did even one time ever, right?
Speaker 0: I probably would have chosen the diving over the swimming back and forth.
Speaker 1: as a kid when I got to a pool that had diving Boards, all I would do is dive over and over again until my parents said we had to go like that was what I would do.
Speaker 1: I actually was pretty good at diving - roller coaster adjacent.
Speaker 0: I would just do cannonballs.
Speaker 0: I wasn't trying to dive correctly.
Speaker 1: Well, I had a lot of goals.
Speaker 1: I would have tried to dive and touch the bottom with my hand and then swim back up or I would try to do that.
Speaker 1: We do that dive and swim as far as I could.
Speaker 0: We would throw things into the pool that sank to the bottom and then you would dive at the same time And try to grab.
Speaker 0: this is when there were two low dives because they obviously not work.
Speaker 0: if they one was high one was Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: So you somewhat you'd.
Speaker 0: you'd both be standing on the low dive.
Speaker 0: Someone on the side would throw something right and then you would both jump and see who came out with it.
Speaker 0: It's like if you didn't get it on its way down.
Speaker 0: You'd have to go come back up for air and dive again to go to the bottom and get it.
Speaker 1: but to use a diving board correctly does require a Tiny amount of instruction because there is a specific technique to a springy diving board and most of the people who fall off of it Don't realize that.
Speaker 0: well, you know There's.
Speaker 0: I think you don't need much technique.
Speaker 1: if your technique is stand at the end and go and jump Yeah, but you know if you want to run head first or you're gonna take a step and jump Yeah, you got it.
Speaker 1: You gotta get a little tiny bit.
Speaker 0: Well, I think it was.
Speaker 0: you know as it was I would when I would do it I would think about it in sort of a video game sort of way and that like I'm running and I need to jump like Mario and I need to land exactly on that spot at the end, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like it was about timing and Spacing out the one jump so that I would land in the right spot And then once I landed in the right spot, it's like the rest is or automatic, right?
Speaker 0: It's like it Springs you into the air and you'd be going the water.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah the coach is saying here The big problem is nobody gets the three meter training or the experience with it when they're very young.
Speaker 1: So they first encounter it when they're older and that seems to have impacted the skill development of divers.
Speaker 0: Listener from other country tell us if you're not United States country still has high dives at the public town pools and such.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm really curious because everything I'm reading digging around a ton of articles People were not getting hurt on these things.
Speaker 1: Anyway, anyway the list others swimming it is dazzle 369 in the chat.
Speaker 1: What about pool toys?
Speaker 0: Oh Well, I'm full.
Speaker 0: total noodle was invented in my lifetime.
Speaker 1: Yeah We did not have.
Speaker 0: I remember a time where our pool did not have Noodles and then they invented the pool noodle and then we had many.
Speaker 1: So we had the toys of dive in and get stuff off the bottom like we talked about.
Speaker 1: but the favorite toys Were the inner tubes and the giant alligator with the handles on it.
Speaker 0: You mean shark with handles on it.
Speaker 1: alligator was way better because it was flatter Animal with handles on it.
Speaker 1: pretty much we would we would play tag of Multiple alligators and you're trying to like tag people and jump across them and not fall in the water.
Speaker 1: We just have.
Speaker 1: we just throw rocks at each other from the alligators.
Speaker 0: I already mentioned the basketball and pool basketball, right?
Speaker 0: We didn't have a water polo set up or a pool volleyball set up But some people did.
Speaker 1: one of my favorite things to do with Cub Scouts was to go to the Days Inn Because you could just rent the pools out at them and play water volleyball.
Speaker 0: Actually water a lot of towns will have like a racquet club or you know Something like that and those places will often have a pools with like, you know water polo water.
Speaker 1: pretty much every YMCA Has a water volleyball set up too.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 0: That's a real Yeah, it's good.
Speaker 0: I know a lot of old people that play and they just sort of play it casually like, you know The same way that like old people are playing pickleball these days
Speaker 1: and the way and sometimes I remember one days in they had it set up where One side was just in the deep end.
Speaker 1: So basically that was how you could get Little kids like us to play against adults is the adults will have to tread water in the deep end and the kids are just like in the shallow end Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah other pool toys beside me the super soaker really was more of a pool like as much of a pool toy as it Wasn't.
Speaker 0: oh, yeah, it was.
Speaker 1: we just have them floating around in the pool with us.
Speaker 0: Sometimes you had the little kick boards.
Speaker 0: kick boards are fun.
Speaker 0: He though.
Speaker 0: They're mostly instructional, right?
Speaker 0: They're still fun because one board is just like.
Speaker 0: ah my arms they can rest for an above-ground pool.
Speaker 1: I think a very common activity was using the pool itself as a toy and what we'd always do is we'd get a bunch of kids in the pool and Start walking around the edge until we got.
Speaker 0: oh, I forgot all about that.
Speaker 0: Yes, we did that too.
Speaker 1: And you could you could actually like if you've never done that even enough.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you could.
Speaker 0: I could do it just by myself.
Speaker 0: I would run around the pool in a circle and then turn around and you try to fight against it Yeah, or you just ride it around on the alligator.
Speaker 0: We but I got all about that, but we did that a lot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was.
Speaker 1: it was surprising how big of a whirlpool you could get going with a bunch of kids in a little pool Worked at.
Speaker 0: hey, you could definitely get a. you know You know.
Speaker 1: Odyssean level whirlpool scale is there in the middle and Charybdis?
Speaker 0: Yeah So, yeah We've gone on way longer than we probably needed to.
Speaker 1: this is what happens when we don't do geek nights that reliably and We don't really see each other that much except during geek nights.
Speaker 0: So yeah, it's it's getting warm here.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna start doing some biking imminently and outside?
Speaker 0: not I've been doing inside bike And no specific promises.
Speaker 1: cuz I'm not gonna shit talk but it is likely we will make some form of content Maybe even some geek nights episodes on location outside.
Speaker 1: cuz why not?
Speaker 1: even if it's just regular geek nights, but we're sitting outside somewhere?
Speaker 0: Yeah, who knows?
Speaker 1: That's only exciting to us not to the listener.
Speaker 1: Obviously.
Speaker 0: I hope that we can.
Speaker 0: you know, I you know, I have more Swimming opportunities in the rest of my life.
Speaker 1: I'm looking into that for some private events just for us to go swimming.
Speaker 0: But the amount of money it cost to live in a place in New York City with a pool Yeah, so there is a. there's a public pool here, which I've been to one or two times and I could go to it Especially not with the work from home.
Speaker 0: It would be much more convenient to go to that public pool, right and you know avoid too many children The problem being the COVID.
Speaker 0: If I was working from home without the COVID the public pool would be like, you know The fancier buildings that have about literally double the rent that we pay down the righties.
Speaker 0: They have these shitty tiny useless pools.
Speaker 1: Ah, one of those buildings has a full-size Tulane lap pool and a small pool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the Tulane lap pool.
Speaker 0: Those are like dinky little pools I want.
Speaker 0: you know, I need an Olympic size pool, right?
Speaker 1: As a in-ground big Actually want a lap pool because the thing I'm most interested in cuz I'm not gonna get a diving pool on the roof of a Residential building that's not.
Speaker 1: that's not feasible.
Speaker 1: But what I got I could do is start swimming laps as exercise.
Speaker 1: that is if you think running or biking is good cardio Go go do more than one lap in a lap and tell me how hard that is.
Speaker 0: I'm not interested in that.
Speaker 1: I want a very interesting.
Speaker 0: I want to ride on the alligator and make a whirlpool And play a play a water volleyball if we do a close friends Airbnb somewhere during this COVID times.
Speaker 1: Well, see if there's a place that has a private.
Speaker 0: That's not a bad idea.
Speaker 0: It's like I was at first.
Speaker 0: you're thinking beach then we were thinking lake but you know what.
Speaker 0: you can get up Pretty much anywhere as long as it has a pool.
Speaker 1: Yeah rent out a house that just has a big pool in the backyard.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, that's what I'm looking into because I got to tell you stuff like that Way cheaper than the very limited number of beach houses that can sleep that many people.
Speaker 1: All right Yeah, this has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights I'll enjoy slinky G dread lily Tenebrae and a bunch of people who really don't want me to say their names.
Speaker 1: Chris the dog Chris Rhymer Quentin Walton decks finke shaya 85.
Speaker 1: Rebecca Dunn review.
Speaker 1: mad bull 34 cowards.
Speaker 1: Sam Erickson sure about her?
Speaker 1: We'll stop all the downloading.
Speaker 1: Taylor Braun.
Speaker 1: The next station is st.
Speaker 1: Patrick.
Speaker 1: st.
Speaker 1: Patrick station.
Speaker 1: several people whose names I won't say.
Speaker 1: my voice is a little hoarse cuz we were at that Rangers game and Might have scored three goals in less than three minutes might have been yelling a lot.
Speaker 1: I was wearing a mask.
Speaker 1: So I was yelling even louder.
Speaker 1: I need to give my throat some time to recover.
Speaker 1: So anyway tonight, I simply leave you with why is it that most of the people who are against abortion are people?
Speaker 0: You wouldn't want to fuck in the first place.
Speaker 1: Boy, these conservatives are really something aren't they?
Speaker 1: they're all in favor of the unborn.
Speaker 1: they will do anything for the unborn But once you're born you're on your own Pro life.
Speaker 1: Conservatives are obsessed with the fetus from conception to nine months after that.
Speaker 1: They don't want to know about you.
Speaker 1: They don't want to hear from you.
Speaker 1: No nothing.
Speaker 1: No neonatal care.
Speaker 1: No daycare.
Speaker 1: No head start.
Speaker 1: No school lunch No food stamps.
Speaker 1: No welfare.
Speaker 1: No nothing.
Speaker 1: If you're pre-born you're fine.
Speaker 0: If you're preschool, you're fucked.