Speaker 0: It's Monday February 7th 2022.
Speaker 0: I'm rim, I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We talk about technological lock-in.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So I had this problem with my computer, you know a ways back.
Speaker 1: wait Wait, I thought I'm the person who doesn't have problems with my computer.
Speaker 0: I just I've got to point out there was a recent recent conversation where we were playing some games with a friend of ours and You were making a point that you'd never have computer problems and somehow everyone else has computer problems.
Speaker 1: So yep, because I'm gonna describe this computer problem to you and it's gonna turn out that it was not actually a computer problem.
Speaker 0: It was.
Speaker 0: it was a in fact a failure of Scott.
Speaker 1: It was a failure of Microsoft.
Speaker 0: So I would I would not blame Microsoft because all I will say is that I blame Microsoft.
Speaker 0: I knew that the thing you're about to describe happened.
Speaker 1: You didn't know this.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: I didn't know this because you know The same thing happened to me once a long time ago and it was an Xbox controller and That's the default mapping.
Speaker 1: Anyway so anyway What was happening was when I opened the settings box in?
Speaker 1: Windows 10 or 11 it was scrolling down Automatically and like I would try to scroll up to get to the top of the window and it would like fight against me and scroll Back down again.
Speaker 1: It was like and it wasn't in any other app.
Speaker 0: You see that is the one thing that was a little weird because when I had this happen, it also affected my web browsers.
Speaker 1: yeah, so only in the windows settings app.
Speaker 1: Specifically.
Speaker 1: I even tried other Microsoft apps that use the same GUI framework like Windows Store.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 1: They work just fine.
Speaker 1: It was only the settings app was scrolling down and I it's it was like someone else had an evil mouse plugged into my computer Ghost and was scrolling their mouse wheel down as hard as they could.
Speaker 1: I could fight against it a little bit But not really.
Speaker 1: so I searched and I searched and I searched and I searched and finally I found a person who was like, hey Do you have like a gamepad plugged in?
Speaker 1: and I'm like I. I have a gamepad plugged in and sure enough if you have an?
Speaker 1: HID USB gamepad plugged in The Microsoft Windows settings app in Windows 10 and 11 Responds to the gamepad.
Speaker 1: you can you can move around you can select things and the left and right triggers Scroll up and down and that means if you have your controller on your desk And something is bumping the right trigger.
Speaker 1: It's gonna scroll down all the time.
Speaker 1: as soon as I unplug the gamepad.
Speaker 1: Everything was perfect.
Speaker 1: So I Agree that.
Speaker 1: that's probably like the ability to control windows or the gamepad.
Speaker 1: You know any app is a good feature but why Does why do agree with you on things only?
Speaker 1: Yeah, how would you even open Windows settings with the gamepad?
Speaker 0: It's like all those games that have an accessibility menu.
Speaker 0: That's behind the inaccessible opening menu, right?
Speaker 1: So I did learn something else in my experimentation.
Speaker 1: There is a button on my.
Speaker 1: I have an SN 30 Pro Plus.
Speaker 1: There is a button which is like, you know, it's like a. I don't know what you would call this button.
Speaker 1: I guess on a switch controller, it would be like the plus or the minus.
Speaker 1: maybe it's like down here on.
Speaker 1: you know It's I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's button 11 12, whatever the hell button it is.
Speaker 1: But if I hold that button down like not it's not a toggle.
Speaker 1: I have to hold it down.
Speaker 1: If I am holding that button down then the right stick becomes will control the mouse.
Speaker 1: You know, the contriggers will scroll like as long as that button is being held.
Speaker 1: I can control anything in Windows Using the gamepad.
Speaker 1: Ooh So that's useful.
Speaker 1: That's that's not bad.
Speaker 1: I mean It should be a toggle but regardless you can control all of Windows with a gamepad if you hold down the correct button Depending what gamepad you have.
Speaker 1: but why would the settings app be different and not require the button to be held down?
Speaker 1: That's you know, yeah, there's my computer.
Speaker 1: I thought it was a software issue.
Speaker 1: I was restart cuz like it wasn't a hardware issue cuz I unplugged all the mice and keyboards and it still happened.
Speaker 0: Yeah So I would have definitely assumed input device because I'm a weirdo who usually has two different keyboards plugged into my computer Like a little organ set up.
Speaker 1: So well, usually usually my gamepad is plugged into charging only and then I'll only switch it too.
Speaker 1: But you know, I forgot to switch it that one time.
Speaker 0: I think I'm doing lately so but an annoyance along those lines.
Speaker 0: So I got my logitech like the g502 like the default gaming mouse.
Speaker 0: Basically.
Speaker 0: I've had this thing forever.
Speaker 0: Well, actually I've had three of them because the scroll wheels do break.
Speaker 0: I just haven't found a better mouse.
Speaker 0: So I keep buying the same thing like an idiot but If I use my main keyboard instead of my gaming keyboard.
Speaker 0: The edge of the keyboard is at the exact right height to where it's very easy to bump the DPI toggle button on the mouse And suddenly change the DPI while I'm like mid FPS Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So another small computer thing right where my.
Speaker 1: I thought my computer is broken, but actually I ended up fixing it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so my podcast setup, you know usually involved, you know for the remote podcast is I three applications Right.
Speaker 1: I have an audio interface and the audio interface Presents to the connects to the computer of the USB cable.
Speaker 1: It has two inputs and it's also an output.
Speaker 1: It's basically a fancy sound card with XLR inputs and it presents to the computer.
Speaker 1: Right, obviously two as you audio inputs that are both mono.
Speaker 1: and it presents to the computer a standard audio output for playing audio.
Speaker 1: No and it presents to the computer an analog audio input that works like a normal Windows microphone would right.
Speaker 1: and that's it.
Speaker 1: and What I would do to make the podcast work remotely is I'd use three programs.
Speaker 1: I would use OBS with an ASIO plug-in to capture my microphone.
Speaker 1: Then I would use discord to talk to rim and in order to get the audio from You know my the ASIO over to discord so rim could hear.
Speaker 1: what I was saying is I had a fake Audio driver that has like a like a fake microphone and a fake speaker.
Speaker 1: So I would tell OBS that to monitor my voice right send the audio to the fake Mic, you know speaker now and then that fake speaker gets routed to a fake microphone Which in that fake microphone would be the would be the discord microphone and then audition is recording on the side.
Speaker 1: It's just recording from the ASIO directly.
Speaker 1: No problem.
Speaker 1: And so that's how I've been doing it for a year.
Speaker 0: two years however long Yeah, but I love it.
Speaker 0: I'm not up on that Windows stuff because I've had professional audio nonsense plugged into my computer for yeah over a day I've been doing it with this fake audio router plug-in.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so It suddenly just stopped working.
Speaker 1: It was always kind of garbage II but it stopped working just now.
Speaker 1: So I'm messing around and I'm uninstalling it reinstalling it.
Speaker 1: It's not you know, it's I fixed it a little bit, but it wasn't.
Speaker 1: you know, it was a little choppy It wasn't great.
Speaker 1: So I'm like, you know what, you know like I just said the audio interface does have that sort of normal microphone the non ASIO one and For some reason I remember when I first tried to use it Which so is
Speaker 0: very likely if you're using MME or you're using like non-professional audio hardware in Windows.
Speaker 0: There are situations where things that seem like they should work might work.
Speaker 0: Sometimes they do work like having two applications get audio from the same device like sometimes it just works in Windows, but sometimes it just fucking doesn't.
Speaker 0: and Better now than it used to be.
Speaker 0: but go back like Four or five years or even worse go back to like earlier versions of Windows.
Speaker 0: It rarely worked.
Speaker 1: So because I was just frustrated and fighting with the fake cable would have taken a long time I said, you know what?
Speaker 1: Let me try that thing again.
Speaker 1: I haven't tried it since I first got it, you know.
Speaker 1: And in fact, I just realized while I was talking just now when I first got it was Windows 10 Maybe Windows 11 to fix something.
Speaker 1: I don't know it's possible But I tried it again and that totally works.
Speaker 1: So now I don't need the fake audio cable and I don't even need to open OBS anymore.
Speaker 1: now all I got is discord which is using the you know, The the regular microphone that the audio interface presents to the computer and I got audition recording from ASIO input one Both at the same time.
Speaker 1: rim can hear me.
Speaker 1: He said I actually sound better.
Speaker 0: You do actually sound better.
Speaker 0: It is noteworthy how much better you sound.
Speaker 1: It sounds like raw audio and And Audition is recording me just fine.
Speaker 1: I even played back a little bit recording to make sure it was working.
Speaker 1: It works.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't even know OBS open.
Speaker 1: My whole thing is simpler.
Speaker 1: So what appeared to be a computer problem was actually a computer improvement.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna uninstall that fake audio.
Speaker 1: Yeah And I guess to remove all the podcasting stuff from OBS because I don't need it for podcasting anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and yeah, so I don't have computer problems.
Speaker 1: I have the opposite.
Speaker 1: I have computer gets better It's.
Speaker 0: uh, it's interesting.
Speaker 0: I guess my advice to all of you is if you have Fucky audio setups that you're trying to use for live streaming like multiple microphones or nonsense from a long time ago
Speaker 1: Try
Speaker 0: just making stuff work the obvious simple way because Windows might have gotten better enough and applications might have gotten better enough.
Speaker 1: I mean my advice just in general in life is to try.
Speaker 1: Things is right.
Speaker 1: It's try to use as few things as possible, right?
Speaker 1: The only place I can't avoid this is at work because at work.
Speaker 1: they like to keep adding more software as a service things.
Speaker 1: Whereas I'm like, you know, we're already using GitHub for source control.
Speaker 1: Why don't we also use it for everything?
Speaker 1: It does right.
Speaker 1: instead of being like, you know It's like you got your JIRA in there.
Speaker 0: It's like get up as project management Right, I've yeah, I've used that it's JIRA is just better.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean it's better for but here's not better for the developers I like.
Speaker 1: all I need is a fucking to-do list.
Speaker 1: I don't need all that JIRA crap It's it.
Speaker 1: the point is just an example of like.
Speaker 1: if you've already got a tool in your you know Toolbox and that tool has a swiss army knife, you know has a knife and a can opener.
Speaker 1: don't go and buy a can opener.
Speaker 0: Well case important
Speaker 1: open, you know
Speaker 0: what changed my life more than anything technologically in like my entire adulthood was the simple Change in Adobe to where the entire creative cloud was just all together in one package always updating Because I use like easily half those applications like constantly now, right?
Speaker 1: well I use.
Speaker 1: I use a good handful of them that it's still worth paying for but that is a good example of.
Speaker 1: there are a Lot of times where I'm like, you know, suddenly I need something that does X and it's like wait I have paid for Adobe.
Speaker 1: I have a thing that does like the other day.
Speaker 0: I had a bunch of old documents.
Speaker 0: I wanted to scan them so I could throw those documents away.
Speaker 0: that is way faster and easier to do with acrobat than with like Photoshop or Random online probably malware tool.
Speaker 1: It's like I think a lot of people out there.
Speaker 1: It's like I need a font.
Speaker 1: They'll go to their browser and search for a font.
Speaker 1: I don't do that.
Speaker 1: I have typed whatever it's like it Yeah in Adobe.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess great a font though.
Speaker 0: The licensing of those fonts is Iffy, but you got it.
Speaker 1: You got a check.
Speaker 1: any wherever you get your font from you got to check the licensing.
Speaker 0: Yeah As someone who has been responsible for checking the licensing of fonts before professionally at my last company.
Speaker 0: Even then The almost no font is actually safe to use.
Speaker 1: It's like a really fucked up area Usually only a problem if you're using it on your website or in a program that you're distributing.
Speaker 1: Yeah Something like that.
Speaker 1: If you're just like making a social media post and you need a font or something like that.
Speaker 1: You can use the phone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know who runs into with the most indie game developers.
Speaker 1: Yep Definitely need to pay for your fonts in your indie game.
Speaker 1: And in fact, I would recommend if you're making games Make your fonts also.
Speaker 1: Yeah It'll be a lot that goes.
Speaker 0: honestly having someone make a font for you is probably cheaper than licensing a lot of fonts.
Speaker 1: Just also if you're me if you have a game, you probably don't you know most video games especially indie games You don't need a full as font Right and most a lot of pixely indie games.
Speaker 1: You just need a pixel font also.
Speaker 1: So you don't even you know, and how many letters do you?
Speaker 1: how many characters do you need?
Speaker 1: You know full Unicode?
Speaker 0: We don't use the letter E in this game Right, yeah, so so uh in some news So as you all know Tesla cars are basically just garbage like there's so much you just we don't even need to get into it.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I mean the TLDR of electric cars.
Speaker 1: is you know You're not really helping solving climate change and the problems of the world unless you just have less cars.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but an electric car is still I guess better than a fossil fuel car kinda Yep, but it's still not a. it's not a huge improvement over a fossil fuel car and it's sad that you know Tesla the company specifically.
Speaker 1: as opposed to other electric car companies those cars are just garbage Like.
Speaker 1: if you want an electric car, there are other ones you can get.
Speaker 0: that's it Way way better.
Speaker 0: people think of Tesla's and they're really expensive But honestly like even the Chevy electric car is way better than a Tesla if we're ready.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I read a thread on Twitter that I don't know if it's a hundred percent true but it feels true and You know all the evidence points to it being true and that Tesla has a problem getting repeat customers and someone buys a Tesla.
Speaker 1: the Experience of owning one is so bad that they won't buy another one.
Speaker 0: when the Tesla consider for a while that reddit group about Tesla's it was people like.
Speaker 0: basically there was a huge number of people who had the option of either Accept the new Tesla they'd been waiting for for like seven months or more but it has defects and they could either sign off that they were willing to deal with those defects and get the car right now or refuse it which was their right.
Speaker 0: and Maybe in six more months, you'll get a Tesla and they're basically like agreeing to take a like broken car Because they're afraid of having to wait longer to get a working one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that does not happen with any other goddamn car in America, right?
Speaker 1: And they basically the art the the person who was you know, their hypothesis, right?
Speaker 1: I guess that's the only thing I read that same thread.
Speaker 0: so right they.
Speaker 1: they posited that you know when Tesla started it was appealing to Environmentally conscious people because it was an electric car, right?
Speaker 1: It was like, you know, you know, but now it can't get repeat customers and that's why you see Ellen Musk Right rubbing elbows with more right-wing type people.
Speaker 1: They got that ridiculous Tesla truck nonsense Right because now they're they can't get repeat customers on the left.
Speaker 1: So they're going for a new audience of people.
Speaker 1: they can get to be first-time customers and then once that's exhausted I guess they'll be done.
Speaker 0: because no, they'll turn it over the Facebook.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they'll have to find new customers somewhere or eventually make a car good enough that it would.
Speaker 0: you know Grant a repeat by yeah, but it's similar.
Speaker 0: There was a thing actually I want to say for a future Monday But there is some significant speculation that a material risk to Amazon Is that they churn through warehouse workers in America so fast that they run out of people.
Speaker 0: They will run out of people who are willing to take that job in the first place.
Speaker 0: Yep, because all the people who would take a job like that have already worked there and either been fired or quit and discussed Or died.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the person who made Trader Joe's the grocery store wrote a book recently.
Speaker 1: I didn't read the book It's on my wish list But they there was some reviews of it and basically the gist I got from the reviews was that that dude?
Speaker 1: Isn't actually like nice or awesome or anything?
Speaker 1: He's just another greedy rich capitalist guy like everyone else trying to run a business and make a lot of money.
Speaker 1: But he recognized that look a better worker retention not having to hire people actually saves a fuck ton of money.
Speaker 1: therefore Trader Joe's treats its employees very well Right and pays them well and tries to keep them and it actually works.
Speaker 1: The guy was correct and he's not doing it altruistically.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's just trying to make more money.
Speaker 1: It works and that's sort of why you know, you go to Trader Joe's and like the employees are sort of like always You know trying to talk to you nice and whatever.
Speaker 1: It's part of it is that they're trained to do that And in a creepy customer service way.
Speaker 1: But part of it is actually honestly that they like working there because they're treated well.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and we see
Speaker 1: this on warehouse
Speaker 0: We see this throughout all of history any restaurant that does the thing, you know bit by bit during kovat a bunch of restaurants We're like trying to deal with the lack of staffing and they pay a lot more and prices don't go up that much.
Speaker 0: But yet service is better.
Speaker 0: The restaurant one is better.
Speaker 0: Everyone's better off.
Speaker 0: Mechanism design says you make the rules of the game cause the outcomes you want.
Speaker 0: even if you can't trust the players You gotta have rules that make sure that even the greediest most unethical motherfucker running a company It is in that person's best interest to treat their workers.
Speaker 1: Well Yeah, the thing is it is in their best interest their work as well and they still don't.
Speaker 1: it's a lot.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so what a Tesla do now, so there's a bunch of articles about this.
Speaker 0: I'll link to the Jalopnik article because it has the most insightful commentary site.
Speaker 0: So yeah good So someone discovered that newer Tesla's they have a really fancy seat that yeah I can move in a bunch of directions like basically any.
Speaker 1: most cars almost every car has that.
Speaker 1: now it is.
Speaker 0: I mean Tesla's are known for having features that Tesla owners make a big deal about.
Speaker 0: that have literally existed in cars forever.
Speaker 1: So nothing I don't remember.
Speaker 1: the last time I was in a car where at least the driver's seat had didn't have motors 2012 Chevy Cruz eco that we have.
Speaker 0: that was a gift.
Speaker 0: has that?
Speaker 1: so So my Mazda have that I don't remember.
Speaker 0: maybe uh, I forget my laser didn't but my laser didn't enough power windows.
Speaker 0: So that was in the 90s.
Speaker 0: but anyway, anyway, so Tesla has this really fancy seat and If you move the seat around too much like too frequently It'll start popping up warnings yelling at you to stop moving the seat around so much and if you keep doing it It'll actually lock you out.
Speaker 0: quote Excessive use of seat track motor.
Speaker 0: detected seat track motor unavailable due to excessive use.
Speaker 0: wait five minutes and try to adjust your seat again.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean that could make you know, it's like if they're trying to do it because they want to.
Speaker 1: you know Reduce wear on the motor.
Speaker 1: That's a problem because other cars have similar motors and don't need to do that.
Speaker 0: That's the very lead the fundamental problem here.
Speaker 0: Is that that kind of solution?
Speaker 0: Belies any idea of a reasonable problem that it is solving.
Speaker 1: Yep So the second question is well is it because it's an electric car and that uses power and they don't want you to drain The battery?
Speaker 1: because that's different than draining the battery?
Speaker 0: and you know your normal car I'll have an all normal car were idling it for like a half hour mostly charges the battery right.
Speaker 1: so that could be true.
Speaker 1: But that the point someone brought up a really good point in our forum that you should join.
Speaker 1: What's that our discord?
Speaker 1: I think was the forum might have been one of the places we talked to the listener.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it really opened my eyes this comment.
Speaker 1: It was so insightful.
Speaker 1: They were like listen you know if you really were making an electric car to try to be eco-friendly right as your goal and Then wouldn't you remove like things like power seats that are draining the battery?
Speaker 1: It's like a roll-up window is a lot more equal friendly than a power window.
Speaker 1: and I was like Yeah, I mean there's other downsides to up to a roll-up window.
Speaker 1: obviously for yeah power window.
Speaker 1: But if you terms of eco-friendliness, it's like yeah You want a car where you manually move the seat around where you manually roll up the windows, right?
Speaker 1: Where as few things use the battery as possible, right?
Speaker 1: You basically you know have like a. you know Even try to make your radio as efficient as you can.
Speaker 1: if you really want to be eco-friendly You wouldn't have power steering, but that's a bit too far.
Speaker 0: Yeah Also that might arguably be a loss Environmentally based on the.
Speaker 1: it could be the externalities of non power hiring the yes But the point is is that you know other things that are putting a drain on the battery power, you know You would want not no power sunroof, right?
Speaker 1: No, right.
Speaker 1: So Tesla while it is an electric car You know forgetting the fact that the car is a piece of shit.
Speaker 1: if it was really trying to be eco-friendly It wouldn't be having you know, no heated seats, right?
Speaker 1: You wouldn't be having that shit in there, right?
Speaker 1: Oh Eric, you know, I guess some people argue by air conditioning.
Speaker 1: I guess it depends where you live if you're.
Speaker 0: in most places air conditioning is probably a net benefit to the environment assuming the car is gonna drive anyway due to the danger of the heat in cars the fact that windows tend to just absolutely wreck the efficiency exact.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of minor points to discuss about all the different electric features.
Speaker 1: Yeah But the general point is still really insightful.
Speaker 1: that look if you were really trying to be eco-friendly Then you would examine every feature on the car.
Speaker 1: You would try to reduce weight and try to reduce power usage in all aspects of the car not simply Taken or a luxury car and just swap in the different hours.
Speaker 0: So that's actually a big.
Speaker 1: you're now green and green.
Speaker 0: That's a big more common argument against electric cars recently.
Speaker 0: Is that while there's the the tire problem, which is his own problem like we know about that problem There is a secondary problem of.
Speaker 0: there's so much heavier in general that now the meme is you're gonna drive So many tons like a tons worth of battery around powered by that battery just to get like four pounds of groceries.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's the fundamental thing.
Speaker 1: Is that the only thing that's gonna make a significant impact on the climate is A lot less cars, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah What car it is And a lot more lithium-ion batteries to drive those e-bikes.
Speaker 0: e-bikes especially the larger ones that are more accessible.
Speaker 0: They're like they're possibly the most environmental possible way to get around for a normal bicycle.
Speaker 1: The regular human-powered bicycle is still the most efficient transportation mechanism we've ever invented?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so one short short of short of a barrel in a river a barrel?
Speaker 1: I I can't.
Speaker 1: I always said it was the bicycle.
Speaker 1: But actually the barrel in the river is more Energy efficient than the bicycle.
Speaker 0: I mean the most energy efficient is I already live on top of a cliff.
Speaker 0: I only have to go down once.
Speaker 1: You could never go home never go home.
Speaker 0: You can only go downhill the rest of your life.
Speaker 0: Oh, that could be a fun indie game.
Speaker 0: I just a game but you can only go down you can never gain.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess the Oregon Trail you can only go west.
Speaker 0: yeah Oregon Trail should have had a fucking we're heading back option.
Speaker 1: It had the dollies you go down the river.
Speaker 0: and So yeah, the little more investigation into this and we'll move on because you can read this article.
Speaker 0: But it talks about how some people are saying well, they switched seat vendors something something But people pointed out that the new supplier bros, so I never heard of I don't.
Speaker 0: I don't know much about interior car like Manufacturing Nothing, and so they make the seats for like every goddamn car.
Speaker 0: But yet it appears only Tesla's have these features around seat abuse metrics Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So it's an interesting Problem among many.
Speaker 0: my advice to you is do not under any circumstances buy a Tesla car.
Speaker 1: No bad idea.
Speaker 1: So try to buy.
Speaker 1: try to you know, buy less cars and drive less in general Yeah, and if your circumstances in life have you stuck in a car centric place and you have no desire or will or ability to Leave yeah, like I have a car now.
Speaker 0: It was a gift.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna like replace it with a better car I'm just gonna keep it as well maintained as I can and get the most use out of it possible.
Speaker 0: So, uh, probably never own a car again, yeah in Some other huge news that honestly might over time become a game-changer Facebook stock collapsed like Mm-hmm a huge amount like a big deal amount and there's a bunch of news in a cluster around it.
Speaker 0: But the key is that the reason for this seems to be twofold.
Speaker 0: on one hand Everybody seems to know that the metaverse is kind of a scam but also The real reason is that Facebook for probably the first time is seeing a decrease in accounts and a decrease in usage That they can't.
Speaker 1: people people have seen this.
Speaker 1: there are people who called this right.
Speaker 1: I got it whoever they are.
Speaker 1: I definitely remember reading articles, you know years ago Yeah that hat that made this call and they were exactly right and they talked about, you know other platforms You know coming for Facebook eating their lunch, right?
Speaker 1: Look tick-tock is totally destroying right Instagram, right?
Speaker 1: It's like they're not.
Speaker 1: Facebook is not winning.
Speaker 1: Young people are not getting Facebook as just this.
Speaker 1: old people are using it and their numbers are shrinking and they're getting older new.
Speaker 1: They're not getting new people onto the platform.
Speaker 0: It's just like my cable television went right.
Speaker 0: It's like if there's a money printing machine But that money printing machine is running out of the only resource that it can use to print that money.
Speaker 1: Yep Now I thought Facebook, you know more recently very recently was making a play Where they're paying a lot of money to hire like all the software engineers in the world And they're that.
Speaker 1: therefore it didn't matter.
Speaker 1: You know what business they did because you know if we have all the software engineers working for us We're the only ones who can make anything
Speaker 0: and I personally know a Terrifying number of people who I have lost from my own company or from other companies I've worked with.
Speaker 0: like half the engineers I know outside of like our friend group have gone to Facebook over the last couple years for these.
Speaker 1: for these I think just today I think they announced like the base pay Like maximum at Amazon was going up to like 350 K and such.
Speaker 1: So the competition is coming through.
Speaker 1: sort of put a stop to that.
Speaker 1: and now the the real Thing that people have been talking about for I guess a year or two that is sort of come to pass is both Apple's increased privacy rules in the App Store iPhones iOS specifically and And GDPR and Europe are basically directly hammering Facebook's bottom line.
Speaker 1: if they can't collect as much data on users Because the privacy controls imposed upon them by governments or you know other Companies yeah that they make less money because their money is having that data and selling that data.
Speaker 1: And I don't think yes, it finally is actually hurting them right.
Speaker 1: they saw it coming and now here It is the ball dropped.
Speaker 1: Facebook is is not doing well.
Speaker 1: I guess in some number of years It will be a myspace as predicted.
Speaker 0: yep, and it's always a matter of when like cable TV Is in the exact same boat.
Speaker 0: right now?
Speaker 0: It still makes so much money that it's hard to convince a company that makes money in that space to pivot and the way Capitalism is.
Speaker 0: it's hard to even say what they could pivot to.
Speaker 0: that would make as much money as the old thing.
Speaker 0: so there's this like deep dark pattern of Incentivization to keep milking that blood out of that stone until the last possible second and then who cares What happens?
Speaker 0: just bail?
Speaker 0: So this might.
Speaker 0: this is honestly the beginning of the end.
Speaker 0: I suspect Facebook like my gut feeling.
Speaker 0: I have no inside knowledge.
Speaker 0: I'm not a Registered investment advisor.
Speaker 0: This is not investment advice.
Speaker 0: I know I say that a lot.
Speaker 0: I really have to say that or I can get a deep shit, but in my personal opinion Facebook as a company had planned to pivot to something like meta for a long time like they knew Something that would attract young people, but also let them.
Speaker 1: they tried Facebook gaming.
Speaker 1: They know Facebook marketplace, but also wouldn't let them be good thing to buy on those young people.
Speaker 0: they needed to attract young people.
Speaker 1: let them spy on those young people and Monetize those young people and there's no other way to make money on young, you know, not just Facebook meta Whatever, but any company.
Speaker 1: you want to make money on young people, right young people Don't have a lot of fucking money unless their parents are rich or some shit, you know.
Speaker 1: so the only way to make money off young people is To steal their data.
Speaker 0: I'll back up a little further.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go even worse.
Speaker 1: if you try to sell young people a subscription they can't.
Speaker 1: if they don't pay for it They'll pirate it or something.
Speaker 0: But even further like how do they make all their money now?
Speaker 0: because of the ads that they can sell to older people based on all that data.
Speaker 0: But a lot of that ecosystem was bolstered by the number of daily users of Facebook, which is dropping.
Speaker 0: so I suspect Facebook expected one of these pivots to work and thought they had more time and I think Maybe kovid might have been a little bit of a factor here in that Facebook's user base dropped faster than they anticipated.
Speaker 0: they couldn't smooth it over and now they're completely fucked.
Speaker 1: All right, also even if the meta, you know hype, you know Cyberspace whatever plan works it's so many years out before that would land and
Speaker 0: you got this impression part of the reason why they were hiring so hard for Their metaverse shit and part of why like blockchain and NFTs and all these other things are there.
Speaker 0: There's two things going on.
Speaker 0: on one hand.
Speaker 0: I think that was Facebook.
Speaker 0: someone inside Definitely knew this was coming and they were aggressively trying to accelerate their metaverse plans.
Speaker 0: Probably before they were ready They started having to shit talk way in advance of delivering something which is one of the primary ways to guarantee you will fail.
Speaker 0: That's why Scott and I were so careful to not shit talk like we used to in older game nights.
Speaker 1: But they you if you have investors you have to shit talk to get them to give you money.
Speaker 0: Yeah up to a point depends on which investors.
Speaker 0: but - there's a broader problem and this is where I'm gonna step back and actually Lean.
Speaker 0: not I. this isn't.
Speaker 0: this is my personal opinion and it is also my professional opinion as a product manager But not a professional opinion.
Speaker 0: reflecting any particular company I work for or have ever worked for except geek nights where this literally represents at least 50% of geek nights is official opinion.
Speaker 0: Fuck you, we could say whatever we want.
Speaker 0: We're geek nights.
Speaker 0: But as a product manager My job that for many years across many companies has been to decide what could make money.
Speaker 0: How do you make money?
Speaker 0: What do you sell?
Speaker 0: What is the strategy?
Speaker 0: Like that's what my actual job is.
Speaker 0: What do you make?
Speaker 0: How do you make it?
Speaker 0: Will it make money?
Speaker 0: How do you make money?
Speaker 0: I'm increasingly convinced that nothing can make money.
Speaker 0: I think the capitalist environment in America is toxic to the point that nothing could possibly make enough money to get enough investment to get off the ground and I don't know what to do about that.
Speaker 1: Make an actual product that's You know.
Speaker 0: good products don't make enough money for investors products that are disposal.
Speaker 1: No not for investors No, but you've enough for profits that you could live on.
Speaker 0: Ah, but how do you get the mud the capital to make the product in the first place?
Speaker 1: Savings.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the poor money is a problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so anyway If some person wants a bankroll as we could definitely make a profitable product It just won't be as profitable as Facebook was until a few days ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the last the last tidbit is that Was I said, oh that Facebook is like threatened to Go like leave Europe over GDPR, please Right, and I know in the past I have said things like, you know mostly related to Google search where I was like encouraging Google search to like, you know If I was like off I was CEO of Google.
Speaker 1: I would tell China and other countries like do what I say or no more Google search in your country to sort of you know.
Speaker 1: To get countries to be good right not to get them to do bad stuff Yeah, but Google was a little bit different back then - yeah.
Speaker 1: But in this case like Facebook saying oh we might have to leave and stop operating in Europe if we can't you know Transfer our data to the US like it just won't work which is sort of technologically true.
Speaker 1: You know, like if someone posts a photo on Instagram, what are you gonna do?
Speaker 1: Let you not let us users see the photo, you know It's like you had to transfer the data from Europe to the US in order for that to happen.
Speaker 1: So you can only follow people in your geography on Facebook right with these data transfer.
Speaker 0: I mean look at what Twitter does.
Speaker 0: Twitter has a whole different moderation system Basically just for Germany because Germany has laws saying you can't let Nazis use your platform.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and not not to mention the sheer amount of like, you know, if you didn't, you know cash the foreign users content on local You know servers the amount of like CDN like traffic that would be going over the international wires would be possible, right?
Speaker 1: They wouldn't be.
Speaker 1: they really they're not lying.
Speaker 1: They wouldn't be able to operate if these law these rules get enforced on them.
Speaker 1: However When Facebook says we might have to leave Europe my response is don't threaten me with a good time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz remember when it comes to situations like this like this is sort of a message to all you nerds out there.
Speaker 0: Ideological purity is a mistake.
Speaker 0: You've got to think about outcomes of actions and Regard like we buy.
Speaker 0: if this exact same situation happened, but the nouns were shuffled around.
Speaker 0: It was a different company over a different issue.
Speaker 0: the right move might be Yeah, we should like.
Speaker 0: we got a. Europe's gonna have to play ball Europe's gonna have to do the right thing.
Speaker 0: But in this case Facebook is a toxic influence on society.
Speaker 0: So fuck them.
Speaker 0: I hope Europe destroys them over this.
Speaker 0: but anyway things Of the day, this is just a little thing, but I think literally a little thing.
Speaker 0: But I think you should appreciate it.
Speaker 0: There is a an individual who has saved Uncountable human lives and that is hard to say exactly how many lives Magawa saved.
Speaker 0: but Magawa is a little rat and This little rat is part of an army of little rats who are very trainable to find landmines particularly in places like Cambodia so that humans can disable them to prevent people from being killed by Random landmines that people left in the ground.
Speaker 0: the landmines kill so many people on a dotted like yearly basis to this day.
Speaker 0: It is terrifying and it's barely talked about in countries like the United States.
Speaker 1: I'm all you know, and it's not talked about often.
Speaker 1: But you know every time landmines come up all the u.s.
Speaker 0: Still has not signed that treaty.
Speaker 0: last I checked.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: We are one of the only countries on earth that reserves the right to use landmines.
Speaker 1: still Yeah something.
Speaker 1: but the thing that I think about a lot that I've never hear other people talk about is that there are places In the world two that come to mind for me are obviously between North and South Korea and the DMZ and also in Israel like in the Golan Heights the border between Israel and Lebanon and you know places like that in the world that are.
Speaker 1: They're not places like Cambodia where people are just living and there used to be landmines from a previous war So people step on them.
Speaker 1: They're places where landmines are actively being used for a current You know conflict right on purpose, but if at some point in the future There is a resolution to that conflict right?
Speaker 1: You're gonna need to get these mice out there, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, because the landmines are there.
Speaker 1: What are you gonna do?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and while there is South Korea suddenly Kumbaya tomorrow, right?
Speaker 1: What the fuck you gonna do there?
Speaker 1: You put all these landmines there you dumbasses.
Speaker 0: Yeah, remember landmines by design are hard to find.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's sort of the point.
Speaker 1: if they were easy to find and disable The soldiers would just do that and never step on them and they would be pointless.
Speaker 0: So yep as of today 164 countries have signed the Ottawa Treaty.
Speaker 1: that how many countries are there?
Speaker 0: Yeah more than that.
Speaker 0: Let's see It is not signed.
Speaker 0: the notable countries where there are 32 countries who could have signed it who chose not to The United States Russia China are the three big ones who have not signed it.
Speaker 1: How about that?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I'd sign that shit day one.
Speaker 1: I'd be like, I guess the Senate has to do something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually presidents have Really pushed for this but the Senate blocks all treaties meeting right now Literally United States actually is incapable of signing treaties currently because of the way our Senate is.
Speaker 1: But we also can't unsign treaties.
Speaker 0: We could just stop following them.
Speaker 0: What's someone gonna do?
Speaker 0: That's a not that that's but we just can't unsign them though I actually we did read.
Speaker 0: we did relatively recently under the former guy Unsigned the treaty that banned intermediate-range nuclear weapons in Europe.
Speaker 1: Oh We could resign that.
Speaker 0: Oh guess who needs to sign that?
Speaker 0: Anyway Kirsten send him as a traitor overturned the filibuster.
Speaker 0: So yeah, this little rat is a hero and in general, I think there is a very important future for humanity where We have animals that we take good care of and we train and collaborate with who basically do jobs for us.
Speaker 0: Imagine writing pulling fiber through tunnels.
Speaker 0: Imagine crows like looking for lost electronics and bringing them to a central place Like.
Speaker 1: I think the people who are currently making police robots should make landmine Finding robots instead and not make landmine planting robots.
Speaker 0: Yeah That you realize though the company that that what if I may if I was the company who is making the landmine placing robots?
Speaker 0: You know, I have also made the landmine finding robot and it is way more expensive than the landmine placing robot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, fuck that company Yep, so look at this little red little hero little hero, dude All right.
Speaker 1: So my thing of the day nerds love swords.
Speaker 1: There's plenty of sword nerds out there.
Speaker 0: Very grateful that I only own one sword.
Speaker 1: there was a you know, and there's an exact for us non sword nerds.
Speaker 1: But you were still a nerd so you still love a sword.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, come on fucking.
Speaker 0: so show me the faux hammer and I am just all about that.
Speaker 1: But there's a certain um, there's like a correct dosage of sword.
Speaker 1: You can't overdose.
Speaker 1: Here's your.
Speaker 1: here is your dose of sword for the year this sword guy.
Speaker 1: There's actually an old video.
Speaker 1: I just didn't discover it till recently.
Speaker 1: I didn't discover.
Speaker 0: you linked me to it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a hot topic in the sword community that I was unaware of so it's hot to me.
Speaker 1: I guess it might have been hot to sword people long ago.
Speaker 1: Is that when you watch movies and TV shows, especially Fantasy ones where swords are involved you often see people carrying swords strapped to their back.
Speaker 1: many anime are guilty of this for sure.
Speaker 1: Usually it's someone with a big-ass claymore, right?
Speaker 1: Hey, you know, you've seen this a sword on your back, right.
Speaker 1: and in fantasy You see people draw the sword from their back or put it back into right.
Speaker 1: that's on their back.
Speaker 1: But if you have to do that in real life, it's unrealistic.
Speaker 1: It's just not done.
Speaker 1: in history.
Speaker 1: No one no historical people have worn swords on their back for battle, right?
Speaker 1: Just there, you know in any country right where swords were used Swords were not put in a sheath on the back.
Speaker 1: It was on the hip or on the horse or It's gonna point out some very specific exception.
Speaker 0: We don't know about.
Speaker 0: we're not in.
Speaker 1: the sword guy in this video said it wasn't done Historically, so I'm going.
Speaker 1: this is sword guy knowledge.
Speaker 1: It's like I know.
Speaker 0: I know that I am simply in beforring things like Non-accessible transport like you're carrying.
Speaker 1: this is something that I knew.
Speaker 1: this is something I just learned from my one dose of sword.
Speaker 0: I've seen this short sword guy before so I do trust him a significant amount.
Speaker 1: I've seen that anyway In this video.
Speaker 1: this sword guy you can fast-forward through most of the video just get to the good part.
Speaker 1: But the point is he made a you know, just to prove that it was a thing He constructed out of wood a back sword, you know, she slash scabbard Whatever the difference is.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'm not a sword guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right That has like a slit on the side so that it's somewhat You know, I guess practical.
Speaker 0: it's way good.
Speaker 1: It's kind of funny to watch the times.
Speaker 1: He tries to put the sword back in there and fails.
Speaker 1: Yeah The main advantage I see in sword on the back is Simply that just you can carry more weight on your back and if a big heavy sword is more comfortable, right?
Speaker 0: Well, I don't think you were necessarily like.
Speaker 0: it comes down to what are you using this sword for?
Speaker 0: There was the only.
Speaker 1: if you're what I'm assuming you're walking a long distance with the sword and you don't have a horse.
Speaker 0: But in that case why?
Speaker 0: it's probably like in the pack or like there's other ways to transport that kind of thing.
Speaker 0: Not if it's a big-ass fucking, you know, I mean like there's mule there's pack mules.
Speaker 0: There's there's camp followers There's all sorts of nonsense.
Speaker 0: I guess what I'm getting at is The era where people wore swords around Was pretty shorts and mostly just dipshits during very brief parts of history in particular cities.
Speaker 1: Hey, I guess in Japan they carried swords around but those were lighter smaller swords, and they never carried them on the back.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm thinking mostly of European dipshits dueling with each other during like certain parts of the Renaissance not Like a little foil like a little light sword, so who needs to carry that on your back, right?
Speaker 0: Well, a lot of them would have basically stilettos because a lot of those sword duels came down to Stab the other guy first real quick and then he's done and you win and walk away like that's it.
Speaker 0: It was one stroke.
Speaker 1: It wasn't a big heavy claymore that needs to be carried on the back cuz it's so heavy.
Speaker 0: Yeah we've got a Another Scott in the.
Speaker 0: I got reading about scabbards and telling us why we're wrong.
Speaker 0: There's some Celts did it anyway.
Speaker 1: Okay, met a moment.
Speaker 1: Let's go Alright.
Speaker 0: the geek nice book club book is not in fact the tale of Genji.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna update the website with the new.
Speaker 0: I actually I'm waiting on that because we have done one episode on the tale of Genji.
Speaker 0: We were going to do at least one more episode on the tale of Genji next Thursday Because I spent two years reading a book having a lot to say about it.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So the next episode We already did one episode.
Speaker 0: It's up.
Speaker 0: You can listen to it If you read the tale of Genji.
Speaker 0: that episode we just talked about like what we thought of Genji the story itself.
Speaker 0: the next one we're gonna talk about a bunch of meta and how the book changed and like the Structure of a novel and like modern readers and all that kind of nonsense history
Speaker 1: and stuff, you know
Speaker 0: Yep, our very facile and limited understanding of hey and era culture much of which I learned from reading the tale of Genji.
Speaker 1: Yep, so the next book club book after the tale of Genji NK jemisins the city we became.
Speaker 1: yeah, I Went.
Speaker 1: immediately after we recorded the first Genji episode.
Speaker 1: I went to bed and I continued reading that book and finished reading that book.
Speaker 1: So before we've even done the second episode on Genji, I finished reading the next book club book.
Speaker 0: But I was not hungry.
Speaker 1: We got to give the listener and we got to give rim some time to read that book.
Speaker 0: This book will not take me long to read.
Speaker 1: I looked at how many didn't take me long to read at all.
Speaker 1: This book has a moment in it.
Speaker 1: That is a big payoff.
Speaker 1: that was very satisfying and I know I was previously hesitant about reading this book because it is the first in a series and I don't like to do that, but I can tell you that even if somehow the great crime happens and you know, the world falls into to ruin and The no other book in this series is ever published that that's okay You're.
Speaker 1: it's not a it's not a cliffhanger deal.
Speaker 0: It's not an R Scott backer situation of wealth.
Speaker 0: We have triggered the literal end of everything you were waiting for and I just stopped writing books.
Speaker 1: Apparently No, it's a. it's basically the ending, you know, you know spoiler, I guess I don't know.
Speaker 1: not really is that you know, there's a lot of times where you'll have like Think about it like this if you watch an episode of GI Joe, right?
Speaker 1: Well, it's like at the end of an episode of GI Joe they beat Cobra, right?
Speaker 1: The the bad guy is defeated.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they don't finish Cobra off.
Speaker 0: They just boil.
Speaker 0: whatever cover was up.
Speaker 1: The right exactly be.
Speaker 1: the current conflict is resolved But the greater conflict is just still out there and that is how this book goes.
Speaker 1: Being the first in a series is that this book completely resolves itself as much as the episode of any TV show Would resolve itself, but the greater larger setting still has a greater unresolved conflict.
Speaker 1: that allows for further books But does not put you in suspense.
Speaker 1: So you don't need to wait for book two to be published.
Speaker 1: I was wrong.
Speaker 1: You can just read book one right now and you should.
Speaker 0: the listener just said and I quote This is a very geek nights book.
Speaker 1: It is a extremely geek.
Speaker 1: It is like Nothing book.
Speaker 1: It was as good as I expected it to be perhaps even better.
Speaker 1: I can't get over that payoff moment.
Speaker 1: It was like me.
Speaker 0: I'll tease you with.
Speaker 0: the genre that it is listed under is Urban fantasy and I'll just leave it at that.
Speaker 1: the.
Speaker 1: the payoff might even be better than what.
Speaker 1: do you see?
Speaker 1: It's like it's such a pale.
Speaker 1: so Yeah, that's all I got to say.
Speaker 0: so yeah, let's get right into it with otherwise no cons coming up.
Speaker 0: if We and/or Scott are at PAX East very likely.
Speaker 0: It'll be for just one day Maybe just to do a panel and hang out for a day.
Speaker 0: It's unlikely.
Speaker 0: I will be at PAX East for the entirety of a PAX East Just considering everything.
Speaker 0: but stay tuned on that.
Speaker 0: It's very likely there'll be at least one geek nice panel there, but it might be like packs unplugged.
Speaker 0: We're just being by myself.
Speaker 0: depends on how Scott's feeling and how everything is Shaping up.
Speaker 0: We can't really.
Speaker 1: maybe I'll decide to go with the last second.
Speaker 1: We'll see what goes up.
Speaker 0: and same thing like unplugged.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: it's pretty easy to go to a kind like that at the last Second unless we're all in and I can't.
Speaker 1: we don't if we don't go to pecs unplugged 2022.
Speaker 1: That's real sad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I I'm really hoping.
Speaker 0: by the time the next pecs unplugged happens I'd like to go to a convention 2022.
Speaker 0: I would like to go to conventions not have to wear a mask because it's safe not because we've given up exactly, so Otherwise, we're working on some panels and stuff.
Speaker 0: Scott's working on the website.
Speaker 0: Like keep following us on the Internet.
Speaker 1: So I should do that shouldn't?
Speaker 0: yep.
Speaker 0: I mean we got time.
Speaker 0: There's no Immediate rush.
Speaker 0: I got some other things I'm working on.
Speaker 0: I'm working on a. I did so.
Speaker 0: I was working on a panel not for a con just for me But I paused that because I'm working on something far more powerful.
Speaker 0: Scott knows about it.
Speaker 0: a good friend of ours knows about it.
Speaker 0: No one else knows what I'm working on.
Speaker 0: Good Lord.
Speaker 0: Do I have some things to say?
Speaker 1: I found okay, let's go on with it with the show here.
Speaker 0: So Technological lock-in.
Speaker 0: What are we talking about?
Speaker 0: Imagine say you made a podcast and you put that podcast up on a platform.
Speaker 0: Let's say Libsyn It happened to be one of many platforms that would host your podcast forever with all the backlog with reasonable prices.
Speaker 0: so let's say you and your friend, let's call him just I don't know scored and Together you do this.
Speaker 0: All right fast forward 1020 years.
Speaker 0: all the other platforms years that offered this stuff don't exist anymore.
Speaker 1: The one you're using happens to still exist and actually if I was starting a podcast today They're actually a lot of really good platforms besides Libsyn, but it's true.
Speaker 1: We're locked in.
Speaker 0: I mean we we did start geek nights like what before there were platforms that there weren't any choices back then.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like not a lot of good ones.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yep.
Speaker 0: Also we have a terrifying backlog.
Speaker 0: That's all free on the internet.
Speaker 0: It's all there.
Speaker 0: So if Libsyn one day came to us and said hey, we're shutting down at the end of this year The amount of hassle and headache and pain that that would cause me and Scott personally me and score personally theoretically would be unimaginable.
Speaker 1: Right and it because of the you know, whenever something like this happens They're always gonna be these technological details so that you know We're you know, you're locked in.
Speaker 1: right if there isn't a technological hang-up of some kind With regards to transitioning away from the platform then there is no lock-in.
Speaker 1: you could just move at any time right, so like if you just Have some sort of I don't know Google Docs equivalent platform right?
Speaker 1: Fogle Fogle Docs, right?
Speaker 1: But they store all your documents in text format or you know some open format.
Speaker 1: Well, there's no lock-in.
Speaker 1: if they shut down you have all your documents in this open format.
Speaker 1: You could just take them all to somewhere else and you're as good as when you started.
Speaker 1: you didn't lose, you know You're not stuck.
Speaker 1: All right, there's always some technological hang-up that makes it painful difficult or impossible to move without Sacrificing something so like in the case of Libsyn.
Speaker 1: if you were to move off of Libsyn, right?
Speaker 1: There would be a hassle re-upload all our mp3 somewhere else.
Speaker 1: We'll get around that.
Speaker 0: Well case though already that presents a problem because a lot of places have a rolling window of how much you can upload.
Speaker 0: we would Get around it somehow, but it would require negotiation and possibly paying extra money, right?
Speaker 1: But what would be impossible would be the fact that we have URLs pointing at mp3 files that are libsyn.com Something something dot mp3.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and all those you are.
Speaker 1: if they shut down All those URLs are broken and we have no way to redirect them and you might think so Don't be like on that everything to another platform.
Speaker 1: We will suffer this permanent set of broken links around the entire internet that we are unable to repair.
Speaker 0: Now you might say but don't you have a website just like redirect of the RSS feed?
Speaker 0: update that yes There are a lot of places that point at those URLs that we do have control over.
Speaker 0: But the beauty of the internet is anyone can link to anything.
Speaker 0: any Shmuck out there could be linking directly to this mp3s And I'm sure a lot of things are and that's what I love about the internet.
Speaker 0: But that also means there is.
Speaker 0: that is an irresolvable problem All right.
Speaker 1: It also means that the company that runs that platform that is locking you in right has some hold on you Right.
Speaker 1: It's like libsyn raises prices.
Speaker 1: What the fuck are we gonna do about it?
Speaker 1: Yeah pay that's what we're gonna do.
Speaker 1: Yeah choice, even if we don't like it, obviously they raise the price too much.
Speaker 1: We would just suffer the consequences and break all the links.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know, there is a. there is a line.
Speaker 1: We only have so much money, but if I raise the price about five bucks a month It's like we just got to pay it.
Speaker 0: We got no choice Right, so a company that was more like geek nights is just me and Scott like.
Speaker 0: there's no one.
Speaker 0: We don't have any other employees.
Speaker 0: So it's not like if this were a company like I've done.
Speaker 0: risk assessment I used to be a chief risk officer for a time and basically Contingency plans for if anything we rely on has a problem of any kind are the kind of thing a company does as a matter Of course, like what are all the things we use?
Speaker 0: what would happen to us if any one of them disappeared tomorrow?
Speaker 0: Like could we resolve that?
Speaker 0: so if we don't think we control completely, yeah Like we do have some plans like we control our domain and there's a lot of damage mitigation we could do.
Speaker 0: but also We live stream the episodes to YouTube.
Speaker 0: That means that the show is available on a different unrelated platform that even uses a different cloud provider from what Libsyn uses Mm-hmm, but also Patreon part of the reason we have the patreon.
Speaker 0: Sometimes we have some special stuff every now and then and I got some things in the hopper that are coming again.
Speaker 1: I mean if I was in charge, we still wouldn't have the patreon.
Speaker 0: but patreon is free and Every geek nights episode I upload to patreon free to anyone.
Speaker 0: You don't even need a patreon account to listen.
Speaker 0: So it's free hosting for every episode of geek nights Which means there is there are two alternate URLs for every geek nights episode that we make at this point Not the whole archive going all the way back in time That are completely independent of each other and independent of our primary provider.
Speaker 1: That's yeah, like that's.
Speaker 1: one thing you can do for lock-in right is if you prepare in advance.
Speaker 0: Usually just having backups will help you with a lot of oh, yeah We also Scott has a backup of every mp3 you've ever uploaded.
Speaker 0: I have a backup of not only every everything but also all the raw wave files and all the projects and everything.
Speaker 0: So there's a lot of mitigation there.
Speaker 0: We don't have to use this specific example any further But I thought a real example might help set the stage for what we're talking about.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess let's go back to the olden the olden days right.
Speaker 1: the oldest examples of computer lock-in Right were I guess if you go way back it was simply that you know people are writing programs in assembly languages and You would be stuck on a particular computer architecture.
Speaker 1: And so, you know, you couldn't moved over either.
Speaker 1: stuck, you know wrote your program for your business on an alpha chip.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you couldn't.
Speaker 1: you couldn't switch over to Apple right.
Speaker 1: you'd have to rewrite all your software, right?
Speaker 1: So that was like.
Speaker 1: that was the first lock-in.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think.
Speaker 1: yet OS lock-in, right?
Speaker 1: It's like oh the program you need only runs on Windows, right?
Speaker 1: It doesn't run on anything else Right, and then there was file format lock-in.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like.
Speaker 1: ah, I see that you have, you know created a word document.
Speaker 1: I guess you're never using word perfect forever because your business is now Microsoft's business.
Speaker 1: What are you gonna do?
Speaker 1: switch your business to word perfect instead lose every document you've ever had be unable to open them.
Speaker 0: Right little things like a connector can be a form of lock-in.
Speaker 0: How many different connectors have were used to connect to phones and things in charge over the years?
Speaker 0: One notable fruit-based company uses a different connector from everybody else.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I bet guess you're buying lightning cables.
Speaker 1: No Yeah, right, you know you could buy them for someone else though, so it's not complete lock-in.
Speaker 0: But these are all different like shades and degrees of lock-in and the important thing to really think about is that lock-in occurs with technology Even if it is not intentional by the companies that are making things.
Speaker 0: Yep, it is a natural course of the more you use something the more you rely on that thing.
Speaker 0: I would actually struggle to quickly catalog from memory every thing every individual thing.
Speaker 0: that would be a problem if we switch providers from Libsyn like.
Speaker 0: That would be an effort to even like fully catalog that and we probably still miss something.
Speaker 0: So yeah, every little thing you use has locked you into some small degree, but then there's the profit motive.
Speaker 0: There are some platforms some services Something as a service like platform as a service cloud providers.
Speaker 0: They have other forms of lock-in where There is an incentive for them to make sure that you build things that will only work on their platform on purpose.
Speaker 1: Yep, it's like, you know what I when Amazon Web Services first came about right the first service They had was ec2 which is literally just run servers.
Speaker 1: I guess before that they had Mechanical Turk and s3.
Speaker 1: But you easy to was like when they first started for real there were some lesser-known services that I actually used in the early days Anyway, but there weren't that many there were.
Speaker 1: now there's like too many.
Speaker 1: No one knows them all Yeah, and but ec2 is just run a Linux server.
Speaker 1: So it wasn't really.
Speaker 1: you weren't locked in.
Speaker 1: if you use that right you can just switch over to.
Speaker 1: you know Any other hosting provider?
Speaker 0: in fact that in that era?
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I used Amazon ec2 for primarily to get out of the lock-in of the one expensive data center.
Speaker 0: I was paying for all the service.
Speaker 0: So we're gonna move all this to Amazon.
Speaker 0: It's way cheaper.
Speaker 1: Fuck you, right and s3 was a little bit of lock-in but not too much.
Speaker 1: It was just a store.
Speaker 1: It's still just a storage bucket and nowadays people even offer other storage systems that use the same API.
Speaker 1: So that's not a lock-in either, right?
Speaker 1: But so when I was at first setting things up on Oz I was conscious of the lock-in potential from day one Because I noticed it wasn't exactly the same as other hosting services, right?
Speaker 1: So when I was at work creating applications that ran on Amazon web services I would be like, alright, we're I'm gonna let us use RDS because that's literally just a database, right?
Speaker 1: If we have to leave Amazon, we can run an equivalent of that service.
Speaker 1: No problem, right?
Speaker 1: this other service That's just a hosted memcached.
Speaker 1: We can just run that if we have to leave.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but then they had other things.
Speaker 1: I remember they had SQ s. they still have it which is simple queue service.
Speaker 1: It's a. it's a pretty good queue system.
Speaker 1: It's just fine.
Speaker 1: It works great.
Speaker 1: But I was like look if we leave Amazon and we got our software written to use SQ s We're gonna have to rewrite all that part of the software to instead use a different queue like rabbit MQ or Some kind of.
Speaker 0: any of you who have ever worked in enterprise are immediately thinking about what happens when you try to migrate a Middleware bus in a company, right?
Speaker 1: So it would.
Speaker 1: it wouldn't be you know a huge effort considering the size of the software but it would still be like a pain in the butt and You'd have to.
Speaker 1: you know, you would need a software engineer or you just be broken, right?
Speaker 1: And it's like.
Speaker 1: well I think it's more important for us to not be stuck With Amazon and be able to go to any provider we want if we find lower prices better service, etc.
Speaker 1: Right better, you know, so but then you're trading off Right instead of using Amazon us.
Speaker 1: I used rabbit MQ and I was like there.
Speaker 0: now we can you know We're going to go but then depending on how you implement that kind of thing You often lose efficiency in that some of these Have like like.
Speaker 0: the way lambda works on Amazon is really cool and depending on your application You can.
Speaker 0: yeah lambda you can scale up like massively parallel simple computations infinitely pretty cheaply.
Speaker 0: But you're pretty much gonna build that around as long as each one takes less than 15 minutes.
Speaker 0: Yep I mean my use cases for that are things that takes less than a second.
Speaker 0: So yeah, usually yeah Yeah, I feel if you have a life you think you're gonna have a quote long-running lambda on Amazon your you.
Speaker 1: That's not what it's for.
Speaker 0: but then there's another kind of lock-in that is the Platform or walled garden that has lock-in on purpose certain kinds of app stores.
Speaker 0: Certainly a show.
Speaker 1: we did a show about walled gardens.
Speaker 1: talking about all these specifically Books.
Speaker 1: you bought books on Kindle.
Speaker 1: I guess you're a Kindle person now, right?
Speaker 0: I bought a bunch of Amazon apps garden Amazon apps about a bunch of Android apps.
Speaker 0: Guess what?
Speaker 0: I don't have on my iPhone.
Speaker 0: Thankfully, I don't need or miss any of those old apps except one.
Speaker 0: I do miss one of them to the point that I might try to remake that app, basically good luck.
Speaker 0: But that is a little more nefarious and interesting in one way because Those kinds of places and are being very generic here because this is thick.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of flavors of this.
Speaker 0: They make no they don't hide the fact that it's a blocked in platform.
Speaker 0: They're like yo, you want to be on a locked in platform?
Speaker 0: Let's go.
Speaker 1: but like so, you know benefits of getting locked in right, you know As long as they don't shut it down or ruin it.
Speaker 1: You know, it's often like everything integrates well, right?
Speaker 1: it's like when something's open it usually has to have lots of integrations and be flexible and whatnot and There and there's less money coming in from being locked in.
Speaker 0: So like here's an example There is almost no reason on earth for anyone who makes PC games to bother making a Mac port like an iOS port.
Speaker 0: Well iOS port you make a lot of money that depending on the kind of game Depends on the game sure compared to the audience Considering that the audience of PC gamers is for certain types of games primarily on gaming pcs at least for now.
Speaker 1: Like hey you bought a game on Steam, right?
Speaker 1: I guess you're a steam user now forever, right?
Speaker 1: You're gonna buy more games.
Speaker 1: You're gonna buy them on Steam.
Speaker 1: if you buy a game on GOG You could download that game and just have it and you could uninstall GOG and never use them again.
Speaker 1: I know that they're not doing so.
Speaker 1: well GOG is is not?
Speaker 1: you know, it's not killing it there.
Speaker 1: They're not you know, they're struggling.
Speaker 0: cuz like I said earlier It's hard to make money doing anything.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So and this is all like we're not even casting a moral judgment.
Speaker 0: lock-in is in some cases a plan to make money.
Speaker 0: in some cases the natural way a certain kind of ecosystem could work.
Speaker 0: in some cases just an affordance of the Physicality of a thing or in a for our just a an externality of the fact that you are using anything to do anything.
Speaker 0: So we're not casting like a moral judge capitalism.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I Do it.
Speaker 1: they just they have gap.
Speaker 1: It's capitalism.
Speaker 1: They have to.
Speaker 1: they have no choice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have a steam account.
Speaker 0: Most of the games I buy are on that steam account.
Speaker 0: I also have a Nintendo account.
Speaker 0: bunch of games are on that.
Speaker 0: I have a GOG account.
Speaker 0: I bought a bunch of stuff from there.
Speaker 0: I have the epic game store.
Speaker 0: I have exactly one game installed So I don't have the last one.
Speaker 0: yeah, you should four nights real fun.
Speaker 1: I mean I would if I didn't have to have another store.
Speaker 0: I mean you could install it just to play it long enough to do a review and then you could just delete it.
Speaker 0: It doesn't do much other than play fortnight.
Speaker 1: Don't trust it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you don't trust it.
Speaker 0: I'm saying is I would like?
Speaker 1: I'll say it is.
Speaker 1: my computer only gets better.
Speaker 0: All I'm saying is I would love to see you play fortnight once after having experienced pub G again in recent memory.
Speaker 1: Let's go.
Speaker 1: Let's go play some fortnight at like PAX or something and we can use.
Speaker 1: you know, not on my computer.
Speaker 0: Uh Okay.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I'll play some fortnight tonight.
Speaker 1: Maybe I guess I maybe I could do the switch one But I really don't want to play with the game.
Speaker 0: Also if you play the switch one that fucks us up because they separate mouse and keyboard people from controller.
Speaker 0: people Like if you put the game in first-person mode You can't play third-person and vice versa because otherwise people who play in third-person just lose.
Speaker 0: They know like they.
Speaker 0: but the thing that's the one thing there's get mad about.
Speaker 0: Yeah talk about lock-in.
Speaker 0: if you ever play a first-person shooter with a mouse and keyboard and You like get used to that and you could try to play a like Serious first-person shooter you've locked your own brain in in some senses.
Speaker 1: Mmm Yeah, you know a lot of the lock-ins we've talked about are sort of you know lock-ins that came.
Speaker 1: You know that you could explain them away as not purely You know, like, you know just greedy lock-in for no reason, right?
Speaker 1: It's like yeah We made this special queuing service.
Speaker 1: But look it, you know It integrates and it's all that you know.
Speaker 1: like.
Speaker 1: we made this because it's easier for everyone to use to get them to use Amazon more as opposed to just using an Existing off-the-shelf one, you know that we couldn't make that integrate with our stuff on the back end.
Speaker 0: But in most product management frameworks not even the reason stuff I've been trained on but so it's front of memory.
Speaker 0: But just like my entire life in this discipline as a career Stickiness is one of the core competencies that you are always told to treat as an asset.
Speaker 0: Nobody talks about any of the externalities of that other than that is one Attribute of many of a product and the more stickiness it has the better product It is.
Speaker 0: from a purely cynical capitalist perspective Yeah, but what?
Speaker 1: the real evil ones are the ones where the stickiness doesn't come as any Benefit other than the stickiness, right?
Speaker 1: So the best example are like the DRMs?
Speaker 1: Yeah, notably like the John Deere tractor repair DRM, right?
Speaker 1: That's currently the government is actually doing okay job.
Speaker 0: all the stuff that makes made it hard for so long to get codes out Of cars and parse those codes.
Speaker 1: Yep, or you know, for example, you know PSD files are a good example, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like yeah, okay They made a proprietary file format that they can keep changing the specs on because they need Photoshop to.
Speaker 1: you know They want to add features to Photoshop.
Speaker 1: They need to add features to PSD files, right?
Speaker 1: So if it was some, you know open format that anyone could modify then it's like well now.
Speaker 1: But what they could do is they could still publish a spec for PSD files, right?
Speaker 1: You know and allow other people to at least read and write them.
Speaker 1: and you know even if it wasn't an open spec that other people could contribute to they could still.
Speaker 1: you know, Let other people read and write PSD files and does not lock you into Photoshop so hard But they don't because they want to lock you into Photoshop so hard.
Speaker 1: Once you've made a PSD file, you need Photoshop to read that file.
Speaker 1: You have to keep paying the subscription forever, right?
Speaker 1: Or you'll never see what's in that file ever again, unless someone of Photoshop opens it for you.
Speaker 0: the enterprise governments and b2b type sectors are where lock-in as a strategy is like common and Super on purpose.
Speaker 0: like that is a place you will see that more than anywhere else.
Speaker 0: Probably.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean people companies invest a lot into customer acquisition.
Speaker 1: the more lock-in they can do especially if it's technological type lock-in Saves the money on not losing customers.
Speaker 1: Right, you get a customer good.
Speaker 1: They're set.
Speaker 1: All right, we don't have to worry about customer service.
Speaker 1: We don't got to spend less money there.
Speaker 1: spend less money everywhere else, right?
Speaker 1: Just say to acquire customers and lock them in.
Speaker 1: You you know, not only do you keep getting money from that customer?
Speaker 1: But you save a lot of money and all the other areas of your business because they're stuck with you.
Speaker 0: They got no choice Yep, but in that case, even if it isn't intentional by a vendor many vendors are doing it on purpose for real.
Speaker 0: It's their main strategy get people using your thing Keep you in the ecosystem forever.
Speaker 0: Now, you can literally never leave and in fact, there's such a critical business partner some of these smaller Something as a service startups.
Speaker 0: I Suspect their goal is to become so indispensable that their biggest customers fight over who buys them.
Speaker 1: Yep, that's the last kind of lock-in when the show here.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: the last kind of lock-in is the not quite technological Lock-in, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you could leave right?
Speaker 1: There's nothing really stopping you from leaving, but it's a purely Money audience lock-in, right?
Speaker 1: so if you are a restaurant and you want to go off of grubhub if you are a Nerd making art and you want to stop using Kickstarter.
Speaker 1: It's like you're not stuck with them at all.
Speaker 1: There is nothing technological Forcing you to stay with grubhub or to stay with Kickstarter.
Speaker 1: in fact They're platform gets we're selling your right or to keep selling your books on Amazon.
Speaker 1: If you're an author you could easily just no problem sell your book somewhere else sell your art somewhere else use a different crowdfunding platform.
Speaker 1: No technological lock-in whatsoever, but they have this audience and you look at your numbers and you say well My last project half the money came from Kickstarter Backers.
Speaker 1: if I go to some other platform Indiegogo game found whatever You know.
Speaker 1: just do a pre-order on itch.io or my own shopping site or whatever I'm like.
Speaker 1: how much of that 50% am I gonna lose?
Speaker 1: how right if I take my restaurant off of grubhub And I'm only listed on.
Speaker 1: you know seamless is grubhub So not there either.
Speaker 1: right on Chow now and my own website You know and my obviously my storefront itself physically, right How many customers are gonna order dinner somewhere else because they just go to grubhub and then search for food?
Speaker 1: Yeah, will that ruin my restaurant?
Speaker 1: am I therefore now stuck with grubhub even though for no technological reason?
Speaker 0: and the answer is often Yes, because honestly, uh, I have there's all.
Speaker 0: there's a barrier to entry there as well.
Speaker 0: if you don't use grubhub How are you going to accept online order?
Speaker 0: seamless is just as bad like they're basically the same except There's the same company.
Speaker 1: They're literally the same thing.
Speaker 0: They're weirdly still separate like website.
Speaker 1: Well, I think it's because there are some people.
Speaker 1: I think it's simply a branding thing.
Speaker 1: is that?
Speaker 1: yeah I think it's a hundred percent the same thing on the back end, but I think some people it's like You know custom on the customer side Are like I'll go to seem and they don't want to do a grubhub.
Speaker 1: is now seamless or a seamless is now grubhub?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll campaign right.
Speaker 1: They'd rather just.
Speaker 1: but there's also The same white label app with two at two things on it, right?
Speaker 0: What are you gonna use?
Speaker 0: Like there aren't that many other players in that space and even if there's a caviar chow now There's a play.
Speaker 0: But if you want to use one of those you're gonna be one of like the four Restaurants in your town on it and no one uses it.
Speaker 0: Yep, or the only way you can make your own direct order site and I've largely given up on that.
Speaker 0: I have really tried to not use grubhub for restaurants.
Speaker 0: Several restaurants in our neighborhood like even talk about has a direct order on their website didn't fucking work.
Speaker 0: I tried it twice.
Speaker 1: like Like couldn't replace has a on their site and integrated they have an order thing.
Speaker 1: That's not.
Speaker 1: it's not first party.
Speaker 1: It's like they're paying a third party for that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah there And I try to use that but the technology of it is so shitty.
Speaker 1: The rest right.
Speaker 1: the restaurant is like, yeah Sometimes if you use that one It doesn't print out and like properly on our side.
Speaker 1: and it's like, you know The grubhub one because it's so big and ubiquitous.
Speaker 1: Not only Does it bring in more customers for the restaurant but it works properly because it's got a huge engineering staff behind it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so but that huge engineering staff and that like even if they're not a monopoly There's plenty of competitors in the space.
Speaker 0: sort of it's moot because the cost to build something good enough To work as well as the user interface of grubhub already works Means you'll never make enough money to recoup that investment.
Speaker 1: Yep, but it's actually good, you know in New York City specifically They are you know, we have some laws coming in or already out that are like You know putting the hammer down on grubhub to make them force them to be less evil.
Speaker 1: so you can be less.
Speaker 0: Morally, I mean the right way to go in New York City the right way to go in New York City.
Speaker 0: That's exactly the kind of thing.
Speaker 0: I'd like to see a municipal public option for Yeah Imagine there's an end like food.
Speaker 0: that NYC literally was just a New York City grubhub equivalent that is sponsored by the by the city.
Speaker 1: The city hires a team of engineers to make it and then it.
Speaker 1: you know The restaurants pay.
Speaker 1: everyone pays for it through taxes.
Speaker 1: the restaurants don't to pay anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they don't.
Speaker 1: we only put restaurant or maybe the restaurant small amount.
Speaker 0: But it's fair and you treat that basically as part of the restaurant tax.
Speaker 0: you do it in a fair man.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of ways to go right tips.
Speaker 1: I'll go to the.
Speaker 0: you know, whatever public options are a way to Prevent certain kinds of lock-in on technology.
Speaker 0: But they baby look.
Speaker 0: the only place we see technology public options in any meaningful way right now.
Speaker 1: This is about municipal ISPs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like that's.
Speaker 0: that's the one area.
Speaker 0: and even then look at such a lot.
Speaker 0: That's a huge lock-in right where you know, you're exciting right now.
Speaker 0: There's actually there.
Speaker 0: It looks like there's some talk.
Speaker 0: Well, I have a.
Speaker 1: there was also some FCC talk.
Speaker 0: I think oh There's a talk of a right to choose your internet provider if you live in a large apartment building.
Speaker 1: Yep, they were.
Speaker 1: they'll say you can't.
Speaker 1: they're gonna get rid of these deals.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I as P's make with buildings to like, you know have unique access to the.
Speaker 0: weirdly my building didn't make a deal.
Speaker 0: I guess they made a deal with both Time Warner deal.
Speaker 0: Yeah We have FiOS and Comcast and something else.
Speaker 0: There's like three here.
Speaker 0: You can pick.
Speaker 1: we have files and RCN and obviously I guess you could hook up the phone line if you wanted to.
Speaker 1: But I guess Verizon just comes in with the FiOS.
Speaker 0: I unhook the phone lines and pushed him into the wall and replaced him with Ethernet.
Speaker 1: I assume that if I got if I asked for phone service, they would hook it up through the FiOS fiber, right?
Speaker 1: They wouldn't hook it up to the.
Speaker 0: I don't know what my phone options are cuz I never even asked.
Speaker 0: I can't imagine wanting a phone.
Speaker 1: I can get that I can get a triple play from Verizon.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I could do that.
Speaker 0: But I wonder if I could go to another local phone loop.
Speaker 0: I just don't know Why would anyone?
Speaker 0: but what's a landline?
Speaker 0: So yeah Anyway, so I think there's a bunch more More narrow topics we can talk about in this phase.
Speaker 0: This is like the intro to the space.
Speaker 0: lock-in is actually a really broad topic and you might see.
Speaker 0: if you have any thoughts on Lock-ins let us know in the forum because we could do an episode on a future Monday.
Speaker 1: come to any of the geek nights community places discord forum Twitter wherever and YouTube comments and Just tell us all the examples of lock-ins that we didn't think of.
Speaker 0: this has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night
Speaker 0: and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Heidi McNichol Alan Joyce, Link Iggi dread lily Tenerbrand a bunch of people who want me to say their names Chris the dog Chris Reimer Clinton Walton
Speaker 1: Dex
Speaker 0: Finn Kashi 85.
Speaker 0: Rebecca Dunn.
Speaker 0: review bed bull 34 cowards Sam Erickson Shervin Munhall Taylor Braun.
Speaker 0: The next station is st.
Speaker 0: Clair st.
Speaker 0: Clair station and several people whose patreon names I will not say.
Speaker 0: I Feel like if you're a geek nights fan you might have seen this one coming so I simply leave you with.
Speaker 1: It's October 31st 2005.
Speaker 1: This is geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Let's do this Leroy We should probably put leeroy in there whatever.
Speaker 1: Doo doo doo doo.
Speaker 1: Oh, I got you start the news like doo doo doo doo doo doo doo, but not the noise.
Speaker 1: Doo doo me going doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo.
Speaker 0: you want to do that originally?
Speaker 0: We're gonna have the So, uh, I guess we could do that or I could make that sound.
Speaker 1: I think this copyrighted or patented by whatever news.
Speaker 0: No, we'll just make it something else.
Speaker 0: It's just Morse code.
Speaker 0: We'll make it say something geeky.
Speaker 1: Let's do this in Morse code.
Speaker 0: That's real slick.
Speaker 0: I like it.
Speaker 1: All right, we're good.
Speaker 1: Okay, so Scalito Scalito.
Speaker 1: So, um Personal lawyer didn't cut it to no surprise.
Speaker 1: So he picks the most conservative judge he could find in all of the appeals course Samuel Alito Yeah.