Speaker 1: It's Wednesday, January 26th, 2022.
Speaker 1: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight we are talking about anime with music.
Speaker 1: Music from anime, OSTs, etc.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So,
Speaker 1: uh, there's something- there's been an attribute of this apartment that I never really thought to, like, say anything about or comment on, but today it was particularly strong to the point that now I wonder if this is a thing in other places in, like, New York City or in other apartment buildings or if it's just us.
Speaker 1: So, the water that comes out of our tap, if it- if we set it to cold, like, no hot water, just the raw, cold water, is so cold it is painful to wash your hands with.
Speaker 0: It is so cold that it is- Oh, now, yeah, this part of the year it is, yeah.
Speaker 1: But it's like that for most, basically, from the beginning of winter until the end of spring, it's that way in this building, and then in the summer it is cold but not painfully cold.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I'm curious what the water temperature is in different buildings, like, straight out of the tap.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, it's the same temperature because it's not- it doesn't have to do with your building.
Speaker 0: I mean, I guess you could have a situation in your building.
Speaker 1: No, because I've been in other apartments, like, even in Beacon where the water coming out of the tap was not significantly colder in the winter.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: Well, especially because I know where the- The water is cold from the reservoir, it's fucking freezing up in the Catskills, right?
Speaker 0: It goes through an underground aqueduct where it doesn't get any fucking warmer, right?
Speaker 0: And then it goes in pipes underground.
Speaker 0: The only way that you're going to get, you know, warmer, cold water this time of year in New York City is if your building, for some reason, has the pipes arranged in such a way that they go near something warm or something.
Speaker 1: Well, that's what I was getting at because- There's so much water, though, that, like- Or depending on if the building has its own water tower.
Speaker 1: A lot of buildings have, like, a mini water tower, even if it's not on the roof.
Speaker 0: Well, if you have a water tower, it's going to be cold again because it's sitting in the- on the roof in the freezing bucket, right?
Speaker 1: There are internal water towers.
Speaker 1: They're actually more common nowadays.
Speaker 0: If you have an internal water tower that has- but the amount of- even if you- if you have a water tower that's already moving, right?
Speaker 0: Your- the amount of energy it would take to warm the water even accidentally is so much because, you know, that amount of water moving or that's already that fucking cold, it's like it's not heating up unless you try, right?
Speaker 0: So you need the energy of the sun in the summer to make the cold water from the Catskills up in the mountain reservoir warm at any kind of scale.
Speaker 1: Yep, but buildings definitely have a big impact on that because I do remember when I worked at I worked in midtown for a while.
Speaker 1: I still work midtown now, technically, I guess, a few years ago.
Speaker 1: It's not like I'm going to the office right now, but the cold water coming out of those taps is consistently about the same temperature no matter what time of year it is.
Speaker 1: But I wonder if it's something about the office building.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of pipes.
Speaker 0: Something about the building because, I guarantee, if you go to the, you know, if you go to, like, the street and you go to one of those, like, water testing things- Oh yeah,
Speaker 1: those things are, like, the water that comes out of those drinking fountains, like, along the east side, that is ice, ice cold.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's going to be, in this time of year, it's going to be ice cold.
Speaker 0: So that's, you know, that's, it's not a problem.
Speaker 0: That's a feature.
Speaker 1: Oh, the colder the better.
Speaker 1: I want my hot tap to be dangerously hot and my cold tap to be painfully cold, like, just on the edge of freezing.
Speaker 0: That is a, that is one of the features that makes New York City tap water so great, is that the most of the year the cold water is really cold.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I, but I guess I'm betting in those old buildings in Midtown, a lot of water is hanging out inside the building because the taps don't get used as often in an office building compared to, like, an apartment building.
Speaker 0: That is another way that the water could warm up, is if simply, like- It's in the pipe just sitting there in the building for four hours.
Speaker 0: If you're in, if you, first thing in the morning, if you wake up before any of your neighbors you turn on the cold tap-
Speaker 1: because in the morning, whenever I take a shower, it is ice cold for, like, four minutes of running the water until hot water finally appears.
Speaker 0: Oh, until the hot water comes through.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the same will be true on the cold side, is that it'll be kind of lukewarm for, like, a little bit, and then the cold water from the supply will come in.
Speaker 1: So yeah, thanks to COVID, that's the most exciting thing I had to talk about in the last week.
Speaker 1: I had a moment, I was like, "Damn, the water's cold today.
Speaker 1: Ow!".
Speaker 0: I mean, I went, I went outside for the second time this year, you know, Dennis was the first time, I went to a hockey game no one else would go to, it was fine, I couldn't convince- even with an Instagram post, I could not convince anyone I knew.
Speaker 1: Oh, so, I think I- BlueShirtsNation, like, the fan account tweeted while you were at the game, near the end of the first period, "Hey, are you in New York?
Speaker 1: Wanna go to this game?
Speaker 1: Free ticket, text
Speaker 1: me.".
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I could not get- so, the person I eventually got to go with was, I went to the Rangers subreddit, and I got some kid from Jersey, right, some 20-something-year-old kid from Jersey.
Speaker 1: I mean, that subreddit's not the worst, like, I've seen worse.
Speaker 0: No, and he was not, you know, was he a person that I would hang out with?
Speaker 0: No, but was he a bad person?
Speaker 0: Also, no, just to- While she's listening, like,
Speaker 0: "Ah!"
Speaker 0: He was an okay person, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know a lot of okay people.
Speaker 1: Like, in some of our worlds, I would have rated her a solid four out of ten.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I think, you know, what I realized, though, is that if, you know, if you think about it, you're going to a- if you go to a public sporting event, especially a big professional sporting
Speaker 1: event- Oh, yeah, you have no idea who's gonna sit next to you in normal time.
Speaker 0: You have no idea.
Speaker 0: It's like, yeah, and it's like, unless you buy a whole luxury box or some shit, right, it's like, you are- someone in your group is sitting next to a total stranger.
Speaker 1: Well, there are places where that doesn't happen.
Speaker 0: If you have an expensive season ticket in certain parts- I said if you have a luxury box or something, yeah.
Speaker 1: If you are part of a non-super professional, like, college or something else where there's a cheering section that is regulars who always sit in the same place all the time- I already discounted your scenarios.
Speaker 0: Yeah, those are the only two possible scenarios.
Speaker 0: But the point is, you're already- you're sitting next to a stranger anyway, so what does it matter if you give one of your tickets to a stranger?
Speaker 0: It's like, it's not a dangerous situation.
Speaker 0: Well, no, it's not even that.
Speaker 1: It's not even your seat.
Speaker 1: It's just that seat is like what a seat would normally be.
Speaker 1: It's what every seat except the one you had a ticket for is normally going to have.
Speaker 0: Right, and it's like, as long as you contacted this person and gave them the ticket via some system that doesn't de-anonymize you so they know your address or some shit, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, okay, he knows my Venmo because he gave me money.
Speaker 0: It's like, okay, that's it.
Speaker 0: You can't find my house.
Speaker 0: It's like, there's no danger whatsoever.
Speaker 0: So it's actually, I think, a very good way if you want to meet people is to invite them to public sporting events.
Speaker 0: Even if you don't give a shit about the sporting event, you get the cheapest seat, whatever.
Speaker 0: It's like, oh, a total stranger that I want to meet?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, it's probably safer to meet you at the top of Citi Field in the cheap seats than it is to meet you at like a cafe or something, you know?
Speaker 1: Yep, you have a lot more escape avenues if that guy has in fact appeared.
Speaker 0: And there's security.
Speaker 0: there is the point, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's security that doesn't fuck around.
Speaker 0: What's he going to do, get thrown out of the stadium?
Speaker 1: Every time I've seen security react to something in a major, like in a professional sport area.
Speaker 0: Especially Madison Square Garden, which will be worse than, I guess, the other stadiums.
Speaker 1: Usually the security people have appeared and dealt with something before I was aware there was something to deal with.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Madison Square Garden, it's much, much tighter.
Speaker 1: Like you hear someone go, whoa, and you look and there's already four security people.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So yeah, if anyone is listening to this and you want to go to Madison Square Garden this year to see ice hockey, you should contact me.
Speaker 1: I feel like the time is coming soon or I'll start going again.
Speaker 0: Come on Friday.
Speaker 1: I'm really, really thinking about it.
Speaker 1: The numbers are just going down.
Speaker 1: Emily's giving me the thumbs up.
Speaker 1: She's like, come on.
Speaker 1: Emily was waffling.
Speaker 1: Well, I was waffling too on going to that other game that you went to.
Speaker 0: All right, Emily, Emily, come with me.
Speaker 1: Also, at least that game you went to, that was a fucking game.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, well, that was a team that was very close in skill level to our team, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, we're not, we're not the elite level of like, you know, Carolina and uh, uh, like a Colorado, but it was, it was captured by, we're on that second level of like the very good teams.
Speaker 0: And so is LA.
Speaker 0: They beat the shit out of us in LA, but you know, we, uh, it was keeping it close.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So anyway, I guess we'll get to some news.
Speaker 1: I got a little news, uh, can talk about a show that I doubt any of you have ever even heard of.
Speaker 1: I think I geeked by it at once because this show is from like 2008, 2007.
Speaker 0: I didn't finish watching it, but I did watch.
Speaker 0: I watched quite a handful of episodes when it, when I think that was a show that was so old.
Speaker 0: I was like downloading fan subs digitally on BitTorrent.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: I, in fact, I found on my, I probably still have those files on my NAS somewhere.
Speaker 1: The reason I stopped watching it is I didn't have a complete run of it and it was a pain to pirate.
Speaker 0: I also don't have a complete run.
Speaker 1: So, uh, Denno coil.
Speaker 0: I do have a complete run.
Speaker 0: Let me check while we're talking.
Speaker 1: Denno coil is now just on Netflix.
Speaker 1: You can just watch it.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's already on there.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: Oh no.
Speaker 1: So I'm a little premature and it will be on there at midnight tonight.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: I was, I thought it was that the news was like, it's coming soon.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Coming soon is midnight tonight.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess we have finally have a Wednesday show.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So, uh, ball says, cause I haven't one, I only saw like six episodes of this show and two, I saw them in like 2008, 2009.
Speaker 1: Like we were still in beacon, but Denno coil was super good from what I saw and much.
Speaker 0: I remember it being good at the time.
Speaker 1: And it's a, it's honestly, it's a serious sci-fi in that much like how ghost in the shell wall, the literal events happening in ghost in the shell are not like what is actually happening in cyberspace today.
Speaker 1: The topics that it addressed were eerily similar to how they were playing out today.
Speaker 1: Like it was pretty good.
Speaker 1: Sci-fi.
Speaker 0: Denno coil is also, oh no, I have fan subs of all 26 episodes in seven 20 P.
Speaker 1: Denno coil is basically exploring what kids today are entering into in terms of what the internet is like to them.
Speaker 0: Well today, meaning 2000 something 22.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Like when it came out, not now, so an anime from 2007 scarily accurately depicted a 15 year old anime, how young children will interact with the kind of internet that exists.
Speaker 1: And it was at least from what I saw up to the point, I stopped extremely prescient and very interesting.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I do have fan subs of the whole fucking 26 episodes.
Speaker 0: If that's how many episodes there are, which I assume is correct.
Speaker 0: So I'm going to give these are seven 20 P. I bet the Netflix is probably better.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I'm going to give this a watch cause.
Speaker 1: uh, I really wanted to finish this show and I just didn't cause it was kind of annoying to find it.
Speaker 0: Well, I got it somehow.
Speaker 0: So I guess that wasn't the problem.
Speaker 1: I all my files in this directory, clearly they're like from different fan subbers and different downloads.
Speaker 0: Mine are all from the same.
Speaker 0: I must've downloaded a torrent of every episode cause they're all the same, every name and everything.
Speaker 1: Um, so yeah, you got something I do.
Speaker 0: I don't have any news, but I got a geek bite.
Speaker 0: I read this manga that came out in English called Sigma Tara by, I hope I pronounced the name correctly.
Speaker 0: Minoru Minoru Furuya.
Speaker 0: Um, so Minoru Furuya is like a, I don't know a lot about this person, but it's, it's like when I saw the name on the comic order form, I'm like, that's the name of a famous mangaka that I know.
Speaker 0: it's the name of a famous mangaka, but I don't know what the hell they've done or who they are, but I know that name from somewhere.
Speaker 0: And I looked it up and they did, you know, the old ping pong club.
Speaker 0: That's how they got famous originally.
Speaker 0: So I was like, aha, at least I know something about you now, even though there's not that much information in English about your works and whatnot.
Speaker 0: But I think that I believe this is the first time any of Minoru's work has been published legally in English.
Speaker 0: Uh, so I think that's correct.
Speaker 0: So, uh, volume one came out from who the hell published it?
Speaker 0: Kodansha.
Speaker 0: Look how thick this fricking thing is.
Speaker 1: Oh, you got it.
Speaker 0: It's a big, it's a big one.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Uh, so I got around to reading it.
Speaker 0: And first of all, what I got to say is that Siguatera, if you don't know, is the name of a certain kind of poisoning you get from eating fish that has some kind of toxins in it from the water, the fish lived in.
Speaker 0: So I didn't know that until I Googled the name of the manga.
Speaker 0: Um, and what it's about is, you know, it's, it's a realistic story.
Speaker 0: Uh, and it's about, you know, teenage angst and drama, right?
Speaker 0: As a teenage kid in school, he's got a friend, they're nerds, they're nerds about motorcycles.
Speaker 0: There's a bully who bullies him, right?
Speaker 0: Uh, but he goes after school secretly to take motorcycle license class, right?
Speaker 0: He sees a hot girl there, but he doesn't know her or talk to her.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: You think it's all pretty typical, just one of those, right?
Speaker 0: Um, but it then after that very typical sort of high school set up, it's sort of a twist everything around, right?
Speaker 0: In a different direction, right?
Speaker 0: Someone that was bad is good.
Speaker 0: Someone that was good is bad actually talks to and dates the girl in a normal kind of way, right?
Speaker 0: Uh, it's very, um, realistic, I guess in terms of that, like I couldn't present me, could not identify with anything going on here, but teenage me could, right?
Speaker 0: This character has the same sort of, you know, teenage feelings that I had when I was 13, 14, right?
Speaker 1: I watched Scott Pilgrim again recently and yeah, there's, there's that kind of situation for sure, right?
Speaker 0: Now, you know, I think where it's going, uh, because there's more volumes, this isn't the whole thing.
Speaker 0: I think that there's going to be literal Siguatera because one of the bad characters, uh, be friends, some kind of fishermen and it's up to something.
Speaker 0: Uh, so I think someone is going to get poisoned with Siguatera, I think is the reason for the title of the, the comic and like the biohazard symbol appears.
Speaker 0: It's very tiny on the cover.
Speaker 0: It's dotting the I in Siguatera, but it appears in the book in various places as sort of Chekhov's biohazard symbol.
Speaker 1: It could be a spoiler to know that Siguatera is basically never fatal.
Speaker 1: That's good to know, but there is no known treatment antidote or cure.
Speaker 0: That's bad.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It primarily about Siguatera.
Speaker 0: I didn't even know it was a thing until I primarily causes diarrhea.
Speaker 0: That sucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Uh, and there's a whole Wikipedia article that I haven't, uh, read because I'm literally, you didn't know about it before right now.
Speaker 0: Did you?
Speaker 1: I'd heard of it, but I didn't.
Speaker 1: It's like, like it's one of those words for like, isn't that some kind of illness?
Speaker 0: I don't really, I ordered, I ordered this manga based on the author being a name that I had heard of.
Speaker 0: Um, and should I recommend you read it?
Speaker 0: Well, it's a well-crafted manga.
Speaker 0: Uh, if you want to identify with feelings of a, of a teenage boy who likes motorcycles, um, then yes, if you appreciate that it is such a finely crafted manga, then yes.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, man, maybe it's good, but it's not like some legendary work, you know, or anything like that.
Speaker 0: Um, you know, and of course, you know, there's a lot of, uh, uh, you know, horniness, right?
Speaker 0: Not like.
Speaker 0: it's not perverted, you know, or, or graphic or any, you know, moe kind of nonsense, nothing like that, but it's like, yeah, he's a 13 year old kid.
Speaker 0: He's going out with a hot girl, right?
Speaker 0: This is how he legitimately feels, right?
Speaker 0: And we're going to illustrate his true feelings, et cetera, right?
Speaker 1: So, but anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 1: So, uh, this is just a really tiny little thing, but, uh, there's a song by Caravan Palace, a band I like called Wonderland that has a fantastic animated music video.
Speaker 1: I'm not just making my thing of the day, an official music video.
Speaker 1: for many years ago, like that's, I feel like that ship sailed in terms of geek nights, things of the day.
Speaker 1: So someone took that song and that video and animated a different story to it, but in the same style of the original, uh, animated music video.
Speaker 1: And it's actually really, officially or unofficially, just some, just some fan.
Speaker 0: Did the band get mad or did the band say it was awesome?
Speaker 1: Uh, the band probably does not know what exists.
Speaker 1: It looks like it's part of a cluster of, so option three.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's basically in this, you know, there's clusters of like AMV people who all follow each other and make stuff and cross promote.
Speaker 1: There's like this cluster of animators who animate videos like this, but this one just, it, it echoed the style of the original video really well, but also told actually a pretty interesting story and it's pretty good.
Speaker 1: Like it's two minutes long.
Speaker 1: It's not that much shorter than like magnetic rows.
Speaker 1: It's worth watching little thing.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: That's all I got.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: Way back in the, I forget when I heard this, but I remember there was some videos watching where someone was in like the Beatles studio and they're playing back like the actual original recording from some Beatles song.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And they had the, you know, the giant studio mixing board.
Speaker 0: And so they were, had like the original recording of every single track.
Speaker 0: And they were like, let's just listen to this, you know, right.
Speaker 0: Cause you, you have only ever heard the final mixed and mastered version.
Speaker 0: You've never heard the original right parts.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And they, and even though, you know, that, you know, I was watching a video.
Speaker 0: So whatever sound was being heard in that studio was going into the microphone of some camera and then encoded into some press thing and then on YouTube or whatever.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like, it still sounded like incredible, like not what you heard ever in your life.
Speaker 0: Um, uh, but I always thought it's like, wow, that's amazing.
Speaker 0: I would love to hear that for like every song ever, but clearly that's something you have to like, you don't have access to right.
Speaker 0: That they're not putting those files out there.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: Those are those some, you can sometimes license those for extreme amounts of money.
Speaker 1: At best.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So, but I stumbled across this, uh, on YouTube, this guy's channel home studio simplified.
Speaker 0: I assume his chat, I didn't look at the other videos he has.
Speaker 0: I assume he's mostly talking about, you know, home recording studio setups, but in this video he somehow got from, and it is the top comment is, uh, I just clicked on that.
Speaker 0: just as you said, where are you getting these multi-tracks?
Speaker 0: answer some awesome people in our Facebook group.
Speaker 0: So someone got the multi-track recording to the staying alive by the Bee Gees, which is, I guess one of the, probably one of the a hundred best songs ever.
Speaker 1: Maybe that is, I feel like that would fit into the top hundred and I would be hard pressed to argue against it.
Speaker 1: I'd have to list.
Speaker 1: I would struggle to list a hundred songs better than that quickly.
Speaker 0: It's an S tier song, regardless of ranking.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: There might be more than a hundred S tier songs regardless.
Speaker 0: So he's got every track from that song from the original studio recording somehow, and he's not taken down from YouTube somehow.
Speaker 0: Um, yeah, so this guy, he opens it up and I think like cakewalk or whatever digital audio workstation is using.
Speaker 0: It's not one that I have, um, or I've seen before.
Speaker 0: And he, he listens to the whole thing and then he listens to each track individually.
Speaker 0: Some of the tracks are like left, right splits, and then he'll play the two tracks together.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Um, and he's just listening to, you know, piece by piece, like what's going on in this song.
Speaker 0: And it's like, it's like, I've heard the song again for the first time.
Speaker 0: It's, it's unbelievable.
Speaker 0: It's like, I think the old, the best metaphor would be like cookies are delicious.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But when you eat raw cookie dough, right.
Speaker 0: It's like, that's, that's like something else.
Speaker 0: Or when you see like comic artists and it's like, you have the finished comic book colored inked printed everything.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But then when you look at the original pencils for the same exact page, it's like, they're not finished, but there's actually something about them.
Speaker 0: That's like more powerful.
Speaker 0: that somehow like got lost in the, you know, in the rest of the production process.
Speaker 1: So not, not to harp on this, but as an aside, that's kind of what our canes animation feels like.
Speaker 1: It looks like you just took that and made it directly and skip that final step.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the, I especially want to draw attention to, right.
Speaker 0: So he listens to the, the original, you know, tracks of this song and, you know, mildly comments on them.
Speaker 0: But the part, you know, you should, this is worth all 37 minutes of your time to listen to the whole thing, but especially right at the 17, he's got YouTube chapters.
Speaker 0: So you're all good at like the 17 and half minute mark.
Speaker 1: Oh, that is literally what I just listened to.
Speaker 1: That's as far as I got.
Speaker 0: There's an acoustic guitar track that I've never heard before in my life.
Speaker 0: It must be so either not existent in the final recording or so turned down in the final recording.
Speaker 0: You can't hear it, but it's like, this is a disco song about as dancy and disco as you can get, right.
Speaker 0: It's literally from the OST of Saturday night fever, that title song that's.
Speaker 0: it was made for that purpose.
Speaker 0: And yet, if you listen to this track, it's clearly the same song, but it sounds like it's some fucking Western track for like a cowboy movie or some shit.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's just unbelievable.
Speaker 0: And the person playing the guitar, even though they're just playing like this steady rhythm, right.
Speaker 0: Their rhythm is like uncannily steady, right.
Speaker 0: It's like, what the hell, who the hell is playing that guitar?
Speaker 0: Also of note, there are some of the strings tracks or like some of the synth string tracks, right.
Speaker 0: They sound like they're from, you know, like, like the, like from old movies, like they don't sound like they're, it's like when you hear them in the song at, you know, as a whole, they make sense, you know, cause disco songs commonly have, you know, strings going on.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But on their own, they sound like, you know, dramatic notes from some melodrama or something.
Speaker 1: Well, that could, that could either be cause it was sampled or it could be because they just like, I don't think it was an accent.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But the, uh, there's also like when you listen to them on their own, there are like these subtleties to the, to the strings that don't come across because there's too much harmonization in the final track, uh, at that are really quite unbelievable, but it's just like, uh, yeah, this is really something, uh, I bet this guy probably other has videos of other raw tracks.
Speaker 1: It feels like this is one of his things.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So raw track reaction, I'm getting into it.
Speaker 0: And, uh, I don't know how it could get better than this.
Speaker 0: What else does he get a raw track?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Cause it won't be nearly as exciting for a small band or like a lot of pop in that.
Speaker 0: I got to see if he's got a queen.
Speaker 0: Any queen song is going to be.
Speaker 0: I am.
Speaker 1: I'm going to Google right now.
Speaker 1: I am, before we get it, I am confident there are queen multi-tracks out there.
Speaker 0: Probably.
Speaker 1: Uh, now I have to go tracks.
Speaker 0: There goes my evening.
Speaker 1: So anyway, in the meta moment, the geek nice book club book, which Scott has finished, uh, and I have, I've reached Genji's demise and beyond.
Speaker 1: We will be doing a show on this.
Speaker 0: You got, you got, you got seven days.
Speaker 1: Hey, one of those chapters was in fact very quick to read.
Speaker 0: It's super quick.
Speaker 0: I read the remainder of that book, I think in less than a week.
Speaker 1: It was a fast read when I was motivated.
Speaker 1: Also, it gets easier to read as it goes on.
Speaker 0: It's not just after the very, after the very short chapter.
Speaker 0: reading is much easier because less happens and the words are more, uh, easier at least the English words.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Otherwise we got no cons coming up for a while.
Speaker 1: We're working on a bunch of stuff, working on the new website.
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Uh, we do live stream the show.
Speaker 1: If you didn't know that on my YouTube channel at geek nights rim, we've been doing this for a long time.
Speaker 1: I say it because you could have seen if you're watching a live stream that I was reading the Wikipedia article on the Sigma Terra disease as we were doing the show.
Speaker 1: That's how we sound like we know stuff.
Speaker 1: We both just have Wikipedia and YouTube in front of us all the time.
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Otherwise I guess we just get right into the main bit.
Speaker 1: I got nothing else right now.
Speaker 0: I got, I know it's the slow time.
Speaker 1: So, uh, anime music.
Speaker 1: Now I realized we hadn't done a show on this and we both haven't read or watched the same things in a little while.
Speaker 1: We'll rectify that soon.
Speaker 1: So we were looking for a topic and I realized the only shows we've ever done about anime music were around openings and endings, not like the soundtracks or scores to anime directly.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 1: And, uh, I did just watch a little bit of Initial D recently for unrelated reasons, which stirred a fire in my soul.
Speaker 1: So it seemed like a decent topic.
Speaker 1: I feel like we might have a lot to say about this.
Speaker 1: Uh, I spent much of my adult life listening heavily to just anime OSTs specifically, especially high school.
Speaker 0: Well, I do think that is one thing that OSTs for, you're talking about animated television, not movies.
Speaker 1: I guess we'll have to clarify a little bit.
Speaker 1: We'll constrain the show a little bit, uh, moment, just so we can get squeezed more shows at it.
Speaker 0: But, uh, if you think, you know, in the United States, at least Hollywood, right.
Speaker 0: And, you know, TV movie productions, movies basically always have soundtracks.
Speaker 0: Sometimes they might be original scores.
Speaker 0: Sometimes they might just be, you know, new recordings of classical songs, old movies do that.
Speaker 0: Or sometimes they'll just be licensed pop songs, but you know, like, uh, or sometimes a combination thereof, but, uh, movies typically have OSTs.
Speaker 0: It's hard to have a movie without a soundtrack, right?
Speaker 0: TV shows in the United States rarely have a soundtrack, especially not an original score or name a song from a Seinfeld.
Speaker 1: There's the song.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: That's it has one.
Speaker 0: There's one song, right?
Speaker 0: And a couple intro, outro riffs and a laugh track.
Speaker 0: It's like, there's no OST, even if you have a serious drama show in the United States, right?
Speaker 0: Think, um, you know, some of the mission impossible has got one song, right?
Speaker 1: It's got a few adjacent Zimmer-esque, but then we're getting into soundtrack versus score, which is a whole other conversation too.
Speaker 0: Well, score is just a type of soundtrack, which is, you know, an original composition for the show, as opposed to already existing songs being collected into a soundtrack.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: That's like a movie could have a soundtrack and a score, et cetera.
Speaker 0: But, uh, I feel like the soundtrack is basically, I, so I guess, I don't know what the official definitions are, but my definitions that I've always gone by is that the soundtrack for a movie or show is all of the songs total, right.
Speaker 0: That are played during, right.
Speaker 0: Included in the audio of the movie or show.
Speaker 0: So like you could have, you know, a lot of animes had like character albums and shit of like tracks that didn't actually play during the show.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So those don't count.
Speaker 0: It's gotta be like, I'm watching mission impossible.
Speaker 0: I'm watching a James Bond movie.
Speaker 0: And during the movie, it goes doo, doo, doo, doo.
Speaker 0: That song is part of the soundtrack of the thing.
Speaker 0: It's the, a score would be okay.
Speaker 0: They stay specifically composed.
Speaker 0: this collection of songs for this movie or TV show.
Speaker 0: The score of Seinfeld is one is one song, right?
Speaker 0: It's right.
Speaker 0: It has an original score.
Speaker 0: It's only one song long.
Speaker 1: And a big part, a big part of that in terms of like just the viewership and the enjoyment of these things is imagine like an anime.
Speaker 1: We're talking about anime today where there's a song that clearly was made for the show and the scene was animated to match the song directly.
Speaker 1: The song was not just like laid behind and edited together scene.
Speaker 1: The song and the scene were conceived together.
Speaker 0: Well, that usually happens the most in musicals, right.
Speaker 0: Where the characters are singing the song that is part of the soundtrack.
Speaker 0: But you think something like, I don't know, Independence Day just has a score whereas something like The Matrix or Star Wars obviously has a score as its total soundtrack, but The Matrix has a score, but it also has Rage Against the Machine, right?
Speaker 0: So it's not, it's a, the soundtrack includes the original score, but also includes already existing songs from the world.
Speaker 1: So I think for this show, we're going to exclude movies because anime movies are just cheat mode.
Speaker 1: Like the best music in all of anime is just a list of anime movies for the most part.
Speaker 0: Well, the point, the fundamental point is that unlike American TV, right, Japanese animation typically has a score or at least a soundtrack to it, but quite often its own original score that you don't get.
Speaker 1: Like Sailor Moon has like nine OSTs, I want to say.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like, what's the, what's the soundtrack for fucking, I don't know, an American animation TV show, you know, name a song from Transformers.
Speaker 0: There's one.
Speaker 0: Well, Transformers, the movie has songs, but that's a collected, right?
Speaker 0: You got Dexter's Lab, I guess has a song, the theme song.
Speaker 1: I guess like, so that's like in high school and college, like I'd listened to the soundtrack to Slayers, which is just a TV show.
Speaker 1: I would just listen to that in my car while I was driving.
Speaker 1: I would not listen to the background music from Deep Space Nine in my car while I was driving anywhere.
Speaker 0: There's no such thing.
Speaker 0: It's like, yeah, it's like for anime, you go to the, if you go to a, you know, uh, a nerdy anime store, anime OSTs are a thing.
Speaker 0: Why aren't OSTs a thing in the United States?
Speaker 0: Cause things don't have an ST.
Speaker 1: They increasingly are for newer works, just like games increasingly have them.
Speaker 1: But if you look at American pop culture from like infinity up until maybe the two thousands, a lot of shows had nothing.
Speaker 0: Even if they wanted to sell a soundtrack for Powerpuff girls, the TV show, it would be like two saw one song on a CD, a single.
Speaker 0: it's like, you know, I think the only soundtracks I saw for cartoons and stuff when I was a kid from the U S were like, you know, uh, like cartoon planet, space ghost, like bad bug and what are the other tracks on there?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But now like people buy the Game of Thrones soundtrack.
Speaker 1: Every video game that has original music sells that as an album.
Speaker 0: Like it's a very different time in the U S but there's more video game soundtracks than animation soundtracks in the U S.
Speaker 1: But I guess if you were an American anime fan, who's about our age, you would never experience that really until you found anime.
Speaker 1: And then you were like, wait, why is there this $40 CD for slayers?
Speaker 1: I guess slayers has a good music and there's just all this music.
Speaker 1: That's great.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, a lot, when I was still buying cassettes, CDs, a good percentage of them were soundtracks to the few things that had them.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: I had a lot of CDs that were just the soundtrack to Indiana Jones, the soundtrack to star Wars.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: Those are, those are real good, by the way, if you listen, I highly recommend, uh, empire strikes back OST, it's probably on Spotify, but you'll hear a lot of stuff in there that you don't hear in the movie.
Speaker 0: Not because it wasn't in the movie, but because you know, someone's talking or there's an X-wing exploding or something.
Speaker 1: Um, so in terms of anime in particular, that's sort of why anime music looms large in the American anime fan community, because this was something that we've just generally hadn't experienced from television shows in our lives up to that point.
Speaker 1: And also the novelty of it was music that was not available and on the radio either.
Speaker 1: It was almost this perfect storm of getting me obsessed with like Megumi Hayashibara.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I'm watching this show.
Speaker 0: The show has a score, like a fucking movie does.
Speaker 0: The quality of it is unbelievable.
Speaker 0: The genre of it is one that often I haven't heard before, sometimes depending on the show.
Speaker 0: Uh, it's really catchy and I want to listen to it more.
Speaker 0: And look, I was able to find, it's hard to get, but because we have internet powers and eventually globalization powers, we're finally able to get it and listen to it all we want.
Speaker 0: Oh my God, this is amazing.
Speaker 1: So in 2007, we did an episode on anime openers and closers, and I actually bring that up because one, I'll link to it, but two, kind of make a point.
Speaker 1: I think if we want to talk about like, what is a good OST, like a good anime soundtrack or song?
Speaker 1: The concept of a good soundtrack for a show could be very different in terms of, is it good because it had a really good opener, but did the, or did the show use the music?
Speaker 1: Was the music an integral part of the show?
Speaker 1: Do you remember any music from the show other than the opener or closer?
Speaker 0: That's, I think that's usually my criteria.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So as much as Kill La Kill has that song, Kill La Kill didn't have particularly memorable music other than that song and the power of its opener and closer to me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I probably, if you played, if you played it, I'd probably be like, oh, that's familiar.
Speaker 0: What's that from?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But if you play don't lose your way, I'm like, yeah, there it is.
Speaker 0: Don't lose your way.
Speaker 0: I know what that is.
Speaker 1: Same thing.
Speaker 1: A lot of people talk about Attack on Titan's music.
Speaker 1: Attack on Titan also has basically one song.
Speaker 0: that the first, I only remember the first opener.
Speaker 0: I can't remember anything else.
Speaker 0: Same.
Speaker 1: So, uh, I dunno, I guess we can go back and forth and just call out in our, our minds, the best anime soundtracks on those criteria of they're actually good in the show.
Speaker 0: Not just, I don't know if there's that many that I could think of.
Speaker 1: I spent about 10 minutes.
Speaker 1: I came up with about 10.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So I could think of ones that are memorable or like, you know, that I list that I listened to intentionally, right?
Speaker 0: When I wasn't watching the show.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 0: Like do I have an MP3 folder from that show in my, once I have an MP3 folder for, or that I have like on a playlist on Spotify or something.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So, uh, the first one, I guess the Macross TV show soundtrack, which has, right.
Speaker 0: It's full of city pop ish tracks.
Speaker 0: Those old school steel guitar while planes are flying.
Speaker 1: This is why it's tough.
Speaker 1: I thought of 10 and I did not think of all the, the min-may musical tracks.
Speaker 1: I didn't think of Macross at all.
Speaker 1: And as soon as you said it, my brain immediately remembered all the music from that show.
Speaker 0: Macross is about music.
Speaker 0: Even Macross seven, literally about music.
Speaker 1: Macross seven didn't have as good a music as the TV show.
Speaker 0: But it mean, but all Macross is literally about music.
Speaker 0: So, uh, that it would, it would be kind of bad if it didn't have a soundtrack.
Speaker 1: Well, it's just classical music pieces, I guess, but I don't think it counts because the actual, anything that was original in the show, wasn't that great.
Speaker 1: And the music that they used in the show, isn't that deep.
Speaker 1: Like I'm not listening to the Nodame soundtrack.
Speaker 1: I'm listening to Rachmaninoff's album, I guess.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I guess the lowest tangy fruit in the universe is Cowboy Bebop, right?
Speaker 1: I mean, Cowboy Bebop and Eska Flonay are the two that I actually put at the top of my list.
Speaker 0: I thought Utenna would be at the top of my list.
Speaker 1: Utenna and Giant Robo are tied at number three in my list.
Speaker 0: Number three?
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: I don't, I don't see the hype for the Giant Robo.
Speaker 0: Giant Robo, I think, I can't even remember the opening song for Giant Robo.
Speaker 1: I can remember it.
Speaker 1: Giant Robo, I think has one of the best constructed original orchestral soundtracks of scores to any anime show ever.
Speaker 0: It definitely has an original orchestral soundtrack.
Speaker 0: I couldn't recognize a single damn song from it and I watched the whole show.
Speaker 1: I remember them all intimately because every character has a leitmotif in the entire show.
Speaker 1: Every score element, the show is scored beginning to end and the leitmotifs interleave with each other through the show, depending on who's on screen or who's important.
Speaker 1: I think it's one of the most iconic anime television show soundtracks of all time.
Speaker 1: I will stand by that to my death.
Speaker 0: However, I can't, I can't remember one damn song from it.
Speaker 1: However, Cowboy Vivaf and Eska Flonay in particular, partly because of the Yokohakano factor, have such sprawling scores, such sprawling soundtracks, the breadth of genres.
Speaker 0: Even, you know, Giant Robo doesn't have that many episodes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but also Giant Robo does one thing.
Speaker 1: It is like an opera.
Speaker 1: It is just opera songs after opera songs.
Speaker 1: There's no like radically different genre in there.
Speaker 1: The Giant Robo soundtrack goes from beginning to end, but Eska Flonay goes from opera to weird pop songs to ridiculous nonsense and Cowboy Vivaf goes even further.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I mean, that's, that's the real challenge, right?
Speaker 0: It's one thing to be like Star Wars, where you have, you know, a certain set of, you know, motifs and themes that you keep remixing and combining and rehashing and, you know, over and over right into different tracks.
Speaker 0: It's another thing completely to have 26 episodes of a show or even just 13.
Speaker 0: And not, and you've got different music on each episode, but also the same music.
Speaker 0: But even though you've got a song you're using like once in episode seven or some shit, right?
Speaker 0: It's still fucking legendary and phenomenal.
Speaker 0: And then you just never go back to it again.
Speaker 0: It's like, yeah, I got another one.
Speaker 0: I don't need to use that one again.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Even John Williams needs to go back and use that one again.
Speaker 0: Yoko Kanno doesn't.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that's it.
Speaker 1: So Eska Flonay is 26 episodes and has more OSTs than I remember.
Speaker 0: Like there's so much music, but then- You know how many CDs there are?
Speaker 0: There's like Cowboy Vivaf box sets just for 26 episodes of show.
Speaker 0: They got fucking CD box sets for that thing.
Speaker 1: But meanwhile, another 26 episode show from that era that didn't have the Yoko Kanno factor has one CD with like seven songs on it.
Speaker 1: Same number of episodes.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: I think so.
Speaker 1: Utena stands out in that to this day, I have never encountered an anime or really anything that has music like J.H.
Speaker 1: Azar's music.
Speaker 0: I mean, the dude has made other non-Utena music and it all sounds like that.
Speaker 0: But yeah, is he a unique composer in that there's.
Speaker 0: a lot of musicians in general will get or criticized for having like one note, like all their stuff sounds the same.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But as long as your stuff doesn't sound like anyone else's stuff, what's wrong with knowing your sound, it being a good sound and sticking to it, right?
Speaker 0: I don't see anything wrong with that.
Speaker 0: You might get played out eventually, like people get tired of you, but you know, look at like Eurobeat guy Dave Rogers.
Speaker 0: He's just.
Speaker 0: he is what he is.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: He's happy with it.
Speaker 0: He sticks to it.
Speaker 0: He's like, this is who I am.
Speaker 0: I'm Eurobeat guy, Dave Rogers.
Speaker 0: I make Eurobeat.
Speaker 0: I love it.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So J.H.
Speaker 0: Azar is like.
Speaker 0: that is like I make this music.
Speaker 0: It doesn't sound like anyone else's music.
Speaker 0: It's it sounds like I made it.
Speaker 0: No one else sounds like it.
Speaker 0: I stick to it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: And I only applied it to one thing, which is Utena.
Speaker 0: And therefore Utena doesn't sound like anything else either.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And like I listen to the Utena soundtrack just kind of randomly throughout my life, like a few weeks ago, I was just listening to it because it's good.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And, you know, Utena has also the structural element of the dual song.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Which is not a lot of shows have that.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: But then the dual songs are that show.
Speaker 1: The rest of the show is other styles.
Speaker 0: It's a lot like how Initial D has the Eurobeat song for the race.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So Initial D is like next down on my list.
Speaker 0: It's not a score, though.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: But in that, I guess it's a it's a it.
Speaker 0: those all those tracks existed on superhero beat CDs.
Speaker 1: I was thinking about what did the music do for the show in that case, in that Initial D saved it from being complete garbage.
Speaker 1: Initial D with any other music or no music.
Speaker 1: I would never have watched that show.
Speaker 1: I would have peaced out halfway through the first episode.
Speaker 1: Never.
Speaker 1: But the Eurobeat, much like Ewan M1 in Doom 1, just pumps you up like it drives the show just like the show has it in it.
Speaker 1: Similarly, the Giant Robo.
Speaker 1: Well, as beautifully animated as it is, the music drives that mood.
Speaker 1: Escaflowne, like the epic scale of that fantasy is really enhanced by the epic scale and grandeur of the music.
Speaker 1: So shows like Slayers, the music is great.
Speaker 1: Like I love all those openers and closers, but it doesn't really do anything for the show itself.
Speaker 1: The sound, the music that just happens in the course of the show, pretty forgettable, to be honest.
Speaker 1: The Megumi Hashibara stuff is mostly openers and closers or like big dramatic moments.
Speaker 0: It's interesting how some, I guess, you know, low rent off the shelf Eurobeat music can elevate Initial D from trash to something special, at least I'll say something special.
Speaker 1: Yes, you didn't say good.
Speaker 1: I agree with you said special.
Speaker 1: That's important.
Speaker 0: Something special.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But meanwhile, the quite prolific Yugi Kaedra.
Speaker 1: That's next on my list.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Yugi Kaedra has made soundtracks.
Speaker 0: We have the same taste in anime music, except for an enormous amount of anime and continues to do so.
Speaker 0: Even like Demon Slayer and stuff, right, is Yuki Kaedra.
Speaker 0: You know, Kimigori, Orange Road was Yuki Kaedra.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But and it all sounds much like Jay Cesar, Yuki Kaedra soundtracks.
Speaker 0: You can tell right away who did it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just immediately obvious.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But even though that music is often incredible, it doesn't seem to have the power to elevate a poop show to anything more than what the show is.
Speaker 0: We've done this on gig nights.
Speaker 1: It tricked us in that it would get us to watch a show that wasn't good.
Speaker 1: But once the magic wore off, like at the end of Noir or halfway through Hack Sign, the spell broke.
Speaker 1: And I was like, wait a minute, only the music's good.
Speaker 1: The music tricked me.
Speaker 0: But it's like Sword Art Online.
Speaker 0: Probably, you know, you go to go to Spotify, find the Sword Art Online OST.
Speaker 0: It's even on there.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like it's going to.
Speaker 0: I've never listened to it, but I'm willing to bet that it's an amazing Yuki Kaedra soundtrack.
Speaker 0: But I also know for a fact Sword Art Online is not good.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: And the soundtrack, for some reason, her music doesn't have that.
Speaker 0: Even though it's amazing, there's something about it.
Speaker 0: It cannot bring the show up at all.
Speaker 0: But it got real.
Speaker 1: do real close.
Speaker 1: Well, partly it was that Initial D did have something going on.
Speaker 1: It's got that scene where he washes the car.
Speaker 0: That like there is.
Speaker 1: however small that emotional arc is, it's there.
Speaker 1: But with Hack Sign and Noir, I guess the difference is.
Speaker 1: when I got to the end of Initial D, I didn't think back and say, wow, fuck that.
Speaker 1: Only the Eurobeat was good.
Speaker 1: I thought, I like that show.
Speaker 1: OK.
Speaker 1: When I got to the end of Noir, I thought, wow, I got fucking tricked and that was a waste of my time.
Speaker 1: I should have just listened to this OST.
Speaker 1: I am angry that I watched this show.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I think what I guess the food analogy would be that like, you know, other music might act as like a fancy spice that like saffron or some shit.
Speaker 0: Where it's like you put some saffron on some bland food or you really make it magical.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But Yuki Kaedra's music is just salt.
Speaker 0: So salt can make, you know, food taste better.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: It can trick you into thinking that not great food is good.
Speaker 0: But bad food with salt is just salty bad food.
Speaker 0: But when you put that salt on a good show, right, like, you know, Madoka Magica or something, it's like, oh, yeah, it needed that salt.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: To make it, you know, Madoka Magica would be a worse show without that music.
Speaker 0: You know, but you couldn't save a bad show with it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: There you go.
Speaker 0: So similarly, yeah, she she has done a lot of a lot of stuff.
Speaker 1: Evangelion, I think, had a fantastic soundtrack in that it's.
Speaker 1: it's as close to background music from an anime that would otherwise be incidental that I will occasionally listen to on purpose for no reason.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The thing with the Evangelion soundtrack is it's there are other songs to it.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But it's really thinking of that one song.
Speaker 1: Doo doo doo doo doo doo.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's called which is not that far off from the some of the doom music that also pumps me up in similar ways.
Speaker 0: Doo doo doo.
Speaker 1: The timpani.
Speaker 0: The song.
Speaker 0: The song is called Decisive Battle.
Speaker 1: That's the one.
Speaker 0: But it's got a bunch of different versions, I guess, of it or I don't know, renditions, whatever you want to call it.
Speaker 1: Often a song like that.
Speaker 1: The way to think like Giant Robo does this is.
Speaker 1: it's a theme that is used in different songs along the way, possibly in different ways.
Speaker 0: It's not the only song from the Evangelion score that besides the opener and closer that stands out.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: There's the.
Speaker 0: there's the hanging out at home one.
Speaker 1: Doo doo doo doo doo.
Speaker 1: But that's why I put Ava much lower on my list.
Speaker 1: That music was extremely integral to the mood of Evangelion, but it was not a great OST by itself.
Speaker 1: Like it was the case where it was a necessary component of Evangelion.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it has a few songs that really stand out and are used to great effect for mood setting and are very memorable and perhaps even listenable on their own.
Speaker 0: But there's not a lot of them that aren't openers and closers.
Speaker 0: It's like the same couple ones used over and over again.
Speaker 0: And in fact, I guess Anno is, you know, is I don't know if it's Shin Godzilla.
Speaker 0: He's using the same decisive battle song again.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: it's like you can't find another song to use.
Speaker 0: You just keep using the same palette of colors of musical colors and all his his works there.
Speaker 0: You know, it's sort of like, all right, I love that song, too.
Speaker 0: It gets me pumped.
Speaker 1: But yeah, but like I won't just sit and listen to the entire Ava OST in an evening, like while I'm working on something necessarily.
Speaker 1: But I will absolutely do that with Escaflowne in a heartbeat.
Speaker 1: And now I'm already getting near the bottom.
Speaker 1: Like I'm starting running out of shows fast.
Speaker 1: Like now I'm at the level of like Gundam Seed, which it worked.
Speaker 1: Like those the songs from the pivotal moments of that show are still burned into my brain, like when the mass driver takes off.
Speaker 1: But outside of those scenes, I forget pretty much any background music from that show at all.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Well, I think that this goes to a problem.
Speaker 0: The problem I'm betting I'm leading towards is a problem with us, because that's an easier explanation.
Speaker 0: But there is an alternate explanation, which is like, OK, most of these shows we mentioned are like hella old, right?
Speaker 0: That's because we're hella old and we watched a lot of these old anime and we didn't watch as many newer anime.
Speaker 0: So therefore, we're not familiar with the newer shows or we don't like them or we didn't hear their soundtracks to point them out as being good.
Speaker 0: But it could also just be that, you know, newer shows are less often having, you know, because it's not like.
Speaker 0: I haven't watched any new anime.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like, what's the newest?
Speaker 0: You know, I've watched some newer shows.
Speaker 1: Well, but more to the point, I've been watching a lot of non anime animation and other TV shows and their scores better than half the stuff on my list just now.
Speaker 1: Like I'm listening to them directly.
Speaker 1: Like I listen to the Centaur World soundtrack a bunch.
Speaker 1: The Arkane soundtrack is fantastic.
Speaker 1: Like there there are recent shows where I have really enjoyed the OSTs and I would put them on this list, except they're not anime.
Speaker 0: But I'm talking like, you know, there are anime specifically.
Speaker 1: The other thing is I can pick out like Beastars, the first and second, especially the second.
Speaker 0: Beastars does not have an OST.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But the openers, what's the other beast one that are fantastic?
Speaker 1: BNA.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: BNA doesn't really have.
Speaker 1: BNA has a rockin' opener.
Speaker 1: This is the problem.
Speaker 1: A lot of the anime.
Speaker 1: I like the music from that's more recent, the openers and closers might be A plus or even S tier standout songs.
Speaker 0: But then the music artist anime that one doesn't really have.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The music in the show is just not at the level of like a cowboy bebop.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You know, of the I've seen more recent anime TV shows.
Speaker 0: I have watched some.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, the lead.
Speaker 0: There just isn't anything about their their soundtracks and scores.
Speaker 0: that's during the show that sticks with me or makes me want to go get the OST or add it to a playlist or anything like that.
Speaker 0: It's been a long time since an anime TV show did that.
Speaker 0: But movies do that very frequently.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That's how movies roll.
Speaker 1: Generally, the way I roll is I'll see a movie and if it had a good score, I'm probably listening to the score like off and on, semi on loop for about a week, like right after I watch the movie.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: That's that's how movies do.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I think we did a show there and we left room to talk about this topic and other areas in the future.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Very important.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion, news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of Geek Nights are Heidi McNichol, Alan Joyce, Link Eiji, Drew, Lily Tenebrae, and a bunch of people who really don't want me to say their names.
Speaker 1: Chris Adade, Chris Reimer, Clinton Walton, Dex, Finn, Kishiai85, Rebecca Dunn, Revue, Madball34, Cowards, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Horl, Taylor Braun.
Speaker 1: The next station is Lawrence, Lawrence Station, and several people whose Patreon names I will not say.
Speaker 1: So yeah, not a lot going on right now.
Speaker 1: Things are slowly opening up.
Speaker 1: New York might get a big blizzard.
Speaker 1: Hopefully it's not big enough to lose internet so we can do a show like normal on Tuesday.
Speaker 1: I assume it'll be fine.
Speaker 1: But we're very likely done with The Tale of Genji, so Thursday next week you're going to see that first show.
Speaker 1: And for now, I leave you with...
Speaker 0: Drop, drop, purple drop.
Speaker 0: Where's this elevator going?
Speaker 0: To the top.
Speaker 0: Everybody come aboard for the gerbil drop.
Speaker 1: What's a gerbil drop?
Speaker 0: I'll show you at the town.
Speaker 0: Drop, drop, gerbil drop.
Speaker 0: So say you got a friend who's frozen in the ice.
Speaker 0: Don't leave him in the ice.
Speaker 0: Do something nice.
Speaker 1: Use his ripple neck to take him to the top.
Speaker 1: We'll see you at the bottom of the gerbil drop.