Speaker 0: It's Tuesday, March 1st, 2022.
Speaker 0: I'm Rym.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight we are talking about Offworld Trading Company.
Speaker 0: A Stardock game from 2016.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Oh, we got a sudden, a sudden news.
Speaker 1: Uh oh.
Speaker 1: They, uh, they signed the Bender guy for the Futurama show so that the Bendergate is over.
Speaker 0: Pikachu face.
Speaker 0: Like, I didn't expect that to happen.
Speaker 0: It was really clear that there were, like, ongoing negotiations that were not public as part of that conversation.
Speaker 1: He's just trying to get paid and he deserves it because, uh, you know, people wouldn't be...
Speaker 0: He's the voice of, it was, he's the voice of Jake and Bender.
Speaker 0: And he did it so well that when I saw Futurama, I thought, that is the voice of Bender and nothing could ever change that for the rest of my life.
Speaker 0: And then I saw Adventure Time and for half of the first episode, I thought, that's just Jake's voice, or that's just Bender's voice.
Speaker 0: And then it became Jake's voice permanently, instantly, and it was over.
Speaker 1: He's got a really good voice, uh, you know.
Speaker 0: Just talking.
Speaker 0: Brad, I was worried as soon as you said, uh oh, breaking news because most breaking news in the last five days has not been great news.
Speaker 1: That news is not for the shows, you know, that's for other things.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: So, uh, of course, we're not gonna cover it as news on Geek Nights, especially not today on a Tuesday, because you should not be coming to us for news about the Russian invasion of Ukraine.
Speaker 0: This is uncharted territory, this is the largest land war in Europe since World War II.
Speaker 1: I mean, there have been instances of invasions, uh, during, well, Geek Nights existed.
Speaker 0: But never on this scale, with this level of escalation, it basically, within 24 hours of it starting, which was, weirdly, I remember we finished the bell show.
Speaker 1: It was, yeah, all the previous invasions, at least, I mean, there were other ones, but, you know, the ones that make the news in the United States, at least, right?
Speaker 1: So, uh, were always us, uh, just, you know, being imperialist and invading people for oil or other nonsense reasons.
Speaker 0: Yup, I mean, uh, we, as a nation, invaded Iraq for literally no reason, not that long ago.
Speaker 1: That's pretty much, you know, most of the wars that I've experienced in my life were of that variety.
Speaker 0: But, uh, I think what's interesting, and then we'll move on, because, again, go to experts to read about this, like, it is moving very rapidly.
Speaker 0: Anything that you hear us even say is probably out of date by the time you listen to this.
Speaker 0: Uh, but I guess it is very interesting to me that, one- Imagine how out of date they were in the newsreel times, right?
Speaker 1: Watching Newsreel, it's like something that happened a month ago.
Speaker 0: It's such a, it's a weird disconnect, like, you know, I was at work and, you know, I had a meeting and, uh, someone, like, the call starts, and someone just says, "Is there any news from the
Speaker 0: front?".
Speaker 0: And that was a perfectly legitimate question that I did not expect to hear in my daily life, like, with a person I was talking to in the year 2022.
Speaker 1: I think only an old person would phrase it that way, though.
Speaker 0: Uh, this was an older person, but not that old.
Speaker 0: Not that old.
Speaker 0: But, uh, I guess it's interesting that the CIA and the UK, all the intelligence organizations of the world kind of leaked what the plan was, and it seems like the intent was to leak Russia's plan so that maybe Russia would change their plan, or not go forward with this.
Speaker 0: And instead, Russia seems to be, as a military power, following the plan that was leaked, regardless of the fact that half the things that were part of that plan didn't pan out.
Speaker 0: And it's a real weird situation right now.
Speaker 0: that's beyond what even most, like, geopolitical scholars expected as a worst-case scenario.
Speaker 1: Alright, well, I mean, you know, if you just do what's expected, that's it, right?
Speaker 0: But, uh, yeah, just pay attention to it.
Speaker 0: I've tweeted at length about the fact that there is not actually a risk of a real nuclear war.
Speaker 1: That seems unlikely.
Speaker 0: It is extremely unlikely, but the thing I really want to point out, and I'm repeating this everywhere I have any amount of following, is that you're going to keep seeing the news talking about nuclear weapons and nuclear war.
Speaker 1: The news loves to talk about anything.
Speaker 1: that's, you know, not going to make you scared.
Speaker 1: You're telling me that the same news is like, "It's 11, where's the fuck are your children?
Speaker 1: Oh my god, you're going to go outside, there's going to be a person out there who's not white, they're going to kill you, stay
Speaker 1: inside.".
Speaker 1: It's like, you're telling me that news is stoking fears about nuclear war?
Speaker 1: That same news, really?
Speaker 0: This news that I've been using for these years, these clamps.
Speaker 0: But I guess what I'll say is this, with nuclear weapons in particular, experts tend to use a lot of jargon when they talk about them.
Speaker 0: So, actually, for real, innocuous news that happens to involve strategic, which is, you know, another jargon term for nuclear weapons, will make them sound far scarier or more dangerous than they actually are if you're uninformed.
Speaker 1: So my advice to you- Not helping them yet, the same problem has a nuclear power.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: Or even things like thermobaric weapons.
Speaker 0: Like, I'm not saying thermobaric weapons are a humane thing to be used.
Speaker 0: Like, do not think that I'm defending thermobaric weapons.
Speaker 0: But thermobaric weapons are not materially beyond what non-thermobaric weapons are.
Speaker 0: Like, the media will use these terms, but if you are not an expert, it is easy to get a lot more scared than you should be about things.
Speaker 0: And if you think, "Oh, I'll go follow experts," they know what's up, they're going to use jargon that's going to confuse and scare you even more.
Speaker 0: So my advice is, one, if you're actually afraid of nuclear war, do not seek out the opinion of experts on nuclear war, because they're going to say things that are going to scare you for no reason.
Speaker 1: And two- Yeah, like the people with their doomsday clock that's at, like, one second away from midnight or whatever.
Speaker 0: Well, actually, the doomsday clock has made it very clear.
Speaker 0: The nuclear threat is not why the clock is where it is.
Speaker 0: It is solely because of climate change.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: Two, if you see news about nuclear anything, right now and for the foreseeable future, and you don't understand that news, do not retweet it or share it with other people or paraphrase it.
Speaker 0: Let other people do that.
Speaker 0: Because if you don't understand it, what are the odds that the people you share it to are going to understand it?
Speaker 0: And a lot of the talking parts about nuclear weapons are extremely scary if you do not have a lot of weird knowledge that most people do not have and should not seek out, frankly.
Speaker 1: The only nuclear weapon news you need to worry about is nukes coming at you right now.
Speaker 1: And if that happens, which is extremely unlikely, again, it's, like, not going to happen.
Speaker 1: If it does, your phone will let you the fuck know, the same way it lets you know when there's a hurricane or anything else.
Speaker 0: Yep, and the only, like, the only thing that could happen in the news, short of a nuke going off, which, again, the odds are basically zero, like, for real, would be if NATO became directly involved with Russian forces, that is the thing that would change that conversation at all.
Speaker 0: So anything that happens that does not include NATO actually, for real, fighting directly with Russian forces, then any news you see about nuclear weapons does not represent any material change in the situation related to nuclear weapons.
Speaker 0: That's hard to internalize.
Speaker 1: You're really helping this by, you know, mentioning the nuclear weapons, right?
Speaker 1: You're sort of getting an old Streisand effect, right?
Speaker 1: No,
Speaker 0: you guys, it's a little, there's
Speaker 1: a little bit of-
Speaker 0: No, 'cause there's a little zebra storyteller of, you gotta almost inoculate yourself against if the news starts talking a big stupid game about it, to remember that unless one of these big things changed, the news is just talking about scarce stuff, it's not actually a material change.
Speaker 1: Is the zebra storyteller the antidote for the Streisand effect or not?
Speaker 0: It may or may not be, I don't know, but, uh, for real, this is a major ongoing conflict with minute-to-minute updates, and I guess the last thing I'll say is, you do not need to follow this second-by-second.
Speaker 0: That does not help your psyche, 'cause you're not gonna, you're not gonna make any different decisions in your life.
Speaker 1: If you're listening to this podcast, it's unlikely that you're in a position to do anything material to help in a significant way, right?
Speaker 1: The only way you can help, you know, as a normal person who is listening to Geek Nights is through collective action, and, uh, you know, contributing your part to a greater whole that might do something.
Speaker 1: So, if you want to do something, seek out such a collective action, otherwise, there's nothing you can do.
Speaker 0: So yeah, uh, enough said about that, we're gonna move into the regular old Geek Nights from this point.
Speaker 0: And, uh, we'll start with, there was big gaming news that dropped kinda out of nowhere.
Speaker 1: Uh, Pokemon, Scarlet, and Violet were announced, there was actually a real- It's surprising, 'cause it doesn't feel like the previous two main, you know, we're talking main Pokemon games, not side deals, right?
Speaker 1: The Sword and Shield ones don't feel like they're that old, and we've already got another one coming up right in.
Speaker 1: It's like, is this, I have to, I didn't look and see, but is this a normal time gap between main Pokemon games?
Speaker 1: Or is it, or was it really shorter like it feels?
Speaker 0: I mean, I haven't beaten a Pokemon game since Pearl, so I'm not really one to talk about.
Speaker 1: I do have to say, right, I beat Pokemon Red and Silver on cartridges back in the day, and I caught all the Pokemon, all of them, right?
Speaker 1: Every single one.
Speaker 0: Sure, Grandpa, no one can catch all the Pokemon now.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: After that, I think I skipped the Ruby, whatever it was, I don't know.
Speaker 1: But basically, since then, I have bought a lot of, not side Pokemon, I've only bought a few side Pokemon games, but I bought a lot of the main Pokemon games, and I would get a few Gyms in and never beat them.
Speaker 1: So, even though a lot of those games were great, and I had no complaints about them whatsoever, I just didn't end up beating them.
Speaker 1: I didn't have the time for it, or they didn't keep my interest.
Speaker 1: It's like I would play and play and play, and it would keep my interest, but then as soon as I saved and put it away, I'd forget about it, and I wouldn't go back to it.
Speaker 1: So, I've learned my lesson, and I'm going to save myself.
Speaker 1: I bought the Shield or Sword one.
Speaker 0: Which were from 2019, so it's been a while.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it has been a while.
Speaker 1: I got a few Gyms in, and then I stopped playing, and I could go back to it, I guess.
Speaker 0: So, I guess, what's noteworthy?
Speaker 1: I learned my lesson, and even though this one, the new one, that Duck starter looks pretty good.
Speaker 1: I like a duck.
Speaker 0: Oh, that duck is the best one.
Speaker 0: That's actually the one I would pick.
Speaker 0: I almost always have gone with whatever the Grass starter is, and I would make an exception.
Speaker 1: I mean, I would normally pick Grass because Green, and Grass is Green, but sometimes the Grass Pokemon, I just go with the coolest one or the cutest one.
Speaker 1: I can't be going based on any other type business, right?
Speaker 1: But anyway, if I hadn't learned my lesson, I would buy this and pick the duck, but I just learned my lesson, I'm not going to buy it, because I know that I'm just going to play a few Gyms and then stop.
Speaker 0: So, I guess what's notable, it's open world, like that seems to be the evolution of mainline Pokemon games.
Speaker 1: The new one, the Sword Shield one kind of is also a little bit.
Speaker 0: Yep, but continuing with that, the open world, that aspect of Pokemon seems like it's going to be a long-standing thing now.
Speaker 0: Two, the puns and the names are Spanish-derived more so than English-derived.
Speaker 1: Well, because every Pokemon game has a region that it takes place in, and that region is often a sort of imitation that is inspired by a real world location, like the Alola Pokemon was a Hawaiian one, right?
Speaker 0: And I've seen Hispanic and Spanish-speaking and Spanish-adjacent gamers being very excited about this all over Twitter.
Speaker 1: The new one they just announced is basically, yeah, it's Spain, it's Pokemon in Spain.
Speaker 1: There's going to be bull Pokemon, probably, that are going to run, they're going full Spain.
Speaker 1: So, we don't know much more.
Speaker 1: Hopefully, without the Inquisition part.
Speaker 0: So, for all the news, all we actually have to go on are a handful of statements, the images from the trailer, which is mostly a live-action skit that really buried the lead.
Speaker 0: Like, if you saw this trailer and didn't know it was the Pokemon trailer for two new mainline Pokemon games, you would not be sure what they were announcing until halfway through the trailer.
Speaker 1: Not to talk about the war again, but it was confirmed by Nintendo, I believe, that they intentionally didn't do their full, they decreased the volume on the marketing because they weren't going to change their announcement date, but they decreased the volume on the marketing and instead of being like, "Holy crap, guys, Pokemon
Speaker 1: Direct!"
Speaker 1: They were just like, "Alright, Pokemon Direct, it's happening, here it
Speaker 1: is.".
Speaker 1: Because there was an invasion going on and they don't want to be like, "Oh, yes, people are being murdered by an invading army.
Speaker 1: Hey, come play
Speaker 1: Pokemon!".
Speaker 0: Like, when I talk, look at me on social media, a lot less just shitposting than usual.
Speaker 0: I feel like a lot of people are dialing down the volume on anything they're doing with good cause.
Speaker 0: In some other news, the playdate continues to slowly gain adoption and interest.
Speaker 1: We talked about the playdate a few times, the new handheld that's black and white and has a little crank on the side.
Speaker 1: that was crowdfunded and then it's been delayed a few times.
Speaker 1: and they released a little tool on their website that lets you make games, but it's a really simple tool that can only make simple games.
Speaker 1: We've been waiting for the real SDK that would let you make whatever the hell software you wanted and that was released yesterday.
Speaker 1: and I tested it out and made a little "Hello World" video game equivalent where you load a background, you load a sprite and you can move the sprite around with a d-pad.
Speaker 1: and that took me longer to set up the dev environment than to write the program.
Speaker 1: It took five minutes, right?
Speaker 1: I just squiggled two PNG files in Photoshop and that was good to go.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, this thing is, you know, the next step they say is they're actually going to deliver them.
Speaker 1: I pre-ordered one so I'm going to get one and I'm working on, you know, I guess shit-talking about making a game for it.
Speaker 1: I can't promise actually making a game for it unless you count my little "Hello World" as a game.
Speaker 0: It's a fun, what I like about it the most is that this feels a lot like something we've talked about on GeekKnights before.
Speaker 0: It's the equivalent of a graphing calculator in that it's the kind of device that's accessible enough to a designer or a coder to mess with, homebrew, and like learn basic principles to make something that'll work out of hardware that it's going to be a fantastic tool for hobbyists, for schools, for game design programs.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of ways you can use this kind of device and I think it's really exciting.
Speaker 1: You know, you've had a lot of these sort of fantasy consoles like the Pico 8 and whatnot where, you know, they create a video game console that never existed, just an imagined one and then they create an emulator for it and then you make games for it, but there are PC games, right?
Speaker 1: You can't really run them on anything else too much.
Speaker 1: Some things you can, but not, you know.
Speaker 1: But here, it's like they took it to the next level.
Speaker 1: You know, programming for the play date is not really dissimilar from programming for the Pico 8 or any other similar simple fantasy console only.
Speaker 1: It's a real console, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, it's a real physical thing that you're going to arrive at some point relatively soon and that's kind of cool.
Speaker 1: We haven't had, I mean, there are people who can make a Game Boy game and make an NES game, right?
Speaker 1: But programming for those platforms is either really difficult because you've got to do assembly or C or whatever.
Speaker 1: there's not really advanced development tools or you use something like NES Maker which is pretty advanced actually, but it's a lot like using Game Maker, RPG Maker, right?
Speaker 1: This is an actual console.
Speaker 1: that's, you know, for the people, right?
Speaker 1: But it's open and you can really make stuff for it, like 100%, just write a program in C and run it on there.
Speaker 1: It's pretty great.
Speaker 0: Alright, we can get into the main bit.
Speaker 0: There's a thing about Switch 2 trending again because of an Nvidia leak but that's all like unconfirmed nonsense, so I'm not going to cover it.
Speaker 1: That's nonsense.
Speaker 1: Also, when is Nintendo included Nvidia hardware in their console?
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: Either this is radically misinterpreted or there's even bigger news that isn't confirmed yet.
Speaker 1: But yeah, Nvidia did get some leakage.
Speaker 0: But I'll cover that later.
Speaker 0: I see a lot of conflicting discussion.
Speaker 1: You can't trust news about leakages unless, you know, it has to be like that Nintendo one where they had all those assets and stuff, right?
Speaker 1: Most leakage news you can't trust.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: So check this out.
Speaker 0: I ski.
Speaker 0: It's one of my main hobbies.
Speaker 0: And sometimes when you ski, you fall.
Speaker 0: You fall over.
Speaker 0: Good reason not to ski.
Speaker 0: Sometimes when you're on a bike, you fall over.
Speaker 0: Sometimes when you're just walking, you fall over.
Speaker 0: What I like about skiing is that if I say, bounce off of a tree, do a 360 vertically and land somewhere, and I'm on a bike, I'm usually bleeding from a couple of places and have like a busted rib or something.
Speaker 0: But when that happens...
Speaker 1: Because if that happens on a bike, you're probably landing on the hard ground, right?
Speaker 0: The bike might land on top of you, which has happened to me before.
Speaker 0: But skiing, if you fall over, you usually just fall into a bunch of snow.
Speaker 0: I fall down all the time skiing, and I almost never have even minor injuries from that compared to mountain biking.
Speaker 0: But once, I was skiing on a trail called Bunny Buster, this really easy blue at Killington, but it was icy, shitty weather.
Speaker 0: And I fell near the top of the trail, and I slid all the way down.
Speaker 0: I couldn't stop myself.
Speaker 0: I slid all the way down on ice to the bottom of the mountain.
Speaker 1: Couldn't you just like, you have the ski poles, can't you just stick them in the ground?
Speaker 0: In this case, the ski, the ground was basically solid ice.
Speaker 0: It was a terrible day for skiing, I really shouldn't have even been there.
Speaker 1: You couldn't just like scrape the ice, you had nothing pointy or whatever to like just create any amount of friction with the ice.
Speaker 0: So I was able to slow myself down.
Speaker 0: I didn't actually make it to the end end of the trail, I slid like always, and very slowly came to a stop.
Speaker 0: And then luckily someone like kicked my skis down to me.
Speaker 0: So this is a video of someone skiing and on a really easy looking black diamond, like just a long, wide, straight piste, but the snow doesn't look great, and they fell like I did that one time on the ice.
Speaker 0: And they start sliding, but they keep sliding, and keep sliding faster and faster and faster.
Speaker 0: They slid on their ass over a kilometer before they eventually crashed into a net.
Speaker 0: They're totally fine, they get up, and they're like "ugh" at the end.
Speaker 0: They had a GoPro on, you get to see the whole thing in glorious detail.
Speaker 1: And to answer your earlier question, I feel like no matter how much of a ski device it is, I feel like with a whole kilometer of time, you've got to be something you can do to create some friction and at least stop.
Speaker 0: So yes, there is a technique called the self-arrest that if you ski in those kinds of conditions, you are supposed to learn.
Speaker 0: And this person clearly did not know how to do this at all.
Speaker 0: It's one thing to slide down like a small blue trail somewhere on a mountain like in the east coast, but sliding a whole kilometer, this is like a case study in.
Speaker 0: you should have learned this basic technique, you got way too far into your learnings, missing something fundamental.
Speaker 0: So, uh...
Speaker 1: Then again, there are some people who will, you know, pay to slide down, right?
Speaker 1: I think it'll do some tubing or some sledding, so...
Speaker 0: So there is a reason why pretty much every ski mountain on Earth bans tubes and sleds and any of those things, because they are considered...
Speaker 1: Because you can't steer them.
Speaker 0: Nope, they are what you would call...
Speaker 1: Or control them.
Speaker 0: ...uncontrolled devices.
Speaker 0: And you can imagine exactly what that means.
Speaker 1: If you're just going, there's nothing you can do about it.
Speaker 1: You got to go one at a time, basically.
Speaker 0: Like as a kid sledding, my main self-defense mechanism, if there was trouble, was to try to jump off of the sled.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course.
Speaker 1: What else can you do?
Speaker 1: The sled's doing what it's doing.
Speaker 1: You can't really steer it that much.
Speaker 0: So, uh, yeah, this is... You can watch someone slide on their ass over a kilometer down a mountain and crash into a net.
Speaker 0: And it's funny because you know they're not hurt.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So when I was in high school, right, I got the... I had money from working a part-time job and I was finally able to just go to... I had the ability, finally, to just go to fucking GameStop and buy video games or EB or whatever the hell store it was in those days.
Speaker 1: And so the Game Boy Color came out and I was like, "You know what?
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna go fucking buy that thing on release
Speaker 1: day.".
Speaker 1: And I fucking did it.
Speaker 0: Man, I never had a Game Boy Color.
Speaker 1: I had a Game Boy Color.
Speaker 1: Then I had a Game Boy Advance.
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: So now, rest in peace, portable Nintendo lineup, right?
Speaker 1: Now it's just Switch, which is both at once all the way over.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: So, and I got the Game Boy Color.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like, "Well, I bought this.
Speaker 1: I can play Game Boy games on it and I can get some of those DX games that work on Game Boys and Game Boy Colors, but I want to get some Game Boy Color only games because otherwise what's the
Speaker 1: point?".
Speaker 1: And the premiere game was Mario Brothers Deluxe, which was, you know, up until that point in time, if you're in 1990, whatever it was, I don't know what year, seven, eight, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'm guessing.
Speaker 1: It's like if you wanted to play Mario Brothers, Super Mario Brothers 1, you needed an NES or a PC with an emulator or something like that.
Speaker 1: To play it portably, it's like, "Could I get a Game Boy that had Mario
Speaker 1: Land?".
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 1: But you couldn't play Mario Brothers 1 portably on any device that existed, really.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's like you could -- By the time we were in high school, if you got a moderately expensive laptop, you could theoretically run an NES emulator.
Speaker 0: But I don't think you all really, unless you're as old as us, know what a laptop looked like, felt like, how much it weighed in that era.
Speaker 0: The Steam Deck is on Marvel.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: So nowadays, I'm like, "HD remakes,
Speaker 1: meh.".
Speaker 1: But at that exact moment, this was the way to play Super Mario Brothers 1 portably.
Speaker 1: It was this game.
Speaker 1: And the game not only had Mario 1, it also had Mario 2, meaning the real Mario 2, the lost levels -- Not Doki Doki Panic.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: In color, on a small device, with a backlight.
Speaker 1: The aspect ratio wasn't exactly the same as the original NES.
Speaker 1: It was a little bit different.
Speaker 1: But I couldn't tell the difference at the time.
Speaker 1: It felt like I was playing Mario 1 straight up.
Speaker 1: And it had a lot of -- It was pretty nice, actually, all things considered.
Speaker 1: And it had extra features, one of those extra features being this little day planner.
Speaker 1: They wanted to somehow be like, "Yeah, if you have this, it's also a
Speaker 1: PDA.".
Speaker 1: And I guess if you had a Game Boy printer, you could print, and it had all this extra stuff in there.
Speaker 0: Well, there was -- 'Cause Nintendo Power had a thing about it, and I was obsessed with it as a kid.
Speaker 0: There was that Game Boy PDA thing that was both a cartridge and, as far as I could tell, never actually released keyboard, specifically for the Game Boy to be a PDA for real.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Nintendo Power had a whole spread about it.
Speaker 1: So this Game Boy Color, though, they had some PDA-ish features in this game as, like, a side extra bonus thing, and there's actually -- If you go back, there's a lot of things like that.
Speaker 1: You know, like, people seem to forget, like, the Wii just had a message calendar system in it and stuff, right?
Speaker 0: It's like -- Yeah, the DS had PictoChat.
Speaker 1: The Wii had a weather app in it, right?
Speaker 0: It's like -- The regular DS had all this, like, local chat room stuff just built into it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the PictoChat, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So, anyway, there was PDA features in here, and there was this fortune-telling thing, and I guess if you wanted to see all the fortunes, you'd have to, like, open this game and check the fortunes, like, every day for a long period of time.
Speaker 1: It's like, "No one did
Speaker 1: that.".
Speaker 1: But somebody here on my thing of the day basically broke the game apart, you know, went and inspected the ROM and found all the fortune-telling stuff and made a little app so that you could, you know, have your own little Mario Deluxe fortune thing.
Speaker 1: I still have the cartridge.
Speaker 1: I don't know where my Game Boy Color went to.
Speaker 1: I don't know what happened to it.
Speaker 1: But I have the cartridge, and I can stick it in a GBA to run it and see and play it if I wanted to.
Speaker 1: So, really fascinating.
Speaker 1: Just look at this side feature in a game that was completely forgotten.
Speaker 0: This is one of the beautiful things about the Internet.
Speaker 0: Any aspect of anything, there will be at least one person who cares about it enough to do a deep dive on it and bring it to the world.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, I had it, and I only remembered that it existed because this person, you know, posted this thing online.
Speaker 1: I'm like, "All right.
Speaker 1: That was in that game.
Speaker 1: I remember
Speaker 1: now.".
Speaker 0: Bowser's Breath engulfs the future.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: There it is.
Speaker 0: In the meta moment, the Geek Nights Book Club book is "The City We Became" by N.K.
Speaker 0: Jemisin.
Speaker 1: We're gonna do the show -- I finished reading it a while ago.
Speaker 1: We're gonna -- I'm almost done reading.
Speaker 1: That book, I've read 1.8 more books.
Speaker 0: We're gonna do a show about it in about a month.
Speaker 0: You should easily be able to read this book by then.
Speaker 0: I highly recommend you read it with us.
Speaker 0: This book, if you have liked any of the books we have ever done on the Geek Nights Book Club, especially the books where we say something like, "Wow, that was a real Geek Nights-y book," you're gonna love the hell out of this book.
Speaker 1: Anything else?
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: Convention's coming up.
Speaker 0: There'll likely be at least one Geek Nights panel at PAX East, but I doubt we will be at PAX East beyond potentially doing that panel, potentially just me, potentially just me and Scott for a day.
Speaker 0: It's too soon to say.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, I don't know.
Speaker 0: We got nothing.
Speaker 0: We're working on the website.
Speaker 0: Well, Scott's mostly working on the website.
Speaker 0: I'm working on some panel stuff for other cons that are online and virtual.
Speaker 0: You might see some of that coming out.
Speaker 0: In fact, you're gonna see an additional list of games for our Atari game design panel at some point in the near future that you can watch.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, just, I don't know, keep following us.
Speaker 0: I got nothing else new.
Speaker 1: Once this website's done, then it's like I'm gonna be in this land of freedom where I won't have any obligation other than the job I have to make money and also maintaining life, right?
Speaker 1: So sustaining myself with eating, cleaning, it's clothing myself, et cetera.
Speaker 1: So I'm not gonna give any specific shit talk, but I will be doing something with that time.
Speaker 1: I don't know what it is, but something.
Speaker 1: And maybe one of those things I do with that time will produce something to share with the rest of the world.
Speaker 0: What you're saying is that you got a hopper and there's things in that hopper.
Speaker 1: Something might come out.
Speaker 1: No promises.
Speaker 0: All right, let's just get right into it.
Speaker 0: So this is a game from 2016 that we noticed and I pointed at.
Speaker 1: I knew it existed, and I knew what the name of it was.
Speaker 1: And that was the extent of what I knew.
Speaker 0: We knew that it was Mule Adjacent.
Speaker 1: I didn't know that until recently.
Speaker 0: We talked about that.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure there's a Geek Nights episode where we mentioned it and said those exact words.
Speaker 1: I don't think we've mentioned this game ever on Geek Nights before.
Speaker 0: Pretty sure we did it at some point, maybe in the forum.
Speaker 0: Well, anyway, this game, we're a little late to the party, but we've actually started playing it.
Speaker 1: A little late, six years late.
Speaker 0: It's still going strong.
Speaker 0: It's had a bunch of DLC.
Speaker 0: It's free for multiplayer on the Epic Games Store like right now, apparently.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I bought a mega bundle of everything on Steam when it was a mega sale.
Speaker 1: And I followed my policy of install it and play it immediately.
Speaker 1: And the game is Offworld Trading Company.
Speaker 1: And what it is, is it's on paper, it's sort of what I always kept asking for, almost.
Speaker 1: It's like 90% of the way there.
Speaker 1: And that it's an RTS.
Speaker 1: We're talking StarCraft, we're talking Warcraft, right?
Speaker 1: Except you don't have to micromanage dudes fighting at all.
Speaker 1: There aren't any dudes to fight.
Speaker 1: There's none of that whatsoever.
Speaker 0: It's just build the base, the game.
Speaker 1: It's you build the base, but then the base creates the resources on its own, just like you have peons making wood and stone in Warcraft, right?
Speaker 1: But then, once you have those goods, you basically play a stock market game with them, well, a commodities market game with them, where you're buying and selling them, trying to make a lot of money.
Speaker 1: And then when you have enough money, you can start buying shares in yourself and also the other players' companies.
Speaker 1: And then if you buy enough shares in someone else's company, they're dead.
Speaker 1: That's how you kill them.
Speaker 1: And so buying shares is sort of like converting money into victory points in sort of board game terms, right?
Speaker 1: And once you bought everyone else out, you win and you play again, I guess.
Speaker 0: And it's basically, if I had to describe how this game feels, imagine
Speaker 0: M.U.L.E.,
Speaker 0: a game that I'm pretty sure we did a Geek Nights episode on, at least.
Speaker 1: We should have.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll check that.
Speaker 0: M.U.L.E.
Speaker 1: is a historic and very important significant game.
Speaker 0: Yep, it's a game that we like.
Speaker 0: We draw inspiration and ideas from.
Speaker 0: It's like one of those-- So does everybody.
Speaker 1: Everybody to us.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: It's literally one of the forgotten masters out there, like Sopwith.
Speaker 0: So basically, it's like that, but scaled up and with a modern sensibility because that
Speaker 0: M.U.L.E.,
Speaker 0: as designed when it first came out, is a product of its era.
Speaker 0: It has several aspects that are dated, that don't work that well, that are kind of arbitrary or random.
Speaker 1: It also has a lot more luck going on.
Speaker 0: It does.
Speaker 0: Of World Trading does not have significant luck.
Speaker 0: If you lose this game, it's because you are terrible at this game.
Speaker 1: Or just not as good as the opponent.
Speaker 0: Yep, this game is hard to be good at.
Speaker 1: Yeah, very, yeah.
Speaker 0: But what it feels like playing is, imagine an RTS, but the RTS is, like I said, build the base, but next to that is a whole ass stock market with like 15 different things you can make and trade, and they all have prices that are going up and down based on what all the other players are doing in the game.
Speaker 0: It actually does act very closely like how a real stock market acts, or a real commodity market acts.
Speaker 1: If I have a shit ton of iron, and I hold onto it, and no one else really has any, and there's a demand for it, people need it, they're going to start buying it, right?
Speaker 1: And the way the game is set up is so that there's never a situation where something's unavailable, right?
Speaker 1: There's never, like, there is no more iron.
Speaker 1: That doesn't happen, because there's this colony, and you can always buy and sell with the colony.
Speaker 1: that's not a player.
Speaker 0: Basically, it acts like there's a market maker, if you know how capital markets work.
Speaker 1: But the market maker has an infinite supply of all resources.
Speaker 1: They're just set a price, so you might not be able to access that infinite supply if you don't have enough money.
Speaker 1: So if you want to buy iron, you can always buy iron, right?
Speaker 1: But the price might be like $200 per iron, but you can get it, right?
Speaker 0: But let's say the price of iron is $200, and I have a shit ton of iron from earlier in the game, and I sell it all, every time I sell even one piece of iron, the price of iron drops a tiny bit, because more entered the market.
Speaker 1: If someone buys an iron, you know, from the market, the price goes up.
Speaker 1: You don't directly trade with other players.
Speaker 1: All your exchanges are with the market, right?
Speaker 1: You buy and sell your iron on the iron market, at the current market rate, whatever that is.
Speaker 1: And every action you take changes that price.
Speaker 1: So, have fun.
Speaker 0: Yep, so you interact, playing basically a real-time strategy game, building a base to get resources, and then buying and selling those resources on the market, and you have to mess with the market, because there is no possible way to make everything you need in this game.
Speaker 0: You cannot be self-sufficient, because unlike most RTSs where you grow forever, you can only grow so much.
Speaker 0: There's a finite number of buildings you can ever build with a little bit of plus or minus one based on events and things you can do in the game, but there's a limit.
Speaker 0: You can only build so many things.
Speaker 0: It's not like old Civ games where you can upgrade everything all the way, build as many cities as you want.
Speaker 0: This game, you can only build so much.
Speaker 1: Right, so if the game was only about money, you know, it's like, well, you could just, you know, concentrate on what's worth a lot and just ignore, you know, what does it matter if I'm trading iron or steel or carbon or whatever, right?
Speaker 1: Well, it matters because you have a base, and that base has to be upgraded four times.
Speaker 1: And to upgrade the base four times based on which faction you've chosen, you're going to need specific resources to do so.
Speaker 1: So like with the really basic expansionist faction, in order to upgrade from level one to two, you need like a pile of steel and you need some glass, right?
Speaker 1: And I think you need some aluminum.
Speaker 0: But like another faction will need chips and steel instead of those.
Speaker 1: You need to get specific resources to upgrade.
Speaker 1: So the beginning parts of the game are all about getting the resources you need to upgrade your base to the next level for the lowest price or producing them yourself, which is still an opportunity cost because you could be producing something else that's worth money, which is actually what matters, right?
Speaker 1: But you have to upgrade if you, you know, so there's a rush to upgrade and sort of a snowball effect because like Rym said, you have a set number of claims, which is it's a hex map.
Speaker 1: So you can only build a number of buildings equal to the number of hexes that you have claims for.
Speaker 1: You start with what, like three or four claims?
Speaker 1: I forget how many, five?
Speaker 0: Well, there's one faction gets an extra one and there's all sorts of nonsense.
Speaker 1: But you only get so many claims and you build that many buildings and like.
Speaker 1: that's it.
Speaker 1: And you can't even to move.
Speaker 1: the claims is sometimes you just can't.
Speaker 1: And like some of the factions can move, could move them a little bit.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: A lot of the times, most of the time they're just permanent.
Speaker 1: So it's like you lay down an iron mine.
Speaker 1: It's like, yeah, you could destroy it and build something else in that spot.
Speaker 1: But that's, you know, you can't move that claim to a different spot.
Speaker 1: You can't, it's like if you suddenly want aluminum instead, it's like, well, there is no aluminum on that spot.
Speaker 1: You didn't use your claim on a spot that has aluminum.
Speaker 1: You can't build an aluminum mine until you upgrade and you get more spots.
Speaker 1: And then eventually once you get to level five, four and five, but mostly five, now the game, everyone's going to have, you're not going to have infinity slots, but you have a lot of slots.
Speaker 1: It's really flexible.
Speaker 1: So then it becomes the game of actually try to eliminate the other people.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, and such.
Speaker 0: So the factions also have their own powers.
Speaker 0: Like each faction has radically different powers, a little bit like games like Dune in that they're radically symmetric.
Speaker 1: Well, like, you know, Starcraft, Zerg, Protoss, humans, all different.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: Just like an RTS.
Speaker 0: So like there's some, there's basic resources.
Speaker 0: you can mine directly from the map.
Speaker 0: And then there's derived resources like computer chips.
Speaker 0: You have to put other resources into something to even make that resource at all, or just buy it from the market.
Speaker 0: And those resources will become more or less valuable, not just based on what the players are doing, but based on what the colony that you're all sharing the map with is doing.
Speaker 0: As it grows, like it's slowly going to always need more and more food.
Speaker 0: Uh, but depending on the details, it might also need a lot of chips or might need glass or might do all sorts of nonsense.
Speaker 0: And you kind of got to just watch this market.
Speaker 0: There's also a direct violence aspect of this game.
Speaker 0: There's something called the black market and you have your cash.
Speaker 0: You have cash that you use, you sell resources, you get cash, you can buy resources.
Speaker 0: You can even tell buildings, hey, if you need a resource, like you need iron because you're the building that makes steel, just buy the iron as you need it.
Speaker 0: And the game will just start to automate all of that for you.
Speaker 1: The game has a lot of quality of life features, right?
Speaker 1: That allow you to like automatically sell, you know, this as it's produced, right?
Speaker 1: Automatically, you know, oh, it's the building that upgrades.
Speaker 1: things automatically upgrade constantly, right?
Speaker 0: Like you don't have to manually buy the resources necessary to like build a building.
Speaker 0: If you have enough cash and you build the building, the game will just automatically buy the right amount of resources with that cash at the current spot price on the market right then and there.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, maybe in order to upgrade your base, you know, you need a thousand iron and you have zero iron and iron is a dollar.
Speaker 1: It'll just tell you, hey, upgrading your base costs a thousand dollars.
Speaker 1: Well, so tells you, and if you have a thousand dollars, you can just click upgrade base and it'll buy a thousand iron and upgrade the base.
Speaker 0: You can also interact with the black market with that cash.
Speaker 0: If you have enough cash on an interval that is faster or slower, depending on a bunch of factors, you can buy things from this black market.
Speaker 0: Some of these things are direct attacks on opponents.
Speaker 0: Some of these things are things like go steal some resources from somewhere on the map or give up a claim to remove it somewhere else.
Speaker 0: There's a bunch of different things there.
Speaker 0: There's also a bunch of different maps that have different characteristics.
Speaker 0: So when you start the game, a limited number of factions are available.
Speaker 0: Not every faction is available in every game.
Speaker 0: A limited number of black market things are available.
Speaker 0: Like every player sees what are the seven things that are even capable of being bought on the black market for this entire game.
Speaker 0: And you kind of have to navigate.
Speaker 0: It's almost like it sets up the play box and then all the players know everything and have to make decisions accordingly.
Speaker 0: There's very little real randomness to it.
Speaker 1: Well, it is randomness in the setup, right?
Speaker 1: But not randomness per player.
Speaker 1: I really like that because if you look at a game like Starcraft, even if you take Starcraft and you remove the thing I hate the most, which is the micromanaging the soldiers, it's still a game where you're like, "I play Zerg no matter what the map is.
Speaker 1: I'm a Zerg person and I've memorized the specific build order and 90% of the time it varies a little
Speaker 1: bit.".
Speaker 1: But you're pretty much sticking to it.
Speaker 1: You've determined that that's the optimal path.
Speaker 1: Build this building, then this building, then this building, and so forth.
Speaker 1: And it's all executing this set plan.
Speaker 1: And there isn't a lot of decision making that happens during the game until the mid or late game when it's like, "All right, what did they
Speaker 1: do?".
Speaker 1: Little rock, paper, scissors going on.
Speaker 1: And also the execution component with the micro.
Speaker 1: In Offworld Trading Company, you start, you see the map.
Speaker 1: Okay, you see which resources are plentiful and which ones aren't, and it's different every time.
Speaker 1: And then you see what's available in the black market, which is different every time.
Speaker 1: And you see which factions you have to choose from.
Speaker 1: There's only four in each, but there's more than four in the whole game.
Speaker 0: Like we were playing multiplayer the other night.
Speaker 0: I'm only good at, well good, I'm making quotes here.
Speaker 0: I am only minimally proficient in one of the four factions.
Speaker 1: And if that faction just might not be available that game.
Speaker 0: And it just wasn't in the first game we played.
Speaker 0: And I did not do well.
Speaker 0: It was a problem.
Speaker 1: So now you have to decide based on the map what the black market is and what factions are available.
Speaker 1: Which faction do you choose?
Speaker 1: Where do you start on the map, right?
Speaker 1: And then if you're not the first person to start, you now also have additional information of, well, they chose that faction.
Speaker 1: Should I change my mind about which one I was going to choose?
Speaker 0: And the default way multiplayer works is real fun.
Speaker 0: Because single player against all AIs does this differently.
Speaker 0: But with multiplayer, there's debt.
Speaker 0: And we'll talk about debt in a minute, because debt is a huge fascinating part of this game.
Speaker 0: Debt has caused many funny things to happen when we played this multiplayer.
Speaker 0: Not just to you.
Speaker 0: I hit D12.
Speaker 0: My credit rating was pretty naturally bad.
Speaker 0: And my stock price was approaching zero.
Speaker 0: So basically, the earlier you play, so everyone's looking at the map, and there's an amount of debt, and it's very high.
Speaker 0: And as you're watching, that amount of debt is slowly ticking down and getting closer and closer and closer from a horribly negative number to zero.
Speaker 1: As soon as you click... So this is like, it's interesting because you could just start playing immediately, which would give you a head start and first pick of your location.
Speaker 0: And you start with a D credit rating and a ton of debt.
Speaker 1: Your debt is enormous if you do that.
Speaker 1: So what really it's doing is, it's like, you're not going to start that early.
Speaker 1: You're just not.
Speaker 1: So you're giving everyone time to look at the map and see what's going on.
Speaker 1: And then by the time you're done looking, now maybe you'll start thinking about actually clicking.
Speaker 1: And it's a pretty clever way to start the game immediately, but also give you time and not just favoring someone who clicks the fastest.
Speaker 0: But it also handles directly the situation that a lot of games where you have a starting position have, where some positions are just better.
Speaker 0: So when we played this multiplayer the other night, in two different games, once it happened to me and once it happened to Scott, two players were looking at the exact same spot.
Speaker 0: You can't see what anyone else is doing until they click.
Speaker 0: We're just looking, looking, looking.
Speaker 0: I'm hovering over a spot and I see the debt counter gets to a point where I think, all right, I could deal with that debt.
Speaker 0: I click and a base appears.
Speaker 0: And I realize in that second that our friend Chris had in fact placed the base there.
Speaker 0: He clicked frames before me.
Speaker 1: Same exact moment.
Speaker 1: I also had a situation where I clicked to put a base and it was like, nope.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, what do you mean, no?
Speaker 1: I'm like, click, click, click.
Speaker 1: It's like someone, other base just comes out and it's like the exact same moment.
Speaker 1: You couldn't, like, if it had landed a few seconds earlier, like even two seconds earlier, I would have been like, I wouldn't have clicked my mouse.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: And I would, I would have been like, oh, okay.
Speaker 1: They took more debt, but literally the same second.
Speaker 1: It was like, come on.
Speaker 0: But it's such a fun mechanic because the longer you wait, the better off your start is, but potentially.
Speaker 1: Well, not if you don't get the good, you've got to weigh that against getting the good spot on the map.
Speaker 1: And not only the good spot on the map, but if you go down earlier, you start producing goods and getting your way on your way to upgrading to level two.
Speaker 1: Other people's bases haven't even landed yet.
Speaker 0: So one of the games I won, I started, you're doing nothing.
Speaker 0: I started way earlier than everyone else and I had a ton of debt, but I had two steel mills operational before another player even laid their base.
Speaker 1: And I won.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 0: So there was something going on there.
Speaker 0: So let's talk about debt because this is sort of the fascinating part of this game.
Speaker 0: And this is how the quality of life of the, like how all these different quality of life features of the game work together so well to remove a lot of the annoying pain of most RTSs.
Speaker 0: The game has the market.
Speaker 0: And if you are buying things automatically that must be bought, like energy, for example, power, your debt's just racking up in the background.
Speaker 0: It's not taking away from your cash.
Speaker 1: If you don't have any money for it.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: But it just racks up debt.
Speaker 0: Debt might be fine.
Speaker 0: You can have a bunch of debt, but your debt, one, there'll be interest.
Speaker 0: And the worse your credit rating is, the worse the interest will be on the debt, regardless of the number of the debt.
Speaker 0: Your credit rating is determined by how bad your debt is relative to the other players.
Speaker 0: There's a few other factors.
Speaker 0: It's actually a fairly complex market, but you don't really need to know those details unless you decide to try to go pro with this game.
Speaker 1: The point is a lot of debt ruins your stock price and makes it easy for other people to buy you out and eliminate you from the game.
Speaker 0: And if your debt's too bad, if you have a de-credit rating, you can't even buy shit from the black market anymore.
Speaker 0: So the cool part about debt is you can accrue debt on purpose.
Speaker 0: You can pay debt off as you feel like it.
Speaker 0: It's just one more mechanic in the game.
Speaker 0: The only things you cannot go into debt for are you cannot buy something from the black market with debt.
Speaker 0: You gotta use cash.
Speaker 0: And you cannot buy any resource except power via debt.
Speaker 0: If you need iron and you don't have any cash, you can't buy iron by going into debt.
Speaker 0: Your buildings that need iron just fucking stop working.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: You could sell something else and then buy iron.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: So you're usually trying to make a machine where like I make a bunch of food.
Speaker 0: I sell that food to afford the iron because I couldn't get any iron.
Speaker 0: Use the iron to make steel.
Speaker 0: I sell the steel for a profit.
Speaker 0: Like you're trying to make a fairly complex supply chain and market for yourself.
Speaker 1: There are some resources that you make because they're just worth a lot of money and what it takes to produce them doesn't cost as much as what you get for selling them.
Speaker 1: And that's just business.
Speaker 1: And there are some resources where it's like power.
Speaker 1: It's like if I don't build a power plant, then I'm going to have to buy power from the market constantly.
Speaker 0: And I've played games where for various reasons the price of power skyrockets.
Speaker 0: And if you don't have enough power generation, you're losing like a thousand dollars a second.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like the price of power might tank to like a dollar.
Speaker 1: And you're like, oh, I'll just turn off my power plants.
Speaker 1: You just buy power from the market and use debt for it or whatever.
Speaker 1: And who cares?
Speaker 1: But then suddenly the price of power goes way up.
Speaker 1: And remember the claims are locked in.
Speaker 1: If you don't have a claim on a spot that's good for a power plant or an unused claim, suddenly your debt starts going up because you have buildings and those buildings are operating and they need power.
Speaker 1: So it's like you're in the market to buy resources to run your buildings.
Speaker 1: And hopefully what comes out the other end of those buildings is worth more than what goes into them at all times to some extent.
Speaker 0: So one other aspect of the game, which is the final like core game mechanic other than victory, is there are five special buildings that do a bunch of different stuff.
Speaker 0: And they take the game from being fairly simplistic into being an infinite sea of human decision making.
Speaker 1: There's a patent lab that lets you get special abilities.
Speaker 1: There's an upgrade building that just lets you upgrade and make other buildings better.
Speaker 0: Both of those require potions, basically like chemicals as fuel to work.
Speaker 1: There's one that's the hacker array that lets you manipulate the market.
Speaker 0: Drive the prices up or down.
Speaker 1: Just fake the market, at least temporarily.
Speaker 1: There's the off world trade here, right, which is where the game gets its name from.
Speaker 1: It's basically a rocket launch pad that gives you access to a second market for all the resources that has different prices.
Speaker 1: because you're selling them, you know, you're basically putting, it's like, oh, iron isn't worth anything on this planet.
Speaker 1: Let me put my iron in a rocket and sell it to another planet.
Speaker 1: And, you know, you got to check the off world market because it's off world trading company and see what the off world prices are.
Speaker 1: They're going to be different than the local prices.
Speaker 1: And you can make a lot of money and it just continuously firing rockets as long as you can keep fueling them and whatnot.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So say the last one is the pleasure dome.
Speaker 1: I wonder what happens in there.
Speaker 1: Pleasure dome is just pleasure.
Speaker 0: Print money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you build pleasure domes and they make money.
Speaker 1: You build them next to the habitats in the colony and if people visit them and you just get free money and it's a way to win.
Speaker 1: If you get a lot of pleasure domes, you can make a lot of money and win that way.
Speaker 0: And then the final mechanic, the way you actually win, like the hit points of you as a player is the stock market.
Speaker 0: Your goal is literally to have enough cash to buy out all the other players and own them as subsidiaries.
Speaker 1: All that other stuff.
Speaker 1: It's like you're getting resources to upgrade your base and then you're upgrading your base so that you can build a machine that makes money.
Speaker 1: And you're building a machine that makes money so that you can buy everyone else's shares until you own all the companies on this planet.
Speaker 1: You have a monopoly and then you win.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's real direct and straightforward and fun.
Speaker 0: And if someone gets knocked out of the game, their faction just keeps running and you can still buy shares in it and just collect profits from it.
Speaker 0: Basically.
Speaker 1: And they are mercifully.
Speaker 1: They don't have to keep playing.
Speaker 1: It's like if you tank at this game real bad, it's a lot like Age of Steam.
Speaker 1: Someone will just buy all your shares and you're eliminated and you can go do something else.
Speaker 1: Go eat a snack or go home.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Or whatever.
Speaker 0: But much like Civilization as well, when the game ends, you get a million charts.
Speaker 0: Everything that happened in the game.
Speaker 0: Like you see the full story of how it went down.
Speaker 0: Look at the market over time.
Speaker 0: Look at who was attacking who.
Speaker 0: Like, oh, it was Rym who was buying all those EMPs the whole time.
Speaker 0: There's proof.
Speaker 1: So, let's see.
Speaker 1: Good things about this game.
Speaker 1: Obviously, I already said it's an RTS.
Speaker 1: We don't have to micromanage dudes.
Speaker 1: That's great.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's also, you know, I love stock market thing.
Speaker 1: I love how it's like really board gamey.
Speaker 0: The stock market feels like I'm playing a complex board game.
Speaker 0: Like it's just really fun.
Speaker 1: Unfortunately, it just feels like a board game that's, you know, doesn't have turns and it's going really too fast.
Speaker 0: We're not good at this game.
Speaker 1: No, I'm awful at this game.
Speaker 1: And despite, you know, it has all those quality of life features automatically by turning, you know, automatically do this.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You really, once you get the keyboard shortcuts down, you understand the really good user interface.
Speaker 1: It's like you never feel like there's no hassles or busy work.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Everything you're doing is like some sort of, you know, real decision that matters.
Speaker 0: Every click is material.
Speaker 0: And APM could even matter up to a point, but not to the degree of like a Starcraft.
Speaker 1: No, it is knowing that it matters at all.
Speaker 1: But regardless, it's way better than the other options.
Speaker 0: Let's say the price of glass is skyrocketing.
Speaker 0: And let's say me and Scott both have a shit ton of glass.
Speaker 0: We're playing real time chicken.
Speaker 0: Who sells all their fucking glass first, captures those profits and ruins the market for the other one.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: Because if I have 100 glass and I just sell it all, it's like, well, the price just goes down.
Speaker 1: And now if rim tries to sell his, he's getting less money for his same amount of glass than I got.
Speaker 0: So the challenges with this game, like I really like it.
Speaker 0: I'm going to keep playing the shit out of it.
Speaker 1: I would like to try to get better at it because.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So the place we're at now in this game is like skill wise.
Speaker 1: You know, I don't want to give two strategy tips because I don't have any.
Speaker 0: I could like to the spreadsheet.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: In single player, when I play against the AI at the normal difficulty, I can beat it pretty reliably.
Speaker 1: But when you play single player, you have the ability to pause the game so you can just pause and think about what you're going to do.
Speaker 1: It's like you're about to upgrade.
Speaker 1: You're like, pause.
Speaker 1: Where am I going to put my claims?
Speaker 1: I'm going to go there, there and there.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: And you unpause and put the claims and really quick.
Speaker 1: And it's like, it's not an issue.
Speaker 1: But when you play multiplayer, there is no pause at all at the game.
Speaker 1: It just has a speed that's too fast for a slow old guy.
Speaker 1: And it's like, I cannot keep up with it.
Speaker 1: Like I'll upgrade my base and be like, uh, uh, uh, I mean, every time I go, uh, I'm losing money, right?
Speaker 1: Not using the claims, don't have buildings down.
Speaker 1: Uh, uh, you know, the market's moving and I'm like, uh, I'm busy paying attention to something else.
Speaker 1: Uh, Oh God.
Speaker 1: Oh God.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: But also the game is very different.
Speaker 0: playing against humans versus the AI, especially when you're not good.
Speaker 1: The AI and the real time mode, when we played three against there, three of us and one AI, it destroyed us.
Speaker 1: Its base was upgraded one level ahead of our basis at all times.
Speaker 0: Its stock price was double any of ours within a couple minutes.
Speaker 1: I don't know what it was doing, but it was just like better than us in every conceivable way.
Speaker 1: And that was the regular difficulty AI, not the cheaty, harder AI.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: The other, uh, challenge with the game is that the learning curve to getting to the point where even at, where you could play the game, multiplayer and kind of understand what's going on and like feel like you understand why you lost up to a point.
Speaker 0: It takes five to 10 hours probably to get to that point.
Speaker 1: The tutorial was a really good tutorial and that it didn't break and it introduced a lot of concepts, but it was by no means complete.
Speaker 1: It didn't tell you how to win.
Speaker 1: It only told you like.
Speaker 1: it basically was like an interface tutorial.
Speaker 0: Not really a game, but to be clear, it was necessary.
Speaker 0: Like that tutorial is necessary to even be ready to engage with.
Speaker 0: So how do I actually play this game?
Speaker 1: You need like the tutorial is like, it'll tell you click here to buy glass.
Speaker 1: Now click here to upgrade your base.
Speaker 1: Now you have more claims.
Speaker 1: So it like it, but it's like it told you what to do, but it didn't tell you why you were doing it or why you might do something else instead or what your other options were.
Speaker 1: It was literally like click here, now click here.
Speaker 0: So I would say you have to play the tutorials first, then play the tutorial like challenges where it makes you play a faction and like win on a predefined map until you can beat all of those.
Speaker 0: Then play some skirmishes with AIs.
Speaker 0: It'll crush you.
Speaker 0: And then if you want to actually try to get good at this game, the only way to engage with it is, in my opinion, is kind of like with chess in that at that point, memorize a couple of basic openings just to get you like into the game enough to try to interact with the more advanced concepts.
Speaker 0: Like I've memorized a couple of build orders that are not like perfect build orders, but they let me get further into the game.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's the.
Speaker 0: I think that's, you know, I'm going to link to the spreadsheet.
Speaker 0: Scott kept talking about the spreadsheet, but I didn't know what it was.
Speaker 0: Then finally, what the fuck spreadsheet?
Speaker 0: And you sent me a link to it.
Speaker 0: And it is literally just this Google Doc that tells you how to someone made it some player of this game.
Speaker 1: Someone made a Google Doc, which is basically the ultimate strategy guide for this game.
Speaker 0: It's real good.
Speaker 0: Like when to found an expansive HQ versus a robotic HQ when not to found it.
Speaker 0: Here's a basic build order and advanced build order and a bunch of expert build like guidelines.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think that's the thing.
Speaker 1: I don't the negative points of this game because it's not perfect.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Is that, you know, it is a little fast for old man Scott, but I guess that's just because I'm slow.
Speaker 1: It's like it's a it's an artist.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: It's not like it's false advertising here.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's if you don't want an artist at all, go play a turn based game instead.
Speaker 0: Go places.
Speaker 0: This is game.
Speaker 0: This game shines with time pressure.
Speaker 0: That is what makes it fun.
Speaker 1: It does have, though, a little bit of that build order stuff, right?
Speaker 0: Though, like I did watch some people are good at it.
Speaker 0: I watched some streams.
Speaker 0: The build orders that are memorizable are just.
Speaker 0: they're very good, but they're worthless against someone who knows what they're doing because the people who know what they're doing adapt radically to what other people are doing.
Speaker 1: The other.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like is a lot of information to take in.
Speaker 1: It's not really the speed of clicking.
Speaker 1: It's the speed of like, what the heck is going on?
Speaker 1: You got people can put.
Speaker 1: No, it's like put their buildings in their area.
Speaker 1: People can put buildings forever.
Speaker 1: So it's like you can't even tell, like, what is that other person doing?
Speaker 1: What buildings they have?
Speaker 1: What's their strategy?
Speaker 1: And in the time it takes, like look at their base and assess that shit has happened and you've missed, you know, price on something could have crashed or skyrocketed or, you know, I
Speaker 0: feel like I've gotten to the point where I don't have to follow a strict build order to not lose when I play the robots.
Speaker 0: And that is as far as I've gotten.
Speaker 0: That's like the equivalent.
Speaker 1: Very.
Speaker 1: I'm wildly inconsistent where it's like I'll either, you know, do great or kind of great or just completely collapse.
Speaker 0: There's the game where you bought me out like right away.
Speaker 0: There was another game where I heard stock price was approaching zero.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like I have.
Speaker 1: the problem is, is that I try to use normal common sense heuristics.
Speaker 1: Like I look at a map and there's like no iron on it anywhere.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, damn, I'll settle that iron and then I'll write the price should go way up and then I'll sell it.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, maybe I'll even use the hacker rate to boost the price of iron even higher.
Speaker 1: Let's just do that.
Speaker 0: What did I do?
Speaker 0: Found a scientific HQ, make steel directly by founding on that iron.
Speaker 0: And who cares about iron?
Speaker 1: No, but that's like, no, I'm saying like I played against the AI and I had a monopoly.
Speaker 1: There was no other iron.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I had it all.
Speaker 1: And the whole game, the price of iron was trash.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, there's no iron on the fucking map.
Speaker 1: The supply, I have all of it.
Speaker 1: I'm fucking De Beers of iron.
Speaker 1: Why is the price never going up unless I use like the hacker array?
Speaker 1: And even then it doesn't go up that much.
Speaker 1: Like this makes no sense.
Speaker 1: Like there must be some reason the price of iron didn't go up.
Speaker 0: Well, there is one aspect of this game that I like in that I think this is part of what makes the game work.
Speaker 0: The market, each of the resources are not just completely fungible, like they're just theme.
Speaker 0: They all are used for specific purposes and tend to have certain patterns.
Speaker 0: like raw metal, like aluminum iron will never become super valuable in any circumstances.
Speaker 1: But it stayed at like way low.
Speaker 1: It didn't even go up to like 20 bucks.
Speaker 0: That implies that the other players, the AIs were not buying much iron from the market.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But there are also situations, right?
Speaker 1: So there's the colony, which is not a player.
Speaker 1: It's just a thing on the map that you can look at.
Speaker 1: And you know, it's what you're always buying and selling with.
Speaker 1: And I saw that the colony had a lot of laboratories, which implies that, you know, those laboratories need chemicals to operate.
Speaker 1: And I said, aha, that library has a lot of chemicals needs with all its laboratories of the science colony.
Speaker 1: I'll build some chemical plants.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And at the time I built them, they were somewhat profitable.
Speaker 1: And then fucking the chemical prices were just like in the shitter.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, demand is so high.
Speaker 1: And I don't see a lot.
Speaker 1: I looked at the other players' bases.
Speaker 1: They weren't making.
Speaker 1: I think one other player had like one chemical plant.
Speaker 1: And it's like, shouldn't the price of chemicals be going up?
Speaker 1: It's like what it's like.
Speaker 1: those common sense heuristics of supply and demand did not apply in several games that I played.
Speaker 1: It was like a common pattern.
Speaker 1: So I need I'm having trouble finding a heuristic of trying to predict what's going to be valuable.
Speaker 0: I know this isn't helpful, but I look at that market the whole time and I kind of treat it like it's the real stock market, the way I would actually invest were I trying to invest in the commodities.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But I mean, that's that that's one way to play is just, you know, like day trading or like, you know, real time trading where like it's like the prices up, sell, sell, sell the prices down, buy, buy, buy constantly.
Speaker 0: But I can't find any long term thinking to apply to the only long term thinking I have is chips always become valuable near the end.
Speaker 0: Food almost always becomes very valuable near the end.
Speaker 0: Fuel is usually more expensive than I expected.
Speaker 0: And power is the thing that will fuck me over really badly if I don't pay attention to it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But it's like I try to.
Speaker 1: I was, you know, in my attempts to find a long term thing, we're like, aha, I can.
Speaker 1: I can predict in this game that this will be valuable later.
Speaker 1: I'll stockpile it early and then make a big move because there's no other supply of it or something like that.
Speaker 1: And that never worked ever.
Speaker 0: Ah, that was one of the multiplayer games with iron for me because I had the hacker array just boost iron like ten times in a row.
Speaker 1: I tried to do I've tried to do that and it didn't work.
Speaker 0: So anyway, the danger is the hacker.
Speaker 1: I think that there's a lot more focus on that sort of, you know, instant reaction of.
Speaker 1: look at the market.
Speaker 1: A number goes green.
Speaker 1: Do you have that resource?
Speaker 1: Start selling.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: A number is red.
Speaker 1: Do you not have that resource?
Speaker 1: You know, start buying that sort of if it's a resource you need.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Or going to need so.
Speaker 0: But I really enjoy this game more so than I expected.
Speaker 1: And the multiplayer game with such high quality of life with, you know, with less micro than other artists, but still an artist.
Speaker 1: And, you know, with despite being so simple, relatively in terms of like what you can do, but having clearly a lot of strategic depth to get better at it in a high skill cap of some kind.
Speaker 1: You know, there's a lot of replay value here.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And if you you might encounter that the eyes are extremely unfun to play against.
Speaker 0: Don't worry about that.
Speaker 0: If you invest the five to 10 hours and just learning the basics of the game, multiplayer against scrubs is super fun.
Speaker 0: Like we were playing for player multiplayer.
Speaker 0: None of us are that good.
Speaker 0: And the games were really close and interesting.
Speaker 0: Kind of like when you play a euro style board game, but none of you have played it before.
Speaker 0: And you're all just kind of fumbling in the dark.
Speaker 0: It can be real fun and real fair and real close.
Speaker 1: The one thing I really didn't like about this game is the single player campaign.
Speaker 1: You can do a single player skirmish, which is basically just play a multiplayer game against A.I.
Speaker 1: to learn your shit.
Speaker 1: But there's a campaign and the campaign is really all these scenarios.
Speaker 1: And like you unlock and you don't even have all the buildings to start with.
Speaker 1: Like you're unlocking them as you go along.
Speaker 1: And it's sort of stateful.
Speaker 1: It's not bad, but like it was not as fun as just playing the normal game.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like remember there's the Wesnoth campaigns, but just Wesnoth multiplayer was like the thing that was worth playing.
Speaker 1: Exactly, exactly.
Speaker 1: So I could see someone getting into the campaign thing and enjoying it, but not me.
Speaker 0: Especially because one thing that's worth noting, the music is fantastic.
Speaker 0: Like the theme is fantastic.
Speaker 0: This like corporate libertarian health game.
Speaker 1: The music is good, but I had to turn it off because it was too distracting.
Speaker 0: I just turned it way down.
Speaker 1: Down works good.
Speaker 0: The writing is really funny.
Speaker 0: Especially, like not just the regular game, like the writing is funny.
Speaker 0: Like when things happen, like when a pleasure dome gets built.
Speaker 0: But the tutorials are, they're not as funny as Portal, but they're close.
Speaker 0: There are jokes and little bits.
Speaker 1: It's that same sort of like tug and cheek, you know, sort of, what's it called?
Speaker 1: Hitchhiker's Guide-esque nerd humor, right?
Speaker 1: Where it's being cute and cartoony and sciency.
Speaker 0: But also being a little bit like, yeah, libertarian dystopia.
Speaker 0: This is what it looks like.
Speaker 0: This is awful.
Speaker 0: Fuck capitalism.
Speaker 1: Yep, exactly.
Speaker 0: The game is very much like capitalism.
Speaker 0: in its final form is awful.
Speaker 1: There's some M.U.L.E.
Speaker 1: references that are not at all veiled in any way whatsoever.
Speaker 0: There's just M.U.L.E.
Speaker 0: on the black market.
Speaker 0: You can just buy it and it goes out and gets resources from the desert.
Speaker 1: And the tutorial references like Dr.
Speaker 1: Bunten, the creator of M.U.L.E It's like by name.
Speaker 0: I think this game is just, like, it has great reviews from a lot of people.
Speaker 0: It's not talked about that often.
Speaker 0: It wasn't talked about that much even when it came out.
Speaker 1: Well, it's a very niche interest, right?
Speaker 1: It is.
Speaker 1: Even perfectly implemented, if I had nothing to complain about.
Speaker 1: Who in the world is the audience for this game?
Speaker 1: It's like nerds like us.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much it.
Speaker 0: And it's interesting that a game that was basically designed for me as a primary demographic is also a game that I'm terrible at.
Speaker 1: I'm so awful at this game.
Speaker 0: Yet I want to play it more.
Speaker 0: So if you listen to Geek Nights, there's a chance you will like this game.
Speaker 0: And I'm pretty sure you can still try it out for free on the Epic Games Store if you want to try it.
Speaker 1: Or just wait for a sale.
Speaker 1: It will be on sale again for very little money.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of Geek Nights are Heidi McNichol, LinkyG, DreadLily, Tenderbrain, a bunch of people who really don't want me to say their names, Krista Dodd, Chris Reimer, Clinton Walt, and Dex Fink, Shaya85, Rebecca Dunn, Review Madbull, 34 Cowards, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Horrell, Taylor Brum, the next station is Rosedale, Rosedale Station, and several names that I will not read out of respect for the people's wishes who have typed them into Patreon.
Speaker 0: So yeah, if I don't know what else to say, I'll simply leave you tonight with... (singing in foreign language).
Speaker 0: (singing in foreign language).