Speaker 0: It's April 20th, 2022.
Speaker 0: I'm Rym.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight we're reviewing Goodbye, Eri, a one-shot manga by Tatsuki Fujimoto.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: It's finally warm enough again.
Speaker 0: I woke up this morning.
Speaker 0: It was too cold to bike to work, so I checked the subway.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, it was really cold for some reason in the morning.
Speaker 0: It was sunny, and I was like, "Huh, I
Speaker 0: wonder.".
Speaker 0: And then I touched the window, and it was freezing, and of course I didn't bike to work.
Speaker 0: But now it was more than 20 degrees warmer when I left work, so I biked home.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the weather site has a bar for the temperature, and today's bar is a very wide bar, right?
Speaker 1: So the low was low, and according to this, it says the low today was 43, and the high today was 60 Fahrenheit.
Speaker 1: Which is still not warm enough, but it's okay.
Speaker 1: It's much better than 43, that's for sure.
Speaker 0: Weather's been weird because a few weeks ago, Hunter Mountain, which is way north of here, and that's where I ski pretty often, was still open because they still had snow.
Speaker 0: You could still go ski there.
Speaker 0: And the night before, it was like 20 degrees Fahrenheit.
Speaker 0: And then the next day, it was like a Saturday skiing was open.
Speaker 0: We didn't go obviously.
Speaker 0: It was 68 degrees Fahrenheit during the day.
Speaker 0: You could have gone skiing in shorts and a t-shirt.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you look at, you know, it seems like this weekend is gonna be the start of at least kinda not freezing fucking cold.
Speaker 0: Oh, this weekend I think is the weekend we're getting the bikes out and starting biking again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this weekend is like the border where we cross over into, "Okay, at least it's not freezing.
Speaker 1: You can actually go outside now without some coats and
Speaker 1: shit.".
Speaker 1: You know, it's not warm warm yet, but it's like, "Okay,
Speaker 1: finally."
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: Not winter anymore.
Speaker 0: I can go outside and just not react as opposed to now when I walk outside and go,
Speaker 0: "Eh."
Speaker 0: There'll be no more "Eh" until September, October, something like that.
Speaker 0: Finally.
Speaker 1: November.
Speaker 0: This felt like a particularly long winter for a lot of reasons.
Speaker 1: But, you know, it's real annoying that it's like, "Come on, it's the end of April
Speaker 1: already.".
Speaker 1: If we only get May, June, July, August, it's like, "Give me the six months of the
Speaker 1: warm.".
Speaker 1: Not just four or five months.
Speaker 0: But also, it's extra bad because of COVID in that we're not eating indoors.
Speaker 0: We're not going to restaurants, so we're extra isolated.
Speaker 0: But when it's warm out, there's outdoor dining, which is oddly freeing to be able to go do that.
Speaker 0: And we got a taste of it when it was warm a couple weeks ago, and then it was taken away, and it's finally back, sort of.
Speaker 0: Next week it'll be back, mostly.
Speaker 0: So, the other thing I noticed, due to pure circumstance, we have not done a Wednesday Geek Nights in a while.
Speaker 0: We had a bunch of disruptions to Geek Nights, the whole unplanned hiatus, but funnily enough, Wednesdays took the brunt of it.
Speaker 0: I think we had a lot of hockey games that just happened to fall on Wednesdays.
Speaker 0: Things kept happening on Wednesdays, so there's a lot of old news.
Speaker 0: We're going to have a bunch of news before we talk about this anime.
Speaker 0: Or this manga.
Speaker 0: I'm going to talk about an anime as a Geek Byte.
Speaker 0: But I want to start with the news that brought back some memories, not pleasant ones.
Speaker 0: If you are about our age, and you went to anime cons in the mid-2000s-ish, like the mid-2000s was the time to seem to peak, there was a phenomenon where kids would buy from this one vendor at pretty much every anime con in America, these gigantic yaoi paddles.
Speaker 1: It was more like a miniature oar for a boat.
Speaker 1: It's like when you go to a baseball game and you can buy the little souvenir baseball bat, and it's a small baseball bat.
Speaker 1: You can't actually play baseball with it.
Speaker 0: But you can whack someone with it.
Speaker 1: Sure, it's made of wood.
Speaker 1: But this was like an oar, like you would row a boat with it.
Speaker 1: Only much smaller, like a miniature.
Speaker 1: But it was solid wood, right?
Speaker 1: And on it was written the word yaoi.
Speaker 0: And then it had a softcore side and a hardcore side.
Speaker 0: And I remember, I don't remember what year it was or even what con it was.
Speaker 0: I think it was Otakon.
Speaker 1: Otakon was the first time I saw them.
Speaker 1: I think it was Otakon, the second Otakon I went to, which might have been '03?
Speaker 0: The problem is it might have been Anime Central where I saw them first.
Speaker 1: Okay, Otakon was definitely the first place I saw one.
Speaker 1: I even remember in the room where the booth was, wasn't the company Hendone?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we'll get to that.
Speaker 0: I got another link.
Speaker 0: So I remember I saw them in the dealer's room and I was like, "Huh, that is slightly
Speaker 0: funny.".
Speaker 0: And then bit by bit, people kept buying them and sure, that would be fine, but they became a problem.
Speaker 0: Because the people who were buying them were also being extremely disruptive with them in ways that are way beyond what you were even imagining.
Speaker 1: I think what it was is that the person selling them was always a very loud, wacky-waving, inflatable-arm-flailing human in the dealer's room.
Speaker 0: This was the kind of person, if I ran an Anime Con, I would have banned that company from my dealer's room back then.
Speaker 1: Agreed, but it's also the kind of person where if I was an Anime Con dealer, I would hire to be my... ...tension-grabbing individual.
Speaker 1: And for people like me, when I see that person there, even all those years ago, the person I was then...
Speaker 0: The AT field comes out immediately when someone like us sees this person.
Speaker 1: The person I was then was still repulsed.
Speaker 1: And when I saw that person, I was like, "Dope, stay away from
Speaker 1: that.".
Speaker 1: But the kind of person who would be attracted to that loud, ostentatious sales pitch is the kind of person who's gonna make trouble at your con.
Speaker 1: So even though, regardless of whether the paddles were being physically used for trouble, which they were on occasion...
Speaker 0: The people who were causing trouble were all carrying them.
Speaker 1: Right, the people who were loud, obnoxious types of people were carrying these paddles because they were attracted to that person and were the kind of person who would buy that paddle.
Speaker 0: There was also another trend happening.
Speaker 1: People making trouble unrelated to paddles were equipped with paddles, and people who were making trouble with paddles were also equipped with paddles.
Speaker 1: So basically, almost everyone who had a paddle, it was strongly correlated with trouble.
Speaker 0: But this was also a time in American anime conventions specifically where trouble was on the rise and the cons were growing massively.
Speaker 0: In the late 90s and early 2000s, when we would go to anime cons, the average attendee...
Speaker 1: I think it was more mid-2000s.
Speaker 0: No, I'm saying this is before that trend.
Speaker 0: If when I went to anime cons in the late 90s or very early 2000s, the average attendee was about my age.
Speaker 0: I was between 17 and 20, and most of the people there were around that age or older.
Speaker 0: But by the mid-2000s, I'm now older, I'm in my 20s, but yet the average attendee at these cons was like 14, maybe even younger.
Speaker 1: Right, the con scene changed from being more like an old sci-fi con style type of deal with the viewing rooms and all that, into a more cosplay in the hallway, make a ruckus play Marco Polo.
Speaker 1: You know, panels and screening rooms aren't popular.
Speaker 0: Go listen to Geek Nights from like 2005, and we talk about this a lot.
Speaker 0: So long not to make the whole show about the fucking yaoi paddle.
Speaker 0: So they were basically banned.
Speaker 0: There was a moment a few years after they came out where one anime con... I think it was actually Anime Next that banned them first, but I don't remember.
Speaker 0: But I'm pretty sure it was Anime Next, but one con banned them and banned that dealer.
Speaker 0: And then basically over the course of a few weeks, every anime con banned these fucking things.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: I think there was a combination of banning the dealer, banning the specific object, banning various uses of the object, but also I think a lot of people just amended their general cosplay weapons policies such that that object, the yaoi paddle, and anything similar was just encompassed and they didn't need to make sort of specific carve-outs to attack that one thing.
Speaker 0: The news from February, because the company had been like, "This is all gone.
Speaker 0: These things disappeared from the
Speaker 0: world.".
Speaker 1: It was a flash in the pan.
Speaker 1: It lasted maybe a year or two.
Speaker 1: But it was big.
Speaker 0: At the end of February this year, a company did a Kickstarter to bring the yaoi paddle back, and people were really excited about this, and it was getting a ton of pledges right away.
Speaker 0: So, Shot and Chaser, my second news from early March, so about a week later, I'm just going to read the headline.
Speaker 0: It's from the Mary Sue, and we won't dwell on the topic because this article will go into more detail than I even remembered.
Speaker 0: I'm just kidding.
Speaker 0: The headline is, and I quote, "What is a yaoi paddle, and why was its Kickstarter taken
Speaker 0: down?".
Speaker 0: So, the entire...
Speaker 1: Because the inventor of the yaoi paddle, I imagine, sued them.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, the company that original wacky wavy inflatable arm-flailing dude, that whole company... He's still around.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's around, but the company was like, "Uh, we still own the rights to those paddles, guys.
Speaker 0: Your Kickstarter is just illegal and we're going to sue
Speaker 0: you.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, I could find some old super popular thing that was a big hit and start a Kickstarter, right?
Speaker 1: I could be like, "Hey guys, I got a Kickstarter for... I'm bringing back Furbies, guys.
Speaker 1: Furbies.
Speaker 1: Remember those?
Speaker 1: Those were a big hit.
Speaker 1: I'm bringing them back.
Speaker 1: Kickstarter.".
Speaker 1: I'd be like, "Uh, you don't own
Speaker 1: Furbies.".
Speaker 0: So, this entire saga came and went during our Unplanned Geek Nights hiatus.
Speaker 0: So, the news is, you can go learn about this weird flash in the pan and how some weirdos tried to bring it back.
Speaker 0: In some other news, that's a pretty big deal and we're going to link directly to their statement.
Speaker 0: AnimeNext, which has always been a pretty solid AnimeCon.
Speaker 0: We used to go off and on.
Speaker 0: I've done panels at it before.
Speaker 0: They cancelled 2022 for very good reasons and it's actually kind of notable that an AnimeCon was able and willing to do this.
Speaker 0: There's a lot going on here to the point that we won't be able to cover everything related to this topic, but it's a big deal.
Speaker 1: There's so much going on, but AnimeNext is a con that has had its ups and downs, lefts and rights, good times, bad times.
Speaker 1: I went to it, I think, once ever.
Speaker 0: I went a bunch of times.
Speaker 0: I did panels.
Speaker 0: I've added a couple years in a row.
Speaker 1: It was split into multiple buildings.
Speaker 1: It was near Giant Stadium in this Meadowlands-ish place.
Speaker 1: I think it's moved since then.
Speaker 1: It's not there anymore.
Speaker 0: Well, you remember, we talked about it a bunch.
Speaker 0: Remember where it moved to?
Speaker 1: No, I forget.
Speaker 0: Atlantic City.
Speaker 1: Oh.
Speaker 0: It was the beach AnimeCon.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I never went to it, but I remember other people going to it.
Speaker 0: In fact, when it moved to Atlantic City, we got kind of excited because our thinking was we could start going again to do Anime panels there.
Speaker 0: And then just, instead of like Anime Boston, where then we're bored and just wandering around Boston, we just go to the beach when we're not doing panels.
Speaker 0: We were really into it, but for a bunch of reasons.
Speaker 0: Every year we wanted to go to AnimeNext after they moved to Atlantic City.
Speaker 0: There was always some other competing event or some reason we couldn't go and it just never worked out.
Speaker 0: But yeah, they cancelled.
Speaker 0: And they cancelled mostly because, if I had to really summarize it, the venue in Atlantic City tried to fuck them over.
Speaker 0: And they, unlike a lot of AnimeCons, had enough money, had enough moral character, and had enough just pure human fortitude to turn around to the venue that was trying to fuck them over and just tell them to fuck off.
Speaker 0: So they cancelled.
Speaker 0: basically the venue, and you can read all the details, like this thing's really long what I'm going to link to.
Speaker 0: The venue basically tried to, one, raise the prices, and two, basically said, "Yeah, we won't require our staff to wear masks or vaccinations or anything because we're an evil company that doesn't care about
Speaker 0: COVID.".
Speaker 0: And AnimeNext was like, "But we require those
Speaker 0: things.".
Speaker 0: And the venue said, "Well, fuck
Speaker 0: you.".
Speaker 0: And AnimeNext said, "Well, we're not holding AnimeNext anymore.
Speaker 0: It's done.
Speaker 0: You're
Speaker 0: fucked.".
Speaker 0: But the way they went about.
Speaker 0: it is fascinating and you should...
Speaker 1: It wasn't the usual, like, you get in trouble because you didn't uphold your contract deal?
Speaker 0: Yep, they are holding the venue to the letter of their contract.
Speaker 0: They are technically running in AnimeNext, but it is not open to the public.
Speaker 0: It's a tiny little event for their own staff, and it's basically a way to get out of this contract.
Speaker 1: Okay, but don't they still have to pay the venue?
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, but they're paying the minimum they can pay.
Speaker 0: There's no clawbacks.
Speaker 0: They basically will be solvent and they're going to figure out what to do on AnimeNext 2023.
Speaker 0: I'm going to read two sentences from AnimeNext's statement because it really, really says it best.
Speaker 1: You know, because normally you'd think, "Oh, well, if they hold a smaller event, the venue saves money not having to do anything, you know, because it's such a small event, and gets paid as if the event was
Speaker 1: large.".
Speaker 1: But it sounds like that's not what's happening here?
Speaker 0: That is not what's happening.
Speaker 0: Basically, they can run a tiny closed-profile event, which means tons of things they would normally pay the convention center for aren't part of it anymore.
Speaker 1: Oh, so the contract didn't have, like, this large base price for all the square footage.
Speaker 1: It was, like, pay-what-you-use kind of deal?
Speaker 0: Sort of.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to stick to what is on this page because I have learned more from various people who have been emailing me about this, and I don't want to share anything that's not public.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, you can't share that, right?
Speaker 0: But I'll read the statement, "Convention leadership, this is from AnimeNext, doesn't feel it is safe, in good faith, or financially responsible to hold AnimeNext 2022.
Speaker 0: Thus, our decision to call off all public-facing
Speaker 0: attractions.".
Speaker 1: Okay, good.
Speaker 0: "Due to contractual obligations, we are still required to hold an 'event' within the convention center.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, we'd trigger multiple cancellation clauses, which would have a significant negative impact on our ability to have future
Speaker 0: events.".
Speaker 0: That is legalese for "Fuck you!
Speaker 0: Don't let the door hit you on the way
Speaker 0: out!".
Speaker 1: I wonder if they'll do something that, like, makes a mess in the... I mean, that only hurts the staff.
Speaker 1: It doesn't hurt the content, right?
Speaker 0: They said they're basically going to hold a bunch of internal, staff-only workshops, team-building exercises, training.
Speaker 0: Imagine if at Kineticon, we had a weekend where we got all our staff together and just did, like, a dry run and training.
Speaker 1: Well, didn't Otacon do exactly that?
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah.
Speaker 0: In fact, me attending the Otacon training event was the last interaction we had with Otacon before they kicked us off the staff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, PAX used to have the bag stuffing was sort of their event, but then they stopped doing that.
Speaker 0: So, uh, good on ya, Anime Next!
Speaker 0: Like, I absolutely support what you did.
Speaker 0: It sucks that this convention venue was so shitty, is the best way to put it, especially about COVID, considering that, you know, I'm about to go to PAX East for a day.
Speaker 0: PAX East requires vaccinations, masks, and all sorts of nonsense.
Speaker 0: Well, no, good nonsense.
Speaker 0: I say nonsense, but, like, they should be requiring these things.
Speaker 0: Uh, in some other, uh, very, very brief news, Anime Expo, many of you follow the Anime Expo Twitter account, and if you do, you may or may not have gotten @spammed with potentially thousands of notifications, because Anime Expo, an anime con I would never attend, for all the reasons we've talked about over the last 16 years of Geek Nights, uh, they let, they gave their Twitter account to NFT scammers by authorizing shady apps to use their official Twitter account.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whenever you go to, like, something that's like, hey, here's, you go to a website, and it's like, we'll tell you your most popular tweets, authorize us to connect to your Twitter account, and you say yes, well great, now they have, you just gave them permission to tweet on your account, and they start tweeting, right?
Speaker 1: So, uh, it's not, you know, I hate it when people say hacked, or, you know, this isn't even a phishing attack level of hacking, right?
Speaker 1: This was, Anime Expo, let some random app, whoever controls the Anime Expo Twitter account, let some random application access their Twitter account, and it started spamming lots and lots of messages to lots and lots of people.
Speaker 1: They did
Speaker 0: the equivalent of, if I walked out into the street, walked up to a random person, handed them my ATM card, and said, by the way, here's the pin, uh, go start telling me what my bank account is, like the balance is on a weekly basis, and I walked away and completely trusted that nothing bad would happen as a result of this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, anyway.
Speaker 0: So, uh, yeah, don't, don't follow Anime Expo on Twitter, because I don't trust them.
Speaker 0: It's just funny.
Speaker 1: It's just funny.
Speaker 1: And some better news, uh, I haven't actually read more than, like, half a volume of this, but, uh, We have, I think we have all the volumes, but I've only read a few of them.
Speaker 1: Uh, but yeah, Delicious in Dungeon, or Dungeon Meshi, right, is a pretty good manga, with the, you know, it's one of those fun RPG-ish premises where a bunch of characters have a, they're on an actual serious fantasy adventure, at least at the start, to rescue someone's sister.
Speaker 0: Like a D&D, Lotus War kind of thing is going on, basically.
Speaker 1: Right, right, well, they were, they were adventurers, they went into a dungeon, someone's sister got trapped by the bad guy, or something like that, and then they escaped, but she's still in there, and they're like, well, we have to go back in the dungeon, but they're poor, and poorly equipped, and, but they're in a hurry, right, so they go in there, they go back into the dungeon to try, on a rescue mission, and, you know, they don't have, like, good supplies or anything, right?
Speaker 1: But they meet a dude who knows how to live in the dungeon, and cook dungeon things, so it's sort of, like, fake cooking show, almost, where, ah, we killed these mushroom monsters, let me show you how to cook 'em, right?
Speaker 1: And it's all about, you know, so that becomes the focus there, while this, within the greater plot, and it's, you know, it's a very popular and high-quality manga, if you're not, it's really funny.
Speaker 1: So, to no surprise to no one, it is gonna get adapted into an anime that was announced a while ago, but we just haven't done a show in so long that we haven't mentioned it.
Speaker 0: Yup, March 14th was when that was announced.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so, like a month ago.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I'm kinda excited for that, that might get me to sign up for, I'm currently subscribed to absolutely no streaming services, other than Amazon Prime Video, because I still have Amazon Prime, so that might get me to turn one back on.
Speaker 0: Well, that means you can't watch the show.
Speaker 0: I'm about to Geek Bite, so I watched The Orbital Children, which is an anime, I think it's-- Oh, I could've watched that, I had Netflix.
Speaker 0: It's short, it's not that long, it's on Netflix, it's a one-season short anime, it's by the guy who did Dennocoil, which is a fantastic show, and-- Oh, that's also on Netflix.
Speaker 1: This is a
Speaker 0: serious, hard sci-fi set in the near future, it's about AIs, and corporate libertarian dystopia, and the future of NASA, and it is, I think it is the best anime I have seen in, that is not a movie, like the best anime TV show, possibly in years, it was so good.
Speaker 0: My soul geek bite is, I'm not even going to tell you anything more about it, I'll say two things, one, just watch it, there's absolutely no reason not to watch this show, and two, if you have read the E.N.M.
Speaker 0: Banks Culture Books, or if you're a fan of Star Trek, but more the E.N.M.
Speaker 0: Banks Culture Books, it is extremely plausible to say that this is the, like, prequel to the Culture Books.
Speaker 0: Like, how did humans get to that point?
Speaker 0: Like, what happened to humans?
Speaker 0: This show covers a lot of really interesting topics, pretty deeply, and with a lot of nuance, and you will be shocked and surprised at some of the twists that it takes along the way.
Speaker 0: I cannot praise the show enough.
Speaker 1: I think the next anime I'm going to watch, that I want to watch, is this one that a lot of people are hyping up, called YA BOI KANG ME.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, I just saw the trailer to that a couple days ago.
Speaker 1: But apparently, the only legal, the only United States legal streaming source is HIDIVE, which I've never had an account for, so, I think I might either A, get a free trial to HIDIVE, and try to watch it all really quick.
Speaker 0: Because we gotta review the YA BOI KANG ME.
Speaker 1: I don't know if all the episodes are out, so it's like if I get a free trial, it's like I might watch all the episodes, and then the free trial might end before the show finishes, so I gotta see if all the episodes are out.
Speaker 0: Well, I leave it to you to coordinate.
Speaker 0: Tell me when I have to get an account.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or I'll just go ARRRRRRRRR.
Speaker 1: Or maybe there's other things.
Speaker 1: on HIDIVE I want to watch, and I'll pay for an account for a little while, who knows.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just go, I'll link to it, just watch what appears to be the opener to this show, and you don't need to know anything else about it.
Speaker 0: You will know from that opener if you care about this show or not.
Speaker 0: That's all I'm going to say about that.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day, I got a really little thing.
Speaker 0: So this is a tweet with four images in it, but it also links to an AP article.
Speaker 0: So a famous surrealist, photographer, and photo montage person, Jerry Welsman, has died.
Speaker 0: He was 87.
Speaker 0: Basically, he was making, among other things, photoshops before Photoshop existed.
Speaker 0: Just in dark rooms, using what are by modern standards, ancient techniques.
Speaker 0: And his work is honestly breathtaking, and it is amazing what you could do with that kind of technology that a lot of people don't really understand.
Speaker 0: Just look at these images, look up this guy's work.
Speaker 0: This is some pretty fascinating stuff.
Speaker 1: Alright, so in the 90s, if you went to the movie theater, you were always going to be hearing stuff about THX, Dolby Digital.
Speaker 1: Before the 90s, really, when I was really young, movie theaters were just like stereo sound.
Speaker 1: They had big sound systems, but they weren't special in any way.
Speaker 0: Not even as a kid, there was a cheap theater we went to, we knew it was mono, there was one big speaker you could see.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like the idea that movie theaters were going to do this surround sound thing was a new thing in my lifetime at a point that I remember it.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, I remember going to movies where it was advertised like, "This movie is in fucking surround sound at select theaters
Speaker 0: only.".
Speaker 0: And in those theaters, it was like one room had it.
Speaker 1: But now, at the point in my life where I understood technology and cared about technology and thought about technology, to where I understood how that worked, was already a point at which movie theaters just had hard drives.
Speaker 1: It's like if you go to a movie theater today, the movie shows up at the movie theater on some hard drives or whatever, and they stick them in, and they just press play.
Speaker 1: It's no different than what you do at home, only much, much fancier, right?
Speaker 1: It's not compressed and whatnot, right?
Speaker 1: They got a fancy projector, et cetera, et cetera.
Speaker 1: But I never really thought about how the hell did Dolby Digital work in 1993, 4, something like that, right?
Speaker 1: It's like they had Dolby Digital surround sound then, how did they deliver that to the movie theater?
Speaker 1: And if you had asked me that question before I knew the answer, right, which was my favorite day of the year.
Speaker 0: I weirdly did know the answer, but not that long ago, and for weird reasons I learned this.
Speaker 1: If you had asked me prior to me seeing this thing of the day, which I saw not that too long ago, I would have said, "Well, I guess they must have sent some sort of DAT tapes, like in one for each channel, and they must have pressed
Speaker 1: play.".
Speaker 1: Or they pressed play on them all at the same time, and they synchronized them somehow, right?
Speaker 0: See, that's a load-bearing somehow, because doing that is literally almost impossible.
Speaker 1: It is indeed impossible, but I couldn't, you know, what other way could I think of doing, right?
Speaker 1: I mean, they're quadraphonic vinyl records, I guess, however those work, right?
Speaker 1: Or you have multiple tracks on like a really wide magnetic tape, I guess, they could have done that.
Speaker 0: But of course, that even opens the question of how is the audio even encoded before it was digital on film?
Speaker 0: Which is also answered by your thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Well, there were a lot of movies, well, back in, there were movie theaters where you would just have a separate, you know, you had the film, and then you had the audio on a separate, you know, recording, and you would play them both at the same time, right?
Speaker 0: That actually was rare or nonexistent, and usually that was solely music.
Speaker 1: Right, and those silent films, you had a person just fucking play in music while the movie was playing.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so apparently the way it works, which is obvious once you see it, is in the space on the side of the film, that's not, you know, that's not showing up, you know, on the screen in front of you.
Speaker 0: Like literally where the little teeth are.
Speaker 1: Right, they're called the sprockets, right?
Speaker 1: So basically in between the sprockets and also next to the sprockets is more space that's unused, right?
Speaker 1: You don't see that, that's not showing up on the screen.
Speaker 1: So they just encode digital audio data and time synchronization data in what looks like QR codes in that space, and then there's a, while the projector is playing the film, there's an optical device that's shining through those, you know, little, you know, basically two-dimensional barcodes on the side of the film.
Speaker 0: So 24 QR codes per second.
Speaker 1: Right, they're sending that digital data to basic, a special computer that decodes it, and then that decoding device connects to the amplifiers, which then connect to the sound system.
Speaker 0: Alright, 96 QR codes per second, each of which includes a bunch of digital data.
Speaker 1: Yep, exactly.
Speaker 1: So my thing of the day is, you know, basically it's like they went out and they got the cheapest old film they could get, which is basically like trailers, right?
Speaker 1: And you know, it's like a full explanation here of like exactly how many bits are in there, kind of how it's encoded.
Speaker 1: If you go on YouTube, you actually saw a video.
Speaker 1: someone had one of the decoding machines, they got real cheap because who the hell needs one of those anymore, right?
Speaker 1: And showed you how it worked and everything.
Speaker 1: And it's like, it's really obvious when you see it, but it's also a genius and it's not something a lot of people have seen.
Speaker 1: Because it's sort of a technology that existed at that moment and now is gone, right?
Speaker 0: In the meta moment, the Geek Nights Book Club book is Nine Fox Gambit.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So yeah, the listener really wanted us to read this book.
Speaker 1: I read it already, now Rym's gonna read it, then a bunch of other listeners gonna read it, and then we're gonna talk about it in a few months from now.
Speaker 1: It's a sci-fi space book with a rocket ship on a space station.
Speaker 1: on the cover of the book, and there's space battles, but of course there's also a lot of allegories involving pretty much everything.
Speaker 1: Democracy, time, calendars, solipsism, immortality, morality, just so much is going on there.
Speaker 0: All the good sci-fi stuff.
Speaker 1: All the good things you have in a serious sci-fi book that wins and is or nominated for many awards.
Speaker 1: And there's also more books in this series, so I haven't read any of them.
Speaker 1: But knowing Rym, if we look historically, every time I've chosen a book club book that is in a series, Rym immediately reads the entire series, and even though I'm the one who chose it, I get maybe part way through, or I just stop immediately.
Speaker 1: I don't know how this happens.
Speaker 0: I consciously chose to read a couple more books of The Wheel of Time.
Speaker 0: You even read a couple more books.
Speaker 1: I picked Wheel of Time.
Speaker 1: Didn't I pick Wheel of Time?
Speaker 0: You did, and you even read a couple more books.
Speaker 1: I read three or four Wheel of Times.
Speaker 1: You read every Wheel of Time.
Speaker 0: So I consciously chose to read the next three or four, but then I woke up from a fugue state and I read them all.
Speaker 1: Somehow.
Speaker 0: I don't regret it.
Speaker 1: You read every culture book.
Speaker 1: I read like two and a half.
Speaker 0: You should read more culture books.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 0: So, use of weapons in the chair.
Speaker 0: There's a thing going on in the Ukraine war that Ukraine is basically wielding the chair as a weapon right now.
Speaker 0: There's a really interesting information war that is happening right now in real life.
Speaker 0: that is directly analogous to what happens in use of weapons.
Speaker 1: In other Metamoment news, I have made significant progress on the new Geek Nights website.
Speaker 0: And I replaced the blue one that is up on the screen right now.
Speaker 1: Yes, and so I'm not shit talking here.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to set a deadline.
Speaker 1: But what I will say is that the chunk of work that I have just completed is the largest individual chunk.
Speaker 1: All the remaining chunks added together are probably still greater than the amount of work that I've done.
Speaker 1: So I guess I'm not halfway there yet.
Speaker 1: But all of those remaining chunks are individually smaller than the chunk I just completed.
Speaker 1: Therefore, I should be able to, you know, do each one in like, you know, some set of hours each and move things right along.
Speaker 1: The next thing I'm doing is, you know, the most requested, most important functionality of actually being able to search.
Speaker 1: So I hope you're excited for that.
Speaker 1: A good search for the podcast is, you know, there's only so many episodes to search through.
Speaker 1: It's not like a Google-level difficult search problem.
Speaker 0: And also, none of you have that.
Speaker 0: Like, I have access to the current backend.
Speaker 0: I can search for Geek Nights episodes way better than you can.
Speaker 1: We're going to do a better search than that.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, we are.
Speaker 0: But that's working out okay for now.
Speaker 0: But the listener has even less.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the listener doesn't have that.
Speaker 0: What's funny, if I Google, if I just Google for, like, things like Geek Nights and, like, not Sitefrontrecruit.com, but like Geek Nights and topics we've done, usually what I find is the old Geek Nights forum.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's out there.
Speaker 0: So, uh, no.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, we'll get right into it.
Speaker 0: So if you're not familiar with Tatsuki Fujimoto, you're probably familiar with Chainsaw Man, which is a, if you've heard of it, it's a pretty popular manga coming up to its conclusion.
Speaker 1: We did an episode on it already.
Speaker 1: It's also going to get an anime adaptation.
Speaker 1: It's also done.
Speaker 1: I've read every volume of it.
Speaker 1: The final English volume of Chainsaw Man is coming out in two months.
Speaker 1: If you want to order it, you order it right now because, you know, from either, you know, from your comic book store or wherever.
Speaker 1: It's available for pre-order immediately.
Speaker 1: It'll be here in a couple months.
Speaker 1: And that would be the last English volume.
Speaker 1: If you can read Japanese, you can read all of Chainsaw Man right now.
Speaker 1: Or, if you get piracy, I'm sure you can read it all right now as well.
Speaker 0: So, the mangaka released a one-shot single manga.
Speaker 0: It's like 200 pages.
Speaker 0: It's one story.
Speaker 1: It's 200 pages, but they go by fast.
Speaker 1: I read it, like, right before work one day.
Speaker 1: It didn't take long.
Speaker 0: Oh, I think the link was posted.
Speaker 0: I don't know if you posted it.
Speaker 0: Someone posted it in the forum, I think.
Speaker 0: And I was like, "Ooh, what's
Speaker 0: this?".
Speaker 0: And I just clicked through it, and then I was done.
Speaker 0: And I was laughing out loud, and then I went to our Discord to be like,
Speaker 0: "Hey!".
Speaker 0: And everyone was reading it, and it was already a thing.
Speaker 0: So, goodbye, Eri.
Speaker 0: We're not going to spoil anything, but what I'll say is this.
Speaker 0: There are some content warnings about it, where maybe some people may not want to read it.
Speaker 0: But if you are capable of reading it, I absolutely recommend you just go read it without knowing anything about it.
Speaker 0: It covers a lot of ground.
Speaker 0: It is a fascinating story.
Speaker 0: It surprised me several times.
Speaker 0: It's sad.
Speaker 0: It's also extremely hilarious.
Speaker 0: But content warning.
Speaker 0: It involves suicide.
Speaker 0: It involves the death of loved ones, the death of parents.
Speaker 0: It involves serious illness.
Speaker 0: It involves bullying.
Speaker 0: This is not light subject matter, despite the fact that it is literally hilarious.
Speaker 0: So, goodbye, Eri.
Speaker 0: If I had to describe it, it kind of just starts out in the middle of the story.
Speaker 0: And the framing is interesting because almost all the panels are laid out like it is someone holding a cell phone and capturing what's happening around them, because that is literally what this manga is.
Speaker 0: It is the story of a kid capturing events around him through his cell phone, almost living his life through capturing the events in the cell phone.
Speaker 0: And occasionally, you get large spreads, like large showings of what has happened around this kid, not through the cell phone.
Speaker 0: Like big single page or multi-page spreads.
Speaker 0: And what it's about is a kid whose mom and dad have asked him to video everything that happens in their mom's life because the mom is dying of a terminal illness.
Speaker 0: And she wants there to be a record of her life and a record of her interactions with her kid.
Speaker 0: And that's basically what this thing is about.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, I think, you know, you read this thing and it's like, there's just some sort of, you know, in one sense, it's a little bit cliche in the sort of, right, you know, it's a manga, but it's, you know, a movie within a movie within a movie deal, right?
Speaker 0: You see this happen a lot whether, you know, there's the itself, there's the story being told within the cell phone in the manga.
Speaker 0: But then there's the movie that is actually made by the kid via the cell phone in the manga.
Speaker 1: Right, you know, you've got whether it's like fucking, you know, singing in the rain, right?
Speaker 1: Or it's...
Speaker 0: But then there's also the girl he meets who is watching movies with him in the manga where he is making movies about that.
Speaker 0: There's layers here.
Speaker 1: And then, of course, you know, there's Paprika and then there's Inception, which, you know, he wasn't allowed to make live action Paprika, so he made Inception instead, right?
Speaker 1: You know, all that stuff.
Speaker 0: Even Millennium Actress with the blurring of fantasy and reality or film and reality.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's a lot like that.
Speaker 1: where, you know, this sort of like, are you watching the recording now?
Speaker 1: Or is there a recording of him making a recording of something else and you're watching that, right?
Speaker 1: You know, watching even though it's a manga, right?
Speaker 0: It's ambiguous at many points.
Speaker 0: Many things will happen and you will think to yourself, did that happen in his movie?
Speaker 0: Did it happen in the real world?
Speaker 0: or did it happen in other frame of reference?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: And it's not resolved.
Speaker 1: There are certain frames that are obviously, you know, in a film on some layer, right?
Speaker 1: Where, you know, there's something happens in that frame that is clearly supernatural or unrealistic.
Speaker 1: And so you have to assume that that's not something that happened in the real world, even though the entire work is a work of fiction, right?
Speaker 1: None of it's in the real, real world.
Speaker 1: But, you know, if there is a base real world on which all of, you know, in the fiction, right, on which those things are resting.
Speaker 1: But there are some things that are clearly not happening in it and some that are or some that are presented as if they are and that are immediately revealed not to be.
Speaker 1: It's like someone will be doing something and you'll think it's a real scene.
Speaker 1: And then immediately the next page, it's like the cell phone is in the shot and the person is like, did I do a good acting job?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And also some of the frames will be like blurry or at the wrong angle or off center, but then other things will be extremely like well framed and in focus.
Speaker 1: Well, and sometimes like that person who just said, you know, they did a good acting job, but also you get the idea that they were what they were acting was not just something that was, you know, I guess in the fiction written for them, but was, you know, a reenactment of something real that happened that just wasn't captured on film when it happened originally.
Speaker 1: And so they're reenacting their own lives for the recording because, you know, the person wrote the movie based on their own life.
Speaker 1: So they want to, you know, but they didn't capture their own life on film at the time.
Speaker 1: So they want to have the people in their life acted out again.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: To get on film to make the movie out of.
Speaker 0: But even better, you get the impression that some of the scenes like that.
Speaker 0: Imagine if you're watching a movie that had acted scenes, reenacted scenes and actual for real footage all mixed together and the movie did not tell you which is which.
Speaker 1: And the movie was actually, you know, live, like happening live.
Speaker 1: But just some of the time they cut away from the live camera and they aim the live camera at a screen that was showing some other movie.
Speaker 0: So I'm going to spoil one thing that happens on page like live, like Broadway theater live.
Speaker 0: Page 18 is where this goes from.
Speaker 0: I am intrigued to.
Speaker 0: I'm reading this to the end right now.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: So it's a minor, minor spoiler.
Speaker 0: But just read this thing.
Speaker 0: So, you know, it starts out.
Speaker 0: this kid is asked by his mom and dad to record his mom's life and you get a really interesting story about it.
Speaker 0: It's poignant.
Speaker 0: It's interesting.
Speaker 0: It's sad.
Speaker 0: There's one moment where it shows the parents asleep and the dialogue is just like dad's asleep, mom's too.
Speaker 0: And then it's quiet for a while.
Speaker 0: And then the kid recording just says, I'm keeping watch in case she dies in her sleep and things like that are happening.
Speaker 0: or dad's crying in secret.
Speaker 0: Mom's about to poo and mom's like, you're not filming this.
Speaker 0: But eventually, like the mom dies, of course, like there's a hospital situation.
Speaker 0: And on page 18, like you're reading this.
Speaker 0: and then on page 18, he runs out of the hospital screaming and crying.
Speaker 1: Well, you missed an important part.
Speaker 1: The mom really wanted him to film the mom dying.
Speaker 0: True Klingon.
Speaker 1: She was like, she's like, she's like, I really need you to fill the moment I die.
Speaker 1: And the kid couldn't do it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: He runs away from the hospital.
Speaker 1: Instead of filming his mom dying, he runs away from the hospital.
Speaker 1: And at that moment, it's like, wait, who's filming this?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So on page 18, you know, page 17, he is running away from the hospital.
Speaker 0: Well, page 16, he, you see a blurry cell phone footage of his feet as he's running away from the hospital.
Speaker 0: Clearly is holding the phone.
Speaker 0: Page 17, you see a shot of him from the front that's perfectly framed and in focus.
Speaker 0: And he's running towards you away from the hospital.
Speaker 0: Page 18, the hospital explodes behind him.
Speaker 1: And it's like, what did he, did he blow up the hospital?
Speaker 0: And that is the tip of the iceberg of where this thing's going.
Speaker 1: It's it, it goes, it goes wild because the ending is amazing.
Speaker 0: I will not even tell you what page 20 shows, but it zooms out even further to something.
Speaker 0: And this there, this manga covers a lot of topics and a lot of ground from that point on.
Speaker 0: And I feel in retrospect, when we got to the very end, I did not even remotely expect what I was going to see at the end of this manga.
Speaker 0: And when I read the last page, I was laughing so hard, I almost choked.
Speaker 0: I was just dumbstruck.
Speaker 0: I was so caught up in what was going on.
Speaker 0: I was absolutely dumbstruck by the last page of this manga.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So, I mean, you know, Chainsaw Man was not Fujimoto's first manga, but it was, you know, I guess their biggest, right?
Speaker 1: It's the one getting an anime adaptation.
Speaker 1: They have some other manga.
Speaker 1: There was one called Fire Punch and one called another, another one shot, one called Look Back.
Speaker 1: that they did.
Speaker 1: And then there was this one.
Speaker 1: And I think, you know, this one, I guess we're talking about it because it's available in English for free and you can read it quickly.
Speaker 1: So we did.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But I'm really curious to read those other two that aren't Chainsaw Man.
Speaker 1: And I think, you know, this person isn't even 30 years old yet, Tatsuki Fujimoto.
Speaker 1: But clearly they're in this, you know, realm of, you know, you know, I don't know if you can consider them a new manga artist since they've been at it for at least some amount of time, but definitely they have become hot.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: They're a big deal.
Speaker 1: Everything I've seen that they've made is on another level of, you know, amazingness.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it's at like the, you know, S tier of amazingness, but it's better than all the other new mangas I'm seeing around.
Speaker 0: Well, like Chainsaw Man intrigued me just from the beginning and just goes to the crazy town.
Speaker 0: I hoped and expected it to go.
Speaker 0: But this one, this one shot, you know what it reminds me of a little bit?
Speaker 0: Of Urasawa's manga.
Speaker 0: It's got some Urasawa type elements to it, but it's not, it's hard to really dig into that without spoiling both Monster and this one off.
Speaker 1: But, you know, I think the difference is, is that, you know, this has, uh, I guess Urasawa still tells a direct, straightforward story.
Speaker 1: Urasawa does not blur the fiction in reality.
Speaker 0: Urasawa has an absolutely reliable external, created a solid universe.
Speaker 1: There are weird things happening in that universe, right?
Speaker 1: People, you know, unrealistic things, mysterious things.
Speaker 0: But the camera you're looking at that universe through, the pages on the, the panels on his pages are just an absolute look at the reality of that world.
Speaker 1: Yes, and they're always, you know, from this narrator perspective, right?
Speaker 1: Not from any character's perspective or anything like that.
Speaker 0: I'm saying more in terms of some of the ways the characters talk and a lot of the way the panel composition and framing is of certain scenes, the way certain scenes linger.
Speaker 0: There are definitely some Urasawa elements.
Speaker 0: Also, the character designs remind me of some of Urasawa's character designs a little bit.
Speaker 0: A little more angular, a little more pointy.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so yeah, I guess there's not really that much to say because it's just a one-shot, 200-page manga that doesn't take long at all to read.
Speaker 0: And you should absolutely read it.
Speaker 1: But yeah, for zero dollars in English digitally, absolutely everyone who can hear my voice right now should be reading this.
Speaker 1: There's really no reason not to.
Speaker 1: The end.
Speaker 1: And also, whatever Tatsuki Fujimoto makes, right, is a key, you know, when you're buying comics or you're looking for comics to read, remember that name, look for it, and see what they're up to because it's probably, you know, they're on the right track of making the high-quality stuff.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And the Patreon patrons for this particular episode of Geek Nights are... And several people whose names I will not say at their specific request.
Speaker 0: So yeah, gonna be at PAX just on Thursday.
Speaker 0: Walk the floor, do one panel.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, we'll resume normal shows next week.
Speaker 0: Might skip a show on Tuesday because I think we have another hockey game.
Speaker 0: And for now, I simply leave you with... So, you want a realistic, down-to-earth show that's completely off the wall and swarming with magic robots?
Speaker 1: That's right!
Speaker 1: You should win things by watching!
Speaker 1: You kids don't know what you want!
Speaker 0: That's why you're still kids, 'cause you're stupid!
Speaker 1: Just tell me what's wrong with the freaking show!