Speaker 1: It's Wednesday, May 18th, 2022.
Speaker 1: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight, we talk about voice acting and voice actors and that whole space.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So tonight begins the second round of the Stanley Cup playoffs for the New York Rangers.
Speaker 0: Well, we're gonna lose, almost definitely.
Speaker 1: Scott is obligated to say that for fear of angering various gods, I guess.
Speaker 0: Well, no.
Speaker 0: In this case, I actually don't.
Speaker 0: If you watched, I saw all three or four games.
Speaker 0: I don't remember how many.
Speaker 0: We played against this team this season.
Speaker 0: It was four.
Speaker 0: Not crushed like every time.
Speaker 0: The one game we won was because Georgia had some amazing shutout.
Speaker 0: The other three games, they completely dominated us.
Speaker 0: I saw two of those games in person.
Speaker 0: We just got crushed.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: They are the rock to our scissors.
Speaker 0: But you know what?
Speaker 0: I don't care.
Speaker 0: I am happy to have just made it this far.
Speaker 1: I mean, the game seven that we just watched, what was the prize?
Speaker 1: At least four more hockey games.
Speaker 0: That was, yeah, but two of them at home, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like.
Speaker 0: all I wanted was some playoff games at MSG.
Speaker 0: I got more than I expected to get.
Speaker 0: And I am satisfied and my expectations have been fulfilled.
Speaker 0: And anything from here on out is just bonus gravy.
Speaker 0: I'll be thrilled if we get even more.
Speaker 0: But I don't, I'm okay because the sooner it ends, right?
Speaker 0: It's like a win-win either way at this point, right?
Speaker 0: If we keep going, obviously that's a win because we win more, right?
Speaker 0: That's great.
Speaker 0: But if we lose, the sooner we lose, A, the sooner I can just stop spending my nights watching hockey and do something else.
Speaker 0: Enjoy this nice weather, go outside or whatever.
Speaker 0: And B, that'll save us a lot of money.
Speaker 0: Because every time the Rangers make more games happen at home, the garden comes and just takes money from us because we clicked.
Speaker 0: And we clicked a button that said yes, you can do that.
Speaker 1: And that amount of money goes up.
Speaker 1: As deeper it gets, the more that number goes up.
Speaker 0: And as soon as there stop being more games, I can get rimmed to compensate me for most of that money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because I might have used a significant percentage of those tickets.
Speaker 0: I looked at the numbers and sadly, it's not going to be so straightforward to calculate how much money you have to give me.
Speaker 0: But I came up with a formula that I think is fair.
Speaker 1: Oh, because we don't know the price of the individual games anymore or something like that?
Speaker 0: So, I mean, no one listening gives a shit.
Speaker 0: But basically, we know the prices of the playoff games exactly, right?
Speaker 0: The prices of the regular season games, if we divide the total amount paid by the number of games, including preseason games, then there is a number.
Speaker 0: But last season, when it ended early because of the pandemic, there were three games of six total tickets in which we were compensated for those games with credit to the current season.
Speaker 0: And the amount credited was more per ticket than an even division of the total price.
Speaker 0: So that means that we don't know the actual face value of all the tickets.
Speaker 0: I could just assume that that price is the price of the regular tickets and then price down the preseason tickets.
Speaker 0: But then we've also got to worry about.
Speaker 0: there were games where we sold the tickets to third parties and we got random amounts of money.
Speaker 0: And there were games that we gave away for free to people, right?
Speaker 0: And there were also free gift card monies that you used entirely to buy one jersey.
Speaker 0: So you owe us back two-thirds of the gift card monies.
Speaker 0: So with all those things combined, I think I have to deploy a percentage-based formula for the non-playoff games.
Speaker 1: It's probably close enough.
Speaker 1: So the first game at home, I guess, will be on Sunday at like 3.30 p.m.
Speaker 1: In the news.
Speaker 1: So last time I went to Anime Central was 2003, is what I want to say.
Speaker 0: Four lifetimes ago.
Speaker 1: I went in 2002.
Speaker 1: I went again in 2003.
Speaker 1: There were some of the best anime cons I've ever been to for a lot of reasons.
Speaker 1: Never bothered going back, but I'd always heard until yesterday with this news good things about Anime Central.
Speaker 1: It was one of the larger anime cons, like one of the biggest ones in the Midwest.
Speaker 0: I can imagine if we lived in the Midwest, that would have been like our Otacon instead of Otacon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it seems like it was big and solid and just continuing to get better, just like pretty much all anime cons were.
Speaker 0: Or maybe it would have been our anime Boston, you know, but anyway.
Speaker 1: So what happened?
Speaker 0: Or Anime NYC.
Speaker 0: Which I've never been to.
Speaker 1: As you know, there is a global pandemic continuing.
Speaker 1: It's killed a million people here.
Speaker 0: It's gotten worse.
Speaker 1: In fact, it's getting worse and worse and worse right now.
Speaker 1: A bunch of my coworkers have it.
Speaker 0: I have some ill coworkers and I am now again hiding.
Speaker 0: I'm only doing inside activities, outside activities, and going to hockey games with the most ridiculous, most powerful mask that hurts my face.
Speaker 1: But even now, so one of my coworkers got it right around when I got it, even though I didn't interact with him like a couple months ago.
Speaker 1: He just got it again.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: So anyway, pretty much all fan conventions, except for Paxis and a handful of others, have basically dropped all of their vaccine requirements and mask mandates and basically anything that was even making them remotely safer.
Speaker 1: Can't say safe.
Speaker 0: Even Paxis.
Speaker 1: Which did everything as well as you can do it, still had one of the staff die of COVID.
Speaker 0: Right, Paxis killed somebody, right?
Speaker 0: It's like someone made a thread that was basically, I was going to write something along those lines of Paxis killed somebody, which is absolutely true, but someone else wrote it even more angrily than I did, right?
Speaker 0: Which is like, you know, it's like no, even the best gaming convention in the universe, right, is not worth, you know, to make it happen, the price of somebody dying before they would have died otherwise is too high a price to pay for just about anything.
Speaker 0: So outside of COVID situations- Let alone just some gaming con.
Speaker 1: So does that apply to non-COVID things like someone trips in the stairwell?
Speaker 0: I mean, it depends.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know- Someone gets drunk at the con and drunk drives and dies?
Speaker 0: The difference here is that you know that- Oh yeah, yeah, COVID- By having the convention, you are creating, you know, this particular scenario of a large amount of people in an enclosed space while the, you know, a deadly virus is there.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, the conditions for someone falling down a stairwell exist everywhere there are stairwells, right?
Speaker 0: That stairwell person might have fallen down the stairwell in their home or their office or a business or wherever, right, if they didn't come to the con.
Speaker 0: That condition is just existing because stairs are a thing.
Speaker 0: But by creating the con, you are creating a new dangerous circumstance that would not have otherwise existed.
Speaker 1: So, I have one other question because this is the question everyone's gonna have to grapple with and I do not think that I'm arguing anything here in particular.
Speaker 1: But based on what the CDC's been saying, this might be as good as it gets forever.
Speaker 1: It's entirely possible.
Speaker 1: And if that's true, then the choice becomes are there cons again at all or not, full stop, with this being the deadly environment.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, if there's...
Speaker 1: Like, what if COVID is just endemic forever because of all the failures of governments?
Speaker 0: Well, endemic is different from what we have now, right?
Speaker 1: Well, it might not get better than this.
Speaker 1: This might be what it looks like when it's endemic.
Speaker 1: There's two or three waves a year, there's booster shots one or two times a year, but they're not 100% effective, and there's just people die of it for the rest of our lives.
Speaker 0: I mean, that could be a thing.
Speaker 1: That seems to be the most likely course.
Speaker 0: Let's say that, you know, tornadoes come through once a day and that's just a thing, right?
Speaker 0: Everywhere.
Speaker 0: There's no hiding from it.
Speaker 0: It's an earth-wide thing.
Speaker 0: Wherever you live on earth, tornadoes...
Speaker 1: I mean, that's kind of what it was like in the summer when I was in Michigan as a kid.
Speaker 0: Right, but I mean, I'm saying everywhere.
Speaker 0: There's no running.
Speaker 0: There's no living somewhere else as an alternative, right?
Speaker 0: So in that case, it's like, well, you hide in the basement once a day, right?
Speaker 0: That's what you would just do, right?
Speaker 0: It's like to avoid the once a day tornado, you would hide in the basement once a day.
Speaker 1: So what if it could come at any time?
Speaker 1: Then you're not going to like stay home.
Speaker 0: You have to be prepared to get to a basement at any time and expect to use the basement once a day.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: It's just unless you are, you're not going to just walk around.
Speaker 0: You're not going to say, "Tornadoes every fucking day.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: Today, I'm going to stay outside when the tornado
Speaker 0: comes.".
Speaker 0: That's your last day, right?
Speaker 0: You're not going to do that.
Speaker 0: So if COVID is just like this for the rest of our lives, you're not just going to go and eat inside at a restaurant, right?
Speaker 0: It's like we're going to change our, hopefully change our society.
Speaker 1: I don't think we will, though.
Speaker 1: I am very confident society will literally 100% give up if that's true.
Speaker 0: Well, if COVID really does stay like this for a long enough period of time... The people who give up, right, will die.
Speaker 1: Up off percentage of the world.
Speaker 0: Eventually, the people who are left are the people who aren't the give up people.
Speaker 1: Not necessarily.
Speaker 1: The death rates are not that high to cause that type of outcome.
Speaker 0: But who knows?
Speaker 0: It could be a strain that comes through, right?
Speaker 0: We never know.
Speaker 0: The point is, I'm not going to stop.
Speaker 0: If tornadoes came every day, even if for 10 years, 20 years, I would never go outside during the tornado.
Speaker 1: Alright, so I just have a question for you.
Speaker 1: If it's about, not the current spike, but the otherwise general background, if it stays around this level forever, will you ever go to a con again or you'd never go to a con again?
Speaker 0: I guess it's going to depend, right?
Speaker 0: Unlike the daily tornado, there could be circumstances in which the convention... Okay, they had the convention during a time when the numbers are mega low, and the circumstances of the convention are good.
Speaker 0: The convention itself is going to be so good that it's worth going to, etc.
Speaker 1: Because one thing that's almost definitely not going to happen, I doubt any cons will have masks or vaccine mandates by next year.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, we're going to Madison Square Garden for three hours.
Speaker 0: There's no mask mandate, but I wear the most serious mask available, and so far it's worked.
Speaker 1: And we're also some of the only people who are wearing masks in the whole arena.
Speaker 0: Right, so it works even though it's a one-way mask.
Speaker 1: Well, TVD, if it works or not, we might just be lucky.
Speaker 1: so far.
Speaker 0: It works so far.
Speaker 0: That's why I said so far.
Speaker 1: Anyway, Anime Central is in a unique case, and they have fucked up badly.
Speaker 1: This is like an unrecoverable situation.
Speaker 1: So they had vaccine requirements, like PAX does, and they had a mask requirement, and they were going to do their event.
Speaker 1: They're still going to do their event.
Speaker 1: They had announced officially, weeks ago, that to clarify, because people were worried that the rules would change, that the rules would not change before the con.
Speaker 1: That masks were going to be required, and the vaccine checks were going to happen.
Speaker 1: Yesterday, maybe two days ago, they officially announced that they're dropping the mask mandate, and they're dropping the vaccine requirement, and they're not giving refunds to anyone.
Speaker 0: Well, see, forget, you know, passing about the discussion about, you know, putting lives at risk to just have an anime con, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, if you have a thing, and you sell the thing, and then you change your mind about what the thing is after you sold it.
Speaker 1: And the thing has a disclaimer saying that they can basically screw you over without any recourse at any time.
Speaker 1: Every convention in terms of service has something like that.
Speaker 0: They do indeed, but invoking such a clause still makes you a piece of shit, regardless.
Speaker 0: It's like, yes, legally, you can do this, but the fact that you did this, go fuck yourself.
Speaker 1: Now, they're doing it with the same rationale that every other nerd convention did it with.
Speaker 1: The government let us do it, so we're good.
Speaker 1: Well, they're not even saying it.
Speaker 1: They're saying the government changed its guidelines, and the convention center is following those, so we have no choice but to follow those.
Speaker 0: They could have done what AnimeNext did.
Speaker 1: Now, what it appears, one thing that might be going on, it sounds like- AnimeNext did something different, didn't they?
Speaker 1: AnimeNext has a very different contract.
Speaker 0: I am aware, but I'm just saying.
Speaker 1: Yes, but it looks like the convention center also said, "We're not gonna make our staff wear masks, nor are we gonna help you with your mask
Speaker 1: bullshit.".
Speaker 0: That's the Midwest.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So, the only thing I really gotta say about this is, if you bought a badge to AnimeCentral, and you feel uncomfortable going now because of this ridiculous change, which is extra egregious considering they specifically said they would not do this, I would suggest you Google something called "credit card chargeback," and that is how you get a refund.
Speaker 1: Thanks to the terms, right.
Speaker 1: The con might ban you for life, but if enough of you do that, you're basically gonna ban AnimeCentral for life.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, you know, the terms of service of the ticket purchase, right, the terms and conditions, I guess, because it's not an internet service or whatever, but it's like, you're not gonna be able to go to small claims court to get the money back, right?
Speaker 1: But, chargeback on the credit card- Oh, you almost definitely could go to small claims court and get the money back, because a convention like this, there is no universe where they show up to small claims court and you get- That's a good point.
Speaker 0: But if they do show up, you're probably gonna lose, because they'll just point out the term and that's it, right?
Speaker 0: There's no refund.
Speaker 0: But, I guess if the judge is ornery, the judge might read that term on their own and say, "It says no refund.
Speaker 0: Get out of
Speaker 0: here.".
Speaker 0: But, yeah, if they don't show up, there is a good chance you just win by default, because the judges just do that.
Speaker 0: Especially if a thousand- I'm not a lawyer, I don't know.
Speaker 1: Especially if thousands of nerds all sue them to small claims court simultaneously.
Speaker 0: The credit card chargeback is much easier, right?
Speaker 1: And the credit card company will pretty much have your back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the only penalty for that is gonna be that, you know, you get banned from Anime Central.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It is possible.
Speaker 1: Anime Central could, like, basically sue you and try to send collections after you via the credit card and dispute it.
Speaker 0: For the price of one- It would cost them more to send the collection person to- It absolutely would.
Speaker 0: The money that they would get back for the price of one ticket.
Speaker 0: Also, you could just get a different credit card or a friend to buy tickets to a future Anime Central.
Speaker 1: Yeah, also, in my experience, it is- All I will say is that I have, many times in my younger, poorer life, been at anime conventions without a badge and no one has ever noticed.
Speaker 1: But, anyway, the broader picture that you'll have to start thinking about is, this is pretty much, I'm confident, the last year.
Speaker 1: any conventions are gonna even have the pretense of taking measures against COVID.
Speaker 1: And everyone's gonna have to collectively decide how they're gonna proceed in terms of gatherings of any kind.
Speaker 1: And based on the numbers I've seen, conventions have not seen that much of a drop-off in attendance this year so far, compared to pre-COVID times.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, somewhere, right, there's a COVID virus factory and it's like rubbing its hand.
Speaker 0: It's like, "Yes, I played the long game.
Speaker 0: Yes, it is now
Speaker 0: working.".
Speaker 1: But there is this situation where the ship might have sailed and society has to decide how they want to live.
Speaker 1: And I just can't imagine a future if, five years from now, masks were still required.
Speaker 1: I think most people completely give up, regardless of the risks and consequences.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 1: In some other news, this looks like an I-Nu-Oh trailer that you just sent me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we've been talking about I-Nu-Oh for a while, 'cause you know we're always waiting for big-time anime theatrical movies to come.
Speaker 0: Those are our favorites.
Speaker 1: Especially by the big directors like Yuasa, Makoto Shinkai.
Speaker 0: Especially since I haven't watched a new TV anime in quite a while.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, you didn't watch Orbital Children, the best anime I've seen in at least six years.
Speaker 1: Also Arkane, the best cartoon I've seen in the last decade.
Speaker 0: We've been waiting for I-Nu-Oh for a while.
Speaker 0: We've known about it for a few years now.
Speaker 0: It's finally imminent, like next month imminent.
Speaker 0: And here is a, sorta I guess a trailer, right?
Speaker 0: With no English subtitles or dub or anything.
Speaker 0: For that movie, and now you can really, this more than any clip I've seen previously, really tells you what the movie is gonna be like and about.
Speaker 0: And it seems pretty hype, and I wanna see it.
Speaker 0: Masaaki Yuasa has been terrific in almost everything that he's done.
Speaker 1: Yuasa is already one of those greats.
Speaker 1: I would wanna show you, when I say Batt in a Thousand, I have to look at the list.
Speaker 1: Real close to Batt in a Thousand.
Speaker 0: Also of note, I didn't send Rim a Link for this, but there was Shin Godzilla, the live action movie directed by Anno, which was maybe the best or second best Godzilla movie thing ever made.
Speaker 0: It was really good.
Speaker 0: I loved it, anyway.
Speaker 0: Most people I know loved it.
Speaker 0: I guess there might be some who didn't, but whatever.
Speaker 0: And there's been teasers coming through that they're gonna make a whole universe of like, Shin whatever, right?
Speaker 0: Shin Ultraman, Shin Kamen Rider, right?
Speaker 1: Expand this, give me Shin Snatch.
Speaker 0: That's not a... But anyway, Shin Ultraman came out.
Speaker 0: It is in the theaters in Japan now, and it is number one at the box office.
Speaker 0: So, bring me the Shin Ultraman with English subtitles, quickly.
Speaker 0: I never even... I can say I know what Ultraman is, but I've never watched an episode or a movie or anything of Ultraman ever.
Speaker 0: I just know what Ultraman is and what he looks like and what his deal is because I'm a nerd.
Speaker 0: But I still want to watch this movie.
Speaker 1: So, in some other news that leads into our main bit a bit, Crunchyroll, there's a whole situation going on with anime voice acting in America for dubs.
Speaker 0: Which gave us a great Wednesday show idea.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and Crunchyroll and that sort of... In the main bit, we're gonna talk about voice acting just overall, not even just in anime.
Speaker 1: But in the anime world, there's a lot going on here and you're gonna have to read this article and learn more about this whole space.
Speaker 1: But to summarize, during COVID, voice acting was difficult to do.
Speaker 1: It wasn't safe to do in person.
Speaker 1: So a lot of it was done remotely, but doing it remotely did reduce the quality, greatly increased the expenses.
Speaker 1: But it also opened up voice acting roles to a much broader and more diverse set of actors.
Speaker 1: So there are a lot of positive and negative aspects of this opening up remote.
Speaker 1: Simultaneously, Crunchyroll is responsible for most of the dubs that happened in America for anime.
Speaker 1: And the studio they use is basically in Texas and they really want all the work to happen in Texas for a lot of reasons.
Speaker 0: Well, they merged with Funimation, which was a big news when he talked about it.
Speaker 0: That now there's basically one major anime player in the US now, The End.
Speaker 0: It's not like the old days where there was so much competition and companies are starting and failing all over.
Speaker 0: It's Funimation, Crunchyroll, they're on top but everyone else is on a much lower level.
Speaker 1: So there's a group of voice actors trying to unionize.
Speaker 0: If you're a voice actor to voice act anime, it's like that's the sole employer now basically.
Speaker 0: The other companies, like say Discotek, they're not dubbing much.
Speaker 1: And then other stuff is done like Disney will do something itself for a big Ghibli movie that they're going to release.
Speaker 1: So all this is leading to a big conversation around how voice acting and dubbing gets done.
Speaker 1: There's a big unionization effort.
Speaker 1: There's voice actors who aggressively want to be back in the studio because the equipment they have at home sucks.
Speaker 1: There's voice actors who are kicked out of the industry because unless they move to Texas, they can't get a job anymore.
Speaker 1: This is all in the backdrop of Texas has turned into a failed fascist state to the point that a lot of people are fleeing Texas.
Speaker 1: Rightly so.
Speaker 1: So it's unethical.
Speaker 0: If you're a business who cares about money, operating in Texas is great if you just care about money because like low taxes, low regulations.
Speaker 1: But a lot of businesses are having to curtail their Texas operations because people who are qualified to do these jobs are fleeing the state at high rates.
Speaker 1: And very few people are willing to move to Texas to take a job unless they're desperate.
Speaker 1: So there's a lot going on here right now.
Speaker 1: And it's hard to say where this is all going.
Speaker 0: One factor that I brought up on our Discord, which is when we were discussing this earlier today, which you should join.
Speaker 1: Our Discord is pretty good.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Is that if you are a voice actor and you go to a studio.
Speaker 0: There is an engineer there, a sound engineer, audio engineer, and they're taking care of all the hardware, software, you know, mixing everything for you.
Speaker 1: But also you're in a facility.
Speaker 1: There's a quiet room.
Speaker 1: There's the sound dampening.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But the point is you can focus entirely on acting and your job.
Speaker 0: If you voice act from home, there is no audio engineer for you.
Speaker 0: You are now your own audio engineer.
Speaker 0: You are being paid the same amount of money, presumably.
Speaker 0: And you are now doing two jobs.
Speaker 0: You could have a scenario where you give remote access to your computer to an audio engineer who's remote and they come in and they audio engineer you.
Speaker 0: software wise.
Speaker 1: So let me break down what that looks like if I because I'm an audio engineer.
Speaker 0: But hardware wise, like they can't do anything for you other than like you can show them what your hardware looks like and they'll tell you what buttons to press.
Speaker 1: It's even worse if I because I have done audio work for a few small video games.
Speaker 1: I've done audio work for a bunch of things over the years, of course, producing gig nights forever.
Speaker 1: And one of the things that I rely on is that I know the physical environment things are recorded in.
Speaker 1: And I have built pipelines based on that.
Speaker 1: I have a pipeline for Scott from home that took a while to set up.
Speaker 1: I have a separate pipeline for if Scott is here.
Speaker 1: I have one pipeline for me.
Speaker 1: I have one pipeline for Emily.
Speaker 1: If I have to merge audio, especially dialogue that was recorded in multiple separate environments, that increases my workload by an order of magnitude.
Speaker 0: That is, I mean, you're still going to have to send in your recorded WAV files to be mastered, mixed, whatever.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: But now every WAV file needs bespoke work.
Speaker 1: It's almost like color matching in film.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Well, that person still has their job and they're doing that part of it.
Speaker 0: But their job is now we're talking about the engineering that is done during the recording session.
Speaker 0: The person who is at the board while the recording is happening, adjusting the levels and that sort of thing, that that job is now gone.
Speaker 0: And this voice or remote and poor.
Speaker 0: And now this voice actor has to do it themselves and isn't being compensated extra for doing that.
Speaker 1: But I'm saying also the studio now has to hire more audio engineers or pay the people who are doing that work a lot more because they have to post work, not the during recording work.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The post work is a lot more than the pre-work.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But now also write the forgetting about the the the the actual quality of the audio recording, like, you know, that quality.
Speaker 0: But think about the quality of the acting of someone who is fully immersed in acting.
Speaker 0: It has no other distractions versus someone who is acting and then has to adjust shit.
Speaker 0: Also, also now has to do a worse job of acting as on one hand, remote recording.
Speaker 1: As we noted before, there is direct evidence that it broadened the diversity of voice actors and gave a lot of what wider audience of people who are good at this job the ability to do it.
Speaker 1: But it also really only became accessible to people who have those skills and had the equipment to be able to do this from home or they were subcontracting out and reducing their own salaries.
Speaker 1: I don't there is no good answer to this.
Speaker 1: I mean, obviously, we got to get this stuff out of Texas because I don't think Texas can be saved in the short term.
Speaker 1: It's probably unethical to even send money to Texas.
Speaker 1: But that aside, I can I don't see a way to resolve this because it is irrespective of all other externalities.
Speaker 1: It is objectively higher quality work to do this in professional studios with people in person.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, it's also higher quality work to get all the actors in the studio together to sort of the cast.
Speaker 0: I forget what the word for it.
Speaker 0: The ensemble.
Speaker 1: Well, that's what we used to see.
Speaker 1: That was in the early anime dubs.
Speaker 1: American anime dubs were usually produced the way a lot of American cartoons were, where every voice actor's performances were recorded completely independently of each other.
Speaker 1: And they'd be all merged together in post.
Speaker 0: And the Japanese ones typically did the ensemble.
Speaker 0: Now, obviously, the pandemic messes up your ensemble, even if you bring people in studio, regardless of what different countries practices were.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But it's like if they actually cared about making the best dub, it's like they would do the ensemble thing.
Speaker 0: And they never did that.
Speaker 0: So there was never a care.
Speaker 0: So even worse, the best dub that the care is just get a dub because we've done the math and we figured out that if we only do subtitles, we won't get enough views.
Speaker 0: And the money it costs to do the dub will get us this many more views, this many more sales.
Speaker 0: And it comes out to be worth it as long as the dub is cheap enough.
Speaker 0: And the quality of the dub, it's like it doesn't seem to is not going to increase the views and sales.
Speaker 0: So it's not worth it to them to do that.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And even worse, ensemble recording.
Speaker 1: Like technically what Scott and I are doing now is an ensemble voice session.
Speaker 1: The two of us.
Speaker 1: We have infrastructure set up to do this.
Speaker 1: Let's forget how moderately complex it was to set this infrastructure up.
Speaker 1: This literally doubles the post-production time I need to spend to get a Geek Nights episode live.
Speaker 1: It literally doubles it.
Speaker 1: There's a bunch of extra work I have to do.
Speaker 1: And that's just with two people where one, I sent Scott the fucking microphone he uses.
Speaker 1: And two, I trust Scott to know how to set up a microphone.
Speaker 0: Plug it into a box.
Speaker 1: You set your levels the right way.
Speaker 1: There's stuff there.
Speaker 1: Your audio is well recorded.
Speaker 1: But it's double effort just to have one person who's not in the studio in an ensemble recording.
Speaker 1: And it doubles again for every additional person.
Speaker 1: Ten people.
Speaker 0: I don't think you're going to do a voice acting ensemble where everyone is remote because you're losing the whole interactive part of the people.
Speaker 0: It's like in the delay on it wouldn't work, right?
Speaker 1: Never mind the local time stamps.
Speaker 1: The timing will be slightly off on every recording.
Speaker 1: I have to fuck with Scott's audio because it's impossible to line up audio.
Speaker 1: The clocks are not the same clock.
Speaker 1: And even beyond that, have you noticed for the last three years, and it's not just Geek Nights, many podcasts, many podcasts, the hosts talk over each other a little bit more than they used to.
Speaker 1: And they run over each other a little bit more than they used to.
Speaker 1: That's because this is not real time.
Speaker 1: There are slight delays and ebb and flow of the network infrastructure.
Speaker 1: And those delays add up to the same thing you see in live news broadcasts where there's a pause like, "Back to you,
Speaker 1: Andy.".
Speaker 1: And there's a pause before Andy responds and says, "Thank you, John," and does his thing.
Speaker 1: So all of that combined makes it infeasible.
Speaker 1: Never mind the fact that voice actors get paid shit because capitalism.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And like you pointed out, I haven't watched a dubbed anime on purpose.
Speaker 1: I can't remember the last anime I watched dubbed in purpose except Cowboy Bebop.
Speaker 1: The dubs, I would never watch an anime dub.
Speaker 1: Why would I?
Speaker 1: Generally, any media, I'd like to see the original audio subtitles if I can.
Speaker 1: And dubs almost, I think, are becoming more of a checkbox in the anime industry in America.
Speaker 1: So they can say there's a dub and potentially syndicate on TV.
Speaker 1: And also an accessibility function for people who couldn't read subtitles.
Speaker 1: And I think that's it.
Speaker 1: So that's even more reasons beyond just the fact that it doesn't make them money, why the quality of the dubs actually doesn't really matter that much.
Speaker 0: To the producer.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Or even to the consumers, frankly.
Speaker 0: There are some consumers that care a lot and some that don't.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But I still get the impression the majority of people who watch anime to the level that they know Crunchyroll exists, care about anime, and are invested in it.
Speaker 1: Those are the kinds of people who tend to watch things subtitled anyway.
Speaker 1: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 1: So, I can only do this once.
Speaker 1: Every year there's a song competition in Europe called Eurovision.
Speaker 1: You might have heard of it.
Speaker 0: What about the ripoff of America's Song Contest?
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: So, Eurovision, I love Eurovision.
Speaker 1: But I gotta say, 2022, as far as I have seen, I haven't watched every song, but I've seen most of them so far, it is one of the better Eurovisions of the last five years.
Speaker 1: This is an above.
Speaker 0: By our measures.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: In terms of what I want from Eurovision, 2022 is delivered in a way that the last four years of Eurovision have not.
Speaker 1: This is a good Eurovision.
Speaker 1: So, what I'm going to link to, my thing of the day, there are a bunch of great songs.
Speaker 1: But mine, my thing of the day is, every year in Eurovision there's that one song.
Speaker 1: The song that people talk about and maybe make memes of or get stuck in their head and they laugh about.
Speaker 1: The weird one.
Speaker 1: The one.
Speaker 1: And this year I think that one is a song called Give That Wolf a Banana by a delightful band called Subwoofler.
Speaker 1: Whose shtick is that they're dressed up as yellow wolves and they sing about eating grandmas.
Speaker 0: Wait, Subwoofler?
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: Oh, like woof?
Speaker 0: Like a dog?
Speaker 0: Why wouldn't it be Subwoofer?
Speaker 1: It's Subwoofer.
Speaker 0: So, Subwoofer.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: S-U-B-W-O-O-L-F-E-R.
Speaker 0: Okay, but keeping the original word, subwoofer, woof, is like dogs.
Speaker 0: go woof, so do wolves.
Speaker 1: Oh, they're equally good.
Speaker 1: The old meme was you have a big dog and that's a woof, you have a tiny dog and that's a subwoof.
Speaker 0: Right, but it's like, subwoofer also makes sense pun-wise.
Speaker 0: It's like, without seeing the word, you couldn't know which pun they were going for because both of them are valid.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, I found another.
Speaker 1: So, I'm going to link to this too because it would be cheating to use this twice.
Speaker 1: I just found a video that Subwoofer put out officially that teaches you how to do the dance in their Eurovision performance.
Speaker 1: We can learn this dance.
Speaker 1: This is not harder than Mambileo.
Speaker 0: Well, do your dance.
Speaker 0: Maybe I will.
Speaker 0: Dancing rim TikTok.
Speaker 1: I'll be making a Patreon exclusive, so what are you at?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so, you know, at least not recently at all, like actually many years ago already, there was a moment at which the United States turned off the analog over-the-air television.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And we, I think we've used this thing of the day, like, you know, some broadcast like final moments stuff, right?
Speaker 0: But there was a time even before I was alive, which was the moment when, you know, it's like they had television running live 24/7, right?
Speaker 0: In the United States, right?
Speaker 0: Or at least, you know, much of it was live, but there was always a broadcast going 24/7 over the air and they only had black and white TV.
Speaker 0: And then one day they had color TV.
Speaker 1: And the way we've done, we've talked about this on Geek Nights before, color TV just used extra signal space and trickery in the existing black and like the existing TV signals that worked on black and white TVs.
Speaker 1: So you could broadcast something in color, but a black and white TV receiving it would work just fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: That's important for this.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: But anyway, so it's like, okay, so you're, you're in the 1950s, sixties, whenever it was right.
Speaker 0: And it's like you go out and you buy yourself, you got to be saved up some money and you got a black and white TV at home.
Speaker 0: You go buy a color one.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And you set it up and you turn it on.
Speaker 0: And it's like at that time, it's like, you know, it's like some of the channels going to be black and white.
Speaker 0: And some of them went to color already.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Big time channels.
Speaker 0: You know, because obviously they weren't selling color TVs before there were any color channels.
Speaker 0: But the TV network also had to switch.
Speaker 0: There had to be a moment and a precise moment for the dog in a channel.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: A precise moment at the TV station where they said, all right, we're all broadcasting black and white pictures.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Well, we got new cameras in the studio.
Speaker 0: And at this moment, we're going to switch and broadcast color over the air instead.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: We're going to flip a switch.
Speaker 0: And if you were watching TV at that moment on a black and white TV, you wouldn't realize you wouldn't really notice much happening, except maybe the image getting a little bit better, but still being black and white.
Speaker 1: Or possibly getting worse because sets for TV were designed for black and white TV for a long time.
Speaker 1: And they had to be designed differently for color for it to look good for a bunch.
Speaker 0: But sometimes the color image, you know, the source, the cameras were so much better that it's like if you're, you know, a lot of black and white TVs, a color signal would look better.
Speaker 0: Even though anyway.
Speaker 0: But there was.
Speaker 0: if you had a color TV, you'd be watching a TV channel that was in black and white.
Speaker 0: And if you happen to be watching at that one moment in all of history where the channel switched to color, what would you see?
Speaker 0: Well, here's a YouTube video of a recording of the news in Iowa at the moment that this channel two in Iowa switched from black and white to color.
Speaker 1: I love how he walks across to like the other set that they had built with a different set of cameras pointed at it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Well, that's how.
Speaker 0: that's how big of a switch it was.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: They had to switch these cameras, stop broadcasting those cameras, start broadcast.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: They even switch his love like after he gets to the new desk.
Speaker 0: Well, they didn't have wireless ones in those days, so he had to eat the wire for the love he was using.
Speaker 0: Just couldn't reach across to.
Speaker 0: he couldn't walk across the studio while wired up.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: So, you know, they did have back then, though, the only girl sure.
Speaker 1: S.M.
Speaker 0: 57.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: But anyway, so yet here is exactly what you would have seen if you had a color TV in Iowa in whatever year this was.
Speaker 0: And we're watching the news when the whole network switched permanently from broadcasting black and white to broadcasting color.
Speaker 1: In the moment, the geek guides book club book is nine, five, scam it within the next month or so.
Speaker 1: We'll just do the show.
Speaker 1: I'm real.
Speaker 1: I think this weekend I might even finish it.
Speaker 1: It's a good book.
Speaker 1: I do want to read the sequels, even though the listener did say that the sequels weren't as good.
Speaker 1: Well, they said two people said the sequels weren't as good, but they also said that the sequels focus on something very different in this universe from what the first book focuses on.
Speaker 1: But what they said the second and third book focus on is actually the kind of thing I'm way into.
Speaker 1: So we'll see.
Speaker 0: It could be sort of like Hyperion.
Speaker 0: By the way, the author of Hyperion is awful.
Speaker 0: We learned that way after doing that episode.
Speaker 1: Also, he got worse and worse as time went on.
Speaker 1: And he's written a few good books, but he's a bad person.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But anyway, it could be like that where like the first book or two.
Speaker 0: It's like there's the story.
Speaker 0: But then there's also like the book itself is, you know, a great book.
Speaker 0: Bad people can make good things.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But then after that, it's like not as good.
Speaker 0: But there's that you still have some desire to know what happens.
Speaker 0: that could keep you going to reading bad books.
Speaker 1: That's why I read all 14 books of The Wheel of Time.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Same deal with Dune, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you read this book and then, you know, you keep going because you want to know what happens, even though they're not good anymore.
Speaker 0: But you just want to know what happens.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I started just reading wikis about shows and about books if I don't want to bother.
Speaker 1: That's what I do.
Speaker 0: Life's too short for that shit.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Love, for example, Attack on Titan.
Speaker 1: First season, really intrigued.
Speaker 1: Second season, got worried.
Speaker 1: Went and read a wiki, realized there was no reason to watch any more of that show.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I can.
Speaker 0: If all I want to do is know what happens, I can do that in a lot less time than it takes to watch the whole thing.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Attack on Titan is kind of a stinker if you actually watch more of it.
Speaker 1: If you haven't watched the new Attack on Titan, my advice to you is if you have fond memories of the old one, just let them remain fond.
Speaker 1: Don't go back and watch He-Man again.
Speaker 1: That's all I'll say.
Speaker 1: It's bad.
Speaker 1: So let's get into it.
Speaker 1: Voice actors, voice acting.
Speaker 0: We did a big news on voice acting, which gave us the idea to do an episode on it, which we never have done.
Speaker 0: Obviously, we have no experience.
Speaker 0: We have almost no experience voice acting.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to say zero.
Speaker 1: We have voice acted in a handful of zero-budget productions over the years.
Speaker 1: Like Valiant Denim.
Speaker 0: One and a half.
Speaker 1: Yes, exactly.
Speaker 0: That was the one I was thinking of.
Speaker 1: I have recorded voice performances for two or three peoples, depending on what you count.
Speaker 1: They're audition tapes to be voice actors.
Speaker 1: I've also recorded voice acting for some video games.
Speaker 1: I've recorded voice acting for trailers for some Kickstarter.
Speaker 1: I've got a little more direct experience, but I don't want to overstate that.
Speaker 0: I've done narrating at the school play, which is sort of like voice acting.
Speaker 0: Only people can see you standing over there in the corner.
Speaker 1: I've been the emcee of many a function over the years.
Speaker 1: I have narrated technical and instructional videos.
Speaker 1: That's actually something I've done professionally for 20 years now.
Speaker 0: The point is that voice acting inherently is the same as acting acting.
Speaker 0: Stage acting, movie acting, TV acting.
Speaker 0: The only difference is that nobody can see you.
Speaker 0: So you have to express the character that you are portraying only with the power of the sounds that you can make with your body.
Speaker 0: It doesn't have to be just your voice.
Speaker 0: You could use any part of your body or device that makes noises.
Speaker 0: Usually it's just your voice, though.
Speaker 0: If they want to add noises of some other sort, the audio people can do that on their own.
Speaker 0: They don't need the voice actors to do that other stuff.
Speaker 0: You don't need to be in there voice acting a Star Wars cartoon, making lightsaber noises with your mouth.
Speaker 0: They can add those in on their own.
Speaker 0: They don't need you.
Speaker 1: What was the thing I saw?
Speaker 1: where you can clearly see actors in one of the recent Star Wars' at a few points in the final cut of the movie clearly saying "pew pew" or making some sort of laser sound with their mouth as they're firing?
Speaker 0: So there's sort of two major things going on.
Speaker 0: One of them is that you have to have this ability to speak usually in a different voice than your natural voice.
Speaker 1: Well, there's very much two kinds of voice actors.
Speaker 1: There are professional voice actors who have an array of voices.
Speaker 1: They have a range of character voices they could do and they can make up new ones.
Speaker 1: So you show them a character, you collaborate with them, and together you come up with the voice of a character that they then embody.
Speaker 1: But then you've got people like John Benjamin who, everything they voice act, they sound the same and it's fine.
Speaker 1: Or like Bender.
Speaker 1: Sometimes there's a voice actor, even if they can do multiple voices, either their natural voice is really good for voice acting or a voice that might have been part of their repertoire just became an iconic voice that they use for much of their career.
Speaker 0: Rest in peace, Gilbert Gottfried.
Speaker 0: The voice he spoke, whenever he was in public, that was not his natural speaking voice.
Speaker 0: That is well known.
Speaker 0: I've heard his real "natural speaking voice" and it is not "Hey, I'm Gilbert
Speaker 0: Gottfried.".
Speaker 0: But he just talked like that in every professional setting.
Speaker 0: If he was being interviewed, if he was voice acting, he had the one voice that he did.
Speaker 0: He didn't do other voices and he only used his natural voice in private settings.
Speaker 1: Similar to Geek Nights, if you see us do panels and you're listening to this, we're not acting acting, but the way we talk on a show like this is not how I talk when I'm just living my life.
Speaker 0: But that's not an intentional thing.
Speaker 1: No it's not, but it's an artifact of the fact that we're talking to a microphone without an audience.
Speaker 1: Also it's an artifact of the nature of a podcast, but we shout and yell and all this stuff that in real life we're a lot more subdued.
Speaker 0: The point is that even if you are a regular actor, stage, screen actor, people are seeing you, having the ability to have a natural voice that is particular, like say Sean Connery, have a voice that you do that is particular in some way, or have the ability to do lots of voices, are just tools of even a stage and screen actor.
Speaker 0: So a voice actor is basically, it's like you just highly specialize in this one aspect of acting, which is that tool set only and not in expressing yourself with your facial expression or your hands, even though you might do those things as well, no one will see them.
Speaker 0: And this is why you do see often, especially productions with more money, can use stage and screen actors for voice acting because they also have those skills.
Speaker 0: Voice actors just specialize in those skills exclusively.
Speaker 1: So a thing that I think is worth noting is there has been a little bit of a change in this industry, not so much with anime, but with the rest of the voice acting world.
Speaker 1: I saw some articles about it recently.
Speaker 1: It's obvious in retrospect, if you think about what's popular, there is increasing demand for voice actors who are also professional singers because a lot of animated shows in particular have more and more music in them, which is drastically limiting the pool of people who are qualified to be both a professional voice actor who can do a character and who can sing professionally at the level that would be needed for a show.
Speaker 1: In the past, a lot of the way that was handled, even in movies, was to have someone who sounds kind of like the voice actor sing when the voice actor needed to sing.
Speaker 1: A lot of old Disney movies did that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, it always comes across great because even in the real world, people, you know, just people you meet, it's like they sing in one way.
Speaker 0: and when they, you know, it's just meet a person who's a singer and isn't an actor at all.
Speaker 0: They sing.
Speaker 0: They don't sound like they do when they talk, right?
Speaker 0: They clearly have a different singing voice.
Speaker 0: It might be related to the talking voice.
Speaker 0: It might not be, right?
Speaker 0: You know, there's even people who have like very strong accents, right?
Speaker 0: And their singing voice has a completely different accent, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, there's a thing people are like, "How come when people from the UK sing, they sound like they have a US accent,
Speaker 0: right?".
Speaker 0: It's like there's a whole thing about that online.
Speaker 0: You can look it up, right?
Speaker 0: So using someone else to do the singing part is not out of the ordinary.
Speaker 0: It totally works great.
Speaker 0: Like the audience almost never knows.
Speaker 0: But it is more expensive because you're hiring someone who is a professional singer first to do the singing.
Speaker 0: If you hire the one voice actor to do the singing and that, right?
Speaker 0: You can save money.
Speaker 1: But it also greatly complicates the production because now you have to figure out in advance exactly what will be sung and won and get all those takes separately from the voice acting.
Speaker 1: It's harder to change things on the fly.
Speaker 1: It's harder to have a character naturally come in and out of singing, which also is increasingly common.
Speaker 0: Song recording is different from voice recording.
Speaker 1: And I think that's only going to continue.
Speaker 0: As long as musicals are popular.
Speaker 1: And right now, especially in animation in the US, musical animation is only getting more popular and only becoming a bigger piece of the pie.
Speaker 0: I think it's always been huge in children's content, right?
Speaker 0: There's always been songs, even if they're like little nursery rhyme type songs.
Speaker 0: That's just always been there, right?
Speaker 1: So another aspect of all this...
Speaker 0: It's spread more, right?
Speaker 0: I think The Simpsons did it once in a while, but then you had the other shows doing it frequently.
Speaker 1: So another aspect of this is a lot of acting, but voice acting has particular concerns around this.
Speaker 1: It is also not a sport in the competitive sense, but it requires a certain amount of physical luck in terms of are your vocal chords and lungs and head and face shape conducive to voice acting?
Speaker 1: Like there are things that could get in your way, especially if you will play multiple characters.
Speaker 1: You can have injuries just like you could on the set of a play or the set of a movie.
Speaker 1: A lot of voice actors destroy their voices.
Speaker 1: It's a problem in the industry.
Speaker 0: You need vocal coaches, vocal training if you're going to do it, right?
Speaker 1: I mean, Scott and I had to learn significantly.
Speaker 1: We used to lose our voices after every major con, me way more so than Scott.
Speaker 1: I had to learn to talk differently, and I talk differently with a microphone than I do in person just hanging out with people.
Speaker 0: Sure, but there are people who... It's like you might be able to talk in a really funny voice, right?
Speaker 0: And you think I could be a voice actor, right?
Speaker 0: All your friends are super entertained by your funny voices that you do, and you're great.
Speaker 0: All right, go and do that funny voice for five, six hours, seven hours.
Speaker 0: And also do the same lines over and over again.
Speaker 1: You've got to say a line in that same funny voice, but it's a sad line.
Speaker 1: Can you still do it?
Speaker 1: Can you act it?
Speaker 1: Or can you just do the facile voice?
Speaker 0: And the endurance aspect, right?
Speaker 0: It's like if you can't do it, then it's not an easy job at all, right?
Speaker 0: And people, when they think of voice acting, especially when we do this on Geek Nights Wednesday, you're mostly thinking about it in the context of cartoons and animation, right?
Speaker 0: Animated content, whether it's computer-generated, hand-drawn, 2D, 3D, whatever, video games, right?
Speaker 0: That's what you're thinking about.
Speaker 0: And the fact is there is a lot more content out there that requires voice acting than just those things.
Speaker 0: Those are just the most visible things, right?
Speaker 0: There are also lots and lots of, say, instructional videos that need narrators, right?
Speaker 0: There are lots and lots of live-action things that are still dubbed, right?
Speaker 0: You've seen Star Wars, right?
Speaker 0: James Earl Jones, everybody knows, was not in the Darth Vader costume.
Speaker 1: Hell, a lot of old movies, but they still do this when they need to, less often because obviously it really hurts the acting.
Speaker 1: A lot of movies, especially older movies, would do ADR and dub over the on-screen spoken lines of the actors because microphones weren't that good, especially in the past.
Speaker 0: Someone would go in and act in a movie, and then after they acted in the movie on the set, they would go into the audio booth and record their own voice over themselves.
Speaker 1: And the worst part is it's so obvious that that was happening.
Speaker 1: now that you can see a lot of these old movies and old TV shows in high-resolution remastering.
Speaker 0: That's why it's really good if you have a Darth Vader who doesn't have a mouth that moves.
Speaker 0: You can put any voice you want on there.
Speaker 1: Another really increasingly complex part of this is diversity in casting, especially because if you can't see the person, some people who are wrong try to argue that it doesn't matter if a white person plays a black person, for example.
Speaker 1: All that matters is the voice that comes out at the end.
Speaker 1: And obviously that is not true, and obviously there's a lot of nuance in that whole conversation, but voice acting also requires a certain amount of expertise in accents, in language, in languages, in being able to learn and speak in particular accurate sub-dialects depending on what kind of character you're playing.
Speaker 1: These are technical, learned academic skills.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, if you go out there, it's like, you know, I could do a Scottish accent, like, "Oh,
Speaker 0: milady!".
Speaker 0: And it's like, you know, it's like, if I do that, it's like, yeah, you realize that I'm making fun of Scottish voices, right?
Speaker 0: Which actually I think are cool, despite, you know, characters like Sean Connery and Scoop McDuck, right?
Speaker 1: But look at Apu and the right and correct controversy around that accent and that voice acting.
Speaker 0: I can say that every Scottish person that I have met and known to be, you know, have an acquaintance with has been a really cool person.
Speaker 0: So anyway.
Speaker 1: In fact, I remember the cool Scottish dude that we ran into a few times.
Speaker 0: That was one of the people I was just thinking of.
Speaker 1: We went to the sci-fi museum together.
Speaker 1: It was a good time.
Speaker 0: There was also that engineer guy who was a Scottish person in New York who played games with a bunch.
Speaker 0: That guy was cool, too.
Speaker 0: I forget his name.
Speaker 0: Sorry, person.
Speaker 0: I think you listened to Geek Nights at some point a hundred years ago.
Speaker 0: If I go and do that voice, right?
Speaker 0: It is nowhere near accurate, right?
Speaker 0: It's so off, right?
Speaker 0: It would drive a Scottish person wild to hear.
Speaker 0: And if I'm doing that for a character, even if it was for, you know, if it was for a stereotype character, well, that's just offensive, right?
Speaker 0: And if it was for a character who was just like, you know, let's say it's a new My Little Pony and there's a pony with haggis on its ass or a golf club and a bagpipe on its ass, right?
Speaker 0: And I voiced that.
Speaker 0: It's like, that's not right.
Speaker 0: It's like that character should sound like a Scottish person.
Speaker 0: sounds.
Speaker 0: you get a Scottish person or someone who has studied the Scottish accent so well and practiced it so much that they are on.
Speaker 0: Think about which is probably going to be a Scottish person.
Speaker 1: It would take to be a voice actor who is acting not just a correct Scottish accent, but the correct Scottish accent of a character who is currently intoxicated as opposed to not intoxicated.
Speaker 1: Or even worse, what if you are voice acting an Englishman in a period drama who is trying to do and failing to do a fake Scottish accent because he is a spy?
Speaker 1: How good of a fucking voice actor do you have to be to pull that off?
Speaker 0: You have to.
Speaker 0: And then you're let's say you're a voice actor.
Speaker 0: You it's like, OK, you've learned the Scottish accent, right?
Speaker 0: Well, now you have to sing.
Speaker 0: And now you're right.
Speaker 0: It's like, OK, you're even a really simple scene, right?
Speaker 0: You're on a roller coaster and you have to scream.
Speaker 0: It's like scream like a Scottish person screams on a roller coaster.
Speaker 0: Fucking know that, right?
Speaker 0: It's like voice acting is so hard, right?
Speaker 0: It is this really hard job that doesn't pay enough.
Speaker 0: They got to work too hard, right?
Speaker 0: It's underappreciated, et cetera, et cetera.
Speaker 0: And as we talked about in the news, most of the people producing dubs, right, especially for translated works, right, where they're producing a non native language dub, don't really give a shit about the quality.
Speaker 0: And it's to the point where this is the old dub subs debate.
Speaker 1: Well, where's the point to this day?
Speaker 1: If they if I hear if you put something out in the other room and don't let us see it.
Speaker 1: Scott and I could with, I suspect, 100 percent accuracy tell you that it is one of three things.
Speaker 1: It is from an anime dub.
Speaker 1: It is from a video game or it is from something else that is more professionally done.
Speaker 0: Pretty much.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But if they don't care about the quality of it.
Speaker 0: Even if I am listening to actors in a language I don't know.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You know, the original Japanese language or French language or whatever language the original language was.
Speaker 0: It's like whichever dub cast, the directors and the and the actors did the best job.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like you, as long as you're able to hear it, it's like they can get across the emotions better than even someone else doing a worse job in your native language.
Speaker 0: And that is why.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I don't go for the subtitles because it must be the native language.
Speaker 0: I go for the subtitles because the acting is actually better.
Speaker 0: That production was the production that did the best job of voice.
Speaker 1: I mean, if I didn't have a job, I would try to learn languages of my favorite literature enough to read books in those native languages.
Speaker 0: But I'm saying if somebody came and told me right that there was an anime made in Japan and it was a great anime.
Speaker 0: And the original language of the anime was Japanese.
Speaker 0: But the Japanese voice actors fucking phoned it in and did a shit job.
Speaker 0: They they hired cheap actors who weren't any good.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But that the Italian dub crew.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: For the Italian audience.
Speaker 0: Did an incredible job.
Speaker 1: I think I would watch it in Italian with English subtitles.
Speaker 0: I would.
Speaker 0: If I had that information available.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And I knew that the English dub was also, you know, not not a high quality one.
Speaker 0: I would seek out the Italian dub.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I want it's like if you had a choice, like you're watching a movie or you can't do this with with regular live action movies.
Speaker 0: You can't be like, you know, you know, I would have really liked, you know, Star Wars better if instead of Mark Hamill, it was, you know, someone else.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Gilbert Gottfried.
Speaker 0: It's like no matter what country you're in, if you got eyeballs and you watch Star Wars, there's you're looking at Mark Hamill.
Speaker 0: That's who you're looking at.
Speaker 0: You're not seeing anyone else up there.
Speaker 0: You can't change it out.
Speaker 0: But with voice acting, you can change it out.
Speaker 0: And if one actor did a better job than another actor, you can go out and hear the better actor or actress instead.
Speaker 0: And why wouldn't you write if subtitles in your native language are available now?
Speaker 1: The other problem in the industry is, one, a lot of anime fans, just like everyone who plays video games, wants to make video games and they're willing to sacrifice a lot to do it.
Speaker 1: A lot of people who watch anime in the American anime fandom want to be voice actors because of the weird.
Speaker 1: I think it's mostly because of the weird ecosystem in America where the voice actors on anime are treated as bigger celebrities than they are in the context of conventions, which has led to a lot of weird outcomes.
Speaker 1: But I don't think we need to dwell on that.
Speaker 1: If you've been to anime cons, you know what I'm talking about.
Speaker 0: I think it is interesting that in Japan, it's like there definitely is a Seiyuu can become famous, right?
Speaker 0: It's like it's to the general public, it seems, right?
Speaker 0: It's like they're known people, right?
Speaker 0: Just like other actors are known, voice actors are also known quantities, right?
Speaker 0: In the United States and other parts of the world, it's like you could be the voice actor for something enormous, right?
Speaker 0: So they're hugely popular and be a complete unknown to everybody.
Speaker 0: People might know your voice when they hear it and never have heard of you, right?
Speaker 0: Nerds might know of some of these people, right?
Speaker 0: But the general public does not know, right?
Speaker 0: The voices of major, major characters don't appear on late shows or walk red carpets.
Speaker 1: So one weird thing I've noticed, the people who do voice acting, who are not anime people, who get a treatment similar to the anime people, is basically anything that nerds care a lot about.
Speaker 1: So if a popular cartoon that has a presence at like the San Diego Comic Con, the voice actors in that show, every nerd knows who they are and they're treated like celebrities.
Speaker 1: But a super famous, important actor who does a voice in a movie that's animated, the nerds don't tend to get that way about them in America.
Speaker 1: But I think that says more about fan culture than about anything else.
Speaker 0: Right, I mean I was saying like if you look at something hugely popular, say Frozen, right?
Speaker 0: That's a mega hit, right?
Speaker 0: All the voice actors on that are also already famous people, right?
Speaker 0: On their own, right?
Speaker 0: So at least most of them are.
Speaker 0: But if you look at The Simpsons, it's like, it's like, it's mega huge, right?
Speaker 0: It's like we know who the people are.
Speaker 1: Now, Simpsons nerds care a lot.
Speaker 0: No, nerds in general know, but the general public all would all know Homer Simpson's voice.
Speaker 0: Everybody, right?
Speaker 0: But if you said, "Alright, who's the voice of Homer
Speaker 0: Simpson?"
Speaker 0: They don't fucking know.
Speaker 0: If you told them that person's name, they'd be like, "I don't know who that
Speaker 0: is.".
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, it's like there's.
Speaker 0: no, even at the top of the voice acting game in the United States, you don't get general public fame.
Speaker 0: You only get nerd fame, even outside of anime, right?
Speaker 0: Even outside of things that are important from other countries, right?
Speaker 0: So that's, it's that, like you said, when it comes to the nerds who do know, there becomes a weird culture around those people who are the voice actors because, right, it's like a special treat in a way for them to appear.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, even though I don't give a shit about them, like when I go to conventions, when I did go to conventions, right?
Speaker 0: It is really fun to meet a voice actor and if they actually are so gracious enough to do the voice, despite people constantly grasping on to the voice.
Speaker 1: Say the line, Bart.
Speaker 0: Right, it's like, it is entertaining, right?
Speaker 0: It is pleasurable, right?
Speaker 0: And they have that power with their, it's just, you know.
Speaker 1: It kind of breaks your brain a little bit.
Speaker 1: Like the few times I've been like talking directly to a voice actor and they slip into the character voice, there's this moment where the brain just goes, "What?
Speaker 1: How is that coming out of a human's mouth in front of me right
Speaker 1: now?".
Speaker 1: Like there's this, it's slightly surprising, even if you see it coming and you know they're about to do it.
Speaker 0: It's the same thing you get when you, you know, see any talented person do their talented thing, right?
Speaker 0: You watch a basketball player do a ridiculous dunk.
Speaker 0: You watch a, you know, expert pianist, right, play a piano amazingly, right?
Speaker 0: You see a singer sing amazingly, right?
Speaker 0: And you see some person, right, do this voice, like holy shit, wow, right?
Speaker 0: It's like the same holy shit, wow kind of thing only, right?
Speaker 0: You know, if Lebron goes around the street, he doesn't have people saying, "Do a dunk, do a
Speaker 0: dunk.".
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 1: Right, but also people don't know who the hell he is.
Speaker 1: Tony Hawk!
Speaker 1: If anyone actually recognizes Tony Hawk, "Do a kickflip" is the first thing they will yell.
Speaker 1: It's basically, it's the freebird of seeing Tony Hawk and recognizing that's Tony Hawk.
Speaker 0: Right, you know, you know, people who have a talent of performing, other people want them to perform because they're so good at it that it brings joy to those who witness it and experience it.
Speaker 0: And I'll admit, if you're a voice actor and people are telling you to do the voice, right, all the time, if they know at the conventions, thankfully not when you're not at the conventions.
Speaker 1: I'll be honest, I would never get tired of that.
Speaker 0: On the one hand, it's annoying, right?
Speaker 0: But on the other hand, it's like that is recognition that your voice is so amazing that people want to hear it.
Speaker 0: So it's like a good and a bad at the same time.
Speaker 1: Even our tiny, like, ageless level of fame.
Speaker 1: When we were going to conventions, how many people come up to us like, "You just did a panel about bad games for an hour.
Speaker 1: I would like you to tell me why my game is bad right
Speaker 1: now.".
Speaker 0: I'd be like, "Because your face is bad.
Speaker 1: Get out of here,
Speaker 1: kid.".
Speaker 0: "Because I don't like your
Speaker 0: face.".
Speaker 1: But
Speaker 0: I actually,
Speaker 1: it's funny, the only voice actors that I can just name off the top of my head are ones that either I know because I'm a nerd who pays a lot of attention to something specific or they're nerdy pop culture things that are hard to avoid, mostly from eras when I was really into that.
Speaker 1: And I've seen a lot of anime with fantastic voice acting and yet I don't remember the names of any of those people anymore even though I watched one episode of Escaflowne and then I was trying to learn more about Miyasakamoto.
Speaker 1: But I think that's just because I'm older and I have less time to spend on frivolous pursuits.
Speaker 0: So there's one last phenomena that I've noticed a bit over time which is there'll be famous people who are not necessarily voice actors, right?
Speaker 1: Ah, but they get attached to an animated movie usually because then they can say their name like "Gilbert Gottfried is in this
Speaker 1: movie.".
Speaker 0: That's not what I'm talking about.
Speaker 0: That's not what I'm talking about at all.
Speaker 0: But they have a distinctive voice that is known, right?
Speaker 0: Or that you've heard that voice somewhere.
Speaker 1: Well, like Thunder Throat.
Speaker 0: Sure, rest in peace that guy.
Speaker 0: And they'll get gigs voice acting on shows usually as cameos or as other characters or something like that, right?
Speaker 0: So, for example, you could watch a lot of children's cartoons and it's like you'll be surprised.
Speaker 0: Weird Al just shows up a lot, right?
Speaker 0: It's like if you aren't thinking about it really hard.
Speaker 1: I mean, he was in My Little Pony.
Speaker 0: Right, if you're not thinking about it hard or aware of it in advance or it's like you just hear someone doing a voice and then it's like, "Wait a minute, that's the Weird Al
Speaker 0: voice.".
Speaker 0: No, that is Weird Al doing that voice.
Speaker 0: He got hired to do voice acting on that show for one episode as that one character.
Speaker 1: Sometimes you get the situation with like a Lorenzo music where there's someone who sounds close enough to a well-known voice, in this case Bill Murray, that people hire this person to basically make people think they heard Bill Murray.
Speaker 0: Kind of.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that happens though.
Speaker 1: That's the thing.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, the Thunder Throat guy died.
Speaker 0: I've heard movie trailers recently where it sounds really similar.
Speaker 1: So, that actually leads into the last topic I wanted to bring up and we'll have to wrap up soon because important hockey is going to start in 15 minutes.
Speaker 1: But voice acting faster than a lot of other acting, I'm not going to say is going to be made obsolete, but technology can replace low-quality voice acting pretty easily.
Speaker 1: Deep fakes.
Speaker 0: Low quality?
Speaker 0: Yes, very much.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So, the things that are going to happen in this industry that we have to deal with is people who are dead or retired or who for moral reasons refuse to work on a show, let's say.
Speaker 1: Deep fakes could just perfectly recreate their voice, good enough for a voice acting gig, and someone else does the performance.
Speaker 1: And it just sounds like that person did the performance.
Speaker 0: It depends on if you own the rights to like your likeness, right?
Speaker 0: So, like just today.
Speaker 1: There are already big debates around what actually fully constitutes a likeness or not.
Speaker 1: Of course.
Speaker 1: I don't want to look like Bill Murray, but what if I just happen to sound exactly like Bill Murray?
Speaker 0: Well, like I was saying, just today, right?
Speaker 1: You know, Stan Lee in his latest years- What if I train a model on Lorenzo Music's voice to then recreate Bill Murray's voice indirectly?
Speaker 0: Anyway, Stan Lee in his very latest years, right?
Speaker 0: There was all sorts of fiascos involving elder abuse and whatnot and signing contracts without, you know, forging a signature on stuff, right?
Speaker 0: But just today, literally, Disney paid the company that was, you know, the one that forged the signatures or whatever, right?
Speaker 0: Stan Lee's company to license for like many, many years.
Speaker 0: I think it was 20 years.
Speaker 0: Look up.
Speaker 0: There'll be articles about it today, about how many years this deal was.
Speaker 0: They licensed from Stan Lee's POW Entertainment, whatever it's called, right?
Speaker 0: His, you know, likeness, right, for a large amount of time so that they can basically recreate a Stan Lee in whatever Marvel shit they want to recreate him in, right?
Speaker 0: And if they have a way to make a computer talk like Stan Lee or, you know, sell a GPS voice Stan Lee for your car GPS or, you know, they're going to do it.
Speaker 0: They got the license for it.
Speaker 0: They're going to do it, right?
Speaker 0: So, if someone tries to sound like you and you're a famous voice, you know, get the - make sure that, you know, you get a licensing deal for that shit.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But also, that'll all be moot because we're going to get to the point to where much like with, you know, motion capture and everything else, even if we have a person doing the acting, we will very likely see increasingly heavily computer modulated performances that come out of that acting.
Speaker 1: So then, no longer does the original actor really have control over that?
Speaker 1: because what's the voice the audience hears?
Speaker 1: and what's the likeness?
Speaker 1: It's the AI generated audio.
Speaker 1: You've just got someone basically working the controls behind it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, could be, could be.
Speaker 0: Okay, I just want to end the show by mentioning that there is a book that's been on my wish list that I haven't read yet.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it'll be Geek Nights Book Club material, but famous voice actress Megumi Hashibara wrote a whole fucking book.
Speaker 0: She wrote a whole book called The Characters Taught Me Everything Living Life One Episode at a Time, and it's been on my wish list.
Speaker 1: Oh, that sounds so good.
Speaker 1: I'm really invested in that already.
Speaker 0: It's got five stars and it's on Amazon and it's got, it's 17 bucks for this book and I've been meaning, it's been on my wish list.
Speaker 0: I've been meaning to read it whenever and that book exists and that book can probably tell you a lot about the life of voice acting, right, from one of the, you know, the S-tier stars of voice acting of all, you know, time.
Speaker 1: And I don't know if you ever, if you ever need me and Scott to voice act for you, all I can say is what you hear now, that's the only voice either of us can do.
Speaker 0: If you want to hire me to voice act, you'll have to wait for me to join the voice acting union and then you can hire me through the union.
Speaker 0: If you somehow like my voice that much and can't find an actor to actually do it and you're aware of the fact that I have no acting skills.
Speaker 1: That's something I'd be willing to do without joining a union.
Speaker 1: If we got the valiant denim team back together for one last episode.
Speaker 0: That seems unlikely.
Speaker 1: That seems extremely un, uh, possible.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: And the Patreon Patreons for this episode of Geek Nights are... Uh, I wonder if any of you thought I was going to try to do an accent or a weird voice for this, but I absolutely am.
Speaker 1: This is hard enough to do as it is to read all these names that quickly, let alone to do it in a weird voice.
Speaker 1: So other than one brave person who appears to have typed it out in an accent, this is all you're getting.
Speaker 1: So, uh, all I leave you with is...
Speaker 0: La granuit, mons le pamplemousse.
Speaker 0: La granuit!
Speaker 1: This isn't Miss Hoover's class.
Speaker 1: Uh, do not know this mad monselle, ouvert, of which you speak.
Speaker 0: What's happening?
Speaker 0: Where am I?
Speaker 0: Sacre bleu!
Speaker 0: What a foolish question!
Speaker 1: You're at West Springfield Elementary School!
Speaker 1: West Springfield?
Speaker 0: I'm at the wrong school!
Speaker 0: En français!
Speaker 1: Bonjour!