Speaker 0: It's Thursday, December 15th, 2022.
Speaker 0: I'm Rym.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights Tonight.
Speaker 0: We are talking about Hanukkah.
Speaker 0: You know, it's only fair if Scott said he did a Christmas show.
Speaker 1: I just don't have any other ideas.
Speaker 0: He did a Christmas show in 2016, but you say that.
Speaker 0: One thing, a common dynamic, especially for the listener who sometimes watches the livestream, especially when I click go live long before we actually start the show, when we're trying to figure out what show to do, the pattern is, I'll have 10 ideas that Scott vetoes, and Scott will have one idea that I veto, and then we're stuck, and then we proceed.
Speaker 0: So I came up with a policy a long time ago, and this is the first time I was able to enact it.
Speaker 0: My policy was, if I ever say, "What should we do this show
Speaker 0: on?"
Speaker 0: and Scott suggests something, I will automatically select it no matter what and do the exact same thing he does to me.
Speaker 0: All right, you can drive.
Speaker 0: Good idea.
Speaker 0: Let's do it.
Speaker 0: I feel good about this show.
Speaker 0: But I think there's enough to talk about.
Speaker 0: But in the open-y bit, as you know, I talked about on the show, we move pretty quick here.
Speaker 0: The 2012 Chevy Cruze that was a gift from Emily's family that got us through COVID, hiking and skiing, blew up in semi-spectacular fashion and is gone.
Speaker 0: And I bought a new devil car that has four miles on it.
Speaker 0: We have a Toyota Corolla Hybrid all-wheel drive 2023.
Speaker 0: We bought the only one the dealership had.
Speaker 0: And I hate buying cars, especially at dealerships.
Speaker 1: I don't know why you didn't do what I suggested and hire the car buying expert.
Speaker 0: I looked at that, and get this, this was actually really easy, and car buying is a lot different than it was the last time I bought a car.
Speaker 1: Because you have to understand, the last time- I've only done it one time, and I just- I've done it twice.
Speaker 1: I did it, I probably didn't do it the best way.
Speaker 0: In the year 1996, I bought with a $3,500 check that my parents wrote for me, a laser.
Speaker 0: Like, that was my first car.
Speaker 0: You know, my parents gave me a check, I gave it to some guy who gave me this car.
Speaker 0: This was one of those, like, buy it from someone in their own driveway and drive it home and hope it doesn't break.
Speaker 0: And then in 2001, I bought the Purple Sunfire that you remember and love.
Speaker 0: The one where one time- Who said I loved it?
Speaker 0: So, we were playing Blaze in the Dark the other night, and Alex plays with us, and I was reminded of an instant that I'm pretty sure you were there for, you and Pete.
Speaker 0: Where we drove that car somewhere, and I stopped to replace the tire, because I got a flat, and I had to put the donut on.
Speaker 0: We were sitting outside like a gas station.
Speaker 0: And I remember that I jacked the car up, and I put the donut on with you guys' help.
Speaker 0: And then when I pulled the jack down, the car didn't go down.
Speaker 0: The shocks just stayed fully extended, and the back of the car just stayed up, like, at an angle.
Speaker 1: I have a memory of a car doing something like that and, like, having to sit on the car to squish the car.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I remember me and Pete got on the back of the car and kind of jumped up and down until we forced the shock back down so we could drive home.
Speaker 0: And I never got that fixed at any point.
Speaker 0: The shocks were still broken when we were living in Beacon.
Speaker 1: I mean, clearly, they're not supposed to do that.
Speaker 0: Oh, no.
Speaker 0: They're not supposed to do that to a degree that I understood.
Speaker 1: I mean, in some cars, they do that on purpose, right?
Speaker 1: It's a lowrider, right?
Speaker 1: I guess, on some level.
Speaker 1: It's not supposed to do that by accident.
Speaker 0: When we were in college, I understood that that was not supposed to happen, but what was I going to do?
Speaker 0: It's not like I could afford to fix anything in that car.
Speaker 0: I could barely afford to change the oil.
Speaker 1: Didn't afford to keep the car from getting repo'd.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The car got repo'd, someone stole the car later, and I never knew what happened to it.
Speaker 0: And I just gave up on it, actually, at that point.
Speaker 1: I don't remember it being stolen.
Speaker 0: That was in Beacon.
Speaker 0: When we moved out of Beacon, I parked it, actually, outside Emily's apartment.
Speaker 0: And then I couldn't come back for, like, two days because a giant blizzard happened.
Speaker 0: And when I came back, the car was gone.
Speaker 0: So I called a bunch of tow places and none of them had it.
Speaker 0: Like, I called all the impound lots I could find in the phone book.
Speaker 0: None of them had it.
Speaker 0: So I filed a police report, like, "Yeah, I guess my car was
Speaker 0: stolen.".
Speaker 0: And then I just didn't do anything because I didn't care.
Speaker 0: Cops never called me back.
Speaker 0: And that car just disappeared.
Speaker 0: To this day, I have no idea what happened to that Sunfire.
Speaker 0: Nor do I care.
Speaker 0: If someone stole it, like, godspeed, it didn't have cooling, nor did it really have oil in it, or power steering fluid, or transmission fluid, and the brakes didn't really work that well.
Speaker 0: But buying a new car is extra special because not only have I never bought a new car, I don't think anyone in my family, my direct line, has ever bought a new car.
Speaker 0: Like, that is not a thing.
Speaker 0: I didn't.
Speaker 0: I could never afford that.
Speaker 0: And by the time I could afford it, I didn't need or want a car.
Speaker 0: So buying the car.
Speaker 0: to tell the short story, I go in and it's hard to get this car.
Speaker 0: Like, there aren't a lot of hybrids available for all the reasons you can read about on a real news site.
Speaker 0: It's actually really hard to buy that kind of car right now.
Speaker 0: Used ones are going for, like, the same price as new ones, which is extra fucked up.
Speaker 0: So the car I want costs, sticker, $28,900.
Speaker 0: Like, that's the sticker price.
Speaker 1: That's not too bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's not too bad.
Speaker 1: In the old days- You had a lot more money than I had when I bought a car, and the car I bought was $19,000.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And that was in 2006.
Speaker 0: I Google around, and basically every dealer within a reasonable trip of New York City adds $3,000 to $4,000 to that.
Speaker 0: They're actually selling them way above sticker because they're in such high demand.
Speaker 0: Like, you can't get them cheap.
Speaker 0: You're going to pay extra.
Speaker 0: This dealership- Yeah, it was actually, like, that seemed reasonable.
Speaker 0: Like, I could deal with that.
Speaker 0: Especially because if I finance it, like, inflation's so bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, loan me money.
Speaker 0: Good luck.
Speaker 0: So, uh, the dealership's like, "Yeah, that car's worth about
Speaker 0: $41,000.".
Speaker 0: And that's the price that they gave me when we went in and looked at it.
Speaker 0: And we just played dumb, and I was like, "Yeah, okay, cool,
Speaker 0: whatever.".
Speaker 0: And we acted like.
Speaker 0: we kind of liked the car.
Speaker 0: Then we left and came back a few days later, said we want to buy it.
Speaker 0: And I didn't haggle until we had filled out the financing form all the way to the bottom.
Speaker 0: Like, all that was left is to sign my name on a piece of paper, and then the process of buying this car would start.
Speaker 0: And then I was just like, "Hey, uh, so all the other dealerships are only marking these up by, like, $3,000.
Speaker 0: So, uh, why does this one cost
Speaker 0: $41,000?".
Speaker 0: And the guy did the thing where he pretends to go talk to his manager for, like, two minutes.
Speaker 0: And he comes back, and he knocks it down to exactly what I said.
Speaker 0: And I was like,
Speaker 0: "Okay.".
Speaker 0: Like, we both were like, "Okay, that was the game.
Speaker 0: The game's
Speaker 0: over.".
Speaker 0: And I bought the car.
Speaker 1: But you did financing?
Speaker 0: Uh, so I did financing because I learned that the interest rate my credit card company, like Chase, offered on their special deal was, like, 7.5%.
Speaker 0: Fuck that.
Speaker 0: Uh, the dealership was, like, 6%, but it's Toyota-thon.
Speaker 0: And there's one of those deals that you're not supposed to be able to get, 3.49%, which is shockingly low.
Speaker 0: Like, I'm literally better off financing and taking the money I would have paid cash for and just putting it in the stock market for two years.
Speaker 1: I mean, that may be true, that they might have had a deal going on, right?
Speaker 1: But, uh, everything that I've heard suggests that, you know, you should be able to get financing elsewhere.
Speaker 1: that's, like, basically even when there's a deal that's lower than what the car dealership offers.
Speaker 1: And then, when you buy a car with cash from the dealer, you should get a lower price.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, so that's the thing I was getting at.
Speaker 0: That was the conventional wisdom.
Speaker 0: That's how I've always approached cars.
Speaker 0: That shit doesn't work anymore.
Speaker 0: I was trying to, like, talk about total price, and the guy was like, "The total price is the same no matter how you finance.
Speaker 0: If you put no money down, if you pay in cash, the price is the price.
Speaker 0: They don't care about that
Speaker 0: anymore.".
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So, uh, 3.5% is apparently insane, and I get the impression, 'cause they basically said, "Oh, yeah, your credit's literally perfect, so we got that
Speaker 0: deal.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, that's not a problem.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I put 10 grand down, and the other thing, there is no prepayment penalty, so I could just pay the whole thing off tomorrow if I wanted.
Speaker 0: I could turn this into cash and pay, like, a couple dollars worth of interest effectively.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, you could always do that, yeah.
Speaker 0: Uh, some, in the old days, a lot of financing wouldn't let you do that.
Speaker 0: My sunfire, if I paid it off early, I would've had to pay a penalty.
Speaker 0: Not that I could've paid it off early.
Speaker 0: I mean, it got repoed.
Speaker 0: I couldn't even pay it.
Speaker 1: Hmm.
Speaker 1: Uh, I'm gonna just add a curio- I mean, the problem is, I would go and, like, type into a website to get an auto loan quote.
Speaker 1: The problem is, I know from having worked literally in my business- Oh, yeah, it'll do a hard check on your credit.
Speaker 1: No, that's not the problem.
Speaker 1: I don't care about that.
Speaker 1: The problem is, if I do that, I will start being inundated.
Speaker 1: By people trying to sell cars.
Speaker 0: Oh, my God.
Speaker 0: I clicked on a website, like, last week on a car, like, some random Toyota dealership.
Speaker 0: Like, I'm interested in this one.
Speaker 0: Those motherfuckers would not respond to an email.
Speaker 0: Like, they didn't email me back, except they tried to email me and they fucked it up, so I went to you.
Speaker 0: Uh, they just called my phone, like, five times a day for weeks.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: I just blocked the number and didn't, uh, buy the car from that dealership.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I have a devil carriage now to replace the one that blew up, and it's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Um, prob- I'm still probably not gonna buy one for- ever.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: You can still borrow mine if you ever need a car.
Speaker 0: Just don't crash it, 'cause it's a nice one.
Speaker 1: I mean, last year- I mean, this year.
Speaker 1: This year's almost over, but I'm not gonna need one again this year.
Speaker 1: Uh, but in all of 2022, I- there were two times that I wanted a vehicle.
Speaker 0: Well, you tried to borrow mine that one time, and, like, you couldn't get a parking brake done.
Speaker 1: Right, that was one of the times- right, so one of the times that we wanted to go apple picking.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And we did not- we ended up just not having the car, and there was no, like, really reasonable alternative, so we simply didn't go, and it wasn't that big a deal.
Speaker 1: It was disappointing, but no- you know, one day, one apple picking.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: That happened to me three- there were three instances over the last two years.
Speaker 0: Well, after the last year, where I went to get that car at, like, 6 AM to go ski, and something on it blew up, and the trip failed, and my whole day turned into car repair shit.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And then the other- the other time was on Thanksgiving, which, out of our control, our family Thanksgiving was in New Jersey.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: We could have used a train to get there and back, but we got relatives to drive us there, and then we used a train to go home.
Speaker 0: Funnily enough, that's when the cruise blew up.
Speaker 0: We drove to Thanksgiving, and on the way home at midnight on the GWB, it blew up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was a minor inconvenience.
Speaker 1: We got, you know, we spent more- a slight amount of time and money in transport, right, on train tickets and whatever, but compared to the cost of car renting or buying, it's like the cost of train tickets one time.
Speaker 0: I did calculate, because we do, like, since COVID started, we ski pretty much every weekend in the winter, and we hike, like, a lot of weekends in the spring and fall.
Speaker 1: Just don't do that.
Speaker 1: You could save a lot of money.
Speaker 0: Those are our primary hobbies, like biking, skiing, running, hiking.
Speaker 1: You don't need the car for biking.
Speaker 1: It's literally the opposite of car.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we actually, we don't, we only use, we only took, the only time we ever took the bikes anywhere in the car was taking them to Wildwood.
Speaker 0: But it ends up being cheaper to own this car, for us, for that profile.
Speaker 1: I mean, if you, right, you're basically, you know, it's like, yes, if you continue, if you insist on doing those activities, you know, owning a car to do those activities is cheaper than doing those activities some other way.
Speaker 1: But what's even cheaper is not doing those things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but those things are great.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: Of course, the car costs, I mean, considering how much we're spending to fly to Colorado to ski in January, the car is actually, it rounds down significantly.
Speaker 1: You could just not do that either.
Speaker 0: So, in the news, I got a little bit of a geek bite, because I've watched the show, at least the first season of it with Emily.
Speaker 0: We might do a little special and talk about it.
Speaker 0: The Ted Lasso Show, which.
Speaker 1: That's the, that's the, that's the, oh, basically, what I know about this show.
Speaker 0: I don't see what you know about it.
Speaker 1: It's basically the only thing on Apple TV Plus that really anyone cares about.
Speaker 0: That is true, it is literally the only thing on Apple TV that anyone gets a shit about.
Speaker 1: People get Apple TV Plus just to watch this one show, right, so it must be, you know, have some sort of, you know, goodness to make people, right, you know, at least it's got enough hype to make people go out and get Apple TV Plus just to watch one damn TV show, right?
Speaker 1: And then it's about, so basically it's some soccer coach who doesn't know what the fuck he's doing and it's silly or heartwarming in some way, the end.
Speaker 0: So, you're close.
Speaker 0: That's like the surface detail.
Speaker 0: And even watching the first episode, it kind of felt like that.
Speaker 0: The full, what the show is actually about is there's a Premier League club and like the owner.
Speaker 1: So it's like, it's a Premier League, it's like the top of English soccer.
Speaker 0: It's a Premier League club, like it's set there, it's realistic and serious.
Speaker 0: The owner like has an acrimonious fucked up divorce and his wife, who he cheated on, ends up owning the club.
Speaker 0: So she tries to pull a producer's and destroy this club, get them relegated down to the bottom, like just burn everything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they could be relegated, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so that's her plan.
Speaker 0: So she hires basically like...
Speaker 1: Why would that be your plan though?
Speaker 1: If you own the club, you're just going to lose money doing that.
Speaker 0: She's raised separately, so she just wants to spite her husband because the one thing you know about her husband when the show starts is he loved that club more than anything on earth.
Speaker 0: That is all he cared about was that club and cheating on her.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: And she basically hires effectively like a high school/college level American coach of sports who literally does not know anything about soccer.
Speaker 0: And hires him and puts him in charge of this, like he doesn't know how soccer works really, like he doesn't know the rules.
Speaker 0: Dude doesn't know.
Speaker 0: relegation is a thing until about halfway through the season.
Speaker 0: There's a great scene later in the show where they explain it to him and they're like, "What?
Speaker 0: You don't have that in the
Speaker 0: US?".
Speaker 0: And he's like, "God no!
Speaker 0: What the fuck is this all about?
Speaker 0: Get
Speaker 0: demoted?".
Speaker 1: No matter how much the Detroit Lions suck, they will always be in the NFL.
Speaker 1: They won't be sent down to some other league.
Speaker 0: But then they float around because they're like, "What does shitty teams in the US
Speaker 0: do?".
Speaker 0: And he's like, "Well actually, depending on the sport, they pretty much tank and play badly on purpose hoping that they'll get better players for the next
Speaker 0: season.".
Speaker 1: Oh, so the trailer gave me the impression that the Ted Lasso coach guy was sort of like a dumb and dumber idiot.
Speaker 0: No!
Speaker 0: That is the lie.
Speaker 0: That is not what the show is about.
Speaker 1: So he's actually, he has a common sense.
Speaker 1: He just doesn't know anything about soccer because he's American.
Speaker 0: So, is that he is a fantastic coach of sports players.
Speaker 0: He just happens to have never coached soccer before.
Speaker 1: Oh, so he's just out of his element.
Speaker 1: He's not an idiot.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: In fact, I will say having watched the entire first season, the way the show really goes is that he is a fantastic coach and nobody believes in him and he's actively being sabotaged.
Speaker 0: But over time, he actually does make a difference and make the team better.
Speaker 1: So it's almost like a one-punch man where everyone looks at him and it's like, "Who's this bald moron guy who's weak and not
Speaker 1: powerful?".
Speaker 1: But actually, he's the strongest one.
Speaker 0: And if I had to say what he's like as a character, take Ned Flanders and cross him 50/50 with our friend Chase Gordon.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: I am literally, that is exactly who this character is.
Speaker 0: The show is fantastic.
Speaker 0: It made me cry about a fake soccer game.
Speaker 0: Like, actually cry at the end of the first season because it starts out silly.
Speaker 0: The characters almost seem like caricatures.
Speaker 0: The first few episodes feel like Disney kids special.
Speaker 0: Like, imagine the Mighty Ducks, but if it wasn't the story of a piece of shit learning to be good in the course of coaching the team.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what the trailer seems like.
Speaker 0: Imagine if it was a guy who is the best guy making everyone else around him better over the course of the movie.
Speaker 0: But where it tricks you is as the show goes on, one by one, all the characters get more complex and more human until the show is a very serious, very heartfelt, very well-written drama.
Speaker 0: And if you watch, I'm not saying you should watch it, I think you'd like it, I don't know if you'd like it, I bet you would get a little choked up in the last episode of season one.
Speaker 0: I would bet a token amount that that would happen if you watch this show and it sneaks up on you just like Ted Lasso, the character, sneaks up on the characters in the show.
Speaker 0: It also gets soccer really right.
Speaker 0: Like, there's a moment where whenever they talk about the game or do strategy, it's really accurate and really right, like in a really good way.
Speaker 0: It treats soccer seriously, which is, that would have been a deal breaker if the soccer was fakie, but no, the soccer is like hyper-realistic and that helps.
Speaker 1: Alright, so the news that nobody could escape this week is we have achieved Fusion.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we have beaten Unity.
Speaker 1: We've achieved Fusion before, this isn't the first Fusion.
Speaker 0: We have achieved Fusion that generated definitely more power output than the power input in a very controlled short experiment.
Speaker 1: Well, it depends on your interpretation, right?
Speaker 1: So the energy, basically the way the Fusion, the simplest explanation of how the Fusion machine is set up is that there is some target made of some material and there are lasers and the lasers fire at the target simultaneously.
Speaker 1: And the lasers apply enough energy, pressure, heat, whatever to the target so that atoms fuse together into bigger atoms, right?
Speaker 1: And then energy is released just like in a star, right?
Speaker 1: Where, you know, hydrogens combine into heliums and energy is released, right?
Speaker 1: Enough to warm a solar system.
Speaker 0: Not just hydrogens and heliums, they all keep combining and they make denser and denser elements as time goes on.
Speaker 1: Right, but it's the opposite of Fission like a nuclear weapon, right?
Speaker 1: Where you break the atoms apart and the energy comes out, right?
Speaker 0: It's the opposite.
Speaker 1: But energy still comes out.
Speaker 0: I would also point out that all modern nuclear weapons are Fusion and Fusion is just a baby step before the Fusion.
Speaker 1: The point is that usually when we've tried this before, right?
Speaker 1: The energy that you need to put into the lasers, right?
Speaker 1: That's the energy input that we're measuring is how much, you know, basically you plug the laser into the wall with your kilowatt, right?
Speaker 1: And you see how much energy the laser needs.
Speaker 0: But what we're not measuring for practical reasons yet is the rest of the setup, like the whole facility that makes this happen.
Speaker 0: that uses energy is not part of this equation.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: There's all kinds of other energy that had to go into this, right?
Speaker 1: It's like someone had to physically put the target there and line everything up and monitor it and measure it and the lights for the people to see what the fuck is going on.
Speaker 1: The heating and cooling for the people who are working there, like there's so much other energy, the energy to go into manufacturing all the equipment and it's like a lot of energy went into it that's not being measured, right?
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But the lasers put about two megajoules of energy into this experiment and about three megajoules of energy were released by the Fusion.
Speaker 0: that happened because of those lasers.
Speaker 0: Which, that is why this is big news.
Speaker 0: They call this ignition in that this was a proof of concept.
Speaker 0: that was the next milestone.
Speaker 0: Everything we've ever done researching Fusion was basically trying to achieve this as the milestone that leads us to the next milestones.
Speaker 1: So to give you sort of a, I guess a ruler, right?
Speaker 1: A measuring stick, right?
Speaker 1: Two megajoules doesn't mean much to most people, right?
Speaker 1: Two megajoules is basically like eating 500 calories of food.
Speaker 1: So like a candy bar, maybe?
Speaker 0: Four slices of white bread, give or take?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Something like that.
Speaker 1: So imagine setting a candy bar on fire and all the energy that comes out of the candy bar, it's just a pile of carbon is left, right?
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 1: And then suddenly there's like an extra half a candy bar.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Take two Snickers bars, mash them up in your hand, reform it, you get two and a half candy bars.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: At least energy wise, you lose.
Speaker 1: the matter is, you know.
Speaker 0: Matter is just energy.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess there is going to be.
Speaker 1: the fused matter is now combined in some other element now, right?
Speaker 1: You have that left.
Speaker 1: That's your byproduct, right?
Speaker 1: You start with some smaller atoms and you end up with bigger ones.
Speaker 0: Imagine a distant future where we're just having fission and fusion back and forth, oscillating, generating energy.
Speaker 1: Maybe, but that sounds a lot like it's going to break the laws of physics, right?
Speaker 0: Well, that means there's entropy.
Speaker 0: There is always entropy.
Speaker 0: Do not get me wrong.
Speaker 1: The point is you could conceivably, right?
Speaker 1: Depending on what targets we have and what lasers we have, because basically that's what the experiment is now, right?
Speaker 1: Is basically keep altering the targets and altering the lasers until you get even better, right?
Speaker 1: Because mathematically, to make a power plant out of using this method, you're going to need to get a way better target, right?
Speaker 1: A target that can withstand a lot more.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, this method is not going to be how we generate usable power with fusion.
Speaker 0: This is how we figure it out.
Speaker 1: You also have to realize at the lab where they do this, the lab is operating 24/7.
Speaker 1: They can recharge and fire the lasers about like every four to six, eight hours.
Speaker 1: There's like some hours long interval.
Speaker 1: Like they can only make an attempt like three, four times a day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like in a mech, you fire those PPCs.
Speaker 0: You can't just fire them again immediately.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Mathematically for a power plant using this technology to function, they need to advance this to the point where the lasers fire like 10 times a second, right?
Speaker 1: We're like going pew, pew, pew, pew, pew and just keep.
Speaker 1: basically, you know, think of it as like button mashing and squeezing out energy, right?
Speaker 0: So there's a gain factor, which is the line, because basically they have for the first time gotten the gain factor above one.
Speaker 0: And this experiment achieved about 1.5 gain factor.
Speaker 0: According to this Vox article, which has real citations to generate enough energy to be usable, not counting all the logistics of that, just the like the rate of return.
Speaker 0: We need the gain factor to approach 100.
Speaker 0: So we got to get three orders of magnitude ish.
Speaker 0: Like we got to really move further.
Speaker 0: This is this is the equivalent of, hey, we proved that we can make a rocket.
Speaker 0: Now let's try to go for the moon someday.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: You know, the thing that still concerns me, it's like is, you know, obviously this isn't really very dangerous at all.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Just shooting a very small object with some lasers.
Speaker 1: Once every eight hours.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But, you know, if you have an actual fusion power plant, you know, it's like you're basically making a star kind of.
Speaker 0: Stars are by some definitions of stable, extremely stable, and by some definitions of predictable, extremely predictable.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But it's like.
Speaker 1: I just feel like, you know, if you're making a star, it's like, you know, imagine if, you know, 2001 was 2010 or 2001, where Jupiter became a star or whatever.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, even that is going to have some negative consequences for Earth.
Speaker 1: And that's pretty far away, at least somewhat far away.
Speaker 1: Really close, cosmically speaking.
Speaker 1: But it's still over there.
Speaker 1: I think that's a kind of concern in the sense that making a star on the Earth, it's sort of like, hey, when I set off the fireworks, like you run away from them.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, it's like you're going to make it if we're going to make a sun.
Speaker 1: I feel like we should sort of run away from it.
Speaker 0: On the Earth, the dumbest
Speaker 1: thing, like a bad
Speaker 0: spot, the dumbest thing any human ever invented, other than the former guys, NFTs, is the Davy Crockett, which was the man per single person launched nuclear artillery that you basically if you fired it, there's no way you would be outside of its radius.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But I would say, you know, while that is true, like that concern, really, that is the concern of any power generation system, because to generate a lot of power, you have generated a lot of power.
Speaker 0: Just like if you have a really good battery, that battery is a grenade.
Speaker 0: That battery is full of it.
Speaker 1: There's going to be something that is releasing energy.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like if you have a megawatt power plant, well, there's some megawatt of energy in there that is in some form.
Speaker 1: It could be electrical or it could be gravity.
Speaker 0: What if we build a Dyson ring?
Speaker 0: Guess what?
Speaker 0: Now we now we have death rays sending energy back to the Earth.
Speaker 0: Like.
Speaker 1: that could be water that's moving so fast that it has, you know, a megawatt of like, you know, if you get hit by that water, it's going to hurt.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, it's dangerous.
Speaker 1: Whatever form the energy takes, kinetic or otherwise, it's if it's a large amount and if you touch it, it's going to hurt.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You have to contain it and control it and stay away from it.
Speaker 0: I guess when it comes to generating power, the thing that a lot of people who are anti nuclear power or just have weird or bad opinions about power generation, they always look at one way to generate power and consider it in a vacuum instead of considering it compared to all the other ways we have to generate power because none of them are good.
Speaker 0: None of them are like other than wind power, which isn't 100 percent either.
Speaker 0: Like nothing is without problems.
Speaker 0: And it's just a matter of which problems are we willing to accept by which ones are necessary.
Speaker 0: It's a balancing act.
Speaker 0: And probably for at least the next thousand years, humans are going to generate power via a lot of different mechanisms.
Speaker 0: because we don't really have there's no answer to this question.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, I think the way I think about it is this.
Speaker 1: You're a human being.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like you need to power your body usually with food.
Speaker 0: But food comes directly from the sun.
Speaker 0: It just passes through a few hands along the way.
Speaker 1: The point is, is I don't see.
Speaker 1: I mean, there are some people, but most people are not just eating one food.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You need to eat a bunch of different foods.
Speaker 0: Also, I want to point out how many people who do eat just one food in the Soil and Fail Reddit are posting about things that are obviously the symptoms of malnutrition.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But if our society needs energy to function in our industrialized society, at least right.
Speaker 1: We can't really be getting it all just from one thing.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: We got these different places.
Speaker 1: There's different needs.
Speaker 1: There's it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: They've got a lot of we got to no matter how many ways we even if we greenify all of our energy on Earth.
Speaker 1: And only use stop burning dead dinosaur fuels or whatever.
Speaker 1: We're going to have to use more than one kind.
Speaker 1: A little wind there, a little water there.
Speaker 1: I don't know what.
Speaker 1: whatever we come up with.
Speaker 0: We will definitely need traditional nuclear power, just better, more modern reactors for hundreds of years at minimum.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that's the news.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's a huge news.
Speaker 0: It's actually a big news.
Speaker 0: It's probably one of the most important like energy scientific developments in the modern era.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, how much time was there between like, you know, Thomas Edison has a light bulb and everyone has a light bulb.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like we've reached the first part.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: So I was a mountain biker.
Speaker 0: I am most no longer a mountain biker, but I don't know a lot about modern mountain bikes, but I know a comparative a lot relative to modern bikes about 90s era mountain bikes because that's what I mountain bike the most.
Speaker 0: And while I had heard of this kind of thing, I never really seen it.
Speaker 1: I didn't know it was seen or heard of it before just now.
Speaker 0: But what this is, if you see, if you look at the picture of my thing of the day, you will see a bike that looks like a joke.
Speaker 0: This looks like the kind of bike that some weird YouTube channel will make.
Speaker 0: Like, ah, we made a bike out of land.
Speaker 0: How does it ride?
Speaker 0: Terribly.
Speaker 0: Haha.
Speaker 0: Square wheeled bike.
Speaker 0: Look at this shit.
Speaker 1: But I first when I saw the image of it, I said, ah, this is like some horrible old product someone made that was super dangerous and didn't, you know, and was limited and then was taken off the market for being ridiculous.
Speaker 0: So the reason I didn't know about this bike or its deal in the 90s is because this was the most expensive, best kind of mountain bike in the world at the time.
Speaker 0: Mountain bikes in the 80s and 90s were not like mountain bikes today.
Speaker 0: They were not safe.
Speaker 0: Not that modern mountain bikes are safe, but they are much safer than like what I was riding.
Speaker 0: This was the top tier.
Speaker 0: This was like the fanciest specialist weird mountain bike that the pros would ride.
Speaker 0: This is the slingshot.
Speaker 0: It does not have the entire triangle.
Speaker 0: You got to look at a picture.
Speaker 0: It's got the rear triangle of the frame, but then the tube under your crotch goes across to the handlebars.
Speaker 0: And from there, you've got the fork that goes down to the wheel with the front suspension, that same shadow 90s front suspension that every mountain bike had back then.
Speaker 0: And there's no other bar.
Speaker 0: There's just a cable holding it together.
Speaker 1: There's no bottom tube.
Speaker 1: It's just a cable.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And as a result, the bike flexes a lot.
Speaker 0: And you might think, wouldn't it just snap?
Speaker 0: No, you're thinking about modern bikes made out of like aluminum or carbon.
Speaker 0: This bike's made out of steel.
Speaker 0: So that's actually not a problem.
Speaker 0: Steel bikes will flex just fine.
Speaker 0: Uh, watch the video.
Speaker 0: It's only 10 minutes long and it goes into extreme detail with someone riding one in the year 2022.
Speaker 0: They got one, they restored it and they wrote it.
Speaker 0: And it is an amazing mountain bike.
Speaker 0: It's actually pretty good even by modern standards because this design has shocking advantages.
Speaker 0: The only reason we don't make bikes like this today is that we developed extremely modern suspensions that could not have been made with material science in the 90s.
Speaker 0: And we have developed like modern carbon fiber.
Speaker 0: That is like nothing we had in the 90s.
Speaker 1: I'm surprised that, you know, with all the different bike events I've been to where people bring out all the weird bikes, I've never seen one of these.
Speaker 0: I can tell you why.
Speaker 0: the video.
Speaker 0: actually I watched this video twice.
Speaker 0: It was so good.
Speaker 0: The reason why is that one, there's a carbon fiber part on this.
Speaker 0: And if you remember, this is from the 90s.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that shit is dodgy.
Speaker 0: If it breaks, you got to make like a custom one.
Speaker 0: But two, there's a critical piece that is like the flex plate that connects this thing together.
Speaker 0: Not the cable, but like this flex plate.
Speaker 0: It's made out of a weird material.
Speaker 0: It's basically irreplaceable and it degrades over time.
Speaker 0: So you've got to like cut and scrape the old one out, acquire or make an equivalent flex plate to replace it, put it in this bike and trust it not to kill you.
Speaker 0: So even the guy riding the bike in the video is like kind of afraid the bike's gonna hurt him the whole time because even though it was vouched for, it's kind of hard to make these bikes safe and nobody's making parts for these things.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So thing of the day in New York City, down on Astor Place in Manhattan on the west side, west-ish, east-ish, I guess it's technically east, but whatever.
Speaker 0: By the big black cube.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's near-ish to the cube, like a block or two away from there.
Speaker 1: In an NYU area, right?
Speaker 1: I guess it's definitely, I guess it wouldn't, even though it's not super close to the water, I guess it would still technically be East Village.
Speaker 1: Anyway, there's a haircut place.
Speaker 1: You go down these stairs, you have to go down, like you're on the sidewalk and it says "Aster Barber" or whatever is a sign.
Speaker 1: You have to go downstairs like you're going in a basement and there's a haircutting place and that place has been there for fucking ever, right?
Speaker 1: In fact, when I first worked in New York City and we lived in Beacon, I would go get my haircut there because I had hair.
Speaker 1: There weren't any good haircut places in the Beacon area and it was conveniently near my work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, back then, you know where I got my haircut?
Speaker 0: At Grand Central because it was really convenient even though it caused- I did that one time.
Speaker 0: It caused like four times the normal haircut place.
Speaker 1: That place isn't there anymore.
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so this place is like a really special kind of place, right?
Speaker 1: It's like when I was a kid growing up, I would go to a barber and it was like three old guys, right?
Speaker 1: And they had three seats and then they had one seat that was like an old metal car for the kids to sit in.
Speaker 1: And then they had a TV playing some sport or whatever.
Speaker 1: In the city, it's usually soccer.
Speaker 1: And then they got all those old timey seats and a bunch of old magazines like golf magazines or whatever, right?
Speaker 1: You know the kind of place, right?
Speaker 1: A white guy barber shop.
Speaker 1: It's completely different from a black guy barber shop, right?
Speaker 1: Which is even cooler.
Speaker 1: But, you know, anyway, so this place though, it's a lot like that, right?
Speaker 1: Except it's an everybody barber shop, right?
Speaker 1: It's like every kind of age, every kind of person, right?
Speaker 1: And it's enormous.
Speaker 1: Like it's not just like this one straight line of chairs, like a handful of them.
Speaker 1: It's like this big giant open room with no walls other than the surrounding walls, right?
Speaker 1: And chairs and mirrors just scattered all about, right?
Speaker 1: And it's like you feel almost like you're going into like a hotel or some shit because you don't, you know, maybe you've been going there a long time and you know who your person is, right?
Speaker 1: You know where their seat is, you know what their hours are and you can find them.
Speaker 1: But usually you're going up to the front desk and there's a person there who's like managing, right?
Speaker 1: And they got everyone's appointments and you're like, you know, you might say, "Oh, I want to see so and
Speaker 1: so.".
Speaker 1: And they'll be like, "Oh, they're not here right now.
Speaker 1: They're
Speaker 1: busy.".
Speaker 0: Would you be willing to accept Joey Jojo?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like there's so many barbers down there, you know, different hairdressers and whatever with different, you know, specialties and whatever, you know.
Speaker 1: But usually if you've never been there before, you just be like, "Hey, I want my
Speaker 1: haircut.".
Speaker 1: And they look at you and they figure out who would be good for your hair, right?
Speaker 1: And they don't do this out loud.
Speaker 1: Like the person at the front just looks at you and then looks at the schedule and who's available and they're like, "Go over there to number whatever," right?
Speaker 1: You know, and there'll be a person there to cut your hair, right?
Speaker 1: You know, and all the bar, you know, the hairdressers, they got, you know, they really personalize out their little zone, right?
Speaker 1: They got, you know, photos and all kinds of shit going on, right?
Speaker 1: So it's a really a special kind of place going on there.
Speaker 1: And mostly NYU students, but all kinds of people go in there, you know, famous people, people who don't have a lot of money, people who do have a lot of money.
Speaker 1: Anyone in New York who needs a haircut, it's a place to go.
Speaker 1: They don't rip you off there, right?
Speaker 1: And so this place during the pan doodle almost went OOB, right?
Speaker 1: Which would have been a travesty.
Speaker 0: I mean, I didn't get any haircuts during the entire pan doodle.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Not people weren't getting haircuts at all, but also, you know, people weren't there.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Not commuting to work, students not studenting, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, even if you were getting a haircut, you weren't getting a haircut and asked to replace it in Manhattan.
Speaker 1: And so that would have been real sad, but this cultural institution was saved by somebody.
Speaker 1: Thank you, person who saved it with your money.
Speaker 0: A sophomore.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: You were great.
Speaker 1: But then now that, you know, NYU is back doing its thing, right?
Speaker 1: Times are not normal, but, you know, it's recovered somewhat economically, at least.
Speaker 1: A student at the NYU, right, came in and they did something amazing.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I know I never thought of this before.
Speaker 1: Somehow they arranged to basically, you know, at night when this place is closed, it's a big old room, right, with barber chairs, but nothing else.
Speaker 1: Just fucking has some parties down there.
Speaker 1: And the owners is like, well, no one's cutting hair down there at that time.
Speaker 1: It's going to make us money.
Speaker 1: Why the fuck wouldn't we do this?
Speaker 1: It's like the perfect place to do this.
Speaker 1: What would be the objection?
Speaker 1: Nothing.
Speaker 1: It's not like bothering anyone.
Speaker 1: No one lives there, right?
Speaker 1: It's in a basement.
Speaker 1: It's legal, right?
Speaker 1: And so sure enough, they're having parties down there now, which is pretty freaking awesome.
Speaker 1: And the New York Times did a little, you know, I guess their one day strike is over.
Speaker 1: So it's okay to read them for now.
Speaker 1: And they did a little piece talking about the parties going on down there.
Speaker 1: Sometimes, you know, the attendance is waxing and waning based on, you know, what day it is, right, stuff like that.
Speaker 1: But they're getting turned out.
Speaker 1: They're getting big time DJs down there.
Speaker 1: It's like, that's pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: Why didn't that, that should have been going on for a long time.
Speaker 1: Why has that only started recently?
Speaker 0: I love in this article the profiles of the people.
Speaker 0: Because they are.
Speaker 1: Whoever, whoever came up with this idea, genius, you're going far in life, right?
Speaker 0: In the meta moment, the Geek Nights Book Club book, Alif the Unseen.
Speaker 0: It's pretty good.
Speaker 1: I'm making a lot of progress.
Speaker 0: I am too.
Speaker 1: I have, I still see Alif though, so I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: Well, you know what, you know who doesn't see Alif, at least as far as I've gotten?
Speaker 0: The government.
Speaker 0: The government does not see Alif yet.
Speaker 0: And that is- Yeah, they're definitely trying.
Speaker 0: Alif is, this book is exactly what it was described to be.
Speaker 0: Which was, "An unnamed Middle Eastern security state, a young Arab Indian hacker, protects watched groups from surveillance and tries to stay out of
Speaker 0: trouble.".
Speaker 0: Yada, yada, yada, jinn.
Speaker 1: The D-J-I-N-N genie kind, not the drinking or card game kind.
Speaker 0: What I do appreciate is, I still am convinced that the framing story is 100% going to be directly relevant to the details of what happens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so my theory of it being a Princess Bride deal, I was wrong.
Speaker 1: It is not a Princess Bride framing story, it is just part of the story.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: That's just, that old man knew some magic and- Yep.
Speaker 0: So this is good, read it, we'll do the show in January or February at the latest.
Speaker 0: Definitely by, like, the first week of February at the rate that I'm reading it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm reading it, you know, every day or so-ish, and I'm 30 to 40 percent-ish done, so.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, we will likely be at PAX East with a couple of panels, but do not expect us to be hanging out there the whole weekend.
Speaker 0: Still seems a little too soon for that.
Speaker 0: Also, it's a four-day con, and considering most of the people we know are still going to avoid cons and it's going to be fully masked, I can't imagine I would have a lot to do if it was just me and Scott for four full days in Boston at a PAX.
Speaker 1: I think we could do a lot of, you know, video produce, you know, content producing stuff.
Speaker 0: We could, and we'll see.
Speaker 0: It's really going to depend on what panel or panels we do and when they're scheduled, and who else is going, and what the situation is in terms of the poop chart, and then we're going to decide what to do.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Alright, so.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Hanukkah?
Speaker 0: Yeah, Hanukkah!
Speaker 1: So, Rym probably doesn't know anything about Hanukkah.
Speaker 0: So, you know what I know about Hanukkah is, one, as a kid, like, to be really blunt, I grew up, especially in, like, middle and high school, in extremely white suburbs in Michigan, like, around Detroit.
Speaker 0: So, there weren't a lot of Jewish people in my schools.
Speaker 0: Like, in high school, there were five or six Jewish kids, and I knew most of them, and that was it in the whole high school.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So, I mean, in my high school, or me, I guess, in all of my schooling, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, my elementary school didn't have any Jewish kids because it was the Catholic school.
Speaker 0: You had to be Catholic or lie about it.
Speaker 1: Oh, sure.
Speaker 1: But, you know, when I went to school, yeah, it's like, Jews were definitely a minority, right?
Speaker 1: It was mostly, you know, white Christian peoples, right?
Speaker 1: But, the number of Jews in the area where I grew up, and Jewish kids I grew up with percentage-wise, it was much greater than the percentage in the
Speaker 1: U.S.,
Speaker 1: and much, much greater than the percentage in the world, right?
Speaker 1: In the entire, in the
Speaker 1: U.S.,
Speaker 1: right, about, like, two and a half percent of the U.S.
Speaker 1: population of adults are Jews, right?
Speaker 1: It's a really small number.
Speaker 1: And, in terms of the world population, it's something like .2%, like, not even 1% of people are Jews, right?
Speaker 1: So, but, where I grew up, it was probably, I don't know, it might have even been 5%?
Speaker 1: Who knows?
Speaker 1: I don't have, I can't count, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you had 5%.
Speaker 0: I had 5.
Speaker 1: But, anyway, so, Hanukkah, right, it's like, when I was a kid, it was just sort of like, hey, you know, we're Jews.
Speaker 1: They're not, right?
Speaker 1: They got Christmas, we got Hanukkah, right?
Speaker 1: I didn't understand, you know, the history, or really care, or anything like that.
Speaker 1: I was like, that's just how it was.
Speaker 1: And I thought, I was getting a good deal.
Speaker 1: I was like, I got eight fucking days, your shitty Christmas, only one day.
Speaker 1: I was like, you know, and I was thinking, I got eight days, I'm getting eight presents.
Speaker 1: Sure, you know, obviously, you're not gonna get eight bomb presents, right?
Speaker 1: You're just gonna get like six, you know, six okay presents, a good present, and a great present, right?
Speaker 1: Unless you're rich or some shit, right?
Speaker 1: You're not getting eight, you know, Nintendo games.
Speaker 1: That's not happening, right?
Speaker 1: You get one Nintendo game, maybe a Lego, and then some other stuff.
Speaker 0: Every now and then, we'd have a blowout Christmas, but they were rare.
Speaker 0: Like, the year the Super Nintendo came out, we got the Super Nintendo, and every launch game was basically the Christmas gift.
Speaker 0: Every single launch game, but the next Christmas after that was somewhat paltry, because that was a very expensive Christmas.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, but then, it's like, the whole time, it's like, you know, I wasn't actually going over to other people's and seeing their Christmases.
Speaker 1: I was seeing TV Christmases, right?
Speaker 1: I went to some kid's house, right, that lived down the street.
Speaker 1: I went over to his house, like, late on Christmas day.
Speaker 0: There were more than eight gifts under that tree, weren't there?
Speaker 1: And I was like, what the fuck is this bullshit?
Speaker 1: Why, how come under your tree, there is, like, a full set of Marvel Super Hero cards?
Speaker 1: Like, the whole fucking set, right?
Speaker 1: When we were kids, like, there was a lot of small gifts.
Speaker 1: And, I was like, that, I'm like, that alone is like, is like a full present.
Speaker 1: I'm like, and you got, like, two Nintendo games under there, and you got, like, a football, and I'm like, what is this?
Speaker 1: This is Christmas, you got one day, you got one thing.
Speaker 1: What the fuck is this spoiling bullshit going on?
Speaker 0: If your parents were middle class, that tree would be absolutely stuffed to capacity underneath and spilling out into the living room with piles of gimps.
Speaker 1: If I was having Christmas, kids get one thing each, right?
Speaker 1: One present per person.
Speaker 1: One, right, you're one person, you get one present.
Speaker 1: That's how it works.
Speaker 1: Santa got room in there for more than one thing per person.
Speaker 1: Okay, but in terms of actual Hanukkah, right, for anyone out there who doesn't know the story of Hanukkah, you can read it on the internet, but I will summarize it for you, right?
Speaker 1: The Jews, right, were in Israel, and there was the Temple, right?
Speaker 1: So, if you know the Western Wall, the Wailing Wall, where the Jews pray in Jerusalem, supposedly, that wall was merely a minor piece of a retaining wall of the Temple, right?
Speaker 1: The Temple, right?
Speaker 0: The literal, giant temple where it was fucking enormous, I don't know, I can't really believe- Now, of course, the historiosity of that edge is more into a bumper sticker that says, "My other car is a
Speaker 0: Ferrari.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like, you know, can I really believe that the Temple was as big as they say it was, right?
Speaker 1: It's like the size that they claim it to be would be like greater than like any construction, right?
Speaker 1: Greater than prayer, whatever, but anyway, they believe that, you know, that Temple was the place, right?
Speaker 1: After the Jews wandered around, right, leaving Egypt, which never happened, you know, they went to Israel, in Jerusalem, they built the Temple.
Speaker 1: It was actually the second Temple.
Speaker 1: By the time of Hanukkah, it was the second Temple, right?
Speaker 1: The first Temple was, they built and destroyed, and then they made another one.
Speaker 1: And the Temple was, it's not like a Temple, like the one you have in your neighborhood, right?
Speaker 1: It was the Temple, which is the place where you could literally sacrifice goats and God would receive them.
Speaker 1: And it's like, you could talk to God in that Temple.
Speaker 1: That was the one, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, he wouldn't listen to you if you were in some other Temple, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, this was the place, right?
Speaker 1: Like a holy, important place.
Speaker 1: Anyway, obviously, the truth of that and the truth of the Hanukkah story greatly in question.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the Archaeological Evidence section of Wikipedia on this Temple is three paragraphs long, total, so...
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, but, you know, clearly there was something there, because a piece of it is still there.
Speaker 1: And the second Temple, the story of Hanukkah, the second Temple was there, right?
Speaker 1: And, you know, the Jews, there was this Jewish tribe called the Maccabees, right?
Speaker 1: They were sort of like, you know, warrior Jews, I guess, something like that, right?
Speaker 1: And the Assyrians, or just Syrians, right?
Speaker 1: You know, they were warring in those times.
Speaker 1: And, you know, the Jews are resisting.
Speaker 1: And the story goes, right, that, you know, in the Temple, they wanted to keep the lights on, right?
Speaker 1: They didn't have enough oil to keep the lights on.
Speaker 1: And somehow, miraculously, the oil that should have lasted, like, not long at all, lasted for eight days, right?
Speaker 1: In some sort of miracle that clearly didn't happen.
Speaker 1: And the Jews won, right, in the war.
Speaker 1: And so that's the story of Hanukkah, right?
Speaker 1: The reality is, is that in terms of Jewish holidays, Hanukkah doesn't rank, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, it is not, like, the actual Jewish holidays that are, like, serious, right?
Speaker 1: Are like, you know, Rosh Hashanah, Rosh Hashanah.
Speaker 1: I always say Rosh Hashanah.
Speaker 1: I guess I can tell this, you know why I say Rosh Hashanah?
Speaker 0: Yeah, we've talked about this at length.
Speaker 0: The problem is, I say it that way because of you, because we find it funny, just like you mispronounce "sod-er".
Speaker 1: Well, do you know why I mispronounce it, though?
Speaker 0: Oh, you know, I don't actually remember.
Speaker 1: So the reason I mispronounce "sold-er", right, is because...
Speaker 0: Oh, because you learned to "sod-er" from that guy who said it that way.
Speaker 1: From an Australian guy, right?
Speaker 1: But, so when I was in high school in the Jewish youth group, one of the youth group people had his brother, I think, right, or father, someone, was a Vietnam veteran who was a Jew who came to tell us, you know, about, you know, the old, the Vietnam times.
Speaker 1: He had his shit together, mostly, right?
Speaker 1: His body wasn't in great shape, but his mind was, you know, pretty good considering the circumstances, right?
Speaker 1: You know, he went to Vietnam and his goal was to live and come back, right?
Speaker 1: And that's how he, he was in charge of his little platoon or whatever.
Speaker 1: And that's what, you know, when he had like, you know, gung-ho guys who wanted to, you know, kill them all, he kicked those people out, right?
Speaker 1: So he was, that's, I think that's how he made it through.
Speaker 1: But anyway, he was a Jew and he got leave, you know, legitimately for Rosh Hashanah, right?
Speaker 1: And he told us that when he was, you know, walking around on leave, some MPs approached him and were like, "Hey, you know, you're supposed to, you know, you're really on leave, show us your papers," right?
Speaker 1: So he showed him the papers, which were legitimate papers.
Speaker 1: that said he's on leave for Rosh Hashanah.
Speaker 0: Oh, you did, I remember this.
Speaker 0: You did tell me this story.
Speaker 1: And the MP is like, "What's this Rosh Hashanah
Speaker 1: business?".
Speaker 1: And so that's why I always say Rosh Hashanah, even though it's Rosh Hashanah.
Speaker 1: So anyway.
Speaker 0: I did say Chipotle at work last week because I ended up eating, I ate at Chipotle.
Speaker 1: And someone just straight up literally next to, you work literally next to Los Tacos Numero Uno and you went to Chipotle?
Speaker 0: I was on the other side of town doing something.
Speaker 0: I was not, believe me, believe me.
Speaker 1: I haven't eaten at a Chipotle in years.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: I was up at the other office.
Speaker 0: If I was at the 120 Park office, I would have been at Los Tacos Numero Uno.
Speaker 1: Rosh Hashanah, correctly pronounced Rosh Hashanah, is like top holiday.
Speaker 1: Yom Kippur also top like in terms of seriousness, Passover, right?
Speaker 1: And some Jews will perhaps accurately tell you the most important Jewish holiday is Shabbos every week, right?
Speaker 1: You know, every Friday night through, you know, Saturday night is like the actual, the most important Jewish holiday.
Speaker 1: Hanukkah doesn't rank in Jewish holidays.
Speaker 1: It's not that important.
Speaker 0: But it happened to be around the same time as the dominant white Christian holiday that completely overpowers all American pop culture every year around that time.
Speaker 0: It has for a very long time.
Speaker 1: The same way that the Jesus birthday happened to be sometime around the Saturnalia and the pagan Yule, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, so what happened is some decades ago, right?
Speaker 1: You know, when all the Christian kids are getting their presents and doing their Christmas, the Jews were like, yeah, you know what?
Speaker 1: We got the Sonicas pretty close, right?
Speaker 1: I'm sure you could look up actually how this happened.
Speaker 1: Maybe someone did it on purpose, like with Kwanzaa, which is on purpose.
Speaker 0: Well, that was probably Hanukkah Harry, just like the real, you know, the saint that Santa Claus was based on.
Speaker 0: Maybe Hanukkah Harry was real.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe.
Speaker 0: Hanukkah Harry, who is the name we now give to whoever, started purposefully conflating Hanukkah with those holidays to give the Jewish kids something in pop culture.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know, Hanukkah just became like, you know, the thing for Jews to celebrate during the holiday season so they could get presents for their kids, capitalism, you know, not feeling left out, etc.
Speaker 1: And I think that's sort of like, you know, every, I guess, you know, I guess not every, but like lots of different cultures and religions have done sort of the same thing, which is like, yeah, around the December times, you know, they do something even if they didn't originally have something, right?
Speaker 0: See, if I was making a new religion now, like say something bad happens and I have to form a cult.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like I would like that's probably my go to.
Speaker 0: if society collapsed.
Speaker 0: As I've said many times in my life, I would make that holiday in February because the idea for I would have is February is when you're sick of this shit.
Speaker 0: It's the coldest.
Speaker 1: February sucks ass.
Speaker 1: It's when we need a holiday the most.
Speaker 1: And all we got is shitty fake Valentine's Day.
Speaker 0: February should be the month of don't do anything.
Speaker 0: Forget a day of rest.
Speaker 0: We got a month of rest.
Speaker 0: That's how I do it.
Speaker 0: That's how my cult will operate after the apocalypse.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And I'll just say, right, you know, as as a Jew.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, when I looked around my town, there was plenty of Hanukkah going on.
Speaker 1: Because we had a disproportionate number of Jews relative to the world and national population.
Speaker 1: But, you know, in the I didn't realize until later on like how little Jewishness there was around everywhere else.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And so I perhaps didn't appreciate right full.
Speaker 1: I did appreciate somewhat.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But I didn't you know, I should have appreciated even more than I did.
Speaker 1: It's like when I saw like Hanukkah stuff on TV or something, I'd be like, oh, look at that.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Oh, we got some.
Speaker 1: But I should have been perhaps two or three times more excited about that because there's not a lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, Rugrats was like the one thing that had a Hanukkah and we were like, hell yes.
Speaker 0: That and Adam Sandler's song, actually, like there's a reason why that song is a Jew.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But that song pierced non-Jewish pop culture.
Speaker 0: Like people know that song.
Speaker 0: I'm not Jewish.
Speaker 0: I knew that song.
Speaker 0: I know all the words to that song.
Speaker 1: That song was a big deal in 1990, whatever.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: In Catholic school, funnily enough, unlike a lot of other Christian denominations, like being pretending to be Catholic as a young atheist in a Catholic school, the school actually did a better job than a lot of other schools of teaching about other religions.
Speaker 0: And they would do like a Hanukkah thing every year.
Speaker 0: But it was very simple and stereotypical.
Speaker 0: We'd all make dreidels, but we didn't.
Speaker 0: actually they didn't explain what the dreidel was.
Speaker 0: We just make them gambling.
Speaker 0: They did not explain that.
Speaker 0: And they would give us gelt, not really explaining, not really delicious, worse than Hershey's.
Speaker 1: But at least it comes in fun, gold foil wrappers.
Speaker 0: And usually we'd have the advent calendar, but we would also do the menorah in the Catholic school.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You know, the something about, you know, the menorah, it's like there's certain like the specific candle you put in the menorah.
Speaker 1: You buy this box.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And it's like this like, you know, I at least I recognize the box.
Speaker 1: Like it's like that's the only Hanukkah candle is the one that comes in that box.
Speaker 1: I forget I forget the name of it.
Speaker 1: What's the name of the stupid candle?
Speaker 1: I'm doing a Google search.
Speaker 1: There's other brands nowadays that have taken over.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But there's one specific one that's like the real one.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I've seen.
Speaker 0: I've seen, you know, because New York, very Jewish city, a lot of there's like everyone's got Christmas and Hanukkah stuff out, like very visibly.
Speaker 0: And in a lot of capital markets, like firms in their lobby, they'll usually have an extremely stylized to the point of almost being unrecognizable menorah.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I found the box, but the box actually.
Speaker 1: I guess the reason that I never had a name for this particular box is because it doesn't have a brand name on it.
Speaker 1: It just says, you know, 44 twist candles, twisted candles made in Israel, Hanukkah candles, kosher.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Product of Tel Aviv, Israel, telephone number.
Speaker 1: Forty four candles.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And is this very specific artwork and the candles like they have this wax that smells a specific way and melts it pretty quickly.
Speaker 1: Actually, they don't last very long for a holiday about oil that lasted too long.
Speaker 1: The Hanukkah candles sure don't last long at all.
Speaker 0: It's to remind you that you like.
Speaker 1: you like that shit.
Speaker 1: You like that shit after dinner.
Speaker 1: That shit's melted before you go to bed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, well, it's good because you won't create a fire hazard.
Speaker 0: Catholic churches, like really traditional ones.
Speaker 0: There's a big candle.
Speaker 0: I forget all the details of why we have it or why they have it.
Speaker 1: Is it like the votive candle or whatever?
Speaker 0: No, votive candles are a different thing.
Speaker 0: That's.
Speaker 0: that's the thing you see in movies where like someone lights a candle for someone who's dead.
Speaker 0: And usually there's a dramatic scene around it.
Speaker 0: There's movies where like the assassin will go.
Speaker 1: Jews have the candle for someone who's dead.
Speaker 1: It's the yahrzeit candle.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there's another candle that it's just the same candle forever.
Speaker 0: Like it'll.
Speaker 0: basically if you just lit it and left it lit, it will burn for fucking ever.
Speaker 0: And they light it like it's special times and they keep the same candle forever.
Speaker 0: But I found something great just skimming through the Wikipedia article on it, because I have associations mostly hanging out with you of like one, celebrating in quotes Christmas by just going out and getting Chinese food, which feels like a very Jewish holiday tradition.
Speaker 0: Go and see a movie.
Speaker 0: But also, you know, food like latkes.
Speaker 0: We'd always like made latkes around this time of year.
Speaker 1: Well, the reason you make the latkes for Hanukkah is because it's a holiday about oil.
Speaker 1: So you got to keep fry shit, right?
Speaker 0: So there's a section in the Wikipedia article.
Speaker 0: There's a paragraph.
Speaker 0: You're going to read it really quick that talks about what Jewish cultures in other parts of the world, like.
Speaker 0: what is their go to food around Hanukkah?
Speaker 0: Indian Jews traditionally consume a galab jamun, which is a like fried dough thing that I actually am a big fan of.
Speaker 0: Let's see.
Speaker 0: Italian Jews.
Speaker 0: Italian Jews eat fried chicken.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's fried.
Speaker 0: And they make a latke like thing out of ricotta.
Speaker 1: Mmm.
Speaker 0: Fratello de riso parrhatica, fried sweet potato pancakes.
Speaker 0: Romanian Jews eat pasta latkes.
Speaker 0: So again, fried.
Speaker 0: You see the theme is holding true.
Speaker 1: Oil.
Speaker 0: Syrian Jews eat a dish made with pumpkin and bulgur wheat that is similar to latkes.
Speaker 0: Mm hmm.
Speaker 0: That's the whole paragraph.
Speaker 0: We ran out.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: But yeah.
Speaker 1: So it's, you know, it's an oil based holiday.
Speaker 1: It's going to have oil based foods.
Speaker 0: I am a fan of oil based foods and I have enjoyed many a Christmas having Chinese food with you and our other friends.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, the thing about the latke that's most important isn't really the fried potato, which is, you know, a pain in the ass, right?
Speaker 1: It's the topping, right?
Speaker 1: You got sour cream and you got applesauce.
Speaker 1: And you can also go both at the same time.
Speaker 0: Both at the same time is the pro move.
Speaker 1: A lot of people, you know, but it's some people, they don't like the applesauce.
Speaker 1: Some people don't like sour cream.
Speaker 1: You know, they do it wrong.
Speaker 0: Thing is, what we did wrong was frying it wrong.
Speaker 0: We fucking sucked at that.
Speaker 0: We know how to cook so much better now.
Speaker 1: Listen, if you go to any Jewish family's house for a Hanukkah festivity, there's going to be basically fighting about who's going to fry the latkes.
Speaker 1: Because even if you don't do, it's not hard to make them.
Speaker 1: You shred up a potato on the box grater or your food processor.
Speaker 0: And if you know even like the bare basics of cooking with oil, you will not make the mistakes that we made in college.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, you put some flour and some other stuff in with the potato.
Speaker 0: Also, get the oil hot before you let the potatoes touch it.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, the oil just goes right into the potatoes and they're horrible.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But even if you use the mix, right, which doesn't taste bad at all, instead of doing the potato, it saves you a bit of work.
Speaker 1: You can't avoid the frying part.
Speaker 1: And it's like frying them kind of sucks and is like annoying to sit there and baby them and get oil all over yourself.
Speaker 0: You got to baby them way more than what I would say.
Speaker 0: you baby a typical fried dish.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So there's always going to be some sort of argument about who's going to do it.
Speaker 1: Who's going to get forced to actually make the latkes.
Speaker 1: Everyone wants to eat them.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But no one wants to make them.
Speaker 0: I imagine two parallel threads of contention because contention thread one, nobody wants to be the one stuck in the kitchen fucking making them.
Speaker 0: But contention thread two, nobody wants whoever's shitty at it being stuck making them.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So, you know, it was always interesting because it's like, you know, you got these eight days of Hanukkah.
Speaker 1: But you would still want to do like it's eight days.
Speaker 1: You're not going to hang out with your extended family for eight days.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Even at Christmas, like we would visit one of the set of grandparents on like Christmas Eve and another one on Christmas Day.
Speaker 0: And that was already.
Speaker 0: the entire family is at one hundred and fifty percent capacity of seeing relatives.
Speaker 0: And nobody wants to meet up again after that for a while.
Speaker 1: See, we were in, I guess, a lucky situation that only there were only cousins and children, which are all similarly aged on my father's side.
Speaker 1: No one really on my mother's side.
Speaker 1: So we only had to get one extended family for Hanukkah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And so, you know, you'd have your eight days and, you know, at home after dinner, it would be like we finished.
Speaker 1: You'd finish dinner, you'd light the candle, you'd get a present.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 1: Sometimes you just go to school the next day to come home, get another present.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Moms hide them in the basement.
Speaker 1: And then there would be one day where you'd get the extended family going on.
Speaker 1: Might not even be during the eight days if you couldn't manage it.
Speaker 1: schedule wise.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: That would be the extended family.
Speaker 1: Hanukkah presents for everybody.
Speaker 1: And then we got old and like around the time when we were in college.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Everyone was similarly aged.
Speaker 1: You know, we just sort of, you know, I think one time we tried, you know, everyone buy presents for everyone kind of deal.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And it was kind of meh.
Speaker 1: And then we're just like, you know what, buying presents is a pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: All of us are, you know, lucky and privileged and well off enough to buy shit we want for ourselves.
Speaker 1: No one fucking wants anything.
Speaker 1: Let's just, you know, the present will all give each other is not having to fucking go buy presents for everybody.
Speaker 1: And we just sort of stopped.
Speaker 1: We just sort of stopped the Hanukkah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: At least for the extended family.
Speaker 1: You know, I got a electric menorah.
Speaker 1: I actually made a USB powered menorah some years ago.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And I'm just like, you know what, you know, I don't believe in any of this nonsense, obviously, but it's fun to make.
Speaker 1: It's fun to have.
Speaker 1: So I can change the colors too.
Speaker 1: I don't got to set a fire.
Speaker 1: Don't got to melt any candles.
Speaker 0: I mean, this weekend I'm going to go out on the balcony and hang up some Christmas lights for the rest of the year and maybe a few weeks into the new year like I do.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm a I'm an angry, loud atheist.
Speaker 0: It's not like I believe in Christmas, but I still like.
Speaker 0: I like a good Christmas song hanging out in the snow.
Speaker 1: But I think maybe next week I'll deal with the pain in the ass and make a latke.
Speaker 0: Ooh, make a latke.
Speaker 1: Maybe this weekend I'll make a latke, even though it's a little early because Hanukkah starts on Sunday night.
Speaker 0: Make the practice latke this weekend.
Speaker 1: Make it on Sunday night.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: So I guess it's time to go see how that hockey game's going.
Speaker 0: I think we'll stop the show right there.
Speaker 1: It didn't start yet because they got some ceremonies.
Speaker 0: Oh, good.
Speaker 0: I was worried.
Speaker 1: It's about to start like in Tuesday.
Speaker 0: Perfect timing.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of Geek Nights are Alan Joyce, Link Iggi, Jarett, Lily Tenenbaum, Chris Hadad, Chris Reimer, Clinton Walton, Dex, Finn, Jewel Hayes, Rebecca Dunn, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Harl.
Speaker 0: Stop all the downloading.
Speaker 0: And many people who have wisely made their pledges down to a dollar or so.
Speaker 0: So I won't say their names because otherwise this list would be way too long.
Speaker 0: But yeah, whatever.
Speaker 0: Rangers 1, we finished the episode right before the Rangers game started, thankfully.
Speaker 0: And for now, I leave you with...