Speaker 0: It's Thursday, July 7th, 2022.
Speaker 0: I'm Rym.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is the Geek Nights Book Club.
Speaker 0: That's a name I haven't heard in a while.
Speaker 0: Tonight, to quote Scott, after the Genji debacle, we have moved on to Nine Fox Gambit by Yoon Ha Lee.
Speaker 0: And tonight, we are going to talk about Nine Fox Gambit.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So, since, you know, we've only done... If we take out the average number of book club books per year, that stat looks great until recently.
Speaker 0: So, if you're not familiar, just to be very clear, we are going to assume that you have already read Nine Fox Gambit.
Speaker 0: So, we're not going to explain the plot.
Speaker 0: We're not going to worry about spoilers.
Speaker 0: We're going to talk about this book like we would among ourselves and with our friends.
Speaker 0: And you're a friend who has read this book.
Speaker 0: So, if you have not read this book, I would suggest you stop listening to this episode and go read Nine Fox Gambit first and then listen to this episode.
Speaker 0: But I can't stop you, I guess, so...
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you really just want to hear people talk about a book you haven't read or partially read, I mean, that's your choice.
Speaker 0: I mean, I did read How Attack on Titan Ends to decide if I would continue watching it.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: I didn't continue watching it after reading that, so...
Speaker 1: Anyway, so yeah, the deal was, you know, we've had this book club thing going on.
Speaker 1: We had the Tale of Genji debacle, where it took way too long to read for a number of reasons.
Speaker 1: And then after that, you know, we alternate choosing books, right?
Speaker 1: So, Rym chose City We Became, which was, you know, we discussed, you can go listen to our episodes about that to discuss whatever you got to hear about that one.
Speaker 1: And then it was back to me, it was back to me again.
Speaker 1: And I was the one who... I chose the Genji.
Speaker 1: I take the full responsibility, right?
Speaker 0: But you could not have foreseen a global pandemic, like getting rid of my commute.
Speaker 0: Not
Speaker 1: at all, but if I had, you know, if I had chosen differently, chosen a very easy to read, small fantasy sci-fi novel like A Good Nerd, and not the first novel ever written by humans ever, in another language, in an archaic style of that foreign language, and then translated, that is very long,
Speaker 0: Well, you did also choose the unabridged version, and two, there's no...
Speaker 1: You always gotta choose an unabridged version.
Speaker 0: All I'm saying is, if push comes to shove, there is an unabridged Count of Monte Cristo.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so yeah, you know, I take responsibility for that choice, right?
Speaker 1: And to make up for that choice, I said, "All right, well, it's my turn
Speaker 1: again.".
Speaker 1: This seems unfair that it was my turn for two years plus, then it was Rym's turn for like a month.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's still Scott Johnson's turn in that 5 game.
Speaker 1: And then it was my turn again already, and it's like, "Well, this seems wrong.
Speaker 1: What should I do?
Speaker 1: Should I give Rym more picks because I make up for all that
Speaker 1: time?".
Speaker 1: Because Rym read the book slowly, too.
Speaker 1: He's also partially responsible.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, there was a joint effort.
Speaker 1: It's not like Rym finished it in a week or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was a joint effort in The Tale of Genji right there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway, so I'm like, "All right, here's what I'll do to make up for it, right?
Speaker 1: I won't even pick.
Speaker 1: I will defer my pick because I know the listener of this show has always frequently and for a long time asked us to read one particular
Speaker 1: book.".
Speaker 1: And I said, "You know what?
Speaker 1: I actually don't know anything about that book other than that.
Speaker 1: it's, you know, a sci-fi novel of some kind.
Speaker 1: But I know the listener has asked many times for us to choose that book and I said, "All right, to make up for the fact that I chose Genji and we fucked it up, I'm going to choose the book the listener wants, right?
Speaker 1: And we'll let the listener pick this one.
Speaker 1: and the listener has always wanted us to read Nine Fox Gambit by Yoon Ha Lee and I didn't know what the hell it was about.
Speaker 1: And then I read it and then after finishing reading it, I made the pick.
Speaker 1: Well, it's like.
Speaker 1: I knew that's what I was going to pick but I finished reading it already before we did the episode on City We Became.
Speaker 0: I actually finished it a while ago.
Speaker 0: In fact, full disclosure, I will not dwell, I will not bring the second or third books into this because we only read the first one officially, but I'm pretty much almost done with all these books now.
Speaker 0: I just kept going.
Speaker 1: That's how RIM does.
Speaker 1: If we read a book that's the first in a series as a book club book, RIM almost always, 99.9% of the time, goes on to read the entire series.
Speaker 1: I usually will just read the one book and stop or I will wait till the whole series is done and try to read it all.
Speaker 1: Sometimes finishing, sometimes not.
Speaker 1: But RIM, he just goes, oh, we did one culture book.
Speaker 1: Time to read every culture book.
Speaker 1: Oh, we read one Wheel of Time book.
Speaker 1: Time to read every Wheel of Time book.
Speaker 0: All 14.
Speaker 1: We read one Nine Fox Gambit book.
Speaker 1: Time to read the whole series, whatever that series is called.
Speaker 1: What is the series called?
Speaker 0: Machines of Empire?
Speaker 0: Machineries of Empire.
Speaker 1: So RIM has read, just so you know, Nine Fox Gambit is the first in a series of books called Machineries of Empire and RIM read, I guess, this three of them?
Speaker 0: I just finished the second one.
Speaker 1: But there are three that have been published so far.
Speaker 0: I don't know if there are more than three that are coming.
Speaker 0: I have not looked into this at all.
Speaker 1: But there are three, if you could read right now, there are three available.
Speaker 1: Correct?
Speaker 0: As far as I can see.
Speaker 1: I did not look too closely.
Speaker 1: So Nine Fox Gambit is a sci-fi novel.
Speaker 1: It takes place in outer space.
Speaker 1: There is a spaceship and a planet, well, space station and some spaceships on the cover.
Speaker 1: And it delivers on all of that, as well as delivering on many other things that are much more worthy of discussion.
Speaker 0: Like if I had to sell it to someone who is not sold on it and it was someone who is like me, I would probably say that this is Utena Space Battle Calendar Warfare with ghosts.
Speaker 0: And that's accurate and I think it would get someone who wouldn't otherwise read it to read it.
Speaker 1: Alright, so the calendars, right?
Speaker 1: The central, you know, there's a lot of themes obviously because it's really boring to have a book which is sort of one idea.
Speaker 1: If you only have one thing to say, that's not a whole novel, right?
Speaker 0: That's a Ray Bradbury short at that point.
Speaker 1: Right, exactly.
Speaker 1: You gotta have a whole lot of things to say but, you know, swirl those around as side threads around your core central thread and the central thread being colonialism, right?
Speaker 1: You know, imperialism, et cetera, right?
Speaker 1: And using the calendar as sort of, you know, a type of magic slash technology really fits well with that.
Speaker 1: because if you think about the history of the world, you think about things like, you know, Jews having a lunar calendar or a lot of countries having lunar calendars, right?
Speaker 1: East Asia, lunar calendars, right?
Speaker 1: Aztec Maya calendars, right?
Speaker 1: Things of that nature.
Speaker 1: is that, you know, historically when humans have colonized, invaded other humans, they replaced their calendar that those people are using and now forced those people to live by their calendar, right?
Speaker 1: So imagine if there was an island in the Pacific Ocean that we had never discovered somehow and there were people living on it, or maybe Atlantis is real, we find it, right?
Speaker 1: We go there, we, you know, we're talking about replacing people's language, right?
Speaker 1: So we can communicate with them, right?
Speaker 1: But we might not replace their language, right?
Speaker 1: We might just, you know, have translators.
Speaker 1: But, you know, if we were to colonize them or even soft colonize them, you know, maybe they're living, like, maybe they don't go by days, you know, 'cause they're at the bottom of the sea.
Speaker 1: They don't even see the sun coming up, right?
Speaker 1: It's like they go by the tide, right?
Speaker 1: So every time the tide comes in and out, that's a new cycle for them of whatever their thing is, right?
Speaker 1: And then they count, I don't know, ten of those, 'cause ten, they still, you know, they arrived and realized decimal numbers are great, even though their math developed separately.
Speaker 1: And so every ten tide changes, right?
Speaker 1: You know, they take a day off of ocean work, right?
Speaker 1: You know, it's like that's how they live.
Speaker 1: We come down there and we start doing things by the, you know, seven days a week with the sun doing days and the movement of the Earth.
Speaker 1: It's like, and we force that upon them, right, is now we can now change their way of life to match our way of life by imposing our calendar upon them.
Speaker 0: - And in this way, this entire book is an allegory to that.
Speaker 0: and that allegory, interestingly, compared to many similar allegories in literature, holds up even to absurd extremes.
Speaker 0: and you can almost read this book as taking that allegory and treating the allegory as literal truth and then exploring every possible edge case.
Speaker 0: and it kind of continues to work.
Speaker 1: - Right, in this universe, right, living according to a particular calendar results in, like, actual power, right?
Speaker 0: - Yep, like the more people in a place follow a very specific calendar and the more specific that calendar is, the more exotic powers everyone in that civilization can wield if they're within the realm of that calendar's, like, control or influence on the universe.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, and also, like, people can come and, like, have heretical calendars to, like, sort of battle.
Speaker 1: Like, they're battling directly with the calendars.
Speaker 1: It's like in the real world, you battle with something else.
Speaker 1: Might or money or something.
Speaker 0: - Space or sex battles.
Speaker 1: - Right, and then the calendar is just something that you, you know, impose to control after domination has occurred, but here, the calendar actually is, you know, the weapon as well, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you battle with the calendar itself.
Speaker 0: - Well, considering that, like-- - In order to impose it.
Speaker 0: - One of the, 'cause the other thing this book is is if you read Iain M. Banks' culture book Use of Weapons, it's also that exact conversation.
Speaker 0: What is a weapon?
Speaker 0: A calendar is just another weapon.
Speaker 0: Or Judeo, what's one of the first things he says?
Speaker 0: I am your gun.
Speaker 1: - Yep, I mean, and in the same fashion in this book, right, when there are actual military battles in this book, 'cause there are plenty of them, both on the ground.
Speaker 1: I mean, the book starts with a ground military battle, right, of, like, infantry battling, and it also has plenty of space battles between spaceships shooting lasers at each other - Also duels between individual people just fighting all the time.
Speaker 1: - Right, but at least when the battles involve groups of people, right, the formations become important, right, and this actual magical slash technological power that comes from having people in formations, both, and they don't really describe the formations in detail, 'cause they don't need to.
Speaker 1: They just get across that both the physical positions of the people relative to each other-- - And their mental states.
Speaker 1: - As well as their mental alignment, right, with each other creates formations, and those formations have actual real world weaponry, you know, weaponry powers of some kind, and that different peoples and different groups in different formations, right, you know, have sort of a rock, paper, scissors deal kind of going on.
Speaker 1: And so a military battle is people, you know, changing their formations, right, to sort of fight with each other, and if you think of a calendar, a calendar is really just a formation for society, right?
Speaker 0: - I mean, look, right now, we're doing gig nights because it's Thursday.
Speaker 0: We could've done this book club book weeks ago, almost a month ago.
Speaker 1: - Could've done it in the morning.
Speaker 1: - But you know what?
Speaker 0: We did it on Thursday, even though it probably would've been easier to do it earlier.
Speaker 0: The calendar has control over us, too.
Speaker 1: - I'm not even working.
Speaker 1: I'm not even working until Monday, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, days mean nothing for me, and I don't watch scheduled television.
Speaker 1: - But in fact, we don't even question the calendar.
Speaker 0: Like, gig nights lined up with the Stanley Cup.
Speaker 0: We didn't move gig nights.
Speaker 0: We just didn't do gig nights.
Speaker 1: - It seems easier.
Speaker 0: - But also think about this from the perspective of society.
Speaker 0: Like, if you conform to the sort of general way the society you live in functions, regardless of whether or not you believe in, like, that that's the right way, your life is just better.
Speaker 0: Like, if I stopped wearing pants, I wouldn't die, but I probably wouldn't continue to be gainfully employed in the way that I am today.
Speaker 0: And this is, like, one of the fundamental themes of this whole book.
Speaker 0: is, like, this society and is it healthy and is this sustainable as a society shifts from being, in a far future, individuals making decisions within a system to individuals being nothing more than the substrate upon which the system itself exists.
Speaker 0: One could argue that as you read this book, all these factions that get mentioned are basically intelligent, sentient gods that are just composed of a bunch of people following these formations.
Speaker 0: And the Hexarchate, which used to be the Heparchate, or Heptarchate, is basically just this metagod.
Speaker 0: And you even get this in detail.
Speaker 0: Like, I love the bits when you see little snippets of parts of the universe that would be world-building that in a less well-written sci-fi novel you would get a lot of detail on, but this book does a good job of giving you just enough to get the idea and then just moving on and trusting you to have understood it.
Speaker 0: But there's this idea in the cowl of the composites, and I find that fascinating.
Speaker 0: that, you know, say in my real job, I'm a product manager, right?
Speaker 0: I make decisions, and I have a bunch of people who work for me and with me, but what if I merged my brain when I was at work in a machine, like a VR magic brain machine, with all of my peers, and we together formed a composite entity that made decisions like a single person, and then we signed out of that thing at the end of the day.
Speaker 0: And it's clear that that's how senior commanders in the kelp operate.
Speaker 0: They form composites instead of individuals.
Speaker 1: And so, right, you go from that idea to what the actual story of the book is that there is a single kelp commander, right?
Speaker 0: - Good old Judeo, the deuce of gears.
Speaker 1: - Well, not that guy.
Speaker 1: - Oh, Kel Cheris, our main character?
Speaker 1: - The main character of the book, right?
Speaker 1: And the book starts off showing you, you know, Kel Cheris in a space battle on the ground, right, and formations and all that, right?
Speaker 1: Sort of, you know, get a little action intro.
Speaker 1: -
Speaker 0: But I gotta say, that in media res action intro, not every sci-fi book, even ones that I end up really liking hook me immediately, but I gotta say, the first few paragraphs of this book pulled me in in the same way that the first Prince of Nothing book did.
Speaker 0: I read one paragraph and I backed up and said, "Wait, what the
Speaker 0: fuck?".
Speaker 1: - I get the feeling, it almost feels like they really want there to be a movie with that kind of intro.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, but I like how--.
Speaker 1: - They really want a movie deal.
Speaker 0: - But all the details of even that initial--.
Speaker 1: - 'Cause if you make any sci-fi book that becomes a movie, you have to start with a space battle, right?
Speaker 1: - Star Wars, immediate space battle, right?
Speaker 0: - You get a Karelian Corvette, or no, you get--.
Speaker 1: - Pee-pee-pee, immediate space battle right at the start, that's what you gotta do, you know, anyway.
Speaker 0: - But I like how these space battles too, like, in terms of trusting the audience, it will throw proper nouns at you that are not explained, but they don't need to be, because there's, just like in the Prince of Nothing and a lot of other well-written books that do this sort of thing, the context is enough to know what you need to know as a reader without having to explain it all in detail.
Speaker 1: - If the book took the time to explain to you, like, ah, their calendar is eight days, and this day is this, and this day is that, and this is how, it's like, it would gain you, it would add nothing to the meaning, you know, or the message of the book whatsoever, it would just take up space, it would be stuff to memorize, nerds would love it, right, certain kinds of nerds who love that shit, you know, the kinds who would write RPG books would love that shit, but it would serve no purpose other than to be a boring part of the book, so they don't, it's like, all you need to know is that they have calendars, and the calendar matters, and the formations, and they matter, and it's like, that's all you need to know.
Speaker 0: - Yep, but I like how everyone's favorite weapon in this book, which they do come up in the other books too, the threshold winnowers, those are mentioned in the first sentence of the book.
Speaker 1: - And they explain the effect of the threshold winnower, 'cause that's what you need to know, how dangerous and terrifying a weapon it is, and when it was used, historically, you need to know that also, to give you the correct respect for it, right, but you don't need to know how it works.
Speaker 1: You know, anything like that, they only tell you what you need to know.
Speaker 0: - The most detailed description you get of a threshold winnower is, actually, there's a little quote here, quote, that returning to corpses that were only corpses, rather than radiation gates contorted against black, blasted walls and glassy rubble, eyes ruptured open, like, it does something horrible, and one thing that's interesting about all the space battles and fights and formations, in my mind, I almost imagine them like the witches in Madoka Magica, like, it is abstract, multidimensional nonsense that is happening in the literal world of this book when the calendar effects are applied.
Speaker 1: - Oh, I actually imagine, you know, in my mind, I imagine the space battles look a lot like, you know, Starcraft, right, like, or, you know, space marines, right, but the space marines have all sorts of like, you know, like, all kinds of like, you know, superhero laser blasts and all kinds
Speaker 0: of ridiculous things that aren't, you know,
Speaker 1: that aren't necessarily coming from any sort of canon, right, just be like, you know, casting magic spells at each other, like they're all the Silver Surfer or some shit.
Speaker 0: - They kind of are, but some of these, like the variable, actually, that's from the second, a bunch of the effects that get described are like the variable geometry inside of the ships, like, clearly, they're like, just, rooms can move and be duplicated and teleported around and all sorts of ridiculous, like, rewrite the world magic from this technology, and it's never really explained.
Speaker 0: 'cause it doesn't actually matter, you get it pretty much right away, and I just, I appreciate that because I'm so sick of reading sci-fi books that are full of a lot of world building instead of getting to the good part.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, so, you got this main character, Calcheris, right, in this, in this-- - She's great, by the way.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, there's a, there's a, there's basically, the thing that I think is really interesting is that the main character and the entire focus of the book is from the perspective of the bad guys.
Speaker 1: It would be like a fucking, I don't know, not Darth Vader, but like, maybe, you know, some really high-ranking TIE fighter pilot.
Speaker 1: Who is the, who is the silver character from the, the, the newer Star Wars sequels?
Speaker 0: - Oh, God, I, I-- - The Stormtrooper one.
Speaker 1: What was her name?
Speaker 0: - I've already lost them.
Speaker 1: I've, I've-- - Right, imagine if, like, that was the main character of the book.
Speaker 1: It's like, Calcheris is, you know, not a bad person, but is necessarily, but is on the bad guys' side, and is not--.
Speaker 0: - Well, it's interesting in that they're the bad
Speaker 1: guys-- - Is fighting for the bad guys, and is not at all, and usually when you have that scenario in a book, nine, 99 times out of 100, it's a story of that good main character realizing they're working for the bad guys and rebelling, and something like, or revolutioning.
Speaker 1: In this case, no, she is 100% on the side of the bad guys, is on the bad guy team, full on, and the whole story is from the focus of the bad guys, being bad.
Speaker 0: - Well, I will say, I will say one thing from the future books.
Speaker 0: I don't think there are good guys.
Speaker 1: - There might not be, but the Heftar Kate/Ceptar Kate is definitely an evil empire.
Speaker 1: - It is at best, it
Speaker 0: is a moral and sort of self-perpetuating empire in the way that empires are, and there are other empires that are similarly powerful with their own calendars adjacent to it, but it definitely is, like, it is clear that these heresies come up a lot, and that this empire, not only is it doing a lot of horrible things, it is not even close to as stable as it appears to be in the start of the book.
Speaker 0: Like, you figure out pretty quick how dire this whole situation is in this book.
Speaker 1: - Well, I mean, they tell you pretty much right away, right, that, A, it used to be a Septar Kate.
Speaker 1: There used to be seven factions within the empire, controlling different parts of the society, and it's now a Septar Kate, not, a Heftar Kate, because they excised one of them.
Speaker 0: - Hexar Kate.
Speaker 0: now, it's six now.
Speaker 1: - Hex, right, Hexar Kate.
Speaker 1: - It used to be seven.
Speaker 1: - Whatever, right.
Speaker 0: - 'Cause there's a little blur at one point where someone counts, says weeks, like two weeks, and someone else is weirded out by it, 'cause they're like, why would you say two weeks instead of 14 days?
Speaker 0: That is almost heretical, what you just said.
Speaker 1: - Yep, but anyway, the faction that was excised was the one that was responsible for, oh, morality and ethics, right?
Speaker 1: - Yep.
Speaker 1: - So that's like, that's explicitly telling you.
Speaker 0: - Well, I love, well, they hit you over the head with it in case you missed it, because, you know, in the whole beginning, you keep getting those transmissions between two people, you don't really know who they are about, like, what's going on.
Speaker 1: - Oh, before, no.
Speaker 1: There's another thing that tells you how evil it is.
Speaker 0: - But in one of those transmissions, eventually it gets stated out loud that it basically, the book does a thing like, you ever heard of something called the moon?
Speaker 0: But it does that with, the heresy was called democracy.
Speaker 0: Like, they just beat you over the head with it if you didn't get it up to that point.
Speaker 0: Because in those early discussions, they talk a lot about how, oh yeah, in the fortress we took over, like, polling is going well, and a vote's gonna happen on X, and it doesn't really explain that right away.
Speaker 1: - Well, I mean, the thing that really tells you how evil the empire is-- - The remembrances, what you find out what those actually are.
Speaker 1: - Yes, there's the remembrances, right?
Speaker 1: So, as part of their calendar, right, there's also rituals, right, that had to be performed, holidays, right?
Speaker 1: That's a part of a calendar, too.
Speaker 0: - I like how the book sneaks this up on you, 'cause they're pretty benign, the ones you hear about at first, and then it doesn't actually reveal to you how horrific and violent the remembrances are.
Speaker 1: - Well, it just tells you, it basically says they're horrific and violent.
Speaker 0: - Yeah, they do, like, ridiculous torture of heretics as part of these remembrances.
Speaker 1: - Right, well, or maybe not even heretics, maybe just anyone, right?
Speaker 1: But the point is, yes, as part of their holidays, in order to make their calendar work, right, the calendar that they have constructed will not hold its power unless they conduct these particular remembrance rituals that involve ritual torture and sacrifice of people, right?
Speaker 0: - Yep, so not a great society.
Speaker 1: - Right, they would, some people would like to, right, there are some people who express their thoughts, like, yeah, we would like to get rid of these remembrances, even though the ethics and morals have been excised from their empire, right?
Speaker 1: There is sort of like, you know, a distaste for the remembrances, like, yeah, we wish we didn't have to do those, but they recognize this absolute truth that if they didn't have those, their calendar would lose all its power, and they would have to use, and it's like, well, they try to come up with a different calendar that would work without the remembrances, right, and they can't seem to come up with one, so they're just ritually torturing and sacrificing people and being okay with that, and
Speaker 0: so, yes.
Speaker 0: - They rationalize it that there's no alternative we know of yet, and that's how they rationalize it as a society.
Speaker 1: - But they're just chill with that, they're just like, yeah, remembrances.
Speaker 0: - But it's also interesting how that sort of-- - They're the evil empire, with no question whatsoever.
Speaker 1: - That
Speaker 0: fits back into this, like, overarching theme in the book around how the Hex Arcade itself almost ends up functioning and having an inertia and a will on its own, arguably even despite the preferences and will of all the people that constitute it, like, you could have a society, but in the real world, we do have societies like this where the far majority of people want reasonable things, yet the society itself chooses the opposite of what the majority of its people want.
Speaker 0: I'm not talking one dictator, I'm talking, like, the society itself, 'cause it's very clear as you start to see the leaders later in the book of the society.
Speaker 1: - You see the leaders early, and I think you don't see them later on, right?
Speaker 1: They're like, right at the start of the book, there's this one chapter with a character who is the leader of one of the sections, one of the six groups, and it's pretty clear that even though there should be six equal leaders, it's pretty clear this person is effectively President, Emperor, King, whatever.
Speaker 1: They're actually the one above the others at least by a little bit, right?
Speaker 1: And he's gotta deal with one of the other ones, one of the other five equals, right?
Speaker 0: - I will say in the second and third books, or at least in the second book for sure, you see a lot of their board meetings, basically.
Speaker 0: You see a lot of them interacting with each other.
Speaker 1: - I'd imagine so, right?
Speaker 1: And the other one he's dealing with is sort of like, I guess he comes across, I forget his name, he comes basically the guy who's keeping Jidao, right?
Speaker 0: - Oh yeah, well there's Kujin, the guy who is basically one of the few people in the empire who figured out within this calendar a way to be immortal.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, so that's the guy who keeps Jidao, that's the, you know, he basically comes across to me like a mad vizier wizard dude.
Speaker 0: - Oh absolutely, that guy is, 'cause the one thing we know from this book about immortality is that he's got some way to be immortal that everyone's trying to figure out.
Speaker 0: The other factions are trying to figure out their own ways to be immortal, and all we know is that they know a little bit about how he does it and they don't think it's a good idea and they wouldn't do it to themselves.
Speaker 1: - Anyone else who's tried has suffered and died horribly.
Speaker 0: - And we also learn toward the end of the book, like the final puzzle piece, that it's probably very similar to what they did to Jidao, our semi-main character.
Speaker 1: - Well, it involved the same piece of technology, what did they call it?
Speaker 0: - The Black Cradle.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, the Black Cradle is what you have to, right, so really, anyone who's ever messed with the Black Cradle ended up in bad or dead shape, except for Jidao, who we'll talk about in a second.
Speaker 0: - So I love how he is portrayed as insane.
Speaker 1: - And Kujin, who became, you know, a mad, vizier, wizard, immortal dude.
Speaker 0: - Yep, so we've got Kujin, who is immortal and appears to be insane to some degree, and then we've got Jidao, who, everyone in this society is telling us, the reader, this person is insane, but then when we meet this person, they seem perfectly reasonable and perfectly rational and that stays true all the way to the end of the first book.
Speaker 1: - Yep.
Speaker 0: - Like, it's hard to disagree with them.
Speaker 1: - Jidao did something in the past that was horrifying, right?
Speaker 0: - Yep, I like how.
Speaker 0: what he did was basically win a battle and then also destroy his own forces and then murder all of his staff.
Speaker 1: - Yep, so, yeah, so there was, Kel Cheris is just a commander in the Kel section of the Hex Arcade, right?
Speaker 1: - Yep.
Speaker 1: - Which is a military section, right, so they're a military-- - Yeah, what do we got, we got the Kel, the Shuos, like, that's where, that's the-- - Those are basically like the spy type, you know, people, right?
Speaker 1: The intelligence, CIA type people.
Speaker 0: - Yep, the rest of them, the Narai, the scientists.
Speaker 1: - Yep.
Speaker 1: -
Speaker 0: And I think the
Speaker 1: rest of
Speaker 0: them don't really come up in detail in book one, but basically they're all like--
Speaker 1: - Those are the ones that, I forget the name of the--
Speaker 0: - Well, there's the Rahal, there's the Vedona--
Speaker 1: - The heretical, ethical, moral ones that were--
Speaker 0: - Yep, and the Vedona actually come up in the first book because they enforce doctrine, they're the ones who enforce those rituals.
Speaker 1: - Right, exactly, right, okay, so, but anyway, so you got Kel, military, basically a space marine, and she wins a battle, and apparently, you know, the president guy is like, hey, we got a problem.
Speaker 1: There's, you know, completely separate from what Cheris is doing, right?
Speaker 1: - Yep.
Speaker 1: - He's like, look, there's this, you know, we have this space station called the Fortress of Scattered Needles, I believe, right?
Speaker 0: - Yeah, 'cause the other fortress that gets mentioned is the Fortress of Spinshot Coins.
Speaker 1: - Right, and so, you got a culture thing already where the space station and all the ships have names and have personalities and AIs and whatnot.
Speaker 0: - Yep, oh, wait a minute, we'll save the servitor talk, I got a lot to say about the servitors.
Speaker 1: - Right, so this Fortress of Scattered Needles is a basically, it's like a huge space colony, it's not like just like a, you know, like a little tiny space station, like the International Space Station, it's like basically a floating, you know, entire colony, like an arcology, basically, right?
Speaker 1: It's enormous, it's floating in space somewhere and it's being conquered, attacked by some heretics with a different calendar of some kind, right?
Speaker 1: It's been infiltrated and taken over and that's not good because, you know, in terms of not just the calendar, but just the formations of their entire society, the control over that space station, its position, its behavior is important.
Speaker 1: and now the fact that they lost control over it means that some other calendars, some other civilizations are encroaching, right?
Speaker 0: - The Haffen are coming in.
Speaker 1: - Exactly, the Haffen, all we really know is that they're some other empire with a different calendar, right?
Speaker 1: They're heretics, right?
Speaker 1: They're other.
Speaker 0: - And they seem to in some way be helping the heretical uprising in this fortress.
Speaker 1: - But we don't know really too much about them other than that they are other, right?
Speaker 1: They're enemies of the Hex Arcade.
Speaker 0: - So yeah, book two, you'll learn a lot about them if you're curious.
Speaker 1: - I'm sure you do.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so yeah, the leaders of the Hex Arcade are like we gotta do something about this and in a very sort of Prince of Nothing fashion, they come before, right?
Speaker 1: And it's like they know what they want to happen but rather than just order it to happen directly by saying do this, right?
Speaker 1: They set up circumstances presumably using their calendar powers and formation powers such that Calcheris, right, is set upon a path to doing what they were gonna order to happen but coming into it of like believing it was her idea and that they agreed to it and let her try
Speaker 0: it.
Speaker 0: - So what's really interesting is having read more of the books, I get the impression that it's even more so than that that it's almost like it's the same way that in a big company or a big military organization in the real world, you have to exert soft power like to get something to happen that if you ordered it outright, people would resist.
Speaker 0: but if it happened quote unquote.
Speaker 0: naturally, people would just assume it came about by a consensus.
Speaker 0: but I love how they depict that because the technology with the signifiers, like everyone's got a signifier, it's basically your, I don't know, your avatar in a chat room, you don't even get to pick it, like it picks you to a degree but then you choose, like there's this whole thing in the book of course but I like how the way they do the interviews is.
Speaker 0: they basically get a bunch of people to each present, here's what I would do if you put me in charge of this situation.
Speaker 1: and everyone's got a very-- - Right, it's like the space station is being conquered, right, we gathered you all here because you're all top quality people in our empire.
Speaker 1: Everyone present your idea on how to solve it, right, and they just go around the room just like normal people, like what's your idea, and someone who's like really big spaceships, right, it's like--
Speaker 0: - But what's cool is they do it anonymously and that's a big theme in these books, there are parts of this empire that are actually way more progressive than anything we have in the real world today despite the other far worse problems of the empire.
Speaker 0: Like the way they do this process, regardless of what you look like, they hide the identities of the people, so they're only evaluated based on the quality of their plan, but at the same time, people certainly look through.
Speaker 0: - They know.
Speaker 0: - Some of them know, some of them clearly don't, even Cheris is like, that one's gotta be a composite the way he's talking, hmm, well the way they're talking.
Speaker 1: - But anyway, the main problem that they're trying to solve is not just reconquer the space station, it's specifically.
Speaker 1: the space station has a technology called ice, the internment ice?
Speaker 0: - The invariant ice, 'cause there are--.
Speaker 1: - Invariant ice.
Speaker 0: - There are technologies, as you read the book, I'm assuming, that rely on the calendars, and there are far weaker, fewer technologies that are named invariant in that they work no matter whose calendar it is, like they are fundamental to the universe.
Speaker 1: - Right, so the invariant ice, they don't really describe it too much, but you get the idea that it's basically an impenetrable ice shield of some kind, and there's basically no way through it, like nobody knows how to get through it, and the sort of an open question of, well, if the space station had invariant ice, how did it fall to begin with?
Speaker 0: - Well, 'cause it fell from within.
Speaker 1: - Right, exactly.
Speaker 1: So, but now to take it from the outside, you have to beat the ice, so really what the people are presenting are not ideas on how to conquer a space station, 'cause the answer is a bunch of spaceships, right?
Speaker 1: It's space battleships.
Speaker 1: It's how are you gonna beat the ice, right?
Speaker 1: What's your idea, right?
Speaker 1: Whoever has the best idea will go with it, and it was basically predetermined that they knew that Kel Cheris was gonna have the idea that they wanted to go with, and it was basically predetermined that that was the idea they were gonna accept.
Speaker 0: - Now, I would accept or believe that they didn't choose Kel Cheris ahead of time, but when the moment came, they looked at all the existing Kel who were out there from their candidate list to see which of them might be in a circumstance that we could pull them into this.
Speaker 0: I'll bet they had other people who were likely to make the same decision, and she was the one who happened to have just disgraced herself in their eyes and thus given them the opportunity.
Speaker 1: - Right, so they go around the room, and they don't even finish going around the room.
Speaker 1: They get to Kel Cheris.
Speaker 1: She says the idea that you knew they were gonna say.
Speaker 0: - I love how she's like, "I'm gonna unfreeze Judeo and have him do it,".
Speaker 0: and then everyone else is like, "What the
Speaker 0: fuck?".
Speaker 1: - Yeah, other people are just like, "I leave the room, forget my idea," right?
Speaker 0: - 'Cause as far as the society's concerned, yeah, one guy immediately is like, "I retract my
Speaker 0: proposal.".
Speaker 0: - Yep, exactly, yeah.
Speaker 1: They're just like, "All right, go
Speaker 1: ahead.".
Speaker 1: They don't even ask anyone else in the room.
Speaker 1: They don't get all the way around the table.
Speaker 1: They're like, "All right, we just had to "sort of do this formality to get this result we wanted.
Speaker 1: "We're here, let's not waste any more time," right?
Speaker 0: - Yep.
Speaker 1: - So what does this mean, right?
Speaker 1: So there's this dude, Judeo, who we already talked about, who fucking was like the best.
Speaker 1: He was like the ultimate warrior.
Speaker 0: - What is it, he has never lost-- - He has never lost a major engagement, ever.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, he's basically just like, you know, the ultimate, you know, super strong, perfect dude.
Speaker 1: But he's dead.
Speaker 1: Well, not entirely dead, right?
Speaker 1: He has immortality thanks to the Black Cradle, only he's not in a corporeal form.
Speaker 1: He's somehow frozen in some kind of thing.
Speaker 0: It's not entirely-- It really feels like some sort of, "We have copied his brain into a computer "and we saved it for future
Speaker 0: use.".
Speaker 1: - Exactly, right.
Speaker 1: They don't explain it because it's not necessary to explain it, just like they don't explain how the calendar's working for detail, right?
Speaker 0: - I do like the foreshadowing of the carrion glass and the carrion gun because that comes into play in the very end.
Speaker 1: - Chekhov's carrion glass.
Speaker 0: - Yep, 'cause full circle in the very end when he basically has convinced or tricked Kel Cheris into subsuming herself into him and just giving her his body.
Speaker 0: And his plan
Speaker 1: all
Speaker 0: along was clearly, my reading of this, just from the first book, he won those battles even if he disagreed with anything this empire was doing because his only plan was to eventually, they'll get him out and they'll put him in a situation that gives him the opportunity to destroy this fucking empire that he has hated for his entire life.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, this dude is just, I guess, only in an incorporeal form of some kind.
Speaker 0: - It's very much like, he's frozen by the Nazis.
Speaker 0: Every couple hundred years, the Nazis wake him up and send him to fight a battle they don't think they can win.
Speaker 1: - He's like a ghost.
Speaker 0: - And every time he decides, can I win this or not?
Speaker 0: And could I destroy the Nazis instead of winning this?
Speaker 1: - He's a ghost and he possesses Kel Cheris, I guess, consensually.
Speaker 0: - Yep.
Speaker 1: - And when she looks in the mirror, she can see him.
Speaker 1: There he is.
Speaker 0: - And nobody else can see him except, what, Kujin?
Speaker 1: - Yeah, nobody else really knows that he's, it just looks like Kel Cheris is walking around, only they promote Kel Cheris like some ultra-rank temporarily because she's possessed by someone who's the highest possible rank.
Speaker 0: - Also, because of one of the most fascinating concepts in this book, other than the gender stuff and the servitors, is the formation instinct that is injected into the brains of the Kel.
Speaker 1: - Yeah, we talked about the formations.
Speaker 0: - No, no, the formation instinct.
Speaker 1: - Well, I thought that was just like, you know, how good they are at formations.
Speaker 0: - No, they could do formations without that.
Speaker 0: They just weren't as powerful.
Speaker 0: The formation instinct, remember, was every Kel is basically has a minor amount of brainwashing where if a Kel who is higher rank than them talks to them, they basically cannot resist whatever that person wants them to do.
Speaker 0: It is like built into their brain.
Speaker 0: 'Cause remember, there's a moment where Judeo and Cheris basically give up one of their own Kel to the heretics as part of a plot, and they revert her to fledge null, meaning they basically erase her personality.
Speaker 0: So she physically is incapable of interacting in any way other than name, rank, and serial number.
Speaker 0: And then you get the finer point when Judeo's talking about this, and I remember he mentioned something offhandedly like, "Oh, yeah, if we didn't have the formation instinct back when I was alive, alive,".
Speaker 0: and then later you get a little tidbit around how, you know, actually, like one character, I forget who says this, but they say something like, "You know, actually, if formation instinct didn't already exist, it would be really hard to convince people that this was ethical to even do in the first
Speaker 0: place.".
Speaker 0: - Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: - Because in the past, at some point, the society said, "We're gonna do formation instinct in the Kel," and that was not a thing before that.
Speaker 1: - Mm.
Speaker 0: - That instinct comes up big in the second book, too.
Speaker 1: - So anyway, the greatest general, the greatest military mind that ever lived in the evil empire, right?
Speaker 1: So, I guess, Darth Vader, right?
Speaker 1: - Yep.
Speaker 1: - Or whatever, right?
Speaker 1: He's like a ghost, right?
Speaker 1: Just like Darth Vader's a ghost.
Speaker 1: Imagine just some regular old Jedi gets possessed by Darth Vader, and now everyone treats that person as if they are Darth Vader, and Darth Vader's in their mind talking to them and is in them and can control their body, kinda, so--.
Speaker 0: - And I gotta say, the writing on all of that is just really well done.
Speaker 1: Like, the interplay between--.
Speaker 1: - I mean, I think that's the kind of thing, it's hard to do that in not a book, right?
Speaker 1: - Yeah.
Speaker 1: - How do you do that in another medium of storytelling?
Speaker 1: Not easily.
Speaker 0: - I can give a few ways to, so, this is an aside, but I was talking to one of our friends 'cause we play Blades in the Dark in the Discord, and we learned of someone else's game where a character got possessed by a ghost.
Speaker 0: So, what they did is they had someone play the ghost in a Discord channel, and they set it up to where only the PC who was possessed could hear what the ghost was saying, and the GM could also hear it, no one else could hear it, and the player who was possessed, if they wanted to interact with the ghost, they had to just talk.
Speaker 0: So, no one heard what the ghost was saying, and it worked really well, and it's a lot like this situation, but the book just portrays it so well, and I like there's one scene where Cheris is getting frustrated because he's talking to her, but she's trying to figure something out, and she gets confused, and it's, there's a lot of good bits around that whole conceit.
Speaker 1: - Anyway, so, you have to.
Speaker 1: basically the greatest military, you know, force is this one person, like they're that dangerous that like, you know, they're like, "How about nukes?
Speaker 1: Nah, not good enough.
Speaker 1: "How about this one dude?
Speaker 1: Oh, that'll get it
Speaker 1: done.".
Speaker 0: - It'd be like if, "Oh no, "we have a Final Fantasy IV problem," and you unfreeze like the guy who's had the world record in Final Fantasy IV running for 400 years.
Speaker 1: - Yeah.
Speaker 1: So, they send this dude in Kel's body, Kel and Jidao, out to do the space battle, and the rest of the book is pretty much just space battle.
Speaker 1: - Yup.
Speaker 1: - You know, there's a lot of developments that happen during the space battle, right?
Speaker 0: - It's pretty fascinating how, as a reader, one, Jidao convinces me to go along with him.
Speaker 0: Like, I'm pretty much on board with him.
Speaker 1: - I mean, I'm on board with him in terms of like, you know, if you want the Texarcate to win, he has the right idea.
Speaker 0: - I pretty early on assumed.
Speaker 1: - I'm not on board with helping them win, but it's clear that he doesn't actually like them, but everything that he's saying is like helping them win at least this immediate battle.
Speaker 0: - I was very sure from the first third of this book and I was 100% sure by the end of this book that he was winning those battles in order to lose the war on purpose.
Speaker 1: - Clearly, there is this inkling of unspokenness that you have this faith that this character is in it for the longest, longest term fall, right?
Speaker 1: - He's playing the long game!
Speaker 1: - Everything he's ever done has been pro-evil empire, except the one time where he won the battle and then murdered his own people afterwards, right?
Speaker 1: The one time.
Speaker 0: - Which arguably is a lot like I guess minor spoiler for adventure time when Finn and Jake commit a cosmic crime to go to the cosmic prison on purpose.
Speaker 0: I think he did something so extreme to basically force them to both kill him and because he was so good they couldn't just actually kill him, so they had to put him in the black cradle.
Speaker 0: I think he orchestrated this from the beginning.
Speaker 0: He committed a crime so bad but was also so good at his job that they had no choice but to trap him in the black cradle.
Speaker 0: and then that began his long con.
Speaker 1: - And once he has the immortality, now he can play the longest game ever of it's like you think about.
Speaker 1: will we live to see I don't know, China fall?
Speaker 1: Will we live to see the US fall?
Speaker 1: Will we live to see Canada fall?
Speaker 1: It's like unlikely, right?
Speaker 1: But you know what?
Speaker 1: If I'm immortal, the odds of me seeing Canada fall are 100%.
Speaker 1: It's gonna fall.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: It's like it's gonna happen, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like this evil empire, when is it gonna fall?
Speaker 1: Ever?
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: It's like well, if I'm immortal, right?
Speaker 1: It's like I'm gonna have opportunities at some point or how long I gotta sleep, no matter how many times they wake me up, it's like at some point, I'm either going to bring about their fall or at least if they fall while I'm asleep, it's like you know, I'll be, someone, whoever conquers them is gonna find me down here right in the Black Aldrin.
Speaker 0: But as a result, I was on board with him and then you see Charis get on board with him pretty quickly and to the end where she literally at least as far as it is portrayed in that second book, in that final chapter, she basically eats the carrion glass and becomes him completely and wholly so that he can continue his
Speaker 1: work.
Speaker 1: Well, it's like a composite being of some kind right?
Speaker 1: Just like the composites they talked about earlier in the book but perhaps more so right?
Speaker 0: Well he's got a lot more history in his brain than she does.
Speaker 1: Sure but they're basically like one person now, right?
Speaker 0: So some aspects that stood out to me around all of that, I like how Kel Charis we get a lot about how she is from a culture that was subsumed by the Empire in a distant past, like a really really small minority group that only lives on like one planet.
Speaker 0: And bit by bit you get all these notes about how like, oh yeah, even the Kel were this completely unrelated spacefaring people who were probably conquered by this Empire at some point and then joined it.
Speaker 0: And that seems to play into the long term, like this Empire is being held together by torture and glue and little else.
Speaker 1: It also seems like not everyone in the Empire is necessarily part of one of the six groups, right?
Speaker 0: It seems like Kel's Charis' family, it's like they're not Kel, they're just- Yeah, she went off to the government university and the family was like, "Your funeral, good luck, have
Speaker 0: fun.".
Speaker 1: Right, and it's like J'Dao changed factions, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, it's not like, you know, it's like, it's almost like six government agencies that run everything.
Speaker 0: But there are just normal people, like there's that Baker who gets involved, who they take the cookies for that assassination plot, like there's just regular people living in this Empire.
Speaker 1: Right, it's interesting.
Speaker 1: at the only times you, because most of the book takes place in spaceships, you know, space, military spaceships, right?
Speaker 1: But the, on the space station, it's like there's normal people living there and you don't see much of them in their everyday life, right?
Speaker 1: And it's sort of what's happening in the space station is very abstract, but they sprinkle in, like, concrete details of very specific tiny events on the space station to sort of give you an overall feeling of like, you know, it's almost like a rear window deal, it's like they show you a little bit of like the lives of a few different people on the space station and then you can sort of get an idea of what the whole space station is like just from that, right?
Speaker 0: And I like how much that contrasts with you.
Speaker 0: basically have the extremely abstract geometric mathematically formulated like, nonsense happening with the battles, but then on the opposite end of that, you've got like the Kell are just hanging out in a like mess hall eating regular ass food like normal people and the juxtaposition of the extreme mathematical
Speaker 1: drama about what table you sit at
Speaker 0: and it really rounds the books in that they are just people in the end.
Speaker 0: and it also makes the the way combat and the way spaceships and the way all this other stuff is described feel almost even more exotic and extreme and nonsensical and I like that juxtaposition quite a bit.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: so the biggest insight you get into what's going on in the space station is that a bunch of the chapters begin or are entirely a letter or some sort of message from one person in the space station to this other person who is presumably the leader of this rebellion, right?
Speaker 0: I like how the person in the space station those letters start out pretty optimistic and then you see them sort of wavering a little bit like a little bit of blah blah blah and then toward the end of the book it's like, "Yo, we're fucked.
Speaker 0: Shit's fucked.
Speaker 0: Get the fuck out.
Speaker 1: Fuck
Speaker 1: this.".
Speaker 1: Right, so it's like one of the people who's like part of the rebellion, you know, is like messaging the leader of the rebellion and you're only getting one half of the communication.
Speaker 1: it's just the message is two, right?
Speaker 1: It'd be like if you saw all the messages from I don't know, the deputy attorney general to like the president.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you don't see how the president responds or reacts in any way.
Speaker 1: Right, exactly.
Speaker 1: And the messages always start out with like jokes about the calendar because I guess they're working on their calendar trying to get it in order and this person is tired of the calendar changing so much as they experiment and try to figure out what works.
Speaker 1: and they're like, "Ah, the fifth of the cow and the fourth of the oxtail and the third of the
Speaker 1: shark.".
Speaker 1: It's like they're just making fun of the calendar.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like, "Day of the I don't even
Speaker 0: care.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like they're just writing whatever bullshit to make fun of the calendar at the start of every message, right?
Speaker 1: And it gets even more bullshitty as time goes on to show how their calendar is in disarray.
Speaker 0: In the second book it's almost like you shift to seeing what the people who would receive those kinds of messages are thinking and doing.
Speaker 1: But yeah, you basically get the idea this rebellion is related to that seventh faction that broke off.
Speaker 1: They're trying to bring about democracy which is the Hexarchate people, some of them barely even know what the hell that means at all.
Speaker 1: It's obviously heretical and they don't like it, whatever it is.
Speaker 1: And the people on the station are trying to have elections and whatnot which is clearly at least in my mind, good.
Speaker 1: And there's definitely some relation between this rebellion and the seventh faction of the Hexarchate that broke away or was eliminated or whatever happened to it.
Speaker 0: Because you read the book.
Speaker 0: That is not all resolved at the end of the book.
Speaker 0: And the second book literally just picks up seconds after the first book ends.
Speaker 0: So I guess other notable things that I think stood out to me is we should talk about the servitors but I first want to talk about pronouns and gender and all of that because at first it's a lot of gender neutral pronouns and at first I wondered if that was just an artifact of Korean language and the translation.
Speaker 0: but it is very clear that that is an intentional part of the story and the society because they dig into that deeper and deeper and deeper over the course of the book and in the second book even goes further.
Speaker 0: but clearly this society has very progressive and evolved ideas of sex and gender in that people may have a man form or a woman form and their pronouns are completely separate from that.
Speaker 0: People use they/them specifically for plot reasons at different points compared to he/her.
Speaker 0: that sort of thing and this is deeply ingrained into the story.
Speaker 0: The idea that someone's physical form actually matters way less than their signifier of who they are.
Speaker 1: It also shows you that you can have an evil empire that it can also be progressive in many ways.
Speaker 1: You can have a fascist country that has free universal healthcare for its citizens who are all deemed to be good people.
Speaker 0: Here's a less extreme example.
Speaker 0: Napoleonic France way more progressive legal system and way more progressive society in many areas but as we both know, extremely not that in many other areas.
Speaker 1: It's sort of this interesting depiction.
Speaker 1: There's scenes where you see when Jidao was in school.
Speaker 1: it seems like a normal college scene.
Speaker 0: Actually the school feels, all the school flashbacks feel a lot like Utena or like Tenchi-Buyo school flashbacks.
Speaker 0: Tenchi-Buyo fits better but you haven't watched it so I couldn't.
Speaker 1: Well that's because the story of what was going on in the school was about rivals and who's gonna pass the test and high-screen.
Speaker 0: A lot of anime, especially 90s anime that were sci-fi and into the early 2000s they'll have like this vague idea of "Oh yeah, I know that person from the academy" and they'll be sort of a vague space academy that for some reason every fucking main character interacted with in some way.
Speaker 1: They were 11 Space Academy.
Speaker 0: But the schools in this feel very similar to that.
Speaker 0: This whole book feels very anime.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of anime type stuff.
Speaker 0: Especially in the end when some of the formations get extremely abstract like people evaporating into literal matrix numbers and such.
Speaker 0: But too the servitors are fascinating because they are... I would be shocked if they were not directly inspired by the drones in the culture books.
Speaker 0: They are like the same kind of entity like to a T and they're delightful.
Speaker 0: I love the servitors.
Speaker 1: There's some sort of intelligent machines.
Speaker 1: They're clearly sentient.
Speaker 0: They're definitely sentient as is proven when Sherris and Jideo have them join fucking formations.
Speaker 0: And I also like the touch of when they ask the servitors to join a formation.
Speaker 0: one, all the other Cal are like "The fuck?
Speaker 0: Servitors can't do
Speaker 0: that.".
Speaker 0: But not only do they ask them, but they ask them.
Speaker 0: They want the servitors consent.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But I think the other thing is that the book makes...
Speaker 0: And the servitors are surprised.
Speaker 0: The fact that they're like "What are you... You want our consent?
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Interesting.".
Speaker 1: But the book makes a frequent point that there's these AI servitors.
Speaker 1: Serv is in their name.
Speaker 1: They exist just to serve the Hexarchate the way Rosie the Robot serves the Jetsons.
Speaker 0: And it is clear that when Jideo was alive, they were not yet sentient.
Speaker 0: And they are now, in this future from that time, definitely sentient.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But also, it seems like almost everyone, or literally everyone in the entire Hexarchate just sort of ignores them as if they're not sentient.
Speaker 1: As if they're just these automated robots that clean the hallways and cook food and do shit like that.
Speaker 0: Except Cal.
Speaker 0: Cal, and especially Cheris, she just thanks them when they do stuff for her.
Speaker 1: Cal Cheris, yes.
Speaker 0: But what's fun about that is, when you get servitor scenes, I like how they notice that, and they all really like her as a result.
Speaker 1: Right, well that's the thing.
Speaker 1: That is used as a device to sort of make Cal Cheris seem like a good person, as different from the other people.
Speaker 1: It's like she actually cares, has some sort of morality, is able to recognize that the servitors are sentient beings that no one else recognizes.
Speaker 1: That she can care for others.
Speaker 1: And no one else is doing this.
Speaker 1: And it sort of sets her apart as the main character that she does this, and befriends all these robots, more so than she befriends other people in the Hex Arcade.
Speaker 1: And, in return, they like her for it, and they help her, and they're like, R2D2s and whatnot.
Speaker 0: And I like how, just like the humans, man form, woman form, alt form, then they also have bird form, snake form, dog form, whatever.
Speaker 1: They got all kinds, yeah, there's all kinds of forms of the robots, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know.
Speaker 0: But it's an algory to the real world.
Speaker 0: If you out there, if you the listener, have not interacted with very wealthy people in the real world, one thing I can say with absolute certainty is that very rich people in the real world treat the humans who serve them the same way the people in the Hex Arcade treat the servitors.
Speaker 0: They think waiters and butlers and maids are invisible automatons, and they will say things in front of those people that they should not say in front of anyone.
Speaker 0: Like, they just, they don't even consider the idea that the waiter might overhear something they say that is sensitive.
Speaker 0: It doesn't even cross their mind that the waiter exists once he's out of view.
Speaker 0: Like, rich people are really like that.
Speaker 1: Right, so in getting help from the servitors, right, they Calcheras gains access and Jedao gains access to information.
Speaker 0: Because the servitors know fucking everything because everyone in the empire just treats them like they don't exist.
Speaker 1: Exactly, they know everything and they are also vastly much more powerful than they imagine because they can go everywhere and have access and do all sorts of things and also they're fucking robots.
Speaker 0: The humans are really lucky that the servitors are different forms with different powers.
Speaker 0: Well, I like how the servitors have their own empire.
Speaker 0: Like, they have basically built all their own secret tunnels.
Speaker 0: They have their own society.
Speaker 0: There's that one bit where they even, whenever
Speaker 1: They're almost like a, they're not, it's like while they serve the Hex Arcade and, you know, don't like try to overthrow it or anything, they're almost like in a symbiotic relationship where it's like, they're just
Speaker 0: literally just playing board games like in the walls where they don't have work to do.
Speaker 1: It's like, they're still their own thing and it's like, they just come and help the Hex Arcade and then in turn, the Hex Arcade gives them what they need to survive and then they go back to doing their own thing.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Secretly.
Speaker 0: But the other fun things about them is like, they they are very interested in what the humans are up to.
Speaker 0: Like, they seem to keep tabs on who's fucking who for no reason just because they can.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 0: But I like this bit about how they have their own communication channels and they actively try to prevent most humans from realizing that they are sentient to the point that they take turns.
Speaker 0: this little bit of world building was so fun, that they take turns whenever they discover that a human is in any way recording or listening to their communication channels, they fill the channels with the most boring nonsense possible until the human goes away so that the humans never overhear them actually talking.
Speaker 0: And I thought that was a fun bit that is definitely going to play into the third book the way things are going.
Speaker 1: But yeah, that's a great, you know, aspect of the book.
Speaker 1: that's clearly, you know, it plays a somewhat significant part towards the end of the book where, you know, they help out in the space battle.
Speaker 1: And, you know, but they're not like a huge part.
Speaker 1: It's clearly, though, a huge part of the world that will come into play later.
Speaker 1: Apparently Rim thinks third book.
Speaker 0: I think so.
Speaker 0: Having read the second book, which just keeps on keeping on from the second book.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I'm not going to spoil anything for later books because we only had to have read one book.
Speaker 1: I guess we should just end by talking about how they somehow managed to get Utena sword duels into this book.
Speaker 0: I love how at one point you learn about the calendrical swords and also like Charis is like way into K-dramas like very clearly.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: And like clearly a weeb, like a weeb adjacent type person.
Speaker 0: And there's a lot of nerdery going.
Speaker 0: Like the characters have a lot of nerderies and hobbies and interests.
Speaker 1: The person who watches K-dramas and talks to the robots.
Speaker 0: I love how sometimes she watches the K-dramas with the robots when she doesn't think anyone's looking.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's very like, you know, you imagine like a high school, you know, girl bedroom kind of scene.
Speaker 0: But we only get a few of these calendrical duels, but basically we know she has that calendrical sword and she's very good with it.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: The way the duels are described is delightful because there is no way to describe it except it is like literally what happens in Shoujo Kakamei Utena when they have a duel.
Speaker 0: Like dragons and fire and nonsense are coming out of these swords.
Speaker 0: Everyone's flying around and they can do it lethally or non-lethally just for funsies.
Speaker 0: You get the impression they do it all the time.
Speaker 0: And it was a nice touch.
Speaker 0: It doesn't really play into the plot that much.
Speaker 0: It's just fun.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean it, you know, it does, there is the one, you know, it's like hinted at earlier in the book and then there's the one major, the biggest one that happens closer to the end and it is much like Utena.
Speaker 1: in that, you know, there's some sort of disagreement/tension between the characters involved in the duel, right, and it's sort of a, you know, you get a sort of a might makes right scenario happening, right, where, you know, based on who wins.
Speaker 1: that is what's going to determine, you know, the course of events going forward.
Speaker 1: But this is why I kept bringing up Utena.
Speaker 0: In Utena, if you, before you see the whole show and get, you know, fully grok what was going on, insofar as anyone other than Ikuhara can actually grok it, not that he necessarily does either, you, you know, it's might makes right.
Speaker 0: If you win the duel, that means you were right.
Speaker 0: But really, it means you were right in the context of how the duels themselves work.
Speaker 0: And not to spoil anything about Utena, I won't go further, but Scott definitely gets what I'm going for there.
Speaker 0: If you've seen Utena, you get it too.
Speaker 0: Back to the calendrical duels, if you win a calendrical duel, you are right in the context of the calendar.
Speaker 1: You are in alignment with the calendar.
Speaker 0: Doesn't mean you're right in any other way, so losing a calendrical duel could almost be more important than winning one.
Speaker 1: A calendric, also got to consider the calendrical duels are not fought between two people of different calendars.
Speaker 1: It's not someone's on the Hexarchate calendar and the other person's a heretic and they're dueling.
Speaker 1: No, you're both in the Hexarchate.
Speaker 1: We're both on the same calendar and you're sort of whoever is in more alignment with that calendar, whoever his heart is in the correct formation with that calendar is probably going to be winning.
Speaker 0: Which is literally one of the most powerful and consistent allegories in Revolutionary Girl Utena.
Speaker 0: So if you liked this book, I think you should watch that anime.
Speaker 1: But I digress.
Speaker 1: So I think the final thing is that I think the reason, the number one reason the listener wanted us to read this book, specifically Geek Nights, is because of the game theory aspects of the story.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: Look out the most powerful generals.
Speaker 0: Everyone who does anything in this society has to be at least what we would consider in our current society a maths genius.
Speaker 0: Everything's math.
Speaker 1: Right, I mean the whole reason they want to go after Kel Cheris is because they're looking for someone who's good enough at math.
Speaker 0: Good enough at math, but also good at guns and everything else.
Speaker 1: Right, it's like all these other Kels don't know math for shit.
Speaker 1: We've got to find one who's, and then what's it called, the guy who called the other Kujin, he's like, "Ah, finally someone I can talk to who's good enough at math.
Speaker 1: Talk about math with
Speaker 1: me.".
Speaker 1: And you know, Jidao, what was he doing when he was in college?
Speaker 1: Designing games, that's what he was doing in college.
Speaker 0: My favorite scene in the entire book is when Jidao, basically to get Cheris to figure something out on her own, makes her design a board game in front of him and critiques it live while she designs it.
Speaker 0: That whole scene is my absolutely favorite scene in this entire book.
Speaker 1: And as much as war is already sort of, you know, abstracted into a game in real life, you know, war games, right, miniatures moving around a thing, right, but the way they conduct the space, you know, the way war is engaged in real life, you know, by actual generals, has some things to do with war games, right?
Speaker 0: More than you'd expect.
Speaker 1: More, right, has, you know, but it's not just Advance Wars, right?
Speaker 1: But the way a general operates in the world of Ninefox Gambit, they're basically just playing Advance Wars, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, and that's the way it's portrayed.
Speaker 1: It's portrayed as it's like, I'll move my, you know, spaceships over here, and I'll, you know, use this calendar move over there and activate the special attack over here.
Speaker 1: How are we going to beat the ice?
Speaker 1: You know, when they're beating the ice, it's, they're basically like playing a board game and winning it to beat the ice.
Speaker 0: Yup, like they play it, eventually they figure out like wait a minute, this is just some calendar bullshit hidden behind a bunch of fancy nonsense.
Speaker 1: Spoilers, they beat that, they get through the ice.
Speaker 0: They get through the ice, right?
Speaker 0: That's actually something I appreciated about the book too.
Speaker 1: Well, cause that was the, it was presented as the first problem at the very beginning of the book.
Speaker 0: But it was also presented as the hardest problem, and then they just immediately like, they go after it right away and they beat it right away.
Speaker 1: Well, it's like they arrive on the scene while they're spaceships, and it's like the ice is up.
Speaker 1: They have to address it right away.
Speaker 1: The same way that in Star Wars they have to get the shield down before they attack the Death Star.
Speaker 1: It's like the first thing they have to do.
Speaker 0: It's Final Fantasy I Light Warriors.
Speaker 0: go fucking beat up Garland.
Speaker 0: What do you do?
Speaker 0: Go straight to Garland.
Speaker 1: It's not like there was anything else you could address first as long as the ice is there.
Speaker 1: What else are you gonna do first?
Speaker 1: So they, they address it first so they can move on with the book.
Speaker 1: Well, otherwise it would be boring to just be sitting there like, well, can't get through the ice.
Speaker 0: But I think the point about game design.
Speaker 1: Next chapter, still can't get through the ice.
Speaker 0: The point about game design that this, that this book and those scenes reinforce the most, I think is that you know, the actual full reality of any situation is too complex to be simulated, and at that like trying to make decisions based on all the data available is in the real world usually an exercise in futility.
Speaker 0: So the smartest thing anyone can do is figure out what data points are the most important and build slower fidelity simulations based on that data to figure out broad decisions and then delegate decisions in detail for the zoomed in parts and trust people which is how the real world works.
Speaker 0: And I think this book just does a really good job of describing how games really literally for real fit into such a concept.
Speaker 1: And pretty much everything that happens in the book is, can be framed as you know games within games within games and you know, it's like these you know, you get your smaller games of like, you know, get the dice.
Speaker 0: Well there's that card game that they play.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: You get your bigger games like Take Back the Space Station, and then the biggest game of all, right, is Jidao Overthrow the Empire somehow.
Speaker 1: Right, and that's left, that's you know, not resolved in the first book, right?
Speaker 1: So.
Speaker 0: Yep, so weaponized calendrical utendidual game theory space battle violence the novel.
Speaker 1: So yeah, it's a very very Geek Nights novel.
Speaker 1: The listener, that's probably why the listener wanted us to read it so much.
Speaker 1: We read it.
Speaker 1: You happy now?
Speaker 0: I really enjoyed it.
Speaker 0: I will definitely finish the series.
Speaker 0: And I'll let you know how it goes.
Speaker 0: But so far book two, I thoroughly enjoyed.
Speaker 0: It'll answer a lot of questions you had.
Speaker 0: It'll go into way more detail than you expect on a bunch of stuff.
Speaker 0: And it's the only thing I would say is there are far fewer space battles in the second book and a lot more board meetings and basically like scrums almost.
Speaker 0: It's uh, you'll see.
Speaker 0: So, as is traditional I am now on the hook to announce the next book whatever it might be.
Speaker 0: And what I have chosen the next book club book is Binti by Nnedi Okorafor.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: I've heard I know the name of the author, but I don't.
Speaker 1: I don't think I've read any book that they've written.
Speaker 0: So their books have been very popular and have been popping up in my feeds quite a bit.
Speaker 0: But this is the one that has popped up the most.
Speaker 0: And I'm just going to read a little snippet from her own website explaining what this book is about.
Speaker 0: Her name is Binti and she is the first of the Himba people to ever be offered a place at Umsa University.
Speaker 0: The finest institution of higher learning in the galaxy!
Speaker 0: It's a sci-fi!
Speaker 1: So it's space.
Speaker 1: we've got another space college, again two space college books in a row.
Speaker 1: I'm in a space college mood, so you can get your They Were 11's and your Utena's out of the way.
Speaker 0: This book fits right into that and I'm really excited to read it.
Speaker 0: And I expect I will be finished with this book within a few weeks, but we'll give you the listener at least a month before we do a show on it, so you've got some time.
Speaker 0: But I highly, highly, highly recommend this book.
Speaker 1: Probably wait for summer to be over.
Speaker 0: I mean summer, laying on the beach and reading.
Speaker 0: I'll definitely finish this book pretty quick.
Speaker 1: I mean my job, my new job is starting on Monday, but I'm never going to work on Friday ever again, so.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of Geek Nights are Alan Joyce, Link Iggi, Dread Lily Tenebrae, and Bunch of People Who Rarely Don't Want Me to Say Their Names, Chris Rimer, Clinton Walton, Dex, Finn, Kishii85, Rebecca Dunn, ReviewMedball34, Cowards, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Harl, Stop All the Downloading, Taylor Braun, and a number of people whose names I will not say at their specific request.
Speaker 0: Now, tonight, we will leave you with something because we won't be doing any shows next week because, as anyone who watched the stream saw, I'm gonna be at the beach.
Speaker 0: So, no Geek Nights, take a break, hit the ground running the week after next week, enjoy your summer, stay safe out there, and I simply leave you with... Tenzou!
Speaker 0: Tenzou... I will never forget you.