Speaker 0: It's Thursday, April 14th, 2022.
Speaker 0: I'm Rym.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights tonight on the Geek Nights Book Club.
Speaker 0: We are talking about N.K.
Speaker 0: Jemisin's "The City We
Speaker 0: Became.".
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Not gonna belabor the point about how refreshing it was to read a book that was written in this millennium.
Speaker 0: In a language that I already speak without requiring a translation.
Speaker 1: Well, the original language of the book is...
Speaker 0: It's original language is a language that I understand well.
Speaker 0: That this book did not take long to read.
Speaker 0: Partly because it was really good.
Speaker 0: Partly because I feel like...
Speaker 1: You're comparing it against a book that took forever to read.
Speaker 0: Yep, like I enjoyed "The Tale of
Speaker 0: Genji."
Speaker 0: Just like if the only bike I had was a Fixie, like it's better than nothing, I'd ride that Fixie around.
Speaker 1: I didn't enjoy "Tale of Genji" as much as this book.
Speaker 0: Oh no, but if my choice was don't bike or bike on a Fixie, I would bike on a Fixie.
Speaker 0: But imagine if I was forced to bike on a Fixie for like a year, and then someone handed me my old bike back.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So yeah.
Speaker 1: So the story with this book is I knew this book existed.
Speaker 1: And I knew that it was, you know, a book by N.K.
Speaker 1: Jemisin, who we're already a fan of, right?
Speaker 1: We read the whole "Broken Earth" already.
Speaker 0: Yeah, literally one of my favorite science fiction/fantasy trilogies of all time.
Speaker 0: With the caveat that I read it very recently, and I think it'll stand the test of time, but I'm not 100% sure.
Speaker 0: So in a decade, if I say the same thing, you know that's a rock solid trilogy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean it's really, really good.
Speaker 1: I just don't, you know, but it's not like at Earthsea level, right?
Speaker 1: It's, you know, even if they might both be S-tier, but they're still ranked relatively within the S-tier.
Speaker 0: I'd have to go read some Earthsea again.
Speaker 0: You know what, they're within knife-fighting distance of each other.
Speaker 1: Maybe, anyway.
Speaker 0: Maybe a longer knife, like a short sword?
Speaker 1: Dueling distance.
Speaker 1: Well, anyway, the point is, I knew this book existed.
Speaker 1: And I knew, or at least I incorrectly thought it was going to be a trilogy.
Speaker 1: Apparently, it's going to be a duology, which is good news.
Speaker 0: Oh, Google still says it's going to be a trilogy.
Speaker 1: It's a duology, according to the announcement for the second book.
Speaker 0: Something was going to be a duology that became a trilogy that became two trilogies, so.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, I read the, there was a, recently there were, you know, like things about the second book and it said duology on it.
Speaker 1: So I'm going by that.
Speaker 1: So I knew I was going to read this book eventually, but I was upset that Rim chose it as the book club book for, for why, right?
Speaker 1: Number one, you know, even though it's going to be, I knew it was going to be an incredible amazing book by an author I already knew who has done no wrong that I wanted to read.
Speaker 1: I was like, we already did a book by this author, right?
Speaker 1: We should be doing, I feel like we should be doing a new author every time.
Speaker 0: Though, unlike things of the day, we do not have a rule about it.
Speaker 1: We don't have a rule about it, but you know, and I can't control what Rim picks.
Speaker 1: I mean, if he actually, you know, sincerely picks account of Monte Cristo, it's like, well, I've been getting ready for another book club three years from now.
Speaker 0: Not just because you said it.
Speaker 0: I've been low key having this small but strange urge to read that book again.
Speaker 1: I'm going to have that strange urge to play breath of the wild.
Speaker 0: It's been more like 20 years.
Speaker 0: God damn.
Speaker 0: It has been 20 years since I read that book.
Speaker 1: Anyway, anyway, so, uh, that was reason number one.
Speaker 1: And reason number two is because I knew it was going to be more than one book.
Speaker 1: I lately, you know, I really like to wait until a thing is done and then go for the whole thing.
Speaker 1: I really am not a fan of, you know, read one, wait and read the second one, because what happens is, you know, I don't remember enough.
Speaker 1: So like, for example, Prince of nothing, which I assume is anymore.
Speaker 0: Then book two came out.
Speaker 0: I read book one again.
Speaker 0: Then I read book two, book three.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: I skimmed through book one.
Speaker 0: I read book two again, and then I read book three.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: So I want to avoid that and just be able to, you know, just read all the things once.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Especially with a book that takes more time, you know, time and whatnot.
Speaker 1: So, uh, but other than that, you know, every other, you know, it was, I had reasons to not pick it as a book club book, but I had absolutely no reasons to be against the book itself.
Speaker 1: I knew that I assumed the greatest of the book.
Speaker 0: I had some gnosis because Emily read the book already.
Speaker 0: And I had Emily's assurance that it ends regardless of future books at a very solid, satisfying point.
Speaker 0: that would not lie.
Speaker 1: This book, despite being a duology or more, we don't know, um, you can read this book.
Speaker 1: And if it was the only book in its series and there was never any other book to follow it, you would not be upset at all.
Speaker 1: It is a complete self-contained ending thing.
Speaker 1: It does leave, you know, a state, you know, a state of a world, you know, builds a world.
Speaker 1: And that world is in a particular state with, so, you know, some unresolved things in it at the end.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: That would allow for continuation, but they're not things that, like, you know, are like enormous, like you must know or otherwise you don't feel like it's over.
Speaker 1: Like, it's like the story is over and, you know, of the characters, at least the major conflict of this first book is.
Speaker 0: it has that feeling, which is actually kind of literal in terms of how it's shown at the end of a fantasy book that ends in the middle.
Speaker 0: And the final chapter is like a battle has been won or something.
Speaker 0: And then the heroes are like looking out over the shore at the looming enemy to come.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: So it would be like if someone wrote a book about a battle in a war.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And the book, the book starts when the battle is starting or like the precursor to the battle.
Speaker 1: And then the book ends after the battle is completely over.
Speaker 1: And like this, you know, every the battlefield is cleaned up and the war is still going on.
Speaker 1: That battle wasn't the ultimate battle that ended the war, clearly.
Speaker 1: But you got a complete story.
Speaker 1: And, you know, even though the questions of the greater situation are still out there, you're not upset.
Speaker 1: Just reading that one story right of within.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: So this book, remember, this is we haven't done these in a while because, again, she took a while.
Speaker 0: The Geek Nights Book Club is a book club, meaning we're assuming very shortly that you have already read this book.
Speaker 0: We're going to talk about this book as two people who have read this book.
Speaker 0: And we're assuming that all of you have read this book.
Speaker 0: So if you have not read this book, other than a little bit of explanation we're going to give in the very beginning, you're probably going to be completely lost.
Speaker 0: And we're just going to spoil a whole bunch of the book.
Speaker 0: We're going to talk about it.
Speaker 0: So I highly encourage you, if you have not read The City We Became, to stop listening to this and go read this book.
Speaker 0: It'll take you like a week.
Speaker 0: I swear.
Speaker 1: I don't, you know, again, I don't personally believe in spoilers, but if I did, I really think that this book only has one thing that's spoilable in it.
Speaker 0: Nothing surprised me except one thing that I could have picked on.
Speaker 1: The one biggest, yes, the one biggest thing.
Speaker 1: That's the thing, right?
Speaker 1: One big, big thing.
Speaker 1: that was usually I'm I'm the person who sees everything coming, right?
Speaker 1: Because any good story is going to have foreshadowing.
Speaker 1: And Chekhov's guns.
Speaker 1: And I spot those.
Speaker 1: Fuck.
Speaker 1: I'm like an expert at spot.
Speaker 1: We should have a game.
Speaker 1: I spotted the check.
Speaker 0: I spotted Chekhov's New Jersey within.
Speaker 1: Oh, that was the easiest one.
Speaker 1: Forget that one.
Speaker 0: As soon as I found out that character is from New Jersey, I was like, I know where this is going.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: No question there.
Speaker 1: But there was, you know, there's another one that there were so many hints.
Speaker 1: Oh, my God.
Speaker 0: Billy, I figured there's about there.
Speaker 0: So I figured it out.
Speaker 0: I want to say, like, the fourth beat where it comes up.
Speaker 0: And at that moment, I thought, wait a minute are.
Speaker 0: Oh, and then I thought, wow, I'm really stupid.
Speaker 0: I really should have picked up on that earlier as I went back.
Speaker 0: And I felt a little as well.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But that was the major one anyway.
Speaker 1: So what the hell is this book?
Speaker 1: So the title of the book is The City We Became.
Speaker 1: I knew it was a book about New York, right?
Speaker 1: Where N.K.
Speaker 1: Jemisin lives?
Speaker 1: in Brooklyn, right?
Speaker 1: You know, we live in Queens anyway.
Speaker 1: And I didn't know anything else other than that.
Speaker 1: It was going to be good.
Speaker 1: So oh, and I knew there was some sort of fantastical element.
Speaker 1: It turns out that the title is a genius title because it has, you know, at least two meanings to it, right?
Speaker 0: It's literal in terms of what happens in the book, how it ends.
Speaker 1: That's the one that I didn't see coming that like right away and not even in chapter one and like the prologue, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, yeah, the book is literally about people who become physical avatars, embodiments of New York, literally like that person is New York City.
Speaker 1: That person, human being is Queens.
Speaker 1: That's who they are, right?
Speaker 1: The same way that, you know, I don't know, you know, other mythological figures, right?
Speaker 1: The way that I don't know.
Speaker 0: I this is the worst possible example, but it just came front of mind because it's very good.
Speaker 0: The way deities work in forgotten realms in Dungeons and Dragons.
Speaker 0: It is exactly literally how deities work.
Speaker 1: A bunch of people, the belief, the belief part.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, the idea
Speaker 1: is kind of a little bit
Speaker 0: that a person will live their life a certain way and whatever God they live their life closest to, they kind of go to that afterlife and eventually by living in a place that's run by that God, they become indistinguishable from that God.
Speaker 0: Like they would make the same decisions that God would do.
Speaker 0: They would say the same thing that God would say.
Speaker 0: And at that point they just become that God.
Speaker 0: They represent that idea or that concept here.
Speaker 0: It's more like all the people in the history of a city together sort of become this meta organism or this meta idea that is literally its own thing that no individual fully controls.
Speaker 1: Like, right.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, it's a common literary, you know, mechanism, right?
Speaker 1: A personification, right?
Speaker 1: Of having some character that represents, you know, some idea, right?
Speaker 1: Animal Farm, whatever.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But in Animal Farm, the characters aren't literally the thing they are representing.
Speaker 1: They are just symbolic.
Speaker 0: Well, here they are both figuratively and literally.
Speaker 0: And I got to tell you, my favorite media anywhere my entire life.
Speaker 0: The thing I like the most is when a story works on an allegorical and a literal level equally well.
Speaker 0: That gets me going.
Speaker 0: The only thing that gets me going more than that is precursor technology.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, imagine if like you had a character that represented, you know, I don't know, democracy in your book.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And then someone punched them and suddenly there were revolutions and dictators rose to power because that person got hurt.
Speaker 0: when Staten Island fucks up Sao Paulo and then it cuts to like freeways, like just chaos ensuing in Sao Paulo.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: In Sao Paulo, Brazil, they were like, there's a person who is the physical embodiment of Sao Paulo.
Speaker 1: They got injured.
Speaker 1: And then the actual city of Sao Paulo in Brazil in the book, not in real life, right, was having like earthquakes or floods or, you know, disasters and things were getting fucked up.
Speaker 1: And it's like that.
Speaker 1: it's literal.
Speaker 1: And that's that's a lot of fun.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But it also is arguably a spoiler for the book because the whole point of the book is they're they're like growing into this role and becoming the avatars of the city and becoming the city.
Speaker 0: But it's in the past tense because they succeed in the book.
Speaker 0: The book ends with them succeeding.
Speaker 1: Kind of.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, mostly, I mean, the part of the city that didn't succeed arguably is not a part of the city, which is kind of part of what the book was saying.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But, you know, the book is about right, you know, in in the mythology of the book, the world that is built is that, you know, not cities don't just have these avatars automatically, right?
Speaker 1: The cities become born.
Speaker 0: Well, it makes the point that there are only two cities like this in the entire Western hemisphere at the time that the book takes place.
Speaker 0: And there were a handful that had ever even appeared in that hemisphere up to that point in human history.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And some failed to appear or, you know, other other things happened and whatnot.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, it's this it's the story of like New York being born, not, you know, but not being born in the way, you know, like go back to, you know, New Amsterdam.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But being born as, you know, a living embodiment city the way that other, you know, really big cities were.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And there is there is actually interesting enough.
Speaker 0: There's this idea of like global alpha cities.
Speaker 0: There's a thing I learned about from a doctor.
Speaker 0: She was the wife of my boss at a job I had way, way back.
Speaker 0: What she studied specifically was the concept of global cities and the idea that there are two cities on Earth for real that are global in a sense that makes them different, unique and transcendent from all other cities and all other ways humans have ever lived.
Speaker 0: And it's just the idea of like studying what makes those cities different and why like why do they act so differently in the real world?
Speaker 0: And those two cities are London and New York.
Speaker 1: Mm hmm.
Speaker 0: And it's a whole.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to try to talk about the theory in detail, because one, my knowledge on it is based on two or three conversations with a doctor who wrote theses on this and the Wikipedia page about it.
Speaker 0: So go read that Wikipedia page.
Speaker 0: You'll already know more than me.
Speaker 1: So anyway, there you know, there's a lot I've read quite, you know, in terms of New York media.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, as a New York person, you know, I quite enjoy New York media.
Speaker 1: You know, there's a lot of people who've made books, movies, TV shows that are like love letters to New York.
Speaker 0: I mean, Cavalier and Clay, right.
Speaker 1: One of our early book club books.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Was was about 20th century New York.
Speaker 1: You have Seinfeld, you have fucking Tale of Two Cities, Dog Day Afternoon, Ghostbusters.
Speaker 0: Oh, Ghostbusters.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: There's tons of them.
Speaker 1: And I feel like, though, most of those that I just mentioned are about an older New York.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, the Cavalier and Clay is definitely about a 20th century New York.
Speaker 0: That is something that was so refreshing to read, not just a contemporary book using contemporary language, but a book that is about New York as it is right now when I am living in it.
Speaker 0: So true and real to what New York is actually like to be here.
Speaker 0: It was like the way the characters talk, the way things are described, the fact that halfway through one word of where the primary avatar was.
Speaker 0: I immediately knew exactly.
Speaker 1: I knew I was 100 percent correct about where they were immediately.
Speaker 0: Highland newspapers that are always like, I know where that is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I knew exactly where that was.
Speaker 1: No question.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it's like, you know, people love cell phones, like everything described very, very realistically.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But I mean, that's, you know, I think all people, right, who enjoy stories, at least have any sort of emotion to them.
Speaker 1: You enjoy hearing people or talk or tell stories about a thing.
Speaker 1: And when you have that, I don't know if there's like a German word for it, some compound, right, where it's like, you know, someone's talking about something and you're like, yep, that's how that is.
Speaker 1: I know that thing you're talking about.
Speaker 1: You're saying exactly how the thing is.
Speaker 1: And I know that same exact feeling that you're describing.
Speaker 0: The reason a lot of people watch reviews of movies they've already seen and love because they want someone else to talk about it and they just want to soak that in.
Speaker 1: It's like you have found, you know, there's a thing that you have inside of you and someone else reveals to you that, you know, without any doubt, they have that thing inside of them as well.
Speaker 1: That knowledge, that experience, you have a shared, you know, commonality with them, some shared humanity with them.
Speaker 1: And it's not just that, but that it's aligning so perfectly.
Speaker 1: You experience the same thing right as them in the same way and have the same feelings about it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like you were just in like this perfect alignment with someone.
Speaker 1: So if you're a New York 21st century person and you read this book, there are just so many things in it that are like, yes, that's exactly how that is.
Speaker 1: This is my.
Speaker 1: I could have written, you know, if I had any writing skills, I could have written this because that's the feelings that I have.
Speaker 1: If I could have translated them into words and with any amount of skill, you know, which I could not.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: This is what it would say.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I could open this book to a random page and read a passage and then immediately talk a lot about that part of New York City.
Speaker 1: I in fact, I went to my kindle here and I had three highlighted sections.
Speaker 1: So one of the highlighted sections.
Speaker 1: This is exactly what we're talking about.
Speaker 1: So Veneza, one of the characters chuckles and says it says, but then you meet someone fine at the neighborhood block party or you go out for Vietnamese pierogies or some other bizarre shit you can't get anywhere but in this dumb ass city.
Speaker 1: or you go see an off off off Broadway Fringe Festival play nobody else has seen or you have a random encounter on the subway that becomes something so special and beautiful that you tell your grandkids about it someday.
Speaker 1: It's like that's New York.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: That's why you pay ten times the rent to live here than in somewhere else where there's nothing to do and you'll never experience anything special other than go to work, come home, watch TV, go to bed.
Speaker 1: It's all that shit is real.
Speaker 1: That is what it is like to live in New York.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And this book is just things like that was not even a full paragraph.
Speaker 0: You're going to find this really funny because the paragraph I highlighted, I felt that to my bones because the paragraph before it is her talking about how much New York City sucks shit, which is also true.
Speaker 1: And yes, it's also true.
Speaker 0: But there's the line where, yeah, well, you New Yorkers, every step, the new ones always say that it's dirty.
Speaker 0: There's too many cars.
Speaker 0: Nothing's maintained the way it should be.
Speaker 0: It's too hot in the summer to go to the winner.
Speaker 0: It sinks like unwashed ass most of the time.
Speaker 0: But you ever notice how none of you ever fucking leave?
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: That's fucking right.
Speaker 1: Because leaving means bumble fuck where nothing ever happens.
Speaker 1: And you don't you can't?
Speaker 1: you want to eat Vietnamese pierogies.
Speaker 1: They don't have those.
Speaker 1: Like when I see an off off Broadway Fringe play, you can't even see a Broadway play in some, you know, some bumble town.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Oh, you want to have a, you know, meet someone at the neighborhood block party.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You'll meet the 10 people you already know because those are the only people who live there.
Speaker 0: It's like living up in like it was a fun place.
Speaker 0: But yeah, we would choose every time we wanted to go out for dinner, like you, me and Emily and Alex, which of the eight restaurants to go to.
Speaker 1: Yep, exactly.
Speaker 0: We want to drive somewhere.
Speaker 1: So we could spend the whole time talking about how great New York is and how bad every other place is.
Speaker 1: But we do that every day on Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: So let's talk about the book instead.
Speaker 1: The non-New York parts of the book.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So I guess a little of the characters first, because I got a lot to say about every one of these characters.
Speaker 1: Well, so all the characters are all, you know, there's the New York character who's only in the prologue, basically.
Speaker 0: And the epilogue.
Speaker 1: And the epilogue.
Speaker 1: Basically becomes a MacGuffin.
Speaker 1: It's throughout the main part of the book.
Speaker 1: The New York character is a MacGuffin because they're trying to find, right, the borrow characters.
Speaker 0: Wikipedia describes the primary so well.
Speaker 0: I'm just going to read this.
Speaker 0: A queer, black, homeless young man, an artist and a hustler.
Speaker 1: That's New York.
Speaker 1: Is that not New York?
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: If you magically turn New York into a person, that's what they would be.
Speaker 1: But OK, so the borrows are just as apt.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Like Manhattan.
Speaker 0: The dude literally forgets who he was and becomes a different person after he lives here even a little bit.
Speaker 1: And which is which is an allegory for, you know, the the, you know, Manhattan, which was conquered, basically.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, the Lenapes were kicked out.
Speaker 1: You know, there was a. what's the name of the the the the little village of black people in Central Park that was blown away.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's all it's allegories for all of that.
Speaker 0: And never mind the fact that like that he's portrayed as becoming indescribable in race, like no one can quite pin on where he's from because he's from everywhere, because so many different types of people are represented by the history of Manhattan specifically and just live there.
Speaker 0: Like a lot of people think of Manhattan as being just midtown, but like go to southern Manhattan or go up to Harlem or go up to Inwood.
Speaker 0: They are radically different neighborhoods.
Speaker 1: But also, it's like I like the fact, especially with Seneca Village, that was the one it was destroyed in 1825.
Speaker 0: The book and Manhattan is a good character to reference to show that does not like gloss over the horrific things that New York or Manhattan has done to people.
Speaker 1: And it's like it's like Manhattan has this like right.
Speaker 1: They know that they have this dangerous past and that they can't really remember it.
Speaker 1: It's like I was evil, but I've forgotten it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Just like Manhattan.
Speaker 1: It's like, yeah, so much evil was done to form Manhattan.
Speaker 1: And it's you don't think about it when you're right.
Speaker 1: But also, there is still capable of that.
Speaker 0: Like Manhattan will still just kill you like Manhattan, destroy lives.
Speaker 0: Manhattan is where Wall Street exists, like Manhattan.
Speaker 1: You just get hit by a car walking on the sidewalk.
Speaker 0: Manhattan is dangerous and can fuck you up.
Speaker 0: And it's trying to like.
Speaker 0: it's mostly doing the right thing.
Speaker 0: And it plays an important role in the city.
Speaker 0: But I love there's one line I highlighted.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to go and keep reading quotes or we're just going to go down that path forever.
Speaker 0: But there's a line where he's talking about the city and they're talking and they're all trying to figure out their powers.
Speaker 0: And they all realize that Manhattan's main power derives from the fact that it needs people to recognize its greatness.
Speaker 0: Anything that happens in Manhattan, there's this undercurrent of the people who did it wanna other people to recognize it and respect it and look and point at it from a distance.
Speaker 0: They want that recognition and that respect.
Speaker 0: And it's an interesting double edged sword.
Speaker 1: It's also interesting that Manhattan, you know, a lot of the other characters, right?
Speaker 1: Brooklyn is a person who lives in Brooklyn.
Speaker 1: Queens is a person who lives in Queens.
Speaker 1: Bronx is a person who lives in the Bronx.
Speaker 1: Manhattan is someone who arrives in Penn Station on a train, right?
Speaker 1: Representing the tourist aspect of like.
Speaker 1: that's what the tourists are.
Speaker 0: But also recommending representing the tech bro who moves to New York because he finally got the good job.
Speaker 0: It represents the business people, the Wall Street nonsense.
Speaker 0: But also what I thought was interesting is Manhattan becomes the direct bodyguard of the city itself.
Speaker 0: because one thing that Manhattan does, and I think this allegory is woven in very well, the money that Manhattan brings in is a big part, despite the fact that we only tap into maybe point one percent of that money.
Speaker 0: That's the only reason New York could even exist in the form that it does.
Speaker 0: Manhattan is the reason New York is able to be what it is, because that brings in this money.
Speaker 0: Granted, we need to tap into more of that money, but Manhattan sort of gives the rest of the city cover to continue to exist.
Speaker 0: Hopefully Wall Street doesn't completely destroy that, which is kind of what the plot of the book was.
Speaker 0: But I digress.
Speaker 1: All right, so the next character is Brooklyn, right?
Speaker 1: In terms of book introduction order.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because Brooklyn saves Manhattan pretty early on, which is pretty apt as well.
Speaker 0: Brooklyn saves Manhattan from its incompetence and naivety.
Speaker 0: But she I think she's my as much as I like Queens, Queens doesn't get enough lines and enough screen time.
Speaker 0: I think Brooklyn is actually my favorite character.
Speaker 1: I kind of like the Bronx anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know, so Brooklyn is a city councilwoman, but used to be a former rapper, former hip hop artist, lawyer, right, whose family owns some brownstones, you know, from back in the day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: And, you know, she's a total, you know, don't take no, she doesn't take shit from anybody.
Speaker 0: The only person who takes less shit than her is Branca.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, you know, it's like.
Speaker 1: I think I think the thing is she's introduced, right?
Speaker 1: And she sort of like saves, you know, she saves Manhattan right away.
Speaker 1: But after that, she's just sort of like, you know, like there's no conflicts that directly involve her biz until right later on.
Speaker 0: Well, she does, though.
Speaker 0: She does protect her own borough first.
Speaker 1: Right, exactly.
Speaker 1: But there's this sort of, you know, this is a lot of.
Speaker 1: the book is sort of like this the this gathering of the boroughs, right?
Speaker 1: They're trying to get together once they realize what the hell's going on, because none of them know anything, right?
Speaker 1: They just suddenly their cities, their boroughs.
Speaker 1: now, they were just people, you know, five minutes ago.
Speaker 0: But the fact that she is very much in Broncos like this to like, I don't have time for this shit.
Speaker 0: Like that's their first thought is such a New York thought.
Speaker 0: But also, like I like her history of like rapper who was also part of a very complex, problematic and important rap culture.
Speaker 0: And the book addresses that directly and she addresses that directly.
Speaker 0: And I like there's a big fight between her and Bronco near the end that really, really stood out as pointed, because on one hand, Brooklyn has to not like can't wave off the fact that there's there.
Speaker 0: Brooklyn's not perfect and that culture is not perfect.
Speaker 0: But also, the Bronx has to recognize that I'm going after Brooklyn because this is whoever's closest to me right now.
Speaker 0: Like, it's not right.
Speaker 0: We're allies, but I'm going to go after whoever is closest to me right now.
Speaker 0: Because that's who I can punch first.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, that's how, you know, again, that's how New York is.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, if the rest of the world was all, you know, eliminated.
Speaker 1: It's like New York.
Speaker 0: Our knives conflict within.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, the Bronx is the ignored forgotten district, like borough of the city to most New Yorkers other than Staten Island, which is rightly ignored and forgotten.
Speaker 1: But all right.
Speaker 1: So that right.
Speaker 1: So you get the.
Speaker 1: Branca, right, was, you know, obviously represents the Bronx name like Branca.
Speaker 0: But Bronx, I love how it has the history of long before New York.
Speaker 0: It's the oldest settlements.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And, you know, of course.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: She like runs, you know, an art.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it's like, is it a museum or like an art?
Speaker 1: It's a gallery.
Speaker 0: It's like it's like a city funded and philanthropist funded gallery that showcases like non white art and non straight art and struggles to get local.
Speaker 1: Local artists are living there, working there.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: They got studios in there, you know, display places in there.
Speaker 1: And Branca runs that shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And she's in her sixties and she'll she'll fuck you up.
Speaker 0: I mean, she fucks up Mrs.
Speaker 0: White pretty early on before she really realizes what she is.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Well, she's also got, you know, but the thing is, Branca also is like the most experience.
Speaker 1: I think, you know, Branca sort of became a borough, I think, before other people.
Speaker 1: It has like more experience with like the city power.
Speaker 0: Well, it's more that she was more in tune with what her boroughs really like, which is compounded by the fact that a lot of New Yorkers don't really know what the Bronx is like.
Speaker 0: The Bronx, it has like physical, very diverse.
Speaker 1: And it also, you know, I think also the Bronx different from other boroughs, at least on purpose, cut off from the rest of the city by Robert Moses.
Speaker 1: That's one thing.
Speaker 0: And the book addresses that.
Speaker 0: I like how they treat those heat freeways as like wounds in the Bronx that were never fully healed.
Speaker 1: But also, right.
Speaker 1: In terms of it's like a lot of the other boroughs, right.
Speaker 1: You know, Manhattan, for example.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like all the evilness of Manhattan is like in, you know, centuries ago.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like, yeah.
Speaker 1: You know, whereas in the Bronx, it's like if you were in the Bronx in like 1950, 1960, even maybe 1970 something, it's like it was sort of like a suburban kind of place, depending on the neighborhood.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, you had like affluent white people and like, you know, homes, driveways.
Speaker 1: And, you know, it might not even you might be like, that's the Bronx.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: it's like, yeah, a significant part of the Bronx looked like that at, you know, not too long ago, but that's all gone now.
Speaker 0: But also the Bronx has been largely on its own historically in that it's not funded enough.
Speaker 0: It's not invested in compared to the other boroughs.
Speaker 0: The other boroughs basically ignore it unless they have to pay attention to it.
Speaker 1: The mayor probably goes to the Bronx less than any other, you know, no matter which mayor it is, which party they're from.
Speaker 1: The Bronx is the least attention.
Speaker 0: So a lot of like current day neighborhoods in the Bronx have to be extremely self-reliant.
Speaker 0: But anyway.
Speaker 0: We got Queens, who is just delightful.
Speaker 1: Queens is extremely Queens.
Speaker 0: She's new.
Speaker 0: She like new to the city.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: A nerd has a job.
Speaker 1: Queens representing the immigrants.
Speaker 1: Queens, the most diverse, you know, place in the entire country's world, maybe.
Speaker 0: Queens is absolutely the most diverse geographic space in America.
Speaker 0: I don't know about the world, but definitely America.
Speaker 0: I've seen multiple papers talk about that.
Speaker 0: And Queens is also a representation, but it's diverse in not just in races, diverse in cultures, diverse in ideas, diverse in neighborhoods, diverse in languages.
Speaker 1: Language is like the number of.
Speaker 1: I think I was at the Queens Museum and they were like, yeah, there's like over like some hundred something languages.
Speaker 0: I saw stats that I'm not going to try to Google now, but it was something to the effect of the.
Speaker 0: the Queens in New York City has the highest density of actively spoken languages of any place on earth.
Speaker 1: According to 138 languages are spoken in Queens.
Speaker 1: Diversity capital of the world.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: According to babel.com.
Speaker 0: But also language site like look what Queens is as a character.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of people who are highly skilled doctors, technology professionals from all over the world who come to New York.
Speaker 0: Queens is where they get their start.
Speaker 0: And they usually end up working for a relatively unethical company that they hate, because that's where all the money and jobs are for people who are that skilled.
Speaker 1: There was even a mention of Rims Neighborhood in this book.
Speaker 0: Yeah, full of tech bros, people like me.
Speaker 0: I came to New York.
Speaker 0: I went straight to Queens and I worked for a relatively unethical company.
Speaker 1: In a neighborhood that was called out for having people like rim in it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a bad part.
Speaker 1: The one part of Queens.
Speaker 1: that's not true.
Speaker 1: It's not good.
Speaker 0: This part of Queens is rapidly becoming Manhattan, too.
Speaker 1: The thing I the thing about Queens is that, you know, not only is the characters spot on, but the scene that really, you know, that house, that house, they all live in, that apartment building, the house, they all the place Queens lives in the apartment building.
Speaker 1: And there's a scene where someone goes up the stairs.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's that's the scene.
Speaker 1: I was thinking of every sees all the people, the different people who live in the different apartments in the building and what they're up to.
Speaker 1: And it's like, it's like they took all of Queens, right?
Speaker 1: Every kind of person that you could possibly put it in somehow fit them into one building and then describe them all on just a few pages, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, I was like, I was in that apartment building and I'm like, I've been in that apartment building forever.
Speaker 1: You know, it's not even a real building.
Speaker 1: But, you know, I've been in buildings just like that.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And it's like even in my building, which is not exactly like that building, it's newer and fancier.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But it still has, you know, a good chunk of that feeling in it, despite being, you know, in a different part of Queens, you know, with more monies and whatnot.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So then we got Staten Island, who, well, is horrible.
Speaker 0: But I got to say this, what a spot on well-written character.
Speaker 1: Well, this is right.
Speaker 1: She's the major.
Speaker 0: So close to figuring it out.
Speaker 0: But the thing is, Staten Island in the real world gets so close to figuring out and then reliably votes for Nazis, destroys itself like it is politically a horrible and dangerous place.
Speaker 1: And there are parts of Staten Island near the north part that aren't that way.
Speaker 1: But pretty much once you go past the north part, it's like it's suddenly, you know, to the car area.
Speaker 0: But she is like the stereotypical white girl who's been sheltered by racist parents in a fucked up marriage, who is afraid to even leave home and has never actually taken the ferry to the city and hates it because everyone around her hates it and is afraid of everyone.
Speaker 0: I mean, she almost kills Sao Paulo within 30 seconds of meeting him because she realizes he's a brown man.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, there is, you know, but even the Staten Island, right, there's sort of like this glimmer of like, you know, maybe right, you know, she'll come around.
Speaker 0: Oh, and if this book was written by anyone other than N.K.
Speaker 0: Jemisin, my fear was they would have had her come around.
Speaker 0: The fact that this book did not have her come around, I think it was very poignant.
Speaker 1: Well, because it's showing you the reality is that, like, yes, there are people in Staten Island.
Speaker 1: I've had coworkers like, you know, they're not bad Staten Island people, even though they live there.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But it's like they live in Staten Island.
Speaker 1: They, you know, they commute, get on the little ferry every day, come to Manhattan, work.
Speaker 0: I used to work downtown.
Speaker 0: There's a one bus stop right outside my office when I worked down there.
Speaker 0: That was one of the main buses that goes back to a neighborhood in Staten Island.
Speaker 0: And people would be lined up all the way down the block to take the commuter bus home every day.
Speaker 0: One hundred percent of those people were white.
Speaker 1: Well, sure.
Speaker 1: But, you know, there are like some people in Staten Island, some percentage of them that are sort of representing that hope that, you know, Staten Island is at least in part New York.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like there is some amount of New Yorkness via the conduit of that ferry that is in the Verrazano.
Speaker 0: I guess the beginning of the book to the beginning of the book makes a very optimistic picture when she's sort of like feeling herself as Staten Island and exploring the island.
Speaker 0: And it does make a point about how Staten Island is a less New York blue collar place.
Speaker 0: But it comes into New York to do the jobs that won't pay anyone else to do because those people can only afford to live in Staten Island, but they can only afford to live there because they're usually middle class ish families who are white, who have land from the 50s, and they just still live in those houses.
Speaker 0: Like it's unearned middle class, third generation wealth.
Speaker 0: And it makes this point about how like these are a different type of person who are part of the fabric of New York.
Speaker 0: A ton of Staten Islanders work in Manhattan and how New York turns his back on them, disrespects them, like ignores them.
Speaker 0: And it starts to make a point that maybe if we embrace them more, they would come around a little bit.
Speaker 0: But the book categorically argues in the end that they'll fuck us over every time.
Speaker 1: Well, the current state of things, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, I wonder, right, is, you know, it's like, I don't think the book will become dated.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like, you know, it'll just be it'll just be set in this time.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: If someone reads this book 50 or 100 years from now, they'll look at it the same way we look.
Speaker 1: You know, I was just comment.
Speaker 0: Trump got 30th century.
Speaker 0: Trump got 33 percent more votes in Staten Island in 2020 than he got in 2016.
Speaker 0: It is getting worse, not better there.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's you know, it's percentage wise, it's not great, but there is still a fraction of it.
Speaker 1: that is, you know, New York right on the north side.
Speaker 0: It bleeds anyway, but just the book portrays her so perfectly, especially that scene where her dad, the like directly corrupt, evil cop who clearly beats his wife, tries to hook her up with the literal Proud Boy Nazi with the swastika tattoo.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: That guy was definitely a Richard Spencer like stand in type to a T. But her inner monologue is fascinating the way it's written, because like you're reading the description of that Nazi guy and I'm reading it.
Speaker 0: I'm thinking I imagine the Proud Boy wearing the suspenders and the erotic mustache with the Nazi hair.
Speaker 0: But the way she sees him as he looks like a gay guy.
Speaker 0: Why is my dad hanging out with a gay guy?
Speaker 0: Like she doesn't even recognize the fact that 1488 is a Nazi tattoo.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: It has to be.
Speaker 1: a lot of people don't.
Speaker 0: They don't, but especially the Staten Island sheltered girl.
Speaker 0: And she's so close to taking the ferry to the city.
Speaker 0: But every time, given the choice between trusting a non-white person and trusting Mrs.
Speaker 0: White, she trusts Mrs.
Speaker 0: White.
Speaker 0: And in the end, she is Mrs.
Speaker 0: Fuck her.
Speaker 1: So there's one more character, which is Vazina, right?
Speaker 1: Who isn't from New York, right?
Speaker 0: Transpose the N and the Z.
Speaker 1: It's hard not to because there's a Vazina trophy.
Speaker 0: Half black, half Portuguese, works in the Bronx, lives in Jersey City.
Speaker 0: I got it literally.
Speaker 0: As soon as I knew she was from Jersey City, I assumed she was going to be the actual Fifth Borough.
Speaker 0: I called it immediately.
Speaker 0: I was 100% sure.
Speaker 1: Easy call, right?
Speaker 0: Because in the real world, Jersey City, like we make fun of Jersey City because fuck Jersey.
Speaker 0: But New Jersey City is so much more tightly coupled to and part of the fabric of New York City than Staten Island.
Speaker 0: It's ludicrous that Staten Island is even part of New York City politically.
Speaker 1: So for people who don't live here, right?
Speaker 1: So to go to Staten Island from New York City, Manhattan or Brooklyn, you need to either use a ferry, which is free, or you can drive over the Verrazano Bridge, which is long.
Speaker 0: Or you can take a bus that uses that same bridge.
Speaker 0: It takes forever.
Speaker 1: And if you reach Staten Island, do you know what's over there?
Speaker 1: It's just like houses.
Speaker 1: Like there's nothing tall there.
Speaker 1: It doesn't feel like a city.
Speaker 1: It feels like a suburb place.
Speaker 1: There's literal farms.
Speaker 1: Strip malls, you know.
Speaker 0: Houses with yards everywhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Pools, swimming pools, right?
Speaker 0: Just empty land.
Speaker 1: Just tons of empty land.
Speaker 1: It doesn't feel like a city.
Speaker 1: Well, there's some nice parks, actually.
Speaker 1: You can like, anyway.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, well, I got my vaccine there.
Speaker 0: So we took our bikes there and biked around the entire island.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so.
Speaker 1: But if you go to Jersey City, right?
Speaker 1: So to get to Jersey City, you can go through like the Lincoln Tunnel, or you can just use George Washington Bridge or the Holland Tunnel, or you can use an Amtrak or a New Jersey transit train, or you can use a path train.
Speaker 1: It's like there are a lot of ways to get to North Jersey.
Speaker 1: A bus, buses, tons of them, right?
Speaker 1: You can't take a bus to Staten Island.
Speaker 1: I guess you can over the Verrazano.
Speaker 1: But anyway, there's a lot of ways to get over to North Jersey.
Speaker 1: Jersey City specifically.
Speaker 1: And if you go over there, you know, Hoboken also, I guess, you know, kinda it's like all that area over there at the very north of Jersey.
Speaker 1: It it, you know, it doesn't feel like the rest of New Jersey.
Speaker 1: Like there are tall office buildings over there like skyscraper ones.
Speaker 0: Dude, that North Jersey is a more dense real city than most cities in America are.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of people there.
Speaker 1: They're actually like little.
Speaker 1: They're not really.
Speaker 1: I guess they're technically ferries, but like water taxis.
Speaker 1: Like a lot of people will live like on the water in North Jersey.
Speaker 1: And I guess when they were still commuting as a thing pre pandemic, people would take a little water taxi over to Manhattan and back right to get to work just because it's cheaper to live over there.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You're a Jersey resident technically.
Speaker 1: You vote for Jersey governor.
Speaker 1: You know, you don't get to vote for New York mayor.
Speaker 1: But those people who live there right are more like, you know, the New Yorkers, right?
Speaker 1: Then people from Staten Island are culturally speaking like they're.
Speaker 0: they're less connected because they go home at the end of the day, like they don't stay out in the city.
Speaker 1: I mean, someone from Queens taking the seven train to Manhattan to their job versus someone living in Jersey City taking a pen train, a path train.
Speaker 1: It's like those are more culturally similar than someone who lives in Staten Island.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I mean, in a just world, that would just be the sixth borough and Yonkers would be the seventh borough.
Speaker 0: And then we go back to six because Staten Island has nothing to do with New York.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So the book officially, you know, I guess spoilers, right?
Speaker 0: Officially recognizes that there's a great line.
Speaker 0: I think Branka figures it out.
Speaker 0: She's like, wait a minute.
Speaker 0: Cities don't follow politics and geographic made up nonsense.
Speaker 0: That's where the city is.
Speaker 0: It's right there.
Speaker 1: Yep, exactly.
Speaker 1: So there's that.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: OK, so now the primary conflict of this book, because really there are.
Speaker 0: there are a couple more characters.
Speaker 0: Sao Paulo figures in pretty heavily.
Speaker 1: And Hong Kong is there a little bit.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Hong Kong's real funny.
Speaker 0: I think I laughed out loud at a few of his lines more than anything, but Sao Paulo was real fun and they used him a lot and he felt pretty true to my very, very.
Speaker 0: I've only been to Sao Paulo twice.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't I don't know anything about Sao Paulo other than, you know, where it is on the map.
Speaker 0: And I've been there a couple of times, but it's interesting because it is imagine Fifth Avenue like it's very Manhattan like city, but ringed by the remnants of favelas and extreme poverty.
Speaker 0: And also imagine if Manhattan had a murder rate.
Speaker 0: that was to the point that like you would have a bodyguard if you could afford it.
Speaker 1: I really like those one scene with Sao Paulo where he was not doing well and they healed him with, you know, Portuguese.
Speaker 0: Hong Kong brings some shitty Portuguese cigarettes that are close enough and some, you know, some Brazilian cigarettes.
Speaker 0: And then they get some Portuguese canned ice cream treats out of the freezer.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: That was at the freeze.
Speaker 1: And I was like.
Speaker 1: I was like, dang, I'm like, does that mean like if I go to some other place and I get hurt that I could get healed with pizza and bagels?
Speaker 1: I mean, I could be in big trouble because where the fuck are they going to get any pizza and bagels from?
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, exactly.
Speaker 0: You're running around Seattle like I got to find a bagel and some quarter water stat.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like I'm in trouble if I leave here.
Speaker 1: Maybe that's why I don't leave here.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You know, the fantasy is reality in that sense.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I guess it's white.
Speaker 0: The only other character.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: So that's the main the main conflict of this book.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Is really, you know, you know, it talks about all the issues.
Speaker 1: But, you know, the gentrification is the main issue that's going on.
Speaker 0: Mrs.
Speaker 0: White represents so many things.
Speaker 0: She represents global capitalism.
Speaker 0: She represents gentrification.
Speaker 0: She represents the imaginary city of really.
Speaker 0: Which is the which is the almost literal stereotype.
Speaker 0: This is what we've been dancing around the whole time of how racist white people who don't understand cities think cities are alive.
Speaker 1: So throughout the book.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: There's clearly some sort of, you know, evil monster.
Speaker 1: There's something about multiple dimensions that they keep alluding to.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, and they can see that like on the Starbucks, there's all these white scene at the end where all this all the national chains are where the evil fungus clumps first.
Speaker 0: That's just.
Speaker 0: that's how it is.
Speaker 0: That's really how it is.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Pretty much.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like, you know, the non it's like, yeah, there are some new things in the city that are like, you know, yeah, it's like they're new, but it's like New York is always changing.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Just because it's new doesn't mean it's not New York.
Speaker 1: But there are things that are, you know, not New York.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: They don't belong.
Speaker 1: It's like even if you're in the real world, it's like, yeah, that state, you know, it's like, ah, there's a crappy tourist gift shop.
Speaker 1: There's a bodega and there's a Chick-fil-A.
Speaker 1: It's like that doesn't fit.
Speaker 0: Chick-fil-A doesn't belong there.
Speaker 1: That doesn't belong here.
Speaker 0: Like the Applebee's in Times Square belongs there, but no other Applebee's in Manhattan belongs there.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: If you was an Applebee's in, you know, I guess there was one in Astoria, but it didn't belong there.
Speaker 1: I guess it's still there.
Speaker 0: Starbucks has existed in New York and that's fine.
Speaker 0: But Starbucks is up here to replace literally everything over time.
Speaker 0: And then they're eventually replaced by banks.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like they're a new.
Speaker 1: So an example of a new thing that fits right.
Speaker 1: It's like, oh, someone opened up yet another boba place.
Speaker 1: It's like, it's like, yeah, that, you know, that fits that.
Speaker 0: I got there like six boba places here now and like in our neighborhood, maybe more.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: You know, it's just there anyway.
Speaker 1: So that's where there's all these white tentacles.
Speaker 1: And the characters are, you know, the New York.
Speaker 1: characters are trying to get together to help.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And then find the main New York.
Speaker 1: The primary.
Speaker 1: And simultaneously.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: There's, you know, Mrs.
Speaker 1: White, who is right up to no good and is clearly, you know, a Lovecraftian horror of sorts.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Both figuratively and in the story, literally.
Speaker 0: I love that.
Speaker 1: That's that's the part I didn't catch.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Until, you know, later I was like, oh, that was so obvious.
Speaker 0: The first time when Staten Island asks her where you're from and she doesn't understand.
Speaker 0: And we knew it started with an R. And I didn't I just I was like, I'll bet that'll come back later.
Speaker 0: And I was trying to figure it out.
Speaker 1: I didn't think about the starting with an R.
Speaker 0: I thought about it, but I did.
Speaker 0: I don't I did not figure it out then.
Speaker 0: Don't I'm not even going to pretend I did.
Speaker 0: I kept every time it came up.
Speaker 0: I was like, are are what could it be?
Speaker 0: It's not just gentrification.
Speaker 0: Like it's got it.
Speaker 0: What could it be?
Speaker 0: What's the R word?
Speaker 0: They wouldn't have brought it up.
Speaker 1: I miss I guess I missed the part with the R hint and maybe I would have found it earlier.
Speaker 0: There are three instances where the R hint comes up before it is revealed.
Speaker 0: Because every time Staten Island has lost over that she's thinking about the R again.
Speaker 0: And she can't quite pronounce it anyway.
Speaker 1: So this you know, Mrs.
Speaker 1: White is all over making trouble.
Speaker 1: Monster in the bathroom scene.
Speaker 1: You know, fucking people up.
Speaker 0: Like what are her appearances?
Speaker 1: Sending Nazis to to fuck up the museum.
Speaker 0: But also sending a white lady with a cell phone calling the cops on someone in the park.
Speaker 0: Like.
Speaker 0: that is so exactly how they are and how that problem is.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's basically all the bad things that are happening in New York.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Have these tentacles on them.
Speaker 1: That only the New York characters can see that like are identifying them.
Speaker 1: You know, as like, yeah, this is, you know, they're trying to prevent New York from being born for some reason.
Speaker 1: And the whole time you're thinking it's, you know, this is some sort of interdimensional war going on.
Speaker 1: that, you know, between cities.
Speaker 0: Well, the way Mrs.
Speaker 0: White describes it to the only person who asks her, which is Staten Island, is, oh, if a city is born, it destroys countless realities.
Speaker 0: It's very much a bokurano type plot.
Speaker 1: But something like that.
Speaker 0: But that's also very much a misrepresentation to edging on the point of an outright lie, because it turns out later, of course, no, she represents a city just like any other city doing the same thing.
Speaker 0: But I like the dual purpose that serves, because on one hand, white supremacy just lies to people.
Speaker 0: It lies straight up to Staten Island, and she believes it because she wants to.
Speaker 0: All her tendrils in the city, like the people, the corrupt cops and the proud boys who wear the tentacles, they wear them because they wanted to.
Speaker 0: They wanted to believe that that's in them, because it's making this point that New York is full of racists.
Speaker 0: We're not going to.
Speaker 0: New York may vote Democrat and maybe a really great place.
Speaker 0: But this book does not pretend that New York is not full of a lot of really shitty people.
Speaker 0: There are shitty people everywhere.
Speaker 0: But it also makes this point that cities naturally gravitate toward minimizing the damage those people do, because you can't be that openly shitty in a city surrounded by millions of people without getting knocked the fuck out.
Speaker 1: Yep, pretty much anyway.
Speaker 1: So this Mrs.
Speaker 1: White is basically creating trouble and pursuing the characters right the whole time, you know, and whatnot.
Speaker 1: And then, you know, they get they're trying to go get Staten Island and that doesn't go so well.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: I love Staten Island.
Speaker 0: straight up joins them, like joins her, gives up, becomes the white supremacist Nazi stronghold for really, yeah, the Lovecraftian city.
Speaker 0: Like that was an interesting place to end.
Speaker 1: So I think the thing there's another layer to it, right, which is that, you know, in term it's still a fantasy novel for nerds in addition to being a New York novel.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And, you know, Lovecraft and Lovecraftian horror universe is public domain.
Speaker 1: It's so old.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But also it's something that, you know, has a place in nerd culture.
Speaker 0: I mean, my parents introduced me to Lovecraft before it was pop culture known like.
Speaker 0: that was something I was reading in elementary school.
Speaker 0: I didn't know about his racism.
Speaker 0: I was just reading it as a naive kid about like, oh, it's existential, non-Euclidean cyclopean horror.
Speaker 0: I'm into this.
Speaker 1: Right, exactly.
Speaker 1: So, you know, but more recently, indeed, you know, there has been a greater focus on the fact that, yeah, Lovecraft is a really awful person.
Speaker 1: His actual works, you know, how great were they really?
Speaker 0: Well, even if they are great at face value, if you know the context of what he believes and you read them again, you cannot escape the fact that all of his non-Euclidean stuff is basically just code for non-white people and cities.
Speaker 1: So, you know, as nerds, right, we had this Lovecraftian thing that was like one of our nerd staples and was actually public domain, you know, and people were using it for all kinds of stuff and enjoying it, right, in a not racist way, right, despite its origins.
Speaker 1: But more of more recent times, right, it's sort of been, you know, less attractive, right, because, you know, there's more focus on the reality of who Lovecraft was.
Speaker 1: And in this book, by making, you know, Relay, right, and, you know, the fantasy of Lovecraft's universe and the city from it, right, the literal enemy, and also white supremacist at the same time, right, the story is able to, right, on the one hand, you know, point out the truth, right, and denounce it strongly, but also be able to tell a story about, right, you
Speaker 0: know, all those
Speaker 1: classic Lovecraftian things, right, tentacle monsters, right, multidimensional scary things.
Speaker 0: Oh, that scene where they try to kill the Bronx with the painting that would have sucked them into, really, yeah, was fantastic.
Speaker 0: Well, it would have sucked them into what the kind of person... It was very clear, it was...
Speaker 1: Non-Euclidean geometries, right, all the tropes of the...
Speaker 0: I read that scene, I thought about that scene a lot, because it's very much... That is what New York looks like to shitty people who have never been here and hate this city for no reason.
Speaker 0: They see it as a filthy city full of piss reek and immigrants and violence, because they're shitty people.
Speaker 0: They don't know what it's actually like here, and that's how a lot of people who complain about New York feel.
Speaker 0: Even tourists who come here and just go to Times Square, go home and think New York sucks, and frankly, great, never come back, you're not the kind of person we want here.
Speaker 1: But, you know, by making it the villain in that way, it's like, look, she was able to tell, right, and sort of take back the Lovecraftian horror and use it, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, by making it the white supremacist villain in that way, and that's sort of like a genius move.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, it's like, you know, if you were just to, you know, write a Lovecraftian horror normally, nowadays, it's sort of like, eh, it's all right, what are you doing, man?
Speaker 1: It's like, that's not good, right?
Speaker 1: Don't do that.
Speaker 1: But here it's like, no, we'll take it back for the nerds, right, the right way.
Speaker 0: But that's the moment when I started figuring it out, that it was literal love, because Lovecraft gets...
Speaker 1: I knew that it was Lovecraftian in nature with all the tentacles and, you know, and everything, but the fact that she was literally also a city, right, got away from me because up until that point, every city was a real city on Earth, geographically, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there's a point where one of the, they're talking about how cities like Atlantis, when they talked about Atlantis is what I figured.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's when you, at that point, it's revealed, basically.
Speaker 0: Yep, because Atlantis was a city that existed and ceased to exist.
Speaker 0: So in our reality, it never existed.
Speaker 0: It was a fiction, it's a fictional city.
Speaker 0: So really, yeah, literal fictional city from our current reality, meaning it is perfectly fair game to be a city in this universe.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but, you know, but also it's like, you know, there was, I didn't realize that, you know, Mrs.
Speaker 1: White was a city because of the interdimensionality aspect.
Speaker 1: I thought that there were like some aliens or something.
Speaker 0: Well, because she was lying to Staten Island.
Speaker 0: There was some other, or maybe like a city from some other dimension, you know, not from a real city on the scale of Sao Paulo or New York or Hong Kong or London.
Speaker 0: in the real world is built on the backs of millions and millions of dead and exploited people.
Speaker 0: You know, even a city that's trying to do good has ruined lots of people along the way.
Speaker 0: That's just how history has always been.
Speaker 0: And all the other cities in this book don't shy away from that.
Speaker 0: But Mrs.
Speaker 0: White doesn't say she's a city.
Speaker 0: She just talks about that death and points out all those other cities are causing it.
Speaker 0: Just openly lies to Staten Island.
Speaker 0: I thought that was a very nice touch.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just, you know, there's just so many of those kinds of alignments, right?
Speaker 1: It's just like, it's like, you know, it's like you could, if you tried to think of something, like you could think of a few, but it's like, how much work must it have been to write this book?
Speaker 1: And basically almost every sentence is like some new alignment of, right, the characters and the reality of the world that we live in.
Speaker 1: While also evoking some other fictional works that evoke something.
Speaker 0: so, so New York, I could almost smell the subway when Manhattan summons a spectral idea of a subway car to escape.
Speaker 0: Like the way the magic works is just real fun in this book, too.
Speaker 1: It's a super New York book.
Speaker 1: You know, it's also a fantasy book.
Speaker 1: It takes back, you know, Lovecraftian horror from the white supremacists.
Speaker 0: You know, yeah, I cannot, I cannot recommend this book to anyone who can read English or a translated version of it.
Speaker 0: Even this book is so fantastic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's such, I just, you know, I asked some of the listener, but, you know, the, they mentioned, you know, I was like, hey, if you don't know anything about New York, right, how does this book come across?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like, well, we got in the chat to Canucks.
Speaker 0: I guess just enjoying this unique glimpse into big city Americana.
Speaker 0: Is it really like that?
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's I'll tell you what, we'll keep the city part and we're going to trade health care parts.
Speaker 0: We had one New Yorker in my book club, but we couldn't tell how much she was joking when she said that Aislinn was, quote, spot on.
Speaker 1: Not joking at all.
Speaker 0: I'm glad I skipped the Staten Island Ferry when I visited New York.
Speaker 1: It actually, the ferry is worth riding.
Speaker 1: The Staten Island Ferry is not a waste of time.
Speaker 0: I would say the Staten Island Ferry is very New York.
Speaker 0: Staten Island is not.
Speaker 0: But the Staten Island Ferry is.
Speaker 0: So I'm going to give you the lowdown.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: If you're a tourist and you come to if you're a tourist and you come to New York, right, you're probably going to want to see some Statue of Liberty.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Which is, you know, if you look at a map and figure out where it is, if you don't understand, but it's out in the water like it's if you go to if you try to go to the bottom of Manhattan and look at it, you're going to need like some binoculars to see anything.
Speaker 0: And there are tour boats that will take you to it.
Speaker 0: The Staten Island Ferry.
Speaker 1: There is an official boat that will take you.
Speaker 1: It is not cheap.
Speaker 1: It's a pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: It's not really worth it.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like, OK, you stand at the bottom of it and it's a little island with a statue on it and then you come back.
Speaker 1: And I don't know if they're letting people to the top anymore.
Speaker 0: They haven't for a long time.
Speaker 1: I don't know if they started again, but even if they do, it's not easy.
Speaker 1: And you probably won't.
Speaker 0: Staten Island Ferry goes past it twice.
Speaker 0: Real close.
Speaker 1: You can get on the Staten Island Ferry for free for no money whatsoever.
Speaker 1: You just get you just wait for it to come.
Speaker 1: You get on it and you look out the window.
Speaker 1: Make sure you're sitting on the New Jersey side of the boat.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So you can see the Statue of Liberty.
Speaker 0: Literally the best way to see it short of hiring a private helicopter to take you to it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And it's like.
Speaker 1: you'll see it.
Speaker 1: You'll see, you know, you have a free boat ride.
Speaker 1: It won't take very long at all.
Speaker 1: It costs zero dollars.
Speaker 1: Then when you get to Staten Island, just wait for the boat to take you right back.
Speaker 1: Don't do anything on Staten Island.
Speaker 0: So you're burying the lead, though.
Speaker 0: The Staten Island Ferry is free.
Speaker 0: And there are a ton of people who will sell you tickets to it in New York.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: There are scammers who stand all around the battery area near the ferry terminal trying to sell tickets to the Staten Island Ferry to tourists who don't know that it's free.
Speaker 1: You can just go on it.
Speaker 1: No money whatsoever.
Speaker 1: Don't buy a ticket to it unless you're, you know, want to make a donation, I guess.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, I really come to the.
Speaker 0: come to the Geek Nights Forum.
Speaker 0: Come to the Discord.
Speaker 0: Talk about this book with us.
Speaker 0: If you've never been to New York, we really want to know what you thought of this book.
Speaker 0: And I really want to stress to you that living here does feel the way that book is like.
Speaker 0: We're not exaggerating.
Speaker 0: And if you ever come here, you'll see it.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So now that we've gotten away with doing a book club book in less than two and a half years, right, we got to make up for lost time and do more books more frequently.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So I the next book club book, you know, usually me and rim alternate choosing right here, even though I guess it's, you know, it's my B that I chose the Genji book, but it's still my turn anyway.
Speaker 1: Tough shit.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: One pick is one pick, no matter how long it takes.
Speaker 1: So but I'm not going to use my pick right in penance for my previous pick.
Speaker 1: I'm going to give this pick away.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And I've given my pick away not to rim.
Speaker 1: rim rim has enough picks.
Speaker 1: He's going to get 50 percent of the picks.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I'm going to give my pick away to the listener.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And the listener has already made their pick right there.
Speaker 1: The listener has been hounding us to read a particular book club book for quite a long time.
Speaker 1: And after I finished Genji, I already read the book.
Speaker 1: I went ahead and I read the book that the listener has been asking for.
Speaker 1: I've already finished it.
Speaker 1: Rim hasn't read a page of it.
Speaker 1: And I can see why the listener has chosen this book as a geek nights book club book.
Speaker 1: There are many geek nights things in it.
Speaker 1: And it wasn't.
Speaker 1: you know, it was.
Speaker 1: I guess it's worthy enough of being a book club book.
Speaker 1: So let's let's let the listener have their day.
Speaker 1: The next geek nights book club book chosen by the listener is Nine Fox Gambit by Yoon Ha Lee.
Speaker 0: So she's been on my list for a long time also because of the listener.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the listener has asked for this book so much.
Speaker 1: So it's like, fine, you know, you can have this one listener.
Speaker 1: We'll give it to you.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: And then I guess Rim will go back to pick.
Speaker 1: We'll go back to, you know, us picking again for now on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got I got to narrow it down.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of I got to choose.
Speaker 0: Do I pick a book that I want an excuse to force myself to read and pull up ahead of other books in my queue or do I pick the book that's currently at the top of my queue?
Speaker 0: That's what I got to think about.
Speaker 1: And just to give you a in case you want like a summary of what this book Nine Fox Gambit is about, it's right where instead of we did a fantasy book here.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So Nine Fox Gambit takes us back to the other nerdy realm of sci fi book.
Speaker 1: We're going back into space.
Speaker 1: And basically what the story is, is that there is a space empire of sorts and they have a space station, but it's like a big fucking space station, like probably Death Star size, like this whole, you know, communities, cities living inside of it.
Speaker 1: It's enormous.
Speaker 0: It's no DS nine.
Speaker 1: And there was some sort of revolution on it of some kind.
Speaker 1: It's been overthrown and the empire sends our main character to go and take care of that and reacquire the space station for the empire.
Speaker 0: I found a summary that says the novel covers space opera, fantasy, Korean folklore and mathematics.
Speaker 1: That's correct.
Speaker 1: And yeah, there are, you know, you're going to get some space battles here, right?
Speaker 1: It is a book with a spaceship on the cover.
Speaker 0: Oh, I haven't read a book with a spaceship on the cover and a space battle in a while now that I think about it.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's also one like a pile of awards.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So, um, you know, probably.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So again, if you somehow listen to this and didn't read this book, just go, go read this book.
Speaker 0: Like, I don't know what to say.
Speaker 0: It's fantastic.
Speaker 0: I love it.
Speaker 1: And the next one is coming soon.
Speaker 1: We, I don't know if we'll do a book club episode on the next one, but we may just do a Thursday episode on the next one, you know, because we're going to read it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's out.
Speaker 0: Absolutely.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And the Patreon, Patrons for this book club episode of Geek Nights are Heidi McNichol, Ellen Joyce, LaClegie, Dread Lily, Tenebra, and a bunch of people who really want me to say their names, Krista Dodd, Chris Freimer, Clinton Walton, Dex, Finn, Help Computer, Shaggy I-85, Rebecca Dunne, Ruby in Bedville, 34 Cowards, Sam Erickson, Servin' Rott Horrell, Taylor Braun.
Speaker 0: The next station is Dundas, Dundas Station, and several people whose names I'm not going to say at their request.
Speaker 0: I simply leave you with something that's going to linger in your brain for a while.
Speaker 0: I apologize, slightly.
Speaker 0: ♪ But I'll keep singing in ♪ ♪ In ♪.