Speaker 0: It's Thursday, July 21st, 2022.
Speaker 0: I'm Rym.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight we are talking about zoos.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So, uh, something that I didn't quite, like, obviously, logically, this was gonna happen someday.
Speaker 0: But I never actually, like, really thought about when it would happen.
Speaker 0: Like, it was something that just did not cross my mind that it even would ever actually happen.
Speaker 0: I did not actively plan for it, but, uh, right before, you know, we took a week off because a bunch of us went to a private beach house in Wildwood to, uh, beach and somehow not get sunburned.
Speaker 0: But, uh, right before that, I, uh, I shaved like you do.
Speaker 0: And then I thought, you know what?
Speaker 0: I should put it, get a new blade out and, like, replace it and bring it to the shore with me because I would like to stay somewhat shaven at the beach so I don't get too hot.
Speaker 0: And then I go and I realize the blade I had just discarded was the last of the gigantic fucking box of blades that I bought when we first moved to New York City in 2009.
Speaker 1: I mean, I have a giant symbol.
Speaker 1: You're using them at my- you're probably changing them too often.
Speaker 1: How many times do you use one blade?
Speaker 0: Uh, 15 to 20?
Speaker 1: Oh, that's actually way too many times to use one blade.
Speaker 1: Ah, well, well.
Speaker 1: You're supposed to use them, like, six to ten times.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 0: However, my shaving patterns have changed a lot over the years because I kept growing a beard and, uh, for a while now- I was about to shame you for being uneconomical, but you're being overly economical.
Speaker 1: Or you're lying, which is not, you know, out of the realm.
Speaker 0: Thing is, I went through blades faster when I would shave my whole face and when I didn't use clippers and I've done all sorts of different stuff.
Speaker 0: But, uh, for a while now, since I did the beard, I pretty much only have to shave, like, one part of my neck and not even that often.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, how many blades were in your mega pack of blades?
Speaker 0: Uh, a thousand?
Speaker 0: Two thousand?
Speaker 1: A thousand?
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: No, the math doesn't work out for 15 shaves, a thousand blades.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing is, I tried to find- That would be 15- even if you shaved every day, if you use one blade 15 times and you have a thousand, that would be 15,000 days, uh, in years, which would be 41 years.
Speaker 1: So, no, you either weren't shaving- you didn't have a thousand blades or you didn't use each one 15 times.
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: well, the tricky part was, right before the show, I went to my Amazon to find, like, the thing I'd actually ordered and the receipt in my email just says, like, "Bulk Package Feather Blades" and if I click on the link to it, it takes me to an Amazon, uh, not available.
Speaker 0: So, I had to buy- Well, I have- I have a package of a hundred blades and it cost me, like, nine dollars and I bought it in- I definitely got way bigger than that, so let me see what I just bought.
Speaker 1: I bought it four years ago and I've only used, like, maybe three or four of the packages.
Speaker 1: that are five blades each, so I've used maybe a quarter at most, about, of the- of the hundred blades, I'd say.
Speaker 0: Yep, so this time, I bought- I'm pretty sure I bought the same thing you were talking about because what I bought now was a pack of one hundred Feather Double Aged Blades- Double Aged Blades and it's, like, one-
Speaker 1: And they're all- they're little packs of five and they're all- they're all crammed into it,
Speaker 0: yeah.
Speaker 0: It's, like, one skinny little thing.
Speaker 0: It's clearly the kind of thing that you would, like, buy and put in, like, by the cash register of your drugstore and sell.
Speaker 1: Yes, that is what it is.
Speaker 0: That is what I have bought now.
Speaker 1: I have the same thing.
Speaker 1: So- Only different brand.
Speaker 0: So, uh, now I realize that the other thing I need to replace is I have this little plastic bin that, whenever I use up a blade, I, uh- Actually, if I- I have one of those, too.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna do this because I think it would be dangerous.
Speaker 0: Uh, it's pretty big, but if I open it, I could theoretically count how many blades are in that fucking thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can guarantee you it's not a thousand.
Speaker 0: I can guarantee I would cut myself.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: It is not- An actual pile of razor blades.
Speaker 0: A literal pile of actual used razor blades.
Speaker 1: Name that Pokemon.
Speaker 1: A pile of razor blades.
Speaker 0: I don't think I can fit many more blades in that thing, either, so I bought a new one of those, too.
Speaker 1: Mine's getting close to, you know.
Speaker 0: It is, like, I had to shove the most recent blade in, and it barely went in.
Speaker 0: If you shake it, it's just, like, a lump.
Speaker 0: So, uh, yeah, I remember way back when we started shaving the right way, we did an episode on it on December 15th, 2005.
Speaker 0: And I don't even know how much money I've saved over the years by not using, like, cartridge razors since we made that call.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, in the news, uh, I don't know, the planet is burning.
Speaker 0: I don't know how much more urgency people who know this is happening can express upon the world, but climate change is rapidly reaching tipping points of extreme consequences, even in industrialized, previously falsely safe places, like London.
Speaker 0: This heatwave is one of the worst heatwaves in modern history in some places, and it's only getting worse.
Speaker 0: I think I saw there were so many fires in London caused just by the high heat, because it's literally never been this hot before, that the city is low-key shutting down, like, trains aren't running, data centers are failing, it's kind of ridiculous.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, the thing still stands.
Speaker 1: It's like, okay, people now can no longer deny that climate action must be taken, right?
Speaker 1: But nobody, even leftist people who want to, you know, like, do environmental stuff, right?
Speaker 1: People are still not willing, and the only way you're going to escape is if massive numbers of people actually drastically change their overall lifestyle.
Speaker 0: Which requires state action.
Speaker 1: If you live, right, you're going to have to change things about the life you live, right?
Speaker 1: You're going to have to maybe live somewhere else, not use cars, not, you know, live without air conditioning.
Speaker 1: You're going to have to do all these things.
Speaker 0: Well, actually, the opposite is going to happen.
Speaker 0: Air conditioning will literally be necessary to live in a large percentage of the habitable parts of the earth.
Speaker 1: People might have to, you know, move out of parts of the world that are not habitable.
Speaker 0: There aren't places.
Speaker 0: The air conditioning is already necessary for life in many areas that are not able to be depopulated.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, no one lives in the Sahara.
Speaker 1: I mean, very few people live in the Sahara desert.
Speaker 0: But even worse, this could actually be rapidly mitigated, mostly by regulating industries.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: That's part of the drastic change in life is that we're going to have to shut down certain industries and be like, "Sorry, this entire industry is ruining the
Speaker 1: world.".
Speaker 1: And, you know, the net benefits are not positive considering the damage you're doing.
Speaker 1: And therefore, everyone's going to have to do without whatever that industry produces and find another way to live.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: You know, that's the solution.
Speaker 1: At least because we've waited so long, that's the solution, right?
Speaker 1: But even then... Nobody's going to do that.
Speaker 1: It's not going to happen.
Speaker 1: People won't change their lifestyles.
Speaker 0: The US government, which has some of the most control over this of any nation on earth, in effect, also failed to take even basic action because, once again, in our Senate, one jackass voted against it and filibustered the whole thing.
Speaker 1: Even if the US was run by me and I banned cars, how much would that delay the global climate change?
Speaker 1: Even if I had done it 10 years ago, 15 years ago, it's like all the other countries are still doing what they're going to do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but at the same time...
Speaker 1: You would need a Scott to run all the big countries, right?
Speaker 1: China, Russia, Europe, European Union, India...
Speaker 0: Well, the problem is, up until now, a lot of the interventions wouldn't have been that drastic and could have been done within the existing political framework.
Speaker 0: And we even have buy-in from a lot of the countries that contribute to this.
Speaker 0: But, of course, for a lot of reasons, humans waited and waited and waited way too long.
Speaker 0: And now we're in this almost worse situation where people have gone from "it's not happening" to "it's happening and there's literally nothing we can ever do, so fuck
Speaker 0: everything.".
Speaker 0: Like, the doomers and the nihilists are replacing the activists.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't know what to do about it because we have no influence over our non-democratic government here in the US.
Speaker 1: I have even less influence over other countries' governments.
Speaker 1: There's no world government.
Speaker 0: I don't know, I feel like it's going to take climate riots and mass displacements?
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, there'll be riots, but even if the riots succeed in, say, overthrowing a government, right?
Speaker 1: And it's like, congrats, you're in charge now, but the problem is unfixable now.
Speaker 0: There's that Kyrgyzets video that shows a lot of statistics that if you just reduce the red meat industry to 10% of what it is today, that would actually get us most of the way toward the targets needed to start reversing this.
Speaker 1: Ban it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, probably should.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm talking about, a real lifestyle change.
Speaker 1: Like, you know, there is no McDonald's or McDonald's doesn't have beef at all, right?
Speaker 1: Or, you know, it's like, you know, significant changes to the way we go about life or what is required.
Speaker 1: Like, things that you will notice and will impact you in a way that will make most people unhappy, right?
Speaker 1: But this is the choice now, right?
Speaker 1: Is it unhappiness A or unhappiness B, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, would you rather never have no cars allowed and no beef ever, right?
Speaker 1: It's just gone.
Speaker 1: It's not a product anymore.
Speaker 1: You can't buy it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: There's no cow farms, ranchers out of business, sorry.
Speaker 1: McDonald's, burger joints, all out of business or open or serve something else, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, big economic devastation for them and/or all those things.
Speaker 1: stay open, but it's 110 degrees out.
Speaker 0: I think what's really interesting to me is how few people, like, actually realized what this was going to look like.
Speaker 0: A lot of people just seem to think it would get hotter.
Speaker 1: Al Gore did with his scary video.
Speaker 0: They seem to not realize that it's not just it gets hotter.
Speaker 0: It's that the climate and weather get radically less stable and predictable.
Speaker 0: Like today, in New York City, a storm that was not in any way predicted suddenly appeared.
Speaker 0: We had 1.5-inch hail.
Speaker 0: That is hail the size of a ping-pong ball.
Speaker 1: I didn't see any of the hail.
Speaker 0: I didn't see that.
Speaker 1: I heard reports of the hail, but I didn't see any out the window.
Speaker 0: That was reported on the news.
Speaker 1: I wonder if we got some pictures of it.
Speaker 1: There was a heavy rain, though.
Speaker 0: There was also 60-mile-an-hour wind gusts, and it rolled through in the span of 20 minutes and it was gone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, you know, New York still seems to have a winter.
Speaker 1: It snowed at least a little bit, right?
Speaker 1: There was some snowing going on at least once.
Speaker 0: Well, in fact, we've had more extreme winters, too.
Speaker 0: There was more snowfall at some of the ski mountains than there is historically.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, but it's not the winter's short.
Speaker 1: It's not as, you know, I haven't seen one of the mega winters in a while.
Speaker 0: What I have seen is our summer is getting split.
Speaker 1: Not in, like, a decade or so.
Speaker 0: What we really don't have anymore in New York City is the spring.
Speaker 0: We sort of have, like, spring turns into, like, the rainy summer.
Speaker 0: Like, we have, like, a monsoon summer and then a dry summer.
Speaker 0: Like, we have different, like, eras of summer now.
Speaker 1: Regardless, right, the summer that we have now is a lot like Tropical Island or Florida.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Which I'm not complaining about because I like that, but it's bad.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm complaining about it in one sense.
Speaker 0: I mean, I enjoy the heat, but also because I cannot change that temperature, I can still enjoy that temperature while I'm in it before it eventually kills me.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, that's heartening.
Speaker 0: In exactly opposite sentiment news, there is this story, and you've got to read all the details.
Speaker 0: I'll link to the Times of India, but there's an NPR article, there's a Twitter thread, there's even a video about it.
Speaker 0: But best I can tell, there was a group of people in a village in India who basically put on their own online fake stream of the Indian Premier League, which is one of those cricket leagues.
Speaker 0: They ran this, like, not even at the same time as the real one, and they ran an illegal betting operation via Telegram where people overseas could illegally bet on IPL.
Speaker 0: But the double twist was the people were illegally betting on an illegal fake IPL.
Speaker 0: So not only were they betting illegally, but they were not betting on the actual sport.
Speaker 0: They were betting on a bunch of villagers making a fake live stream and rigging what was happening in the game while they were taking votes in real time.
Speaker 1: So imagine if I went to the public park where there's a baseball field, and I got 18 friends together, and we all dressed up as the Mets and the Yankees.
Speaker 1: We went and bought jerseys and uniforms and equipment and everything.
Speaker 0: And we got a camera with a close-in angle, so you see the players, but you don't see anything else.
Speaker 1: Right, we got a bunch of cameras, and we had a broadcaster doing broadcasting, and we had some graphics.
Speaker 1: And we pretended, so that if you looked at the camera, and you never see the stands, because there are no stands, and you just only see the field, and we zoom in to people's faces a lot, and it's like if the people watching didn't actually know anything about baseball, other than that there is a baseball, there is a Mets and a Yankees, right?
Speaker 1: It could be convincing, especially with I'm capable of 4K live streaming.
Speaker 1: We could convince somebody who doesn't know anything about baseball that they are watching a real Mets-Yankees game.
Speaker 1: It's possible to do that with technology that's available off the shelf.
Speaker 1: So if the other people don't know better, and the other people are gamblers, yes, it is entirely feasible.
Speaker 1: You could convince them to bet on a game, but that game is just you and your friends pretending to reenact.
Speaker 1: Basically, they're betting on a reenactment, right?
Speaker 1: And then we can enact whatever we like in order to make them lose their bets and take their money.
Speaker 0: So this is all just amazing, and of course this is only in the news because apparently they got caught, but my hat is off to that amazing con.
Speaker 0: That is very much the kind of thing I want to do in Blades in the Dark in our next section.
Speaker 0: Rig the Ghost Races.
Speaker 1: You know, I wonder, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, there's plenty of people doing war reenactments, medieval historical reenactments.
Speaker 0: Ooh, like reenact the 1947 World Series or something?
Speaker 1: Right, it's like, are there sports reenactors?
Speaker 1: There must be, right?
Speaker 1: I've never seen one, but there must be sports reenactors out there somewhere.
Speaker 0: Like, play the game semi for real, but make sure the box score matches the historical box score and any notable incidents still happen.
Speaker 1: I think, you know, yes and no, right?
Speaker 1: But I think part of the problem is that, you know, a sports reenactment at some point requires feats of strength, right?
Speaker 1: That the reenactors may not be capable of.
Speaker 0: There probably aren't enough, like, to be a Civil War reenactor, you need to have a costume and be able to walk forward slowly.
Speaker 1: Let's reenact the first time a figure skater did a triple axel at the Olympics.
Speaker 1: Okay, who here can do a triple axel?
Speaker 1: Anybody?
Speaker 1: It's like, nobody.
Speaker 0: How many Harlem Globetrotters can you find for a sport to be able to, like, miss a critical bad-bad?
Speaker 0: Like, get struck out at a critical moment with a special kind of curveball?
Speaker 0: that was, like, part of the story of that year?
Speaker 0: Like, you're not gonna pull that off.
Speaker 1: Let's reenact the time that Shaq dunked over.
Speaker 1: It's like, any Shaqs?
Speaker 1: We got any Shaqs to spare?
Speaker 0: Board game reenactment.
Speaker 0: Let's play T&E, but we'll play it so that Scott wins because it was the famous game that Scott won in Odd 8.
Speaker 1: Let's just reenact that game over and over.
Speaker 1: We need to play a real T&E.
Speaker 1: Let's just reenact that one.
Speaker 1: We can't beat that one.
Speaker 1: We'll never play a better game of T&E than that.
Speaker 1: Let's just do that one again.
Speaker 1: E-Sports reenactment.
Speaker 0: You know, it's interesting because with E-Sports, people just watch the replays, and I remember a friend of ours- Same thing with regular sports.
Speaker 1: You can watch replays.
Speaker 0: Well, I remember a friend of ours years ago got a DVD box set that was basically an entire season of their particular baseball team, and they were just watching that season, like, from beginning to end over the course of a month.
Speaker 0: Which, I guess, if I was way deeper into hockey, I could see rewatching a particularly good Stanley Cup playoff series.
Speaker 0: So, I don't think we need reenactments since we record sports directly in a way that we've never recorded before.
Speaker 1: I think you would be reenacting sports that happened prior to recording.
Speaker 0: True.
Speaker 0: Of course, at that point, is it reenactment, or do you just make a movie?
Speaker 0: Like, hire actors and just film it like a movie?
Speaker 1: No, that's what reenactment is.
Speaker 1: Civil War reenactors don't have video of the battle.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: No, but I'm saying, the way you would do a sports reenactment is do it like you would make a- like, if you're doing a- reenacting a baseball game, you do a baseball movie, and you just make it the way Hollywood would make a movie about baseball.
Speaker 0: They don't have that many professional baseballers playing a full game, they just fake it all.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: The other
Speaker 0: way I see most people reenacting that we can get into the rest of the show is they'll take more modern sports games and set up the players the right way and just let it play the old game and see how closely it matches up to the real game.
Speaker 0: And that's actually really popular.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day!
Speaker 0: So, I don't really mountain bike anymore.
Speaker 0: COVID wasn't the only thing that got in my way.
Speaker 0: Being 40 got in my way too.
Speaker 0: But I do still really like mountain biking.
Speaker 0: And there's a race that looks so fun.
Speaker 0: I, on one hand, I would like to be in this race at least once.
Speaker 0: This is moderately within my abilities.
Speaker 0: But on the other hand, the time frame I have left where something even close to this is even remotely safe, considering that I'm already 40, is narrowing rapidly to the point that there is no chance I will ever do this.
Speaker 0: But it is called the Mega Avalanche.
Speaker 0: And it is an all-start race, or a mass start race, meaning like a thousand people all start from a starting line simultaneously.
Speaker 1: That's dangerous.
Speaker 0: It takes like 40 minutes to get to the bottom.
Speaker 0: It is a race in the Alps at a ski resort on mountain bikes.
Speaker 0: You start at the top in snow and then by the bottom you're in dirt.
Speaker 0: And this video, my thing of the day, is someone winning this thing with full commentary, start to finish, 43 minutes 37 seconds.
Speaker 0: This is amazing to watch.
Speaker 0: It's just really chill and fun.
Speaker 1: After you get away from the thousand people.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, absolutely.
Speaker 0: And it looks like the first bit of the race requires a lot of stamina and like, it's difficult not in a mountain biking way, but more in just a, can you run up this hill with your bike?
Speaker 0: Can you actually bike on snow?
Speaker 0: And that seems to spread everyone out real, real far before they hit the single track parts.
Speaker 0: This just looks so- How do you even know which way to go?
Speaker 1: Is it like, can't you just go, the goal is to just get to the bottom.
Speaker 1: however you can get down there?
Speaker 0: It looks like there's markers.
Speaker 0: I think people practice the run, like they know the route, there's other people, like I don't know all the details.
Speaker 1: There must be a way to get to the top without, you know, walking because 40 minutes downhill is- Well yeah, you realize the way- Is there a cable car or something?
Speaker 0: So when I would mountain bike, what you do is, it's ski resorts and you just bring your mountain bike on the ski lift.
Speaker 0: They usually have special things you can attach your bikes to.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: And still a really tall ski lift.
Speaker 1: There gotta be a cable car instead.
Speaker 0: I mean, well this one would probably be a gondola, but even small mountains often have little gondolas, so.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I would love to do this, especially because the course, but for the aspect of racing, and but for the aspect of there's a thousand other people like doing it.
Speaker 0: The course itself, this is not like that dangerous if you don't do anything stupid and don't try to go crazy fast and win the race.
Speaker 0: Just biking down this on a modern mountain bike for fun would actually be pretty safe.
Speaker 0: And I can't actually find references of anyone ever dying in this race.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean if you go, if you're not trying to go fast and there's not a lot of people that might run into you or that you'll run into.
Speaker 1: And you have a very modern bike, you know, that has like lots of- Not a single, you definitely don't want a hardtail.
Speaker 0: You don't want to do this on a full suspension bike.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like and you know, it's like yeah, you could you could just sort of go- But long segments of it are- And you got decent, you know, quality brakes.
Speaker 1: It's like you'll make it to the bottom.
Speaker 0: Yep, long segments of this are like- Gas might hurt.
Speaker 0: Are very much the easy, like I would consider them, I would actually say they're an easy mountain biking trail.
Speaker 0: They're only hard because these people are trying to do them as fast as possible.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So what do you got?
Speaker 1: Uh, what did I have?
Speaker 0: How have you forgotten?
Speaker 1: All right, I remember now.
Speaker 1: So Wikipedia is a website that we use every damn day for all kinds of shit, right?
Speaker 1: You know, it needs no explanation.
Speaker 1: And it's also well known that there are a lot of people who try to vandalize Wikipedia, right?
Speaker 1: Some of them are just vandals, you know, the same reason people vandalize everything.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But you know, because Wikipedia is treated by many people as like a, you know, a trusted source of information, if you can successfully put false information on Wikipedia, then you can convince a lot of people that something is true if they don't bother to check the sources or anything, right?
Speaker 1: And you can make fake sources and, right?
Speaker 1: So there are, and there are a lot of people out there who have very, you know, there's how many billions of people?
Speaker 1: There's people out there who have really specific agendas for something.
Speaker 1: And for whatever reason, those, some of those people attempt to vandalize Wikipedia in a specific way, especially on the non-English Wikipedias, which have a lot smaller communities maintaining and defending them.
Speaker 1: So, on Wikipedia, there is a page called Long Term Abuse, and it is a record of basically all the people who are not just Wikipedia vandals.
Speaker 1: That would be a list, you know, ridiculously long.
Speaker 1: These are people who are, they stick with it, right?
Speaker 1: They keep on trying to vandalize Wikipedia in a specific way for a specific reason.
Speaker 1: And they keep doing it like they have not given up.
Speaker 1: They keep evading bans, getting new IP addresses, like they are tryharding.
Speaker 1: They're trying so hard that Wikipedia gave these people their own page.
Speaker 1: And some of the stories of these people are so specific and hilarious, right?
Speaker 1: You know, right at the top, there's what the Bambi one, right?
Speaker 1: Bambi Fan 101 focuses on Disney articles, claims to be a young boy in the Southern US with a professed love of juvenile-themed movies.
Speaker 1: So there's someone out there who is like, they just want to vent, they want to control the Disney message on Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: Billy North adds fictitious individual Clutch Con to associated acts or former member fields of infoboxes for alternative rock and blues artists.
Speaker 0: He just goes to small-time bands and adds this fake name to them, and that's it.
Speaker 1: But it's not just that they do that, that's funny, but they keep doing it.
Speaker 1: They get banned, they go to try to get new IP addresses and new accounts and do whatever to keep doing it.
Speaker 1: They've not given up.
Speaker 1: Any chance they get, they go to a hotel, they got Wi-Fi at a hotel, they got a different IP address, they make a sock puppet, and they get to it.
Speaker 1: They're like, "All right, it's Clutch Con time, let's
Speaker 1: go."
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: They get banned, they go to their friend's house, they go at it again, and they've been doing this over a long period.
Speaker 1: It's like,
Speaker 1: "Really?"
Speaker 1: They just don't give up.
Speaker 1: And that's what makes it notable.
Speaker 0: It's interesting that this would be someone's hobby.
Speaker 0: It's funny because I expected, scrolling down this list when you first called my attention to this page, it would mostly be people who have a very specific political agenda, like they're doing it for some purpose, but a lot of these just seem completely nonsensical.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like, "Motorsports and Japan LTA," right?
Speaker 1: Pro-Japanese, anti-Korean edits, that's not surprising.
Speaker 1: A lot of the edits are people with nationalist or racist ideas or whatever, trying to promote one side over the other.
Speaker 1: But, they only do it in the topic area of motorsports.
Speaker 1: They're also guilty of edit warring and disparaging others' knowledge of the English language.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Yep, it is actually kind of amazing that Wikipedia is as relatively stable and reliable as it is.
Speaker 0: I long ago stopped interacting with the editor community, I just don't have time for that anymore.
Speaker 0: It has come a long way, but now the body of documentation on how Wikipedia gets managed by the people who dedicate themselves to doing this has far outstripped the time I have left in my life to read words, to read it all.
Speaker 0: In the meta moment, the Geek Nights Book Club book is Binti.
Speaker 0: It's a really, really short book.
Speaker 1: We're gonna read it.
Speaker 1: Someone told me that it was very, very short, and I'm like, "Well, Brim, did you know that when you selected
Speaker 1: it?".
Speaker 0: I did, because it's part of a trilogy, and I'm gonna read all three.
Speaker 1: Is all three the book club selection?
Speaker 0: No, we'll just read the first one.
Speaker 0: I think we'll have enough to say about it.
Speaker 1: You just want a really short book club book?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think it'll be a good palate cleanser, a little bit of an appetizer.
Speaker 0: Also, it won a bunch of awards.
Speaker 0: The Hugo at the Nebula for Best Novella.
Speaker 1: But I'm just saying, when something's real short, it's sort of like, "Alright, is it even a
Speaker 1: novel?".
Speaker 1: I feel like to be a book club book, it should be a novel, not a novella.
Speaker 0: Oh, so you're saying, "Alright, so for the next book club book, I will pick something that is definitely a long
Speaker 0: novel.".
Speaker 1: It doesn't have to be a long novel, it just has to be a novel.
Speaker 0: It could be around counts, and an island, like Monte Cristo or something.
Speaker 1: Novels have a very wide range.
Speaker 0: Should I pick another epic?
Speaker 1: I think that we do have a word for novella, and a word for novel, right?
Speaker 1: We should maybe have a word for big novel that we can use to separate those out of the... right?
Speaker 0: But this thing is about space college, which is a topic that is near and dear to geek nights.
Speaker 0: We love the shit out of a They Were Eleven style, there's some fancy university in space, galactic whatever.
Speaker 0: So, I figured we should read this, and if you do still think this was too short, and you have complaints about that, I will restore the median length of books in my next book club pick, is all I'm saying.
Speaker 1: I think that Genji already restored the median length.
Speaker 0: In some other news, I will be live on Sunday at PAX West 2022, without Scott, with a... I'm rewriting a talk I gave a long time ago by myself at PAX Australia.
Speaker 0: I have a lot more to say, and I got a whole different thing.
Speaker 0: The panel on Sunday, September 4th, 1230pm, in the Sasquatch Theatre, will be losing.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Gotta talk about losing.
Speaker 1: The website is moving along, you know, on the one hand, my new job is only four days a week.
Speaker 1: Like, it's Thursday, I'm not working tomorrow.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: That's just how it is, you know.
Speaker 1: I'm going to the beach, but, yeah, I'm going to the beach, so can't really work on the website at the beach, so...
Speaker 0: I mean, beach is a fair excuse for not doing pretty much anything, so...
Speaker 1: You know, also the other thing is when you work four days a week, right, it's like I actually have work to do.
Speaker 1: It's a new job, first of all.
Speaker 1: You'd hope they wouldn't hire me with nothing for me to do.
Speaker 1: But, yeah, I'm actually filling all the work hours with work, you know, moving right along with that, you know.
Speaker 1: It's like, I guess, you know, usually I don't care too much about keeping or impressing my employer or anything, but I don't want to lose the four day a week job or have them believe that, ah, he's not very productive with the four days, he's got to go do five days, you want more, you need 20% more work.
Speaker 0: Plus, I will definitely say that any time I've started a new job, like when I got my first project, the novelty alone actually gets me to work way harder.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: I
Speaker 0: mean, at least my job, every job I've taken has had radical shifts in the amount of novelty or the type of work that I do to the point that at least the first month is always like a really exciting rollercoaster, and then I get bored and jaded like I always do.
Speaker 1: Regardless, you know, I made a bunch of progress in my time off between the jobs, but, you know, I didn't get over the finish line.
Speaker 1: We'll get there, you know.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty excited about it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it'll happen eventually, you know, who knows, next year, right?
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 1: Who knows?
Speaker 1: Ah, yeah, that's all the real meta that's going on over here.
Speaker 0: Alright, so, we got actually a decent amount of Thursday ideas of weird topics we've never covered somehow or all these years.
Speaker 0: We always have our backup plan of pick a food item, but we're rapidly running out of food items we can talk about.
Speaker 0: But somehow, we have talked about amusement parks, but we haven't talked about other kinds of parks, so we're going to today talk about zoos or zoological gardens or animal parks or menageries.
Speaker 1: Yep, I mean, you know, I think the first thing that comes to most people's minds when you talk about a zoo, right, is the animal welfare aspect.
Speaker 0: There is a wide range of animal welfare statuses of zoos ranging from actually doing for real impressive conservation work with animals all the way down to this place should be shut down and everyone involved in it should be in jail and the animals probably have to be euthanized.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, historically speaking, I feel like, you know, basically all zoos, not even a century ago, right, you know, like 20th century, like there was a time, you know, maybe, you know, even within my life, I've seen some places that should be shut down, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, mid or, you know, mid 20th century, I guess like within our lifetimes is when basically zoos stopped basically being 100% bad.
Speaker 0: Like they were, I mean, olden times, it was like the king's got a bunch of tigers, like in cages.
Speaker 1: They were just, well, that's a menagerie, but that's where zoos came from.
Speaker 1: Historically, people were just taking animals, you know, and putting, and you're putting them in cages for the amusement of people and not treating the animals well, not knowing how to treat the animals well, not really caring as long as the people were amused, right, and entertained by being able to get close to an animal.
Speaker 1: That normally would be, you know, a) it's like even before video, it's like you could never, like, you know, someone talked about a tiger, you saw maybe a photo of a tiger or a drawing of a tiger.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, remember that ancient thing of the day where a lion skin had been sent somewhere in Europe as a gift and the taxidermist was tasked with filling it out to make it look like a real lion again.
Speaker 0: And they had no idea what a lion was supposed to look like and the results were equal parts delightful and terrifying.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And it's like, you know, lions don't live where you live, so it's like you will just never see one.
Speaker 1: if, you know, and then people made zoos for amusement purposes because like, wow, that's a, you know, in the time where it's like, you know, there wasn't TV, movies, video games, internet, it's like seeing a live lion, that ranks pretty high up there in the entertainment level.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Right up there with intentional train crashes.
Speaker 1: It's like that's where the zoo came from, but then people over time, I guess, you know, realized, hey, this isn't great, this is the opposite of great.
Speaker 1: And some portion of the zoos, you know, either shut down, which I guess is good, or B, you know, changed their behavior to being about helping the animals and still having them out for entertainment purposes, but that was just, you know, to get money to help the animals, right, from the spectators.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So we're really only going to talk about like modern zoos that we've interacted with or that people like you would interact with.
Speaker 0: because if you want to know the full history, there is a very long Wikipedia article that I'm skimming through right now as part of Geek Nights, as those of you on the stream could see.
Speaker 1: And we're not going to do aquariums because we need another episode.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, we do.
Speaker 0: Plus, I have different opinions on them and different anecdotes and different thoughts because, you know, as kids get taken to zoos, like that's the thing, and I have a lot of very strong and foundational memories as a child of going to the Detroit Zoo, which...
Speaker 1: I've been to many zoos and zoo-like things.
Speaker 0: We would go to that zoo several times a year because that was just a thing the family would do.
Speaker 0: It was like it was a fun day to hang out at the zoo.
Speaker 0: There's a lot going on at the zoo.
Speaker 0: As kids, on one hand, we were excited to go to the zoo, but on the other hand, we always tried to convince our parents to take us to Cedar Point instead.
Speaker 0: You know, kids.
Speaker 1: Well, there's combos like Busch Gardens.
Speaker 1: It seems like a lot of amusement parks have like some sort of safari thing, you know, combo.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Cedar Point had a...
Speaker 1: Disney's got one, right?
Speaker 0: I don't know if it still does, but it had a giant aquarium inside the park that we used to go to.
Speaker 0: that was just free.
Speaker 0: It was just like part of the park, like you're riding roller coasters.
Speaker 0: There's a gigantic, legit aquarium just there.
Speaker 0: But the zoo was interesting because part of it was seeing the animals, but as a kid, at least, part of it, I was always just very fascinated with like the operations of a zoo.
Speaker 0: Like how do you make a zoo and how does it work and like how do they get into the enclosures and how do they keep the animals from escaping?
Speaker 0: And as a kid, I was always really fascinated by that kind of stuff and I was always trying to like see behind the scenes and like.
Speaker 0: that was just a focus of what I would pay attention to as a kid.
Speaker 0: I also kind of wanted to pet the animals and it's a good thing that adults and fences prevented me from doing so or I would have.
Speaker 0: But as I get older, I didn't really go to zoos a lot because of, you know, they're a mixed bag and not all of them have great animal welfare.
Speaker 0: And I think the first big zoo I went to again, like as an adult, was actually when you and I were in Australia and we went to that zoo in Melbourne and we spent like an entire day there taking photos.
Speaker 1: It was like, you know, it was a few hours.
Speaker 1: I don't know, it was the whole day.
Speaker 0: We spent most of the day there.
Speaker 0: It wasn't open that long.
Speaker 1: It was several hours.
Speaker 0: It was like three.
Speaker 0: It was GTFO time and we had to get out.
Speaker 0: We got shooed out of the gift shop at the end because they were shutting up.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, we went to every part of that zoo that they had.
Speaker 0: But it was a good time.
Speaker 0: That zoo trip was particularly notable for me because one, we went to a zoo that had animals that aren't in a lot of American zoos.
Speaker 0: There was a very different zoo experience.
Speaker 1: And two, I think that if you go to a small zoo, it's going to have just local type animals.
Speaker 1: If you go to a bigger zoo, it'll have some exotic animals from parts far away or animals that are more difficult to take care of or difficult to acquire.
Speaker 1: And then the mega big zoo, like San Diego Zoo, has got like fucking everything from around the world.
Speaker 0: Oh, how about that?
Speaker 0: The Melbourne Zoo is one of the few zoos that has a picture on the front of the Wikipedia article.
Speaker 0: It's one of the bigger zoos.
Speaker 1: That is a thing though.
Speaker 1: If you can go to a smaller zoo in a different place, and now you'll see animals that might be hard to see at the zoo where you live.
Speaker 1: But they just got those animals easy over there.
Speaker 0: It's always like sometimes you see animals that are perfectly happy.
Speaker 0: Like you see a zoo and there's a zebra and the zebra is actually exhibiting happy zebra behaviors and seems pretty happy and at least reasonably comfortable.
Speaker 0: But then you see the bear who's clearly having mental health issues because he's bored and trapped in a shitty zoo.
Speaker 0: And as a kid that definitely colored my opinions of zoos because a lot of zoos I saw were not great as a kid.
Speaker 0: And I guess unlike a lot of other families, my mom was an expert in animal welfare so she would point these behaviors out to us as kids.
Speaker 0: And I think that really, really impacted how I view zoos in my entire life after that.
Speaker 1: Well I think even if you don't know about animal welfare, looking at the animals, I think it's like you can just sort of tell.
Speaker 1: You look at say the enclosure an animal is in and you can tell it's not well kept.
Speaker 1: It doesn't take a genius to be like, "Wow, nobody's cleaning that water.
Speaker 1: those penguins are in.
Speaker 1: Look how dirty it
Speaker 1: is.".
Speaker 0: Or, "I can't read kangaroo body language but that kangaroo looks extremely
Speaker 0: bored.".
Speaker 1: Or, "Why is that monkey banging his head on the
Speaker 1: wall?".
Speaker 0: There's actually a fantastic lecture I saw a while ago that I think about a lot because it has a very quotable moment where it talks about how on one hand we as humans cannot anthropomorphize every animal we interact with because they are very different intelligences.
Speaker 0: They're very different beings.
Speaker 0: Humans often project their own deal onto other things.
Speaker 0: I mean look at how many people get weird about the Roomba that dies and have an emotional attachment to it or something.
Speaker 0: So on one hand it's very easy for a human to drastically misunderstand an animal when they project.
Speaker 0: Case in point, the monkey's smiling at me.
Speaker 0: He must be happy.
Speaker 0: But on the other hand, this lecture made a very good point about how animals are individuals and have a sense of self-identity and we do have lots of direct evidence of this.
Speaker 0: And while we can't anthropomorphize, at the same time, the most powerful starting point we have to understand what an animal's thinking is by anthropomorphizing them to a degree.
Speaker 0: Because since we're an individual and they're an individual, our first best guess as to why they're doing something is the most obvious answer.
Speaker 0: Like all those things that came around Twitter about a year ago where people were like, "Wait, do bears just like hang out and watch the
Speaker 0: sunset?".
Speaker 0: And the answer appears to be that yes, sometimes bears will just like scoop out a little area, like sit down and get company, and just stare out over the mountains and watch the sunset just like a human would.
Speaker 1: It's the most exciting thing they got to see.
Speaker 1: They don't got TV.
Speaker 1: They don't got video games.
Speaker 0: Plus, I'm an evolved monkey with both TV and video games, and sometimes I'll just go sit and stare out over a sunset.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so.
Speaker 1: Alright, so let's review some zoos.
Speaker 0: Alright, honestly, the Melbourne Zoo is the best zoo I've ever been to.
Speaker 1: It's a pretty good zoo.
Speaker 1: It might be the best zoo I've ever been to.
Speaker 1: It was an excellent zoo.
Speaker 0: The exhibits were varied.
Speaker 0: The animals looked very well cared for.
Speaker 0: It was very educational.
Speaker 0: It did not have any of the weird, like, it is surprising how much pseudoscientific racist nonsense is embedded in zoos all over the world.
Speaker 0: Even if it's not intentional in current day, it's because the exhibit was designed in like the 1910s and they haven't updated it, but there wasn't a lot of that there.
Speaker 0: Every person we encountered who was staff, if we asked a question, they knew and gave a, they were just happy that we were talking to them and would overshare.
Speaker 0: It was an overall pretty good experience.
Speaker 1: I've been to a lot of New York zoos, right?
Speaker 1: So in New York City, there's a few zoos, right?
Speaker 1: Mostly the Bronx Zoo is the big one.
Speaker 1: But there's also a Central Park Zoo and a Queens, there's a zoo in Queens and they're all actually owned, they're all run by the same organization, right?
Speaker 1: They're all basically the same zoo, just with multiple locations.
Speaker 1: I don't know if they have more locations than those three.
Speaker 1: They might.
Speaker 1: I'm just not aware of them.
Speaker 1: I haven't been to the Bronx Zoo in many years.
Speaker 1: I could go basically whenever I wanted, but I'm mad at the Bronx Zoo.
Speaker 1: So when I was real young, we went to the Bronx Zoo.
Speaker 0: Ooh, a crunch!
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: When I was young and I went to the Bronx Zoo, I bought this snow globe there and then it was a big deal later in life because that turned out to be like a rare snow globe among the snow globe peoples.
Speaker 1: So I have a memory of that.
Speaker 1: But then I went to the Bronx Zoo again and a little bit later.
Speaker 1: It's good.
Speaker 1: The Bronx Zoo, at least when I went to it the second time and I was older and I have a better memory of it and they were no longer selling the snow globe.
Speaker 1: It has all kinds of different sections for all the different kinds of animals.
Speaker 1: Unlike the Melbourne one, it was sort of a circle shape like you walk around to get everything.
Speaker 0: More importantly, you would naturally get to each exhibit.
Speaker 0: It suddenly guided you on the best path.
Speaker 1: It was like a Stu Leonard's basically where you go in a circle from beginning to end.
Speaker 1: The Bronx Zoo, from what I remember of it, is that it's more of a go wherever you want kind of deal.
Speaker 1: Like an amusement park.
Speaker 1: Like go here, go there.
Speaker 1: It has some really notable parts of it.
Speaker 1: Like the monkey house.
Speaker 1: The fact that they have the guts to call it the monkey house.
Speaker 1: I think they might have changed the name of it.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: The monkey mezzan.
Speaker 1: I don't know what they call it now.
Speaker 1: But it has some good animals there.
Speaker 1: But my favorite part of the Bronx Zoo, which is also my mother's favorite part, was the aptly named House of Darkness.
Speaker 1: They literally had a house of darkness.
Speaker 0: Which is something I was...
Speaker 1: I'm wrong.
Speaker 1: It was called World of Darkness.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it was basically off onto the side of the zoo.
Speaker 1: It was in the zoo, but not in the main path.
Speaker 1: It was this building with no windows and one double-doored entrance.
Speaker 1: And inside, it was dark.
Speaker 1: And in there were all nocturnal animals.
Speaker 1: And I presume that when the animals went to sleep, which they basically had these animals reversed.
Speaker 1: They would be night in the building during zoo hours.
Speaker 1: And then when the people left, I think, I'm not 100% sure, I just assumed this, that they would turn on the lights and the animals would sleep.
Speaker 0: Seeing little fruit bats eating watermelon in places like that is just an absolute treasure.
Speaker 1: So they had all kinds of snakes and reptiles and even underwater.
Speaker 1: They had smaller aquarium tanks.
Speaker 1: I think I might have seen an electric eel in there.
Speaker 1: Things that lived in the deep sea where it's dark.
Speaker 1: Any animal that lives where it's dark was in the World of Darkness.
Speaker 1: And then in between, granted it was a long period of time, but in between when I went to the Bronx Zoo last, which might have been high school, last millennium.
Speaker 1: And now, I feel like it was still quite a while ago, maybe a decade ago or more, they closed the World of Darkness.
Speaker 1: They were like, "Nope, we're done with
Speaker 1: that.".
Speaker 1: And I'm like, "What the hell?
Speaker 1: That was the best part of the zoo when you closed it?
Speaker 1: Alright, I don't even know what to
Speaker 1: do.".
Speaker 1: But I haven't been to the Central Park Zoo because, why?
Speaker 1: I don't feel the compulsion to go there.
Speaker 1: But I have been to the Queen Zoo, which is a tiny little zoo out in Corona Park, out near Citi Field and whatnot.
Speaker 1: And it's just a little zoo.
Speaker 1: This one you walk around in a circle, but it won't take you very long at all.
Speaker 1: And they got mostly not very exciting animals, more normal animals.
Speaker 1: They got a farm/petting zoo across the street.
Speaker 1: And that's cow, sheep, pig, that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: But in the zoo area, they've got brown bear.
Speaker 1: And it's like, "Okay, they got an
Speaker 1: eagle.".
Speaker 1: It's like,
Speaker 1: "Alright.".
Speaker 1: They got a big dome aviary thing with birds in there.
Speaker 0: I love the bird parts.
Speaker 0: Especially the bigger the enclosure is, the more free the birds are.
Speaker 1: It's real big.
Speaker 1: It's like a big geodesic kind of enclosure thing.
Speaker 1: But the most exciting, the highlight of that zoo is they got a whole sea lion thing.
Speaker 1: It's like the largest part of the zoo by far.
Speaker 1: And it's like every few hours or so, they feed the sea lion and it's like, well, sea lions or manatees or whatever.
Speaker 1: I don't know which ones they are.
Speaker 1: I think it's sea lions.
Speaker 1: There's even a difference.
Speaker 0: I just have this vague memory as a kid at the Detroit Zoo.
Speaker 0: of all the animals I wanted to see were always asleep and hiding every time we went.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 1: This zoo, they're not hiding.
Speaker 1: And basically, they bring the sea lions out on a schedule.
Speaker 1: If you go to the zoo, it's like you're going to see it at least once, no matter what.
Speaker 1: And it's like.
Speaker 1: the main event at the Queen Zoo is the feeding of the sea lion.
Speaker 1: But the other, the hidden main event, is they got this tiny little enclosure.
Speaker 1: And you might think, "Oh, what animal's in the tiny enclosure?
Speaker 1: That's not
Speaker 1: cool.".
Speaker 1: It's this special kind of deer.
Speaker 1: It's the world's tiniest deer.
Speaker 1: Oh, those little guys!
Speaker 1: It's the world's tiniest deer variety.
Speaker 1: And it's just like this really cute, really tiny deer hanging out in there.
Speaker 1: It's like, you could miss it easily if you don't go and look for it off in the corner.
Speaker 1: But it's like, you don't see that thing pretty often.
Speaker 1: It's like an animal.
Speaker 1: It's like it's one thing to go to a zoo and see an animal that you don't see often.
Speaker 1: In person.
Speaker 1: So you go see penguin.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know a penguin exists.
Speaker 1: You might not see them that often in person unless you live in the south bottom of the world.
Speaker 1: But you know what a penguin is.
Speaker 1: So it still has some excitement, but not incredible excitement.
Speaker 1: But it's like, I bet you didn't even know that tiny deer existed.
Speaker 1: And there it is, live, walking around.
Speaker 1: You never even heard of this thing.
Speaker 1: It's like, I think that's what I like the most about a zoo, is when you see an animal you didn't even know was an animal, it's almost like meeting an alien kind of deal.
Speaker 0: Especially if it's a zoo that's well designed to where you can sort of observe them doing mostly natural behaviors, like they don't even know you're there, is the best.
Speaker 0: When we were in Japan, the last time Emily and I were in Japan we went to the zoo, and I just remember for a while I was looking down at this monkey enclosure and there was a little monkey.
Speaker 0: And really working on trying to make something with a stick.
Speaker 0: There was definitely some attempt at crafting happening down there.
Speaker 0: And it was just fascinating to watch.
Speaker 0: But that zoo also had the traditional petting zoo of.
Speaker 0: here is a pile of guinea pigs that kids are allowed to manhandle.
Speaker 0: that frankly just has to be banned.
Speaker 0: It's just kids hurting little guys.
Speaker 0: Like a lot of petting zoos, at least most American petting zoos get it right in that it's animals that kids are unlikely to be able to hurt in any way, but I'm not a fan of the let kids manhandle guinea pigs thing.
Speaker 1: So where I grew up there was a farm, was it kind of a zoo?
Speaker 1: I think it's still there, it's called Silverman's Farm.
Speaker 0: We had something similar, you're going as a kid, feed some goats, and feed a horse.
Speaker 1: You get your pumpkins, you get your apple cider there.
Speaker 1: But they had farm animals there, goats, sheep, goose.
Speaker 1: When I was a kid they had a peacock, just one, I don't know if it's still there.
Speaker 1: Farm animals, these are animals that are being taken care of as a livestock farm setting.
Speaker 1: A bunch of chickens and a coop.
Speaker 1: And there's a wire fence, so you can't really get at the animals, but they would let you put a quarter in a little vending machine, but instead of gumballs food came out and you would hold your hand up to the fence and the animals would all lick the food out of your hand.
Speaker 1: So you couldn't really mess with the animals so much, and I guess that was okay.
Speaker 1: But there was another place, the Caskill Game Farm, which has a long and storied history.
Speaker 1: I won't get into, but we went there when I was a kid and that was basically, it's called Caskill Game Farm, but it was like a petting zoo, not too many exotic animals, mostly the same kind of farm animals, but basically they're just all over, you could just mess with them.
Speaker 0: We actually had a pleasant surprise, because the last time I was in Australia with Emily, we were hiking in the Blue Mountains and then it rained on the last day so we couldn't do the last hike safely, so we just headed back to the city early, and on the way we see this giant animal exhibit place, and we figure we'll go see.
Speaker 0: what's the deal with this place, is this going to be one of those bad places, what's the deal?
Speaker 0: And we roll in, and it was actually surprisingly better for the animals than we expected, and ended up being a pretty good experience.
Speaker 0: We go in and it's mostly the equivalent of what you just described, but for Australia, so it's a lot of wallabies and quokkas and dingos and animals that are just common in Australia.
Speaker 1: Well I mean we did go to that other place in Australia to see the koalas, and that wasn't really a zoo.
Speaker 0: It was a preserve.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was like a preserve, and it's like they just happen to have a walkway.
Speaker 1: It's like this is where koalas live, we'll make a walkway so that you can walk around and see them sleeping 90% of the day.
Speaker 0: I like places like that a lot, because that's where a zoo is serving more of its conservation mission, while also teaching people about the animals and letting them see them, but without messing with the animals.
Speaker 1: Right, well rather than taking animals and bringing them far away to some other place that they don't belong, and putting them in a box of some kind, it's like you just go to where the animal is, it's like, you know.
Speaker 0: That's also where I learned that you can keep koalas from in or out into, or trap them in or keep them out of a place with a wall that's about a foot tall.
Speaker 1: Like people, I know, pretty much everyone who ever goes to Costa Rica goes to see the sloths, right?
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like, you're going to where the sloth is.
Speaker 1: It's like, I've seen sloths in zoos here, but it's like, you still meet the sloth where he lives.
Speaker 0: Well, to see all the flying foxes in Australia, I didn't even go anywhere in particular, I just went to Centennial Park, there's one tree that a whole colony of them lives in, and just walk over there and you just get right up to them.
Speaker 0: They're just right there, everyone knows, no one messes with them, it's not even official, it's just that's where they live, and it's super cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Castle Game Farm has been closed for quite a while, I think it was for sale, it might still be for sale, someone tried to renovate it into a hotel unsuccessfully.
Speaker 1: And I think lost a lot of money on it last I heard, and that's why they're trying to sell it.
Speaker 1: But I don't think they're going to be able to recoup their investment, they're going to have to just realize they made a bad investment.
Speaker 1: But yeah, it's a good thing that place shut down, because it was not a great place for the animals.
Speaker 0: But that place we went to in Australia, in the end, the thing I thought was nice about it is the kangaroos and wallabies and a lot of the animals just wandering around, and you can just interact with them.
Speaker 0: And they had hay dispensers, basically hay in an ice cream cone without the ice cream, so you could just feed them if they wanted it.
Speaker 0: But all the animals that were able to be interacted with with humans, there were little ropes, and they had all these signs everywhere that basically said if an animal goes behind these ropes, you can't fuck with them, leave them alone.
Speaker 0: So an animal that was done with your shit had a very easy way to get away from you and avoid human entanglement if they didn't want to deal with it.
Speaker 0: And it seemed like that system for those kinds of animals actually worked pretty well.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if the animal is an animal that learns that that's a place where there's no people, the animal will learn that.
Speaker 1: A dog can learn that super easily.
Speaker 1: A lot of other animals can learn that as well.
Speaker 1: And that's actually probably not a bad system to set up for a pet if you have one either.
Speaker 1: I think the only problem might be, let's say you have a dog, if it's sick it might hide in there.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, well we do that.
Speaker 0: Mookie has a tunnel that he sleeps in, but dogs, often you have a crate, because you need to be able to get a dog in a crate if you have to take him to the vet or something.
Speaker 0: So the crate is like the safe space.
Speaker 0: The contract is, listen dog, I will only fuck with you in the crate if it's an emergency.
Speaker 0: So you are safe in there unless you're going to the vet.
Speaker 1: So that's the thing animals learn, that's sort of natural, you don't even really need to train them.
Speaker 0: I remember the first year, it was the 4th of July.
Speaker 1: You just set up a place, put them in it, and then don't go in there.
Speaker 0: When we got Miles as a puppy, the first year there were fireworks that he was around for.
Speaker 0: The first firework went off, and he was in that crate and even pulled the door shut and hid in there until they stopped.
Speaker 1: Yep, that's how it's going to be.
Speaker 0: But I think zoos and things like them are pretty important, because a lot of humans, especially in places like the US, don't seem to ever really interact with animals.
Speaker 0: A lot of people don't even have pets, don't know people who have pets, and just, I think there's a certain amount of human empathy that can only really be learned by interacting with animals.
Speaker 0: If nothing else, to instill the sense of awe, like, you know a tiger exists, but imagine you'd never seen a tiger in person.
Speaker 0: And you don't give a shit about animals, and then you go to a zoo one day, and you actually see how big a tiger actually is in real life, up close.
Speaker 0: And if you somehow have never seen a tiger, you see it move.
Speaker 0: They're so much bigger than you realize, and you see them move their paw or their foot even a little bit, and you see those gigantic muscles, you see them roar or fight or do something.
Speaker 0: I think that sense of awe and wonder is important to get humans to care even the tiniest bit about the natural world.
Speaker 1: It's like you wonder what it would be like to see a dinosaur, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, seeing an elephant ain't too much different.
Speaker 1: It's a big animal.
Speaker 0: It's a big animal that isn't around anymore.
Speaker 1: On
Speaker 0: one hand, this is likely worse for the animals than just being wild, but on the other hand, making sure some percentage of humans care at all about animals is probably more important to the welfare of the rest of the animals long-term than the discomfort of the small number of animals that are almost sacrificed to the zoo.
Speaker 0: Of course, zoos need to have strong regulations to where that sacrifice has to be minimized as much as possible.
Speaker 1: Well, I think if zoos hadn't existed historically for bad reasons, that they wouldn't have come into existence later.
Speaker 0: I think they would've in a different form, but I think they are going to be a major part of how we convince humans to care at all about climate change.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Well, I do think that's.
Speaker 1: the thing is that, you know...
Speaker 0: Better help them adapt to climate change?
Speaker 1: You don't need to let people go to those, the publican, right?
Speaker 1: That's the real thing.
Speaker 1: Or, you let people in.
Speaker 1: You can do a lot of the functions that zoos serve, right?
Speaker 1: Like all the zoos that get the pandas to mate so that there are still pandas, even though pandas don't seem to want there to be pandas anymore.
Speaker 0: I've read a fascinating thing that...
Speaker 1: You don't need to let the public just have access to it, even for a price.
Speaker 1: That could just be a private facility that employees go to, and that's it.
Speaker 0: I think some of the best hybrid models are places where their primary mission is that, but their mission is also outreach, and then people can come in to observe those practices.
Speaker 0: And see some representation of the animals, but not necessarily in the open format amusement park style of a lot of zoos.
Speaker 0: There's also the animal ambassadors of like, you find the one wolf who's like weirdly cool with people, and you basically just
Speaker 1: use them,
Speaker 0: like bring them to schools, let people interact with them, like they're the ambassador for their species to the people who need that to be convinced to care.
Speaker 0: Which is a thing, kind of like pets, like there's pros and cons to allowing humans to have pets, but in the end, people who have pets demonstrably are more likely to demonstrate empathy in their adult lives than people who don't.
Speaker 0: There's lots of quality of life and like human learning aspects, so it's a very nuanced topic that we are not experts enough to talk about too much further.
Speaker 0: So zoos are a mixed bag, and I think will continue to be a mixed bag, but I think their importance is actually only going to grow as their mission changes due to climate change.
Speaker 1: So there also might be animals that, you know, it's like right now, there's some animals, right, where it's like, you know, maybe they grew up in captivity or something and they can't survive in the wild for whatever reason, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like, rather than let the animal go extinct, right, it's like a zoo is where it can actually live, sadly, that's the only choice, right?
Speaker 1: But I think with climate change and also other reasons, habitat destruction, burning rainforests, et cetera, et cetera.
Speaker 0: Well, there's a balance.
Speaker 0: Some species we can help to repopulate or help survive, other species just will not be able to live in the world that we've made.
Speaker 1: Right, we're making it, there are other people who are making a shitty world and, you know, as a side effect, you know, eliminating some animal species, and it's like, well, it's like that animal species is better off in the wild, but some other fucker destroyed the wild, and now there is no wild anymore for that particular animal, so we can, the animal can either live in the zoo or not live because of that other piece of shit that did that.
Speaker 0: Well, that lecture that talks about, you know, the whole, like, watching an animal and thinking and just intuitively understand, like, oh, that rabbit's frustrated because he's trying to get under the bed and you've blocked it off, and he's mad at you because he saw you block it off, and he's frustrated and looking for, like, your first best guess at their behavior.
Speaker 0: He had a bit at the end, he mostly talked about how, like, the question is, are humans compassionate enough and also brave enough to actually make a world that we can share with animals, or are we just going to keep destroying everything?
Speaker 1: Hopefully aliens will come and put humans in the zoo.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, we're really speedrunning the lead up to the Bell Riots in Star Trek right now, except I don't think Vulcans are going to show up and cause us to cease warring with each other anytime soon.
Speaker 1: But I'm saying, you know, you think about it this way, right?
Speaker 1: So, you know, on the one hand, it's like all our climate damaging is going to kill humans.
Speaker 1: If somebody came and put us in a zoo, right, it's like the same way the pandas go in the zoo, it's like, oh, thanks aliens for helping, you know, it's like, yeah, we live in a zoo, we don't like it, there's no internet in there.
Speaker 1: But at least there's still humans.
Speaker 1: It's like, if the choice is be extinct on Earth or be in the alien zoo, right, I'm not going to be hypocritical.
Speaker 0: I mean, it might be the shitty alien zoo.
Speaker 1: Right, sure, but I'm not going to be hypocritical and be like, yeah, it's better for the animal to go in the human zoo.
Speaker 0: Of course, at the same time.
Speaker 1: It's also acceptable for the human to go in the alien zoo.
Speaker 0: If aliens found Earth, they might be like, well, bacteria clearly rule this planet.
Speaker 1: The tiny aliens.
Speaker 0: Bacteria have made these giant structures to house them and move them around.
Speaker 1: Yes, the aliens perhaps are bacteria.
Speaker 0: We're studying one of the bacteria skyscrapers and it made a weird noise when we cut it open.
Speaker 0: I wonder what that was all about.
Speaker 1: I mean, it is possible that like we've been visited by aliens that are just five celled organisms or something.
Speaker 1: Who knows what they are.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, zoos, mixed bag.
Speaker 0: I have good memories of going to some, bad memories of going to others.
Speaker 0: I think they serve an important place in the world, but their mission needs to evolve.
Speaker 1: I do enjoy going to a zoo.
Speaker 1: I'll probably go to one again someday.
Speaker 0: You know where I absolutely want to go back specifically?
Speaker 0: I do want to go back to Phillip Island and see all those fairy penguins again.
Speaker 0: That was actually, that was a really fun night.
Speaker 1: I wonder if there's another, I wonder if there's a one of those type of things, just a different animal somewhere else.
Speaker 0: Yes, there absolutely are.
Speaker 1: Right, I'd rather go to one of those than see an animal I saw already.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I want to go out.
Speaker 0: We got a lot of fun looking at the bats at night and seeing all their business when they get active.
Speaker 0: But there are tours in places like Australia to do that for all sorts of animals.
Speaker 1: In fact, Scott, you want to go upstate and camp at the wolf sanctuary?
Speaker 0: We're thinking about going with Red and some other people too.
Speaker 1: I will say this though, I think I said this in 2012 when we did an episode about Pax Australia that we went to.
Speaker 1: But we did the penguin thing, we paid for the deluxe penguin experience.
Speaker 1: Up until that point in my life, I've always paid for standard experience of everything.
Speaker 1: It always felt like a ripoff to pay more to get the deluxe edition.
Speaker 0: Well, the difference between the regular, the premium, and then the special thing we did.
Speaker 0: One, the price wasn't that different.
Speaker 1: And two, the price was that different.
Speaker 1: We just had money finally.
Speaker 0: True, but the difference in what you get was like, they were like completely different things.
Speaker 0: They would be like, "Alright, you can play Counter Strike or for $100 more, we're going to give you airsoft guns and we're going to do it for real in this giant
Speaker 0: warehouse.".
Speaker 1: The point is, I think when it comes to a zoo type situation, especially if it's the good zoo or zoo-like place.
Speaker 0: The non-intrusive, guided, expert access.
Speaker 1: If it's a non-evil, animal caretaking place, I would encourage people who can afford to do so to get whatever the deluxe experience is for two reasons.
Speaker 1: Number one, you'll have a better, fancier experience getting closer to animals, experiences that other people aren't going to have, something memorable, it's worth your money.
Speaker 1: And two, if it's a good place, they need more money to help take care of the animals.
Speaker 1: And that's a way that you can give them more money.
Speaker 0: And it's not like we were messing with the prairie penguins, we were sitting silently with night vision goggles, watching them from the distance.
Speaker 0: Oh, so one last thing the listener pointed out, the pair David Deer, the little guy, survived being wiped out in China because some rich European Duke bred them from a small population from the Berlin Zoo and later reintroduced them into China.
Speaker 1: Is that what the world's smallest deer species is?
Speaker 0: Which deer is which?
Speaker 0: I'm looking up what that pair David- It's a pudu fawn, the world's smallest deer.
Speaker 0: Oh no, a pair David is a gigantic, it's a totally different deer.
Speaker 0: Oh, those are the guys with the really thi- okay, the really thi-.
Speaker 0: I see this guy, look at him.
Speaker 1: It's a pudu fawn, p-u-d-u, it is categorized as vulnerable, but yeah, it is a- it's a really tiny deer, it's like, smaller than most dogs, it's like a foot long, basically.
Speaker 0: Alright, I think it's time to get dinner and then go play some Fortnite.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: I will not say.
Speaker 0: We are back from our hiatus, we will be mostly regularly scheduled for much of the rest of the summer, and for tonight, since I'm about to bounce and play some Fortnite, I simply leave you with... Well then, if you're going to push me... I would choose the right-hand weevil.
Speaker 0: It has significant advantage in both length and breadth.
Speaker 0: There, I have you.
Speaker 0: You're completely dished.
Speaker 1: Do you not know that in the service, one must always choose the lesser of two weevils?