Speaker 1: It's Monday, July 25th, 2022.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight We are talking about software as a service.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So, uh, you know in olden times we would say the inverse of the weather.
Speaker 1: So when it's warm, we'd always say like woman and make this old reference.
Speaker 1: and if it's cold out We'd say warm today and we kind of vacillate but it's fucking warm today I must say having biked back home from work just now.
Speaker 0: Oh It's so nice.
Speaker 1: I'm loving I'm not complaining.
Speaker 1: It is this is a consequence of the earth being destroyed by powers beyond my control.
Speaker 1: But in my local I can't affect it area.
Speaker 1: I am perfectly comfortable in weather between 85 and 95 degrees Fahrenheit and we could even push that a little higher.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean finally, you know, it's like got some beach times.
Speaker 0: Yeah bike times go lay in the park time.
Speaker 1: No, uh, was that we went to Sandy Hookley yesterday and you're just hanging out on Friday.
Speaker 1: That was real good work Friday real good ocean water.
Speaker 0: That was no surprise.
Speaker 0: Why the sharks are loving it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, looks like they open up Rockaway Beach again, which was closed for several days due to shark sightings.
Speaker 1: And even then they were like, yeah, there's no real risk.
Speaker 0: But you know, I'm not sure how long it was actually closed.
Speaker 1: It looks like it was closed for a few days because it was closed on Sunday.
Speaker 1: I checked it was hard to say it was hard to say no and then I got it And I saw it was closed.
Speaker 1: so I signed up for Beach Alerts and then I got an alert at like 4 p.m.
Speaker 1: yesterday.
Speaker 1: that said Rockaways are open again for swimming starting tomorrow
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm,
Speaker 1: but so while we're there over in New Jersey like off like North New Jersey like to the left to Sandy Hook in North like if you're just on that Beach a Giant plume of black smoke just like a rose from the ground like gigantic in the distance.
Speaker 0: Well, there's like a port over there.
Speaker 0: there is so I was like a big.
Speaker 0: there's usually some large military boat over there.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, that thing's always there at some.
Speaker 1: so Every time within I think oh, what's the deal with all that stuff over there?
Speaker 1: and I never look.
Speaker 0: I'm not military nerd enough to know if it belongs to the Coast Guard or the Navy or if it's in Service or if it's a destroyer or a cruiser or something else.
Speaker 1: Oh, I Do.
Speaker 1: I know after I finished my bout of swimming.
Speaker 1: I stagger back to the beach and I just pull up my phone.
Speaker 1: I look on Twitter and I type, you know Be black smoke cloud North Jersey.
Speaker 1: just see like is there something going on?
Speaker 1: And what I find is that about every six months There's a storm of tweets where people are like what the fuck is that giant black smoke cloud from New Jersey like that part in New Jersey?
Speaker 1: and then like days later There's a news story that is like this is the fire that caused this giant cloud of smoke?
Speaker 1: So, uh, I didn't see a lot of tweets for this one So I don't think it's one is nearly as big as the other ones in the past.
Speaker 1: and then I found pictures of all the other Times that happened and they were so much worse that this one was probably a non event.
Speaker 1: I don't think that many people are.
Speaker 0: there's so many fires in this one place because there's a whole.
Speaker 1: it's a confluence of shipping and industry.
Speaker 1: There's just.
Speaker 1: they're all different causes to one time.
Speaker 1: It was a chemical plant one time.
Speaker 1: It was a ship that caught on fire one time.
Speaker 1: It was a truck that crashed on a 95.
Speaker 1: My god, is that a ratio?
Speaker 1: I'm in the mood to watch some Horatio.
Speaker 1: It's about that time.
Speaker 1: But anyway, remember yet on the last geek nights I started the show doing the typical thing of talk about a thing without saying what it was.
Speaker 1: and Before we did the show I said what I was gonna talk about and you had a guess about what I was actually gonna talk about.
Speaker 1: that was wrong But not a bad guess.
Speaker 1: Do you remember what your guess was?
Speaker 0: Water in the ceiling.
Speaker 1: So guess what I came home to today Water in the ceiling but not in our apartment.
Speaker 1: I Come into the lobby by after biking home and there's a giant bucket in the lobby and there is water Streaming out of the ceiling into this bucket.
Speaker 1: looks like they've been constantly replacing this bucket.
Speaker 1: There's no problem in our apartment.
Speaker 1: So for once the water in the ceiling is actually water in the floor.
Speaker 0: I good in your apartment hundred percent.
Speaker 1: There's nothing wrong in our apartment.
Speaker 1: So for once the gods have been kind.
Speaker 1: It's water in the floor instead of water in the ceiling.
Speaker 1: It's not my problem.
Speaker 1: Okay All right, I guess we got a lot of news.
Speaker 1: I guess you would dive right into it unless you have something interesting to share.
Speaker 1: That's as good as what I mean, you know, I had.
Speaker 0: I went to the beach on Friday went to City field on Saturday.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah hung out inside on Sunday.
Speaker 1: I did on Saturday, so I went out run computer.
Speaker 0: just got here two weeks early.
Speaker 1: I was gonna go out running and I thought I'll see how far I get in the heat.
Speaker 1: I made it about six miles at my normal pace and then my body was like listen I let you get this far, but this is gonna be a problem.
Speaker 1: But at the same time I felt pretty good.
Speaker 1: so I actually ran the rest of the half marathon just at a slower speed and I actually gave up a half mile before mile 13 because at that point my body said nope you were done It would be inadvisable to proceed.
Speaker 1: So I just stopped and then I biked home.
Speaker 0: Good idea.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a fun time Sucks hit the bricks.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the thing is Even I you Scott and I both talk a lot about like oh don't collect things on us.
Speaker 1: That's a good reason like avoid completionist mentality.
Speaker 1: Like all these harmful behaviors even I At 12 and a half miles a tiny part of my brain said just go a little bit further You'll hit 13 you'll hit a magic number and thankfully the conscious part of my brain said fuck that.
Speaker 1: And I just stopped immediately right next to a city bike station got on a bike and started slowly back in home.
Speaker 1: But just fuck it.
Speaker 0: I mean I rode in the The New York City Century three times.
Speaker 0: it no longer exists.
Speaker 0: I rode in the final one as well and the second time I did it The weather was just bad and it was.
Speaker 0: it was gross and it sucked.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was.
Speaker 0: it was man.
Speaker 0: He just wasn't good.
Speaker 0: So when I got to Astoria, I was like well to finish the hundred miles.
Speaker 0: I got to go all the way to the Bronx all the way back down like Fuck that Basically after the Astoria.
Speaker 0: rest stop though.
Speaker 0: I went over the bridge to Manhattan I got the free water bottle t-shirt and I went right back over the bridge home Like screw this.
Speaker 1: So there is a bunch of tech news and in one news, uh, a chess playing robot broke a seven-year-old kid's finger.
Speaker 0: I watched the video of this which is blurry and far away, which I guess is for the best.
Speaker 0: Yeah It looked like security camera footage, but basically the robot like, you know moves the piece right and Then the kid goes to move his piece and somehow the robot keeps going and doesn't just stay where it was.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got a lot to say about exactly what happened here But I pointed the article is really funny because the head of the Moscow chess Federation said quote The robot broke.
Speaker 1: the robot broke the child's finger.
Speaker 0: This is of course bad Which thanks, I guess I think the thing is it breaks his finger by it has a piece, right?
Speaker 0: and it's putting the piece down and it presses the piece down towards the table and then releases it and it's like.
Speaker 0: I Feel like there's no reason for it to even do that ever.
Speaker 0: it should hover.
Speaker 0: You know It should get close enough and then let go and the piece can just drop.
Speaker 0: that is really harder because something Drop it from like a centimeter.
Speaker 0: It doesn't have to.
Speaker 1: you know drop me from a centimeter would still be able to injure a person from the pressing to get it to a centimeter.
Speaker 0: But your finger isn't a centimeter.
Speaker 1: your finger is not likely completely pressed flat against the ground.
Speaker 1: Probably his finger was a little higher.
Speaker 1: probably caught it an angle.
Speaker 1: It could cause a serious injury either way.
Speaker 0: I Think you know and plus it would just let go.
Speaker 0: and that then if you're there You're why?
Speaker 1: well, you're just gonna back up one centimeter.
Speaker 0: It would let go of the piece and now it's like it's not hurting you because even then the wobble introduced Introduces a significant amount of uncertainty.
Speaker 1: There is a far more important underlying issue here robots in general all robots are extremely dangerous unless they follow best engineering practices with hardware interlocks and People who make software who often don't interface with hardware like this tend to solve problems thinking like a software engineer and don't incorporate the extreme multi-redundant system Nature of like hardware interlocks that all machines that interact with humans require full stop.
Speaker 1: This is just like absolute egregious Misconduct that this robot saying well allowed humans to be within striking distance of it.
Speaker 0: I Mean really it should have one of those You know basically the equivalent of what an elevator has where your hand is in it and it goes Exactly a hardware interlock people.
Speaker 1: if the beam is broken by anything the robot is not allowed.
Speaker 1: That's a. that board is a no-go zone until the obstruction is cleared plus pressure sensors.
Speaker 1: if it encounters Resistance when placing the piece it has to immediately back up and then issue an emergency stop.
Speaker 1: I could list all the different things because one of my intern jobs when I first worked at IBM was inventorying disaster scenarios for hardware interlocks in the fab.
Speaker 1: So I does a job.
Speaker 1: I sat there and brainstormed on all the ways this one machine could kill someone and then the engineer Can't can't kill you.
Speaker 1: Ah This chest mark could definitely kill a person.
Speaker 0: We're gonna put your head under it.
Speaker 0: What if I make my move and Then I put your art put your neck under it.
Speaker 1: So I coincidentally sneeze and That sneeze coincidentally breaks one of the legs in my chair and I fall forward just as the robot decides to make its move.
Speaker 0: I don't think your head would fit under it cuz it doesn't lift the piece high enough.
Speaker 0: It depends your head onto it.
Speaker 1: Ah, so the other thing people underestimate in this kind of situation.
Speaker 1: Is that reliable?
Speaker 1: servo motors, especially with leverage even if they don't look that strong are Terrifyingly strong and they know I'm not I'm not questioning this.
Speaker 0: Your head wouldn't get under the.
Speaker 1: oh no It wouldn't have to.
Speaker 1: it would coming across Just to get to the vision where it's gonna drop.
Speaker 1: the piece could hit someone's head enough to fracture their skull depending on exactly What kinds of motors they're using?
Speaker 1: I don't know the detail.
Speaker 0: It has to be a very very it's possible but that would have to be extremely unlucky.
Speaker 1: for yes, and That is the nature of machine safety and real engineering and hardware interlocks you it.
Speaker 1: the chance has to not just be very low It has to be either zero if possible or like beyond negligible anyway.
Speaker 1: Anyway, this is just a comedy of errors and the people who let humans be around this robot in my opinion are guilty of extreme Misconduct with technology.
Speaker 0: the thing I don't understand about the whole situation Right is why the fuck is a chess robot necessary only because it's cool.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: That's purely cool.
Speaker 0: Just play digital fucking chess, right unless you're playing against a person, you know with the nice pieces It's like what's wrong with a digital event?
Speaker 0: Just a chess video game.
Speaker 1: pure cool factor, especially if you're trying to get kids invested in chess.
Speaker 1: chess is already not Popular among kids especially because they know that the computers get more popular there.
Speaker 1: It's hard to make chess more popular.
Speaker 0: Yeah, play a different game then.
Speaker 1: Ah, baby Of course computers what we can go anyway, we've talked.
Speaker 1: that's a Tuesday topic.
Speaker 1: moving on Amazon one of the evil mega corpse in our corporate libertarian hellhole one of the drivers of the capitalist excesses destroying the world.
Speaker 1: Amazon is Purchasing one medical.
Speaker 0: This is if you don't know what one medical is.
Speaker 1: I pay for one medical.
Speaker 1: So does Emily I use it heavily.
Speaker 0: Oh, I got.
Speaker 0: I mean I get it for free Like I had it for free at my last work and my current work.
Speaker 0: But I didn't even bother taking the free sign up because I already have a doctor.
Speaker 0: I don't really need a different doctor No, but yeah, if I guess if I didn't already have a doctor, right?
Speaker 0: I probably would have gone with the one medical.
Speaker 1: You know why I signed up for it my last job.
Speaker 1: I was hard.
Speaker 1: I couldn't find any PCP who would take me.
Speaker 1: like no one had openings for anything that my insurance took or that took my Just gone to my doctor.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know if they took my insurance.
Speaker 1: It wasn't great insurance.
Speaker 0: I go to NYU.
Speaker 1: It's like it's an enormous, you know network of Practice insurance that my last job was not great and I'm gonna leave it at that.
Speaker 1: But okay, they gave it.
Speaker 1: then they were after after this insurance after like a month They were like, okay, this is your it sucks.
Speaker 1: So they gave us one medical on top of it because one medical took that insurance and then I can instantly get a doctor.
Speaker 0: So one medical basically is sort of like.
Speaker 0: it's not velvet rope doctor.
Speaker 0: It's like I don't know.
Speaker 0: What is like it is the station at the extension at the airport.
Speaker 1: doctor This is the premium economy Concierge medical service.
Speaker 1: So if you fly on a plane, there's coach which is fuck you Like good luck have fun.
Speaker 1: and then on the other end there's business class like the ten thousand dollar ticket with the Private lounge and the concierge and shall I warm sir's butthole?
Speaker 1: but in between the two this premium economy it costs like 50% more than regular economy and the seats are slightly bigger and you get a slightly nicer area to sit sometimes.
Speaker 0: So one medical it's like you pay I think if you pay for it as well like a hundred bucks a year I'm not a lot.
Speaker 0: It's not a lot.
Speaker 0: You know, even if you're you know hard up a hundred bucks a year.
Speaker 0: That's you know, what?
Speaker 0: It's divided by twelve less than ten bucks a month.
Speaker 1: Especially you don't have great insurance.
Speaker 1: This is not an ad for one medical But I know multiple people who got health care that they likely would not have received Because they had a crappy like bare minimum Obamacare style health care plan plus one medical which took that plan.
Speaker 0: Yep, so one medical basically is just like a doctor that had.
Speaker 0: you know It's a doctor Network right of medical places for regular doctoring.
Speaker 0: It's like they don't have hospitals But you know if they're they have less patients they they pay more attention to you right and they got modern technologies Right and supposedly they're paying more attention to you, you know less waiting for appointment.
Speaker 1: that is absolutely true.
Speaker 1: in my experience.
Speaker 0: I have right more time to spend more time with you right etc.
Speaker 1: I've never had to wait the appointment I don't have to talk to anyone I click on an app or a website to make any appointments any Cancellations all my medical records are in one place like easily accessible like everything just works.
Speaker 0: Yep, so Amazon buys them right?
Speaker 0: So now the question is alright.
Speaker 0: Obviously, that's not great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is terrifying and bad news.
Speaker 0: But the second question is like, okay Well, what is Amazon gonna do?
Speaker 0: because on the one hand all the evil things you can think Amazon is gonna do Yeah involve taking patient data and using it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know in bad privacy that are not just illegal.
Speaker 1: But like the best way I'd put this is there are laws that if you're rich enough in America and you break them There's basically no consequences.
Speaker 1: But there are some laws.
Speaker 1: no matter how rich you are if you fuck up around those laws or regulations The industry term is you are fucked.
Speaker 1: For example, don't piss off the IRS like actually piss them off granted That's kind of hard to do.
Speaker 1: don't violate the GDPR in Europe and don't violate HIPAA in the United States Mmm, so my suspicion this is pure speculation.
Speaker 1: I'd we have no inside info pure just guessing.
Speaker 1: my guess is what Amazon is purchasing is the fact that one medical has a Platform that has basically passed muster on all HIPAA regulations.
Speaker 1: yet Does modern things like apps that just show you all your medical records and like transferring them between a bunch of doctors?
Speaker 1: I've seen four different primary care practitioners in four years for my physicals and Every one of them knew everything like instantly.
Speaker 0: I see the same one every time.
Speaker 1: So I've had bad luck for you for four years in a row.
Speaker 1: I get a physical next year.
Speaker 1: I set up a physical.
Speaker 1: I find out my doctor has retired or quit or moved away from New York or something that happened to me.
Speaker 0: I came to the city.
Speaker 0: The first doctor I saw was like the best doctor.
Speaker 0: No, he didn't retire.
Speaker 0: He got a job as like a director in Florida.
Speaker 0: He was such a good.
Speaker 0: He was such a good doctor He had to go down there.
Speaker 1: You're going to blackjack Right.
Speaker 0: So now I have basically the second best doctor at the same place.
Speaker 0: I was just like, alright Well, whatever other doctor is at the same place I'll go to and I've had that doctor for like a decade plus.
Speaker 1: so yeah part of my problem is I Basically never need to go to the doctor.
Speaker 1: like the last time I went for anything other than a physical which I only get every other year was When I hit my balls on my bike in that bike accident Years.
Speaker 0: I think I think I'm gonna go soon.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, then for my once my new insurance starts, I'm 40 I'm gonna make an appointment to get the all the Adult older man checkups a little bit early just in case.
Speaker 1: cuz why not?
Speaker 0: I'll see.
Speaker 0: if my what my if I'll go to the regular doctor if he says I should then I will be says don't bother I won't.
Speaker 1: so I suspect Amazon wants to offer services in this space and I suspect they're buying one medical mostly because they've built a technology a Platform a bunch of services that do all of this in a way that has passed legal and regulatory muster.
Speaker 1: I Suspect that is the only reason they have purchased one medical.
Speaker 0: I also think that you know, there there are so many ideas of ways the Amazon could use.
Speaker 0: you know the data that one medical has.
Speaker 0: yeah, you know technologies and Some of them may be difficult to accomplish legally, but given the resources of Amazon They can.
Speaker 0: basically you know of all those ideas.
Speaker 0: they can push them to their limits, right?
Speaker 0: So for example, you know, it's like oh go to one medical and then your prescriptions get filled by Amazon who is Manufacturing.
Speaker 1: I was actually gonna say my guess number two is Amazon wants to offer an online Pharmacy that's just integrated with one medical and everything else and just works.
Speaker 0: They could also be like, oh well now, you know Even if they you know Maybe they can get away with I don't know if they can right get away with like anonymizing all the data Right and then, you know, they can use that to like, you know, okay Well, we know that you know There's a lot of this disease with this kind of person and then we have our information over here that tells us What kind of people are based on their shopping though
Speaker 1: using that type of data even in an anonymized fashion gets real?
Speaker 1: Close to illegal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's like what it's like.
Speaker 0: they don't have to know that for it's like.
Speaker 0: it's one thing.
Speaker 0: if they say Alright, we know rim has diabetes.
Speaker 0: Let's show them insulin ads, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's over the line.
Speaker 0: clearly I hope it would be over the line But it's another thing to be like, okay We have this anonymized set of data that we can predict who's got diabetes and then we got over here our shopping data.
Speaker 0: So already you can predict.
Speaker 0: Predicting that is already Possibly illegal or possibly in some regulations Would be you know, it would be illegal, but if there's any way to do it Amazon's gonna try.
Speaker 1: Do you know how much trouble Nintendo had to go through to even have a?
Speaker 1: this is an accurate heart rate monitor in the switch?
Speaker 1: Yeah per ring fit.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, I think the thing that's getting scary now is technology wise right?
Speaker 0: the Apple watch.
Speaker 0: if you look I think it was two or three Apple keynotes ago.
Speaker 0: whenever the whenever the Apple watch 7 was announced It must have been September of last year, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that Apple keynote was I think terrifying.
Speaker 1: Oh it by the eyes of Apple watch or you will just die, right?
Speaker 0: Apple's marketing whatever you want to say about it has always been our products are magical Wonderful luxurious, you know, you make your life better Etc.
Speaker 0: It's always been positive messaging from Apple no matter how Corny or wrong or inaccurate or overstated or carefully worded, right?
Speaker 0: But that was the first time I can remember ever Apple having marketing of fear right of saying buy an Apple watch or your kids might get Right, if you don't if your kids don't have Apple watches They could be kidnapped and you never know where they are.
Speaker 0: If your kids don't know if you don't have an Apple watch you might have a heart attack and die And if you have one you could live.
Speaker 0: it would save your life.
Speaker 0: get an Apple watch or die.
Speaker 0: It's like they.
Speaker 0: that's never happened before right?
Speaker 0: and they're still going with that same Basically line of selling the Apple watch.
Speaker 0: Yeah Stories you see news stories occasionally.
Speaker 0: I just saw one like two weeks ago.
Speaker 0: That was like up.
Speaker 0: Somebody got alerts on their Apple watch For a regular heart rate and they felt fine that but the alert kept coming up enough times That they said, you know what?
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go to the hospital.
Speaker 0: They were a true story.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's a true story or not, but it could be.
Speaker 0: And it turned out they had some like surprise Fast-growing rare tumor thing that was gonna kill them.
Speaker 1: Well, that's it at the fact that the Apple watch is a bunch of sensors that are actually shockingly accurate.
Speaker 1: Considering like the fact that they're just in a watch That data can make a lot of life-changing predictions if that technology is regulated.
Speaker 0: Well, right I mean, you know, it's entirely possibly a true story.
Speaker 0: But to go around telling people buy this or die is like, oh boy I mean, well you could buy a Google watch and see if that'll help you out like.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying like, you know, but you know if.
Speaker 0: If that's gonna be the thing and that's gonna be the the sales pitch for a whole line of health-related Products now because it used to be the health products are just like track your biz, right?
Speaker 0: You know what's up with your own body.
Speaker 0: now, it's get it or die.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, and if we you know, if Apple's the only one in that zone It's like Amazon's got to do something to get in that zone.
Speaker 1: So by buying one because thanks to kovat The rate of long-term illness and disability across the global population is going to be significantly higher in the future than it would have otherwise Been.
Speaker 1: health care is to put it in the ghoulish terms of capitalism a hot space to invest in right now.
Speaker 0: So Amazon, I wouldn't be surprised if somehow the Amazon one medical merger leads to a buy Amazon product or die Situation.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but at least my choice will be among two mega corpse to decide if I live or die.
Speaker 0: You could buy either corporation a or corporation a. both start with a and they both sell something that promises to Extend your life.
Speaker 0: Yeah by detecting death.
Speaker 1: now This is right on the heels of Amazon basically like doing a partnership with grubhub.
Speaker 1: Amazon is.
Speaker 1: it looks like it's in a round of merging things into itself as much as possible.
Speaker 1: again In some other news some fantastic news.
Speaker 1: Microsoft, you know my they own minecraft.
Speaker 1: The official announcement.
Speaker 1: the word is NFTs are fucking bent mm-hmm across Minecraft Integrations with NFTs.
Speaker 1: anything related to NFTs 100% banned full stop.
Speaker 1: they issued a statement that is Unequivocable.
Speaker 1: it is it is direct.
Speaker 1: There is no way to weasel out of it.
Speaker 1: And the funniest part about this is that I learned because of this announcement.
Speaker 1: There are a bunch of companies who built some blockchain NFT bullshit that integrated with custom minecraft servers.
Speaker 1: All of them are fucked now every one of them Right.
Speaker 0: Well, there's a second news on.
Speaker 0: this is obviously a great news, right?
Speaker 0: Microsoft is basically to my knowledge.
Speaker 0: Microsoft has no coin bullshit and Continues to have no coin bullshit.
Speaker 0: So that's that's good for them, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I guess that's also true of Apple.
Speaker 0: and yeah, right Apple hasn't done any cool Any coin bullshit.
Speaker 1: a heuristic you can use our crypto bullshit is.
Speaker 1: you know that old axiom of if a company has a lot Of bad engineers, it'll likely have more bad engineers over time and vice versa.
Speaker 1: If a company does any coin stuff, they are more likely a bad company than good.
Speaker 1: and if a company does no coin stuff They're more likely a good company than bad.
Speaker 0: But anyway Was I saying all right, so the the news on top of this is that there are some other people who are pro coin.
Speaker 0: I don't want to mention who they are And who are upset at this news and they they have.
Speaker 0: they're determined they're gonna fail.
Speaker 1: Oh I got it up.
Speaker 1: I got the whole article up about these guys.
Speaker 0: They are determined to make basically a Minecraft coin clone And they that like they're gonna make it better than minecraft and it's like dude.
Speaker 1: people have been making my craft for how long to almost like Every venture capitalist like low tier dipshit even adjacent to gaming has sold someone on.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna make a better minecraft and it's gonna be worth billions.
Speaker 0: Right minecraft where it is now, right?
Speaker 0: Let's see.
Speaker 0: When was the first minecraft released in?
Speaker 0: 2011. so it's 11 years old.
Speaker 0: So if you have the resources of Microsoft Right who granted Microsoft hasn't owned it for the whole 11 year period?
Speaker 0: but You would need all that money and the resources of even even before then minecraft had a lot of money Right because it sold a lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So you would need all those resources over the course of 10 to 11 years and that will catch you up To where minecraft is now, right?
Speaker 0: It's like if you're starting from nothing how the and minecraft is still being developed.
Speaker 0: How are you going to catch up with it?
Speaker 0: trying to make the same damn thing?
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, your only hope is to make something else.
Speaker 0: You're trying to make the same thing good, right?
Speaker 1: It's like well, you never mind the fact that everyone who's claiming this in this ecosystem.
Speaker 1: All they actually want to make is Basically a scam program that convinces people to convert their money into useless database tokens, basically Yeah, this isn't a situation where like you're making another FPS where it's like, okay people played the one FPS.
Speaker 0: it's done.
Speaker 0: They're done playing it.
Speaker 0: You're gonna try to make another the next one that they're gonna buy next because they're done with the first one.
Speaker 0: This is like Everyone's playing minecraft.
Speaker 0: How are you gonna get them to play something that's not minecraft?
Speaker 0: It's the same reason you can't get anyone to play anything that's not fucking D&D or Magic the Gathering Like.
Speaker 1: but the cool part is Microsoft like their announcement about this.
Speaker 1: was it actually explained why and they said it so succinctly the speculative pricing and investment mentality around NFTs takes the focus away from playing the game and Encourages profiteering which we think is inconsistent with the long-term joy and success of our players.
Speaker 1: Of course, they also said quote integrations of entities with minecraft are generally not something will support or allow.
Speaker 1: Oh, there's another really fun thing.
Speaker 1: They said.
Speaker 1: they basically said these are bad for everyone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, obvious, which they absolutely are.
Speaker 0: But I mean you can see the same thing even without the coin part, right?
Speaker 0: You can see that what they're saying is absolutely true.
Speaker 0: I just talked about Magic the Gathering And it's like yeah the profiteering that has been with Magic the Gathering since its inception has definitely You know put sort of a hamper on the play of Magic the Gathering, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah Generally anything that makes scarcity where scarcity is not necessary is just a consequence of a broken capitalist economy.
Speaker 1: Yeah and yet more news.
Speaker 1: Global warming is of course destroying the world and I hate that.
Speaker 1: that's just gonna be our news probably for the rest of our lives.
Speaker 1: But now France one of the few countries that is actually Heavily investing in nuclear power as a means to stop emitting carbon into the atmosphere to try to stop this They're running into a problem and that a lot of their second-gen nuclear reactors Can't cool themselves effectively because they rely on passive cooling via water from local rivers that are now too
Speaker 0: hot.
Speaker 0: Yep, just about every nuclear power plant right?
Speaker 0: It's like cooling itself with a river or well cooling towers Nuclear reactors Mostly like.
Speaker 1: there are far better ways to do this But those ways are a lot more expensive and it's a lot cheaper to use a nearby body of water to do this, obviously Yeah, so the climate change has made that water too hot.
Speaker 0: So it basically the water is too hot.
Speaker 0: It can't cool the nuclear reactor.
Speaker 0: So you can't really operate the nuclear reactor or you have to operate it at a much lower, you know power output and Then it's like well You know if you continue to operate it with the hot water, guess what?
Speaker 0: You're gonna be a big trouble.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you don't do.
Speaker 0: you obviously aren't gonna do that.
Speaker 0: And now what happens?
Speaker 0: Well, you don't have enough power.
Speaker 0: everyone's turning on their air conditioners and got to get that power extra power from somewhere and They burn fossil fuel somewhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not.
Speaker 1: and the worst part is this is on the heels of Germany and a number of other countries that otherwise have very good progressive ideas Basically turning their back on nuclear power For somewhat dubious reasons.
Speaker 1: because despite all the trouble of nuclear power It objectively kills far fewer people and harms far fewer people than even a fraction of the equivalent production via coal.
Speaker 1: But people don't.
Speaker 1: people don't think about externalities of both options.
Speaker 1: people like to think of option a has externalities Therefore we can't do it.
Speaker 1: and then they look at option B and they don't actually talk about the externalities of option B. There is no option without externalities.
Speaker 1: There is no way to generate power without consequences.
Speaker 1: somewhere Mmm, and this is on the heels of.
Speaker 0: there is one way The biological way, uh So have chlorophyll in your bod and be a plant.
Speaker 0: that is true.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 0: Your generate it won't be electricity necessarily.
Speaker 0: You want to know what nervous system there would be kind of.
Speaker 1: so you want to know?
Speaker 1: One of the biggest mass extinction events in the world history is little guys figured out that they could make chlorophyll and do that sort of thing and They started pumping an extremely toxic substance that we call oxygen into the air and killed almost all of the life on earth.
Speaker 1: Mmm, so there are externalities of even that type of thing.
Speaker 0: if we is that is that like.
Speaker 0: maybe that's like, you know They're oxygen, you know focused being then carbon focused beings that oxygen beings All right, and it's like when we're in harmony together, then we have a symbiotic relationship, right?
Speaker 0: Where it's like they release the the oxygen and we breathe the oxygen release the carbon and everything's you know in balance.
Speaker 0: And then if the balance is disrupted well one form of life just dies and the other one dominates Until eventually right and it just cycles that way, you know back and forth right.
Speaker 0: eventually You know the the other the opposite will rise again.
Speaker 0: Yeah Cuz like the air will have so much oxygen in it The trees will sort of suffocate themselves and then the oxygen beings come back into play.
Speaker 1: So even worse and then we'll get out of the news.
Speaker 1: There's a story pointing out that.
Speaker 1: so if you don't know Really close to New York City like way closer than you would expect there actually was a nuclear power plant that ran for a long time.
Speaker 1: Indian point.
Speaker 0: it was.
Speaker 0: it had been Native American point.
Speaker 1: yeah, it was the one of the jankiest rip like Nuclear power plants in America because America is not building nuclear power plants anymore.
Speaker 1: It was really.
Speaker 0: it was really old.
Speaker 0: It had a lot of problems.
Speaker 0: It was basically like the nuclear power plant from the Simpsons.
Speaker 0: So this guy didn't even look at it and see how sad it looks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it doesn't like.
Speaker 1: pictures of it look terrifying Misguided.
Speaker 1: progressives and environmentalists had been advocating for years to shut it down, which I Supported.
Speaker 1: we needed to shut it down, but they were advocating shut it down.
Speaker 0: Stop not shut it down After we build a better nuclear power plant to take up the load Right, cuz even though some you know, all kinds of people were against it right for their own reasons.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know I mean it was a shitty Absolutely before shutting it down And all parts of the political spectrum.
Speaker 0: people were for shutting it down for different reasons Which is why it was able.
Speaker 0: it was politically able to get it shut down because there was some agreement on that part of the Policy.
Speaker 0: right they shut it down part But the where to get more energy part of the policy had vast disagreement.
Speaker 1: not even that's disagreement.
Speaker 1: No discussion nobody advocating for it shutting down Argued or discussed.
Speaker 1: where will we get the power from if we shut it?
Speaker 0: That's because right the there was a dispute over where to get more power from.
Speaker 0: the problem was is that a Lot of the people in that dispute were nimby's of various shapes and sizes who wanted nothing to be built anywhere.
Speaker 0: It's like even some of them who may have been you know for say solar panels, you know panels or hydro or Wind or something or whatever?
Speaker 0: Geothermal anything they may have been nominally for that existing somewhere Would not permit basically that to exist anywhere.
Speaker 0: in the state of New York There's no location.
Speaker 0: Well at which they would be okay with it like.
Speaker 1: so right near our apartment There's a cogeneration plant which generates a bunch of pollution If they replace that with a nuclear power plant like right next to us, I would absolutely support that.
Speaker 1: I would rather live Directly next to a Modern nuclear power plant then within a hundred miles of a coal or oil power plant.
Speaker 0: I would also rather have that be especially since there's an area right near the power plant is known as asthma alley Because all the all the kids who Oh surprise Public housing projects kids right living near the power plant that burns fossil fuels Have a higher rate of asthma than kids who live say out in the woods or whatever.
Speaker 1: So because all these nimby's wouldn't let us build more nuclear power.
Speaker 1: The end result now this news New York State's fossil fuel use has soared Catastrophically solely because the Indian point was shut down.
Speaker 1: We're burning more coal and oil in New York State than ever.
Speaker 1: So, uh, yeah getting a little sick of the anti-nuclear Movement because we do not have alternatives.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like, you know, it's like listen, you know, just do something.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah, okay nuclear's got problems.
Speaker 0: But it's like anything is better than burning the fossil fuel, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, even if you're gonna build a nuclear power plant and then you know figure out just just do it to fit You know while you while you can to figure out something.
Speaker 0: but you ever play power grid the board game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like come on build an interim power plant just to get you to the next phase of society.
Speaker 0: It's like at the end of the game of power grid.
Speaker 0: You've got amazing power plants, right?
Speaker 0: But it's like in the minute, you know the beginning of the game.
Speaker 0: It's like you're just burning coal oil crash Whatever, you know, you'll do whatever.
Speaker 0: garbage nuclear a solar solar one that really sucks.
Speaker 0: It only makes like a small amount of energy power that one anything you can do to get power to the houses Right, and then at the end of the game then you'll have something amazing and great, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah Actually, I'll link to.
Speaker 1: there's a great kurgis act video.
Speaker 1: I can't make them things of the day because I've linked to them a bunch in the past but they did a long-form analysis of how nuclear power probably is the best and Most likely to succeed way to get us off of fossil fuels before we can do something else
Speaker 0: and like a Dyson sphere
Speaker 1: Yeah, actually to get us to the point where we could do something like a mini Dyson sphere, but it might be impossible to get to that distant phase without using nuclear power in the middle room because nothing else could generate that much power Except coal and oil which will literally kill us all if we burn.
Speaker 0: thing I want to think about is like, you know, cuz I'm a nerd right?
Speaker 0: I think about in board game video game jobs, right?
Speaker 0: It's like let's say that it takes, you know X energies to build right the.
Speaker 0: what something right?
Speaker 0: there's already some project and You know the earth only has X Energies, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you play Starcraft.
Speaker 0: It's like eventually there's no Tyderium.
Speaker 1: Are you?
Speaker 1: are you about to talk about the Olduvai theory?
Speaker 1: I'm just saying I'm just curious if that's what you're going for.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we could we could get.
Speaker 0: if we don't, you know, spend our energy wisely, you know, even if we go nuclear It's like alright, there's no more nuclear material left geniuses.
Speaker 0: Now what you didn't?
Speaker 0: you didn't build the next thing?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so basically your energy on air conditioning instead.
Speaker 1: now what there is a critical art credible argument with a lot of debate.
Speaker 1: This is not settled science.
Speaker 1: This is like an ongoing debate among experts and has been for At least a hundred years, but there's a theory or an idea that the you the earth has a finite amount of Accessible energy to pre-industrial civilizations meaning there is energy You can access only with an advanced fully powered civilization.
Speaker 1: and there's other energy that starting from nothing Cavemen could eventually harness that energy and like rebuild society.
Speaker 1: if you use up that Accessible energy and then you fuck up the idea is that now it's too late.
Speaker 1: There is literally no way to ever make an advanced society on earth again.
Speaker 1: you had your chance.
Speaker 1: the accessible resources are gone unless aliens come and Harness the inaccessible energy.
Speaker 1: You've destroyed the possibility of civilization on earth.
Speaker 0: There could be and you know a new and like a long period of time it could come back.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah dinosaur dinosaurs like right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's all.
Speaker 0: phase two of all the human They call the humans die and someone else arises.
Speaker 0: in a few billion years They could burn us the way we burn the dinosaur.
Speaker 1: Ah, but that is all well, actually it wasn't really dinosaurs It's mostly algae.
Speaker 1: but anyway the I'll just say the problem is that could be a clock that still runs out because There's a limited number of cycles that can happen before the Sun starts to emit less energy and then we're all fucked.
Speaker 0: That's a very long time.
Speaker 1: It is a very long time.
Speaker 0: We have quite a few chances before that happened.
Speaker 1: Yep uh, but my point to get into the main bit is just that nuclear power in my personal opinion is Possibly the only way we have to avoid having to have that conversation.
Speaker 1: but anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: so You know in New York There's all those like big peers that go out like off of Manhattan that are abandoned But look like they had like old-timey like 1920s stuff on them Like all those pleasure peers as a few of them that I can think of.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a lot of them are gone But there's you know There's a few around the one on the east side.
Speaker 1: actually sadly they blocked off now and it looks like they're gonna tear it down Because it's sinking into the river, but it's
Speaker 0: dangerous
Speaker 1: Yeah, and also before if they don't tear it down like kids hang out on that thing Like I see them every time I run fast it
Speaker 0: I would hang out there and I see here's you can go on like oh, yeah Can RCP or down in Brooklyn is happening?
Speaker 0: There's yeah, you know a lot going on down there.
Speaker 1: So if you ever go to the UK there are structures easily an order of magnitude bigger than some of the biggest peers in New York City that Are all decrepit and abandoned.
Speaker 1: now, but they're still out there.
Speaker 1: We're talking like the size of a convention center just hanging out like off over the water slowly rusting and those are pleasure peers from like the like a Effectively old-timey like late Victorian through Edwardian Britain.
Speaker 0: Yeah And you ever watch your watch great mouse detective, right?
Speaker 0: It's like they go.
Speaker 0: they go to this tavern.
Speaker 0: Where's the tavern?
Speaker 0: It's like down off the side very like there's a dock right in front of the door to the tavern Clearly off some pier like, you know down.
Speaker 0: it's not up on the street level.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you got a place like Brighton like that was the history of their whole city.
Speaker 1: And basically this video is.
Speaker 1: it's long It's like 45 minutes.
Speaker 1: it's a documentary but it talks about.
Speaker 1: it's like what those peers were actually like when they were in use.
Speaker 0: and I Wonder what goes on in there?
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: You're pretty close to the truth.
Speaker 0: They know the truth.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the truth.
Speaker 1: if you have an idea that the old old-timey people were different from modern people watch this video.
Speaker 1: No, but those peers did some cool shit that I think we need to bring back today.
Speaker 0: Is it unsafe shit?
Speaker 1: No, absolutely not Okay.
Speaker 1: Other there was the one woman who would had a show where she would dive off the pier into the water over and over again After cajoling people into betting money that she wouldn't make it.
Speaker 1: but otherwise, that's pretty much cool.
Speaker 1: Hey say what do you got?
Speaker 0: so While we're still talking about so much climate change because that's all we're gonna be talking about the rest of our lives anyway?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, you know this year is the hottest summer I've ever experienced and it's also the coldest summer I ever will experience again Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: That's a very different move.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So I'm pretty sure this story does not look fake to me.
Speaker 0: It looks like a real story on a real website, right?
Speaker 0: So But basically here's the deal.
Speaker 0: air conditioning is not great, right, you know Even the best air conditioners like the mini split ones or like the big the big ones for a big building.
Speaker 0: You know the efficiency of them.
Speaker 0: It's like it's using a lot of energy, you know, just to move heat from one side to the other.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: there
Speaker 1: are extremely efficient ones however, they can only be deployed in very large dense buildings and Yeah, that's not what you can put in like a bus or someone's small house
Speaker 0: Yeah, but one of the things that hurts the efficiency of an air conditioner is that it is not just cooling All right, just pumping heat from one side to the other.
Speaker 0: It's also Dehumidifying right because you have bait like you ever see like air conditioners people have and it's like this You know a little outlet on them and like water just leaks onto the street or the outside because it's condensation, right?
Speaker 0: You know, everyone knows you got a hot thing a cold thing Condensation right and it's humid inside.
Speaker 0: right is.
Speaker 0: humidity is always relative.
Speaker 0: It's it's about right.
Speaker 0: It's not about the total amount of water.
Speaker 0: It's about how much water the air can hold versus how much water is in the air, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like the capacity of a sponge Versus how wet it is.
Speaker 0: if you decrease the sponges capacity the same amount of water suddenly gets really wet.
Speaker 0: But the point is you want to dehumidify because it feels gross right.
Speaker 0: people don't like it when it's really humid.
Speaker 0: So air conditioners as a side effect of what they do.
Speaker 0: They're dehumidifying right?
Speaker 0: You know, the water is condensing in the air conditioner and leaking outside the the building, right?
Speaker 0: So but when air conditioners do that, that's really inefficient it's it's hurting.
Speaker 0: or if the air conditioner didn't have to dehumidify if you just had a dry hot place and You wanted to cool it down the air conditioner could do that much more readily with much less energy.
Speaker 0: So if you could find a way to dehumidify Separately from the air conditioner, right?
Speaker 0: That was say more efficient than the dehumidifiers that we have that you just go and buy What we used in RIT.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I thought that was a humidifier.
Speaker 1: No, that was a dehumidifier.
Speaker 1: Okay, the point is if you just buy a dehumidifier we live we our apartment was underground and basically a swamp.
Speaker 0: Anyway, if you buy a dehumidifier, those are not really that efficient either.
Speaker 0: right and yet to keep emptying the water right which sucks.
Speaker 0: So how could if we could make a more efficient dehumidifier?
Speaker 0: Not only would that be good on its own?
Speaker 0: Especially for you know, just places that needed to be dry for whatever reason.
Speaker 0: libraries, you know present any kind of thing like that.
Speaker 0: but You could combine it with an air conditioner and the air conditioner and this better Dehumidifier combined would use less energy than just the air conditioner on its own.
Speaker 0: So somebody has invented what appears to be a somewhat ingenious Dehumidifier and the way it works is there's a desiccant in it.
Speaker 0: So a desiccant is basically the opposite of a humectant, right?
Speaker 0: It's just like a chemical that takes water out of.
Speaker 0: you know The air and that's why you have like what do they call the silica gel packets, right?
Speaker 0: Whenever you buy something the silica gel is a desiccant.
Speaker 0: It's it's making sure that the box with the sneakers in it stays dry and you know It doesn't get ruined during shipping and gets all soggy or whatever.
Speaker 0: All right, so, you know, I guess mothballs I guess keep moths away.
Speaker 0: I don't know they might also be a desiccant.
Speaker 0: No mothball.
Speaker 1: so there are different mothballs now, but mothballs relief release that naphthalene which is deadly to moths.
Speaker 0: Okay, not great for you either.
Speaker 1: mothballs are not good for humans.
Speaker 0: But I thought they also preserve the clothes with dryness.
Speaker 0: I could be.
Speaker 1: no they just make the clothes smell like an old grandma from the 20s.
Speaker 0: alright The point is the way this Dehumidifier works is they got a desiccant in there and they got two sides to the dehumidifier, right?
Speaker 0: So one side the desiccant is bringing in all the water.
Speaker 0: like give me that water, right?
Speaker 0: I'm a desiccant.
Speaker 0: That's what I do.
Speaker 0: on the other side They're using energy, right but a small amount to sort of refresh the desiccant That was just used and is already full Right, and then once the one side right is sort of refreshed the whole thing swaps.
Speaker 0: And now you're refreshing the side that's full while the other side does the dehumidifying.
Speaker 1: So now we got a heat pump and a humidity pump.
Speaker 0: It's basically a chemical humidity pump and because the desiccant is doing a lot of the work The only energy you're expending is the energy to refresh the desiccant.
Speaker 0: It's a lot more efficient in theory I guess than the normal old.
Speaker 1: I haven't read all the details on it But I imagine the production and the life cycle of the desiccant.
Speaker 1: it can be done at scale and thus economically.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know if you have to replace you're gonna have to replace the desiccants completely at some point.
Speaker 0: Yeah But it's you know, it's I think of it similarly to way I think about like a catalytic converter to where there's like.
Speaker 0: You know, it's a chemical process that's happening right?
Speaker 0: That's you know, saving you energy.
Speaker 0: so if you put one of these and set it up in a room it'll dry it out and then your air conditioner will also use less energy.
Speaker 0: and Hopefully this can you know, hopefully this is just you know, the kind of idea that can work, right?
Speaker 0: You know people are trying to solve climate change with ideas for producing energy And they're covering energy and capturing carbon.
Speaker 0: It's like you could do a lot just by finding more efficient ways to do things We already do right and we have to do all of these things, right?
Speaker 0: It's like they replace fossil fuels with a battery-powered car, but it's like.
Speaker 0: is it more efficient?
Speaker 0: Maybe you know, but it's like being more efficient is gonna help a lot more.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right It's like find a way to get the same amount of work done with less juice and here is one way to do that.
Speaker 1: Maybe in the meta moment the geek big geek nights book club book.
Speaker 1: It'll be a very short one Which is my gift to you after the tale of Genji a few times ago.
Speaker 1: Binti by Nnedi Okorafor.
Speaker 1: It is about a Space Academy and someone traveling to join the Space Academy.
Speaker 1: It'll probably take you one session to read.
Speaker 1: We'll do the show either next Thursday or the following Thursday.
Speaker 1: I see no reason not to and depending on Scott picks.
Speaker 1: I have chosen.
Speaker 1: there are two books.
Speaker 1: I'm thinking of.
Speaker 1: so we'll see what Scott picks before I pick mine, but It'll be.
Speaker 1: maybe I'll let Scott choose among the two For my good.
Speaker 0: Oh Is that is that gonna be a new.
Speaker 0: we could do that as a new book club thing, right?
Speaker 0: I swear and right.
Speaker 1: see like starting now who chose the first ever book club, but I Don't have an easy way to check that right now with my streaming setup, right?
Speaker 0: Whoever it was right the other person can choose the final book.
Speaker 0: you use our current system.
Speaker 1: Yeah, make sure make sure everyone who had the starting player marker everyone gets one legit pick, right?
Speaker 0: Our current system is you have you pick whatever you want.
Speaker 0: The other person has no veto No, nothing.
Speaker 0: and then we just take turns right and we just use.
Speaker 0: you know, basically threats to.
Speaker 0: Maybe we could switch over to an I cut you choose scenario where you choose two books and the other person picks Which of the two and we go back and forth like that instead.
Speaker 1: I like this idea So we'll figure out exactly who gets to do this first.
Speaker 1: But if it is me then on the next one, I will offer two choices.
Speaker 0: I cut you choose.
Speaker 1: Yeah defense if you want to sting.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I want to reveal anything about what my two will be because they are.
Speaker 1: They are so diametrically radically different from each other that it's almost funny and I don't want to.
Speaker 0: I mean you could always just choose two awful books or You know or choose two amazing ones or make it a hard choice.
Speaker 1: Yeah, exactly, but I feel like choosing two awful books just makes the person who put that choice up look bad.
Speaker 1: So I think we are discouraged from that by peer pressure.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think so.
Speaker 0: with I cut you choose right?
Speaker 0: It's like you could basically guarantee that a particular book never becomes book club book by just always choosing the other option Right.
Speaker 1: It's basically It always.
Speaker 0: rim could have just come up and be like katamani cristo and the star fiction kind of money.
Speaker 0: Right, exactly.
Speaker 0: Just keep.
Speaker 0: you could just keep doing that Again.
Speaker 1: one day Scott will be like, you know what?
Speaker 1: I'll take the katamani cristo over that.
Speaker 1: that like Star Trek Star Wars fan fiction crossover.
Speaker 0: Will I?
Speaker 1: That can also be a gambit.
Speaker 1: what if I put forth a choice like that and Scott fix the one?
Speaker 1: I was hoping he wouldn't?
Speaker 0: Yeah It's like you have to read it too, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I picked the bad one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's.
Speaker 1: that's one of the important separations of power That's the safety check on this entire process because we both have to read the book.
Speaker 1: So we are both incentivized to not put up a book that we do not want to read.
Speaker 0: Yep Okay All right, any other metamoment?
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's just get right into it.
Speaker 1: software as a service.
Speaker 1: this is an area where I can speak very directly and professionally because Much of my career has been being a product manager selling Designing maintaining software as a service offerings in a variety of markets.
Speaker 0: Yep, so I mean back in the day.
Speaker 0: if you wanted software, right?
Speaker 0: You would buy the software.
Speaker 0: someone would give you right the software or at least a copy of it either the source code or Compiled binary version of it and you have it and now you can run it and no one can stop you from using it.
Speaker 0: If you have the source code, you can modify it easily.
Speaker 0: If you don't you can modify it with difficulty.
Speaker 0: Maybe it has plugins that you can write who knows?
Speaker 0: but you have the software.
Speaker 0: you never have to whoever gave it to you.
Speaker 0: You never have to give them money ever again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, unless they do some maybe some tricky DRM or you know some other shady Like you have to pay them for upgrades upgrades or patches you have to pay them.
Speaker 1: maybe they offer Professional services to like help you out with it.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of ways to go.
Speaker 1: but like you think of a ticketing system.
Speaker 1: you buy JIRA they give you an exe You're running on your server.
Speaker 1: You've got a local JIRA and you pay someone to administer it.
Speaker 0: right now We talked about you know, the the game streaming like, you know, the what's it called?
Speaker 0: Can't remember the name of the stupid Google thing?
Speaker 1: Oh stadia.
Speaker 0: Yeah the stadia, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know that that's basically software as a service, right?
Speaker 0: somebody else will run the software on their computer right and They're just gonna send you the user interface of that software.
Speaker 0: and in the year 22 The way you do that is with a website usually or sometimes a mobile app Or maybe even a desktop app if they're really, you know, cool But your computer isn't really doing any of the work of the software, right?
Speaker 0: The database is not in your computer.
Speaker 0: the the processing is the heavy-duty processing isn't happening on your computer.
Speaker 0: yeah, you are.
Speaker 0: just all the inputs and outputs are going over the network to the software that is hosted somewhere else and You're seeing and hearing and interacting with just the front end on your local device, whatever it is.
Speaker 0: and because of that The company that makes the software Can now charge you money indefinitely or cut you off right or put limits on your use of the software or control.
Speaker 0: You know whatever way they want to break it up.
Speaker 0: They can be like, ah, you can do 10 uses a month or You know, however, their software works, right but at the same time pricing models and whatever.
Speaker 1: However, you use the software.
Speaker 1: if say the software breaks they got to deal with it.
Speaker 0: Not you Yep, there are many upsides right?
Speaker 0: You don't have to patch maintain the software.
Speaker 0: Someone else is doing that.
Speaker 0: It's just always up to date all the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah You also can't prevent it from being updated because they're just updating it at their wish.
Speaker 1: I will say right now I see that and have my entire career as a positive not a negative update.
Speaker 0: your shit Yep You know, there's some other problems right.
Speaker 0: security wise it's like well someone else is responsible for the security.
Speaker 0: you like that.
Speaker 0: But if they fuck up, well, they fucked up not just you they fuck up everybody.
Speaker 0: There's a single point of failure that is now under attack, right?
Speaker 0: It's like we don't.
Speaker 0: it's like if you have a thousand Microsoft Exchange servers as even if someone finds a vulnerability They have to now find all the exchange servers.
Speaker 0: It's like you might not get hit.
Speaker 0: but if there's just one exchange server for the whole world like exchange comm or something It's like no one's gonna bother with any other exchange server.
Speaker 0: They're just gonna hit that one.
Speaker 1: Now that can get because there's there's a lot of subtle like variations on this that edge into other something as a service Discussions.
Speaker 1: So for example when I you know, I was telling stuff like this I'll give some concrete examples some software that monitors your financial transactions.
Speaker 1: Like let's say I'm a product manager I have a company I'm selling that.
Speaker 1: so we actually offered it in a few different modes.
Speaker 1: on one hand We offered it as a pure hosted software as a service solution.
Speaker 1: You run our agents in your infrastructure.
Speaker 1: It sends all the logs to our servers and you just log into a web page and you access everything do everything Mm-hmm the traditional software as a service.
Speaker 1: We also had a model where we would do the same thing, but you're all your shit would be on its own Dedicated tenancy not shared with any other tenancies like.
Speaker 1: it is not a shared platform.
Speaker 1: I'm running an instance just for you.
Speaker 0: We charge a lot more for that obviously But you're basically right when you do that, you're basically all you're doing is selling the software and you're also reselling hosting.
Speaker 0: Yep, basically.
Speaker 0: and and IT services, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like you're busy.
Speaker 0: a bundle deal.
Speaker 0: It's like I'm selling you the software and I'm selling you hosting and IT labor So that you don't have to do that part yourself.
Speaker 0: and a combo deal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like buying a Gameboy and a carrying case batteries in a combo deal.
Speaker 1: Now a third option we offered was we will give us a sir give us physical infrastructure cloud something Give us a place to run it in your own environment.
Speaker 1: We will have access to your environment via a secure channel.
Speaker 1: We will deploy the software in your environment and run it in your environment and manage it for you.
Speaker 1: But the data never leaves your environment.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now if they obviously people want to do that for compliance reasons.
Speaker 0: But the only danger with that setup is they could be like, aha We're gonna stop paying keep running the software.
Speaker 0: Obviously, they won't get updates or support or any.
Speaker 1: also Spoilers.
Speaker 1: if someone tried to do that, it would not go well for them.
Speaker 0: I'm sure it wouldn't but they could try right with other modes.
Speaker 0: They have no chance of trying that abs.
Speaker 0: It'd be impossible.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because you could just block them.
Speaker 0: close their account.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 1: Another variation on all this is some services will give you like the software service.
Speaker 1: they host the software for you like all those details I just talked about don't matter that much for this and They will also administer it for you like if there's configuration or like management still like they'll sort of just do it and some of them will do ever like.
Speaker 1: they will make you do everything and they'll give you logins to the front end and Effectively logins to like the administrative backend like yeah manage your own users on our platform Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I've seen both out there in the wild.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's every variation that you can kind of think of right.
Speaker 0: and so software as a service.
Speaker 0: This model has sort of taken over over the past decade or so, right decade and a half maybe And there really isn't.
Speaker 0: you know, very few people now are making Software that you sell unless it's like in the App Store or something.
Speaker 1: and even then Subscription software isn't quite software as a service like Adobe Creative Cloud.
Speaker 1: We're both using it right now.
Speaker 1: Good night.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: That is not.
Speaker 1: arguably that is not software as a service.
Speaker 1: That is software via subscription.
Speaker 1: They just give me the is.
Speaker 0: there are some services they provide like.
Speaker 0: they're you know document cloud and yeah Parts of it, but it's not software as a service.
Speaker 0: It is a subscription for regular software.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're not helping me run audition locally.
Speaker 1: They're not like they do have like web.
Speaker 0: there is like web lightroom that you can log into But it's obviously not getting used that much exactly.
Speaker 0: It's like there are.
Speaker 0: there are some parts of it that are software as a service II but it's mostly software You're installing and running.
Speaker 1: Yep And a big part of this like if I had to say anything software as a service is possibly the hottest Technology sector on earth right now in terms of the money that is being made by companies, right?
Speaker 0: pretty much every company that makes software has just gone with this model by default, right because Everyone's got web browsers Since phones became a thing.
Speaker 0: Everyone's got all kinds of different devices.
Speaker 0: It's like to start with a new company making new software.
Speaker 0: It's like what platform are you gonna target right?
Speaker 0: It's like it used to be just oh you make Windows software.
Speaker 0: You don't need to make anything else.
Speaker 0: just make Microsoft Windows software.
Speaker 0: you're done.
Speaker 0: right now It's like well people got Linux servers.
Speaker 0: They got Windows.
Speaker 0: They got Macs.
Speaker 0: They got iPhones.
Speaker 0: They got Androids.
Speaker 0: They got Nintendo switches.
Speaker 0: It's like Jesus Christ.
Speaker 0: I can't.
Speaker 0: I'm not a tiny company.
Speaker 0: I can't afford to port my software ten times Right.
Speaker 0: I got to make web software that runs on everything because everything has a web browser and then which means I got to make A web server and I can't have people installing a web server on their computers.
Speaker 0: That's just not gonna work.
Speaker 0: So You're just sort of making software as a service as a necessity but also because of the revenue stream necessity.
Speaker 0: where is if you try to sell software?
Speaker 0: and Just as a press, you know a fit object, right?
Speaker 0: You don't get a continuous revenue stream these days.
Speaker 0: and Then what right you run out of money?
Speaker 0: You can't pay your people.
Speaker 0: you need to have a continuous way to pay your people which means you need to get customers paying Continuously no matter how big or small whatever you're selling is.
Speaker 1: I think a big driver of this is that Most of the software as a service offerings are not a technology.
Speaker 1: It's not a. they're not selling this to technology companies.
Speaker 1: They're selling it to Normal companies that are doing something and those companies don't necessarily have like a ton of IT Expertise internally, they're like making books.
Speaker 1: They're printing books and they just need access to something to manage their book inventory or manage the subscribers to their whatever Like whatever that stuff is.
Speaker 1: They just need but they need the process.
Speaker 1: They're paying for access to software that will enact some sort of process or handle some sort of problem for them.
Speaker 1: They don't want to have to deal with the technology aspect of running that software nor should they necessarily.
Speaker 0: Yeah, think about something like, you know a CRM right.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of sass CRM some of them really enormous like Salesforce is absolutely huge.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's like the smaller tier one that I've used occasionally.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so think about this, right?
Speaker 0: Salesforce is a generic CRM, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, it's like a one-size-fits-all deal.
Speaker 1: What are you selling?
Speaker 1: shoes knives doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: computers, right?
Speaker 0: You're if you sell anything, right?
Speaker 0: It's sort of you can make it fit, right?
Speaker 0: It's never gonna be a perfect fit for whatever your business is unless your business is selling Salesforce right Because that's probably right.
Speaker 0: there number one customer is themselves, right?
Speaker 0: So but it's like Hey, what are you gonna do if you're some company selling shoes and you need a CRM?
Speaker 0: You can get this CRM that has been devised Enormous resources gone into developing it for a large number of years has an army of some of like top tier engineers working on it Right and you know keeps getting updates and but all this IT stuff is just taking care of.
Speaker 0: it's not cheap But you know, what's more expensive?
Speaker 0: It's like what would it cost you?
Speaker 0: What's your alternative?
Speaker 0: right a?
Speaker 0: use something else?
Speaker 0: That's not as good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right Be nothing you nothing is what a lot of people do.
Speaker 0: use nothing.
Speaker 0: See try to make your own.
Speaker 0: that's just for you.
Speaker 0: That's perfect fit for you.
Speaker 0: But the amount it would cost to build something It's a perfect fit for you that solves all that you would have to Resolve all these problems that the people at the SAS company have already solved over the years, right?
Speaker 0: It's like You're not gonna.
Speaker 0: meanwhile you're just distracting you from your actual job of selling shoes, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you really kind of have no choice as a non tech company than to sort of use these SAS products Right.
Speaker 0: It's like it just doesn't make sense to do anything else.
Speaker 1: Well even more interesting a lot of SAS offerings.
Speaker 1: what they come out of is a company Has a problem to solve and there isn't a SAS solution for that thing exactly.
Speaker 1: They need to solve it So there's no choice.
Speaker 1: They have to solve it themselves and then often what happens is being able to solve that problem.
Speaker 1: It's more lucrative than how you would make money with that solution.
Speaker 1: and those companies end up selling The software they built to solve their own problem to everyone else who has that problem and then they stopped selling Whatever it is, they originally sold.
Speaker 0: Yeah people do this on purpose.
Speaker 0: now It's.
Speaker 0: it's so, you know common and sort of obvious.
Speaker 1: I have done this on purpose in my professional career.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like people, you know, it's like they're like, oh well we make shoes, right People.
Speaker 0: all the other shoe companies need a need software.
Speaker 0: We make shoes and we know that we need this software that does X and we can't find anything that does X worth a shit Right, and we know there's more shoe companies besides us.
Speaker 0: So if we make something that does X that's a big investment.
Speaker 0: But there isn't a competitor and if we're first to market and we do a good enough job We can get every other shoe company to use it.
Speaker 0: They'll have no choice right?
Speaker 0: And then we don't even need to worry about selling shoes because we'll just sell the X tool that helps shoe selling companies And we're good, right?
Speaker 1: It's a hell of a business model and It's worked out very well for me over the years.
Speaker 0: It's worked.
Speaker 0: I've seen it happen frequently, right?
Speaker 1: so One interesting aspect of that, you know Cuz I have a lot of direct experience as a head of product in this space like lots of sales.
Speaker 1: One thing I can say that was very true.
Speaker 1: Is that Selling it this way, you know, I mentioned before two options.
Speaker 1: Here's the software.
Speaker 1: use it on your own or we'll run it for you Say I did like, you know, I sell the software.
Speaker 1: We used to sell some of that software directly to people.
Speaker 1: use it as you see fit.
Speaker 1: All right, our documentation had to be legit our documentation.
Speaker 1: We spent so much keeping our user guide up to date for external, you know, Joey Jojo Shaben who buys our software That documentation better answer any question they have about how to set this stuff up or they're open in a ticket to my own help Desk and that's costing me money.
Speaker 1: So what's easier?
Speaker 1: making real user guides, which don't really exist in the modern world often or Just hosting it for people and then I only need to make user guides for teams inside my own company who I can hire and train at scale.
Speaker 1: the economy of scale of sell of Having a team to manage the software that you give other people access for to Compared to giving them direct access to the software to manage themselves.
Speaker 1: The economy of scale for your service team is.
Speaker 1: it is hard to express how much of a game changer that is.
Speaker 0: Yeah So at least also, you know from the perspective of someone who makes software for a living, right?
Speaker 0: What you know, I've always up until now.
Speaker 0: I've always worked at companies that were not technology companies, right?
Speaker 0: They were always doing some other business of some kind and they just had data or websites or both and they needed Engineers, you know because they weren't you know to make software.
Speaker 1: I have always worked at technology companies.
Speaker 0: Yeah You know and what I noticed right was basically what was happening is all I was doing at work and a lot of places was gluing Existing solutions together solutions mostly but also open source solutions, right?
Speaker 0: And like I wasn't making software really not very much right?
Speaker 0: I was just there was like other software we were buying, you know We didn't have that many engineers like we couldn't build and they weren't hiring a bunch more that they needed to you know Create in anything ambitious.
Speaker 0: So I was like all we were doing was buying or installing free or Available products that existed that someone else was making and all my work was just gluing those things together.
Speaker 1: So guess what is easy to sell as a service?
Speaker 1: Gluing things together the service and a lot of companies.
Speaker 1: That's all they do.
Speaker 0: There is that is true.
Speaker 0: If there's a combination that is a common combination You can sell a service of.
Speaker 0: you know If those two things don't combine themselves together with their own glue on their own You can sell some glue until they run you out of the market sell them the KFC Taco Bell as a service exactly.
Speaker 0: But what was happening was I was like, hey, you know my job.
Speaker 0: It's like I you know, I enjoy writing.
Speaker 0: Creating software like, you know is a different thing than gluing software.
Speaker 0: Like you're still programming but it's different, right?
Speaker 0: It's not you know, it's like, you know, you go and you do some advent of code even you know Just a little programming problems and you're like, oh, this is real programming not just serializing Serializing data from one shape to another which you're not really solving any processing Problems, right?
Speaker 0: You're just sort of organizing information.
Speaker 0: It's more like information science and less programming going on, right?
Speaker 0: So It's like alright I guess I'll go work at a technology company if I want to make software and actually do a different activity.
Speaker 0: and it you know It makes me think like hey, you know, you think worldwide everyone complains about this developer shortage Which may or may not exist.
Speaker 0: But it really makes sense to be like hey Shouldn't all the you know, having all the engineers right work together at few companies Making solutions that are you know, incredible even if only broadly applicable Makes a lot more sense than having engineers at every company Making kind of mass illusions, right because they don't have the resources and the manpower to make anything amazing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, it's like.
Speaker 0: this is just how it has to be unless the you know Everyone in the world learns how to program.
Speaker 1: Why some percentage of restaurants have a shitty website with like a broken flash link on them and some percentage have a custom website That's janky and the rest have paid some company to manage it for them.
Speaker 0: and some have no website and they're only on you Your grub hubs and whatnot.
Speaker 1: Oh, and if they're not on grow pub and they're not don't have a website.
Speaker 1: as far as I'm concerned They don't exist sure But it's like.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's like, you know, it just makes sense, you know in terms of the economy, you know Forget capitalism just even if you had socialism just efficiency wise economy.
Speaker 0: I have all the engineers, you know.
Speaker 0: not reinventing the wheel working together making better solutions Right, even if they're not bespoke solutions, you know, and then you know, okay if there really does need to be a bespoke solution It can just be a combination or a plug-in or a modification of some existing broader solution, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah sales force like I you know, they use the example.
Speaker 0: just because it's so enormous right, you know how many plugins they got going on.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: that's how they they you know have become so big is because they got you know Whatever your if your business doesn't work with the basic version It's like they got plugins and glue and all cut.
Speaker 0: they can make it they'll.
Speaker 0: they have engineers.
Speaker 0: They were like you.
Speaker 0: will you get a contract with them and Salesforce employees will program something to make sure that your business works on their platform.
Speaker 1: I wonder if you and I have both interact with the same people itself on Salesforce over the years.
Speaker 0: There's there's so many people there.
Speaker 0: There's no way.
Speaker 0: but that's the thing is they have armies of people doing this one thing It's like there's no point in trying to do anything else and the same goes for all the other SAS solutions.
Speaker 0: Right Google search is a SAS solution, right?
Speaker 0: It's just a free one.
Speaker 0: It's like what kind of search engine are you gonna make you have no chance?
Speaker 1: Well SAS take a big rule those all kinds of problems But you have no chance.
Speaker 1: SAS didn't really become as big as it is until Modern web browsers and the modern internet arose.
Speaker 1: before that it was actually really hard to offer this kind of solution.
Speaker 1: I was involved in some of this at IBM and you know in earlier internet days a Lot of Citrix involved in software as a server, right?
Speaker 0: Well, that's I was gonna say because the like the first thing I mentioned was how hard it is to port and Develop a desktop application that's multi-platform without the web.
Speaker 0: this common, you know.
Speaker 0: You write once run anywhere deal.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: your only other option was like a Java thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah my old company We were kind of before that like when I was first there Java web start was how we offered access to our software.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like, you know if you don't have even if you do all your processing on some server somewhere without the web browser.
Speaker 0: You need some sort of client-side application that will give the you know, the person access to that service and If you have to hit multiple platforms You're stuck to make multiple client-side apps and port them.
Speaker 0: and it's it's like you haven't solved.
Speaker 0: you Still have to get a whole bunch of engineers to do that.
Speaker 0: No matter how trivial the client-side app is.
Speaker 0: It's like but the web means you just need some web devs and now you've hit every Possible client device in.
Speaker 0: you know the universe even like an old Apple - or something.
Speaker 1: How many websites just hit a whole bunch of basically like web API microservices to do whatever it is.
Speaker 1: They're doing.
Speaker 0: I Mean all of them.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, basically.
Speaker 0: So, yeah software as a service is like is now.
Speaker 0: You know the business model and the technological model that is currently dominant and I think will remain dominant for the foreseeable future.
Speaker 0: right and you know unless Something really drastic would have to change for a different, you know model to take out software as a service.
Speaker 1: Yep This is a space that I have been professionally involved in for a long time and expect to continue to be so for a long Time to come.
Speaker 1: this has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening.
Speaker 1: music can't leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and make comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: and the patreon patrons for this July 25th episode of the geek guys podcast are Alan joys the geegee.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna keep you in that voice.
Speaker 1: Greatly Tenebrae a bunch of people who really don't want me to say if their names Chris the doctors Reimer Clinton Walton decks Finn shy 85.
Speaker 1: Rebecca.
Speaker 1: done review.
Speaker 1: mad bull 34 cowards.
Speaker 1: Sam Erickson Shervin von Horrell.
Speaker 1: Stop all the downloading Taylor Brown.
Speaker 1: The next station is Lawrence West.
Speaker 1: Lawrence West station and a bunch of people whose names I am NOT going to say.
Speaker 1: Summer's in full swing.
Speaker 1: We have not yet lost power at any trouble.
Speaker 1: So we keep doing geek nights and we don't expect any Disruptions to geek nights at least until around pecs West time.
Speaker 1: So, uh Your listening is safe.
Speaker 1: And for right now, I simply leave you with.