Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, August 16th, 2022.
Speaker 1: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight we are talking about casino games, like craps and shit.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Uh, so being a person who has no hair, I mean even when I had hair, I would often wear a baseball hat.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: That's a thing I wear outside to protect my eyes from the cursed sun.
Speaker 1: I get a couple of baseball adjacent hats and a bunch of bucket hats too.
Speaker 1: I alternate between the two.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think when I had hair, I had the fitted hat, right, so it's not adjustable in the back for you not hat experts.
Speaker 0: And you have to get a hat that's just exactly the right size and they're usually made of wool.
Speaker 0: so, you know, they'll shrink but they won't grow.
Speaker 0: So if you buy one too small you're in trouble and too big it won't shrink that much, right?
Speaker 0: You have to be like exactly right.
Speaker 0: So, you know, since the other problem is that a lot of the fitted hats, in the front part, they have like this like buckram.
Speaker 0: It's like this white mesh kind of plastic deal and it keeps the front of the hat up, right?
Speaker 0: So it doesn't like go pfft, you know?
Speaker 1: Yeah, most of my hats actually aren't like, because I don't wear baseball baseball caps, I just wear caps with rims so they kind of just collapse on the top of my head and that's fine.
Speaker 0: But anyway, but once I had no hair, right, the buckram becomes an issue.
Speaker 0: It's not comfortable against a bald head.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 0: And so I tried, I heard that people would like, you know, cut the buckram out of the hat and I was like to make it like collapse but still have a nice wool fitted hat.
Speaker 0: and I attempted that on one hat and basically wasted a hat.
Speaker 0: That was bad.
Speaker 0: So I switched to getting the non-fitted hat, right?
Speaker 0: You know, just not the one with the snapback, right?
Speaker 0: Because that's, you know, cheap, the kind with like, you know, the cloth adjustable strap, right?
Speaker 1: I got one of those recently, actually.
Speaker 1: I got a hat, Emily got a hat that's just like a production hat that just says "animator" and I got one that just says "producer" and I wear it sometimes.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I've had, you know, I had a Mets hat and a Rangers hat and you wear them seasonally, right?
Speaker 0: You don't want to wear a Rangers hat in the summer.
Speaker 0: That's weird.
Speaker 0: You don't want to wear a Mets hat in the winter.
Speaker 1: Actually on my run the other day I saw a guy just wearing a full-on Rangers jersey and Rangers cap just like walking in the park.
Speaker 0: Wasn't he warm?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was like 100 degrees.
Speaker 0: It's like, what the heck?
Speaker 0: It's a good warm out.
Speaker 0: I mean, I like it hot but, you know.
Speaker 1: I like it hot because I'm gonna wear shorts.
Speaker 0: A hockey jersey is like, you know, it's not like a coat but it kind of keeps you warm a little bit, right?
Speaker 0: Warm enough in a hockey.
Speaker 1: Oh, in fact, I have often worn a hockey jersey as a middle layer instead of a fleece when I'm skiing.
Speaker 0: So anyway, my Mets hat is pretty old and so it's all dirty and gross because another thing is when you have no hair, all your head sweat just absorbs right into the hat.
Speaker 0: That's disgusting.
Speaker 0: So I attempted to wash the hat.
Speaker 0: So I got, you know, the wool light and I went for the hand wash, right?
Speaker 0: And I got someone, I watched some videos and people were like saying, "Yeah, take a toothbrush and you can scrub
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 0: I'm like, "Oh, I have many spare toothbrushes that will never be
Speaker 0: used.".
Speaker 0: I popped one open, right?
Speaker 0: And I attempted to clean the hat, you know, rough thoroughly.
Speaker 1: Waste a second hat?
Speaker 0: Uh, no.
Speaker 0: And then I hung it up to dry and then I waited for it to be dry and then I checked it out.
Speaker 0: And it didn't look any cleaner.
Speaker 0: So I went to the store today, uh, while I was in Manhattan, I went to the lids and I bought the literally the exact same hat.
Speaker 0: Like the same brand, the same hat, 100 identical, only new.
Speaker 0: And the hats are very different colors.
Speaker 0: The old hat is like black blue, I want to say.
Speaker 0: And the new hat is bright blue.
Speaker 0: This is a podcast, you can't see it.
Speaker 0: But, uh, the dirtiness level of the old hat is now very apparent.
Speaker 0: It is an extremely stark contrast.
Speaker 1: See, I've avoided this because most of the hats I wear...
Speaker 0: Disturbingly stark contrast between the two hat colors.
Speaker 1: Most of the hats I wear are black or they're like a sports hat, like a boating hat that's made out of a weird material.
Speaker 0: Because you're an old man, you wear an old man hat.
Speaker 0: Most of the other hats I wear are cycling caps where it doesn't matter how dirty they are because I put a helmet on top.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Actually, the hat I wear the most is just a baseball-like cap from H&M that I just bought for like five bucks a long time ago that somehow has not fallen apart.
Speaker 1: So yeah, there's a ton of gaming news.
Speaker 1: We skipped Tuesday's show last week, so we had to catch up on a little bit.
Speaker 0: It's not a gaming season, right?
Speaker 0: Because it's the summer, so there's not a lot of sitting inside playing video games happening.
Speaker 1: And also, without the conventions, you know, COVID and everything, it's not like we're playing a ton of new board games, like, often enough to just have reviews every two weeks.
Speaker 1: But, uh, there is a bunch of gaming news.
Speaker 1: We'll start with, uh, there's a lot going on with Unity.
Speaker 0: The gaming engine, like, basically Unity- I remember when, yeah, I remember when the Unity engine first came out, I was like, I had never heard of it.
Speaker 0: And, you know, people were like, "Oh, yeah, we're using
Speaker 0: Unity.".
Speaker 0: I'm like, "What the hell is
Speaker 0: that?".
Speaker 0: I never heard of that, right?
Speaker 0: I've heard of Unreal Engine, I've heard of, you know, all these other engines.
Speaker 0: I never heard of any freaking Unity engine.
Speaker 0: But the thing that Unity did is that, I think, that made it successful over time, right, even though I guess I underestimated it initially, right, is that it was a little bit easier to make games in than some of the other engines in terms of, like, its user interface, right, what language.
Speaker 0: You could write games in JavaScript, right?
Speaker 0: You can't do that.
Speaker 1: Not anymore, thankfully.
Speaker 1: Thankfully, they got past that.
Speaker 1: Even in the early days, that was a problem.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's like, you could do it, right?
Speaker 0: And it's like, that makes, you know, getting from zero to something easier than being forced to write a game in C#, C++, whatever, right?
Speaker 0: And not being a professional programmer.
Speaker 0: And the other thing is that the Unity engine was pretty good at, like, being able to deploy a game to multiple platforms.
Speaker 0: Like, develop once, and then you've got a web game that runs in, like, this browser plug-in thing, and you've got your game can run on a PlayStation or a PC or whatever, even though you only developed one game, you don't have to do as much work.
Speaker 0: cross-platform porting, right?
Speaker 0: Whereas, you know, if you make some PC game and you want to release it on other platforms, you got to hire some other studio to make ports, right, in the classical model.
Speaker 0: So those made it quite successful, plus I think their licensing model also, right?
Speaker 1: Well, the licensing model of basically, it's free until you're making, like, real money.
Speaker 0: Exactly, right?
Speaker 0: So the Unreal engines of the world were not as good at that part, right?
Speaker 0: So, over time, Unity became quite a successful frickin' thing, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, it's one of the big game engines now, it's for real.
Speaker 1: I'd say it's pretty much, it's the number two, like, big studios with money and resources, but there's a lot of reasons why they will prefer Unreal, but Unity is- You can make iPhone games, you can make Android games, everything, you know, it's like, damn.
Speaker 1: But basically, what's been happening in the news lately, and the reason Unity's been in the news so much, is the game engine is actually working fine, like, there's nothing particularly wrong with it, but-
Speaker 0: I mean, it has some issues, but it's not, you know, it's still in an okay spot, relatively speaking, it's-
Speaker 1: Well, you know what, it's the second tier game engine, like, it's a little jankier than Unreal in a lot of ways.
Speaker 1: People
Speaker 0: I know who are like, you know, I see them tweeting, because they work with Unity all the time, it's like, they have a lot of complaints with it, you know, and the way it works and such, but it's like, it still works, it's just, you know, it's just got issues, right?
Speaker 1: Yep, but basically- Technical issues.
Speaker 1: What's been going on with Unity right now, the reason it's been in the news so much-
Speaker 0: Stock's
Speaker 1: been all over the place, is that, and I'm super generalizing, just so we can get past this news, we got a lot more to talk about, but basically, they really make their money, like, what Unity makes money with is monetizing shitware games, and helping the people who make those games monetize them with ads, you know, the way most games make money.
Speaker 0: Yeah, 'cause, you know, you make, when your game gets a lot of money, then you owe Unity money, and therefore, they help you make your game make a lot of money, and the way to do that is to make, you know, some microtransaction bullshit.
Speaker 1: And for a bunch of reasons, this doesn't look like it's been going well lately, this has not been working out for them that well, they're not generating the shareholder value that the stock market expects them to generate, there's a lot going on, so their stock's been all over the place, up and down on this whole, like, situation with them, and a company that's pretty dodgy, AppLovin, tried to buy Unity.
Speaker 0: First, the iron source, they were trying to merge with iron source, which was a dodgy company that was, like, distributing malware.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they definitely used to, I don't know if they still do, but they used to just make malware.
Speaker 1: So, they were gonna buy iron source and merge with it, independently, AppLovin tried to buy them, and it looks like, as of today, Unity has rejected this offer, and they're gonna go forward.
Speaker 0: The board recommended the shareholders vote against, but the shareholders could vote for, they didn't vote yet.
Speaker 0: But the board says no, which usually means it'll be a no.
Speaker 1: Yep, AppLovin offered to buy it for a premium over the current stock price, which is a relatively low stock price compared to where it's been historically.
Speaker 1: There's a lot going on here, and I think the meta story, the details of what's happening with Unity here aren't that important.
Speaker 1: I think what's important is that this entire, the number two game engine, like, the one that almost everyone you interact with is gonna use to make a game, really has no way to make money except via shitware monetization, just like everything else in the gaming industry right now.
Speaker 0: The games that people make with it make money this way, so therefore the engine has to make money that same way.
Speaker 0: What the AppLovin company does, as far as I can tell, is you make software, and you wanna make some money with bullshit microtransactions, and basically, you just pay them, and they take a cut and help you out with that.
Speaker 0: All you gotta do is make some app, and it's like, well, I made an app, but I didn't build in anything into the app to make any money, right, like selling coins or whatever.
Speaker 0: Hey, AppLovin, yeah, here's my app, you publish it and make money with it, and then you take a cut, okay, and they just do that, unlike, that's what normal publishers do, but traditional publishers do the same thing.
Speaker 0: But AppLovin will basically do it for anybody, as opposed to, you know, being picky and choosy like normal publishers.
Speaker 1: And it really, like, poking through their website, like AppLovin, it is very much, like, it's not a scam, it is just the skeeviest, like, this is what is underpinning a lot of the games industry and a lot of the app world right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I had never heard of AppLovin before this, and they're way bigger than I ever imagined.
Speaker 1: Well, because people think that, like, these AAA games make all the money, but no, the games that make all the money are, like, absolute bottom tier princess tooth falling out with ads and gotcha, that kind of nonsense, like, that is how you make money.
Speaker 1: Those
Speaker 0: games, yeah, those games cause nothing to make and bring in some hefty pile of, you know, gambling money, right, whereas the AAA games cost a fortune to make, and they bring in maybe slightly more than a fortune, right, but, you know, it's not as good a deal as making, if you spent all of the money you spent on the AAA game making garbage games, you'd get a much bigger ROI.
Speaker 1: But I guess if you are a game enthusiast, you're trying to make games, you're interested in games, do not, I would not read into all of this as a reason to not use Unity as an engine itself.
Speaker 0: Especially if you don't have to pay for it?
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: Like, Unity is still a fine engine, and I expect that the company will continue to invest in it enough to make it succeed.
Speaker 1: It does have problems, but it works pretty well.
Speaker 1: This situation, I don't know where this is going, I don't know how it gets resolved, I don't really know what the future of game monetization is going to be, but it can't be what it is now.
Speaker 1: But I'm hoping this is a sideshow, because I do think one of the big futures that Unity could have is the same thing that Unreal has, where another big driver of these game engines being developed is to do things like how they made The Mandalorian.
Speaker 1: To make volumes and video walls for in-camera effects and real-time effects, basically replacing what we use green screens for today in a lot of productions.
Speaker 1: I always envisioned that, especially when Unity bought Weta, they got a better render pipeline they're going to incorporate in for higher quality.
Speaker 1: Not so much for games, but for things like that.
Speaker 1: I could see a world where big time movie and TV studios use some sort of Unreal technology to produce their television and do their effects.
Speaker 1: And the smaller tier, like B-tier shows, use a cheaper solution using Unity and a bunch of their stuff to do it instead.
Speaker 0: I see a world, no no no, we're clearly heading to a world where someone goes to make a TV show using Unity, and then the TV show has microtransactions.
Speaker 1: I mean, really, we're heading toward a world where the temperature is so high that there's no humans left, and the last app gets its last monetization hit.
Speaker 0: No one can play any games on their phone because their phones just overheat.
Speaker 1: It's like that terrifying cartoon everyone saw as a kid, where the World War I, the animals take over after the last two humans die in World War I, but the last two humans were just playing some app game, Princess Teeth Fallout.
Speaker 1: So, some other news.
Speaker 1: Two games are really having a big profile in the online discussion lately.
Speaker 1: We've not played either of them yet.
Speaker 1: But there's Cult of the Lamb, which has had a big buzz for a while, but the marketing blitz around this game seems to have just stepped up like crazy.
Speaker 1: And then there's multiverses, which I am deeply suspicious of, for reasons we'll get into.
Speaker 0: So these two games are just the hot games right now.
Speaker 0: They're so hot right now, oh my god, right?
Speaker 0: So the Cult of the Lamb game appears to be some combination of Animal Crossing, but also twin stick shooting, maybe?
Speaker 0: But the styling of it is very dark, spooky, you're running a creepy cult kind of deal.
Speaker 0: So that's what I've heard about it.
Speaker 0: I might try it, depends on how much it costs, right?
Speaker 0: But yeah, build a town, but also try to succeed, unlike Animal Crossing where you can't fail.
Speaker 0: And the multiverses is just Smash Brothers, except you have Warner Brothers Cartoon Network characters and Lebron James as one of the characters as well.
Speaker 0: So it's a little bit of Space Jam.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's interesting, my suspicions, I'll play multiverses, this is free, I don't want to be able to talk about it.
Speaker 0: When I was a kid, right?
Speaker 1: This is the kind of game that your friend whose uncle "worked at Nintendo" would make up having played on a Neo Geo.
Speaker 0: When I was a kid, Shaq-Fu was its own game, we didn't fix in the Shaq-Fu with the other.
Speaker 1: Shaq-Fu versus Mortal Kombat.
Speaker 0: I mean, a lot of people have attempted to make Smash clones with varying levels of success, none of them remotely close to actual Smash Brothers.
Speaker 0: But this one is A, free to play, and B, it seems to be going down the Fortnite road.
Speaker 0: It's like, this looks like Fortnite Smash Brothers, and you know what?
Speaker 0: That could succeed, right?
Speaker 0: Because Fortnite was really just, you know, accessible change business model version of PUBG, which is a more serious game.
Speaker 1: But also better game design aimed at players having fun instead of competition, there's a lot going on there.
Speaker 0: I think Smash, you know, the difference between Smash and PUBG is that PUBG is intended to be what it is.
Speaker 0: Smash is sort of accidentally hardcore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Smash was not intended to be a game that people have serious esports competitions in.
Speaker 0: Right, it's like because the people who make Smash are not taking the competitive people into account, there just ends up being, right, this sort of competitive way to play it, that sort of incidental, accidental, right, that's there.
Speaker 0: Which is like, you know, if anyone is actually trying, you know, it's like if anyone is actually trying to play competitively, well then it's no longer a fun, silly game, right?
Speaker 0: But if those people didn't exist, Smash Brothers would just be a fun, you know, a fun whatever game.
Speaker 0: Multiverses, I don't know if they're trying to make it competitive or serious or not, right?
Speaker 1: I highly doubt it because I feel like this is the kind of game that is going to go primarily on, it's free with whatever microtransactions and stuff they do, just like Fortnite does to get kids to pay money.
Speaker 1: Coupled with, kids will be invested in the intellectual property of, like whatever, like during the Steven Universe, they can play as Steven Universe and have them fight Superman.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: And somehow Superman doesn't just win, it's like, I know Steven Universe has a lot of powers, but it's like, Superman, unless Steven Universe has a kryptonite gem in his stomach, one punch and he's going to be, you know, Gibbs everywhere, right?
Speaker 1: Well we'll see, because on one hand, I am just generally, I am deeply suspicious of any game that is free to play, that is not necessarily bad, but it is often a warning sign, because game has to make its money somehow, and if you're not paying money, they're getting money from you.
Speaker 1: somehow, you gotta think about that.
Speaker 0: But that's it, incorporating intellectual properties has been a help for Fortnite, right?
Speaker 1: Oh it absolutely has.
Speaker 0: If they, unlike, you know, Smash kept adding characters, adding characters, but eventually it's like, okay, we're done, right?
Speaker 0: I think Multiverse has an opportunity to basically not end, because it's not some, you know, it's not a Nintendo game.
Speaker 1: Well it can be like a MOBA, but coupled with, you know, what Fortnite does with Seasons, and like, oh, an event is happening, ten new characters just appeared, you can play them, just this month, and then they're going to go away, like all sorts of nonsense like that can happen.
Speaker 0: If they get enough money, if they sort of hit the critical money level, they're just going to keep this thing alive, right?
Speaker 0: It's going to keep going, and keep getting updates, and keep modifying, and it has some potential to succeed in a capitalism way, that the other Smash-a-likes have not.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Oh man, so one of the listeners actually played some Multiverses, and they're implying that the monetization is "scummy as
Speaker 1: fuck."
Speaker 1: You don't say,
Speaker 1: "Pikachu.jpg.".
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Because it's free to play, like, I am more than willing to play it enough so we can do a real review of it at some point.
Speaker 0: I will play it for zero dollars, and then uninstall it.
Speaker 1: It finally, it just released for real yesterday, up until this point it was only in an open beta.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's why it's so hot right now.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So, we'll see, we'll play it, we'll do a review of it, we'll see if there's something going on here, but for me to play it beyond what it'll take to do a review, it would have to be more fun than Smash, because the one thing about platform fighters like this is that I have personally never found them fun unless I am playing in the same room as the other people.
Speaker 1: Like, that is where the magic is.
Speaker 1: in a game like this, and at least for me, like, playing Smash online always felt kind of weird and hollow, kind of like playing fighting games online, unless I knew who I was playing with directly and I was friends with them, I always felt a little, like, not as fun.
Speaker 0: That's true, but, you know, Nintendo's really bad at the real-time online game.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, so there's no way to play Smash online, or even in person with multiple Switches, effectively.
Speaker 0: But, but, the multiverses might not have that problem, because it's like, you know, a PC game, like, it might, the online play might actually be decent.
Speaker 0: You know, low enough, enough latency, who knows?
Speaker 0: But I would suspect they are definitely planning to absolutely cram this thing with characters, because- As long as they keep making money, I think, yeah, they're just gonna keep it going.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, especially because they have defined classes, like, there's five classes of characters that'll have similar movesets, and every character also has a horizontal, vertical, or hybrid, I guess, directionality, like, what way do they like to fight?
Speaker 1: So, I bet we're gonna see, like, 50 characters that all are basically the same, but are just the different skins.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they'll be, you know, crook slightly so.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll see, we'll play it, we'll do a review of it.
Speaker 1: Cult of the Lamb, I expect I'll play too.
Speaker 0: I still really want to see a fighting game where, you know, it's asymmetrical on purpose, right?
Speaker 0: And it's like, you know, even the One Punch Man game, it's like they balanced it out, because Saitama takes forever to show up, right?
Speaker 0: That matches the canon of the manga, right?
Speaker 0: Anime.
Speaker 0: But, like, give me the Superman who punches, and most opponents just explode, right?
Speaker 0: But what do you get into that game?
Speaker 1: You play what, everyone's Superman?
Speaker 1: It's just Superman punching invincible Superman forever?
Speaker 0: Well, no, because there'll be, you gotta make it make sense, right?
Speaker 0: There'll be a Batman with kryptonite.
Speaker 0: It's like, okay, so I'll pick Batman.
Speaker 0: Okay, well, now I'll pick someone who's stronger than Batman, not as strong as Superman, right?
Speaker 0: It's like Wonder Woman's gonna be Batman, she actually has powers, right?
Speaker 0: And she doesn't give a shit about kryptonite.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, so you can mix it up in that way, right?
Speaker 0: So there's a little bit of rock-paper-scissors going on, right?
Speaker 0: And plus, you can throw some other god-tier characters, there's people who are stronger than Superman, right?
Speaker 0: Let's see, Superman can't catch the Flash, right?
Speaker 0: Flash can just run away till time runs out.
Speaker 0: And I've only used DC characters so far.
Speaker 1: Make it versus FPS, it's just Superman versus the Flash.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: One of you is running around like Doomguy trying not to get punched, and one of you is Superman just trying to punch the Flash even once.
Speaker 0: And that's the entire game.
Speaker 0: Plus, it would be fun to play such a game with random characters.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So, some other news.
Speaker 1: There have been, of course, a huge number of sexual harassment and racism and other cases in a ton of different video game studios, as happens, as is the open, known thing.
Speaker 0: There's been sexual harassment and racism everywhere on Earth that humans have been for millennia.
Speaker 0: But games- Including video game studios.
Speaker 1: But video game studios definitely have a higher than average concentration of it for a lot of reasons.
Speaker 1: But a lot of nerds like to act as though Nintendo is somehow exempt from this or immune to this.
Speaker 1: And there is a story breaking today, at noon, talking about a huge and terrifying amount of sexual harassment that Nintendo of America's QA testers face.
Speaker 1: Nintendo of America seems to have a big problem, and this article goes into extreme detail.
Speaker 1: And you should read the entire article because there's a lot going on here, there's way too much to summarize.
Speaker 1: But, uh, in the first paragraph, you will go from, "That doesn't seem as bad as I expected to.
Speaker 1: That is way worse than I expected in the span of, like, two
Speaker 1: sentences.".
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, these companies, right, Nintendo specifically, right, is one of those companies where everything is so secret and hidden, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, so, if there's bad- that hides the good shit that we want them to tell us, like, "Hey, what the fuck is going on with Metroid Prime
Speaker 0: 4?".
Speaker 0: And it also hides the bad shit, like, we're mistreating all our employees.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: So, um, but I think that's- you can see, though, that, you know, the people in Japan, right, they're keeping the lips tight, right?
Speaker 0: And the people in America, right, I don't know how people know this, but you can read about this, Nintendo of America sort of had these two levels of employees.
Speaker 0: There's, like, the real employees and sort of, like, the second class of, like, contractor, not real employees.
Speaker 0: They'll have, like, different colored cards and they can't eat at, like, the Cafe Mario.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, it's, like, they're sort of, like, second class citizens, even though, in many cases, they're working full time for Nintendo, no one else, right?
Speaker 0: But they're just not- technically not full employees, they don't get the same benefits, right?
Speaker 1: Yup, if you've never encountered this, it is super common in every industry.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But, you know, the people who are- who have the good card, right, the real employees, quote, "real," right, they're not- even if bad shit's happening, there's a strong pressure incentive for them not to say anything, right?
Speaker 0: And then, a lot of the people who aren't, they want to become, right, the other, you know, they want to upgrade, so a lot of them will keep their mouths shut.
Speaker 0: It's only down in the QA department, right?
Speaker 0: That's where, right, it's, like, far away from power, the loyalty decreases, right?
Speaker 0: You know, the- you know, it's, like, they know they're not going anywhere, they're just coming there to test some game, you know, they're not- The QA people in internal America aren't even testing the game, they're testing the localization of the game, right?
Speaker 0: So, it's, like, they're way down, and they're, you know, A, more likely to be mistreated, and B, more likely to report the mistreatment due to, like, what do I- what do I have to lose, right?
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: And, of course, that's what happened, but, you know, the fact that it's- that culture, right, of any company comes from the top, so the fact that it's happening down there makes it very suspicious and/or likely that it's actually, you know, part of the culture throughout.
Speaker 0: It's just the, you know, the structure of things is going to make it very difficult for any of the problems anywhere else in the organization higher up to ever be revealed.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: And an interesting sort of sidebar here is that part of where all this harassment is happening, and it's not just Nintendo, but this is a good story to highlight it, it's in the unmoderated collaboration spaces within large companies.
Speaker 1: A
Speaker 0: lot of
Speaker 1: the less obvious sexual harassment isn't in person, and with remote work, obviously, that's driven that too, but, like, in person, that's a- it's a different form of harassment, it's responded to in different ways, companies tend to have more policies around dealing with it when it comes to light, but there is this sea of basically unmoderated chat rooms and bulletin boards and systems inside of big companies where this stuff happens, and companies don't seem to have, like, internal moderators.
Speaker 1: Like, very rarely are there internal moderators, like- Because if you're a company, right?
Speaker 0: Let's say you have a Slack and it's really big, right?
Speaker 0: And you can't monitor it all.
Speaker 0: Okay, so you hire a moderator whose full-time job is to moderate your internal Slack, right?
Speaker 0: And what does that person do?
Speaker 1: First of all- One, that person in a just company should have firing power.
Speaker 0: Right, but that person, A, costs you money to hire, they're an employee, right?
Speaker 0: And do they make you any money?
Speaker 0: No, they cost you money because all they do is get employees fired and you have to hire a newbie.
Speaker 1: Arguably though, they would make you money because they would fire the shitty toxic employees, thus making your company more successful and be able to retain better talent.
Speaker 1: You also would stop driving away good people, but nobody makes that calculation.
Speaker 0: That's too forward-thinking for capitalists.
Speaker 0: That's also long-term thinking that capitalists don't have, right?
Speaker 1: Yep, so this article gets into a lot of details, and you should read the entire thing.
Speaker 1: It's going to teach you about what's going on in these unmoderated spaces.
Speaker 1: It's going to teach you how Nintendo is not really better at this than other companies, especially when it comes to sexual discrimination and sexual harassment.
Speaker 1: It's going to take you through this whole unfair ecosystem of contractors who work full-time for big companies via other companies that hire them out, which is largely predatory and unsustainable.
Speaker 1: There's a lot going on here.
Speaker 1: This article is extremely well-researched and there's really nothing else.
Speaker 1: I can say that you're not going to get out of this article, at least I hope you'll get out of the article.
Speaker 1: Let's move on to conventions.
Speaker 1: So, big news, Gen Con is in one of the terrifying states in America that is banning abortion and going crazy as the Cold Civil War continues to escalate and the laws start to radically diverge between red states and blue states here.
Speaker 1: And now Gen Con is in a tough situation.
Speaker 1: They are in a dangerous red state that's passed terrible laws, and now they're at a point where vendors and attendees are boycotting them over this because they don't want to travel to the state anymore.
Speaker 0: And their contract has four years left, I believe?
Speaker 0: Some number of years?
Speaker 1: That's what I think I read.
Speaker 0: So they can't, I don't know what the contract says, but it probably, my guess, based on what other conventions' contracts say, is that they have to run some event in that convention center for X years, and if they don't, they have to pay some kind of penalty.
Speaker 0: And it may or may not say they can't run any other event competing somewhere else,
Speaker 1: but
Speaker 0: they're kind of in a tight spot to where it's like, do they stay, which is bad, or there's no good answer for them, because staying is bad and leaving might just be the end.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: They're going to have to do something, though, because I want to say Lone Shark Games was the first bigger name to come out and say, "We're never coming back again.
Speaker 1: We will not interact with Indiana full
Speaker 1: stop.".
Speaker 1: And a few other companies have come out and said this since then, and this is an open, ongoing conversation right now, and we're going to have to see where this goes.
Speaker 1: I could definitely foresee, unless somehow the US government takes action to stop red states from passing these kinds of laws, I think we're going to see the flight of companies and conventions from basically every red state over time.
Speaker 1: It's going to happen quickly.
Speaker 1: This is going to happen over the course of a decade, and nerd conventions are really only going to be in blue states.
Speaker 1: I think that's where this is going.
Speaker 1: And the ones that stay in red states, I hope this doesn't happen, but I suspect it'll be a lot like Anime Matsuri, like the bad ones will stay.
Speaker 0: There are still people who will run things there, but I think a lot of it's like you look at, say, before the red states really went over the cliff in the past decade or two.
Speaker 0: There were a lot of countries.
Speaker 0: It's like you wouldn't run a game con in North Korea unless you were North Korean.
Speaker 0: It's like you wouldn't run, what other country's evil?
Speaker 0: You get Saudi Arabia.
Speaker 0: Saudi Arabian people might run a game con in Saudi Arabia, but no one else is going to.
Speaker 0: Especially people who believe in women's rights and such.
Speaker 1: There's the line of sanctions.
Speaker 1: Like right now, we live in a country that is sanctioning Russia because it invaded a neighbor.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like even though the people there, some of the people there, but even though many of the people there actually are Saudi Arabia, there's probably tons of nerds who are perfectly chill and are not evil or they don't support what their government's doing in any way.
Speaker 0: Just like all the nerds who live in red states and don't support what the government's doing in any way.
Speaker 0: That's just where they live.
Speaker 0: And they deserve and want a convention.
Speaker 0: But anyone who's not from there, right, it's like doesn't want to take money from the place that they are.
Speaker 0: That's not an evil place and send it to a, you know, even though many of the citizens, you know, are perfectly good or even most, it's like you're still helping out these, you know, the powerful evil people.
Speaker 1: Well, even worse, because in America.
Speaker 0: And there's sort of this line, right, the line is basically does that place like violate the human rights of the people in the place?
Speaker 1: I would say the abortion ban specifically has crossed that line directly and permanently.
Speaker 0: I mean, some of the gun action that was going on also crossed the line.
Speaker 0: It's like the gun stuff was like on the line and then they made it worse and that crossed the line and then the abortion stuff went even further over the line off the cliff.
Speaker 1: Because there is the argument people will make that, you know, if you move these events away from these states, you hurt the good people there.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, by holding the event there, you are voting with your dollars that the government of that state should continue doing what it's doing.
Speaker 1: That there are no consequences for making these decisions.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, if you when you engage in, you know, if it's a capitalist society.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So it's like, OK, first of all, if you don't if we still have the capitalism.
Speaker 0: It's like, yes, you want to destroy it.
Speaker 0: But if it's still there, then until it's destroyed, you still have to play that game.
Speaker 1: I mean, you could do red line.
Speaker 1: Like, how did I summarize the plot of red line?
Speaker 1: Imagine if North Korea hated more than anything else in the world.
Speaker 1: Not the situation in South Korea, not not with America.
Speaker 1: If North Korea hated car racing and that was the entire society was built around hating car racing and we chose to host F1 in North Korea without their permission.
Speaker 1: If you could somehow host a subversive Gen Con in Indiana, where the state of Indiana got no money from it whatsoever and it actively undermined the government, that would be a way to proceed.
Speaker 1: But I don't think that's possible under capitalism.
Speaker 0: As long as you're still as long as the game of capitalism is still the game that is being played, as much as you want to end that game.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: We're still playing it.
Speaker 0: Therefore, in playing it, don't give your points.
Speaker 0: Don't let the bad guys score points.
Speaker 0: It's like, don't help.
Speaker 1: How many times have we played a board game and Scott is like, if you go there, you'll get X points and rim will get real Y points and rim will win.
Speaker 1: And how often do they just do it anyway?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So in the real world, it's like do what you can to prevent the bad guys from scoring points as long as the game is the game it is.
Speaker 0: Don't do that.
Speaker 1: And if you if you're another argument I've seen is that it wouldn't be enough to matter.
Speaker 1: I just point out this.
Speaker 1: Gen Con alone accounts for 10 percent of all of the economic impact in the state of Indiana from events hosted there.
Speaker 0: Ten percent.
Speaker 0: That includes, right?
Speaker 0: All of the performance racing events.
Speaker 1: The National FFA Convention.
Speaker 1: The FDIC International.
Speaker 1: I'm on a website that lists the top events.
Speaker 0: How many Indianapolis Colts games?
Speaker 0: The Indy 500.
Speaker 0: And how many concerts are played in Indianapolis in the stadium?
Speaker 0: How many people stop there on their tours?
Speaker 0: Big time musicians?
Speaker 1: Because it's a first follower situation.
Speaker 1: If Gen Con leaves Indiana, other events will also start to leave Indiana.
Speaker 1: And we'll see what happens.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile, TwitchCon actually did something really good.
Speaker 0: Well, they undid something bad.
Speaker 1: Well, so first they did what pretty much every convention out there except PAX and MagFest and a handful of others are doing.
Speaker 1: And they gave up on masks because, you know, the entire society gave up on masks.
Speaker 1: The CDC gave up on masks.
Speaker 1: Like that ship just sailed.
Speaker 1: And TwitchCon basically was like, yep, masks aren't required anymore.
Speaker 1: And there was actually such an outcry from the partners and the attendees and the guests that they backed down.
Speaker 1: They're going to require masks at TwitchCon, which I see as a win.
Speaker 0: And they're also going to require vaccine or negative tests.
Speaker 1: I mean, we're in a weird situation because we don't have a new multivalent booster yet.
Speaker 1: But the one thing we do know is that the anecdotal data seems to show that mass cons that actually enforce masking have way less COVID afterward than unmasked cons.
Speaker 0: Except for some reason PAX East this year.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, PAX East didn't have a huge number of cases, from what I can gather.
Speaker 0: It wasn't great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, it wasn't great.
Speaker 0: Someone literally died.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But there's no good stats.
Speaker 0: From COVID that they definitely got at PAX East.
Speaker 1: The problem is there aren't stats to track on this anymore.
Speaker 1: All we have to go on are things like people self-reporting or people like admitting they caught it on social media.
Speaker 1: Like we don't have real data to show.
Speaker 1: All we can base this on is like meta-analysis.
Speaker 1: And the only meta-analysis we've got is that cons that fully require masks definitely seem to have far fewer cases than cons that don't require masks.
Speaker 1: It's all kind of moot because I'm still not going to cons in this environment except in and out to do panels.
Speaker 1: I would definitely not go to TwitchCon regardless of the masking situation.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: But the most fascinating thing to come out of this is that after Twitch made this announcement, there was a counter-backlash from the shitty people who attend TwitchCon who are now, they're saying they're boycotting it.
Speaker 1: Which, frankly...
Speaker 0: Go ahead.
Speaker 0: Bye.
Speaker 0: Talk about one of the... That makes the cons safer.
Speaker 1: Talk about one of the fastest and easiest ways to purge a whole bunch of bad people from your convention.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I mean, that's the real thing.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, the masks, there is evidence to suggest that the quality masks, right, the N95-ish ones, if worn properly, do have, you know, they do decrease transmission, right?
Speaker 0: Which is just common sense.
Speaker 0: Like, yeah.
Speaker 0: If things get in to you through your nose and mouth and you physically block them from getting in there with a fine enough filter, it's like, yeah, obviously it works and there's evidence that it works.
Speaker 0: But if having some requirement, right, that just filters out bad people, right, that makes life better.
Speaker 0: It's like you don't have to moderate if they self-moderate, right?
Speaker 0: It's sort of like, you know, how all the right-wing evil people would be like, ah, we'll make you lick bacon to come in the airport because they're being Islamophobic.
Speaker 1: You have to say the words Black Lives Matter to come in.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: Like, if you had a filter that wasn't going to infringe upon someone's human rights and wasn't discriminatory and unjust, and it really only filtered out people who deserve to be filtered out justly, right?
Speaker 0: And not based on some unfair of any prejudice or whatever.
Speaker 0: That's what this is.
Speaker 0: It's like, you've got to wear a mask and have a Vex.
Speaker 0: It's like, anyone who isn't willing to do that is a person who doesn't respect other human beings and their right to live.
Speaker 0: And therefore, if they don't come, good.
Speaker 1: Because right now we're in this liminal period where COVID's not gone.
Speaker 1: It's not fully endemic yet.
Speaker 1: So if cons are going to happen at all in this environment, it seems deeply unethical to have just unmasked conventions during this current environment.
Speaker 1: Maybe that'll change with the multivalent vaccine, but we don't have one yet.
Speaker 0: Listen, even forgetting the COVID biz, it's like people are getting all kinds of con plagues all these years.
Speaker 1: If there weren't COVID, I would just never go to cons again if masks were required other than during a pandemic.
Speaker 0: But the point is, is that like, they do work.
Speaker 0: We could eliminate all the con plagues, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, how many flus and all kinds of other stuff.
Speaker 1: You could theoretically, but at the same time, you would also greatly reduce the quality of life and enjoyment of those events permanently.
Speaker 0: Well, I think that you're just somewhat meh about wearing a mask, right?
Speaker 0: Doctors wear it all day, that'll give a shit, right?
Speaker 0: That's a you problem, huh, to wear a mask.
Speaker 1: That's why, like I said, I will go back to cons when it is safe to go and prudent to go without a mask.
Speaker 1: And there's a reason why right now we're not going to any cons.
Speaker 0: But the question I'm raising, though, is was it safe and prudent to go without a mask before COVID?
Speaker 1: I mean, then what you're asking is a much broader question.
Speaker 0: Were we being cavalier and just getting sick and gross?
Speaker 1: What you're asking is, should we make everyone wear masks in public all the time forever?
Speaker 0: It doesn't have to be, just inside.
Speaker 1: Inside all the time forever?
Speaker 0: In a place that is sufficiently crowded and not ventilated well enough.
Speaker 1: So what about bars and restaurants?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: What about schools, every convention, like everything?
Speaker 0: I mean, will it be worth it if we do it long enough, if we actually could somehow miraculously do it?
Speaker 0: And make everyone do it.
Speaker 0: How long until, like, so many viruses are just gone, would it be worth it?
Speaker 1: Probably not, because you couldn't actually have complete coverage.
Speaker 0: Obviously, it's sort of a moot question, because we can't, right?
Speaker 0: We won't get everyone to cooperate.
Speaker 1: Also, the accessibility aspects of that, people can't read lips very easily.
Speaker 1: People have a lot of difficulty understanding each other in crowded environments.
Speaker 0: There's plenty of issues, but it's like, the benefit of so many sicknesses just being gone, it's like, mmm, that's a tempting reward.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it also means you have to keep wearing those masks forever.
Speaker 1: There's no, like, well, let's give up, because it's not like all viruses and bacteria and infections just disappear.
Speaker 0: No, but a lot of them.
Speaker 0: They wouldn't disappear, but so many less people would get sick.
Speaker 1: It's hard to say, because one thing I was seeing is that...
Speaker 0: I haven't had any sickness whatsoever.
Speaker 1: I have gotten, like, ten sinus infections.
Speaker 0: Well, that's your noses first.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I'm pretty much, I feel like next year might be the year that cons happen again, but we at least know the next two PAXes will require masks.
Speaker 1: And we'll see what, and MagFest looks like they're going to require masks.
Speaker 1: Though I am not booking travel to MagFest, because I'm not super confident that January is going to be a great time, COVID-wise, in America.
Speaker 1: So I assume we're going to be skipping MagFest this coming year.
Speaker 1: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 1: So this video, the item that they make is beautiful, but the process is the point.
Speaker 1: This is an 8 minute and 30 second long video that will take you through the process of making an extremely beautiful blue jelly cake.
Speaker 1: Night sky jelly.
Speaker 1: It looks like a gem.
Speaker 1: It's amazing looking.
Speaker 1: But the process of making it is equally amazing looking.
Speaker 1: It's basically an art piece.
Speaker 1: The person making it is using all glassware.
Speaker 1: They've got light filtering through it.
Speaker 1: This video is the kind of thing you just put on in the evening before you go to bed and just watch it start to finish.
Speaker 1: I don't know what else I can say, except it's mesmerizing.
Speaker 0: So it's like a double art, right?
Speaker 0: They're making a work of art, but then they found a way to make the work of art with particular tools in a particular setting so that it itself is a performance.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: Like a concert I saw a long time ago where two dudes were painting random crap on big canvases on either side of a stage while a band was playing with them.
Speaker 1: And over the course of this, their paintings, they ended up bringing the two paintings together and putting them at a weird angle and suddenly an image emerged that wasn't obvious from seeing them separately.
Speaker 1: And they did it all as part of a single song on stage.
Speaker 0: Alright, so there's a big, if you don't know, there's a huge community of nerds that love making keyboards, mechanical keyboards.
Speaker 0: You buy switches, you buy caps, you can make custom boards, all kinds of stuff, right?
Speaker 0: I've not seen too many people make custom mice.
Speaker 1: I feel like what I would do is take apart an existing mouse and build new components around it.
Speaker 0: Sure, you could do that, right?
Speaker 0: But there's a few, obviously, but it's not common, right?
Speaker 0: Custom gamepads, really common, right?
Speaker 0: Changing out the shells, all kinds of stuff, but not too much in the custom mouse department.
Speaker 0: Well, here's a GitHub repository.
Speaker 0: someone made that they're actively working on it.
Speaker 0: And in here, they've got everything you need to make a mouse from basically scratch, right?
Speaker 0: We're talking the circuit boards, we're talking, you know, 3D printing the enclosure, we're talking driver software.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, everything that is necessary to create a computer mouse.
Speaker 0: This is like the foundation.
Speaker 0: And we're not talking regular old boring mouse, we're talking gaming mouse.
Speaker 0: So I could see this being the start of like an explosion of custom mouse making, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, none of this.
Speaker 0: having, you know, people who are really into, you know, computer stuff, the same people currently buying mechanical keyboard caps would no longer buy a Razer mouse or a Logitech mouse, right?
Speaker 0: They'd all make a mouse.
Speaker 0: And that would be pretty sweet.
Speaker 0: I would love that.
Speaker 0: Especially if those mice just have this nice open source driver, you don't got to install some bullshit Logitech software.
Speaker 0: To go with your mouse or whatever.
Speaker 1: I mean, you don't have to.
Speaker 1: My weird Logitech mouse does just work without that weird driver.
Speaker 0: Sure, but there's features that are not accessible.
Speaker 1: It does.
Speaker 1: I do install the driver because I use those features.
Speaker 1: You can access those features without the driver, but you have to do it by fucking with the mouse itself, which is super annoying.
Speaker 0: Depends on the features, depends on the mouse.
Speaker 0: Regardless.
Speaker 1: Like I remember I programmed, when I first got this mouse, I programmed all my settings into it rather than installing the driver.
Speaker 1: But then when the mouse died, I had to reprogram all again, so then I installed the software, and I could save all those settings on the computer in a file that I could import into a new mouse.
Speaker 0: I'm looking forward to the day where we can do custom trackpad, right?
Speaker 0: That's like, that would be really sweet.
Speaker 1: Ah, but what, I mean, for aesthetics, just take an existing trackpad and put a different, like, casing around it.
Speaker 0: It won't work.
Speaker 1: What do you mean?
Speaker 1: it won't work?
Speaker 0: What are you gonna- Would you take like an Apple Magic trackpad and put like a sticker on top of it?
Speaker 1: No, not on top of it.
Speaker 1: Like, so what, you just want to replace the surface?
Speaker 1: Like, what are you gonna do?
Speaker 1: that's gonna be better or different than an existing trackpad?
Speaker 1: I mean, you could choose the size- Even a mouse, no one's gonna make a mouse that's different.
Speaker 1: They're just gonna make a mouse that aesthetically looks different.
Speaker 0: Well, you could choose the size, the texture, the colors, the material.
Speaker 0: You know, there's a lot of factors there that, you know, mostly aesthetic ones.
Speaker 1: I don't know if you have a lot of choice in the texture, considering how those things work.
Speaker 0: You might be some choice.
Speaker 0: Some.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 1: My counterpoint is I feel like this is gonna be a little too niche and never really kick off, except among mega nerds.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: You know, someone just designs, you know, a board, an enclosure, and then, you know, the mechanical keyboard.
Speaker 0: people, they do these group buys, right, where they put an order in, and then they let enough people order it.
Speaker 0: So it's like, you just need one person to make a design, and then they put the order in and do the group buy, and then eventually everyone gets a mouse.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it'll be interesting if someone designs, because the thing that I'm most interested in in mice, like the internals, they're fine.
Speaker 1: All I care about is the shape of the mouse itself, the physical form factor.
Speaker 1: If someone designed a really interesting, cool one that let me get away from these angular things that I'm using now.
Speaker 0: -Pilot razor blades.
Speaker 0: -Yeah.
Speaker 1: Granted, I'm not that fussed about the pilot razor blades.
Speaker 1: Like, I got a pilot razor blades right now, and it works okay.
Speaker 1: -Plus I got my little thumb shelf, which I'm still...
Speaker 0: -I got the default razor mouse, the Death Adder Elite, and there's only two complaints I have with it.
Speaker 0: One, the software, obviously, and two, it has these rubber grips on the side, and they're just, like, they're coming off.
Speaker 1: -Oh, ew.
Speaker 1: -Yeah.
Speaker 1: -Ew.
Speaker 0: -But otherwise, it works perfectly.
Speaker 1: I'm on my second, like, standard Logitech G50... I forget what the exact mouse it is.
Speaker 1: The G502, that's the one, the Hero.
Speaker 1: Well, my second one, I keep breaking these scroll wheels.
Speaker 0: Look, now that I've played with the rubber bit, it's really coming off.
Speaker 1: Oh, oh, it's done, you're gonna get a new mouse now.
Speaker 0: I got it back in, I got it back in.
Speaker 1: You're gonna unconsciously pick that thing out.
Speaker 1: It's over.
Speaker 1: As soon as it's pickable, you're gonna pick it.
Speaker 1: No human could resist that.
Speaker 0: When did I get this mouse?
Speaker 1: You're thinking about picking at it right now.
Speaker 0: It's a four-year-old mouse.
Speaker 1: I await the day, we're gonna be playing some video game, and you're like, "Wait a minute, give me a second, I just picked the thing off my
Speaker 1: mouse.".
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: In the meta moment, the Geek's Night Book Club book is Binti!
Speaker 1: We should do the show, I assume you're not gonna read it by Thursday, so two weeks from now we should do the show.
Speaker 1: It's a short read.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 1: And then, uh, you get to pick the next book.
Speaker 1: I did, and now I did tell the listener what the two choices will be for when I pick the next book, but I almost want to divert and, because I've never actually read all- Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: I haven't chosen two books yet, and I don't know which two that you are thinking about.
Speaker 1: It's mostly that I want to see what your immediate reaction is to the choice.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: When the time comes.
Speaker 1: But, the Book Club book right now is Binti.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, I will be live at PAX West 2022 on Sunday, September 4th at 1230 PM in a mask, because PAX not only just requires masks for all the attendees, even if you're on stage, you gotta wear a mask.
Speaker 1: So, uh, do you wanna panel?
Speaker 0: Considering that's only a couple weeks from now, there is a 0% chance I'm going there.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So, I'll be there for that.
Speaker 1: Emily's got some stuff going on, and, uh, otherwise, we'll be spending most of our time outside of the con, bumming around in Seattle, 'cause I'm not super into playing board games in masks in a crowded, loud convention center.
Speaker 1: I think I can wait on that a little bit.
Speaker 1: Uh, I think that's all we got going.
Speaker 1: I know the website's coming along.
Speaker 1: We'll do a show on Thursday on something, and, uh, let's get right into the main bit.
Speaker 1: Casino games!
Speaker 0: Yeah, we've talked a lot on this show, and elsewhere, about, you know, evils of gambling, right?
Speaker 0: You know, luck in games.
Speaker 0: You know, casinos are bad.
Speaker 0: But we've never actually done a show about the games of chance that are commonly played in casinos.
Speaker 0: Like, the games specifically.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So, we're gonna review, like, slot machine as a game, or craps as a game.
Speaker 0: I think slot machine is definitely the number one game, right?
Speaker 0: So, slot machine is an awful game.
Speaker 0: You pull up, you push a button, and it either says you win or you lose, and that's it.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, in some ways, that's just awful.
Speaker 0: But in other ways, I actually kind of- It's pure!
Speaker 1: It's not like- The pure, original one-armed bandit isn't lying to you.
Speaker 0: It's like, "Hey, hit this
Speaker 0: button!".
Speaker 0: Well, it is and it isn't lying to you.
Speaker 0: I'll talk about that in a second.
Speaker 1: Oh, I got some things to say about that, too.
Speaker 1: I specifically called out old games for a reason.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of games that are actually just slot machines with just obscuring the fact that they're a slot machine.
Speaker 0: The slot machine is honest.
Speaker 0: It's like, look, there isn't really anything here.
Speaker 0: You're just pushing a button and finding out if you won or not.
Speaker 0: Candy Lad is a slot machine, right?
Speaker 0: The turn order choice is the slot pull, and then you're finding out if you won, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, there's no difference mechanically, so at least the slot machine is honest.
Speaker 0: It's push a button and I tell you if you won.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: So, I guess the thing about slot machines that I find interesting is that, like you said, there's no game there.
Speaker 1: The game is just- It is completely random, you have no control over it, but the evolution of the slot machine moved from a way to get money from drunk people in bars to an entire industry that is designed around obfuscating without directly lying about the odds, and I've noticed that a lot of the popular slot machines seem to-
Speaker 0: In regulated casinos.
Speaker 0: We're only talking about regulated, non-cheating casinos.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they give the player a lot of false choices.
Speaker 1: They give you a lot of options that modify the odds in some way, but are you betting on all three lines, or all five lines, or all seven lines?
Speaker 0: You can put in all these options.
Speaker 0: How fast do you want to lose your money?
Speaker 0: That's what that's asking you.
Speaker 1: Yup, because when it comes to it, any game of pure chance, especially when the odds are against you, which in all casinos the odds are against you, that's how the casino makes money, the vig will always be there, the casino's always gonna win in the end.
Speaker 1: Your best strategy, if you are gambling to win money, is to bet small amounts so that you can persist gambling as long as possible until you are ahead enough.
Speaker 0: Betting five lines is basically almost identical to betting one line five times.
Speaker 0: It's very close.
Speaker 0: I don't want to say it's exact without doing the math on it, but you're basically just losing money faster when you bet more.
Speaker 0: The one thing that's evil about the slot machines, especially modern slot machines, is let's say, hypothetically, you have a one dollar slot machine.
Speaker 0: You put in a dollar, you pull the lever, you find out if you won or not, right?
Speaker 0: Now, let's say you get, I don't know, three cherries, right?
Speaker 0: And that's a jackpot, and it pays out like a thousand dollars.
Speaker 0: Well, you just won $999, right?
Speaker 0: Let's say you pull the slot machine and it gives you, I don't know, two bars and a watermelon.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, the two bars maybe comes out to be like, you win, quote, win 50 cents, right?
Speaker 0: Well, actually, you put a dollar in the slot machine, so you really lost 50 cents, right?
Speaker 0: Slot machines, as they are designed today, pretty much universally, will never say you lose, right?
Speaker 0: They'll at worst be like, they'll be silent, like you didn't win anything.
Speaker 0: If you win 50 cents on a dollar bet, it will say, congratulations, you won 50 cents.
Speaker 0: It's like, you didn't, you lost, you lost 50 cents, right?
Speaker 0: 'Cause you put in a dollar.
Speaker 0: If I was in charge, I would make it illegal, 'cause this is the psychological manipulation, is that the slot machine should only be allowed to indicate, aesthetically or literally, a win, if the win is greater than the amount wagered, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they would game that you would win five cents over and over and over again.
Speaker 0: Sure, but that means you put in a dollar, if a dollar five comes out, you won five cents, great.
Speaker 0: True.
Speaker 0: Good, that's much better than winning five cents when you actually lost 95 cents, right, on your dollar bet.
Speaker 0: The other thing is, I do appreciate the aesthetics of slot machines, especially modern ones, like they're hella fancy.
Speaker 0: I remember
Speaker 1: the last time we went to Atlantic City was right when all the holographic slot machines were all the rage, and everything were like these beautiful art canvases, kinda like the art on the back of old pinball machines, that's just beautiful, but they're of course, they're a skin on a garbo game, just like some terrible platformer that happened to have a Blues Brothers skin on it on the SNES, functionally identical to a similar game that has, I don't know, the home improvement skin over it.
Speaker 0: What I think happened though is there was this era of slot machines getting fancier and fancier and cooler and cooler aesthetically, and then they all became like these video slots with just a big flat screen with a big flat LCD that has different graphics on it, and while the graphics might be really fancy from intellectual properties, I've seen Game of Thrones slot machines and shit like that, the machine is just a big machine with two LCD screens on it.
Speaker 0: But I guess what I find interesting is that, I much prefer the fancy mechanical ones, same just like pinball, you want the fancy mechanical one.
Speaker 1: Well like when we talk about nothing, when we talk about a game, especially when we review tabletop games, where the theme is what people care about, but we only review the game based on the game itself, like the game is what I care about, slot machines are basically that too, it is amazing to me that someone would decide to play a slot machine, and I imagine, because they wouldn't be doing this unless it works, they specifically choose to play the Game of Thrones slot machine because they like Game of Thrones, even though the Game of Thrones slot machine is 100% identical to the Porky Pig slot machine right next to it, in effect.
Speaker 0: Well I guess in a typical casino, a fancy slot machine like the Game of Thrones one is going to be like a $20 slot, it's not going to be like, you know, if you want to play a penny slot, it's going to be like some sad old one that's just got three wheels,
Speaker 1: right?
Speaker 1: Well I mean the game itself of a slot machine really is just, what payout percentage did they program into that slot machine in the back?
Speaker 0: And how fast do you want to lose your money?
Speaker 1: Yup, but as a game, it's nothing, it's literally nothing, there is no game here.
Speaker 0: Alright so, the next video poker, video poker is 99% the same thing as a slot machine.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: The only difference is that you get one decision to make after the initial deal of cards, it's a very simple and obvious decision, I suppose you could fuck it up.
Speaker 1: Yup, but it's one of those works.
Speaker 0: The game could deal you four aces and you could just throw away two of them, it's not going to stop you from doing that.
Speaker 1: Video poker is amazing to me, and I've seen other games do this too, like not even just casino games, games that give the player a choice that is just a simple optimization problem.
Speaker 1: Lot of tabletop games will have decisions that are like this, where if you lack the basic skills, the decision is meaningful to you, it is difficult to you, you have to make a decision.
Speaker 1: But once you figure out how to play optimally, you literally will do it perfectly every time no matter what, there is no way you'll ever make a mistake, and now it just punishes people who cannot solve this very simple optimization puzzle.
Speaker 1: And I suspect this exists solely to give players an illusion of increased agency so that they feel like they have more input into the game than they do.
Speaker 0: I think it is a literal illusion, I'm not 100% confident because I haven't googled it yet, but I am 90% plus sure that the decision you make on the video poker gambling machine doesn't actually matter.
Speaker 0: The game is just using the same random number generator as a slot machine, deciding how much it's going to pay out, and if it's decided it's going to pay out a jackpot, you can just throw away all five cards and the next five cards will be a jackpot.
Speaker 0: If you threw away one card, no matter what you do, I think it's going to force the result that it has decided.
Speaker 0: If it decided you're going to lose, it's like, you're going to lose.
Speaker 0: I don't think it has a virtual deck of cards that it's legitimately shuffling.
Speaker 0: I could be wrong, but that's my guess, it's the same thing as a slot machine, just with a skin that makes it feel like you're making a choice that matters when you're not.
Speaker 1: It would have to be something like that, or else you couldn't guarantee the right returns to the casino.
Speaker 1: You couldn't guarantee your vig the right way.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I would say video poker and a lot of games like it.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of games that aren't casino games that are like this.
Speaker 1: They're games that give the player an illusion of agency, but there is in fact no agency.
Speaker 1: Video poker is just a slot machine, and a lot of those games are also just a slot machine.
Speaker 0: Similarly, they have video bet on horses running around a digital horse race.
Speaker 0: It's like, here's ten virtual horses.
Speaker 0: they're about to race, place a bet, the random number generator chooses the order of the horse's result is going to be, and then the horses have different odds plugged in.
Speaker 1: Well hell, make a slot machine that five tumblers line up, and then you get to keep one or more of them and spin again.
Speaker 0: There are slots like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 1: Video poker is just a slot machine with that rule, basically.
Speaker 0: There are also slot machines where you can try to stop the spinners manually.
Speaker 0: There's no skill to it.
Speaker 0: It's impossible.
Speaker 1: I guess we get through some of the garbo games first.
Speaker 1: There's a whole type of game that are in casinos, and I have only in my life ever seen extremely old people playing them.
Speaker 1: This is bingo and keno and all the games like that, that are literally just buy a lottery ticket at the casino as opposed to buying a lottery ticket at the gas station, and then sit there.
Speaker 0: We're having lotteries, we're gonna just play the lottery all damn day, just constant lotteries, buy tickets, choose numbers, whatever.
Speaker 0: I think that the appeal of that is obviously it's just a lottery, but I think the appeal of it is that you sort of get that slow reveal you get with bingo.
Speaker 0: There's this sort of anticipation and sort of an emotional narrative to the revealing of the numbers that happens based on which particular lottery type game you're playing.
Speaker 0: Whereas a slot machine is sort of like an instant gratification.
Speaker 0: It spins a little bit and then results.
Speaker 0: Whereas the keno, if you're an old person at the casino, you could sit there quite a while, play bingo.
Speaker 0: Bingo takes a while.
Speaker 0: You're sitting there playing bingo and you get that come on, come on feeling for quite a while, and then you lose your money.
Speaker 1: When I was a little kid, me and my brother and all the local kids, we had a little bingo machine, like the roller thing and everything, and we would just play bingo.
Speaker 1: And I just remember having this moment where we sort of collectively were like, "Wait a minute, this game is fucking nothing,".
Speaker 1: and we just never played it again.
Speaker 0: Rumor has it that BB King, legendary musician BB King, knew something about keno, and when they would go with the band to the casino, everyone else would go and play normal casino shit and lose all their money.
Speaker 0: And that BB King would play keno and somehow come out ahead every fucking time.
Speaker 0: I don't believe that's the case, because the casino was crooked or they knew it was BB King.
Speaker 0: But that is a legendary tale that, even though I don't literally believe it, I guess I can believe it in my heart.
Speaker 1: Well you know what it could be?
Speaker 1: So keno, unlike a lot of other games, we're not talking about casinos and payouts on this show, but keno, apparently many casinos used to have a much lower house edge on keno.
Speaker 1: But it's not regulated, like you can pick whatever house edge you want effectively.
Speaker 0: According to Wikipedia- As long as you're public about it.
Speaker 1: Yep, the house edge ranges from 4% to
Speaker 1: 35%. 35%!
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but like- Well look, if you want to play keno, obviously I recommend against gambling of any kind with real money.
Speaker 1: If you want to play keno, figure out whatever BB King was doing.
Speaker 0: Right, but maybe look and see what the house edge is.
Speaker 0: If you've already decided you're going to do it, I can't stop you.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's interesting though- Don't play if it's 35%.
Speaker 1: I feel like bingo, keno, slot machines, and video poker are all fundamentally the same game that just reveal the result in different ways.
Speaker 1: And I feel like the four of them together are just designed to capture all the different types of person who could easily become addicted to that sensation.
Speaker 1: Like the people who just get trapped in a chair at a casino and the penny slots every day for the rest of their lives.
Speaker 1: Like I think they're just directly predatory games.
Speaker 0: There's one more game that's exactly the same and that's roulette, which is reveal who- place your bets on numbers and reveal who won by a cool spinning ball thing.
Speaker 1: Roulette, however, at least it's interesting, roulette has a sort of veneer of class over it because of how it's portrayed in movies.
Speaker 1: Like a roulette wheel is an iconic thing that you see in movies that the society tells you, "Oh, classy people are playing this game.
Speaker 0: Classy people are gambling
Speaker 0: here.".
Speaker 0: Oh, you know, French nobles would play roulette in the castle or whatever, right?
Speaker 1: But also, roulette is- what I do find interesting about roulette is that in the end, as a game, roulette- one, as a casino game, roulette has better payout odds than most other games.
Speaker 0: Well, hold on.
Speaker 0: Well, it used to.
Speaker 0: The defining feature of roulette that I actually appreciate is that unlike- we just talked about how, you know, the casino controls the take on the keynote, right?
Speaker 0: On roulette, all the choices are bad for you because you're not the house, but you choose the take.
Speaker 0: You could just bet on red every time or you can bet on 20 every time.
Speaker 0: It's your choice how much you want to lose, how fast.
Speaker 1: You choose your odds.
Speaker 1: The game is just a push your luck game.
Speaker 1: You look at your current resources and you decide, "How much do I want to push my luck?
Speaker 1: How much do I want to risk for a
Speaker 1: reward?".
Speaker 1: You basically pick your odds for every roll.
Speaker 0: The casino might choose, you know, a high minimum for the table.
Speaker 0: It's like you can't even put a chip down and listen to $10, $20, $50 chip.
Speaker 0: But at least, you know, you can choose where you put that chip, right?
Speaker 0: So one thing that a lot of people don't know- You have a lot of fun and interest- you have a lot of choices.
Speaker 0: None of them are particularly interesting, but they're kind of fun.
Speaker 0: And the 0-0, while that is there for the casino's benefit, it's kind of fun if it happens.
Speaker 1: The 0-0 is only an American roulette that was added to give the house more of an advantage.
Speaker 1: French roulette only has 0.
Speaker 1: 0-0 was an American invention.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 1: America is really good at just taking something and making it slightly worse and then mass producing it.
Speaker 0: Today I learned.
Speaker 0: But, you know, the physical nature of the roulette is kind of fun, right?
Speaker 0: It's like I would play roulette for not real money, just chips.
Speaker 0: you have lying around and a wheel, right?
Speaker 0: To decide, you know, as a random mechanism for something else, right?
Speaker 1: I found roulette is okay as a social, almost like cosplaying/larping game.
Speaker 1: Like it's a game where imagine you get around with people, you're dressed up in '20s gangster's clothes, and you roleplay gangsters while you're playing roulette.
Speaker 0: Oh, can I be the dealer who controls the rigged table?
Speaker 0: Yeah!
Speaker 1: That thing of the day years ago that someone took apart a legit rigged table from the '20s and they showed how it worked and it was fascinating.
Speaker 0: But the physical nature of it is fun, right?
Speaker 0: You don't get to put the ball on the wheel or spin it, but that would be fun if you did.
Speaker 0: But even just putting chips on the table is fun.
Speaker 1: So putting the ball on the table.
Speaker 0: Everyone likes to play with chips.
Speaker 1: That segues to what I believe is the second best casino game, but it's still a terrible bad game, don't get me wrong.
Speaker 1: And that's craps.
Speaker 1: Craps, you get to control the ball.
Speaker 0: Craps, again, the actual game of craps.
Speaker 0: Restrictions.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, so the actual game of craps, in my mind, I'm not going to try to explain to you how to play craps because craps- Watch a YouTube video about it.
Speaker 1: Even then, I suspect you will be confused because what you will find is that most things that claim to teach you craps get way deep into bidding strategies and odds instead of just explaining the rules, which are actually pretty straightforward.
Speaker 1: But I think the craps table is designed to be fast-moving, to confuse people to the point that they bet more than they expected.
Speaker 1: I have witnessed people playing craps for real with real money who aren't quite sure what's going on, and then suddenly all their money's gone.
Speaker 1: They don't know what happened.
Speaker 0: Right, so the thing with craps is that it's unlike the other games at the casino, it's sort of a cooperative game.
Speaker 0: It's not actually cooperative.
Speaker 0: It's fake cooperative.
Speaker 1: It's a social game.
Speaker 1: You're either betting with whoever's throwing the dice, or you're betting against whoever's throwing the dice.
Speaker 0: And that feels fun.
Speaker 0: It's not like you win more.
Speaker 0: It's not like you're actually cooperating.
Speaker 0: It's not like if rim wins, I win, right?
Speaker 0: It's like we're all betting on the same, most of us, right?
Speaker 0: Most of the people at the table are betting for the same thing to happen.
Speaker 0: We're all betting different amounts.
Speaker 0: Everyone's betting different amounts, but most of us want the same thing to happen.
Speaker 0: So if that thing happens, everyone at the table wins.
Speaker 0: So it's sort of like when you're at a sporting event and you all want your team to win, only your team is just dice.
Speaker 0: It's like you're all in it together, and if the dice come up good, everyone's like,
Speaker 0: "Yeah!"
Speaker 0: High-fiving and shit, right?
Speaker 0: And if the dice come up bad, everyone's like, "Fuck
Speaker 0: you!".
Speaker 1: And this is what I find fascinating because roulette has this veneer of classiness, and it has these physical artifacts.
Speaker 1: It's almost like craps and roulette draw a kind of person to play them that can't be gotten by the slot machine, even though in the end, they're really the same game, just with a different skin.
Speaker 0: There is also the social thing going on with craps, right?
Speaker 0: Because of the winning together, rooting together for the same result.
Speaker 1: Or betting against, "I got booed at a craps table because I bet don't pass.
Speaker 1: I bet against the
Speaker 1: roller.".
Speaker 0: But also, you can bet and you can be someone who bets and rolls the dice simultaneously.
Speaker 1: In fact, most places you have to put a bet down if you're rolling.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 1: And they let you keep rolling until you lose, and then it's sort of a social thing of who gets to roll next.
Speaker 0: But it's like, if you're rolling, it's like you're rolling for everybody, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So it's like, even though it's completely random and superstitious, right?
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, because the betting, if I actually explained the detailed rules of all the different bets you can put, imagine Gonshan Clever, but if it doesn't actually tell you what to do.
Speaker 1: Imagine if Gonshan Clever had another set of places you could put dice that wasn't marked on your score sheet, but you just had to know that you could do that.
Speaker 1: Craps has shit like that.
Speaker 0: But when you roll the dice, they force you to A, roll these casino dice.
Speaker 0: They're not rigged, right?
Speaker 1: Even worse, they will usually present to you five dice, and you pick which two you want to use.
Speaker 0: And if you mess up, and if at any moment you accidentally conceal the dice and no one can see them, they'll be like,
Speaker 0: "Hey!".
Speaker 0: There's no way you could possibly swap out the dice for some rigged ones, right?
Speaker 0: And then when you throw them, throw them however the hell you want, they must, in order for the dice roll to count, the dice have to go all the way across the whole table, and both have to hit the wall on the other side of the table.
Speaker 0: And the wall on the other side of the table has all these foam spikes on it that are going to bounce the dice all over the hell.
Speaker 1: You're not going to Jugadoo Jones this one.
Speaker 0: And thankfully, the one great feature is that unlike your RPG tables, your dice aren't going to fall on the floor because the walls are high.
Speaker 0: If they do fall on the floor, it obviously doesn't count.
Speaker 0: So it's like there's no way you're going to cheat, it's completely random, it doesn't matter who throws the dice, but there's a social element to being the person who's throwing.
Speaker 1: Well, there's a social element to the game itself, because the game, I think roulette, uses this veneer of classiness and this evocation of the French Riviera to get people invested in playing the game.
Speaker 1: Craps causes a spectacle at the table, like at that one pack where we were playing Ghost Court and random strangers were coming up like, "What the fuck's going on
Speaker 1: here?".
Speaker 1: Or tumbling dice and random strangers like, "What's going on
Speaker 1: It's the table, people are yelling, there's stuff going on, and if you walk over, it's real easy to join in.
Speaker 1: I've seen people like, "Oh, give me some
Speaker 1: chips!".
Speaker 1: And they put them down, "Now you bet, you're
Speaker 1: in!".
Speaker 1: And the game has increasingly complex, advanced bets you can make.
Speaker 0: I don't know how any of those work.
Speaker 1: I do know how they work.
Speaker 0: I only know how the normal one works, and that's enough.
Speaker 0: Because I would never bet on anything else.
Speaker 1: I have played craps in real casinos on a number of occasions.
Speaker 1: I would not do it again.
Speaker 1: I haven't done it in over a decade.
Speaker 1: Fuck this shit.
Speaker 1: But craps, basically, I think, is designed to get people to start playing and not fully understand what's going on.
Speaker 1: They understand that I'm either betting for the guy rolling the dice or against the guy rolling the dice.
Speaker 1: And the game is designed to use the rituals and the social peer pressure to draw you into making worse and worse bets as you start doing the more and more advanced things as you learn how to play.
Speaker 1: And craps, unlike most other casino games, has this whole fucking language and lexicon like roll for the galaxy and race for the galaxy and all this slang.
Speaker 1: And they, like, intimate and bring you into this world.
Speaker 1: And they use this terminology and expect you to start using it.
Speaker 1: And I think it gives people a false sense of control and a false sense of mastery on what is, in the end, just a slot machine by way of a bunch of obfuscation.
Speaker 0: There is one more even darker element to craps, right?
Speaker 0: And that is this multiplier, right?
Speaker 0: So basically you bet on, you know, you make the normal bet like we want the craps to, you know, pass or don't pass, basically.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And then after if you're if it's going to if you get the first number down, we really don't want to explain the rules.
Speaker 0: But, you know, the first number happens, which means, OK, it's possible for us to win.
Speaker 0: You can basically put a multiplied second bet, basically, sort of like.
Speaker 1: this is one of those things that is not.
Speaker 1: So the board, the table has places to put your bets like a table.
Speaker 1: But the bet Scott's describing, there's no place for that.
Speaker 1: You just put it.
Speaker 0: you just put it behind your like on this unmarked area.
Speaker 1: There's that.
Speaker 1: I'm telling you, this is designed to cause a little bit regardless.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: The point is, is that tables will list a minimum bet and will also list a multiplier.
Speaker 0: So if the multiplier is like 10 X, which is high, you could bet 10 more than your initial bet on the multiplier part.
Speaker 1: And even worse, the odds are actually pretty good on the multiplier bets.
Speaker 0: If the multiplier is high enough, craps actually can mathematically become, I don't want to say disadvantageous to the house, but not like the worst.
Speaker 0: Like one of the better more ways you can spend your money, lose your money in a casino would be to make a high multiplier.
Speaker 0: Bets at craps is one of the better choices, but better ways to lose.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's still a losing bet, but it's not as bad as some of the other like a slot machine or the other things you could do.
Speaker 0: Casinos will, especially on the strip.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: In like in Vegas, where there's casinos competing with each other and walking foot traffic or Atlantic City, where there's foot traffic.
Speaker 0: Put a craps table at the front of the casino by the entrance with a high multiplier, which will attract a crowd.
Speaker 0: People will be making a lot of money because of the high multiplier.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And there'll be excitement and it will be sort of like a loss leader for the casino itself to get people into the casino because they see the craps table is out front by the door.
Speaker 0: People come in because there's all that excitement there.
Speaker 0: And now those people are ensnared by the rest of the casino where they lose money even faster.
Speaker 0: The other thing I've seen only a few intelligent people who will not I don't want to say intelligent, but like that will just stay at the craps table and bet that multiplier and slowly.
Speaker 1: But I've also seen a lot of casinos will have a very high minimum on their craps tables.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I think casinos in general these days have a lot of high minimums on everything, especially table games that aren't like.
Speaker 1: Like there are a lot of non-traditional table games that have hit the market that are just worse than anything we've described, but are designed to like, I don't know, predate on a modern generation.
Speaker 0: Like they're designed, you know, the last time I was in a casino, I was like, you know, you know, it's like, I know I'm going to lose all my money.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But it's like, if I put 25 cents in Pac-Man, I'm losing 25 cents no matter what happens.
Speaker 0: So it's like at least in a casino, if I put 25 cents, it's like, there's a non-zero chance some of that money comes back.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You know, don't do this, but that's true.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, you know, I'm here to basically purchase entertainment.
Speaker 0: I expect to lose all this money.
Speaker 0: I want to lose it slowly in the most fun way possible.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But the table games are obviously the fun, interesting, you know, tactile thing, throwing the dice and whatnot.
Speaker 0: So then you go over to the craps area and it's like the cheapest table will be like five dollar minimum.
Speaker 0: That's like a bidding five dollars, five.
Speaker 0: It's more like 40.
Speaker 0: Well, I see that's the thing.
Speaker 0: But at the smallest one might be five.
Speaker 0: You're more likely to see like 10, 15, 20.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: As the lowest.
Speaker 0: It's like you can bet 20 whole fucking dollars on one goddamn roll of craps.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Not one literal roll of the dice, but like one, you know.
Speaker 1: I mean, you could additionally bet 20 dollars on one roll of the dice.
Speaker 1: You can bet the field.
Speaker 0: But it's like, you know, you're not.
Speaker 0: But I guess that's a lot of fucking money to bet at once.
Speaker 0: It's like if they had a 50 cent craps table, I could, you know, I could reasonably sit there and lose money slowly for like a few hours.
Speaker 0: But it's like for 20 bucks, it's like I'm not even touching that you out of your mind.
Speaker 1: The design of the game is such that it will incur all the bets you have to make.
Speaker 1: The odds are obfuscated and the game moves fast to try to convince you to make mistakes, basically, and not actually play the odds.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So I guess the last big game, because we got a lot of time here, the mega popular one is poker.
Speaker 0: Actual poker.
Speaker 0: Actual poker, Holdem, et cetera.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And mostly Texas Holdem is the game.
Speaker 0: And the interesting thing about Holdem is that you are not playing against the house.
Speaker 0: You are playing against the other people you're playing poker with.
Speaker 0: And the house is basically taking a just a normal a cut straight across the board.
Speaker 0: because they are facilitating the poker game.
Speaker 0: They're providing the table, the dealer, the cards, the you know, the making sure no one cheats, et cetera.
Speaker 0: They're providing this service.
Speaker 0: So they take a cut and you could actually win if you're better at poker than the people you're playing against.
Speaker 0: But if everyone is, you know, a Texas Holdem master type person, of which there are many such people, then again, it becomes a game of luck.
Speaker 0: But it at least has, you know, a skill element that the other games don't have.
Speaker 0: And it has an element of not just a game of chance, as long as there is some skill disparity present.
Speaker 1: So I still think it would be fascinating to play serious games with a betting structure around them in an environment.
Speaker 0: I mean, I would love for there to be a place right.
Speaker 0: Much like a casino that would facilitate and take a cut of competitive games that were skill based.
Speaker 0: You know, we want to bet on table tennis.
Speaker 0: You provide a judge and a table and equipment.
Speaker 0: that's all checked out and we'll pay you a cut.
Speaker 0: and we're mean.
Speaker 0: This other person are going to bet on our game of table tennis and you're going to take all our money and give the money to the winner to make sure there's no shenanigans.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like that's.
Speaker 0: that sounds good to me.
Speaker 0: I mean, I wouldn't do that because I can't play table tennis, but people who are good at table tennis would be perfectly reasonable to do that.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's not a casino where you're guaranteed to lose.
Speaker 0: You're betting on your own skills.
Speaker 0: You know, it's not really gambling.
Speaker 0: It's not a game of chance.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if you take the betting out, if we're just reviewing the games, poker is...
Speaker 0: I would just pay for someone to provide equipment and judge a game that had no prize.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Pay someone to just set up, I don't know, the four hour long German board game.
Speaker 1: Make sure everyone follows the rules.
Speaker 1: Facilitate everything.
Speaker 1: Count the victory points at the end.
Speaker 0: Please facilitate this game of diplomacy.
Speaker 0: so it goes quickly for us.
Speaker 0: Here's 50 bucks.
Speaker 1: That's actually something I've never seen.
Speaker 1: That is the high class board game cafe.
Speaker 1: It's basically like a casino.
Speaker 1: There's no gambling, but there is a. there is a like a pit boss at every table, like running everything.
Speaker 0: You're paying for facilitate.
Speaker 0: I would love that.
Speaker 0: So poker, Texas Hold'em is the closest you get to that in a casino.
Speaker 0: I guess the final game we should mention is Blackjack, which is still is just a game of chance, just like all those other ones.
Speaker 0: But there's the counting element, which basically doesn't really exist anymore because they've mitigated it so much.
Speaker 1: Or even if it does exist, it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: Even if you count perfectly, it's still random enough to where you're not going to come out ahead.
Speaker 0: Most of the time.
Speaker 0: But there was indeed a period of time where there was a way to cheat the game in quotes, right?
Speaker 0: And that makes it, I guess, different than the other casino games.
Speaker 1: Blackjack has pretty much always existed solely to convince people who think they're smarter than they are that they can beat the house.
Speaker 0: I think that before card counting was discovered, slash invented, slash mastered, perfected some decades past.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It was just a game of chance like the others.
Speaker 0: But once it was discovered, it's like, well, why keep it?
Speaker 0: And they keep it, I think, for the reason you just said is that because there is this history of people being able to beat it, but it's been mitigated.
Speaker 0: They can get rubes who believe they can beat it to come and play what the rube who knows all the other games are a game of chance thinks Blackjack isn't.
Speaker 0: And it is.
Speaker 0: And they lose their money on it, right?
Speaker 0: It's sort of like a next level bluff by the house to keep the Blackjack tables.
Speaker 1: Blackjack as a game is interesting in that it's a good game for kids and a terrible game for adults.
Speaker 1: Because if you play single deck Blackjack with kids, there's actually like kids will learn about.
Speaker 1: just like I used to play.
Speaker 1: Grandma would deal Blackjack for me and my brother.
Speaker 1: We play with poker chips and it was actually pretty fun a little bit until we learned how to do math.
Speaker 1: But also, grandma didn't follow the normal casino rules because in a casino, the dealer has rules they have to hit in certain situations like they can't just play at their own discretion.
Speaker 1: They're following a playbook.
Speaker 1: Grandma just played to win.
Speaker 0: So if you had Microsoft Entertainment Pack for Windows 3.1, it came with a Blackjack that was called Dr.
Speaker 0: Blackjack, which before Microsoft bought it was called Professor Blackjack.
Speaker 1: I remember Dr.
Speaker 1: Blackjack.
Speaker 0: Is this from like the early 90s?
Speaker 0: And Dr.
Speaker 0: Blackjack was just video Blackjack against nobody on your computer with Windows 3.1.
Speaker 0: But it would teach you how to count cards.
Speaker 0: It just showed you the count the whole time.
Speaker 0: And so it's like if you read the instructions, you could actually practice counting cards using Dr.
Speaker 0: Blackjack.
Speaker 0: And then go to a casino and lose all your money because by the early 90s when this came out, card counting didn't work anymore.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But I guess the game itself is...
Speaker 0: My Chinese food is here.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: I think we'll just stop.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: I will not say.
Speaker 1: I recorded this on my gaming headset because it was late and I just finished A Game of Burning Wheel.
Speaker 1: I didn't want to turn all the stuff back on.
Speaker 1: So, yeah.
Speaker 1: Casino games.
Speaker 1: Let us know what you think of that Lamb cult game and we might do a show on it in the near future.
Speaker 1: But for now I simply leave you with... [MUSIC].