Speaker 0: It's Tuesday, May 24th, 2022.
Speaker 0: I'm Rym.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight we are talking about game monetization.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: I did not expect on May 24th, 2022, to still be talking about the Stanley Cup playoffs on Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Here we are.
Speaker 1: We could have talked about the other teams, right?
Speaker 1: I mean, it's a thing that we only talk about, you know, rarely, because, A, you know, in Geek Nights from, say, 2005 to 2013, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like, you know, we got out of college and we didn't see so much hockey because there wasn't yet illegal streaming.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It was actually hard to watch hockey.
Speaker 0: Also, we were poor.
Speaker 0: We couldn't actually afford...
Speaker 1: We could have afforded to pay for cable, but we weren't gonna.
Speaker 0: No, but we couldn't afford to, like, go to New York City and see Rangers games.
Speaker 1: No, we definitely couldn't afford that more than, you know, once in a blue moon.
Speaker 1: And so it wasn't until, like, you know, 2014, 2015, the team was ridiculously good, like reached the finals good.
Speaker 1: And we were able to go, you know, watch in Bryant Park, at least.
Speaker 1: And we had, you know, a source for a few playoff tickets here and there.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: Plus, Emily got into hockey big and it kind of got me back into hockey because I really hadn't followed it much since 2004.
Speaker 1: I was never out of hockey.
Speaker 1: It's just my ability to watch it changed, right?
Speaker 0: Well, I noticed I watched hockey religiously up until the year 2000.
Speaker 0: What happened in the year 2000?
Speaker 0: Went to college, didn't have cable anymore.
Speaker 1: Watched college hockey instead.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: I was still into hockey, but I wasn't watching the NHL at the time.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, even freshman year, like, my roommate paid for cable because he was watching all those soccer games.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: You had that weird roommate.
Speaker 0: I'm glad my roommate was silent.
Speaker 1: He wasn't weird.
Speaker 1: He was just a soccer dude.
Speaker 1: Oh.
Speaker 0: He paid for cable, though.
Speaker 1: He wasn't strange in any way.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: He wasn't like Greg's roommate.
Speaker 1: He was just really big into soccer.
Speaker 1: That was his thing, you know?
Speaker 1: Anyway, but it's like, how could I watch hockey?
Speaker 1: It's not, you didn't get, you know, it's like, even if I was going to watch it on that tiny cable TV in our dorm, it's like, am I really going to spend?
Speaker 1: Like, you know, my evenings in the dorm.
Speaker 1: It's like I had class some evenings.
Speaker 0: The alternative was either night class or sneaking into a room somewhere to play battle tech.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to skip on anime club to go watch a hockey game, right?
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, a non in-person one, a TV one alone when the team isn't any good, right?
Speaker 1: You know, people might say, oh, a Fairweather fan only watching when the team is good.
Speaker 1: Well, first of all, when I've had the capacity to watch and the team has been bad, I still watched.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And I didn't, it's not like I changed teams at any point.
Speaker 0: Well, similarly, what was funny is when I think back, I was, you know, I grew up in Detroit, Red Wings fan, because family's Red Wings fan.
Speaker 0: The whole family is obsessed with hockey, like the extended family, everyone, it's a thing.
Speaker 0: Detroit's one of those cities.
Speaker 0: And I never experienced a team being bad.
Speaker 0: They were literally great the entirety of my childhood up until I went to RIT and for about four or five years, even after I got to RIT.
Speaker 0: So I stopped watching while they were still great, just because it was hard to watch.
Speaker 1: And then, I mean, the Rangers, it's like they won at the Stanley Cup when I was 12.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So, and we didn't, I think that's around that that's around the time we even got cable.
Speaker 1: So even though it was in the area, I couldn't watch that many games unless they were on like, you know, like ABC or something like that.
Speaker 1: And the major.
Speaker 0: I mean, meanwhile, my parents, they were watching Red Wings games where you get tickets for free at the Coliseum during the Dead Wings era.
Speaker 1: Well, my parents had, yeah, like Rangers season tickets in the 70s for like a few bucks each, right?
Speaker 1: Whatever the, you know, the un-renovated garden.
Speaker 0: That was two arenas ago in Detroit.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But I watched, you know, 90s Rangers, right?
Speaker 1: Which started out about as good as they could be.
Speaker 1: And they stayed pretty good.
Speaker 1: They had Wayne Gretzky, you know, but then towards the end of the 90s, you know, not as good, right?
Speaker 1: Fadin, Fadin, you know.
Speaker 1: And then, you know, when I was in college and the rest of that decade, you know, 2000 through 2010 was pretty much, you know, the time when we did in between, right?
Speaker 1: The pre-Lunkquist era.
Speaker 1: So it's like, you know, once the Lunkquist era began, that's when, you know, we started having some hope again, right?
Speaker 1: And now we, the gap between the Mike Richter era and the Lunkquist era was kind of a big, you know, gap.
Speaker 1: But there was no gap basically between the Lunkquist era and the Shisterkin era.
Speaker 0: They went from having like one of the literally best goalies in the entire NHL to having literally one of the best goalies in the NHL.
Speaker 1: And then, you know, it coincided with the time where we were able to live in the city and have tickets and now we don't suck again.
Speaker 1: And this is the first time, right, where all of that is lined up, right?
Speaker 1: Even though we've been doing the show for over 15 years, it's like this is the first time we lived in the city and we have tickets and they're in the playoffs and they actually got past the first round.
Speaker 1: So now it's right.
Speaker 1: So that's why suddenly the hockey talk has increased beyond the usual levels.
Speaker 1: It's even surpassing bike talk, even though I did a whole bunch of biking this week.
Speaker 0: We also did a whole bunch of biking and yeah, actually some trouble getting back.
Speaker 0: So on the Sunday, Emily and I went to the Sunday Rangers game and we tried to leave.
Speaker 1: Let's just let's just change the days of geek nights.
Speaker 1: We have a hard time coming up with topics for tech news, gaming, whatever.
Speaker 1: Let's just fucking do bike podcasts and hockey podcasts.
Speaker 0: Bike, hockey.
Speaker 0: We could still do gaming, I think, pretty easily.
Speaker 1: Well, it's like we got to get into, you know, specific bike topics, right?
Speaker 1: Start, you know, being like, oh, which, you know, you want to use?
Speaker 1: the Shimano or the SRAM?
Speaker 0: What kind of cadence do you like to ride at in different conditions?
Speaker 0: The 90 or the 70?
Speaker 1: A whole podcast about specific biking topics.
Speaker 0: We try out 10 different chamois butters.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, we'll see how this goes tonight.
Speaker 0: We can try to finish the show quick so we can, one, play Blades in the Dark because tonight is a geek night's night, a Blades in the Dark night and a very important hockey night.
Speaker 1: It's the same thing for me, only replace the Blades in the Dark with cooking a dinner.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we went a little too hard against the Denver Sisters and there were consequences.
Speaker 0: But anyway, there's a ton of gaming news.
Speaker 0: We're not going to, can't talk about everything.
Speaker 0: I think we even skipped a Tuesday show because of hockey or something.
Speaker 0: So, just got right into it.
Speaker 0: PlayStation Plus, I don't think there's that many geek nights listeners who care about this, but gamers care about this.
Speaker 0: It's a useful service if you're a PlayStation person.
Speaker 0: I don't know a lot about it because I haven't had a PlayStation since the PS1.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my, what I under, basically all I know is that PlayStation Plus is basically the same thing as like Nintendo Online, right?
Speaker 1: Except... You're paying for the ability to like play PlayStation games online and you get some games and you get some other shit.
Speaker 0: That kind of thing, but the news is, so they're changing that and they're upgrading it and there's like better plans now, but it's a tiered system, like there's different levels of plan.
Speaker 0: So, they just did a, like some sort of change in the membership to add these tiers.
Speaker 0: And if you have an existing plan under the old system, you have to, if you want to continue using it or get access to any of this new stuff, you have to upgrade your plan.
Speaker 0: But the way they appear to be doing it is they'll pro-rate...
Speaker 1: No carrying over, no legacy plans.
Speaker 1: What if you don't do anything?
Speaker 1: Did they automatically pick a plan for you?
Speaker 0: I don't know, actually.
Speaker 1: They'd cancel you?
Speaker 1: I don't imagine they would cancel you.
Speaker 1: They want to keep getting your money.
Speaker 0: So, we're only, I only want to focus on, because the news here is that they did this.
Speaker 0: There's a new tier, there's good stuff in these tiers and you got to get, you got to upgrade to get this stuff.
Speaker 0: They rolled it out in Asia first and a bunch of people tried to upgrade and it charged them basically back rent on their existing subscription.
Speaker 0: You got to pay to upgrade to then have the privilege of paying more.
Speaker 1: Was that an accident in the billing system?
Speaker 1: No!
Speaker 0: There's a lot going on here.
Speaker 0: So, the new tiers are $100 or $120 a year, so like $10 a month.
Speaker 0: But what was happening, I found an article that explains a little bit of what was going on, it took a while to figure this out.
Speaker 0: And no one's 100% sure yet.
Speaker 0: Sony won't issue statements clarifying.
Speaker 1: People in Asia are posting- That's what bothers me the most, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, companies doing shady stuff or having bad takes or whatever.
Speaker 1: But it's like, at least just have the guts to say the truth and give the full information about whatever your evil shit is.
Speaker 1: And it's like, it's like, just do that and I can at least respect, you know, it's like, you know, all right, you're doing something I think is real shitty.
Speaker 1: But you know what?
Speaker 1: You came out, you said it, you defended it, you didn't try to hide it, you didn't try to not say anything, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, at least I can respect that, right?
Speaker 1: Just coming out being like, yep, we are going to charge you 50 bucks a month, fucking deal with it, do that.
Speaker 1: And I'll be like, you know what?
Speaker 1: That's bullshit, but respect, right?
Speaker 1: Someone's like, secretly like, oh, yeah, we have plans, they're new plans, they're great, 50 bucks a month.
Speaker 1: It's like, what?
Speaker 1: What'd you say?
Speaker 1: Oh, nothing.
Speaker 0: So, so one guy posted a screenshot where he tried to upgrade and it said, oh, you got to pay this back rent.
Speaker 0: It was 430 fucking dollars.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no, thanks.
Speaker 1: So what happened, but somebody who just buys a brand new PlayStation today with a brand new account.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: How much would they pay?
Speaker 0: They'd pay the normal 120 bucks a month or a year divided by 12.
Speaker 0: So what happened was, way back, there were, you could, in various ways, get discounted extensions to the previous PlayStation stuff.
Speaker 0: So people were stacking those subscriptions.
Speaker 0: Every time there was a discount, people would add years to their subscription just to buy it at a cheaper rate.
Speaker 0: Because these people, and this is what I don't get about Sony, the people they're screwing over here are not the casual gamers who might not even notice.
Speaker 0: They're screwing over like the PlayStation lifers, like the people who are 100 percent invested to the point that they were doing things like literally buying renewals in advance through like 2030 for the PlayStation network.
Speaker 1: I did that for Xbox Live once because there was a deal.
Speaker 0: I mean, if Steam had a monthly charge.
Speaker 1: I bought one early year to save money.
Speaker 0: If Steam had a monthly charge and that was something I had expected and like went into eyes open, like, of course, if Steam did that now, I'd burn the world down.
Speaker 0: But but if something like that happened, I would definitely be the kind of person who would buy like 50 years of it all at once just to never have to worry about it again.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, this is that, you know, on the one hand, you're like, you know, you think about it in those terms, like why are you screwing over your best customer?
Speaker 1: But also you think of it in the other terms.
Speaker 1: These are your worst company.
Speaker 1: If you're a company that sells something to a niche.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And you might think PlayStation is super popular.
Speaker 1: How is that a niche?
Speaker 1: But it's like the people who are really playing PlayStation a lot is a niche group.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Just like we always talk about how comic book companies are making like 10 variant covers.
Speaker 1: It's like the business is to milk the niche.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Squeak.
Speaker 1: You got those people who care the most.
Speaker 1: Squeeze every dollar out of those people, because if trying to trying to squeeze a little bit of dollars out of a lot of people is much more difficult.
Speaker 0: So it's even worse than that, because remember, I've gotten a lot of formal training over the last several years in modern like product management frameworks.
Speaker 0: A lot of it's nonsense.
Speaker 0: But the thing that everyone in the industry talks about are is like modern pricing strategies.
Speaker 0: And one of the primary pricing strategies is never give anyone a discount ever.
Speaker 0: And if you're going to give a discount, it's not a discount.
Speaker 0: Whenever a company offers you a discount on a subscription or something, what they're actually doing is testing you.
Speaker 0: They're trying to find out, are you the kind of person who's willing to go through a hassle to get the service and save money?
Speaker 1: Meaning like, well, that's mail in rebate.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: Mail in rebate coupons.
Speaker 0: The coupon industry is predatory in the same way, because once they discover that you're willing to put up with nonsense to get a slight discount, they know that you're probably also going to continue to pay for that.
Speaker 0: Even if there isn't a discount and they can heap trouble upon you and you'll gladly take it because you care about this service a lot.
Speaker 0: So basically, Sony in this case seems to be punishing people who went through the hassle to get discounts and they're basically making them pay back the discount they got if they want to continue using the service.
Speaker 0: And they're also saying, yeah, so if you're a lifer, fuck you, you got to pay or we're taking everything away.
Speaker 1: Well, I think the way the coupons, I always thought of coupons, you know, that this standard clipping newspaper style, you know, my grandma, my mom did that a lot back in the day.
Speaker 1: I don't know how much they do it anymore.
Speaker 1: My mom does that anymore.
Speaker 1: But the way I always thought about those was like, there are certain things that at the grocery store where you have consumable goods, right?
Speaker 1: It's not a subscription, right?
Speaker 1: Like, say, a Malamar.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, my mom likes a Malamar, but she ain't buying a full price Malamar.
Speaker 1: But if there's a Malamar coupon or a Malamar sale, then she's going to buy them.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So basically, it's like every time they make a coupon, they're creating a sale, right?
Speaker 1: It's like they're they're pushing.
Speaker 0: It's like that used to be the primary reason for products, for coupons, coupled with now they're in the store if they buy even one other thing you made out.
Speaker 1: Well, the coupons are manufacturer's coupons.
Speaker 0: Well, there's there's different kinds of coupons, of course.
Speaker 1: That's not the manufacturer's coupon, right?
Speaker 0: But the coupons also generate data on basically who has more time than money versus more money than time and also make sure that anyone who values their time more than that small amount of money doesn't get the discount.
Speaker 0: They only give the discount to the people are willing to put up with the pain in the ass of the coupon.
Speaker 0: That is a specific strategy in modern pricing.
Speaker 0: So this is sort of going further and saying, hey, anyone who used the coupon.
Speaker 0: If you want to continue to like upgrade and use the new service, you've got to pay us back for all the coupons you ever used.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, who knows, so of course, PlayStation people are flipping out and no one else even noticed.
Speaker 0: And what was really funny is the Reddit threads and all the things I found about this.
Speaker 0: Nobody really understood it until some PlayStation lifer like came in and explained what was going on, because the PlayStation ecosystem, the people who will pay for PlayStation online is definitely it is a niche in the gaming industry.
Speaker 0: It is a very specific kind of gamer for the most part.
Speaker 0: So you got any news?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So everybody knows, at least in the tabletop world, right?
Speaker 1: You know, still the hottest, the hottest thing since sliced bread is, you know, letter games and Cole Whirly.
Speaker 1: And they're they're games that have titles that are a single word that is four letters like, you know, root and fort.
Speaker 1: Well, Cole Whirly didn't do four, but letter games did and oath.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And the new game is Arcs, A-R-C-S, and they're exhausting all of the typical themes and they're now in space.
Speaker 1: And you can read all the designer diaries about this game.
Speaker 1: They're on board game geek and you can.
Speaker 1: the Kickstarter is live.
Speaker 1: I guess that's the news.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: The campaign for this game is live.
Speaker 1: And of course, it funded in two seconds.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And the core can see to the game is I didn't read all the details because it's a lot to read.
Speaker 1: Basically, it you know, it was going to be a game, you know, similar to oath and that there is sort of a statefulness to it, but a little a little shorter.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, in the in terms of sessions.
Speaker 1: But it turns out that now and I guess the version of the game that is currently being sold or at least promoted.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Who knows what else will change before it's actually released?
Speaker 1: You know, if it's the final final version or not, you know how they like to edit.
Speaker 1: But it's like if you buy the base game, all it does is play the base game.
Speaker 1: And then there's an expansion that lets you tie a sequence of like a handful of base game plays together into a campaign.
Speaker 1: So you could imagine like, you know, you buy power grid and you can play power grid.
Speaker 1: And then if you buy an expansion, it's like, OK, the expansion lets you play power grid three times in a row and carry some stuff over, you know, between the the power grids.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's tough because like we reviewed oath.
Speaker 0: I like oath, but at the same time, games that have that kind of mechanic, I have found have a rapidly diminishing return on investment unless you actually play them in that campaign style.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, I think that's, you know.
Speaker 1: If you think about RPGs, which are more tabletop RPGs, which are more typically campaign, even though that's happening less these days.
Speaker 1: You know, there's more.
Speaker 1: there's more of them that are not dependent on a campaign type setting.
Speaker 1: But it's like, you know, the ones that are designed to have a campaign.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like even if you played some good DND or, you know, you know, any place in place in the dark.
Speaker 1: It's like it's meant to be a campaign.
Speaker 1: If you just play the one session, it could be good.
Speaker 1: You could have a good one session, but a lot of the mechanics like it don't ever get used in the one session.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Free market.
Speaker 1: It's like that's a one session.
Speaker 0: You can't play one session is like, oh, because I'd say half the interesting things I can do in oath don't actually matter to the current game of oath.
Speaker 1: It's you know, it depends, right, because, you know, now we're basically you know, we had the the the role playing games.
Speaker 1: It's actually kind of interesting because you would think that you would have sort of like these two ends are at the role playing end and the board game end sort of coming together to meet in the middle.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But actually, what I've seen more is that the role playing games started out historically with more game in them and less role playing.
Speaker 0: Old DND was not about role playing.
Speaker 0: It was about getting gold out of a dungeon.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: The old tabletop RPGs were closer to war games.
Speaker 1: And they moved towards the role playing side and away from the mechanical board game side.
Speaker 1: And now the board games, which weren't even trying to be role playing in any way, shape or form, they were just board games.
Speaker 1: We're now seeing those move towards the role playing side.
Speaker 0: And I think part of what this works to towards the storytelling and away from the competitive mechanical ortho game aspects, I have noticed that there is a big audience, probably the biggest audience of role playing.
Speaker 0: People are interested in role playing just as a broad category who more open games with more social mechanics or fewer like crunchy mechanics.
Speaker 0: I think that's a bigger market.
Speaker 0: But I think there's a huge sub segment of the role playing community who, for whatever reason, either don't like to are incapable of role playing without an extreme amount of structure or they prefer to only role play around the edges of what is primarily an extremely mechanical game.
Speaker 0: And I think I've seen the board game role playing games start sliding very deeply into that niche.
Speaker 1: But yeah, but Arx definitely is going to have a lot of role playing ish type.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I hate to say it, though.
Speaker 0: I'm like, I'm interested that I'd like to try it and play it and review it, but I've only gotten a little bit of oath in.
Speaker 0: I still haven't even tapped out the fullness of root.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, you know, part of that was, you know, how many packs is?
Speaker 1: would we have gone to and played some of these games had there not been a pandemic?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: At least eight or so.
Speaker 0: We lost years of tabletop gaming here at geek nights.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And also, it's just, you know, we're not getting people together.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Because people aren't.
Speaker 1: you know, that was the reason I played Netrunner for so many years is because, you know, I talked about a lot of the other reasons.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like play a game.
Speaker 1: People know how to play.
Speaker 1: They show up and play immediately.
Speaker 1: They play quickly.
Speaker 1: They play to win.
Speaker 1: They cooperate together to try to make everyone to, you know, make everyone better at the game.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: The good community and whatnot.
Speaker 1: But just having people who want to play such that they prioritize that activity over over other activities in their life.
Speaker 1: You show up on the night to play the game and people are there.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And they want to play is important.
Speaker 0: I'm going to play Blades in the dark in an hour and a half.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: But if I'm like, you know, it's like to try to get people to come.
Speaker 0: And play oath is, you know, it's not quite pulling teeth, but it's like, oh, it's a weird problem for me because I would come over to your apartment to play like Maria or Rude or pretty much any of these other games.
Speaker 0: But I don't feel that compelled to play oath because I don't expect that we would play five games with the exact same people.
Speaker 1: Because you find five people who are dedicated and then do well.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: There are five people who live here.
Speaker 0: And I don't find the experience as engaging on literally any game I got.
Speaker 1: I got Pax Pammer, too.
Speaker 1: We could play that or any.
Speaker 1: just, you know, are you going to not ski and come play a game?
Speaker 0: Oh, no.
Speaker 0: So all those games.
Speaker 0: But the point I'm getting at is more nuanced.
Speaker 0: The games that don't have this campaign or carry over structure are way easier to get them together.
Speaker 0: I'm way more willing to prioritize them over a game like oath where I don't.
Speaker 0: even if I did get people together, I don't expect it would happen in person.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm considering it, you know, when this, you know, less pandemic ish.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I think I might attempt again to not not find a public gaming group, but like, you know, find and hand craft some, you know, possibly people who are currently strangers.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Oh, I know the people who ran the pretty good board gaming group that was in the beer hall here right before covid and then covid came and it died.
Speaker 1: But actually, I'm looking for people who are like, you know, going to approach board games the way that the people I played Netrunner with.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like they'll play games.
Speaker 1: They'll play quickly.
Speaker 1: They're coming to play as their primary goal.
Speaker 0: Oh, these these people are like that.
Speaker 0: It's a lot like when like you me and some of our packs friends sit down at the table and just immediately play a game.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I just said, you know, I'm going to try to fight.
Speaker 1: There are plenty of nerds in this area, like tons of them.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: They're out there.
Speaker 1: I just, you know, go and find these people.
Speaker 0: So, of course, the pandemic is making that hard because the one thing tabletop games, not easy to play outside, even in the best of.
Speaker 1: Well, it depends.
Speaker 1: It depends on the game.
Speaker 0: It depends almost not except card games.
Speaker 1: Hive is good outside.
Speaker 0: Hive works OK.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Toy games, card games, small games, set up a route outside under any circumstances.
Speaker 1: It depends on what the game's components are.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Play trains on an iPad outside.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I feel like I'd rather just sit inside and play trains.
Speaker 1: It's nicer to sit outside.
Speaker 0: True.
Speaker 1: What if everyone has their own iPad and we all just, you know, are lazing around in like lounge chairs on the roof playing train.
Speaker 0: Well, speaking of which, it looks like it's your turn in the train game.
Speaker 1: So anyway, we'll see.
Speaker 1: I'm podcasting right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I'm not.
Speaker 0: obviously I'm not going to kickstart this because Kickstarter is dead to me.
Speaker 0: And I encourage all of you to delete your accounts.
Speaker 0: But it's already got almost it's approaching a million dollars kickstarted.
Speaker 0: Clearly, nerds don't care about the blockchain thing.
Speaker 0: I'm able to keep using Kickstarter.
Speaker 1: Well, that's what they can't stop them.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: In some other news, that's kind of relevant to the main bit, as you'll see, at least orthogonally.
Speaker 0: So our good friend, Reggie, always well, not our good friend, like the collective, our good friend, Nintendo fans, gaming enthusiasts, good friend.
Speaker 0: Reggie always seems a pretty good person overall, tended to say the right things, tended to focus on the right things where we saw.
Speaker 1: Reggie's not perfect, but, you know, he's.
Speaker 1: he's.
Speaker 1: he's at his core, an advertising marketing guy.
Speaker 1: He was, you know, but, you know, he was.
Speaker 1: he was fun.
Speaker 1: He sort of understood the fans.
Speaker 1: A lot of his things that, you know, you would might blame him for.
Speaker 1: Are he honest?
Speaker 1: He honestly say he has like a book that came out recently.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Or something.
Speaker 1: That's why there's all these Reggie stories lately.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But it's like it's true.
Speaker 1: Basically, it's Nintendo.
Speaker 1: Japan is the way they are.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And he was doing what he.
Speaker 1: Could within those bounds.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So, well, you know what it is, I respect, though, that Reggie has a good attitude, a good personality, and, you know, he understands the fans desires, even though he can't, you know, necessarily realistically do what they want him to do.
Speaker 1: And he has fun with it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: And well, there's there's a famous quotation that's actually very relevant to this.
Speaker 0: It is possible to commit no mistakes and still lose.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And, you know, he's he's OK, you know, saying, you know, he doesn't like to say everything right.
Speaker 1: Like I would.
Speaker 1: But, you know, you know, he he says things like it is right.
Speaker 1: He's not one of those people who's just not saying anything.
Speaker 0: So what he just said that's relevant is he did not say that he supports unions like how to be clear.
Speaker 0: I don't give him more credit, but he also did not say he opposes unions.
Speaker 0: He did not say they're a good thing or a bad thing.
Speaker 0: But what he said was the gaming industry has to absolutely embrace unions right now.
Speaker 0: And there's a lot of talk about why and there's there's a whole follow up conversation, read this Kotaku article about it.
Speaker 0: But basically, they're coming whether you like it or not.
Speaker 0: The industry is evolving rapidly.
Speaker 0: They're probably necessary.
Speaker 0: And game companies that are trying to fight it or pretend it's not happening are going to lose out like they're the problem right now.
Speaker 0: Like, even if you're if you run a game company and you're a senior executive and you hate unions, you're going to if you if you if you try to fight the union, the union is going to eventually destroy you.
Speaker 0: Facts, which leads to the final news here, Raven Software, the QA workers, their union vote succeeded.
Speaker 0: They won.
Speaker 0: They had an MLB vote.
Speaker 0: It is the.
Speaker 0: it is Activision's first game developer union.
Speaker 0: Mm hmm.
Speaker 0: And Activision Blizzard is not happy about it.
Speaker 0: They've issued several, several fucked up statements about it.
Speaker 0: They're not refusing to respond to requests for comment from multiple organizations.
Speaker 0: But yeah, this is absolutely a good thing and this needs to continue.
Speaker 0: Unionization in the games industry is super important, despite Activision saying, and I quote.
Speaker 0: Decisions affecting entire studios should not be made by 19 Raven employees.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what should they maybe made by 19 extremely rich white executives who have no stake in the game?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's good for the union.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Tough, tough shit for the video game company.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day, what do you got?
Speaker 1: So this article comes from a conservative magazine, right?
Speaker 1: Even but it's not an article about politics, so I'll allow it.
Speaker 1: And it is, you know, it's this magazine called The Spectator, which is basically, you know, the way I've always seen this magazine is.
Speaker 1: it's like The New Yorker, only conservative and and from the UK.
Speaker 1: And it's super old.
Speaker 1: It's from like the eighteen hundred.
Speaker 0: So what is talking about is a site I've known about for a long time.
Speaker 0: I'm weirdly invested in it, but it's a.
Speaker 1: it's a. it's not a fake news is what I'm saying, even though it comes from a right wing source.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's more like something you would see in National Geographic.
Speaker 1: But the thing that's suspicious about it is that this is literally the every place on the Internet that's talking about this news is linking to this one article.
Speaker 1: It is the only English language source that I could find at all about this place.
Speaker 0: I've read if there's been a few news articles over the years.
Speaker 0: I feel like every four or five years, someone know those other ones were about.
Speaker 0: So I'm going to get to that.
Speaker 0: The other articles I found are basically one paragraph blurbs that basically are just someone discovering that this site exists and going, whoa, why don't more people talk about this?
Speaker 0: And that's pretty much the extent of it.
Speaker 1: Well, the very scant research that I did, right, is that.
Speaker 1: so let's just, you know, stop doing our typical feet around the bush deal, right?
Speaker 1: There is a place in the country of Turkey known as Carahan Caron Tepe.
Speaker 0: Is that?
Speaker 0: I believe you would pronounce that right.
Speaker 1: And it is basically.
Speaker 1: there is clearly an ancient village, city, civilization, place, right?
Speaker 0: Art, artifacts, lots of art with the well, well, yeah, we're still we are we are almost literally beating around the bush.
Speaker 0: What that art is, but the notable thing is conservative estimates about the age of this site place it too old to make sense, right?
Speaker 1: Like eleven thousand years old.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this place is like and that's not that's not some made up thing.
Speaker 1: It's like there was actually a human civilization capable of making art and all this stuff or could have been, you know, Neanderthal.
Speaker 1: Who knows?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Some other to put that in perspective.
Speaker 0: So forty thousand years ago, modern human like humans appeared like we are today physically.
Speaker 1: Mm hmm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's like, you know, when was Rome a few a couple thousand recently, like yesterday, right?
Speaker 0: Rome is like yesterday, Rome didn't fall until the fourteen hundreds.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So this place is like, you know, we found like skeletons that are really old, but like in terms of civilizations, it's like this is as old as it gets.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's quite a lot there.
Speaker 1: The thing is, any articles I've found about like, you know, it's like older stuff are talking about like Gobekli Tepe.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like Carahen Tepe was discovered only, I think, in twenty twenty one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that other site was more well known, but it has from what I remember it as it was there's a lot.
Speaker 0: there's been more research on that site, but that site was less well preserved and had fewer artifacts and did not have the extent that this site has.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So I don't know why there isn't more in-depth English language reporting about this site.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's because of the status of politics in Turkey and people, you know, going there and, you know, doing journalism.
Speaker 0: But I've read one one thing that has been a factor is that this is one of those rare sites that is rare enough to where there are archaeologists who argue that we shouldn't excavate too much and we should wait, assuming that excavation technology will get better.
Speaker 1: Maybe, but yeah, it was discovered by some shepherd dude and it's like, you know, it does it in terms of archaeology.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like it doesn't get better than this.
Speaker 0: I mean, this is this is at least eight thousand years older than the Minoan civilization, which is one of the oldest civilizations we even know existed.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: If you think about if you think about fantasy archaeology, not even real archaeology, fantasy archaeology in the dark.
Speaker 0: This site is older than the cataclysm.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like a fantasy archaeology like Indiana Jones is like, let's find the Ark of the Covenant.
Speaker 1: Let's find the Holy Grail.
Speaker 1: This shit is multiple times older than a Holy Grail or an Ark of the Covenant would be if those things were real.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: There could have been five Minoan civilizations that came and went in succession in the in the time between now and where this site appears to have been built by humans.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we didn't actually point.
Speaker 1: is this is significant enough that you should learn about what the hell's going on there.
Speaker 0: I think they really like penises.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, what else did they have for entertainment?
Speaker 1: It's eleven thousand years ago.
Speaker 1: This is not video games.
Speaker 1: What else did they have?
Speaker 1: They had.
Speaker 0: this is this is a you might think, oh, there's some penises.
Speaker 0: No, go read this article.
Speaker 0: There's penises.
Speaker 0: There are.
Speaker 0: OK, here's the note to the Stonehenge, one of the oldest things we know about half as old as this.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So my thing of the day, much more recent fact, it was uploaded this month.
Speaker 0: So, you know, the NES, the Nintendo Entertainment System forget special later versions and the whole Castlevania three thing, but generally it had one sound chip and it was a pretty good sound chip for its time.
Speaker 0: The NES had some really good music at two square wave channels.
Speaker 0: You had a triangle wave, you had the PCM and he had the static channel like pretty good biz.
Speaker 0: NES games got good music.
Speaker 0: And this person is a very short YouTube video.
Speaker 0: They explain how this chip works really simply, like they show all the sounds and then they point something out that a lot of people don't realize.
Speaker 0: I didn't realize this, the imperfections of that chip, not the limitations of how the audio was generated and how it could have been used by an NES, but the limitations of the specific implementation of that chip itself.
Speaker 0: So what do they do?
Speaker 0: They redesigned the chip to function identically to how the NES would have used it.
Speaker 0: But one by one, they fix all of the problems with that chip.
Speaker 0: And guess what?
Speaker 0: NES music through it just sounds better.
Speaker 1: Well, but I mean, what's?
Speaker 1: that seems kind of meh when you can think about like the Castlevania three, which just had the better sound chip.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it just had a different, better sound chip.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's more, that seems like a better idea to me.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, it is a better idea.
Speaker 0: This is more, the cool part of it is theoretically you could crack, you could put this into an emulator and have an option to hear.
Speaker 0: like, what would the sound sound like if there weren't all these artifacting errors happening?
Speaker 0: In the NES, because a lot of the music that was written for the NES didn't necessarily use those, that artifacting on purpose to achieve any particular effect.
Speaker 0: It was just a side effect of how the music was made, but it also gave the capability to make new music that actually works better with this chip.
Speaker 0: And I don't want to, like, you can watch the video, it's short and it explains in detail every single thing they did.
Speaker 0: And it starts with the stepper that's making those triangle waves, now they aren't actually triangle waves, they're kind of broken.
Speaker 0: And that's the first thing they fix.
Speaker 0: And then it just goes deeper and deeper and deeper.
Speaker 0: In the meta moment, the Geek Nights Book Club book is Ninefox Gambit.
Speaker 0: It's, I think I've said this a bunch of times, but I don't want to belabor the point, it is about violent calendars and I really enjoy it and I'm very nearly done with it.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure I'm going to be done with it by the end of this weekend, so I'd say the next Thursday episode we do, we should just do the Book Club book on it.
Speaker 0: You should start reading it.
Speaker 0: It'll probably only take you like a week to read it.
Speaker 0: It's a fast read.
Speaker 1: I mean, I read the whole thing a while ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, obviously, we have no conventions coming up.
Speaker 1: Website progress is coming along.
Speaker 1: I'm working on a feature to where, let me know out there, listener, right, what podcast player you use, because there are features in their RSS feed features and there are ID3 tag features that allow me to put chapters in podcasts.
Speaker 1: So like you could skip straight to Thing of the Day more easily, for example.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And I am going to implement.
Speaker 1: I'm going to try to implement both of those in a way that works somehow, but obviously only some things are going to support it.
Speaker 1: So, you know, I want to see how worthwhile it is.
Speaker 1: You know, we only have one listener.
Speaker 1: I got to know if that one listener doesn't use a podcast app where that will do anything, or at least if you let me know what app it is, I can research, like, you know, what that app supports and try to implement.
Speaker 0: The listener just pointed out in the chat, even Sieve only starts in 4000 B.C.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 1: Very, very apt listener.
Speaker 1: A plus that listener is probably smart and uses a high quality podcast app that will support chapters, which I should finish programming as soon as the weather is not good enough for the hockey ends.
Speaker 0: The funny thing is the weather, not great today, but hockey in the dark.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, anyway, I think that's all the matter.
Speaker 0: we got for a while about check out our discord, check out our forum, check out our live streams.
Speaker 0: The listeners just chatting here.
Speaker 0: I just said words that were fed to me via the listener.
Speaker 0: That happens occasionally.
Speaker 0: And yeah, we're online doing stuff and you'll see us doing more and more stuff as time goes on and it's nice out and we'll leave it at that.
Speaker 0: so we don't shit talk.
Speaker 0: So let's dive right into it.
Speaker 0: We've I can't believe we've never actually done a geek nights episode on this topic.
Speaker 1: We've talked about this topic so much.
Speaker 1: News is and other, you know, opening bits.
Speaker 0: We've done three separate panels that touch on aspects of this area in the past.
Speaker 0: We did one on like a panel on like how to make money making games.
Speaker 1: We're doing that geek nights thing again where we don't say what the thing is.
Speaker 1: We're talking about making money by selling games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, somehow.
Speaker 0: So I'll link to our old lectures because they cover a lot of ground here, but I think one, we can't go too, too deep on a lot of the details tonight or we'll run into hockey.
Speaker 0: And those are those are future shows.
Speaker 0: We just be cannibalizing.
Speaker 0: But two, I think we should focus on.
Speaker 0: let's not talk about the before money of how you get money to even make a game and just talk about, say, you've got a game.
Speaker 0: How the hell do you make money from it rather to recoup your costs to whatever?
Speaker 0: Just how do you make money?
Speaker 0: I'm assuming so.
Speaker 1: We live in a capitalist society, right?
Speaker 1: You need money to live.
Speaker 1: If you spend your time making a game, video game, tabletop game, role playing game, any kind of game.
Speaker 1: You spend your time on that.
Speaker 1: You might want to recoup your investment of time, resources, et cetera, in the form of money and maybe even do that well enough or enough to not have to do some other job.
Speaker 1: And that could be.
Speaker 1: your only job is do.
Speaker 1: it is converting your time and effort into games and turning those into money.
Speaker 1: And there are so many different ways to do it and they keep changing.
Speaker 1: And the laws around doing it and just the structure of our society and everything makes it like this unique situation where that that type of work does is like different from a lot of other types of work, even other types of entertainment work, like making music or making movies, even though there are some similarities.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of similarities, but the industries are structured differently in, honestly, extremely toxic ways that make gaming this perfect storm of problems because a lot of movies fail to make their money back.
Speaker 0: But there's all their revenue streams and stuff that happens like the movie industry is structured very differently.
Speaker 0: But games, even if we just talked about video games, let alone tabletop, I'd say ninety nine point nine percent of all games that ever made make do not even make back the money it took to make them.
Speaker 1: Probably not.
Speaker 0: And I struggle as a professional product manager in capital markets to figure out if it's even possible to make money from the vast majority of games.
Speaker 0: Regardless of the quality of those games, there are games that make a lot of money.
Speaker 0: They are rare.
Speaker 0: They're usually well supported and the margins are probably not even that big.
Speaker 0: There's a handful of games that have, you know, they get some sort of cult status.
Speaker 0: The algorithm promotes them and they sell way higher than anyone expected.
Speaker 0: But those are black swan events that are so rare.
Speaker 0: They're almost not worth talking about.
Speaker 0: So what do we do?
Speaker 0: What are we at a game?
Speaker 0: You Scott and I made it advanced train wars.
Speaker 0: We made some game.
Speaker 0: It's it's a video game.
Speaker 0: It can run on any platform.
Speaker 0: Let's say we are like it's already done, ready to go.
Speaker 1: What do I do?
Speaker 1: Well, the first issue is that unlike other forms of artwork, is that copyright law only partially applies, right?
Speaker 1: It's like any music or art or other sorts of things you make for the game are protected by copyright law.
Speaker 1: And so, you know, other people couldn't steal those things, at least legally.
Speaker 1: We could try to sue them if they did.
Speaker 1: But the actual rules of the game, right?
Speaker 1: We could try to patent them, I guess.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: You know, yeah, that gets into dicey.
Speaker 0: A few game companies have tried that crap over the years, but it hasn't been successful.
Speaker 1: Yeah, nobody does that.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So it's like someone could just copy our game.
Speaker 1: And this happens all the fucking time.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, how many wordles are there or how many?
Speaker 1: when threes came out, there was like 20, 48 came out like a day after.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, right.
Speaker 1: So we have to make our game in such a way that nobody out there can replicate it and do a better job quickly.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: There has to be something about our game that, like, can't be beat or can't be easily copied, you know, like there's something to it.
Speaker 0: So it's even worse in that regard because they don't even have to make.
Speaker 0: doing it better doesn't even necessarily mean making your game better.
Speaker 0: They could take your game, make it worse, market it better, sell more of it.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, so this is so if you think about games, games that are successful.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like every game that's successful is in some way has an aspect that can't just be copied and beaten.
Speaker 1: So all those FPS is out there.
Speaker 1: It's like, well, people can copy FPS is, but wait.
Speaker 1: But the ones that make money are ones that have these, you know, multiplayer communities that are, you know, carefully, you know, administered and whatnot.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like it's not easy to set that up or they're part of a franchise of single player games that people know and already like.
Speaker 1: And they think there's some sort of a story or plot or movie with cut scenes that's attached to the game.
Speaker 1: And that's all copyrighted.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And, you know, people have some attachment to that.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's a Star Wars FPS or something like that.
Speaker 1: Or, you know, some new intellectual property is attached to it.
Speaker 0: I mean, if I have like forever comes out, a lot of people would just buy it sight unseen.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, so, you know, that you need to have something like that.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, right.
Speaker 1: People aren't going to.
Speaker 1: no matter what monetization method you choose, you're no one's going to pay for the game because it's like if I just put out a really solid FPS, it's like there's a ton of really solid FPS.
Speaker 1: is mine better.
Speaker 1: Be free to have anyone to choose it if it doesn't have a thing attached to it that makes it unique, better, special, you know, not something every other FPS has.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: But that applies no matter what kind of game.
Speaker 0: So let's say we did that.
Speaker 0: Our game is unique.
Speaker 0: It is Advanced Wars 18XX something.
Speaker 0: It's unique and it's not.
Speaker 0: it's not a complete narrow niche.
Speaker 0: It's a game that we think gamers would buy enough for us to make some money.
Speaker 0: Well, now we have to think about it.
Speaker 1: So the first the first way we could try to make money is to literally sell the game, just be like, you pay us money and you we will give you the copy of this game and then you could play it all you want forever.
Speaker 1: And some people still do this.
Speaker 1: But nowadays you have to do it digitally because who's buying physical cartridges?
Speaker 0: Look, I'm so invested in gaming that I have been podcasting about gaming for like 15 years.
Speaker 0: And yet I very rarely buy new games.
Speaker 0: And when I do, I buy them in bulk for almost zero dollars.
Speaker 1: Yep, exactly.
Speaker 1: And the place someone buys them from is going to take a cut.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Is Steam takes a cut.
Speaker 1: Nintendo eShop takes a cut.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Apple App Store takes a cut.
Speaker 0: You might say, oh, I'll sell it directly.
Speaker 0: Well, one, no, you won't.
Speaker 1: And two, we know it will come to your website to buy your game and download a set up.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Hey, you want to you want to buy an exe file from me for 20 bucks?
Speaker 0: Just put your credit card into my website.
Speaker 1: PayPal me, at least that's a little safer.
Speaker 1: But yeah, so that's not happening.
Speaker 1: So the problem with this method is that a relative to your development cost, right, you're going to have to charge an amount of money.
Speaker 1: that is like no matter where you set your price point, right?
Speaker 1: If you set the price too low, you'll never have enough sales at that low price point to make enough money.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And if you set the price too high, well, you're going to further decrease sales.
Speaker 1: And it's like you'll get more per sale.
Speaker 1: But it's like that doesn't seem to be a magic number at which, you know, you will make like unless your game is a mega hit.
Speaker 0: This is where any of you got like an MBA and you think you can solve this problem.
Speaker 0: You think, you know, this concept of supply and demand because you took Econ 101 as a freshman in college.
Speaker 1: The supply is infinity here.
Speaker 1: That doesn't make sense.
Speaker 0: Well, supply and demand demand as a simplistic set of two curves is.
Speaker 0: Laughable to the point of being absurd.
Speaker 0: The only way to
Speaker 1: succeed,
Speaker 0: the most the most the most true metric is value based pricing instead, where the all the price you can charge for something is dependent solely on how much your customer values, what they will get from that thing, but what it costs you to make the thing is not part of the equation.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 1: So the way that and you can take advantage of that, the way to make money on the buy my game for a flat price deal is to make a game where the cost of development was low.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You look out there at like the vampire survivors or the spires of the world.
Speaker 1: And it's like those can make money just selling the game because they can keep going to new platforms, keep reaching more audiences, keep finding more customers.
Speaker 0: I still play this today, but they don't make any more money for me.
Speaker 0: I bought it.
Speaker 0: Well, I bought it twice.
Speaker 0: I bought it on the switch, but I digress.
Speaker 1: But they but they can keep the cash flow going because people keep finding out about the game, making the game didn't cost nearly as much as making most other game.
Speaker 0: Well, it and it turns into a long tale of revenue.
Speaker 0: Like people will just keep occasionally buying Slay the Spire for a long, long, long, long time.
Speaker 0: And you don't have to spend much money to keep that happening.
Speaker 1: I mean, it does eventually narrow down to a trickle.
Speaker 0: But then you do a release tied to a bundle with your new game that you're going to get to new game in a second, because, yeah, that's the only monetization model I'm aware of that works.
Speaker 0: That isn't evil.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, but even the the big, big triple-A titles are not succeeding with the.
Speaker 1: just buy my game and that's it.
Speaker 1: They're all doing extra stuff on top of that because it's not enough.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And the core problem is even if you did make a bunch of money on that initial, I'm just selling my game like, you know, people have done since, you know, selling NES cartridges and games for, you know, on floppy disks and whatnot.
Speaker 1: It's that you get the money once and that's it.
Speaker 1: It's like when people want to if you have a game studio, it's like you form a game studio, you make a game, you sell the game, you get money.
Speaker 1: And then it's like, all right, we pay everyone and we, you know, we pay off all our debts and everything and maybe have extra money.
Speaker 1: And it's like, do you want to keep making games?
Speaker 1: Well, that you just you only got like it was like winning the lottery lump sum.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like that's it.
Speaker 1: You want it to have a sustainable business, right?
Speaker 1: Like a grocery store.
Speaker 1: It's like cash flow is constant.
Speaker 1: It's always coming in.
Speaker 1: You can't have this.
Speaker 1: cash flow comes in once every four or five years deal.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You need constant cash flow and just only making money when you release the cash flow and release your game.
Speaker 1: And not at any other time, even if the game is successful, does not provide a steady stream of cash flow, does not provide a stable business, cannot keep food on the table for people, even if all the games are mega hits.
Speaker 0: Never mind the fact that the vast, vast crushing majority of games, no matter how good they are, will sell less than 50 copies anyway, like selling a few hundred.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: I'm saying like if you're a hit, if you're not a hit, it doesn't matter what your monetization method is.
Speaker 1: You're not a hit.
Speaker 1: It's like you didn't make any money, no matter what tricks.
Speaker 0: Everyone I know is release games on Steam, even studios.
Speaker 0: A thousand sales is like the most ludicrous dream come true.
Speaker 0: A thousand, a hundred is better than most people will ever see.
Speaker 0: The 30s to 40s run a lot of games end up seeing and that drives this even worse ecosystem where even if you pick a price, no one will pay attention to your game because there's no discoverability.
Speaker 0: Your game is in a list, unsorted among tens of thousands of other games, many of which are selling for like a dollar or are actually just free.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So you almost have to pay for marketing and people and all the things to get.
Speaker 0: people even pay attention or know that your game exists in the first place, which either drives your price up higher or takes even more of your tiny profits away or more likely just fails.
Speaker 1: Or becomes gambling.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like I go into debt to pay for ads and hopefully the ads make the game sell and then I make all my money back.
Speaker 1: So gamble.
Speaker 0: So the next possibility is that you sell the game directly, just like we said, and maybe you make some money back.
Speaker 0: You probably don't make that much.
Speaker 0: But what you really do, the most effective way to make money is to use if that was successful enough,
Speaker 1: you
Speaker 0: use that as the hype machine leading into your next game and you usually try to get an investor, a publisher, someone who's going to front money for your next game based on the success of your previous game.
Speaker 0: A lot of people make.
Speaker 0: a studio will make its first game knowing it won't sell many copies and it'll be a commercial disaster because their goal is not to make money with the first game.
Speaker 0: It is to make money with their second game by getting a publisher and using the first game to get the publisher to notice them.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You're just trying to get some, you know, and this all this stuff applies to, you know, any size of, you know, studio or whatever.
Speaker 0: It's like, I mean, this applies to a lot of industries, not just gaming.
Speaker 1: I'm a generic professional or a bunch of people.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like you.
Speaker 1: if you can get the publisher, it's like, OK, well, that takes the risk away.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like even if the second game that the publisher funded is a flop, I was still able to keep food on the table.
Speaker 1: I got this investment and I use that to feed myself while I made a game and the game failed.
Speaker 1: Maybe I now have to do something else.
Speaker 1: But I was able to live by making games for a period of time, regardless of the game succeeding or failing.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: This this the risk of whether the game succeeded or failed was taken on by the publisher and taken off of my shoulder as the game maker.
Speaker 1: So.
Speaker 0: But now you're in a relationship with a publisher, guess who gets some creative control now?
Speaker 0: Guess who starts guiding you toward how to make money?
Speaker 0: Because now you haven't actually solved your monetization problem.
Speaker 0: You've kicked that can down the road and made it someone else's problem.
Speaker 0: Now you've got a publisher.
Speaker 0: Their problem is how do I make money so I can pay these jerks, Rym and Scott back for what I owe them?
Speaker 0: and simultaneously how can I milk them so I make money?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So those are.
Speaker 1: you know, you make one game, you sell it or you try to make a series of games constantly, each one funding the next rolling over.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Maybe you get a maybe you hit a jackpot and some kind of series and you just keep making sequels forever.
Speaker 1: You can get a whole franchise going and that would be one way to go about it.
Speaker 1: The other thing, all right, the thing that people are trying to do these days is try ways that get you the constant cash flow.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Have some is one way.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: You can do it whether it's free to play or not.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: That's just the initial barrier to entry.
Speaker 1: But it's like once someone's in the game, once they're playing it, it's like, OK, we got a player.
Speaker 1: Let's try to get more money out of them.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: We got their initial monies, whether it was zero or a lot or right.
Speaker 1: But we're just going to get more monies from them.
Speaker 1: So you can sell DLCs, you can sell cosmetic bullshit, you can, you know, basically manufacture any possible thing that could make the player give you more money for more game, for more stuff in the game, gambling, you know, gambling where they always lose whatever you can come up with, whatever kind of nonsense.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And the fact is that on the from the perspective of the player, a lot of those monetization techniques, the gambling ones, the pay for things that aren't purely cosmetic.
Speaker 1: You know, most of those are like immoral.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Absolutely.
Speaker 0: Directly immoral, predatory.
Speaker 0: And what's sad is that they are the most effective way to monetize games and they are one of the only ways people successfully monetize games currently.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, on the one hand, it's like, yeah, it's immoral to do that.
Speaker 1: But if you're on the game making end, it's like, you know, sometimes you feel like that you have no choice.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: that's the only way that you can continue to do this.
Speaker 1: And people don't take the well, don't do that.
Speaker 1: That means your business isn't viable.
Speaker 1: They don't take that as an answer.
Speaker 1: The same reason we talk about conventions operating, you know, when this covid, it's like people don't take well, then your business shouldn't exist.
Speaker 1: You should go out of business as like a viable path.
Speaker 0: I hate to say this, but I think the games industry tabletop and video has hit a point where the vast majority of it is unsustainable and will collapse.
Speaker 0: Almost every studio is going to go under eventually.
Speaker 0: Almost every game designer, everything is so.
Speaker 0: it's such a weak and broken ecosystem right now.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, they're not going to collapse as long as they can continue to operate immorally.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but even then that's starting to.
Speaker 0: there's only so much blood you can get out of that stone.
Speaker 0: The economy being bad means fewer people, the people who are like fewer people gamble.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, the people who are most likely to or more people gamble because they're desperate.
Speaker 0: I'd say the people who are predated upon by a lot of these types of monetization schemes are the same people predated upon by MLM schemes and NFT scams and all that other stuff.
Speaker 0: So you're competing with scams, you're competing with scams and scammers for these people's attention, but also those people will eventually run out of money because this is a person who will not pay twenty dollars for a game, but will gladly pay four hundred dollars for the exact same game if you just sell it to sell the payment part of it to them slightly differently.
Speaker 0: Yep, like think about the terrifying implications of that statement.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, the one, I guess, morally acceptable, the main morally acceptable way to go about this right is to basically break up your game into pieces and sell them individually to sort of change the perception.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: If I have a game, you know, with twenty levels in it and I sell it to you for twenty dollars.
Speaker 1: Well, OK, you know, at least I got all my twenty dollars, even if you only played level one and then gave up.
Speaker 1: But what if I sell you five levels for twenty dollars, I might still write there might be enough there.
Speaker 1: That's like if someone was willing to pay twenty dollars and play one level and stop playing the game and I gave him twenty levels, what they would also pay twenty dollars or five levels, play one level and stop playing.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Is that I'm still right.
Speaker 1: So why would I give you know, I can give less game for the same price.
Speaker 1: And then people who do play the game and finish and if they still want more, now I can start selling levels, you know, additional content.
Speaker 0: Toby Fox actually did that with expansions for tabletop games.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: It's a fantastic model.
Speaker 0: So what Toby did is Undertale, I still to this day say it has the best score of any video game I have ever played, but it's a fantastic game.
Speaker 0: And he made the sequel Delta Room.
Speaker 0: Delta Room is going to be five chapters long.
Speaker 0: It's on the switch and all these platforms, chapters one and two, he released them just free.
Speaker 0: He released one and then he released two just totally free.
Speaker 0: But chapters three, four and five are going to cost money.
Speaker 0: Smart way to go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, you know, you just have to for this to work, your game just has to be good enough and compelling enough that someone will actually want to continue and play more.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: But that is so rare, because even if your game is good, it's very hard to even convince people to try it in the first place.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So, yes, that's another way.
Speaker 0: The most ethical way today, which was ruined by Kickstarter, unfortunately, is crowdfunding up front where you do a Kickstarter like crowdfunding campaign that functions as a preorder.
Speaker 0: If it succeeds, you got paid and you make the game for the people who wanted it.
Speaker 0: Everybody wins.
Speaker 1: And if it doesn't get funded, assuming you actually deliver the game, you don't just like fail to make the game, which you might.
Speaker 0: But let's assume you succeed.
Speaker 0: I think that is the model for the future.
Speaker 0: Unfortunately, Kickstarter as a company has fucked up so badly that I'm deleting my account and I urge you to never use them again because of their block.
Speaker 1: But there are other companies that do crowd.
Speaker 0: their companies are coming into that niche.
Speaker 1: You could just do a preorder yourself.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: The problem, the thing is, this is not necessarily perfect.
Speaker 1: So first of all, there are.
Speaker 1: Companies that are, you know, they don't they have plenty of money, right.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, Nintendo will do a preorder for, you know, like a Zelda game.
Speaker 1: But, you know, that's, you know, I guess in the digital era, that doesn't mean much anymore.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But in the cartridge era, it meant a lot because it was.
Speaker 1: it wasn't to help them make the game.
Speaker 1: The game was made.
Speaker 1: It was to help them figure out how many to ship to which game stops.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Nowadays, the preorders on, you know, big time video games don't make much sense.
Speaker 0: Well, they do because what they are is marketing and proof of demand, because, again, the primary unit of the economy of games is attention, not dollars.
Speaker 1: Yes, sure.
Speaker 1: But, you know, it's like they don't need to preorder if they have enough money to make the game and pay all their people already.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: They're already wealthy.
Speaker 1: The preorder is needed only for the small people who it's like if we want to make this game to begin with, we don't we?
Speaker 1: it's like we would have to quit our jobs.
Speaker 0: I would argue the people do preorder as a necessary part of monetization because they capture people, they make that they're making the game.
Speaker 0: They do a preorder and they always put some bonus in the preorder.
Speaker 0: that won't be for the general.
Speaker 1: Those preorders, the preorders that come from the big companies happen after the game is made.
Speaker 1: They're doing it before the game is released.
Speaker 1: But after it's made, that is not by Halo five special edition with all this garbage that happens like a week or a month before Halo is released, not five years when they start making it.
Speaker 0: So they happen way earlier in the pipeline nowadays than you'd expect for a lot of companies.
Speaker 1: Those those triple-A games take like years to make.
Speaker 1: They're not doing the special edition preorders as the day they start making the game.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But the preorders from crowdfunding for small places happen before any before like almost anything is made.
Speaker 0: That's why the model of the Kickstarter style model of it gets funded or it doesn't is probably the best way to go.
Speaker 0: But then the economy is going to be around the attention of if there's a million, million, million game people trying to kickstart, trying to crowdsource all their games.
Speaker 0: Most of them aren't going to get crowdsourced in the first place.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And also it come now, it's no longer about, you know, while that seems, you know, it seems good, the crowdfunding from the perspective of a small time place doesn't have enough.
Speaker 1: Can't get a publisher.
Speaker 1: They don't want.
Speaker 1: they want to quit their jobs.
Speaker 1: Like it all makes sense when you think about that way.
Speaker 1: But there's parts of it that don't make sense.
Speaker 1: Like, wait a minute.
Speaker 1: You know, even if I crowdfund this game, it's like I'm even if everything I've seen about the game looks good and even if they do deliver it, it's like I'm buying games sight unseen.
Speaker 1: Now I'm making my purchasing decisions not based on who makes the best game, but based on who makes the best, you know, campaign video.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And it's like there might be better games out there that you missed because the campaign videos are shitty.
Speaker 1: You're going to buy games, but I would point out it's already good campaign videos with all monetization schemes.
Speaker 0: It's already like this because you have to make a really slick pitch and get marketing crap out everywhere or no one will literally ever hear your game exists.
Speaker 1: You know, and it's like, you know, now it's like the quality of the games again is not mattering.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, if you're going to accept capitalism, you're supposed to believe in that voting with your dollars, which is voting for don't.
Speaker 1: Voting for the thing that you like the most.
Speaker 1: Voting for the thing you like the most means you have to know if you like the thing before you spend the money, not after you spend the money.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Because they spend it.
Speaker 1: You're just speculating on your.
Speaker 1: instead of gambling for money, you're gambling for entertainment.
Speaker 0: Another.
Speaker 1: I'm betting that this will be entertaining.
Speaker 0: I was wrong.
Speaker 1: Damn it.
Speaker 0: Another growing model is the Patreon style model.
Speaker 0: And there are several games that are funded this way.
Speaker 0: They have some sort of Patreon like system where you pay them a fee, like a monthly fee or annual fee or something.
Speaker 0: But you're basically.
Speaker 0: it's not like I'm paying a monthly fee to access this game.
Speaker 0: I'm paying a monthly fee to access this game and have a direct line to the creator.
Speaker 0: And these games tend to be games where content in the game changes and continually gets updated based on the whims and desires of the people who pay the most directly into that system.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: In these cases, you're not so much actually paying for a game.
Speaker 1: It's like there is a game there, but, you know, you might play it.
Speaker 1: But what you're actually paying for is like, you know, is just literally it's Patreon.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You're an artist that you appreciate their works and you are supporting them and you want to maybe a parasocial relationship with them.
Speaker 0: I was about to say that is just monetizing parasocial relationships.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You want to.
Speaker 1: you want to access their community or them or whatever.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And it's like you're paying for that.
Speaker 1: And the person the art, the person happens to produce happens to be a game.
Speaker 1: But it has.
Speaker 1: you're not monetizing the game really.
Speaker 1: You know, you're just.
Speaker 1: you're just.
Speaker 1: it's the same as other forms.
Speaker 1: You know, it wouldn't be any different as if they were a musician or a filmmaker or a photographer or whatever.
Speaker 1: You know, it just happens to be that they make games, you know.
Speaker 1: And I guess that's not the worst.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Because those are all valid ways to fund those other forms.
Speaker 0: But just like with everything else in capitalism, it leads to a patron.
Speaker 0: You know, it's called Patreon.
Speaker 0: It leads to a patron system where rich nerds are the only people who decide what kinds of games get made and how those games get made.
Speaker 0: And that's it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, this is thing is, you know, people complain all about copyright, rightly so.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of problems with the current copyright regime and copyright in general.
Speaker 1: But the copyright system that came into play right, you know, in the last couple of centuries replaced the patronage system, which was way worse.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, if you believe that someone who makes art with all of their time should be someone who deserves, you know, food, shelter, et cetera, and you don't set up socialism.
Speaker 1: so where everyone just gets those things, no matter what, as a human right, then it must follow that those people who are artists must get money somehow.
Speaker 1: And there's not really a lot of other ideas out there, video games or other medium for how those people can get money without one of these kind of shenanigans.
Speaker 0: And they're all problematic, mostly, so I can think of two more like different monetization models and we're running out of like fundamental ways you can do this other than just you're rich and you release games that you want and you don't care if anyone plays them.
Speaker 1: Well, there's the really basic one, which is subscription, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you have a World of Warcraft and it costs X a month dollars.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And it's like you can get the steady cash flow.
Speaker 1: And because now not only have you made a game, you're constantly making more game.
Speaker 1: It's a game that never ends.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And so that's your.
Speaker 1: you're delivering value to the people who are constantly paying and it's a service that you keep up.
Speaker 1: And it's like, you know, when I was a long time ago, I felt that I never did that right for any game because I was like, you know, so used to just buying a game and owning it.
Speaker 1: And also I didn't have that much money to subscribe to a video game like that.
Speaker 1: You know, the more than that cost more than Netflix costs now.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But it's actually not bad.
Speaker 0: The subscription game model, if so, if Overwatch got rid of those loot boxes for skins and it was just ten bucks a month, I would just pay ten bucks a month.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like, sure, it's it's a lot of money for, you know, most people to pay.
Speaker 0: But think about the value you get.
Speaker 0: I play Overwatch ten hours a week.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, dollar an hour for not even a dollar an hour.
Speaker 0: So ten bucks a month for 40 hours of entertainment a month.
Speaker 0: That is a crazy good deal.
Speaker 1: If your game is really good and you can deliver a player base, right, you know, to get a lot of people playing it who really care about it and it has some multiplayer online component of it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: That's, you know, especially if it's MMO, obviously.
Speaker 1: Then it's like, hey, you know, you can feed all your staff as an ongoing business with a subscription model.
Speaker 1: And it's like there's really nothing wrong with that.
Speaker 1: The only really downside is that, you know, if you can't sustain the game, you know, in the long term, eventually it's going to fade and lose popularity.
Speaker 0: It also doesn't work for games that are a one and done like I made in Advance Wars.
Speaker 0: There it is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it has to be a forever game and, you know, no game lasts forever.
Speaker 1: But it keeps people out of the game who don't have a lot of money.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Because even up even five dollars a month or like what, you know, is like kids can't be paying five dollars a month.
Speaker 1: It's like only adults are going to be with jobs are going to be able to like subscribe.
Speaker 0: The industry is going this way.
Speaker 0: This PlayStation Network and all these things and game pass increasingly.
Speaker 0: a lot of kids, their parents buy them a subscription and they just get whatever games are in that subscription.
Speaker 0: And there's the only games they get.
Speaker 0: That is the most common way parents interact with their kids in terms of video games.
Speaker 1: Now, what I mean, if you can get a game and get your game into one of those subscriptions, you get a piece of.
Speaker 1: you get a piece of the money or I don't know how to calculate it.
Speaker 1: Do they do it like royalties, like however many people play the game?
Speaker 0: Once that ecosystem scales up, I'm pretty sure it's going to be like Spotify where you don't make shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like every time someone plays, every time someone with the bundle plays your game, you get a fraction of some penny.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like so.
Speaker 0: two other ways you can go is one, the game that is designed as an e-sport and you make your money from the e-sport itself as opposed to from the game.
Speaker 1: However, I mean, that's the same.
Speaker 1: You know, that's the same as making money from merch or from any sort of ancillary things around the game.
Speaker 0: I still don't think anyone has tried like.
Speaker 0: I don't think the ecosystem is mature enough to support that fully.
Speaker 0: The attempts that have been made have mostly failed.
Speaker 0: It's not like hockey where they make their money from the fact that people are watching hockey, not for the fact that people are playing hockey directly.
Speaker 0: But we're not there.
Speaker 1: There are companies that make money from people playing hockey or hockey equipment companies, but they're not making as much money as like the NHL is.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: And the last way that is, I've seen a few small time game designers and game makers do this.
Speaker 0: They make a game, but they are themselves or they know someone who is a live streamer.
Speaker 0: The game is very entertaining to watch.
Speaker 0: or they set up an ecosystem where people basically pay for the live stream.
Speaker 0: They make their money almost entirely from the live streaming.
Speaker 0: Someone buying the game and playing it on their own is almost like a secondary effect.
Speaker 0: It's just like bonus money.
Speaker 0: But that is also rare.
Speaker 1: Usually people are paying streamers to stream their game as a form of advertising.
Speaker 1: How do you make you like if someone streams your game, you don't make money from that.
Speaker 1: You pay for that.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: So what if you have a deal with a streamer where you make a game, they stream your game, your game is uniquely entertaining in a stream and that and you share revenue with the streamer.
Speaker 1: I've never seen that small stuff.
Speaker 0: I, I strongly suspect the streamers streaming totally accurate battle simulator specifically make more money than that game has ever made in sales.
Speaker 1: What I mean, the streamers make the money, but the people who make the game are spending money on that.
Speaker 1: So the streamers are.
Speaker 1: the streamers are advertised are basically doing sponsor.
Speaker 0: I'm saying if you make a game, a way to monetize it is to also be the streamer instead of paying a streamer and the stream might make money or the stream might cause the game to make money.
Speaker 0: It basically buys you a two lottery tickets.
Speaker 0: All it costs you is doing two completely different jobs simultaneously.
Speaker 1: Well, but why would you if you're if you are if you can be a successful streamer, right?
Speaker 1: Why would you make a game for yourself to play that might get you a second revo stream?
Speaker 0: This only assumes we're in the situation you and I talked about.
Speaker 1: We already made just play games that other people have made.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: This assumes what we said at the beginning of this bit.
Speaker 0: We already made the game.
Speaker 0: How do we make money with it?
Speaker 0: How do you and I make money with the game?
Speaker 0: We start live streaming it and try to make an entertaining live stream.
Speaker 1: that that still makes no sense.
Speaker 1: If you can make a successful live stream.
Speaker 1: Why did you make a game like we are?
Speaker 1: But we probably make more money than someone else's more popular game than your own unpopular game.
Speaker 0: I'm saying we already made the game.
Speaker 0: So now we're trying to monetize it, monetize it by streaming.
Speaker 1: You're going to if you're.
Speaker 1: if your stream is not successful, you're not going to monetize.
Speaker 1: You're not going to be able to monetize your own if selling the game is not successful.
Speaker 0: You're not going to monetize selling the game.
Speaker 0: It's the same thing.
Speaker 1: If your stream is successful, you could make more money.
Speaker 1: Streaming another already popular game than you could streaming your own unpopular game.
Speaker 0: It depends.
Speaker 1: So there's no reason to stream your own game.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Like as a way to make money, except as we agreed at the start of the show, the whole premise was you already make the game.
Speaker 0: Now, how do you make money with it?
Speaker 1: Streaming your own game is not a good way to make money.
Speaker 0: How do you know?
Speaker 0: streaming probably makes more money for the people who stream than most games do?
Speaker 1: So if you already made it straight, you've already made a game, right?
Speaker 1: And you're a successful streamer.
Speaker 1: Even if you've already made the game, streaming another more popular game will make you more money streaming.
Speaker 0: Well, that's your fault for having made the game already made game.
Speaker 0: That's your fault for having made the game in the first place.
Speaker 1: You can't.
Speaker 1: streaming is not a way to monetize a game you have made.
Speaker 0: It's a way to I think it absolutely is getting paid for the stream.
Speaker 0: I think there's more money there, but I think the use for this now in the current ecosystem would be specifically the fairly rare situation of you've made a game.
Speaker 0: It wasn't successful.
Speaker 0: You don't want to pay some other streamer to stream it.
Speaker 0: You start streaming your own game or you do a revenue sharing with the stream.
Speaker 1: That's not good.
Speaker 1: That makes no sense, because if you are if you are capable of of making a popular stream, even if you've already made an unpopular game, you will make more money streaming on another someone else's popular game, not necessarily the ecosystem in your own game.
Speaker 1: That ecosystem is going to make your stream unpopular.
Speaker 0: Generally, the ecosystems of the people who stream big games is a very small number of streamers who make all the money and nobody else makes anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so but people who stream unpopular games, there's nobody who's popular, right?
Speaker 1: You have to stream a popular game to have any chance and to begin with, not necessarily if you're a popular streamer, actually, even the popular streamers, if you watch their streams, as soon as they switch like a sponsored game, the views drop to nothing.
Speaker 1: Well, if you are capable of being a popular streamer and you try to give yourself free sponsored slots to your own game, everyone will stop watching you immediately when you switch to the game that you made.
Speaker 0: I mean, you say that, but I still think it's a monetization model.
Speaker 0: that's possible because like we said, the assumption was it's not monetizing the game.
Speaker 1: You're just being a streamer who happens to have made a game and you will make more money just being a streamer if you're a good.
Speaker 0: Well, like I said, that's your fault for having made the game in the first place.
Speaker 1: That's you're making no sense anyway.
Speaker 1: It's time.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows, SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of Geek Nights are.
Speaker 0: Ellen Joyce, Linky G, Dred Lilly, Tenebrae, a bunch of people who really don't want me to say their names, Krista Dodd, Chris Reimer, Clinton Walton, Dex Fink, Shia 85, Rebecca Dunn, Review, Madbull, 34, Cowards, Sam Erickson, Sherwin Von Horrell, Stop All the Downloading, Taylor Braun.
Speaker 0: The next station is St.
Speaker 0: George, St.
Speaker 0: George Station and several people whose names I will not say.
Speaker 0: I don't know what else can be said about the horrific school shooting that seems to have happened today.
Speaker 0: that is separate from the other two shootings that just happened.
Speaker 0: So I don't know what to say other than disown your Republican relatives.
Speaker 0: And I leave you simply with.
Speaker 1: these kids weren't unlucky.
Speaker 1: This only happens in this country.
Speaker 1: And nowhere else, nowhere else do little kids go to school thinking that they might be shot that day.
Speaker 1: Nowhere else do parents have to talk to their kids, as I have had to do, about why they got locked into a bathroom and told to be quiet for five minutes just in case a bad man entered that building.
Speaker 1: Nowhere else does that happen except here in the United States of America.
Speaker 1: And it is a choice.
Speaker 1: It is our choice to let it continue.
Speaker 0: What are we doing?