Speaker 1: It's Thursday, June 1st, 2023.
Speaker 1: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is the Geek Nights Book Club.
Speaker 1: Tonight, we are talking about Sam and Rushdie's The Satanic Versus.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're gonna do this show a couple weeks ago, but of course I got sick, so here we are.
Speaker 0: I was actually, I'm still like 5% sick maybe.
Speaker 0: It was only like a two day sickness.
Speaker 0: I am only.
Speaker 0: I took it yesterday off work and that was it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I took a whole week off work for that cold.
Speaker 1: Well, that sinus infection.
Speaker 1: It was not a cold, it was bacterial.
Speaker 1: But that sucked.
Speaker 1: So luckily, I took some notes so I'd remember to talk about the specific things.
Speaker 1: I really got stuck in my craw reading this book.
Speaker 1: But I want to be very clear that one thing we're not going to do in this episode is get into much of the sociopolitical situation around this book.
Speaker 1: One, because we're not experts in it.
Speaker 1: Two, because that would be longer than the book club episode.
Speaker 1: And three, because at least for me, in my opinion, I really want to engage with the novel as a novel with one exception.
Speaker 1: Maybe two, but the exception that really stood out to me is I always assumed and knew that this book, because of the portrayal of Muhammad and the ladies and the situation.
Speaker 0: Muhammad's not in this book, just a guy named Mahoud.
Speaker 1: Apparently in many translations, it's even more ambiguous.
Speaker 1: He's just referred to as "the messenger" and that's it.
Speaker 0: That seems less ambiguous, but okay.
Speaker 1: But I guess I always sort of knew from learning history that that was the driver of this specific fatwa.
Speaker 1: But what no one told me, and I never knew until I got to a certain part later in the book, when a certain Imam appears,
Speaker 0: and that
Speaker 1: is definitely just a parody of Khomeini, and I'm pretty sure Khomeini was specifically personally mad about that, and that was probably the impetus for him more so than this over other books that transgressed to a similar degree at the time.
Speaker 1: I feel like that was a bigger part of that situation than what I learned in high school led me to believe.
Speaker 0: Well, it could be.
Speaker 0: The way I saw it is that if I was a religious fundamentalist, the part that really believed, the part of this book that would make me the most mad, at least I'm guessing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because I can think of a few parts.
Speaker 0: Right, but the part that I think might make such a person the most angry was the part where it was like, at first, Mahoud was getting messages from the angel Gabriel.
Speaker 0: But then, he was just sort of, you know, anytime he wanted something, right?
Speaker 0: Saying, you know, be like, do what I say, why should we do what you say?
Speaker 0: Close my eyes.
Speaker 0: Gabriel just told me to, now do it, right?
Speaker 0: It's like there's that whole part where it's like just obviously portraying the prophet as just a liar who's making shit up to get his way.
Speaker 1: With, of course, we'll get into the allegory of, was it the other way around?
Speaker 1: And it was the modern person using this internal metaphor of their idea of Muhammad to process their own traumas and interactions.
Speaker 1: But anyway, the other part that I could see was the specific nature of the fact that it was Indian Muslims portrayed primarily in the book, in the primary story, because that is where the original riots occurred and the fatwa came after that.
Speaker 1: And it made, like, the cross-cultural part of that actually led to significant amounts of that anger early, because it intersected with an already persecuted in a different way from other Islamic communities situation, so there was a lot more going on there.
Speaker 1: And until I read this book, I didn't actually know that it was about Indian Muslims, as opposed, like, I didn't know that.
Speaker 1: I just knew very broad strokes about the story.
Speaker 0: I knew nothing about the content of the actual novel till I read it.
Speaker 0: I knew.
Speaker 0: I mean, I knew.
Speaker 0: I was like, when I was reading the first chapter, I was like, what the fuck is going on?
Speaker 0: And then eventually you realize what's going on, like, oh, it's a hijacking, like about, you know, pages in.
Speaker 1: And that is definitely, talk about, of all the, you know, there's some books you read where there's, like, a slow build up and then you're like, okay, I see where this book is going.
Speaker 1: But some books just come in and hit you over the head with a hammer of like, what the fuck's going on?
Speaker 1: Bam, bam, bam, bam.
Speaker 1: And then you get through a chapter or two and then you're like, oh, okay, I see what's going on.
Speaker 1: I see where we are.
Speaker 0: And I kind of like, it sort of starts like you're on a plane with these two dudes.
Speaker 0: And it's like, you understand that these two dudes knew each other from somewhere and are on the plane and together and it's sort of murky, right?
Speaker 0: And then it's like, usually you expect like a novel wants to grab people on the first page, right?
Speaker 0: That's what they always tell you to do.
Speaker 1: And it did grab me, but not in the normal way.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But it's like, you know, it's not until several pages in where it's like the clouds begin to clear and it's like, it's a hijacking and they're going to die immediately.
Speaker 1: And also the way that opening scene was written just really struck me as that's where, that's where I recognize too, because I'd never read any of Simon Rushdie's works other than a couple of essays and short articles and interviews.
Speaker 0: If I have, I don't remember this.
Speaker 0: So as far as I know, this is the only thing I've written.
Speaker 1: So I guess I didn't expect just not knowing the sheer amount of poetry and like the way the writing was.
Speaker 1: So it almost felt like, wait, there's some guys on a plane and then poetry exploded the plane.
Speaker 1: Like it felt like poems came in and things exploded.
Speaker 1: And I, it took me a while to figure out that wasn't an allegory or a metaphor, at least in that context.
Speaker 0: Or was it?
Speaker 1: Well, I would say reading it at first, like, wait, is this an allegory?
Speaker 1: Followed by, no, this is literally happening.
Speaker 1: Followed by, wait, this, this is an allegory by multiple steps.
Speaker 1: Followed like in the first chapter to the first chapter with, oh, so now they just fell to the ground and they're in London.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So I don't know if there's like some actual, like if I would talk to like a literature professor and they would actually be able to define what the difference is between like fantasy and magical realism or any of those sorts of,
Speaker 1: Wikipedia says this is in the genre of magical realism straight up
Speaker 0: for whatever.
Speaker 0: So it's like, you know, it takes place in the eighties, at least the main plot takes place in the eighties.
Speaker 0: But there are also dream sequences which take place in the past world.
Speaker 1: One feels like it's in the seventies, like the one with the Amman, I'd say.
Speaker 1: One feels like it takes place in a vague period.
Speaker 1: One is definitely like the founding of Islam.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And a few of them take place, like in the different places on earth at the same time.
Speaker 1: Well, the one with the Boyarder, the one with the, the South American Nazi and that whole situation, like that era.
Speaker 0: The pilgrimage takes place at the same time as the, yeah.
Speaker 0: But it's like, you know, you can in a lot of books with that have dream sequences and things like that, you might be questioning like what's real, what's not real, or at least nothing's real.
Speaker 0: It's all a work of fiction.
Speaker 0: But like, you know, but it's like within the world of the fiction, what's real and what's not real.
Speaker 0: And the thing is, it's like the whole thing could be not real if they died in the plane crash, which they could have.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like it could all be so great.
Speaker 1: And this is a credit to Sam and Rushdie.
Speaker 1: Gabriel considers that that is a possibility at multiple points in this book.
Speaker 1: Like he thinks to himself, like, did I die?
Speaker 1: Is it?
Speaker 1: I think Saladin actually does, too, when he's turning into a goat in that scene.
Speaker 1: I remember there's a moment where he's like, this is too absurd.
Speaker 1: I must have just died in that plane crash.
Speaker 1: And this is just like, maybe I'm in the hospital.
Speaker 1: That's got to be it.
Speaker 1: I'm in the hospital.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So these two dudes die in a plane crash.
Speaker 0: Who were these two dudes?
Speaker 0: He got Chamsha.
Speaker 0: Chamsha Saladin.
Speaker 0: He's a guy who is a voice actor.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And he's from India.
Speaker 1: We'll get back to that.
Speaker 1: The fact that he's a voice actor is like super, super important to what this book is about.
Speaker 0: He's a super talented voice actor from India.
Speaker 0: But he's one of those people who, you know, is an immigrant who is, I guess, you know, I guess in modern day, you would consider him like a London weeb.
Speaker 0: Is there a word for that?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like, I think of.
Speaker 0: like, you know, the white dudes who go to Japan.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And are like, you know, all in on Japan.
Speaker 0: Japan is the best.
Speaker 1: And they shun their original place they came from.
Speaker 1: If this book were set today, he would be wearing a t-shirt with like a picture of Queen Victoria on it, unironically.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Or like what's the, you know, keep calm, whatever.
Speaker 1: This is the kind of person who would like follow gossip of the royal family and like driving Austin Powers car.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like he's that right.
Speaker 0: So it's like, you know, even though he's from India, it's like he changed his name to be less, you know, ethnic, I guess whatever word you want to use.
Speaker 1: But also in a way more ethnic in that he almost makes it like more the stereotype of what people would expect, which fit with it.
Speaker 1: There's a lot going on there.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And then so you got give real.
Speaker 0: now give real is sort of like, you know, he's.
Speaker 0: he's also an actor.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But he's an actor in India, a movie actor.
Speaker 0: He appears on screen.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Not just a movie actor.
Speaker 1: He is like the biggest actor at the time, like he is in Indian cinema, the most important and famous person.
Speaker 1: And to the fact that even globally, he's well known.
Speaker 0: But he's always in movies.
Speaker 0: He's always portraying like gods and heroes and legendary figures.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And, you know, he is not even though he's, you know, is a worldly person.
Speaker 0: He is the opposite in that he has not thrown away his Indian ness.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But he's very not conservative.
Speaker 0: Like he's getting with all the ladies and being all, you know, Hollywood style.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So you got these two guys and they're on a plane, which is hijacked and basically one of them metaphorically, allegorically and literally becomes an angel.
Speaker 1: And one of them becomes a demon, though there's a little bit of a an indication that they flipped at some point like that.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So that's the thing is like you look at both of them and it's like.
Speaker 0: it's not clearly like, you know, if you just look at these characters, there isn't a clear like, you know, good guy, bad guy deal the way there might be in like, you know, an anime where it's like, ah, yes.
Speaker 0: You know, the Gundam pilot is good and char is bad.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like, I mean, it's not like.
Speaker 1: in a lot of ways they're both kind of bad with a big asterisk there in that they both do a lot of shitty things.
Speaker 1: But the angel actually does more shitty things.
Speaker 1: I would say like his crimes are arguably greater.
Speaker 0: It's it's tough to say.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But, yeah, they have each have, you know, positive and also, you know, they have aspects that you can look at as laudable and aspects that you can look at is not so laudable.
Speaker 0: And, you know, the first thing that tips you off to who's good, who's bad is after they crash and they might be dead.
Speaker 0: But that doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: They're they're alive somehow.
Speaker 0: Only them to no one else on the plane.
Speaker 0: You don't hear anything about anyone else who is on that plane.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And there they get rescued on some island or on a beach or something by some old lady on a beach in the English coast somewhere.
Speaker 1: And that is the whole thing.
Speaker 0: But a very depopulated place.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But basically the cops come.
Speaker 0: And the cops, when they arrive, arrest Chamcha for like being an illegal immigrant.
Speaker 1: And they totally ignore Gabriel.
Speaker 1: There's no difference between them except.
Speaker 1: And this is where the allegory and like the way this is portrayed gets murky and interesting and interwoven.
Speaker 1: Because on one hand, Gabriel's glowing in the book and has like almost a halo and Saladin is starting to grow horns.
Speaker 1: So that's that is happening from the magical literally happening.
Speaker 1: But and his breath became sulfurous.
Speaker 1: that like that is the thing as well.
Speaker 1: But simultaneously, if you treat that as pure allegory, you've got.
Speaker 1: Gabriel happens to go into the wardrobe of this woman's house and put on like an English smoking jacket.
Speaker 1: And Chamcha is too sick and doesn't get up right away.
Speaker 1: So when the cops come, they see two strangers who are clearly not white people.
Speaker 1: And the only difference between them is one of them looks like he should be there to their biased eyes and one of them doesn't.
Speaker 1: So they arrest the one who's not wearing an English smoking jacket.
Speaker 0: And Gabriel does nothing to speak up and save.
Speaker 0: He just stands there.
Speaker 0: He just lets the police take him.
Speaker 0: And then as a result, Chamcha suffers greatly and now hates Gabriel a lot.
Speaker 1: Tries to kill him several times.
Speaker 0: He's like, fuck that guy.
Speaker 0: He just let me get arrested.
Speaker 0: And I had to suffer with the cops being pieces of shit and everything.
Speaker 1: And it's very clear, like if anyone's missing the super obvious lit crit like analysis conversation here that a reading of this scene and this this reading is throughout the entire book.
Speaker 1: But this seems such a good example of it.
Speaker 1: It is very clearly because think about it.
Speaker 1: The voice actor gets arrested.
Speaker 1: The movie star doesn't, which also leads to who passes more in the dominant culture of the place they've immigrated to.
Speaker 1: And thus they're treated very differently.
Speaker 0: And Chamcha is more of a person, you know, he's a person like, you know, of London in every way.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, he loves, you know, he loves London food.
Speaker 0: Like his spirit.
Speaker 1: He is more a Londoner than a lot of English people by birth.
Speaker 1: Yet he looks more foreign to the white people, which ties back to the fact that there's a reason he was only ever allowed to be a voice actor.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile, Gabriel passes effectively more appearance wise, yet he is much less of that spiritually and personally.
Speaker 1: Like he's, well, he's got a whole other thing going on.
Speaker 1: It's not like they're opposites.
Speaker 1: Gabriel's a little more insane as a character than Chamcha.
Speaker 0: He gets more insane and less insane at different times.
Speaker 0: But he's, you know, he's definitely lost it.
Speaker 0: He's lost the plot.
Speaker 1: But the way they're written is also just fantastic.
Speaker 1: Like their dialogue and like Chamcha, it's interesting how Chamcha is almost the more level headed one most of the time.
Speaker 1: Like in the police car and a lot of scenes when weird stuff's happening, he is almost always like, wait, is this really happening or am I going crazy?
Speaker 1: What's going on?
Speaker 1: Gabriel definitely just rolls with it more before he has that revelation.
Speaker 1: And that happens repeatedly.
Speaker 1: Like he's less connected to humanity as a character than Chamcha is.
Speaker 0: Alright, so these two main characters and their plot is like driving the rest of the story.
Speaker 0: It's like the thread that's holding everything else together.
Speaker 0: But there's basically several other smaller novels that are all linked in some way to them, a little bit at least.
Speaker 0: And it's this huge book, I guess not huge, but it's larger than most.
Speaker 0: It's not like a war and peace deal.
Speaker 0: We finished it.
Speaker 0: It was easier to read than Tale of Genji.
Speaker 1: Honestly, I blew through it just because it was compelling.
Speaker 1: Like it was a good read.
Speaker 0: Yeah, by several orders of magnitude.
Speaker 0: But it's not one of those books where he's got one thing to say.
Speaker 0: He's got several things to say and he just managed to orchestrate and get all these pieces to fit together into one cohesive puzzle.
Speaker 1: And it worked because sometimes you're reading a book.
Speaker 1: The Princeton Nothing books did this to me a few times, but it's pretty common in books where a novel has a bunch of different threads that may or may not be super interconnected.
Speaker 1: And you get really invested in one and then it jumps to another one.
Speaker 1: you don't care about that much.
Speaker 1: You're like, "Ah,
Speaker 1: shit.".
Speaker 1: You're like almost slogging through it to get back to the good part.
Speaker 1: But this one, every time it jumped to a different perspective, it pulled me right along with it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't think there was any of them that I cared more or less about.
Speaker 0: There wasn't like, "Oh, this is the good one and the other ones I don't care
Speaker 0: about.".
Speaker 0: That part.
Speaker 1: The Jahilius story, like the first dreams, that was the one that I found the most compelling partly because I'm interested in...
Speaker 0: Well, that's the part about the literal title of the book, the Satanic Verses, right?
Speaker 0: So for that reason, that was the most, you know...
Speaker 1: Well, also because that one, another way to look at those dreams, because there's like four of them... Four or five, depending on how you count, because some of them are short or not necessarily... Anyway.
Speaker 1: I'd say that they're all echoes of each other because it's almost the same type of story in the dreams happening over and over again, but in a different era with a different context.
Speaker 1: But it's the same human lens of the players in the story, like rationalizing the decisions they're making.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, you have these separate stories that are somehow tied together either because Gabriel's dreaming them or because they're actually taking place in the same world and there's some minor linkage or, you know, whatever reason.
Speaker 0: But they all have characters that line up with each other, right?
Speaker 0: The biggest one is the three or four Aishas.
Speaker 0: It feels like almost every one of the different stories has an Aisha in it, right?
Speaker 0: And it's like, you know, the same way that like you might read, you know, a normal novel and it's like, ah, this person in the novel is representing Jesus, even though... Right?
Speaker 0: And it's like, you know, it's allegory in that sense, whereas in here, rather than... They do have the external, you know, references like, ah, my hound is Mohammed, but they also have internal ones where it's like, we'll make a character and we'll make another character, right?
Speaker 1: Well, like Hind, the Sultan's wife from Jahalia.
Speaker 1: And then you've got Hind in London.
Speaker 1: And those two characters are not the same, but there's a bunch of echoes between the two of them.
Speaker 1: Like they're tied narratively, but not directly.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And it's not always so blatant with the same name characters, right?
Speaker 0: Because you've got the angel Gabriel, right?
Speaker 0: You've got Gabriel with a similar name, right?
Speaker 0: But Gabriel is, you know, having these wild dreams and it's sort of like he's receiving.
Speaker 0: that, you know, by dreaming, he is receiving, you know, I guess, prophecy in these dreams.
Speaker 1: And that's what he's talking about.
Speaker 0: The same way that, yeah, because the only thing, you know, I didn't, I still don't know much about the Quran, right?
Speaker 0: But I tried to do at least some research, right?
Speaker 0: And the main key thing to know, you know, I think possibly the only thing you really need to know about the Quran to understand this book is that, you know, I'm a Jew, so I know about the Old Testament, right?
Speaker 0: The five books of Moses.
Speaker 0: Why are they called the five books of Moses?
Speaker 0: Because supposedly, obviously not truly, but supposedly Moses walking through the fucking desert, right?
Speaker 0: After he freed the people from Egypt and God was like, yo, Moses, write this shit down, right?
Speaker 0: And so Moses wrote five books down, right?
Speaker 0: And so the Quran is supposedly.
Speaker 0: there was a dude named Mohammed and the angel Gabriel was like, yo, Mohammed, write this down, right?
Speaker 0: And that what he wrote down was the Quran.
Speaker 0: So in the book, you have my hound receiving prophecy from Gabriel and not writing it down.
Speaker 0: Someone else wrote it down for him because he couldn't write.
Speaker 0: And you've got Gabriel receiving dreams, right, from who knows where, right?
Speaker 0: And you've got, was it one of the Aishas, right, is receiving, you know, prophecy that tells her to go walk into the water.
Speaker 0: Yeah, definitely.
Speaker 1: It is very clear that nobody actually made it through that water.
Speaker 0: Yeah, obviously.
Speaker 1: But when those dreams are happening, and this is where, because not to compare this to all the nerdy stuff we often talk about, but like one of the things we always praised utenna as an anime for was that it weren't like if you take the allegory at any level or
Speaker 0: decide
Speaker 1: which parts to follow, they're still very self-consistent and still tell the same story a different way.
Speaker 1: And that happens here, too, because one reading of those dreams in prophecy is literally the Mohammed or my hound received prophecy from the angel Gabriel as manifested in the future.
Speaker 1: And you could have a time thing like the future affects the past or the past affects the future because it could be the other way around.
Speaker 1: Modern Gabriel is receiving these dreams from the past in some magical way, but in those sequences repeatedly Gabriel keeps like almost noting that he has no power over it and whoever he's receiving the dream from kind of takes control and speaks the words they want to hear into him and they come back out of him.
Speaker 1: Which could imply more that it's two different people in two different eras who are speaking to a non-existent internal angel to rationalize the decisions they were going to make anyway.
Speaker 1: Because there's multiple points where someone says, oh, and like right back to the beginning, the satanic verses, oh, well, God, the angel told me this, but Satan told me that.
Speaker 1: And even in that scene, I think Gabriel says something to the reader.
Speaker 1: I just remember this line because I made a note about it, something to the effect of, but it was me both times.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Well, OK, so we got to get to that.
Speaker 0: So first of all, this book has some unnamed narrator who is a character.
Speaker 1: I would argue on one level.
Speaker 1: that unnamed narrator I thought was the base internal monologue of all humans that people interpret as divine.
Speaker 1: But I also wondered if that was if it's more magical, the actual Angel Gabriel who has been inserting himself or itself into these characters along the way.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: That's what makes it, you know, the kind of book that I like is that, you know, I've been ranting about this constantly over the past year or few.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Is that there are some works of fiction across all mediums.
Speaker 0: And especially today, the popular ones, the serials on television, especially where they're all about the only question they ask of the audience is what happens next?
Speaker 0: And then they answer it.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And then there's no questioning.
Speaker 0: So I think, you know, a good example would be like those who's the guy who makes the movies, like the who's the guy who said the Inception, the Inception movie guy and the.
Speaker 0: Oh, did you also do Interstellar?
Speaker 0: Same guy.
Speaker 1: Nolan and all them.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to think.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So his he creates this wild thing.
Speaker 1: There's no allegory there.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: And then he at the end of the movie, he basically explains it.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: He's like.
Speaker 0: he's like, you know, it's like, sure, at the end of Inception, spoilers.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like they cut away before the top stops spinning.
Speaker 0: If it does.
Speaker 1: I would argue and I'm going to say something mean a lot of people mistake not answering that question for being deep.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But that's not to me.
Speaker 0: That's not challenging to the audience.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like because you're not asking any other questions, not asking questions about life or meaning or right.
Speaker 0: It's like you don't walk out of there, you know, seeing those movies like, you know, like thinking like questioning existence.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But you look at, you know, easy.
Speaker 0: You know, we did it 2001 already as a book club.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like, what's the end of 2001?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, you could like you could try to explain a little bit like, OK, so the aliens took him and kept him somewhere or something.
Speaker 1: But something.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But it's like, what does it mean?
Speaker 0: It's like it's challenge.
Speaker 0: It's not ask you what happened or what happens next.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's challenging.
Speaker 0: You're you're philosophically right.
Speaker 0: You know what you believe about the short life that you are going to live on this earth.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And you have to answer it for yourself.
Speaker 0: They don't tell you what the answer is.
Speaker 1: And even to get back to Inception example, say you try to scratch the surface and dig deeper and ask questions, even if the movie or the work didn't necessarily compel you to.
Speaker 1: If you go deep on, say, Inception, you'll exhaust all your possibilities and lay out a fairly simple map of ideas and stories.
Speaker 1: But even now, like thinking about this book and reading it, if you keep trying to line up allegories and like explain things, you can basically go infinitely deep because every angle asks more questions and ties back to other things you read and radically, diametrically opposed literary interpretations of parts of this book make perfect, consistent sense next to each other in the same story.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: That is one thing right now.
Speaker 0: It's one thing to be so abstract.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: That it's like you put up like a Mondrian where it's like, I guess, Mondrian is still pretty good.
Speaker 0: I like him a lot.
Speaker 0: But it's like, you know, you put like a dot on you on a painting and it's like up to people to interpret the dot.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like you barely you know, it's like it's so wide open.
Speaker 0: What did you really craft?
Speaker 1: First, I do remember we were at the MoMA once and we were, you and me, this was years ago, and there was a big white wall and there was a little plaque at the bottom.
Speaker 1: We walk over to it and the plaque said this wall was shot with a pellet on this date at this time.
Speaker 1: We stood there for a while looking at the wall, debating whether or not it was really shot and trying to find the bullet hole.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: But, you know, think about like a Picasso, right, where it's still abstract.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But there is still so much there.
Speaker 0: It's not like.
Speaker 0: they're just, you know, lazily making some open ended thing and being like, haha, it's challenging you.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like, no, it really is.
Speaker 1: Well, it grounds you.
Speaker 1: The challenge and the literary discussion and the introspection are grounded in very specific literary notes, specific facts, specific framing to point you in a direction of inquiry instead of just having an open, like, you know, a completely open inquiry piece of art is almost not materially deeper than a zero inquiry art.
Speaker 1: The magic is art that guides you into deep inquiry with the fewest pieces necessary to do so.
Speaker 0: And so we have this mysterious, you know, narrator.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Who they do.
Speaker 0: You would almost any book, any book written today would at the end of the book reveal with no doubt who that narrator is.
Speaker 1: And then Kaiser, so they walked away.
Speaker 0: I was 90 percent.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, I was expecting right.
Speaker 0: Half expecting, I guess, because like, you know, was that at the end of the book, that narrator was going to come in and close it off.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And that narrator basically stops coming in like two thirds of the way through.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I mean, they're still narrating.
Speaker 0: But earlier in the book, there are times where the narrator breaks the fourth wall.
Speaker 1: Oh, he's talking to you directly.
Speaker 1: And he's right.
Speaker 0: He basically talks about themselves.
Speaker 1: Where do you see what's about to fucking happen?
Speaker 1: Like he's right.
Speaker 0: And that's the character.
Speaker 0: The narrator is the character who says it was me both times.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And there's another important scene.
Speaker 0: The only time where the the narrator actually appears like in and meets was he meets Gabriel.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: He's like on a better.
Speaker 0: So I forget the details.
Speaker 0: But Gabriel walks in a room and he's there and it might have been challenged to the walks in the room.
Speaker 0: One of the two characters walks into a room.
Speaker 1: I want to point out that it is not that we're just forgetful because I know like, Scott, you have a reputation for forgetting the names of characters and I'm not great about it either.
Speaker 1: Like, to be fair.
Speaker 1: But in this case, the duality and the sort of flipping of roles is so integral to this book that it is very easy to forget which character did what because the book is doing that on purpose.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But anyway, one of the main characters, I should look up which one.
Speaker 0: It's important.
Speaker 0: Like one of the most important scenes, even though it's so short.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like such like this ridiculously significant, important scene in the book is like as like a page or two.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: They go in the room and the dude is there.
Speaker 0: who's the narrator.
Speaker 0: Clearly.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You could just tell somehow with even though it didn't say so.
Speaker 0: And he's like the narrator is trying to like, you know, tell whoever it is, you know, something.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like influence them.
Speaker 0: And he's being challenged.
Speaker 0: He's basically being asked, like, are you are you God or are you Satan?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like the character knows.
Speaker 0: He's like, which one are you?
Speaker 0: And he's just sort of like laughs at him.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like, well, you don't know which one I am, bro.
Speaker 1: So right.
Speaker 0: And my interpretation, my friend is another part where the narrator comes back and talks to the reader and is like, well, that did do didn't know which one I was.
Speaker 0: If I was if I was one of them at all to be, you know, either one, I could have been something, you know, that's right.
Speaker 1: It's like, and knowing that this book is partly widely interpreted to be an interrogation of salmon, Russia's own life and struggles with living between cultures.
Speaker 1: I'd say that two strong interpretations are that, well, three, if you want to go a fully mystical route, interpretation number one, it is God, but God isn't good or evil.
Speaker 1: And it's a coin flipping in the wind.
Speaker 1: Like both of them are God and Satan at the same time.
Speaker 0: Actual Angel Gabriel works, too.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Satan works.
Speaker 1: I think a compelling one is that that is a stand in for the concept of human consciousness.
Speaker 1: All humans.
Speaker 1: But I want to really elaborate on it.
Speaker 1: All humans have this sort of.
Speaker 1: what our consciousness is, is something that we can only interrogate through ourselves.
Speaker 1: And I think this work explores that very well, because it is very much.
Speaker 1: there's a common thread of characters asking themselves questions and making decisions or often doing something with no introspection, like when some murders happen and there's a bunch of scenes along the way.
Speaker 1: Or even in the beginning, when Gabriel just doesn't do anything, which I'm just getting arrested, he doesn't think about not doing anything.
Speaker 1: The act almost happens like it was predetermined.
Speaker 1: And then he starts talking to himself or becoming the angel or something, almost just to rationalize and explain why he did what he did.
Speaker 1: Which is a lot that meant pretty well to how human consciousness works.
Speaker 1: And it would fit the idea that my hound was.
Speaker 1: it was my hound all along.
Speaker 1: Every character is themself all along.
Speaker 0: And we know we know for a fact that baseball players swing the bat before they can see.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: And thus, that character is the innate consciousness that is inside of all humans, because we're all interrogating and interpreting the world through the same flawed shared lens.
Speaker 1: But a third interpretation, and I was poking around, the third one that I got a hundred for is that that is Sam and Rushdie himself.
Speaker 0: Could be.
Speaker 0: That's a good one.
Speaker 1: Who is God, if in terms of writing the book.
Speaker 1: And based on what I've read about Sam and Rushdie, that really does feel like the kind of thing he would have done, but would never admit to.
Speaker 0: So maybe.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So we got to talk about the title of the books, the satanic verses.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So it's like, what the hell are the satanic verses?
Speaker 0: I didn't know this until I read the book and I looked it up.
Speaker 1: And it's almost every religion that has a book has a concept of these apocryphal.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So here's the deal.
Speaker 0: Forget the book for a second.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: In Earth.
Speaker 0: Supposedly.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Mohammed went to Mecca, the place geographically with his with his clan of tribe of peoples.
Speaker 0: The earliest Islamic peoples.
Speaker 0: And in Mecca, there were these other tribes there, too.
Speaker 0: They were already there.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And those other tribes had other gods.
Speaker 0: They were worshipping.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: What were their names?
Speaker 0: There were.
Speaker 0: there were a lot of like, you know, female gods or goddesses.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And basically, like they at first they were kind of chill with Mohammed's people coming to live there.
Speaker 0: Until Mohammed was like, no, no, no, no, no.
Speaker 0: We got to do some monotheism here.
Speaker 0: Get these other gods out of here.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And then they're like, get out of here, bro.
Speaker 0: We were cool with the polytheism.
Speaker 0: Everyone doing their own thing.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But we're not cool with you trying to, you know, eliminate our existing traditions in this area.
Speaker 0: And to make, you know, our people.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Become your way.
Speaker 0: Go go live over there instead.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: And then you've got the pragmatic rulers of this place being like, look, say these these other gods are also cool and we're cool with you and everything will be fine.
Speaker 1: And he's like, you know what?
Speaker 1: Yeah, this will work out.
Speaker 1: And then immediately he's like, oh, no, no, that's not going to work.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It changes his mind.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So basically and then in the book.
Speaker 0: You have these dreams that Gabriel is having of Jhilia.
Speaker 0: And it's basically that story retold.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's you know, with my hound instead of Mohammed.
Speaker 0: And whatnot.
Speaker 0: And basically, you know, what happens is, you know, Islam begins to take over everywhere except Jhilia slash Mecca.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Until it's like surrounding.
Speaker 0: And then Mohammed comes back.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: And defeats the gods that are or sentences do to go defeat the gods that are and there's a whole undercurrent there of the nature of how movements that are oppressed tend to spread partly because of that oppression.
Speaker 1: And that comes up both in the beginning and toward the end with all the riots and the trumpet and the fire and all that other stuff like that.
Speaker 1: That is a thread.
Speaker 1: And it definitely seems to follow sort of the history of like how religions have spread in the real world.
Speaker 0: But so anyway, the thing I want to focus on, though, are these satanic verses.
Speaker 0: is that, you know, Mohammed receives right instructions from, you know, or my hound receives instructions from the angel Gabriel or himself or whatever.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: And so he's like.
Speaker 0: he's like, what should I do?
Speaker 0: And at first, you know, the narrator right is the one delivering the messages.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So even if the narrator isn't the angel Gabriel, they are still acting the part and delivering the messages to my hound.
Speaker 0: And at first tells him, you know, except, right, the other lady gods.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And then and then comes back the second time.
Speaker 0: It was him both times and says, no, no, no monotheism.
Speaker 0: There's only one God get.
Speaker 0: Allah is the is the only one.
Speaker 0: Get them out of here.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And so and, you know, my hound goes at the second.
Speaker 0: He just the hound decides on his own.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: The second verse is the must have been actually the real Gabriel.
Speaker 0: And the first one was Satan.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Was was lying to him and telling him to accept those pagan gods.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing.
Speaker 0: I think the key of one of like, you know, maybe the second most central focus of the book is that those pagan gods happen to all be goddesses.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: That were all the three of them.
Speaker 0: I think there were three goddesses.
Speaker 1: The hound makes a really good point early in the book.
Speaker 1: And that theme comes up later because sexism is addressed in these books as well.
Speaker 1: Pretty directly how.
Speaker 1: Oh, so we have a bunch of female goddesses.
Speaker 1: Goddesses have power, but women don't.
Speaker 1: And now you want to have a god who takes away even that last power that women have from our society.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And so the satanic verses were the the pro women versus.
Speaker 0: And then you can see.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: The way it's a commentary, obviously, on the way Islam treats women, which is just obvious.
Speaker 0: to get into that.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: As much as well.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But then look at the other characters who are in line.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: With my hound.
Speaker 0: Gabriel, most of all.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And the way he treats women in his life.
Speaker 0: The story starts with, like, a married woman that he cheated with and then left behind jumping off a building and killing her.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that happens right away.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You know, he's got the girl who comes.
Speaker 1: One thing we haven't mentioned, if you haven't read the book and you're just listening to this, the book is laugh out loud funny sometimes.
Speaker 1: And this is very much intentional.
Speaker 1: And a lot of people speak to its humor.
Speaker 1: But she she likes splats and there's a whole thing about the splat.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And then when she comes back, like on a flying carpet, like, yeah, as a ghost messing with an echo.
Speaker 1: But also, yeah, there's there's that whole.
Speaker 1: I don't remember much because that happens pretty early.
Speaker 1: So I don't remember much about it.
Speaker 0: She comes back a few times.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they're short, really short scenes.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And then when he's in London, there's the the mountaineer alley.
Speaker 0: Hallelujah.
Speaker 1: The name.
Speaker 1: we haven't talked about all the names yet.
Speaker 1: Beyond the few we mentioned.
Speaker 0: Hallelujah Cone, the mountaineer who can climb who climbed Everest.
Speaker 0: Yeah, everything.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like he's mistreating her real bad, too.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And then.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You got the.
Speaker 0: there's actually one of the Aisha's.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: The one who is, you know, the butterfly one.
Speaker 0: Like, ah, she is a woman.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Receiving these prophecies or whatever, supposedly.
Speaker 0: And you get you have all this, you know, it's all lining up in that way.
Speaker 0: And then the biggest one is there's the Aisha who is the prostitute.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: The 15 year old one.
Speaker 0: Which is basically my hounds wife is right.
Speaker 0: My hounds, I guess, favorite wife is Aisha.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And you don't really hear from her.
Speaker 0: You just sort of know that my hounds has a wife who's the favorite one.
Speaker 0: And her name is Aisha.
Speaker 0: And then there's the whole part where the the prostitutes are like the last holdouts in the area.
Speaker 1: And she names herself basically the same name as my hounds beautiful wife.
Speaker 1: And you can read into what why that might have happened.
Speaker 1: And you see that a lot.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of not the.
Speaker 0: the blog is a ball.
Speaker 0: But he's like the.
Speaker 0: I guess he's the the Chamcha equivalent.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like, you know, the the the truth.
Speaker 0: Yeller speaker guy who's he's basically hiding out right in the.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And that's where we get all the to be a eunuch.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And he's hiding out in the in the prostitute area.
Speaker 1: But all a lot of the names are very like.
Speaker 1: the names themselves mean something and are pointed, not just tying characters together by having the same names.
Speaker 1: But like the fact that basically the street rapper who the the sultan basically hires to dis Islam is named the ball.
Speaker 0: Mm hmm.
Speaker 1: And I think, oh, yeah, right.
Speaker 1: And in the end of the book, when he's got the flame trumpet, he names that as real.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I was probably the trumpet part stood out like, wait a minute.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: As soon as he was like, I see flame come out of the trumpet, I was like, that's going to be Chekhov.
Speaker 0: I forgot about the trumpets.
Speaker 0: That's good.
Speaker 1: That's going to be a real play.
Speaker 1: That's basically a flamethrower.
Speaker 1: That's a. that's also a metaphor for speaking words that cause Molotov to get thrown means you might as well have just thrown the Molotov.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So what are the parts of this book you talk about?
Speaker 0: I mean, I guess the magic lamp.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So at the very beginning, Chekhov's magic lamp.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And when his dad is like, there's the whole because that is that is Chomsha's dad.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So Gabriel's family, you hear about early in the book, but then basically they're gone.
Speaker 0: It's just sort of giving you his background.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Whereas Chomsha's dad is like a significant character.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Where, you know, he has like this weird relationship with the with the walnut tree.
Speaker 0: And everything was in his dad.
Speaker 1: There's definitely because if we if we look at this through the lens of more an immigrant story and people who are transitioning between two cultures or caught between two cultures like that, which is the one of the primary and most important allegories of this work, to be clear, it is definitely his dad is a mixed bag.
Speaker 1: because on one hand, his dad is outright abusive in some ways.
Speaker 1: But on the other hand, his dad is not wrong that the choices he's making to fetishize London are not going to end.
Speaker 1: well for him.
Speaker 1: But that magic lamp, the whole as soon as you learn that dad won't let him touch the magic lamp until he's older.
Speaker 1: And and I was like, that lamp's coming back.
Speaker 1: That's Chekhov's lamp.
Speaker 1: And then it comes back as, well, because of the decisions you made, I'm never going to let you have this lamp.
Speaker 1: And then it literally is Chekhov's lamp, because that's literally the gun that Gabriel uses to kill himself.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was just.
Speaker 1: I did not expect the lamp to come back in that specific manner, because that opens up.
Speaker 1: You could do a whole podcast just talking about the metaphor of the lamp, because think about from Chomps's perspective as a naive kid in India who has dreams of going to London and leaving his what he is.
Speaker 1: Wrongly, and like he considers his home native culture to be bad in some way for a lot of reasons that we could interrogate.
Speaker 1: And he wants to leave it behind.
Speaker 1: And the magic lamp is always free.
Speaker 0: It's a lot like those people who aren't white, who, you know, I'm not saying that Chomps is like white supremacist bad levels.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But he definitely elevates.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of people who are not white who become white supremacists.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, they end up believing.
Speaker 0: And, you know, there's a lot of misogynist women out there.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You know, yeah.
Speaker 0: And there's a woman who's saying I belong in the kitchen as a baby factory.
Speaker 0: Like there are people like that.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And that's sort of, you know, Chomps is not at that level because but he is sort of like, you know, London is out there colonized.
Speaker 0: You know, UK is out there colonizing India.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And he's Indian and he's like, go London.
Speaker 0: Yeah, colonize.
Speaker 1: He's like my.
Speaker 1: where I live sucks.
Speaker 1: And they were right to colonize us.
Speaker 1: And then he gets there.
Speaker 1: And of course, he's not accepted the way that he wants to be.
Speaker 1: I mean, we see how the police treat him and it only goes downhill from there.
Speaker 1: But then he goes back to Bombay and he doesn't fit in there anymore either, even if he wants to.
Speaker 1: And I think that is a very common and important story.
Speaker 1: And that's a lot of what this book is about.
Speaker 1: Even if you strip away all the magic and everything else that's going on, it's ultimately about that.
Speaker 1: It's about the the insidious and pernicious nature of white supremacy and colonialism and how it almost converts people from colonized cultures to its cause.
Speaker 1: But we'll never actually reward them in the same way that the magic lamp represented all of his dreams of what it would be like if you got to London and became a Londoner and like join what he perceived as the modern enlightened world.
Speaker 1: And in the end, the lamp is just an avenue for suicide.
Speaker 1: But it's very notable that it is not him who even uses the lamp in the end.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I mean, we could go on for a very long time, probably for days and days.
Speaker 0: Is there anything else that's so significant, though, that we really want to mention it?
Speaker 1: You know, I did like like.
Speaker 1: it stuck with me one of the early short segments, the Argentinian story.
Speaker 1: Because it was told a little bit differently from the others, because it was, you know, the the woman, what, Diamond?
Speaker 1: Was that their name, like Rosa Diamond?
Speaker 0: I barely remember it, this part.
Speaker 0: I do remember it.
Speaker 0: That exists.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: And I wasn't super clear as I was reading it on what happened.
Speaker 0: He was it was basically.
Speaker 0: I think it was, you know, your meta knowledge.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: He was commenting on the, you know, the war.
Speaker 1: Well, the war.
Speaker 1: The fact that a bunch of Nazis did move to Argentina because like but also how like you have even colonizers who move to the place and almost do the reverse, like they appropriate and adopt the culture.
Speaker 1: Like you've got the English people coming to Argentina and basically cosplaying as Argentinians and cosplaying their warped perception of Argentinian machismo and masculine honor and how when the murder happens and the nonsense goes down, all the Argentinians are like, listen, you fucking English people, if you just leave now, we won't like bring you to our courts and prosecute you.
Speaker 1: Like it was.
Speaker 1: there's a really important other side of the story of colonialism that sort of really inspects the idea that it never works out in either direction.
Speaker 1: The appropriation and the infiltration is just as dangerous and toxic as the expropriation and exfiltration.
Speaker 0: I mean, I mean, I said war.
Speaker 0: I was talking about the Falken Islands war.
Speaker 1: Oh, he's basically a weeb about...
Speaker 0: Which keep in mind, the Falken Islands was not long before this book was published.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: It was really close time frame wise.
Speaker 1: And there's a whole extra historical context about that war they won't have time to get into.
Speaker 0: But it sort of felt like, though, like he's got this whole book to work with and it's like that wasn't anywhere close to the main point of the book.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But he just sort of had space to like, you know, and was managed to fit in, you know, comments on other things that were just going on.
Speaker 0: Well, it's like, oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: And he, you know, he brought he was brought with him from England, his new ideas from Germany.
Speaker 1: And then you get a very abstract description of what is obviously a Nazi flag, followed by the.
Speaker 1: the wife has her affair on the island.
Speaker 1: that is all white for some reason.
Speaker 1: And there's no color there.
Speaker 1: And everything's just white except for the red of the blood from the murder and the red from the Nazi flag.
Speaker 1: And that is almost Sam and Rashi just hitting you over the head like, yeah, that's where all of this leads ultimately.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, this like since we probably shouldn't go on forever.
Speaker 0: Oh, we should talk about the pilgrimage deal.
Speaker 0: That's the.
Speaker 1: oh, yeah, because that that's a whole other thing around.
Speaker 1: the people make their own myths and it doesn't matter the truth of an event like that.
Speaker 1: Like, let's say that literally happened.
Speaker 1: Faithful people would very likely say, and all the pilgrims made it to the other side and survived, even though that is obviously not what happened.
Speaker 0: Or they did, but it was in the afterlife.
Speaker 1: Which, you know, actually, that makes me think that gets back to the whole concept of the magic lamp.
Speaker 1: What's your reward for doing what white colonial culture wants you to do?
Speaker 1: Well, you're going to die because your reward is in an afterlife and the afterlife doesn't exist.
Speaker 0: But, yeah, so there's this.
Speaker 0: one of the Aishas, right, is like this is poor town in India.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And it's because or is it India?
Speaker 0: It's no, I couldn't.
Speaker 1: I was not clear on that.
Speaker 1: All I was and I wasn't even clear on when it was set right away.
Speaker 0: All I couldn't figure out the geography, but clearly they had to cross the water to get to Mecca.
Speaker 1: But she basically performed almost like an accidental miracle, like she detected the breast cancer, like she had an almost like a sort of miracle and people were kind of on board with her.
Speaker 1: And then through plausible things that happen, people start to follow her.
Speaker 1: Obviously, I'm skipping over the detail because I don't remember that part of the book super well.
Speaker 0: I focused on other parts, but it's weird because like it's one it's like a thread they go back to.
Speaker 0: But there's like a large gap where they don't go back to it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like it's there.
Speaker 0: They it goes away from it for a long time.
Speaker 0: And then towards the end of the book goes back to it until it wraps up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but so it's not like a lot of books were like, I guess, sort of evenly like, you know, Prince of Nothing.
Speaker 0: Good example of like.
Speaker 0: you got three different things going on and they go one, two, three, one, two, three, one, two, three, one, two, three.
Speaker 0: This book is just like one, five, one, one, one, two, three, four, seven, one, two, five, three.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Just there's no like set pattern of like going back and forth between the different, you know, and now it's a dream and now it's Chamcha again and now it's, you know, whatever.
Speaker 1: But it's definitely that feels like because the Imam story, like the one making it a Khomeini, they both.
Speaker 1: definitely it's almost like an escalation because people follow Mahound and things happen.
Speaker 1: People follow Aisha to their just straight up deaths and people follow the Imam to his ulterior motives.
Speaker 1: And there's definitely a very clear critique of blind faith in extremism leads to death and misery and ruin.
Speaker 1: And that is very prominently and explicitly portrayed over and over and over again.
Speaker 1: Even Chamcha blindly following his idealized internal vision of England leads to ruin.
Speaker 0: But I think the thing that I focused on in the pilgrimage part, right, where this cast of characters that was following pilgrimage, right, and what each one sort of represented.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So it was the guy driving the car who was trying to convince them to stop.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not go.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You had like the people who still believed, but they couldn't manage to walk that far.
Speaker 0: They got in the car.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It was like, you know, it's sort of like people are getting in and out of the car.
Speaker 1: And what you and you always and over time you see like it distills down to the people who are either too blind to what's happening or are too extreme or they're just in too deep and they can't admit to themselves that maybe they should back out.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And then the car breaks, but it keeps walking anyway.
Speaker 0: But obviously doesn't walk into the water.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like they get to the final end.
Speaker 0: It's like who walks into the water and who doesn't.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Who doesn't even go to begin with?
Speaker 1: Well, because very rarely, like look at look at the other plots, the person who's leading people to their deaths is rarely the one who suffers the direct consequences that their followers suffer.
Speaker 0: I mean, she really had nothing to lose.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: She was just a really poor person making dolls and selling them to this dude.
Speaker 0: It's like, yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: One other thing I think we're talking about, it's seen from the beginning, but it's one of the last notes I had that I wanted to come back to that we didn't discuss the fact there's this hole in that police scene.
Speaker 1: I remember that the car, the police, when they first show up, are all identical and faceless, like he can't differentiate them like they're they are just the concept of police.
Speaker 1: But then there's a moment when suddenly a bunch of them all have specific faces and like suddenly he sees them all individually.
Speaker 1: And remember when he sees them all, fucking none of them are like English going back to old times.
Speaker 1: We got Irish people and like all these different people who had immigrated and assimilated in previous eras who have now taken on the roles that the colonial oppressors gave them, basically being the police.
Speaker 1: And that's that that faceless and then suddenly non faceless nature comes back time and time again.
Speaker 1: And that scene was just so directly like the allegory was hitting you in the face to make sure you don't miss it, because when they escape the hospital, all the animal people he's I remember the one animal person who helps them escape is like, that's the power of these English.
Speaker 1: They describe you and you become what they described.
Speaker 1: But when he calls the cops out, there's this great moment where suddenly like the cops kind of stop beating him up and they start to almost fight with each other a little bit.
Speaker 1: And then they realize what they're doing and they like turn around and unify and then resume beating the shit out of him.
Speaker 0: Mm hmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the whole the I guess we didn't comment too much about the act, like literally turning into some kind of devil beast.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And literally having some magical glowing halo, like somehow, you know, if they didn't die in the plane crash, it's like nobody's like all the people who aren't there.
Speaker 1: The cops are just like, oh, what are you some kind of go person now?
Speaker 1: Like they don't they don't even in any way react to that.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like it's not, you know, even though it's supposed to be taking place in Earth, in London, UK, 1980s, whatever, it's like if there was a goat person in the 80s, people would have been like, holy shit, this wasn't some P.T.
Speaker 0: Barnum stuff.
Speaker 0: This is the real deal.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Of course.
Speaker 1: Clearly it is.
Speaker 1: The allegory is around the people.
Speaker 1: That is their like projected perception of him as a nonwhite, what they presume to be illegal immigrant.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You know, but like it goes away.
Speaker 0: It's like you would think that like that would like.
Speaker 0: if that happens in most books, that's a thing that like, you know, is like, well, it goes away.
Speaker 1: And what was the place called the hot wax club?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Hot wax, the nightclub.
Speaker 1: I have I have a page open where I have the list of names of characters and there's the names of places at the bottom.
Speaker 0: And then, you know, Gabriel's Halo, I think also goes away around like at the same time ish.
Speaker 1: Well, because eventually the veneer comes back.
Speaker 0: Does it come back like one time?
Speaker 1: because the veneer of the divine falls away and what's left is humans dealing with the decisions they have made because no one's answering your questions but you and no one's holding you accountable to those questions and the answers and the decisions you make with the people around you.
Speaker 0: But it's like, you know, it's normally right.
Speaker 0: It's it's not like some, you know, lazy allegory.
Speaker 0: We're like, aha, the bad guy turns into the devil and the good guy turns into the halo.
Speaker 0: And it's not the exact opposite either.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Where it's like, aha, the bad guy gets the halo, right?
Speaker 1: Well, because they flip.
Speaker 1: It's almost like a coin flipping through the air and who's, quote, good or bad or satanic or godly is almost like oscillating because they're both pulled in opposite directions by the culture they're assimilating into for different reasons.
Speaker 1: Hmm.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, this book is absolutely 100 percent worth reading if you listen to all this and somehow like didn't read the book and just listen to the book club for some reason.
Speaker 1: Like, I wish I'd read this book sooner.
Speaker 1: I really enjoyed it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Maybe a lot to think about.
Speaker 1: I'm still thinking about it.
Speaker 0: I mean, if you know, when you hear about alleged to say this all the time.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But it's like when this is why I try not to, you know, spend too much time watching, reading.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: We say with Evangelion, the anime, you might like it, you might hate it, you might hate anime.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: The fact that in the year two thousand and twenty three, people are still talking about it a lot.
Speaker 1: That means that it's worth figuring out what the deal is.
Speaker 0: If there was something that's legendary and famous that you've heard of.
Speaker 0: It's like, oh, that's a famous book.
Speaker 0: It's like is a reason the book got famous.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You might not like it, but you should at least know something about it.
Speaker 0: It's like, would I rather?
Speaker 0: it's like, you know, would I rather watch Citizen Kane or Star Wars and rather watch?
Speaker 0: I could watch Star Wars a hundred times.
Speaker 0: But Citizen Kane is famous for reasons.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It doesn't get famous just by random.
Speaker 0: It's not like some random movie got picked to be famous.
Speaker 0: It's not like some random book.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: The book or the movie earned that legendary famousness somehow.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And if you go and check it out, you will realize why.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: I know it's like.
Speaker 0: I can't even say it's like, yeah, I get is like an S-tier book, but I can't say that it exceeded expectations because it was such a famous book.
Speaker 0: I expected it to be as I went in expecting.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: He's one of the most famous authors of the modern.
Speaker 0: It was merely like an eight year book.
Speaker 0: I would be like, oh, I heard I thought this book was legendary.
Speaker 0: What's going on?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just kind of good.
Speaker 1: I'm glad we picked this one instead of the other option, even though I do want to read it and I will read it at some point.
Speaker 1: for Coast Pendulum.
Speaker 0: It was decided randomly.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But for Coast Pendulum, Umberto Eco.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But one thing I know about Eco's writing is it is not quite as perfectly crafted as Rushdeez.
Speaker 0: I mean, I've heard of the other book and I've heard of Umberto Eco, but I've never similar.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the contents of those books are.
Speaker 0: I don't know anything about the person or anything.
Speaker 1: So have you.
Speaker 0: But I would have similar high expectations from something that I've heard of and is clearly famous.
Speaker 1: Have you ever read?
Speaker 1: It's not that long.
Speaker 1: Umberto Eco, there's a he wrote an essay in the 90s titled Ur-Fascism and it is you should read it.
Speaker 1: It is it's pretty short and it is one of the most poignant, concise and well written descriptions of what fascism ultimately is that has ever been put to paper.
Speaker 1: Like it is a very important essay that I think more people should read.
Speaker 1: But Umberto Eco's writing is not as, I don't know, florid and pleasant as Rushdeez, like Rushdeez is just such a good writer.
Speaker 1: It the words felt they had a good brain feel as I read them in a way that important classic books for all time tend to have that
Speaker 0: it was definitely a situation where it's like, you know, like what how what like what life do you have to live to be able to learn to write like that?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like, OK, like what would I have to practice to write to arrange words in that order?
Speaker 1: Because I keep saying poetry in florid because if you haven't read this book yet, it the prose is I'd say 30 percent poetry, 70 percent novel, just the way it reads.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So I guess I had to pick some other books to read.
Speaker 1: You don't have to pick it today, but if you're ready, I don't know if they're going to be as good as this one.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: So wait.
Speaker 1: I mean, we picked one of the most famous books of the modern era, so.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So all right.
Speaker 0: So today is June 1st.
Speaker 0: We start in the Pride Month.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So I went and I looked around for some, you know, LGBTQ plus fiction.
Speaker 0: And so I found out.
Speaker 0: I found out that there is a famous gay author named Stephen Rowley, right, who is married to a author, Byron Lane, and they both released new books on May 30th, like a couple of days ago.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's great, because Focos, Pendulum and Satanic Verses came out in the same year.
Speaker 1: That's why I picked them both as options.
Speaker 0: But hold on.
Speaker 0: Here's the problem, right, is I went and I checked out what the deal with these books are.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And Stephen Rowley's book, The Celebrants, sounds like it has some potential.
Speaker 0: Like I felt like I kind of would want to read that book.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Let me read a description of it here.
Speaker 0: Let me see.
Speaker 0: There it is.
Speaker 0: OK, so it's been a minute or five years since Jordan Vargas last saw his college friends and twenty eight years since their graduation, when their adult lives began.
Speaker 0: Now, Jordan, Geordie, Naomi, Craig and Marielle, like his five friends, are at the brink of a new decade, responsibilities of adulthood.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: They still haven't figured out their lives, blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 0: Every year they have a reunion.
Speaker 0: They have a reunion in Big Sur, California, where they throw.
Speaker 0: they throw each other living funerals.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Sort of like a weird friend tradition school.
Speaker 0: But this time, right, you know, someone has a secret that's going to upend everything.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So that one that one sounds like I might want to read it.
Speaker 0: Possibly.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: The book by Byron Lane, Big Gay Wedding.
Speaker 0: I don't feel like I want to read it.
Speaker 0: It's basically, you know, gay people go back to have a wedding in mom's barn in Louisiana.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And it's like, all right, I can I can see where that's going.
Speaker 0: It's a little on the nose, at least based on the description.
Speaker 0: But that's OK.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Is it like a story or I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's called Big Gay Wedding.
Speaker 0: It just came out.
Speaker 0: I'm you know, if that sounds good to you, go read it.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I'm not knocking it.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying me personally.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I don't want to put two choices out there and one of them is one I don't want.
Speaker 0: So even though it would have been cool to pick the two books by the two gay married authors that came out on the same day as the two picks, I'm going to replace one of them.
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 1: You don't have to replace it today, but I know.
Speaker 0: So I have a replacement, which is, I guess this book came out a while ago.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But recently a Twitter account.
Speaker 1: Oh, you're you're going to pick.
Speaker 1: This is how you lose the time war.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: So I know that everybody knows about Bigelow's Dickolas Wolfwood.
Speaker 0: So recently a Twitter account, Bigelow's Dickolas Wolfwood tweeted about this book that's been out for a while.
Speaker 1: I got to read the tweet because the tweet was like.
Speaker 1: I found it.
Speaker 1: Here's the tweet.
Speaker 1: I'm reading the entire thing.
Speaker 1: Read this.
Speaker 1: Do not look at me out there anything about it.
Speaker 1: Just read it.
Speaker 1: It's only like 200 pages.
Speaker 1: You can download it on Audible.
Speaker 1: It's only four hours.
Speaker 1: Do it right now.
Speaker 1: I'm extremely serious.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So there's a book called This is How We Lose the Time War.
Speaker 1: This is how you lose the time war.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And it's real short, just like Bigelow's Dickolas said.
Speaker 0: And it is indeed a lesbian romance book.
Speaker 0: That's not really a spoiler.
Speaker 0: I already read the whole book because it's so short.
Speaker 0: But yeah, that's also, you know, an appropriate selection for a Pride Month book club.
Speaker 0: So you can either choose the book I already read.
Speaker 0: That's mega popular or this new book that also seems very popular.
Speaker 1: I guess you decided at the end of the last show.
Speaker 1: So I feel like I should keep that precedent going so we don't have it all.
Speaker 1: I like that.
Speaker 0: I can't force you to do anything.
Speaker 1: But I really want to read.
Speaker 1: This is How You Lose the Time War.
Speaker 1: And I haven't yet.
Speaker 1: So I think we should do that one.
Speaker 0: OK, good.
Speaker 0: I already read it.
Speaker 0: Good.
Speaker 0: You saved me a lot of work.
Speaker 1: Well, I think we should give the listener.
Speaker 0: Sorry.
Speaker 0: Sorry to the two husbands.
Speaker 0: I want to just, you know, prop your books up again.
Speaker 0: Stephen Rowley and Byron Lane.
Speaker 0: The books, The Celebrants and Big Gay Wedding.
Speaker 1: I think The Celebrants will return to our selection.
Speaker 0: If you're looking for some Pride Month beach reading, there you go.
Speaker 1: Because I'm going to bring it for Coast Pendulum back at some point in the decisions, but not in.
Speaker 0: Oh, you get it.
Speaker 0: We're going to allow reruns.
Speaker 1: I think we can in the decisions if they weren't picked.
Speaker 0: But you could keep bringing a book back and keep trying it.
Speaker 1: But I'm going to follow or I'm going to follow my own precedent in the same way that George Washington set a precedent of just not running for a third term.
Speaker 1: I am just going to say that I will never bring the same book twice in a row in my decision.
Speaker 1: There at least has to be twice in a row.
Speaker 1: OK, so I might bring that back at some point about you can't you can't try.
Speaker 0: You can't put it up if it gets chopped down three times.
Speaker 0: That's it's dead.
Speaker 0: I might go with.
Speaker 1: if it gets chopped down, the time that's appropriate before you're allowed to bring it up again gets exponentially longer.
Speaker 0: Oh, so it's like when you're trying to test to see the websites up again, it's like every second.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Every five seconds, like if it goes through like four book clubs from now, then I'm not going to bring it up again for years.
Speaker 1: And if it doesn't make it to that point, I'm just going to bring it up when we're in the retirement home.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So the next book is This Is How You Lose the Time War, which I already got from the library, read and returned today.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I'm going to follow the biggles dickles wolf woods advice and I'm not going to learn anything about it.
Speaker 1: I'm just going to read it.
Speaker 1: We'll give you a. we'll give you.
Speaker 1: involves.
Speaker 0: it involves a war time travel.
Speaker 1: I imagine birds.
Speaker 0: No, OK, because they're I mean, there's not no birds in it, but it does not.
Speaker 0: it's not about birds.
Speaker 0: It's birds on the cover.
Speaker 1: There's one full quote from Madeline Miller and it just says this book has it all, period.
Speaker 0: It does indeed have that is in a short amount of time.
Speaker 0: There's all is in there.
Speaker 1: All right, I'm game.
Speaker 1: We'll do that, I imagine we'll do this episode, not the next Thursday episode, but the following one, just to give it time for people to find out.
Speaker 1: we did the book club and read the book, but might record it early because this doesn't.
Speaker 1: it's 200 pages like I could read that in an afternoon.
Speaker 0: It's a very, very.
Speaker 0: I was literally like.
Speaker 0: actually I thought it was due today at the library, but it was due next week.
Speaker 0: But because I thought it was due today, it's like I had 25 percent of the book left yesterday.
Speaker 0: And it I guess I finished it before dinner.
Speaker 0: It's just like it's super.
Speaker 0: you know, it's.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's not Binti short now, but it's a short.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: And the Geek Nights Patreon patrons want me to say their name on the show.
Speaker 1: This episode are my filters not working the way I normally do.
Speaker 1: So let me click on this until it works.
Speaker 1: Linky, G-Dragon, Lily, Tenebra, Case, Care, Makes, Music, Chris, the Dodd, Clinton, Walton, Dex, Finn, Joel Hayes, Penny, Rhymer, Rebecca, Dunn, Sam, Erickson, Shervin, Von Hurl and a ton of people who give just a dollar, presumably to get access to that backup RSS feed, which is actually not too bad.
Speaker 1: I use that to QA Geek Nights sometimes.
Speaker 1: But yeah, we're.
Speaker 1: we're back from illness, back to do our thing.
Speaker 1: Wednesday episodes might be temporarily saved because our cup overflow with lately suddenly, magically on Wednesday episodes.
Speaker 1: So I expect next Wednesday we're going to talk about Spider-Man.
Speaker 1: And for now, tonight, I leave you with.
Speaker 1: Hi, Max Edrum here with.
Speaker 1: This is my guest.
Speaker 1: I heard you were big time in.
Speaker 1: the old pop is.
Speaker 1: I'm going to take that as a no comment.
Speaker 1: So gritty time.
Speaker 1: What I'm talking about and you're not is that more people prefer the new refreshing taste of Coke over Pepsi.
Speaker 1: Sweaty.
Speaker 1: It's true.
Speaker 1: More people are, as we cokeologists say, catching the wave.
Speaker 1: Catch it if you can.
Speaker 1: Can catch the wave Coke.