Speaker 1: It's Tuesday April 18th 2023.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights night.
Speaker 1: We're talking about lore In video games not data's nemesis.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: And y'all are playing Marvel snap way more than I play Marvel snap and I play it.
Speaker 0: Listen, I only play in the morning.
Speaker 0: I wake up and I do my morning biz and then I get to the computer and before I do my the Java paid to I play Marvel snap until the daily missions are complete.
Speaker 1: I play my first Marvel snap until the first bowel movement I have given day and that is when I play Marvel snap until I'm done Boweling and then I play again like over lunch.
Speaker 0: Sometimes I'm not reading I complete all the daily missions And then I just don't play again at all period until the next.
Speaker 1: I see I don't you complete the missions.
Speaker 1: I ignore the missions and just play and every night I just go and click on all the missions I accidentally got because I happen to achieve whatever they're asking for.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, I don't like.
Speaker 0: the only time it's like I'm not I don't have to try to do with.
Speaker 0: the missions are asking for 90 Play 500 power with the cards like yeah, I just play until they're all complete by happenstance.
Speaker 0: But there might be an annoying one.
Speaker 0: That's like it is, you know It's a really weird one and I might have to like play a different deck for two seconds.
Speaker 0: Like if it's like play ten ongoing cards like alright I'll make a deck of all ongoing cards and clear that right.
Speaker 0: just cuz I have I only have one ongoing card in my deck Right, so it's like, you know.
Speaker 0: But and the other thing is like sometimes if they're you know If the when the seasons coming to an end if I if there's some season missions You might have to take a look and make sure that you got them all right, which usually you've got them all right.
Speaker 0: It's just gonna happen not naturally You don't have to think about it but just in case you got a check and then You know in the past the previous season They changed the rules to where when you hit a tenth rank like you hit rank 50 you get five ranks free.
Speaker 0: So you just teleport from 50 to 55 you get to 60 to teleport you to 65.
Speaker 0: So what I did is because of that new rule I you know I put in like one extra hour just like right to get up to 70 right because it's 70 you get a big credit reward.
Speaker 1: Well, I do not think about it that hard I just play.
Speaker 1: but if I'm it right if I'm at any nine I usually will just push a little more cuz usually just a few a few games and you'll automatically get enough cubes to go Up to the next rank.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but then at 80 you don't really get anything worthwhile And at 90 you get a bunch of gold and it's like I could push for 90.
Speaker 0: The problem is I don't have the cards to make a meta day.
Speaker 1: I only.
Speaker 1: I only just got Dracula and Dracula ain't even in my meta anymore.
Speaker 1: I can't even use them now.
Speaker 1: I got him too late.
Speaker 0: You should just play that.
Speaker 0: I've been playing the deck.
Speaker 1: I'm playing that.
Speaker 1: turn him that deck that the tournament deck that I just copied.
Speaker 1: That's the like hella discard deck.
Speaker 0: Oh, can't you copy a tournament decker because I already was playing discard.
Speaker 1: So now I have two different discard decks and I'm sort of.
Speaker 0: I just played the Dracula kind.
Speaker 0: I don't like the the hella K.
Speaker 1: I liked the Dracula more modok kind and it won a lot.
Speaker 1: but this other tournament deck It wins a lot more and it's usually big eight pew victories.
Speaker 0: But I'm also missing some cards.
Speaker 1: I happen to have all the cards.
Speaker 0: for that one It's like it's weird.
Speaker 0: It's like every single top meta deck.
Speaker 1: I'm missing like a couple cards Yeah, or it's like well, I find funny is every what time anyone in our discord complains about not having a card I have always had that card, but I'm missing a bunch of cards that most of you have and don't even use.
Speaker 0: It's like this is you know, if they made it, you know It's just someone make a card game where people can have every card, right?
Speaker 0: Well, we had that.
Speaker 1: it was called Let me trade even though I know letting trading happen would just bring even more capital as they're not gonna let trading.
Speaker 0: It's not gonna happen.
Speaker 0: They wouldn't mind though if they let you trade variants only right?
Speaker 0: It's like I could trade.
Speaker 0: it's like you can't you know, it's like I'll trade you all my pixels.
Speaker 0: I don't want any of these right?
Speaker 0: you give me those nice ones that I actually want.
Speaker 1: So one funny thing and I know I'm gonna come right in and in before you and say that I know this is just a statistical anomaly that is very likely like it is common and expected but it felt like whenever I play blade, which sometimes I'll play like I got him round one and even if the odds are Astronomically low like one in six or one in seven that hell is gonna be one.
Speaker 0: It's not astronomically low.
Speaker 0: That's just pretty good.
Speaker 1: so but it felt like it happened a lot.
Speaker 1: so I started keeping track of one metric for the last week and that metric us.
Speaker 1: If I have hella in my hand and I put played blade one how many other cards were in my hand?
Speaker 1: and two was hella discarded out of 44 times.
Speaker 1: that has occurred in about two weeks 100% of the time.
Speaker 1: I am not exaggerating or joking.
Speaker 1: Hella was the card discarded no matter how many cards are in my hand.
Speaker 1: So you you threw down 44 blades 44 blades over two and a half weeks where hella was.
Speaker 1: how many you eliminated cases where hella has to already be in my hand.
Speaker 1: I don't count it if there's other shenanigans Like if I play blade on Something where blades gonna go off multiple times like it has to hit on the first time or it doesn't count like I thought about.
Speaker 0: So basically you see didn't record.
Speaker 0: So the thing is really statistically speaking you should be including the cases where you played blade and hella wasn't in the hand.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but even though you're counting cases where hella was in the hand there were at least one non Hella card in the hand other than
Speaker 1: well with the other caveat that I have never played blade where there's only two other cards In my hand and one of them's hella like.
Speaker 1: that's just stupid right?
Speaker 0: That's a stupid play, right?
Speaker 1: I will try a one in three if I if I'm feeling lucky and it actually works out Normally with other cards, but not with blade.
Speaker 1: So I'm just gonna keep track of this until the first time hella is until blade does not discard hella.
Speaker 1: It's just funny that that I did.
Speaker 1: I noticed it and so far based on the data I have collected it is true blade.
Speaker 0: Hey, I mean, you know, you might just if you're unlucky you're unlucky.
Speaker 0: But the point is that I'll say in the deck the discard deck I have yeah, is that I only play Colleen sif and modok.
Speaker 0: I don't have to have no luck doesn't enter into it.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's my other deck That I think my other discard deck is almost identical to your discard.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't I don't play around with luck that way.
Speaker 0: You don't you don't get burnt.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like Consistency is king for winning card games.
Speaker 1: It is like 70 80 percent.
Speaker 0: right now with this day if your win rate is 70 80 percent That's higher than any meta deck ever.
Speaker 0: So I don't I don't play.
Speaker 1: I'm down in the 40s because I don't play so I don't have.
Speaker 0: your win rate is 70 80 percent.
Speaker 1: It's like how are you down in the 40s cuz I play 10 games over the course of a couple days Like I don't play.
Speaker 0: that I did you then.
Speaker 0: how did you have 40 times?
Speaker 0: That with blade hella plays right right now.
Speaker 1: I'm playing more often.
Speaker 1: I don't know my win rate is right now, but I want to.
Speaker 1: I tend to win.
Speaker 0: You're playing only on the pooper.
Speaker 0: It's like You're not using a tracker.
Speaker 0: So how do you even know what your win rate is?
Speaker 1: that because I started writing down these fucking blade games.
Speaker 0: You got paper in the in the shed.
Speaker 1: I got paper that I can't my little my moleskine.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm using it for right now.
Speaker 1: the hella blade situation Anyway.
Speaker 1: So in the news, of course NHL Stanley Cup's happening first important games tonight.
Speaker 1: So that's why I kind of rushed through the show.
Speaker 0: playoffs are happening.
Speaker 0: The Stanley Cup is an object It can't have a Stanley Cup.
Speaker 1: playoffs are happening and we're in round one right now.
Speaker 0: and so far The exciting you know.
Speaker 0: yesterday the to add to East games which you know, we're in we're okay.
Speaker 0: And then they had two exciting West games, but of course It's like no one's up for that shit like there's no one on the East Coast is So in the news, you know when there's a Company like they would ruin the internet day.
Speaker 1: April Fool's Day has often been the day where a lot of companies would announce something That they think is a joke and they intend to be seen as a joke.
Speaker 1: But the thing they announced as a joke is better than the things they actually announced and people actually want the joke.
Speaker 0: internet date This year fell on a weekend, which I think and also fatigue I think contributed to it being less of a thing, which I was very happy about.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but One of the things that happened actually the day before that day But most people didn't notice it until that day was Sega announced a visual novel murder mystery where Sonic the Hedgehog is dead And I think that was an on-purpose April Fool.
Speaker 1: It was so.
Speaker 1: people thought it acted like it was a joke at first and then it appeared on Steam And you can actually play it and it was really.
Speaker 0: I downloaded it and played it for five minutes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I did not download it yet, but I will.
Speaker 1: I'm just glad that it was a real thing and not a joke.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: hey, you know a lot of people have made the April Fool's Day joke, but also real thing, right?
Speaker 1: Yep, which I think is the pro ist way to handle the current form of ruin the internet day, right?
Speaker 0: It's like we will make a silly novelty product or at least imitation facsimile replacement thereof.
Speaker 0: Right, like how many times is like, you know?
Speaker 0: Some cards against humanity must have done this like a few times right where they're like.
Speaker 0: Hey, we printed some silly cards on April Fool's Day.
Speaker 0: buy them, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah They definitely were the ones who would push that kind of thing the most I Don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't remember specifically if they did that.
Speaker 0: It just feels like that's something that they would do.
Speaker 1: Yeah in Some other news that is a little more interesting or at least we talk about this every year as GDQ is coming up real quick It's earlier than usually.
Speaker 0: usually it's like 4th of July weekend.
Speaker 1: now It's May 28th through June 4th.
Speaker 0: So like I think the reason for this is because of their change of location, right?
Speaker 0: Their previous GDQ the regular one that was in, you know around January was going to be an in-person one But it was in a bad state a literally Florida bad place.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what has gone pretty fast to the point that I would not go there, especially not going to Florida Yeah, so they were like fuck you, Florida We're not having our event there and they held an online one.
Speaker 0: even they didn't want to.
Speaker 0: they wanted in-person one again And then they're like fine.
Speaker 0: So now they moved to a different state.
Speaker 0: What state did they move to?
Speaker 0: Is it Minnesota?
Speaker 0: Maybe I don't know Milwaukee, Wisconsin.
Speaker 1: I Realize it's not actually on.
Speaker 1: I'm on the actual official page and it's not like obvious where it is.
Speaker 0: I haven't clicked event info attendance guide and hotel booking.
Speaker 0: it is in Minneapolis, Minnesota so it's it.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's in Minnesota, which is for some reason a Place that a lot of gaming things tend to have a big in the Midwest.
Speaker 0: Well, I think it's just Minnesota.
Speaker 0: specifically like location wise it's in the middle So the people from both sides can get to it.
Speaker 0: It's sort of fair, right?
Speaker 0: It's a city, right?
Speaker 0: it's not just like, you know, even though Minnesota the state has a lot of Unpopulated areas or sparsely populated areas, you know Minneapolis is.
Speaker 1: there is a history to just in general of the American Midwest much like North Jersey just having a huge number of small gaming conventions and events relative to like other states.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so but anyway, that's they got a new location and a state that they find acceptable.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the registration is open.
Speaker 0: They've already published the fee in person.
Speaker 0: The them getting that new deal with the new location is why the dates were moved.
Speaker 1: I think so.
Speaker 1: So I bet starting next year.
Speaker 1: It'll move back to our traditional dates.
Speaker 0: Maybe something in this location that they've got the hill in Minneapolis.
Speaker 0: Maybe someone's got like 4th of July booked there for years Or maybe this will just be a better time.
Speaker 1: Like I don't know I feel like honestly when GDQ is during actual summer I tend to watch most of it way later because I'm outside.
Speaker 1: I don't really want to be sitting watching something but it Yep.
Speaker 1: Yeah this springtime.
Speaker 1: There's more likelihood of bad or at least not perfect weather.
Speaker 1: So I'm more likely to watch something live.
Speaker 1: So we'll see Two good ones in the list.
Speaker 1: I I'm curious about that.
Speaker 1: There's always a maniac mansion or like an adventure game kind of thing.
Speaker 1: They're doing loom again.
Speaker 1: I see some x-men arcade at the end.
Speaker 0: Yeah, x-men arcade how it's like, how could you go faster in that?
Speaker 0: It's sort of like.
Speaker 0: Well, it says win the.
Speaker 1: so Metroid master is doing a two-player co-op one CC attempt One player one CC attempt.
Speaker 1: Okay They're special.
Speaker 0: Basically, if they die that doesn't count.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but yeah, I assume if you play that game as long as you don't die it's like the time it takes is gonna be pretty much the same.
Speaker 0: because like You know, it's like.
Speaker 0: how much faster can you kill the bad guys, right?
Speaker 0: It's like they.
Speaker 0: there's only so many attacks you have.
Speaker 0: you have so many mutant powers.
Speaker 0: I guess there's a little bit of strategy of like what screen has a lot of bad guys.
Speaker 0: So therefore using the mutant power can speed the game up by getting through.
Speaker 0: that's not like gauntlet.
Speaker 1: We're like there's secrets and paths and things you can follow.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like but it's pretty much of.
Speaker 0: it's like a really narrow window of time variance As long as you don't die on how long it will take to be like.
Speaker 1: the same Issue applies to final fight where there are two final fight three speed runs.
Speaker 1: Yeah Hey got any news.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the people who made Pokemon go and What was the first one that didn't have a have a license?
Speaker 0: Oh ingress ingress?
Speaker 1: We've done panels about.
Speaker 1: I uploaded some YouTube shorts and then what those?
Speaker 0: a Harry Potter when they shut down, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then I think there was some other ones but they basically just keep making.
Speaker 0: had that one game ingress And then they managed to.
Speaker 0: it was it was had problems.
Speaker 0: We've talked about it extensively more than it deserves to be talked about.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they've effectively Rebranded that same game with different intellectual properties to make it successful.
Speaker 0: and it's all.
Speaker 0: but it's only worked once really with Pokemon go.
Speaker 0: And now they're trying again This time with monster hunter and the cooperation of Capcom.
Speaker 0: And they've added this time based on what the previews say they've added a little bit more Real quote real game to it.
Speaker 0: We're like you have to swipe to fight.
Speaker 0: Actually fight the monsters right sort of like a little Simon Says kind of deal like what you gotta throw the little pokeball like Technically you could throw it wrong.
Speaker 0: I guess no, but this is a little bit more than that.
Speaker 0: This is like off the month.
Speaker 0: You could like theoretically lose to a monster if you were just awful at it.
Speaker 0: I also read that they're gonna have things like you can go paintball Monsters and then just do all the fighting when you get home so you can go out and do your location.
Speaker 0: You have to set.
Speaker 0: well, you know if you're going out to do location stuff You don't have to like stand in each location and do comment.
Speaker 1: I bet I know why they're doing that because one of the things I see people who are weirdly into Pokemon go still complain about Is that they live in places where you can't walk around so they drive everywhere.
Speaker 1: So they'd rather just drive past places and that instead of stopping in their cars at places to Pokemon go and then continuing.
Speaker 0: yeah, but anyway, but I Guess if you're a monster hunter person and I think there is a quite an overlap between monster hunter people and Pokemon people At least I know several people who are into both things I People.
Speaker 1: I know I can't imagine them playing both of those games.
Speaker 0: So I know some people who play both of those games.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I know I mean both played both of the other.
Speaker 1: the antic walk around and do basically the same thing games.
Speaker 0: Well, that's the thing right is?
Speaker 0: I guess if you're a person who loves both of these games.
Speaker 0: right, it's like Could you end up like Going at doing?
Speaker 0: you're walking around and like you hope you go to a location.
Speaker 0: open up Pokemon go play play play play play Play.
Speaker 0: open up the monster hunter play play play play play.
Speaker 0: then change locations.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's possible especially if there's like raid locations and I feel like it's gonna have that kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: yeah, I wonder if people are gonna gonna do that.
Speaker 0: and or I wonder if this one will Peter out the way the Harry Potter one day.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna guess this one will Peter out similar to the Harry Potter one.
Speaker 1: My guess is Pokemon.
Speaker 1: intellectual property is the sole driver of continued interest in Pokemon go.
Speaker 0: But this this monster hunter has a lot in common with Pokemon that Harry Potter doesn't.
Speaker 1: it does.
Speaker 0: But it doesn't have any of monsters and I don't think it has as much Redding all sorts of different monster bits to craft things.
Speaker 0: It doesn't have as much reach in North America As a much bigger reach than you realize monster hunter is.
Speaker 1: I know it's huge.
Speaker 1: I don't think it has the reach of folks not fortnight huge.
Speaker 0: It's not Pokemon huge, but I think it's actually.
Speaker 0: you know what it is.
Speaker 0: it's like Pokemon is big because you're taking into account, you know, the anime and the merchandise and the move.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, there's a whole system feeding that that core intellectual property, right?
Speaker 0: I think if you compared only the Pokemon video game in North America to only Monster hunter video game in North America.
Speaker 0: I think the numbers there are probably closer than you realize.
Speaker 1: and no I'm not disagreeing with that at all.
Speaker 1: I just think the copy the overlap in terms of someone who will want to play a walk-around nothing Yeah.
Speaker 0: So what I'm saying is that I think only the kind of person who's playing The video game the real video game is the kind of person who's gonna play the walk-around one.
Speaker 1: I think someone who plays monster hunter the video game But does not play Pokemon the video game will be likely less interested in this once they realize what it is.
Speaker 1: But I think Pokemon I've seen it that IP will get people to consume terrible terrible things.
Speaker 0: just Here's unaware of what's going on in the monster hunter.
Speaker 1: I just don't think it's big enough to stay in a game like this in North America.
Speaker 0: It's I think it's.
Speaker 0: I think it definitely could be big enough.
Speaker 1: Well, we'll see.
Speaker 1: I'll bet that this Peters out around the same time frame that Harry Potter was bigger than monster hunter as an IP and that died.
Speaker 0: But Harry Potter doesn't have a video game right.
Speaker 0: so audience and you know.
Speaker 0: And it doesn't have a collecting thing going on.
Speaker 0: right monster hunter is like very similar to Pokemon.
Speaker 1: So yep, we shall see but anyway Things of the day.
Speaker 1: so a little video.
Speaker 1: This is a train guy.
Speaker 1: He's got a. there's a complex model train set up and They've gone further.
Speaker 1: There's a camera on one of the trains so you can go around.
Speaker 0: I've seen people do that before.
Speaker 1: yeah but the problem is there's a monster.
Speaker 1: if you want to take this train there is a cat and they videoed the various interactions between the cat who lives in the place where this train set is and The train trying to navigate its space and this was Surprisingly cute and actually really funny and wholesome.
Speaker 1: I it's a short video, and I recommend watching it.
Speaker 0: I mean you know model trains at least the real ones are pretty sturdy.
Speaker 0: a cat's not gonna break them as long as doesn't like Fall off the table, but it's funny cuz like one of them.
Speaker 0: They don't go fast enough to hurt the cat either.
Speaker 1: Get electrocuted on the rails It doesn't do anything just sits there but it like looks at it when it comes back around the cat's looking at it with malice of forethought and Suddenly a little cat paw just goes bop out of nowhere.
Speaker 0: Yep Well, so I want you to imagine that there's a water main break which is bad news.
Speaker 0: right means everyone Can't drink water and has to wait, and you know it's it's not good.
Speaker 0: You got to fix that shit quickly right?
Speaker 1: I mean when they turn off the water at RIT They shut the campus down.
Speaker 0: Yeah And also right water mains have high pressure water right.
Speaker 0: cuz it's like think about the pressure coming out in your shower.
Speaker 0: Well the main water main That's serving the whole building the whole area has to have enough pressure for all that.
Speaker 0: if everyone turns on their shower at the same Time water has to come out right.
Speaker 0: so that's the amount of pressure.
Speaker 0: That's upstream in the water supply right.
Speaker 0: so What do you do if you have this high pressure water pipe and it breaks and you got to fix it?
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: you know water is coming out of it like Flooding everybody.
Speaker 0: I guess you could try to find the valves on either end and like close one and then Right then sort of repair it like weld it shut maybe But you know that's not maybe not the best idea on the situation.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of ways to handle that but anyway.
Speaker 0: It's like well if you're not gonna turn off the water How could you possibly seal it shut?
Speaker 0: it's not like you could weld while there's water going Right.
Speaker 0: it's not like you could take some sort of metal lid and like you know wrap it around.
Speaker 0: It's like it's just gonna blast.
Speaker 0: you know you no one no human is strong enough to like.
Speaker 0: You know maybe I guess they could invent some sort of machine that does it and the machine is stronger than the blasting water.
Speaker 0: But nope there is of course a much simpler way to do it.
Speaker 0: That is probably not interesting at all to anyone with plumbing knowledge.
Speaker 0: They'd be like yep That's how you do that, but for someone without plumbing knowledge This is not a repair that you would see every day.
Speaker 0: It's not a technique that you would know unless someone taught it to you.
Speaker 0: so seeing somebody Use this repair method that is simple, but yet ingenious is like oh That's how they do that and that's nice to see and you feel like you're learning when you want to see this.
Speaker 1: yeah Yeah in the meta moment really quickly of course no conventions for us for a while But stay tuned for what's coming up.
Speaker 1: video from an online panel of zinc icon is on YouTube already and Soon I should have some video from the panel.
Speaker 1: Scott And I just did at PAX East on competitive versus casual.
Speaker 1: so I actually had someone of all day.
Speaker 1: someone messaged me on LinkedIn Asking if there was video of that panel.
Speaker 0: Okay, so well someone else someone in the crowd videoed the panel and just uploaded their unedited video to you guys.
Speaker 1: So and hopefully this will be the last time we've had to record a panel at a con in masks Just because it it definitely muffles the audio.
Speaker 1: I've had to do some Significant audio engineering to get this out.
Speaker 1: the audio good, but it's good enough.
Speaker 1: It'll work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the new microphones.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're pretty good -.
Speaker 0: yeah, the website is progressing.
Speaker 0: It helps that we now know that those microphones have a touchscreen and we can adjust them And it also.
Speaker 0: the book club book is The satanic versus by Salman Rushdie and I as of yesterday have read every satanic verse I got.
Speaker 1: I got a couple more weeks of verses and then I'll be good to go.
Speaker 0: I know there are zero verses from the lips of Satan that have not entered that have not been transcribed into English and then Inserted into my eyeballs and interpreted by my meat brain.
Speaker 1: So just so give a couple weeks.
Speaker 1: We'll do the show on it.
Speaker 1: If you haven't started reading it.
Speaker 1: It's not actually that long of a read Just roll with it, but it wasn't due with the library until for two more.
Speaker 0: I'm supposed to return it on Thursday and I finished it yesterday.
Speaker 0: so and I think the library was a great strategy for the book club because I was like Well, I have to finish this by X day, right so I can return it on time.
Speaker 0: I don't want to renew it renewing sucks Yeah, and then it's like well, it means I had to read this many pages per day.
Speaker 0: but sometimes You might read a little under because like a big chapter ends.
Speaker 0: and sometimes you read a little over because you can see it's like Three pages to the next chapter, right?
Speaker 0: In the middle of something and then once the end is in sight It's like you're holding like a handful of pages in your right hand and it's like alright, I guess we're finishing this.
Speaker 0: It's like the end.
Speaker 1: I think the most important thing for any of you who haven't picked up this book club book.
Speaker 1: yet Is that if you did not know the geopolitical context of?
Speaker 1: The government of Iran and religious extremists trying to murder the man who wrote it You would never believe that a government and a religion Or at least an aspect of a religion was trying to murder anyone over what is just a perfectly straightforward book.
Speaker 1: Well,
Speaker 0: no, no No, if I I mean there was a particular chapter in there where if I knew that there were fundamentalists radical religious people on earth and I knew that that religion that was being talked about in that chapter was their chapter I Could see how it would make those fundamentalist people quite angry.
Speaker 1: true To get to the level Particular chapter, but to get to the level of global theological leaders and heads of government That's just.
Speaker 0: that was just a. I mean if there was right a you know, we're close to it I guess but it's like We we to my knowledge.
Speaker 0: I don't see any like ultra right-wing Christian governments, right At least you know, I guess state we see states in the United States that they have those we just talked about, Florida Yeah, but we haven't seen countries right that you know, we would probably see the same thing.
Speaker 0: But also, you know note that it was only one going after people for like, you know LGBTQ books like.
Speaker 1: I guess also there are tons of books that cover similar or even more offensive to that group Content and this one was picked out for specific political reasons related to Iran.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's just it's really just to quit right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, there there are tons and tons and tons of you know books movies whatever media artwork stories criticizing Everything that there is to criticize.
Speaker 1: 88 was just a particularly unlucky year to be the one who wrote a book about this, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know It just so happens.
Speaker 0: the fundamentalist people only find out about and focus on certain ones for completely Circumstantial reasons and it happened to be Zalman Rushdie and this book and also that French guy with the comics And a few and a few others who I apologize.
Speaker 0: I don't know of you.
Speaker 1: Well, it's like with the whole South Park thing where they portrayed Muhammad a couple of times as just a superhero In the show and then later they couldn't portray it again after a backlash, but no one actually noticed the first time.
Speaker 1: hmm Anyway, anyway, let's just dive right into it because there's hockey coming.
Speaker 1: so uh Lore in games is kind of an interesting topic because like.
Speaker 1: on one hand You've got a style of game that has existed for all of time the kind of game that's gone.
Speaker 1: I don't really like to play that much anymore.
Speaker 1: where there's a game an independent of that game.
Speaker 1: There's basically Tooltips filled with just pages and pages of text.
Speaker 1: you can read if you care But they don't in any way impact the game.
Speaker 1: like you might even not know that that lore is in there like I don't know a Scrolls type game where you could find out the pages of text about a particular Name of a person in the game.
Speaker 0: the ones you think of are like the old scrolls, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, where you can read you could go into a place in like this books in like every house and you can read the books.
Speaker 0: Right and the books are only a few pages each.
Speaker 1: But you know They're telling you information about the game world or setting.
Speaker 1: that Doesn't really matter in terms of the mechanics of the game you're playing.
Speaker 1: It's just kind of there and in fact if you missed it might not even know you missed anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I mean, you know this this it's not just video games, right?
Speaker 0: It's like there's role-playing games that come with lots and lots of text.
Speaker 0: There are Board games that have like stories before in the front of the instruction manual, right?
Speaker 1: What is this?
Speaker 1: while I'm moving cubes and discs around a map what's it about Germany?
Speaker 0: something right there.
Speaker 0: every war game has a fucking.
Speaker 0: You know all kinds of shit lore real often non-fictional lore You know.
Speaker 0: even in any s game It's like, you know Zelda 1 you open up the instruction manual has lore and you know and at the end There's this lore at the end.
Speaker 0: We're at this text before at the beginning of the game.
Speaker 1: in the other two You don't read the instruction book.
Speaker 1: Is that Zelda?
Speaker 1: Answer.
Speaker 1: No, that's it.
Speaker 1: It's complicated.
Speaker 1: who was involved in that game.
Speaker 1: But yeah, there's just some princess asleep.
Speaker 1: What am I doing?
Speaker 1: Huh?
Speaker 1: Right or left?
Speaker 1: it doesn't matter, right.
Speaker 0: but you know people may have games and the games have looked and sometimes the lore is delivered as Cutscenes.
Speaker 0: right and for some reason when the lore is delivered in like a cutscene form or an unskippable form or Dialogue along the way right half-life 2 being the most indicated Style, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah people don't sort of view it as a separate thing because you just sort of Get it for free.
Speaker 0: right people tend to.
Speaker 0: when they people talk about lore they're usually talking about when the lore is delivered as In a separate or non integrated fashion such that only some of the people who go out of their way to Get that, you know additional Experience will get it and most people will not.
Speaker 0: We matter what kind of game it is.
Speaker 1: I'd also say there's an interesting phenomenon where there are definitely a large number of people who play games Primarily to seek out that lore specifically.
Speaker 0: almost more so there are people who play games and give no craps about lore.
Speaker 1: Overwatch is so much like that.
Speaker 1: Like I play a lot of overwatch Like it's my primary FPS right now and I gotta say I actually don't know what the fuck is up with most of the characters.
Speaker 1: I don't know what the story is.
Speaker 0: Even fortnight has lower.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a fuck if I know what's going on in fortnight Scott's Kojo is always trying to explain like oh, yeah There's so-and-so attack so and so and why.
Speaker 1: that's why that statues there and I'm just like, uh, anyway, there's a sniper in that tree.
Speaker 0: It's like there's nothing wrong with being either kind of person, right?
Speaker 0: I just feel like When you make a game of any kind Right.
Speaker 0: It's like you're trying to cater to these two audiences and you sort of taken these two Almost separate products with separate audiences and sort of glued one to the other, right?
Speaker 0: It's like well, there's people who need scissors and there's people who need forks.
Speaker 0: so I took a scissor and glued it to a fork and now everyone buys my scissor fork.
Speaker 0: the four people just sort of Use the fork part and like there's a scissor hanging off there for no reason that they never cut anything with and this is Buy it and they cut everything with it and there's a fork hanging off that they never eat with.
Speaker 0: and It's like why didn't the fork person buy a fork and this is a person by a scissor.
Speaker 0: Why are you selling scissor forks?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like if you're going to combine the two things they should be integrated right?
Speaker 0: Like I said half-life 2 Etc, etc.
Speaker 0: to where you know The people getting it are getting the full thing and they're not just sort of ignoring half of what the effort.
Speaker 1: There's a lot to parse here.
Speaker 1: there's a lot going on.
Speaker 1: So on one hand some of this is just the evolution of games.
Speaker 1: Like I think a lot of that old.
Speaker 1: There's four paragraphs of text in a tooltip if you click on an item in your inventory that you would never otherwise find.
Speaker 1: I think that just comes out of the tang to the limitations of how old games were made.
Speaker 1: Lotta old em, like a lot of old muds were.
Speaker 1: just look at stuff and there's walls of text everywhere.
Speaker 0: Well, I think some of that is okay because like you might be playing a game, right?
Speaker 0: And you might not be a lore person who's out there.
Speaker 0: You don't really wants to learn everything about the world But you might see an object in the game and be like I want to just I'm playing this game I just want to know more about that thing right there.
Speaker 0: You know, like I need more information about that one thing and then there you go.
Speaker 0: The information is there when you need it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right But I guess when you need.
Speaker 1: it is also an interesting attribute because some games that lore in No way intersects with playing beating or enjoying the game at all other than Exploring it for its own sake.
Speaker 1: like there's nothing you could learn from the lore that would impact you decisions You would make in other parts of the game.
Speaker 0: No But it might.
Speaker 0: you might be able to instead of feasting on all of the lore and becoming like an expert on you know The universe of whatever name it is, right?
Speaker 0: You might take in a little bit of lore here a little bit of lore there, right?
Speaker 0: Just to sort of you know pepper it in right?
Speaker 0: I think that a good example right and I think a game that has a really interesting take on lore is the Metroid Prime right where and the other Metroid Prime's where you'd go around the game and The game would want you to scan things to get lower, right?
Speaker 0: and so First of all You had some people who were just like completionist because the game would tell you how much of the lore you found and scanned.
Speaker 0: So whether you read the lore or not There was like this incentive.
Speaker 0: If you're a completionist, it's like find every hidden lore thing that could be scanned and scan them all.
Speaker 1: Yeah Even if you never read the text and I think that kind of player much like the Korok seeds 50/50 if they read the lore or not Probably don't not.
Speaker 0: Yeah But at the same time that someone who really wants lore Right might read all the lore or at least find them all online or something and read them.
Speaker 0: But a Casual player right might just sort of scan the lore as they go around right mostly not reading it But in a particularly interesting room.
Speaker 0: Let's say they might see like some creature in a tank of liquid and they'll scan it and they'll be like.
Speaker 0: That's a unique and interesting thing.
Speaker 0: What's up with that?
Speaker 0: and they read it and there's additional context there and that can you know in?
Speaker 0: Enhances the meaning and the storytelling of the area that they're in.
Speaker 0: Right, even though they only read like one out of 20 30 lures.
Speaker 1: I would say that is well done and well designed.
Speaker 1: Consuming that kind of lore should lead to better heuristics in terms of interacting with the game.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying that's required but that is a sign of high to high level elegant design, right?
Speaker 0: it would certainly be a very good game design if you know the story of The things in the game actually impacted the play.
Speaker 0: It can make you just care more right even though it might not change your game decisions Just making you care more and increasing the you know emotional impact of the next boss fight.
Speaker 0: because you read the lower and Day or sex human revolution.
Speaker 1: There's a moment where some lore basically I found out that some character caused the death of an NPC I liked and I chose to kill a bunch of other fuckers that I otherwise wouldn't have killed once I found that out
Speaker 0: Right, so it's like, you know, even if it didn't have a decision component, you know If that character was just the next boss fight no matter what and you were going to kill them no matter what?
Speaker 0: It's just knowing that information Right?
Speaker 0: might you know make you care more about that next boss, you know Like residence because we're talking about residuals.
Speaker 1: the other day Resident Evil 4 knowing what's going on in the world kind of impacted how I interacted with the world.
Speaker 1: but like other resident evils Fuck if I know what's going on.
Speaker 1: I'm just playing the game and solving the puzzles Right.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's definitely Resident Evil definitely has a problem.
Speaker 0: I played a lot of them almost um You know.
Speaker 0: and it's like if you don't know the stories of like earlier ones like and you try to play like five.
Speaker 0: It's like there's huge, you know moments that are supposed to have an emotional impact in five But if you haven't played one, two, three four, it's like who the hell is this?
Speaker 0: And why do I care?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like surprise.
Speaker 0: It was me all along.
Speaker 0: It's like Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: it's like what I don't.
Speaker 0: It's like it was me all along.
Speaker 0: it's like you're still alive.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, it's completely different.
Speaker 1: But there's also the evolution of lore dumps like as craft in that like the half-life thing.
Speaker 1: the when people first played half-life and half-life - The fact that you're like the game is just sort of you're learning the story While you play and like walking around like that style of lore dump was really novel.
Speaker 1: But now honestly when a game does that to me all I can think is oh, they're just doing the half-life thing.
Speaker 0: It's just a cutscene where I can walk around during yeah Mmm, so I think the biggest problem for me is that like, you know, I'm a person who reads fantasy novels, right?
Speaker 0: And sci-fi novels.
Speaker 0: It's not like I dislike lore and learning about fictional worlds, right?
Speaker 0: The problem is is that at least video games and to a larger extent other kinds of games When they deliver the lore in a non integrated way, right?
Speaker 0: It's sort of like, you know a wrong mood wrong time.
Speaker 0: deal where it's like.
Speaker 0: I'm right now playing, you know I'm not literally right now, but let's say that I'm right now playing an old-school, right?
Speaker 0: I'm playing an old-school because I'm in the mood to go explore and You know level up my dude and hit some monsters with a sword or yell at them and make them fall off a cliff.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like that's the mood I'm in.
Speaker 0: if I was in the mood to read some books, I would go get a fantasy novel and read it.
Speaker 0: Oh, right.
Speaker 0: So if I'm walking around slashing skeletons, and I there's a treasure chest.
Speaker 0: I'm like, ooh gold Yes swords.
Speaker 1: Yes magic spells You open that treasure chest and it's like here are four paragraphs of text, right.
Speaker 0: and then there's a book and it's like, okay there's one book.
Speaker 0: if it has like a Paragraph it's like I might you know, it might I might read it Especially.
Speaker 0: it might cuz you know, it might have like a secret on it like, you know Oh, there's treasure in this place.
Speaker 0: go find it or something like that, right?
Speaker 0: But if I go in it's like aha I beat the skeleton and I got a key and I open the open a door and there's like a library in there with a Bunch of books.
Speaker 0: It's like well, I'm not in a book reading mood right now.
Speaker 1: Well, it's funny.
Speaker 0: I believe I was in a book reading mood.
Speaker 0: I would never go.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I'm gonna read I'm gonna go load Skyrim go back to that library room Read all those books on the shelf that are in there.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I blame actually like five pages of text each.
Speaker 1: early RPGs like JRPGs in particular.
Speaker 1: Final Fantasy was a big component here where the trope was.
Speaker 1: you'd find a library at some point like usually toward the like the middle of the game or like the second the end of the second third of the game and you could Walk around this room and like click on each shelf to quote read the book But because it was a Super Nintendo or even on it
Speaker 0: and see yeah,
Speaker 1: it's like one sentence like Ashura did the whatever and that's why X is why you're like, that's
Speaker 0: fine That's like.
Speaker 1: it takes two seconds, but I feel like people game designers Especially people who might have played those games and are now making games Remember that feeling.
Speaker 1: but they use modern technology and they just think to themselves Man, what if when I clicked on that it gave me an actual fucking book to read and would be if you think that And it's like in principle like that's awesome.
Speaker 0: But in reality, you know who how many people are in a reading mood, right?
Speaker 0: Well, they get to that book And actually experience it the more likely they open it up and say wow It's cool that this book has several pages of text and all these books are actually different.
Speaker 0: not reading them I do.
Speaker 0: I'll feel bad though for it because there is some talented writers out there who are writing all those lures for video games for for everything right and You know everyone even the people who care about lore are playing the video game part, right?
Speaker 0: You can't not play the game part, but only some of the people are reading the lore part.
Speaker 0: so it's like a bunch of people did all this work to write so much text and Or make cutscenes and all this other stuff and a lot of people who are playing some percentage are just skipping that.
Speaker 1: Well, look at overwatch.
Speaker 1: go further.
Speaker 1: It ain't even in the game.
Speaker 1: You want to learn that lower like the characters talk to each other in the game?
Speaker 1: But honestly, I have no idea what the fuck they're talking about And the only way to know is to watch YouTube videos and read comics that are outside of the game entirely.
Speaker 1: They're not even in the game.
Speaker 0: We played the moon breakers and there was like some audio drama in the top right corner.
Speaker 0: Did you listen to the audio drum?
Speaker 1: I couldn't figure out how to stop it from playing at first because that you know for 10 seconds.
Speaker 1: so it just kept playing while I was playing the game and I I feel bad because it sounded like there was some interesting stuff going on there.
Speaker 0: We put a lot of effort into it, but it's like my brain Miniatures.
Speaker 1: my brain started filtering it out after about a minute and a half and I remembered.
Speaker 1: I noticed unless wait a minute And I realized it had stopped playing and it was like 40 minutes long and I didn't remember One thing.
Speaker 1: I could not tell you anything about what that audio had explained for the previous half hour.
Speaker 1: And then there's games like like a lot of adventure games.
Speaker 1: do this or disco.
Speaker 1: Elysium is a really good example where Part of the game is like.
Speaker 1: the game is figure out the lore, you know This game is literally and there's other games like it.
Speaker 1: You don't know shit about the world as a player and you're not expected to Playing the game.
Speaker 1: Your goal is to figure out what the fuck is going on.
Speaker 1: So the game mechanics are Learn lore use that lore to react to the world to learn more lore mmm, and that is very elegant, but that also does not lend itself to games that are not Adjacent to the adventure game genre without extreme play craft.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So I mean, you know, I talked about What's it called?
Speaker 0: King of Dragon Pass has a very unique thing going on where you know, there's this sort of Common lore like things that like basically everyone knows about.
Speaker 0: you know the gods and the history of the world right and when you start the game up all that lore is like in there and you Can just read it right which takes a while It's like.
Speaker 0: but it actually matters because some of this right when you go on a hero quest in the game Part of the hero quests are basically like sort of reading comprehension tests.
Speaker 0: I'm like, how much do you remember from that lore?
Speaker 0: you read you have to.
Speaker 0: there's multiple choice questions, you know answer them correctly You know, otherwise you might not succeed at the hero quest.
Speaker 0: but at the same time right doing things in the game reveals And or modifies the lore.
Speaker 0: so it's like you'll go to a page in the lore in the game about like a god Right, maybe like, you know the Thor equivalent and it's like, you know, there's the black text which is the text That's always there every time right and then based on if something happened in the game.
Speaker 0: There might be like Edits that come into play right because it's like, you know like some added blue sentences or some things crossed out or changed because you played and things happened and Maybe you learned differently or your people believe differently or you know You discovered an artifact and then it's that right.
Speaker 0: and it's like the history right.
Speaker 0: it changes It might be changing to be more correct or more incorrect or who knows We're with a certain motive but it's like.
Speaker 0: it's not like a set in stone thing.
Speaker 0: It's like actually part of the game like you're playing this numbers game.
Speaker 0: But meanwhile, this lore is like an actual Object, right?
Speaker 1: Well, you know what else does a shade of the lore.
Speaker 0: edits are in effect like inventory items in a sense But you need that knowledge and to read that lore in order to you know, do and accomplish certain quest.
Speaker 1: Heaven's vault.
Speaker 1: we're similar like you're learning the language and learning the lore as a mechanic in the course of play.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm There's also I mean so many.
Speaker 0: that's a story game like if you're not paying it, you know If you don't pay attention to the story, there's literally no game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like what are you doing?
Speaker 0: Missed.
Speaker 0: it's like I guess in mist you could solve a bunch of puzzles and not but it's like they do it.
Speaker 0: You wouldn't care about something.
Speaker 1: Hades is interesting in that it basically it is a solid just game to play.
Speaker 1: They basically instead of like getting a heart container.
Speaker 1: It also gives you some lower as you get better at the game like oh, yeah, you beat that thing.
Speaker 1: Now you can find out what this guy's deal is.
Speaker 1: and just because the game's well-written You're kind of excited about that and that is it diffuses itself throughout the rest of the game pretty well.
Speaker 1: I think Hades does lower very well as well.
Speaker 0: the lore in Hades comes in the form of Dialogue, right like RPG text box dialogue and it's never that long.
Speaker 0: It's like you that's the key right, it's not.
Speaker 0: it's.
Speaker 0: it's like you'll talk.
Speaker 0: you go around and talk to someone and there'll be a few sentences.
Speaker 0: and it's like If you do something, there'll be a few more sentences, right and you're never like reading pages and pages of stuff.
Speaker 0: You're never there watching a long-ass cutscene.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right, but they're able to reveal a lot in with very little.
Speaker 0: so yep.
Speaker 1: But then because you that has been revealed to you those characters when they give their little one-liners along the way in the like Stock encounters that are not changing anything about the game other than your particular run.
Speaker 1: that does color your perception and feeling about the experience Just like the the example you gave about a Metroid game and a piece of lore in a room.
Speaker 0: Yep Yeah, I think overall right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know lore is good, you know to have those people who like it.
Speaker 0: There's people who ignore it and it.
Speaker 0: it doesn't harm them by being there So but can't hurt right.
Speaker 0: at the very least It doesn't hurt to have it as long as you don't like make it so intrusive or something.
Speaker 0: But I've never I've never seen a game that was like hurt by having lore right, the worst case was they.
Speaker 0: someone put a lot of effort into lore that was ignored and That's sad right for the person who made it.
Speaker 0: But at the same time if the lore is not integrated Well, if someone's expecting me to like read a fucking book in the middle of playing a game It's like brain, you know, at least my brain doesn't like to do that Even though I like reading and I like playing games.
Speaker 0: I don't like to.
Speaker 0: it would be this.
Speaker 0: it would be the same in reverse like imagine if I was reading a novel and on Page 10 it was like beat 10 levels of missile command before you can read the next page.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess like, you know Move to play missile command right now.
Speaker 1: get that shit out of here with a novel you were coming in expecting.
Speaker 1: I just I want this story.
Speaker 1: It'll be conveyed to me via words in the movie.
Speaker 1: I want this story.
Speaker 1: It'll be conveyed to me via Spectacle and also a bunch of words.
Speaker 1: but a video game I'm going in or an entertainment software.
Speaker 1: thus me interacting with the software has to be pleasant and Entertaining if that software is just passing me through to a novel.
Speaker 1: I would have rather just read a novel the software.
Speaker 1: You could do something right?
Speaker 0: You could have like just included a novel in the box with the game As a PDF.
Speaker 0: They do or they sell them separately.
Speaker 0: right and it's like on the one hand.
Speaker 0: I'm not the kind of person It's like if I see a book that has a game brand on it, right?
Speaker 0: I'm not likely to think I'm Honestly, right going to think less of that book, right?
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna think that it's like a great book worth my time reading.
Speaker 0: but if the book is like included It's tough cuz how you know, I guess it would have to be in the old days when it was physical buying of games
Speaker 1: Like if I was a kid and they released us like Zelda 4 came out on the Super Nintendo or something like an Zelda that we didn't exist.
Speaker 1: and I put myself in that mindset of being a kid and there was a version of that game.
Speaker 1: that Came with a book about Zelda and Zelda lore.
Speaker 1: I would have read that thing cover to cover problems.
Speaker 0: If I buy a game on Steam and there's a PDF I probably won't even know that PDF is there.
Speaker 0: or if there's an e-book I won't even know it's there.
Speaker 0: But if I go back in time It's like I buy a big old PC game in a giant box that there's just.
Speaker 0: it's a big cardboard with a tiny CD jewel Case in there, right?
Speaker 0: It's like sieve 2 came with a big old rule book and that was rules and I read a lot of it, right?
Speaker 0: It's like if mech warrior 2 came with a lore book.
Speaker 0: I would have read that lore book.
Speaker 1: Yeah I didn't know much about the lore of the battle tech universe until RIT even though I knew I knew it existed.
Speaker 0: I knew a lot of it.
Speaker 0: Thanks to the there being a battle tech cartoon.
Speaker 0: That helped a lot.
Speaker 0: I knew what like mech warrior on the Super Nintendo taught me Yeah But anyway It doesn't hurt to have it But if you don't integrate it a lot of people are going to ignore it which is sad.
Speaker 0: You should integrate it no matter what kind of game it is.
Speaker 0: It should it just be off to the side as like a wall of text, right?
Speaker 1: Do integrate.
Speaker 1: people won't call it lower like people Right.
Speaker 0: It's like when I say lower I'm talking about all you know, but usually fictional.
Speaker 0: You know storytelling that is attached to the game, but most people are talking about Walls of text that you can ignore.
Speaker 1: Yep in video games This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night
Speaker 1: and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights are Ellen Joyce link Eiji dread lily Tenebrae case care makes music Chris Haddad Clinton Walton deaths Finn Joel Hayes penny rhymer Rebecca Dunn Sam Erickson Shervin von Horo and a bunch of people whose names I'm not going to say at their request.
Speaker 1: So, you know we skip Wednesday last week because we realized something profound about geek nights.
Speaker 1: We struggle to do Wednesday shows partly because Scott and I watch radically different media.
Speaker 1: But why is that a problem now?
Speaker 1: because Wednesday geek nights is the only geek nights where our sole topic is the consumption of media and Reacting to our consumption of media.
Speaker 1: It's not like games where they're.
Speaker 1: it's not the active pursuits or the areas where we have some actual Expertise.
Speaker 1: so it's sort of a weird day.
Speaker 1: So we are currently working on Retooling Wednesday geek nights in some fashion and we're also consider we're gonna add we're gonna do something We haven't done in like 14 years.
Speaker 1: We might add a couple of segments to geek nights and change up a few of the existing segments Possibly trialing them on Wednesday episodes.
Speaker 1: So stay tuned on that.
Speaker 1: the next Wednesday episode May in fact be a discussion of how we're going to retool Wednesday geek nights.
Speaker 1: you heard it here first.
Speaker 1: No one will know this unless they listened to the stinger on this episode at least for now.
Speaker 1: So, uh, I leave you as The final stinger stinger With.
Speaker 2: I don't know.
Speaker 2: she's like move your skulls to the basement because I got these drapes.
Speaker 2: I don't even get that.
Speaker 2: I'm like honey.
Speaker 2: This is work.
Speaker 2: Are you serious?
Speaker 2: Yeah, I can't put him in the basement.
Speaker 2: I mean, man.
Speaker 2: So I said fine.
Speaker 2: I'll do it.
Speaker 2: I'll put him in the basement.
Speaker 2: I started taking him down, you know, and I'm moving him one at a time.
Speaker 2: All right, right, right.
Speaker 2: I'm just kind of waiting to see what she does.
Speaker 2: I want to see how she's gonna react to it.
Speaker 2: Yeah, and she's like, you know, can you put a tarp over him?
Speaker 2: Also?
Speaker 2: Oh, no, like no, I'm not Damn it.
Speaker 2: I'm not gonna put a tarp over these things Dennis.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 2: I'll collection man.
Speaker 2: I know it's my skull collection.
Speaker 2: I worked hard to get these things and we're turning clean them.
Speaker 2: fine.
Speaker 2: Fine.
Speaker 2: I'll put him in the basement.
Speaker 2: Let's put him in the basement.
Speaker 2: But now why cover him?
Speaker 2: What is the point of covering them if you're gonna display him?
Speaker 2: if I can't display him up top?
Speaker 2: I'll put him in the basement and display them but then put a tarp.
Speaker 1: No fucking way right on and absolutely course.