Speaker 0: It's Tuesday, April 4th, 2023.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 1: And I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, we are reviewing the hot new trick-taking game, Cat in the Box.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So, uh, today is a date that is actually pretty important.
Speaker 0: Like, two earth-changing things happened in very different contexts today.
Speaker 0: And I think, I suspect, most of you listening, partly because of the American-centered focus of a lot of pop culture and, like, the kind of person who would listen to Geek Nights, you're probably thinking about the whole Trumpy thing that just happened.
Speaker 0: But a way, way more important thing happened today.
Speaker 0: Finland, officially, has joined the NATO military defensive pact in Europe.
Speaker 0: And you might be wondering, why is that such a big deal?
Speaker 0: Well, if you don't know the history of NATO, it was originally formed, essentially, to be the military alliance to make sure the Soviet Union didn't invade Europe after World War II, and that existence during the early Cold War didn't actually last that long.
Speaker 0: NATO evolved very rapidly into being a couple of things, and it's effectively a purely defensive military alliance whose primary mission is to say, "Yo, countries can't invade each other like it's the 1800s.
Speaker 0: If anyone invades any of our members, it's war with all of us.
Speaker 0: Stay out of Castle
Speaker 0: Lemongrab.".
Speaker 1: Right, and there's so many of us, and we're basically the strongest, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, it's pretty much like a war game you play, right?
Speaker 1: It's Tuesday Geek Nights, right?
Speaker 1: You play a board game.
Speaker 1: Imagine, you know, if there wasn't some end game, because it's not a board game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can't win the real world.
Speaker 0: It's not like CIV.
Speaker 1: Right, and it's just like, imagine if there's like, you know, many, many players that are all like really strong, and like they've maxed out their tech charts and everything, and all of them are officially on the same team, and if you attack any one of them, they literally all attack you, and their combined might is like several times greater than the rest of the world combined.
Speaker 1: It's like, well, I guess you just can't fuck with any of them, right?
Speaker 0: And if you don't attack them, they kind of just sit there, at least militarily, like their army isn't like moving around on your borders, it's just sitting there.
Speaker 1: Right, so now imagine, right, there's two things additionally to imagine, right?
Speaker 1: The first thing is imagine you're not in that alliance, and some country that isn't very big population-wise, but is very, very strong military-wise relative to its population, or maybe
Speaker 0: they're just next to you and way big,
Speaker 1: joins that alliance like decades, you know, maybe even almost a century after it was created, and now it's even bigger.
Speaker 1: Well,
Speaker 0: especially if you even, even like four years ago, three years ago, in fact, I would say up until the Russian illegal invasion of Ukraine started, if you asked anyone on Earth, anywhere in the world, who had heard of Finland and heard of NATO and knew anything about them, if NATO would ever join Finland, they would laugh at you and run out of breath laughing.
Speaker 0: Nobody in the world thought Finland would ever join NATO.
Speaker 0: Now, Finland worked with NATO.
Speaker 0: Finland is very closely aligned with NATO, but Finland would never join, partly due to Finland's history of being invaded by the Soviets and the Nazis simultaneously and getting very spiky as a result.
Speaker 0: That's a summary of a lot of history that is glossing over a lot of details, but it's kind of how it went down.
Speaker 0: So Finland really tried to be a country that said we're not aligned with anyone, just don't fuck with us.
Speaker 0: Russia's aggression has gotten to the point to where Finland is actually afraid that Russia might do something to them, and that is why they joined.
Speaker 0: Public opinion was like 10% of Finns wanted to join NATO, and after Russia invaded Ukraine, like 91% wanted to join NATO.
Speaker 1: The second thing I wanted you to imagine is imagine you're playing in this war game, and there's some giant alliance that's unbeatable, but it never attacks anyone.
Speaker 0: And you're trading with it heavily, like all your trade routes go there already.
Speaker 1: Right, and it's like it's over there, but you're not in it, right?
Speaker 1: But now you're in it.
Speaker 1: It's like you're feeling, like imagine the feeling of safety that has just appeared, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, there's this giant thing that is the most dangerous alliance of all the great, it's an all-star team basically, and it's like now you're on that all-star team.
Speaker 1: It's like the feeling that you would have, right, joining that team.
Speaker 1: It's like ah, no one can fuck with me now, right?
Speaker 1: It's like I don't have to worry anymore.
Speaker 0: And the other function that NATO provides is often if the UN or a collective of democratically-leaning nations want to intervene in, say, a genocide situation, it's almost always going to be NATO that actually does that work, but that's actually a secondary function.
Speaker 0: It's primary function is- It depends where the genociding is.
Speaker 0: Yes, and it also depends on the complications of the UN and a bunch of stuff that's out of scope for geek nights, not because we don't want to talk about it, because you should not be listening to us talk about it.
Speaker 1: Trying to keep it, you know, it's Tuesday, right?
Speaker 0: It is Tuesday, but what I'll say is, in my opinion, this is a win for the world.
Speaker 0: Like, it is rare that we get news where I would say that is no strings attached, just good news that made the world a safer place.
Speaker 0: Like, and I'm guilty of this, especially, you know, Twitter.
Speaker 0: less so, because I don't use Twitter anymore, but of really focusing on the things that are fucked up and the battles we're losing around the world.
Speaker 0: But wins do happen, and I think it's important to celebrate them when they do.
Speaker 0: And this is just good news for the world that this happened.
Speaker 0: We are materially safer today than we were yesterday as a world.
Speaker 1: No, the people of Finland are.
Speaker 0: Well, arguably everyone else, because this likely will deter further Russian escalation of this conflict, because now they can't fuck with Finland.
Speaker 0: Sweden's about to join NATO as well.
Speaker 0: As soon as there is no official war anymore, Ukraine is going to join NATO.
Speaker 0: It's starting to come together.
Speaker 0: And of course, the Trump thing happened today, but whatever.
Speaker 0: He was charged with 34 felony counts, and it's now a component situation.
Speaker 1: I still haven't seen what exactly the felonies were.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, you can.
Speaker 0: The arraignment happened today.
Speaker 0: The indictment was released.
Speaker 0: You can just read it.
Speaker 1: I have not read it.
Speaker 1: I thought that they were, wasn't it all like, you know, like falsification of business records?
Speaker 0: So the fun part is, this is a full, this is, all I'll say is, this is the least dangerous thing that is happening to that dude right now in terms of lawsuits and criminal charges.
Speaker 0: Like, this is the lowest hanging, weakest thing.
Speaker 0: But even this, every one of those counts theoretically could be four years in prison.
Speaker 0: It's a classy felony.
Speaker 1: Right, and it's like people think like, oh, they're getting, you know, it's, you know, you think, okay, they got Al Capone like on some technicality, right?
Speaker 1: But it's like, tax evasion is a normal crime that people get in trouble for all the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, falsifying business records too.
Speaker 0: Like if I falsified one business record for gig nights, like to cheat on my taxes or something, I would go to fucking prison.
Speaker 1: Right, this isn't some weird, it's, you know, even though you think, ah, they didn't get him on the thing he really did, right?
Speaker 1: The thing he really did was evil XYZ, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, but this is a crime that is commonly charged to various shady business people.
Speaker 1: Like people go to prison for this all the time.
Speaker 1: It's a regular deal.
Speaker 1: It's not strange, right?
Speaker 1: It just happens to be the thing that the New York DA investigated and found and believes they found evidence of and has a case for.
Speaker 1: And so that is what they chose to charge him with.
Speaker 1: And it's a thing that evil people do a lot, which is, you know, when they do their accounting, they write down that they spent the money on thing A, when actually the money was spent on thing B. And you know what?
Speaker 1: It's a crime, even if thing A and thing B are both legal things.
Speaker 1: Like if you, if you have, if I have a, I don't know, a grocery store and I write down that I spent a thousand dollars on potatoes and I spent the thousand dollars on employees, that's a crime.
Speaker 1: I have to write down what I spent the money for truthfully in my accounting.
Speaker 0: And the funniest part of this.
Speaker 1: And if I was a grocery store and I did that and the amount of money was big enough to draw attention, I would get charged with the same crime, not thirty four times.
Speaker 0: And the argument American Republicans are making across the board today is actually kind of funny.
Speaker 0: And I feel like this isn't going to work out.
Speaker 0: They're basically saying you're only charged with this because he's Trump and you're politicized.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: is people get charged with this all the time.
Speaker 0: What they're actually saying is you charged a rich person with a crime that only poor people are supposed to go to prison for.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's what they're actually saying.
Speaker 1: But rich people are charged with this crime also.
Speaker 1: They usually just the only the truly evil ones actually do it.
Speaker 0: Or they plead guilty and agree to a plea deal or something.
Speaker 1: Or I'm surprised they didn't do that.
Speaker 1: That's what you should have done.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, there's a lot going on there that I think is out of the scope of a Tuesday gig nights.
Speaker 1: Or they rich people wisely get away with it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: By not being not being mafia like fake mafioso incompetent.
Speaker 0: His lawyer sounds like a like a bad mafia actor from a B movie.
Speaker 0: It's really funny to listen to this, dude.
Speaker 0: But I guess this is not a small deal.
Speaker 0: What happened?
Speaker 0: and like don't pop the corks on the champagne about how he's finally going down because there's a long road to come.
Speaker 0: Like, don't hold your breath on this.
Speaker 1: But this is not to say he's not guilty to be a hung jury.
Speaker 0: A lot of luck could happen.
Speaker 0: But this is not.
Speaker 0: this is not nothing.
Speaker 0: This is a real danger to this dude.
Speaker 1: He's not happy.
Speaker 0: No, he is definitely not happy.
Speaker 0: What if CNN was great?
Speaker 0: I was actually watching CNN at work when it went down and CNN was like, he looks irritated and angry and deflated.
Speaker 0: And then one of the other CNN people is like, that is not the face of defiance.
Speaker 0: And then he starts laughing.
Speaker 0: And this was on the air live.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: In tragic news, Klaus Teuber, who you may know as the designer of Settlers of Catan, one of the most important board games to ever be written and designed, has died after a brief and severe illness.
Speaker 0: He was 70.
Speaker 0: His family confirmed the death in a press release.
Speaker 0: The tabletop world is mourning this man.
Speaker 1: I mean, I mean, what I what I heard is least from the.
Speaker 1: you know, it's not a person ever knew.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But to my knowledge, not some milkshake duck.
Speaker 1: He was just like a nice old man.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I've never heard of any.
Speaker 0: I've never heard a negative story about him.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: But basically, he didn't actually design that many games.
Speaker 1: But there are others that you may have heard.
Speaker 0: Let's see.
Speaker 0: I've played Hoity Toity.
Speaker 1: The Endecker.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Hoity Toity is a big one.
Speaker 0: Hoity Toity.
Speaker 1: Because it was the only good one.
Speaker 1: Settlers just so much bigger.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And Settlers like to give you a sense, but gig nights, if Settlers hadn't been made and we hadn't encountered it when we did, I don't think gig nights would have formed.
Speaker 0: I don't even know if our friendship like that Settlers of Catan was deeply foundational to my life because of when and how I encountered it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, prior to right going to college, right.
Speaker 1: You know, the board games I knew were the ones they had at the toy store, some of which were nerdy.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Like Axis and Allies, Risk, Shogun.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Which is renamed ten times.
Speaker 0: IkuSub.
Speaker 1: And then there were the ones that they had at the gaming store, BattleTech, D&D.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Magic the Gathering.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: These were the nerdy tabletop game.
Speaker 0: I think the nerdiest tabletop game I knew of were those war games, but I didn't actually know what they were like.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: In the United States, it's like the board games didn't really, like there weren't lots of new ones, you know.
Speaker 1: It's like occasionally you might see one that was like, you know, even when I thought there was a new one, like I was a kid watching TV to be a commercial for some new board game.
Speaker 1: And it would be like, there were always usually kids board games and you'd think it was a new one, but actually it was just a reprint of some Milton Bradley one from the sixties or the fifties.
Speaker 1: Or it's like, you know, it's like they, or it was an already existing game.
Speaker 1: They got reprinted and they updated the graphics and they put out ads for it.
Speaker 1: Very rare that there were truly new board games in the US on the market.
Speaker 1: And if they weren't the Milton Bradley Parker Brothers ones that were in the toy store, they weren't in, they weren't available easily at all.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And then settlers came along and we were in college and some people were playing settlers and I was like, I was not interested in whatever that was, even though I knew nothing about whatever that was.
Speaker 0: And partly like, to be fair, part of the reason we were interested is people playing.
Speaker 0: it were a little shady.
Speaker 0: I'm just going to leave it at that.
Speaker 1: But they were, I'm like, all I knew is that those people over there that I don't want to mess with are playing, are doing something called settlers and they're doing it all the time.
Speaker 1: And I don't want to be with those people.
Speaker 1: So I don't want to be with that settlers, whatever that settlers is, it's got nothing to do with me.
Speaker 1: Meh.
Speaker 0: And we kind of just ended up playing a game with them one night.
Speaker 0: I don't remember why.
Speaker 1: Somehow I ended up playing the settlers and I'm like, oh, that's what this is.
Speaker 0: And we thought it was a rule.
Speaker 1: This is the year 2000.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: God damn, that was a long time ago.
Speaker 0: I just like, I just like flash back to how much, how much of my life I've lived since that point.
Speaker 0: But I remember we thought the way the robber worked is if someone rolled a seven, everyone had to give them a card and the robber moved to the desert.
Speaker 1: That's not what I, no, I thought that it was just customary to try to bribe them with a card so that you could convince them not to bribe, not to attack you.
Speaker 0: But, you know, they refused to continue to play with us after Scott put, just took a bribe and then put the robber on a guy.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the guy got so mad, we never played with them again.
Speaker 0: But we had our own copy by that point.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the point was, is that, you know, we had the settlers and we started playing that a whole bunch.
Speaker 1: And then that pretty much led us to go, you know, we went to the game store where I was already going to the game store, but I wasn't looking, you know, for anything other than, you know, RPGs, Battletechs, card games.
Speaker 0: And we started to look at the shelf we never looked at normally.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: There was the shelf over the dice or the shelf of board games that were not Toys R Us, toy store games.
Speaker 1: And I was like, oh, well, this is the section where the settlers comes from.
Speaker 1: It's the section the settlers is in.
Speaker 1: But there's other things here.
Speaker 1: Let's take a look at those.
Speaker 1: And we're still here 23 years later looking at those other ones.
Speaker 1: And it's become, you know, I guess we were ahead of the curve.
Speaker 1: We were so cool.
Speaker 1: But it became a phenomenon of, you know, the European non toy store, quote, designer board games are now a huge thing.
Speaker 1: Everybody's all over it.
Speaker 0: I mean, now, like settlers is in the toy stores like that.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: That is not how it was.
Speaker 0: And while we've been right on settlers, probably because we played it out, I've played settlers easily over 100 times, probably a couple of hundred times because I used to play a lot, especially with the five, six player expansion.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I only played the cities and nights a few times.
Speaker 0: I actually enjoyed it.
Speaker 1: It was pretty good, but not that many times.
Speaker 0: But while we have played settlers out, like I still recommend settlers to people all the time because it is a fantastic game.
Speaker 0: Don't judge a game by what it's like when Fox only final destination happens.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like if you've played settlers, you know, it's like that's really.
Speaker 1: the only criticism you can make of settlers is that if you have played it many, many, many times and you are, you know, someone who really thinks about winning and strategy and tries hard at games to win, you will see the truth of settlers, which is that if all players are pro, the dice will determine the winner.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: That's just you might.
Speaker 1: So if all players are pro, you might as well toss a coin to see who won.
Speaker 0: But that applies to every game ever designed on Earth.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: But well, well, other than the arbitrary ones, the draw ones and the solvable ones.
Speaker 1: What I'm saying is that it's possible, you know, going through the motions of a settlers instead of tossing a coin might be satisfying, even though you wreck everyone recognizes the dice, determine the result.
Speaker 1: But if any number of players are not pro settlers is is like a for real game.
Speaker 1: There isn't really you know, it's it's.
Speaker 1: it's like what's wrong with it?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, think about it.
Speaker 0: We talk like a tabletop game.
Speaker 0: If it hits the table 10 times, that's already a legendary game in our eyes.
Speaker 0: Like if I'll play a game 10 times, that is like an S tier game.
Speaker 0: That is amazing.
Speaker 0: Even more than once is a big hurdle.
Speaker 0: A lot of games have to get over.
Speaker 0: And yet I think most people who that I played it do play a hundred times.
Speaker 0: That says something.
Speaker 1: I think the most people I know who play Catan end up playing it many, many times.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Like people go through a phase like Catan is their thing and they keep playing it a bunch, which is something I don't see for other really popular games.
Speaker 1: Like, you know, like, you know, a lot of people have bought copies of root, like I've heard from, you know, the listener that it's like selling out constantly.
Speaker 1: And like you can't get it in a lot of places.
Speaker 1: And, you know, it's like any time it comes out like they, you know, it's like it sells quickly.
Speaker 1: But yet how many people are playing root many, many times?
Speaker 0: I want to.
Speaker 0: And now that now that the pan doodle is in the long tail, I feel like I want to make that happen.
Speaker 1: But I'm saying is like I think a lot of people have root clearly because it sold a lot of copies.
Speaker 1: A lot of people have wingspan because it sold a lot of copies.
Speaker 1: But at least I don't have any data, so I could just be wrong and completely bullshitting.
Speaker 1: But my feeling is that people aren't playing.
Speaker 1: If they have wingspan, people aren't playing wingspan constantly and making it like a thing and playing it a whole bunch.
Speaker 1: They're playing it occasionally, you know, a few times.
Speaker 1: But I see lots of people who when they become Settlers people, then they go through a phase of playing it a fuckton.
Speaker 0: I think games that trigger that are extremely rare.
Speaker 0: And there's some like I struggle to define exactly what it is.
Speaker 0: There's like this sweet spot of interaction and politics and mechanics that I would have to spend some time thinking about to try to identify what it is.
Speaker 0: But T&E does that for me.
Speaker 0: Hans and Toytonica actually does that for me.
Speaker 0: A lot of trick taking games do and the list is running out fast.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the point is, is that Klaus, the gentleman who made Settlers, we have much to thank him for and it is sad that he has departed from the world of the living.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: Four went out for a legend.
Speaker 0: And one last little news on an upbeat.
Speaker 0: So you might remember there was a Dungeons and Dragons movie a long time ago and we'll never speak of it again.
Speaker 0: I never actually saw it.
Speaker 1: There's the one that we saw in the theater.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I did not go.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: I was not there.
Speaker 0: I refused to go.
Speaker 0: You all went anyway.
Speaker 0: And I was like, it's going to be bad.
Speaker 1: I went knowing it would be garbage.
Speaker 1: And it was.
Speaker 1: I don't remember much about it, though.
Speaker 1: Other than that, it was garbage.
Speaker 0: I stayed home and played Counter Strike.
Speaker 0: Like, I remember.
Speaker 0: It was forgettable, right?
Speaker 0: You all came back and I was like, how was it?
Speaker 0: And you were like, and then that was.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I knew it was gonna be before I went.
Speaker 1: It wasn't like.
Speaker 1: I was disappointed.
Speaker 1: So, weren't there other D&D, besides the cartoon, right?
Speaker 1: Weren't there other D&D movies?
Speaker 1: Like, there was definitely that video.
Speaker 1: choose your own adventure one.
Speaker 0: That doesn't count.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: I don't actually know.
Speaker 0: I can only think of the two that are legit movies.
Speaker 0: If there was another one, I'm unaware of it or I'm stupid.
Speaker 0: We both forgot it and the listener is going to make fun of us.
Speaker 0: But I can't think of one.
Speaker 0: So, the new D&D movie.
Speaker 1: So, I go on IMDB, for example.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: Are these books or are these movies?
Speaker 1: Hold on.
Speaker 0: So, while you look that up, to explain, there is a new Dungeons and Dragons movie.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's a television movie.
Speaker 1: The TV movies.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it can't count TV movies.
Speaker 0: That's a rabbit hole that goes forever.
Speaker 1: But there were other things that existed.
Speaker 1: But yeah, in terms of theatrical movies.
Speaker 0: If we talk about TV movies, there were like six Lost Boys movies.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I guess in terms of theatrical movies, there was just the year 2000 Dungeons and Dragons that we saw.
Speaker 1: And then the new one, which is 23 years later.
Speaker 1: The honor among thieves one.
Speaker 0: So, how's it doing?
Speaker 0: It knocked Janwick 4 and Scream 4 out of the box office.
Speaker 0: It is crazy popular so far.
Speaker 0: The reviews come in and are saying it's great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and people have said positive things about it.
Speaker 1: But my expectations are still the same.
Speaker 0: Mine are pretty high because I think what's going on here.
Speaker 0: Because I don't usually read reviews of movies until after I see them.
Speaker 0: And I do plan to see this movie.
Speaker 0: But full disclosure, I have a lot of Hasbro stock.
Speaker 0: And I'm curious.
Speaker 0: I read a bunch of reviews.
Speaker 0: And what people seem to be saying is interesting.
Speaker 0: So you know how the things that are the D&D media that are popular are like acting and critical role and all these like D&D play shows like they're popular among certain set of people.
Speaker 0: I'm not a fan of these things, but I understand why people are nothing wrong with these things like.
Speaker 0: I want to be clear.
Speaker 0: But I think what people wanted from a D&D movie is for it to be an evolved form of what they think it feels like to play D&D.
Speaker 0: Which means sometimes it's serious.
Speaker 0: Sometimes it's funny.
Speaker 0: D&D type shit happens like the heist goes wrong or a dragon shows up at the wrong time or you burn the town down.
Speaker 0: And I get the impression this movie is that.
Speaker 0: It's the funny, weird, like.
Speaker 0: this is obviously very directly a D&D game happening.
Speaker 1: You mean the live action slayers?
Speaker 1: Is that what it is?
Speaker 1: They did.
Speaker 1: It was called Slayers.
Speaker 0: There's a bunch of Slayers we haven't watched that we should probably catch up on at some point.
Speaker 0: You and Emily never saw Try.
Speaker 0: I still have DVDs that we borrowed from Laura.
Speaker 0: Slayers is great.
Speaker 0: You love Slayers.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm only going to live so long.
Speaker 1: How much time do I want to spend watching Slayers?
Speaker 0: There's like 26 episodes of Try and like what, 13 are the one that came after Try?
Speaker 1: What could I do with those 13 hours?
Speaker 0: Play four games of Everdell.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: You keep going on about this Everdell.
Speaker 0: It's a good game.
Speaker 0: Just takes too long unless you have the right people at the table.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: So got a little thing, not gaming related, but it's a channel.
Speaker 0: I found that's great.
Speaker 0: It's a YouTube short channel.
Speaker 0: And all it is, is this woman who knows about cooking.
Speaker 0: I looked at her other stuff and she used to be a chef.
Speaker 0: But all she does is comment on a certain genre of cooking video that I'm going to describe as white people who have no idea how to cook sharing their absolutely terrifying recipes.
Speaker 1: I've noticed this genre lately as well in the video short category.
Speaker 1: YouTube shorts.
Speaker 1: It's, you know, whatever.
Speaker 0: It's really easy to make them with the app.
Speaker 0: That's why people are making them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I noticed this whole genre of person who actually knows about something.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Looks at they watch a short video of someone messing around trying to make a viral video who doesn't know what they're doing and they comment on it.
Speaker 1: So I've seen a mostly for cooking.
Speaker 1: It's like someone does some wild cooking and the person watching it is like, yeah, this is a bunch of bullshit.
Speaker 0: The chef is just watching, being quiet.
Speaker 0: Then he's like, that's going to spread salmonella.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But on YouTube shorts, there's someone who does it for like hardware projects and they're like, yeah, this person is making a finger removing device.
Speaker 1: And like they actually know about hardware and they're like, all right.
Speaker 1: So that person invented the screwdriver.
Speaker 1: Congrats.
Speaker 1: They're like just making fun of people doing dumb stuff.
Speaker 0: But I guess what I like about this one is, I mean, the videos are terrifying and her commentary is great.
Speaker 0: But the format she presents is that she just describes what they're doing directly.
Speaker 0: And you can hear the sarcasm just like oozing through the way she's described what they're doing.
Speaker 0: Like, oh, yeah, you don't need to stir.
Speaker 0: That is fine.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess if you like geek nights, sarcasm, you'll like that sarcasm as well.
Speaker 0: So what do you got?
Speaker 1: So on the right now, Resident Evil 4, an old game is so hot right now because the remake is out.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: The basically, you know, I think Capcom has a really good thing going with the way they handle Resident Evil, which is where they've got new games coming.
Speaker 1: And then they sort of cycle through redoing the old game.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: This sort of in wave is like a wave that comes up.
Speaker 1: So it's like they went one, two, three, four.
Speaker 1: And the newest one is what, eight, I think, or not.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't even know.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I'm actually going back through the back catalog.
Speaker 0: I just started replaying four.
Speaker 1: I've actually played almost.
Speaker 1: I haven't played the newest one, but I think I've played six or seven of the rest.
Speaker 1: I played about most of them.
Speaker 0: Basically, I played two, three, part of four, part of five.
Speaker 0: And honestly, that's it.
Speaker 0: I never played one.
Speaker 1: I think I've done at least one through.
Speaker 1: I know I've done up to five, I think six and maybe seven.
Speaker 1: I don't know what.
Speaker 0: I've never actually played Resident Evil one.
Speaker 1: Oh, I beat Resident Evil one.
Speaker 1: But I played Resident Evil one many times, but I didn't beat it until there was the remake.
Speaker 1: It's way more playable than the original.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: The remakes are a lot of quality of life improvements in these games.
Speaker 1: Many.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because especially because a lot of them are sort of hard to play.
Speaker 1: But the thing is they remade four and it's like, OK, good.
Speaker 1: You remade four, but four didn't really need the quality of life improvement.
Speaker 0: The original is like.
Speaker 0: the original original was fine to play.
Speaker 1: Like four is playable, right?
Speaker 1: One, two and three needed the help.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I played remakes of those to actually beat them.
Speaker 1: But four doesn't is very playable without the help.
Speaker 1: But the help is welcome.
Speaker 1: You know, it's not unwelcome.
Speaker 1: But anyway, they're promoting the fact the remake of four is out now.
Speaker 1: And they made these cute little one minute like chibi animations.
Speaker 1: And so far there's three of them.
Speaker 1: I'm only good.
Speaker 1: We can link to just the first one.
Speaker 1: I trust the listener is smart enough, if they enjoy it, to go to the YouTube channel and find the other videos that are in the same series.
Speaker 1: Because the YouTube channel has other Capcom related videos as well.
Speaker 1: But you're intelligent enough.
Speaker 1: I know you can do it.
Speaker 1: I don't need to provide you all the links, right?
Speaker 1: One is enough.
Speaker 0: These are just perfect.
Speaker 1: It's just these really cute one minute videos that are like, yeah, they're ads for the Resident Evil 4 remake.
Speaker 1: Yes, they're ads, but they are very cute one minute little chibi animations that are really funny and cute.
Speaker 1: And also I think they work well for Resident Evil 4.
Speaker 1: Because I think having played most of the Resident Evils, 4 has the most straightforward, comprehensible, understandable, relatable story.
Speaker 0: I've watched people play most of the Resident Evils.
Speaker 0: And yeah, absolutely from the watching people play them on livestreams or on a couch.
Speaker 0: Yeah, 4 makes sense-ish.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's literally like, go rescue the president's daughter.
Speaker 1: It's so straightforward compared to the other ones.
Speaker 1: Where it's like there's more mystery or what, you know, it's like, this is what it is.
Speaker 1: Where it's like, you know, 6 or whatever is like, what the fuck is going on here?
Speaker 0: In about a moment, the Geek Guys Book Club book is Sam and Rushdie's The Satanic Versus.
Speaker 1: Ah, so I went to the library to get this book.
Speaker 1: And I got a cool limited edition time special edition Mets library card.
Speaker 1: they just came out with.
Speaker 1: And then I got the book.
Speaker 1: And the book is like 500 pages.
Speaker 1: And I have to return the book by April 20th.
Speaker 1: And I have to read, I calculated, 30 pages per day-ish to finish the book by then.
Speaker 1: I guess I can renew it.
Speaker 1: But, you know, have I read 30 pages per day?
Speaker 1: I'm a little behind.
Speaker 1: I'm like 100 pages in.
Speaker 0: But it's still a good target date to shoot for.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But, you know, it's like I can even though I'm like behind, it's like I can still calculate.
Speaker 1: Well, it's been 8x days.
Speaker 1: Like let's say it's been 8 days.
Speaker 1: I know that I need to be on page 240.
Speaker 1: So I could just, I know like where my target is at all times.
Speaker 1: And like I know I'm behind it right now.
Speaker 1: But I'm still reading it every day.
Speaker 1: Like trying to catch up to the target.
Speaker 0: But also we have entered a critical season.
Speaker 0: The season of I can go lay in the park and read.
Speaker 1: Well, it's going to get colder I guess next week.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I did bike home today.
Speaker 0: It was like 72 when I left the office.
Speaker 1: Today is, yeah, today is the, it's all, it's somewhat warm.
Speaker 1: Instead of being a little cold, it's now somewhat warm.
Speaker 1: But not warm enough, but somewhat warm.
Speaker 0: It's warm enough to bike.
Speaker 1: Yeah, oh yeah.
Speaker 1: Definitely warm enough for biking right now, for sure.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was hard to bike home because everybody took every city bike in midtown.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm reading this book and the only thing I can say about this book is that I do not have enough knowledge about the Quran to understand a lot of what is going on.
Speaker 1: I mean like I understand what's happening, but I just can't understand like what is a, what is a reference or retelling and what is original.
Speaker 1: Because I don't know the original story.
Speaker 0: Have you ever read any of, or seen, there's a lot of stories, a bunch of them, all written by all different people that are basically an angel and a devil, but they're kind of friends.
Speaker 1: Yes, I've read many of those, right Neil Gaiman, right Good Omens and all, you know.
Speaker 0: That's the part to focus on.
Speaker 0: I don't know if knowledge of the Quran will help or hinder.
Speaker 0: I think we're going to have a lot to say about this book.
Speaker 1: But it's like, damn it, I kind of, it's like it makes me want to stop and read the Quran and come back.
Speaker 1: Or maybe I can get a Cliffs Notes Quran somewhere.
Speaker 1: It's not like I've read, it's not like I've read, it's not like I've read the Old or New Testaments either.
Speaker 1: I just know like, you know, the basics like, you know, Genesis, Exodus, whatever.
Speaker 1: So I just, I just need that same outline, you know, idea.
Speaker 1: Because clearly, right, the story of, there is some original story of Muhammad in the Satanic Verses that I feel like I gotta know in order to fully understand.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know, I'll admit, I only know the historical context of that particular debate, well I shouldn't say debate, that particular point of contention.
Speaker 0: Because it was crucial to why the government of Iran wants the author of this book dead to this day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all I know is that they want him dead.
Speaker 1: I didn't understand the theological reasons.
Speaker 0: It's because of that, but really it was a, the book came out at the right time for Iran's government to stir up some shit for tangentially related political reasons.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying my theological knowledge is admittedly extremely lacking, there's no reason to even hide that fact, right?
Speaker 1: And I believe, you know, while I fully understand what is happening in the book, I feel like I am missing on many, you know, allegories, references, symbolisms because of my lack of knowledge of some referenced source material.
Speaker 0: Well we'll see how we progress, and if we read some theology in between parts of this book, we'll let you know.
Speaker 0: so you have a good bead on how we're progressing and how you should progress if you're reading along.
Speaker 0: And otherwise, I think we got no cons coming up for a while, so...
Speaker 1: Summer time.
Speaker 1: It used to be summer was like stacked cons, like cons every weekend, and now it's like summer is the no cons season.
Speaker 1: Everyone moved their cons out of the summer.
Speaker 0: I'm going to a Star Trek con in May in Philly.
Speaker 0: I don't think Scott is interested, but if you want to go, we're driving there.
Speaker 1: I'm not interested in the Star Trek con.
Speaker 0: We might hang out at Schojo's house the day after it.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: We're playing it by ear.
Speaker 0: We got to make our plans.
Speaker 0: Looking at Kinetic Con, but might overlap with other plans we're making, so I don't know if we want to, but even then, that's already a ways from now.
Speaker 0: That's like July.
Speaker 0: So yeah, stay tuned on what we're doing.
Speaker 0: You might see some more non-convention content.
Speaker 0: I got video that Scott shared from the PAX East.
Speaker 0: we were just at.
Speaker 0: that will be turned into some YouTube stuff soon.
Speaker 0: And also, I'll just note that I have been trying to put at least one YouTube short.
Speaker 0: that is a succinct point cut out of one of our many, many Geek Nights panels from over the years onto YouTube about once a day.
Speaker 0: And they're getting a lot of views, so if you like this content, let me know.
Speaker 0: If you have any thoughts on it, I'm evolving how to make these better based on which ones get views, which ones don't, which ones get likes, which ones don't.
Speaker 0: And right now, there's some pretty clear trends that are actually helping me make these better and make a faster pipeline to just crank them out.
Speaker 1: I guess the only thing I really have tickets to right now besides playoff hockey...
Speaker 0: Well, I got regular hockey tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Oh, and Nick Cave is going to be performing in New York in September.
Speaker 0: I'm getting fucking tickets to that.
Speaker 0: And I'm planning to go to a lot of live music over the next six months.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we bought tickets to see, you know, after we went, you know, I think, did I talk about the Dreamcatcher disappointing K-pop concert?
Speaker 0: Yes, you did when I talked about the last Rockstars.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so, but the Mama Moo is the, like, I've never seen them live because they've only been in the US a few times and with very short performances.
Speaker 1: But it is well known and well documented on YouTube that they are, like, in terms of K-pop groups, they're absolutely the best live K-pop group there probably is ever, right?
Speaker 1: Probably even better than BTS in terms of the performance on stage live.
Speaker 1: And they have a US tour now after so long, right?
Speaker 1: After how many years?
Speaker 1: They've been around, like, nine years at least, right?
Speaker 1: They finally have a US tour.
Speaker 1: We paid the big money to sit, like, close because it's in the UBS arena where the Islanders play, at least the New York one is.
Speaker 1: And it sold out, like, immediately.
Speaker 1: But then they opened up the 200s and the 300s and now it's not even sold out.
Speaker 1: And you can buy, I think, you can get a cheap ticket for, like, what, 60 bucks, right?
Speaker 1: So, I would recommend, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Even if you don't care at all, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, the performance is just so good.
Speaker 0: We did a Geek Knives on live music a while back.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll link to that because TL;DL, live music is just great even if you're not a super fan of that music most of the time.
Speaker 1: It's on a Tuesday, May 16th.
Speaker 1: But, look, they have a whole US tour.
Speaker 1: So, depending on where you are, you know, somewhere else.
Speaker 1: And I bet everywhere else is a lot cheaper than New York, too.
Speaker 0: So, it's been a while since we've reviewed a new tabletop game because for some reason we haven't been able to get together with people and play board games or go to cons for a while.
Speaker 0: But, here we are.
Speaker 0: We were at PAX East.
Speaker 0: We played a few games.
Speaker 0: There was that chili sauce distilling game that we could probably do a show on because I liked it.
Speaker 0: But I think I want to play it one more time before I pass judgment on it.
Speaker 0: But Cat in the Box needed two plays for us to review it.
Speaker 0: And I cannot imagine that more play will change my opinion of this game.
Speaker 0: It will probably change my heuristics and, like, I'll figure out how to be good at it.
Speaker 0: But Cat in the Box is such an elegant, well-designed, trick-taking game that I'm just gonna say it's S tier right now.
Speaker 0: I bought a copy, like, immediately after I got home from PAX.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's up there, right?
Speaker 1: So, we played a lot of trick-taking games, especially a lot of the small Japanese ones that seem to be a whole trend, right?
Speaker 1: You know, we've talked about.
Speaker 1: there's the scared ghost one and there's the Haifu one and, you know, there's just so many, right?
Speaker 1: And there's the classic ones, you know, your wizards, tarts, spades, wist, all those.
Speaker 1: Anyway, but this one is really different in terms of what Rim just said.
Speaker 1: The level of polish.
Speaker 1: It is so streamlined and so straightforward.
Speaker 1: It doesn't have any, like, weird gotchas or anything, you know, like, "Oh, you can only trump on the second moon of the third
Speaker 1: moon.".
Speaker 1: There's no weird anything.
Speaker 0: If you have formed a coalition with the player who chose the trump, then the other coalition forms the alternate trump, like, moon.
Speaker 0: None of that crap.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I feel like a lot of trick-taking games, even ones that are pretty smooth, they have one little quirk, at least one, like, quirk or gotcha.
Speaker 1: that makes them a little rough rules-wise, right?
Speaker 1: Even if they have something, you know, and some of them, which I think are smooth, don't have, like, a strategy or a, you know, anything to crunch your brain on decision-wise.
Speaker 1: Like, they're just sort of straightforward.
Speaker 1: Like, you draw your hand, it's easy to figure out the best way to play that hand, and you win or lose based on the draw.
Speaker 0: Now, sometimes that becomes crunchy.
Speaker 0: if you get good at the game and start counting, or, you know, like, you gain some skill.
Speaker 0: Sometimes they become crunchy until you're good at the game.
Speaker 0: But, uh, I guess we're about to describe the rules, because the game is so simple, but what I'll say is- The game is so simple, I can teach you the entire rules, and I will do so.
Speaker 0: Yep, but a point before, uh, I have rarely seen a trick-taking game that is so quick to teach to a table where nobody makes a mistake.
Speaker 0: Like, goddamn, did everyone understand how to play this game after about three minutes of instruction.
Speaker 1: Especially because you already had some trick-taking knowledge.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But even if you don't, I think you could learn it very quickly.
Speaker 0: Like, I like Nekozu Dice, but this is like a breath of fresh air.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: The only reason- like, this could be someone's first trick-taking game.
Speaker 1: The only reason I think you wouldn't want it to be is because the genius of it shines when you have the understanding of a trick-taking game and you see how this is a twist on that formula.
Speaker 1: And it's sort of like you can appreciate it, right?
Speaker 1: Whereas if you could just play this, never having taken a trick in your life, but you wouldn't have a full appreciation for what they've done here.
Speaker 1: So how does this game work?
Speaker 1: It's really simple.
Speaker 1: There's a deck of cards, numbered one through nine, and every number, there are five copies.
Speaker 1: So five ones, five twos, five nines, right?
Speaker 1: There's forty-five cards.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And you deal out the cards to all the players.
Speaker 0: It's very important to note, these cards are all the same.
Speaker 0: All the fives are the same.
Speaker 0: They're all just black.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's no suits.
Speaker 1: It's just numbered one through nine, just deal out the cards.
Speaker 1: And you deal them out, and everyone now has a hand, and everyone picks a card to sort of get rid of, right?
Speaker 1: They just throw it out of the game, basically.
Speaker 1: Let's say I have a one in my hand, and I throw it out.
Speaker 1: Well, now I know that there's only four ones left in the game total, right?
Speaker 1: Because there were five, there could be even less than four, but I know that there are less than five ones available in the total deck because I threw one out, right?
Speaker 1: Okay, and then you start playing a trick-taking game, a very normal trick-taking game.
Speaker 1: You play a card, everyone has to follow suit, whoever has the highest in that suit wins, unless someone didn't have that suit, in which case they can play a different suit.
Speaker 1: If they played the Trump suit, then they would win, right?
Speaker 1: Even against someone who had... It's just basic trick-taking game, nothing weird about it whatsoever, completely normal, not one weird rule at all.
Speaker 1: None.
Speaker 1: No special anything, the red suit is Trump.
Speaker 1: But wait, didn't you just say that all the cards are all black, there's no suits on them?
Speaker 0: Well, when you play a card, you play it on a little cardboard thing in front of you, and you decide what its suit is at the moment you play it.
Speaker 1: Right, so I play a five, and I say, "This five is
Speaker 1: yellow.".
Speaker 1: I decided it.
Speaker 1: When I play it, at the moment I play it, I decide I can pick any suit I want, and I say, "It's five, yellow, it's
Speaker 1: yellow.".
Speaker 1: And what I do when I do that is I take a little marker, and there's a board, and the board has 45 slots on it, one for every card.
Speaker 1: And I put a marker on the yellow five.
Speaker 1: Now, someone else might have a five in their hand, and they might want to play it.
Speaker 1: Well, they can, no problem.
Speaker 1: They just can't say it's yellow, because, well, the yellow five already got played.
Speaker 0: Because remember, the name of this game, fully, is Cat in the Box, and then subtitle, Quantum Trick-Taking Game.
Speaker 0: Because the rule is, you can only play one real card, meaning a yellow five, there's only one yellow five.
Speaker 0: You can't play a card that has already been played, the combo of number and color.
Speaker 0: It's a riff on Schrodinger's Cat.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So, everyone goes around playing a trick-taking game.
Speaker 1: So, I play a yellow five, right?
Speaker 1: Well, now it's Rim is to the left of me.
Speaker 1: Alright, so Rim, I guess he has to follow suit.
Speaker 1: So, if he plays a two, he's gotta say yellow.
Speaker 1: He can't be like, "Red
Speaker 1: two.".
Speaker 0: Well, I could be red two, but I have to then first say, "Oh, no!
Speaker 0: I'm out of yellow!
Speaker 0: That
Speaker 0: sucks!".
Speaker 0: And then I take a marker off my board, showing that I'm, quote, "out of yellow," and I play some other suits.
Speaker 1: Which means that for the rest of that round, Rim can never play another yellow card, because he said he didn't have any yellows left.
Speaker 0: If I desuit myself by just declaring I've desuited, I am tied to that for the rest of the hand.
Speaker 0: And if it turns out that yellow is literally the only play I have left for one of my cards, I'm just effed.
Speaker 1: Right, so that's the final thing.
Speaker 1: You play cards, you decide the suit when you play them, and when you decide the suit, you can only choose a suit for that card that hasn't been played by any other player.
Speaker 1: And you can't choose a suit if you have already declared yourself to be desuited in that, right?
Speaker 1: And then, if someone is in a position where all the cards remaining in their hand have no legal play, then that person has caused a paradox, and they lose, and they get boned, and they lose points.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, everyone gets a point for every trick they took.
Speaker 1: At the beginning of each round, you can bid on how many tricks you think you're gonna take.
Speaker 0: But your options are just like one, two, or three.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can't, right?
Speaker 1: So if you go over three, that doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: But if you hit exactly the bid that you made, then you get bonus points equal to these markers on this.
Speaker 0: So, basically when you play the yellow five, and you put the marker on yellow five, and say later you play a yellow six, or a blue five, or whatever's next to it on that marker board orthogonally.
Speaker 0: Your bonus points, if you hit your bid, are the total number of your markers that is largest of a contiguously orthogonally adjacent set.
Speaker 0: So if I make a big blob of like eight of them, daddy eight points, and I probably definitely won the entire game, because that's nuts.
Speaker 1: Right, but it's like you have an incentive to pick colors, you know, suits, such that your markers on the board are orthogonally adjacent.
Speaker 1: So you want to make runs in the same suit.
Speaker 1: You want to be like, I played the yellow four, and the yellow five, and the yellow six.
Speaker 1: Or you also want to pick, right, like I played the yellow four, and the blue, well there's two, there's the easy side of the board.
Speaker 0: I was about to say, there's that easy baby mode, and there's a really good mode.
Speaker 1: In the baby mode, everything's lined up, so you can just be like blue four, yellow four, green four, right, blue five, and make a blob that way.
Speaker 1: But in the hard mode, everything's offset a little bit, so you can still make runs like three, four, five in the same suit.
Speaker 1: But if it's like, you want to be like blue two, yellow three, green four, that would make a vertical column.
Speaker 0: So the only other rule, and just standard trick taking rule, you can't lead the trump suit unless it's been broken.
Speaker 0: Like that's it.
Speaker 0: And that's a totally normal, that's not a gotcha, that's just a regular old trick taking thing.
Speaker 0: Like trick taking 101.
Speaker 1: And that's the whole game, you play several rounds, you lose the most points, the end.
Speaker 0: And it's great.
Speaker 0: Of the two games we played, I came in second place by one point in the first game, and I won the second game.
Speaker 0: But I don't think that was my, the first game.
Speaker 0: that was luck, but I do have some heuristics.
Speaker 0: Like there is some skill here, and I think play can evolve based on what I noticed in the two games we played.
Speaker 1: I am ashamed to admit it took me several games to learn.
Speaker 1: the most basic fact is, right?
Speaker 1: And so I'm going to teach it to you so you don't fuck it up.
Speaker 0: Oh, then I'll teach the thing I figured out in game two.
Speaker 1: This is so simple and obvious, I should have figured it out as soon as I heard the rules.
Speaker 1: It took me several games to understand this.
Speaker 1: That there are five copies of any number in the deck, right?
Speaker 1: And you can only, so there are five fours, right?
Speaker 1: In the whole deck.
Speaker 1: If four fours get played, obviously the fifth one can never be played, otherwise trouble.
Speaker 1: If you start in your opening hand and you've got more than one four or more than one two, and you take one of them and throw it out at the start, then you know the other one is perfectly safe.
Speaker 1: You can always, as long as you don't desuit yourself and stupidly, right?
Speaker 1: You'll know that you can safely play that other one, right?
Speaker 1: So if you draw in your opening hand like three threes, obviously you should probably throw away one of the threes, and now you know for sure those other two threes are safe, and you can just sort of hold them till the end of the round, and you won't paradox that way.
Speaker 1: Try to get all the other cards.
Speaker 1: If you've got like one four in your opening hand, okay, keep it, but try to play it quickly.
Speaker 1: That way you can get it out, and if no one else is thrown away at four, and there's a dangerous paradoxical four out there, at least it's not in your hand, and I paradoxed often when I started playing, and once I understood this, I stopped paradoxing basically.
Speaker 0: I only paradoxed once, and it was a negative zero paradox.
Speaker 0: I was okay on that one.
Speaker 0: So my slightly more advanced heuristic that worked so well is kind of like when you showed how you were winning citadels, and everyone was like, "Oh fuck, that's why Scott was
Speaker 0: winning.".
Speaker 1: Mine wasn't even a heuristic.
Speaker 1: It was just like a basic fact.
Speaker 1: It was so simple.
Speaker 1: I don't know how I didn't understand that from game one.
Speaker 0: My baby heuristic that is the sole reason I won that second game and will definitely not work again was, whatever number every single player played first, unless there was like a weird situation with like, you know, like someone leads something really high first round, whatever they play, I assumed they were trying to get rid of it because they have more than one in their hand.
Speaker 1: No, you would get rid of it early because you don't have more than one in your hand.
Speaker 0: Well no, meaning they have more than one in their hand after throwing stuff away, and they're trying to get rid of the most dangerous card in their hand.
Speaker 1: But if you have multiple numbers of a card in your hand...
Speaker 0: Say you have two fours in your hand after you threw stuff away.
Speaker 1: But I would have thrown away one of the fours.
Speaker 0: What if you have three fours and three ones when you have to decide what to throw away?
Speaker 1: That's really weird.
Speaker 0: I had draws like that every game.
Speaker 1: The other thing is that when you get to the end of the round, you don't play your final card.
Speaker 1: So really you can save two cards.
Speaker 1: So if I had three ones and three fours, I would throw away a one at the start, or maybe throw away a four at the start, and then one of the ones, I would just sort of say, "This is the card.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to play this round no matter
Speaker 1: what.".
Speaker 1: And now I know that the ones and the fours are all safe to play, and I would put those also, deprioritize playing those, and try to get all the other cards played first.
Speaker 1: I went harder.
Speaker 1: Because I know that those are the dangerous and risky ones.
Speaker 0: Because the fact that if someone paradoxes the hand ends immediately, I won the second game.
Speaker 0: because every time someone paradoxed, almost every time I would have been forced to paradox if it got around to me, but someone paradoxed before, I aggressively tried to make someone paradox.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: And the way I would do that is...
Speaker 1: Especially, the turn order matters a lot too, especially on the final round.
Speaker 1: Like if you can see, because everyone's going to deal one hand, right?
Speaker 1: So if you say, "Okay, I'm the first dealer in the first round, and then that means on the last round, I will be going second.
Speaker 1: And so I'm probably relatively
Speaker 1: safe."
Speaker 1: Because you're not going to paradox before the last round unless you're really bad, right?
Speaker 0: It happened a couple times though.
Speaker 0: You can just get screwed by the colors or like being forced to desuit or something.
Speaker 1: It's possible, but it's like on that final round, it's like, "Okay, I'm going to be going second.
Speaker 1: I'm kind of safe, but I can obviously be in a position of power to really hurt the third or fourth
Speaker 1: players.".
Speaker 1: If I look at that board on that final turn, and I see that three threes have been used, and I've got the fourth three, it's like, "I'll play
Speaker 1: that.".
Speaker 1: And it's like, "All right, it can't be a three.
Speaker 1: What do you
Speaker 1: got?".
Speaker 0: So what I did, and this was super effective just saying in these early games, I don't think it'll last because obviously this is easily defeated.
Speaker 0: Whoever in the first hand, whatever number, I look at all the numbers.
Speaker 0: everyone who did not lead played.
Speaker 0: I pick one of those players, especially if I have one or two of that number, and I do the same thing like pushing spades and hearts.
Speaker 0: I play that number at my next opportunity to try to force them into a corner by getting to the point where I hope they had two threes, let's say, they got rid of one.
Speaker 0: I force other threes out to try to get to the point to where all four threes are taken up.
Speaker 0: So now they've got a liability in their hand.
Speaker 1: I mean, filling up a number in general is going to create the most dangerous situation for someone.
Speaker 0: So I would try to keep two of a number, which is highly risky, like two fives.
Speaker 0: Someone plays a five, I play a five, my next two cards are fives, just trying to fuck them over.
Speaker 1: Well, if you have two fives and you haven't shoved one under at the start, right?
Speaker 0: I would keep one sometimes.
Speaker 1: It's like, right, well it's like, you know that if you keep one of them to the end, you're safe.
Speaker 1: But if you can play both, then you know you've definitely probably put the hurt on somebody.
Speaker 0: Exactly, and I played this game both times the same way I play hearts.
Speaker 0: I don't try necessarily to minimize my score so much as I try to fuck over other players and force them into bad situations.
Speaker 0: And that's just how I often play trick-taking games.
Speaker 0: And it's highly effective in two plays of this game.
Speaker 1: I think the worst draw in this game would actually be like three pair, right?
Speaker 1: Because you, let's say, got two twos, two threes, two fours.
Speaker 1: I can hide a two at the start, I can save a three at the end.
Speaker 1: It's like, well I've got two fours and I have to play them both, right?
Speaker 0: If I had that situation, I would aggressively desuit early on purpose.
Speaker 0: Which, you remember, I desuited way early and everyone was like,
Speaker 0: "Whoa!"
Speaker 0: And I won, so.
Speaker 1: But it's like, I would try, I would play those fours, right?
Speaker 1: I would try to play them quickly so that, you know, because there's a risk that there could be five of them out there.
Speaker 0: In that situation, if I had like three pairs, I would aggressively desuit to try to get them all out on purpose.
Speaker 0: Because, early, quickly, because if you have those cards and you're playing with the skewed board, then that lines up into an extremely orthogonally adjacent pile of points.
Speaker 0: That is worth the risk.
Speaker 0: You can have like a seven, eight, nine point hand and that'll probably win you the whole thing.
Speaker 0: It's worth going for it.
Speaker 0: Of course, if you paradox!
Speaker 1: The problem is desuiting too early, you might end up hurting yourself because it's like, okay, I know for sure that there are, I ditched a one at the start and I've got a second one.
Speaker 1: And I know there's only four ones out there, right?
Speaker 1: And I desuit, you know, in blue or something.
Speaker 1: And then everyone gets played except the blue one.
Speaker 1: And I'm the only, this is the only one that's left because I ditched one of them.
Speaker 1: But I can't play it because I desuited blue too early.
Speaker 1: And now I screwed myself.
Speaker 1: That's the risk you take when you desuit too early.
Speaker 0: I played a very aggressive, high risk strategy in a game where everyone else at the table was playing very safely and conservatively.
Speaker 0: So I want to see what happens if someone else goes as aggro as I go and I imagine we both get fucked over and someone else wins.
Speaker 1: I think the thing is, in those early games, I was trying to play safe, but I wasn't playing safe because I didn't understand how to play safe.
Speaker 0: And
Speaker 1: I just explained how to play safe is to just realize, there are five of each card, if you ditch one at the start or the end, then all other cards of that number are safe, as long as you don't hurt yourself by desuiting a color too early, then you know which, you can separate your hand into the numbers that could paradox and the numbers that can't paradox.
Speaker 0: I just realized, you know why we were able to get such heuristics and figure stuff out so quickly with two plays in this game and other trick-taking games?
Speaker 1: We played with a bunch of smart people several times in a row.
Speaker 0: Well, I only played twice, but not just that.
Speaker 1: I think we played three or four times.
Speaker 0: Without suits, counting cards is trivial.
Speaker 0: Everyone at the table can have a full count in their head.
Speaker 1: What do you mean counting cards?
Speaker 1: There's a board that shows you which cards have been played with little gems.
Speaker 1: So playing this game... You don't have to count anything.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: So playing this game lets you, as a player, who may not necessarily count cards in Hearts or Wizard or something else, feel what it's like to play a trick-taking game if you were counting cards.
Speaker 1: That is the magic of this game, and I just realized it.
Speaker 1: Look at the board, and you can see, I got a yellow six, and you look at the board, and it shows you that the yellow seven and eight have already been played.
Speaker 1: And you're like, "Yellow six?
Speaker 1: Oh, you have a six, not a yellow
Speaker 1: six.".
Speaker 1: But you make it a yellow six, because you've seen that the seven and the eight have already been played, and it's like, "Well, you know what could beat
Speaker 1: that?".
Speaker 1: Unless they break and play drums.
Speaker 0: The only information you have to keep track of, really, is what card did you throw away?
Speaker 0: Because that's the only information you have, other than your hand, that no one else has.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: And you would love to know what everyone else threw away.
Speaker 1: That would be super valuable information.
Speaker 0: So yeah, you could probably take other trick-taking games as a teaching exercise to make the count on a board like this, so people could experience what hearts is like if everyone was counting cards.
Speaker 1: I feel like you could just play one hand of Wizard, right?
Speaker 1: Until everyone understands it.
Speaker 1: Just play Wizard until everyone gets it, and then just immediately switch to this instead.
Speaker 0: I think this game's gonna be a big hit with my family, too.
Speaker 1: I think anyone who is a trick-taking game enjoyer should add this one.
Speaker 1: If you're only gonna have five trick-taking games on your shelf, besides regular deck of cards, it's probably this one, a Wizard, maybe the Haifu one, the Yokozu dice.
Speaker 1: Those are the top ones that I've done.
Speaker 1: So, Fuji Flush, I guess if that counts, maybe.
Speaker 0: Moo is an elevated experience that is not for everyone.
Speaker 0: I like Moo, but I can't.
Speaker 0: I'm not good at it.
Speaker 1: Maybe the stick-elm, maybe?
Speaker 0: Ooh, I really like stick-elm, but I haven't played it in so long.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but this one is above--.
Speaker 0: The last time we played stick-elm was at the PAX, where the seventh guest arrived.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the point is, the cat one is above the stick-elms of the world, right?
Speaker 0: Well, stick-elm, I don't know if I like it because it's good, or I like it because it's almost an inversion.
Speaker 0: It's such the opposite of everything trick-taking games stand for.
Speaker 0: It's like the deconstruction of a trick-taking game, so I don't know if it's good, or if it's just so novel that I'm obsessed with it.
Speaker 0: It might not be good.
Speaker 1: But anyway, also, coming up with this genius, and also the deluxe edition that we were playing has very nice pieces, all these cute little gems with cat-related and science-related items.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, the game, the style is just great.
Speaker 0: The cute little cat with a little chromatic aberration, this game's just a gem.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So, excellent game, and it's not expensive, and it's not large, which is great.
Speaker 1: Oh, and I guess we wanted to mention, the game was published by Hobby Japan.
Speaker 1: It's a Japanese game.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, right.
Speaker 1: Who was the designer again?
Speaker 0: Oh, the designer.
Speaker 0: Oh, I gotta go back.
Speaker 0: I was clicking around in photos of the game for the livestream while we were talking.
Speaker 0: The designer of this game, Muneyuki Yokuchi.
Speaker 1: Okay, well yeah, good job to that person.
Speaker 1: But the thing I learned, thanks to this game, is I thought Hobby Japan was a magazine, which it is, I guess, about Gundam modeling and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: But apparently, Hobby Japan is a publisher of many different nerdy things in Japan, not just a magazine.
Speaker 0: Most euro games?
Speaker 1: If you buy D&D in Japan, it's translated and locally published by Hobby Japan.
Speaker 0: They've even got the distribution rights to Advanced Squad Leader.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like, I didn't realize Hobby Japan was this whole publishing company.
Speaker 1: I thought it was just a magazine.
Speaker 1: But nope, it's a whole publishing company, they publish lots of stuff over there, including board games, including this tabletop game.
Speaker 1: So, that's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of Geek Nights are Alan Drosling, Gigi Drel, Lieutenant Brett Case, K.R.
Speaker 0: Makes Music, Krista Dodd, Clinton Walton, Dex, Finn, Joel Hayes, Penny Rymer, Rebecca Dunn, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Hurl, and many, many people who choose to give an amount that is smaller than $5.
Speaker 0: Like a dollar or something, I assume, because you want that customized RSS feed.
Speaker 0: that's actually pretty nice.
Speaker 0: One person gives $4.99, which is extra funny, you were cool.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I'm actually distracted talking about people drinking inadvisable things in a Discord right now, so I'm just going to leave you with...
Speaker 1: Your man might have the Star Wars Lego set Death Star, but can he chug his sparkling water and not burp?