Speaker 0: It's Thursday April 6th 2023.
Speaker 0: I'm rim And this is geek night tonight.
Speaker 0: We were talking about stadiums Colosseum's arenas and the like.
Speaker 0: let's do this sir, it's warm today like Shockingly warm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, it's it's really.
Speaker 1: it's strange because on the one hand it did get.
Speaker 1: you know, this is you know It's not cold, right?
Speaker 1: I would like it to be warmer, but this is my watch while I was running.
Speaker 0: It was 77 right.
Speaker 1: my watch right now says it's 76.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 1: That's you know, I'm not gonna complain if it's 76.
Speaker 0: You and I are it of a corn.
Speaker 0: I wanted to be like 84 and sunny and higher.
Speaker 1: The number can't be too high.
Speaker 1: There's no number that would be high that I would complain, right?
Speaker 1: It's good.
Speaker 1: We can go.
Speaker 1: I can go to the other side the the Sun facing side of mercury and I could be warmer.
Speaker 0: So I would I know a closer.
Speaker 0: what I'm curious about is I would at least once like to be in either Hyderabad or Singapore with you at the height of their summer and I'm just curious to see if your opinion would change because I have been in 120 degree heat and While it didn't kill me I would prefer to not be in that heat for too long unless I'm like in a sauna or on a beach that I can escape from That to somewhere.
Speaker 0: that is not that hot Mmm, I think my upper limit of comfort is about a hundred and five if it's dry.
Speaker 1: ish Mmm, but I mean, you know, I walked through the desert and I you know, I wasn't upset at all.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, but So the sad thing is I was looking at the weather stuff cuz you know The weather has been more variable for the last several years as we know like anyone who lives can notice that and scientists agree that's true.
Speaker 0: it is way more variable and it's solely because of Advancing climate change.
Speaker 0: climate change doesn't mean everything gets hotter immediately means everything gets more fucked up and variable.
Speaker 0: But there's talk that at least in the New York City area.
Speaker 0: This is very likely to be the hottest summer ever Recorded.
Speaker 0: Yes, and I think Scott and we're gonna treat that I'm gonna treat this the same way.
Speaker 0: I treat a tornado because tornadoes cause devastation.
Speaker 0: They kill people.
Speaker 0: They are bad news.
Speaker 0: But I wish I wish there were no more tornadoes just like I wish there were no more hockey fights.
Speaker 0: But I was at a hockey game last.
Speaker 1: wish there were no more a lot of things.
Speaker 0: There was a hockey fight at the fact there were a lot of hockey many many.
Speaker 0: This was the fight in his hockey game I seen in a while in person and for a meaningless game.
Speaker 1: It was way too fighty, right?
Speaker 0: So, uh, I may have stood up and screamed and cheered during those fights.
Speaker 0: I might have yelled fuck him up at one point, especially when someone deserved it, which they did.
Speaker 0: Yep, don't hit our goalie in the nuts with your stick.
Speaker 0: that is like that is a sin in hockey.
Speaker 1: Well, they got a $5,000 fine But I would.
Speaker 0: I would want to watch any hockey fight I can see and to ban hockey fighting immediately if I had the power To do so.
Speaker 0: I will watch any tornado in the Midwest from an open garage door sitting on a lawn chair.
Speaker 0: But that is because I did not cause that tornado.
Speaker 1: As long as I'm confident enough that I can run and get to the basement if the tornado comes in my direction, yes More than once in my life.
Speaker 0: There was the moment of like my mom or my dad say like Pausing for a minute while we're watching it like literally watching a tornado and then saying all right garage doors closing everybody into the basement.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's too close Coming this way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they would never.
Speaker 0: they were always.
Speaker 0: they would always act completely calm.
Speaker 0: But they were definitely not calm when they said that because my mom would like follow tornadoes in her car because it was cool.
Speaker 0: So when mom was like, yeah, the path is perpendicular to your right that's all good.
Speaker 1: But if it's parallel Let's see it.
Speaker 0: But in some good news before I get into my actual like super bad news.
Speaker 0: Ah Stanley Cup's coming playoff other the playoff.
Speaker 1: the people are in the playoffs a whole nother week before you can go on with this news.
Speaker 0: yeah, the playoffs are set for the non wildcard teams and No wildcards are locked in.
Speaker 0: so there is like a knife fight and a crab bucket Among the people trying to get the wildcard slot and everyone else is just lynched.
Speaker 0: They're just waiting for the playoffs to start.
Speaker 0: like yeah, there's a little bit of seed contention, but it's not that big a deal.
Speaker 0: I guess nobody wants to go against Boston in round one.
Speaker 0: But what are you gonna do?
Speaker 1: I still say it's mad that there are 82 hockey games, right?
Speaker 1: Because it's so asymmetrical.
Speaker 1: There should really be I forget.
Speaker 1: I think it's seven when I did the math.
Speaker 1: I think it might have been 70 something Basically, there's right now, right?
Speaker 1: There are four divisions in two conferences and each of the divisions is eight teams.
Speaker 1: It's perfectly even eight eight eight eight four thirty-two.
Speaker 0: Thank you.
Speaker 0: recent expansions.
Speaker 1: So you want to see Every possible team should come to every possible building one time each right.
Speaker 0: who tops the main bit, right?
Speaker 1: So therefore you should play Every team and every other division right which is 24 teams and the three other divisions twice once home once away.
Speaker 1: So 24 times 2 is 48, right.
Speaker 1: and then you want to play the teams that are in your own division.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: more than that, right because they're in your division.
Speaker 1: You should play them more frequently.
Speaker 0: I like is this vision is like a competitive boundary but also because practically if Everybody played everybody equally that is a lot of flying and that is bad for the world and bad for the players, right?
Speaker 1: But you are one of the teams in your division.
Speaker 1: You don't have to play yourself, right?
Speaker 1: So it's not eight.
Speaker 1: It's seven, right?
Speaker 1: So it's seven other teams in your division.
Speaker 1: You should play them four times each.
Speaker 1: seven times four is 28 28 plus 48.
Speaker 1: Yes 76.
Speaker 0: There should be 76 NHL games per season and before you wait, how do they balance it out?
Speaker 0: Well, they kind of just decide like yeah, it's like instead there's 82.
Speaker 1: So there's basically just because they want to make more money and sell more tickets to more games that are mostly meaningless.
Speaker 1: They tack on six games to every season against who knows what team And it's just like right now.
Speaker 0: I say if they're gonna do that it asymmetrizes Everything.
Speaker 0: they should do that Sort of how the NFL has those games like.
Speaker 0: oh, hey These two teams are just gonna play in London.
Speaker 0: because why not like for this one guy?
Speaker 1: Well, well technically one of those teams is the home team.
Speaker 1: But technically but NFL has a symmetrical system where each season you rotate which of the other Divisions you're gonna your division is gonna play against more because obviously you don't play against every team every year.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you play against each team in your division, which is only four teams, right twice Home and away and then based on what year it is you cycle through the other.
Speaker 1: You know teams that are out there and it's it actually makes perfect sense.
Speaker 0: Yep so, uh, yeah the game last night was pretty good and See hockey's coming.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna curse anything, but I'm excited to see at least some number of playoff hockey games where the Rangers are playing.
Speaker 1: in those games you you may see none if they Win enough of them.
Speaker 0: so in some bad news and this is news that I don't think a lot of people Realized was happening because one it happened.
Speaker 1: It's literally the top news on every news Yeah, but it happened real fast and I didn't know about it till this morning.
Speaker 0: It's basically a today only now and while it had been talked about before and this has been talked about in a lot of places But Tennessee is where it's happening first.
Speaker 0: It evolved so quickly.
Speaker 0: This is one of those things that went from.
Speaker 0: People who are experts would say things like oh that could happen But it would never really happen.
Speaker 0: and then very rapidly went to oh not only can it happen The Republicans just fucking did it like right now live out of nowhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean if you know, that's people.
Speaker 1: If it can happen, right?
Speaker 1: It's like it's the same thing.
Speaker 1: people joke about what's that platinum coin.
Speaker 1: platinum coin can happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, feel like we might need that platinum coin before long and you know what?
Speaker 0: I still think Biden's just fucking do it.
Speaker 0: just print the platinum coin.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 1: Why not do it now?
Speaker 1: What do you?
Speaker 1: why do you got to wait for there to be the?
Speaker 0: I don't think I say.
Speaker 0: just do it because one thing That's what I say.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: Why wait for the crisis moment.
Speaker 1: Just do it get a Problem.
Speaker 0: people who pay attention you see like the politician who's on the right side of history or at least the relatively better side Of history makes a big move.
Speaker 0: Yeah, fine.
Speaker 0: I'll support it.
Speaker 0: and the people who aren't paying that much attention They won't understand or care.
Speaker 0: They won't remember the coin when it comes to the election It's not gonna influence whether or not they vote or not.
Speaker 0: Like it's not gonna have any consequences.
Speaker 0: So just do it.
Speaker 0: but so basically what's happening?
Speaker 0: and I'm gonna skip over all the details because this could be hours of talking but I'll link to an article and NPR that explains like the details of how this happened why it happened what the impact is.
Speaker 0: but basically Tennessee in America is a state that Likely would be a left-leaning Democratic state but is heavily gerrymandered inside of itself Basically to prevent non-white.
Speaker 1: basically, there's Nashville and there's Memphis which are two cities of actually mostly Democratic people not white people, you know that are really cool You know their car places, but other than being car places Those are pretty cool cities and the rest of Tennessee is a not good place.
Speaker 1: That is very sparse Let's just say fashy and unpopulated Right.
Speaker 0: So the state basically Gerrymandered all the progressive and non-white votes into a small number of districts as happens all over America.
Speaker 0: And it's not.
Speaker 0: this is not a different situation from a lot of these states in America.
Speaker 0: So a minority of the population.
Speaker 1: but also it does need to be said right that you know without the gerrymandering The if you just take the total population of Tennessee, right it, you know, these are people that vote, you know Senators are right-wing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it's a total.
Speaker 1: the total voting population is still majority.
Speaker 0: not good though, partly because voter suppression Prevents a lot of people.
Speaker 0: That's also.
Speaker 0: that's also a fact and voter suppression is controlled by the people we're about to talk about.
Speaker 0: So the Republican Party the fashy party has like a mega majority in the state in the Tennessee like State House so They can technically just vote to kick anyone out for any reason just like, you know our house could at the federal level.
Speaker 0: So they just decided to kick the three Democrats out that represent these like not super white districts just because they're Democrats and They're just doing it the first one actually breaking right before we started the show.
Speaker 0: The first vote finished and one of them was kicked out.
Speaker 0: They're gonna kick the other two out and this is This is extremely dangerous to American democracy because it is highly likely other.
Speaker 1: Well, they get to vote new people in.
Speaker 0: Yep, they could vote the same people in.
Speaker 0: We'll see what happens.
Speaker 0: But this is the.
Speaker 0: all I'm gonna say is this is the kind of thing that was happening in state Legislatures in the equivalent of purple states in America in the 20 years leading up to the actual Civil War and nothing like this Has happened since the 1800s until just now.
Speaker 0: April 6 2023. so I Don't think there'd be a Civil War like Sherman style.
Speaker 0: I don't think I'm like that but It could look a lot like what the troubles looked like in Northern Ireland long term if things continue to go down this road.
Speaker 0: hmm, so read up on this.
Speaker 0: this is a Big crazy history happening and there's a lot to talk about there But we really have time to get into it in geek nights on a Thursday.
Speaker 0: Also, I'm hungry and it's nice out.
Speaker 0: So what do you got?
Speaker 0: any news?
Speaker 1: Well, I don't have a specific single news, I just want to say that in general right now It's like for some reason a mega movie season is happening.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, not just a mega movie season but a weirdly high percentage of these movers or movies I do actually want to see at some point.
Speaker 1: Okay, so let's so we got to go.
Speaker 1: So first of all, I guess we'll talk about it when rim gets a chance to see it.
Speaker 1: But I saw Susan made the new Makoto Shinkai movie which came out actually a little while ago.
Speaker 1: But it's you know, it's gonna be in the US.
Speaker 0: Remember this is the one with the chair and if you know if you know what I'm talking about You know what I'm talking about, right?
Speaker 1: So I saw the premiere.
Speaker 1: Shinkai was there.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about it on as soon as room sees it on a Wednesday show, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you can see that soon.
Speaker 1: There's the Mario movie, which I haven't seen.
Speaker 1: I expect it to be bad.
Speaker 1: I've seen some ads for it.
Speaker 1: That's about it.
Speaker 1: But everything I've heard and also I assumed before I heard is that it's just gonna be a fan service fiesta.
Speaker 1: So I'm assuming it's to be bad, but I probably see it anyway, all right There's dungeons and dragons movie which we already mentioned.
Speaker 1: a couple people are saying it's good.
Speaker 1: I saw a I guess an added off was a full trailer a partial trailer.
Speaker 1: I'm not personally interested but people said it's good.
Speaker 1: So I think if you're the kind of person who actually likes a D&D Oh, I'm gonna go further.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I saw the best review.
Speaker 0: It wasn't like a newspaper review It was just some nerd on reddit.
Speaker 0: They basically said don't the Dungeons and Dragons movie.
Speaker 0: Imagine if one of those live streams of D&D was actually good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so anyway, so there's that that's exists.
Speaker 1: at least I'm not gonna see that one spider-verse - ah must watch Just what what?
Speaker 1: what did you say?
Speaker 0: I diverse?
Speaker 1: - oh, yeah We're gonna.
Speaker 1: the spider-man movie has actually come the animated one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's coming much sooner than I thought isn't it?
Speaker 0: Like absolute must-watch movie.
Speaker 0: I'm seeing that one in the theater like no question.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, we all go in in New York.
Speaker 1: We love spider-man Especially.
Speaker 1: and then yeah, I saw John wick for already.
Speaker 1: I mean I don't.
Speaker 1: I guess I'm not gonna tell you anything that happens in it.
Speaker 0: I still have it.
Speaker 0: We were planning to watch John wick 3 with red and a couple other people so I haven't actually seen 3 yet.
Speaker 1: Well 3 is a lot better and at least in my opinion than 4.
Speaker 0: I mean my order is my favorite.
Speaker 0: John wick is still 1 2 has some great scenes, but I think one is a better movie.
Speaker 1: Well 4 is basically just sort of like.
Speaker 1: first of all, it's really long, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like I like a long wordy lock me in a theater for four hours daddy.
Speaker 1: I also like a long movie, but Obviously the majority of it is just fighting with no talking or plot advancement, which is what you would expect from a John wick, right?
Speaker 1: It does.
Speaker 1: that's what it's on the label is you're gonna see action scenes.
Speaker 1: It's like if you cut out the action scenes This movie might be 20 to 30.
Speaker 0: John wick is just dynasty warriors with a gun basically basically Yes, the problem is is that?
Speaker 1: Imagine I give you like, you know, I get some Eileen's cheesecake right like the best the best cheesecake, right.
Speaker 1: and It's like okay you eat a slice and it's like that was delicious and they eat another slice.
Speaker 1: It's still delicious, but you're full now, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah Sometimes sometimes you're like Homer in hell with the donuts and you just keep going.
Speaker 1: But it's like John wick for had was just so many minutes of action scenes.
Speaker 1: Right that like even though they would mix it up and do different things and there was still you know Something going on there and it wasn't bad.
Speaker 1: I was full.
Speaker 1: I was like just Get on with it.
Speaker 1: Just show me the plot already, right?
Speaker 1: Not that there was much plot But yeah, you know, it's like whatever.
Speaker 1: And there's that one and I feel like there's one more.
Speaker 1: Oh, and there's the the trailer.
Speaker 1: during while I was seeing John wick for they showed a trailer for a movie Call.
Speaker 1: but from this I guess simple similar studio same studio same, you know, the people that brought you whatever, right?
Speaker 0: Called sisu which is oh, yeah Also known as a Finnish guy murders a lot of bad people.
Speaker 0: Yes
Speaker 1: It's basically about an old Finnish gold prospector who murders a bunch of Nazis and it's like It's but you could consider it to just be another John wick movie basically, but it's like, you know Hey, you know different character different plot different whatever might you know,
Speaker 0: and then I'm late.
Speaker 1: Trailer convinced me that yeah I want to see that right.
Speaker 0: one more on the list that I'm actually into even though it's actually from last year and I just Slept on it is if you've seen people talking about the menu, that's my kind of horror comedy movie like straight up.
Speaker 1: I never never heard.
Speaker 0: Oh, uh, if there's a trailer, but I feel like I don't know.
Speaker 0: the trailer looks spoilery and yeah.
Speaker 0: but well how I was sold on it is.
Speaker 0: I just saw our short clip and it was just a scene in the movie and All it is is there's a woman in a fancy restaurant and she orders a cheeseburger From a really intense and creepy chef and I was sold on this movie just from seeing that scene.
Speaker 1: Okay People are hype on this new Barbie movie and that seems like something I might watch.
Speaker 1: if it I wouldn't go to the theater.
Speaker 0: I might go to the theater to see Barbie.
Speaker 1: I don't need to.
Speaker 1: and then I've been seeing.
Speaker 1: you know, obviously I don't go see any superhero movies.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen a live-action superhero movie in the theater.
Speaker 0: The last Thor movie I saw spider-man in like 2002.
Speaker 0: I saw the last Thor the second to last Thor movie, which I liked.
Speaker 0: I heard the one after.
Speaker 0: that's not that good The first guy And part and not so much the other ones.
Speaker 1: you've seen way more than I have right but the.
Speaker 1: I saw a trailer for the new Flash movie and basically the the plot that was you know delivered the plot synopsis that was delivered in the trailer.
Speaker 1: Read like all the DC comic books.
Speaker 1: I hate to read I have no interest in that whatsoever.
Speaker 1: It was like I got a. you know, they'll run so fast travel through time bullshit.
Speaker 1: Batman shows up, you know.
Speaker 1: And then they try bat they make.
Speaker 0: Batman is is actually Michael Keaton again to try to be cool Right and you know see if it was if they would just made Batman with Michael Keaton without all these other superheroes.
Speaker 0: I would actually probably be willing to see it.
Speaker 1: Oh There is a live-action Knights of the Zodiac coming in May.
Speaker 1: that's you know, Saint Seiya, right?
Speaker 1: And then there's that for the people, you know who love that kind of action is the the the The Nicolas Cage Renfield deal.
Speaker 0: So after having just recently.
Speaker 1: I know there will be some nerds who care about that.
Speaker 0: So I was kind of done like the cage.
Speaker 0: I felt like I was done with him But I watched on a plane recently for a work trip that the unbearable burden of like great talent or whatever the the movie That is Nick Cage playing Nick Cage in a cage movie.
Speaker 0: It was kind of not what I expected and actually a really good movie like.
Speaker 0: surprisingly so I kind of want to see Renfield now because I Really?
Speaker 0: Enjoy that other Nick Cage movie that I just watched.
Speaker 1: Yeah, is that there's like a Ninja Turtle one.
Speaker 1: come in.
Speaker 1: There's a. You know, it's
Speaker 0: weird cuz this feels like how my life was free internet where just like there was all these movies I wanted to see and I was at the theater like at Least once a week for much of my life up until our IT when I didn't have any money.
Speaker 1: Oh There's the.
Speaker 1: I don't know where it's gonna be on.
Speaker 1: There's the one that's like.
Speaker 1: There's the Tetris one the Michael Jordan shoes one and like a pinball one that is sort of like those fictionalized Documentary ones.
Speaker 0: Yeah, those are always hit or miss.
Speaker 0: I kind of wait to see if people talk about him after they come out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, anyway Book times movie season for some reason.
Speaker 0: But anyway things Of the day.
Speaker 0: so Emily I watched this the other night and it is up your alley Scott.
Speaker 0: This is a New Yorker cartoon.
Speaker 0: They have some originals and it's on this YouTube channel.
Speaker 0: It's linked to.
Speaker 0: it is 10 minutes long Neighborhood.
Speaker 0: nostalgia comes to life and all I'm gonna say is this is basically you want to see some s-tier old New York guys?
Speaker 0: Talking about New York this this short is s-tier old, New York guys This is just a really good day.
Speaker 0: This is delightful.
Speaker 0: It is definitely worth watching and it is both nostalgic to what New York was like but also Real about like.
Speaker 0: not everything was great in that era of New York.
Speaker 0: Like.
Speaker 0: we can't pretend that New York was perfect in the olden times and is terrible.
Speaker 0: now There's like one of the guys went to prison for a couple of dimes after he got involved with the mob.
Speaker 1: So Yeah So yeah my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: if you watch the news in the u.s Right every time someone brings up the idea of taxing the rich right not on the federal level in the u.s But you know in the local levels then everyone's like, ah, if you tax the rich They'll leave and then you'll actually lose tote tax revenue because you'll be.
Speaker 1: you'll have.
Speaker 1: you know All those people who are in that higher tax bracket that you that you created won't even live here anymore Right now.
Speaker 1: they're at least paying a little bit if they're paying, you know this tax right now.
Speaker 0: My old argument used to be face value before we get into your thing of the day was you know what good if they leave Rents come down because while we're getting less tax revenue also all their rich person bullshit goes away with them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway, the point is is that studies show that actually no they won't leave right there.
Speaker 1: Basically, almost you would take you would have to set taxes to like 60 like I think they had a number in this video.
Speaker 1: I forget what the number was but like a very high percentage before it's gets to the point where you're.
Speaker 0: If you don't live in New York Exactly, but you know, it's.
Speaker 1: it's not just true for New York.
Speaker 1: It's true for most places like that place where the person lives.
Speaker 1: They've set down roots.
Speaker 1: That's where the people they know are.
Speaker 1: that's where their business is.
Speaker 1: It's like moving isn't easy.
Speaker 1: It's actually harder to move when you're rich because you've got so much shit, right?
Speaker 1: It's like if you're you know poor and you don't have a lot of stuff moving is can you know?
Speaker 1: Expensive moving is difficult.
Speaker 0: The most expensive moving is lower middle-class American family, right?
Speaker 1: But the roots that you have set down are not as much right?
Speaker 1: It's like if I had less stuff I could just pick up all my stuff and get in a van and also think a rich Person.
Speaker 0: they're living exactly where they want to be living because money is no barrier to that Yep.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so this person did sort of like this video Which is sort of like it reads sort of like a Daily Show segment or you know, whatever Where they go around and they're like, you know calling rich people are ringing on their doorbells and being like hey You know taxes are going up.
Speaker 1: We're gonna we'll help you move and they're not interested, right?
Speaker 1: It's a whole.
Speaker 1: it's a whole bit about basically to drive home the point that like no they won't leave Tax them more right but it's in a in a comedic and funny in a funny way.
Speaker 0: So yeah in the meta moment the geek nights book club book Which we're gonna try to target to do the show around the end of April the satanic verses by Sam and Rushdee Behind my the number of pages I need to read in order to.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I had to partly because it got real nice out When I would have been reading I went.
Speaker 1: the problem is is that you know I'm reading the book and then I fall asleep not because I'm bored with the book, but because I'm tired.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, we are.
Speaker 0: we're in our 40s.
Speaker 0: So give us a give some slack.
Speaker 1: It's like I lay on the couch and then I wake up with this You know my hand in the book and say well But if nothing else so many people have tried to murder this man because of this book.
Speaker 0: and if you read this book based on What I've read so far it is Really kind of insane to imagine that someone would want to murder this man over this specific book.
Speaker 0: Otherwise no cons for a while.
Speaker 0: Uh We'll see what happens.
Speaker 0: Hopefully we'll see you at PAX West and packs unplugged.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be summer.
Speaker 0: hopefully we'll do some interesting side content.
Speaker 0: Maybe do some live streams or some geek nights episodes outside all the stuff We were really trying to do right before a kovat hit.
Speaker 0: and then old technology We tried wasn't great, but I think now we have a really good setup.
Speaker 0: So stay tuned.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the website is coming along.
Speaker 0: I got some videos.
Speaker 0: all the video got Scott got from the panel We did at PAX East.
Speaker 0: I think I can put something together with that.
Speaker 0: So gonna work on that ID.
Speaker 0: I need some bad weather now, I need like weather that keeps me inside long enough to edit that video together.
Speaker 0: So hope for some storms over here And I think we get right into it cuz I was in a hockey game last night and a fixture in my life because I was not.
Speaker 0: grew up in Detroit moved to Rochester now, I live in New York City and Go to a lot of sports.
Speaker 0: Like I enjoy watching people compete in a variety of sports.
Speaker 0: I went to monster truck shows Which there are some sports and competitions there.
Speaker 0: It's not just rolling it like the it's not just rolling over cars for fun.
Speaker 0: They also ostensibly have some amount of competition.
Speaker 0: a lot of hockey a lot of basketball various levels of hockey and basketball including extremely amateur levels and anyone who goes to a lot of sports has a lot of opinions on the different arenas and venues and places that sports happen and a Sports.
Speaker 1: but other large entertainment events, you know the big concerts.
Speaker 1: Yeah, mostly big concerts.
Speaker 0: Let's leave convention centers out of this though because that gets a little we're talking about.
Speaker 1: you know an arena or you know a a stadium or a colosseum or you know a place where there is a Central area of attention.
Speaker 1: Yeah and a large number of seats in one room.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right like, you know a circus circuses, you know A Place where there's only one thing going on and everyone is there to see that one thing.
Speaker 1: but a circus has three rings right, but not we're gonna not include things like, you know an opera house or a Hall right where it's like you're.
Speaker 1: it's really only for one thing like, you know, you go it's.
Speaker 1: you know It's it's a it's a multi-purpose sort of arena, right?
Speaker 0: But also that's when they're big enough.
Speaker 1: basically, you know modern equivalents of the Colosseum in Rome were there.
Speaker 1: I don't know historically were there colosseums before the Colosseum or was that the first one?
Speaker 0: there were arenas all over Lots.
Speaker 1: they weren't like that one.
Speaker 1: Well, there was.
Speaker 1: that was like the biggest.
Speaker 0: There are proto versions like that.
Speaker 0: But yeah, that was basically like the one the government was like, alright This is we're gonna make the big one because we don't want anyone to riot in the city.
Speaker 1: There weren't bigger ones that just no don't look exist any longer.
Speaker 0: Uh, not that I know of and I'm qualifying there just because I'm not a hundred percent sure.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then as time went on I guess, you know, the any of the modern ones are basically children of that one.
Speaker 1: I've
Speaker 0: never been to that one, but I have been to the chariot arena in the in Constantinople the capital of the Eastern Roman Empire Which is huge and has the serpent column in it and there's there's cool stuff there And actually the track is like still there like the course that they ran.
Speaker 0: it's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: but the other thing about these big arenas and venues and like colosseums is that Because of their scale and because they are designed fundamentally to host the maximum number of people Like you think of these as an unlimited number of people effectively would go to this thing if they could.
Speaker 0: how do we get as?
Speaker 0: Many people into this thing.
Speaker 0: They're all bespoke.
Speaker 0: They're all unique.
Speaker 0: They're not just cookie cutter like the jolos arena that I watched the Red Wings in as a kid is So different from Madison Square Garden that they are like different kinds of buildings.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, I mean that's.
Speaker 1: I think that's the thing.
Speaker 1: is it every time someone makes one of these right?
Speaker 1: They really you know There are a lot of things in common between them now But no one ever really makes the same one twice because you've got a different place.
Speaker 1: You're putting it in.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you've got a different, you know Kind of culture.
Speaker 1: you have a different kinds of events that are going to be held there.
Speaker 0: Are you a city that can have a place that only does hockey or do you need that place to also do?
Speaker 0: Basketball because hockey is not that big.
Speaker 1: You've got different, you know laws and regulations in the place where you're building this thing, right?
Speaker 1: You have different interests, you know, and there's just so many hands and any time one of these things is made Right so that they're all unique and interesting but also in their own ology and best practices change Way faster than they can should and do.
Speaker 0: build these things.
Speaker 0: So every one that gets built is already the state of the art unless it's in a city that fucks it up.
Speaker 0: so like I like I have a lot of nostalgia for the Joe Louis Arena.
Speaker 0: the new arena they play in is Objectively just better in every depends in which you know what you're counting as better, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean sometimes they fuck up and make it worse But like I could it is how it was hard in say the 1940s to put as many seats in say a hockey arena as we can do with modern technology.
Speaker 0: today in 2023 like like look at Madison Square Garden, which is already pretty old They got this whole like third level that is just hanging from the inside of the facility You couldn't add 40s.
Speaker 1: Well, they added that on.
Speaker 1: Yeah wasn't there?
Speaker 0: that couldn't have been built in 1940.
Speaker 1: No, it was a renovation it wasn't you know a built thing, yeah But you know, it's like some places you like you're.
Speaker 1: yet you're in the United States, you know in Boston You get your Fenway Park right.
Speaker 1: in Chicago You got your Wrigley Field like super old baseball stadiums, right and those super old baseball stadiums.
Speaker 1: They sort of because they're so old Right, they sort of have a character in a history because they managed to not destroy them like everyone else.
Speaker 1: did you know who?
Speaker 1: Upgraded You know, so they managed to hold on to those for so long.
Speaker 1: It's like well now you're stuck with them and they have deficiencies, right and they lack some modern accoutrement that you can't really fix because they're just too small or they're too old, right you can only do so much You know, you don't want to ruin it and but they can renovate to some extent, right?
Speaker 1: But it's like yeah, and the problem is you get things like well Fenway Park, you know Some of the seats aren't good.
Speaker 1: You could be sitting behind a post or You could.
Speaker 0: there there are Islanders where they used to play like.
Speaker 0: there are literally just huge sections.
Speaker 0: You can't see anything right?
Speaker 1: They're like, you know, they'll be Not enough seats.
Speaker 1: and it's like yeah, we have a huge event here, but we don't have enough tickets.
Speaker 1: So the price is on the tickets.
Speaker 1: We do have a fortune.
Speaker 1: Where's some other bigger stadium?
Speaker 1: the ticket prices can at least get down a bit because there's a little more supply going on.
Speaker 1: More of the seats can see better.
Speaker 1: You know, you have weird things like I guess again Fenway Park.
Speaker 1: They have the big green monster in left field, right?
Speaker 1: It's like no one would make a baseball stadium like that today.
Speaker 1: now It's sort of a character thing, right?
Speaker 1: But yeah, it's also makes the game a bit.
Speaker 0: The red wings.
Speaker 0: before the Joe they used to play in the the Olympia and I remember my family would always talk about like going Redwings games in that old facility.
Speaker 0: the state the stairs and the seats were so steep that according to family legend Many people would fall and seriously injure themselves every single game trying to get into and out of their seats.
Speaker 0: drunk Yep.
Speaker 1: But yeah, it's like I've been going to stadiums sir, you know, I guess since I knew what the hell was going on.
Speaker 1: Yeah Some of them don't exist anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And also there's the trend that a lot of the places I went as a kid were named after famous people Named after places like.
Speaker 0: they had just local character color names.
Speaker 0: but most of the places now like the Red Wings played in the Olympia and then they played in a Joe Louis arena and now they play in the Little Caesars arena.
Speaker 1: Well, hold on now, right?
Speaker 1: So the the thing there it's not.
Speaker 1: people think that that's like a change.
Speaker 1: that's happened Right, it's.
Speaker 1: I don't think that's a change at all.
Speaker 0: You know the ones that didn't have these commercialized names were the rare ones for a long time.
Speaker 1: No, no, no, that's not at all.
Speaker 1: They've always had a commercialized name, right?
Speaker 1: It wasn't named Shea Stadium because they wanted to honor Mr.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's cuz there was a rich guy named Shea.
Speaker 1: That's why it's just the rich people used to put their own fucking name on the stuff Carnegie Hall or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then there are no rich people would to put their names on it.
Speaker 1: the rich company It's just whoever was rich at the time put their name on the thing that Detroit set.
Speaker 0: We just named it after Joe Louis.
Speaker 1: I Guess so, but the exceptions Joe Louis, I guess once he was success and the Olympia was just called Olympia Stadium, right?
Speaker 1: Well, the the exceptions for example would be like in New York.
Speaker 1: There was the Polo Grounds.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: That was it was literally named.
Speaker 1: It was the place where they played polo.
Speaker 1: It's like it did.
Speaker 1: They didn't have a name for it.
Speaker 1: It was just the polo ground.
Speaker 1: And then the other exceptions would be things like Yankee Stadium giant stadium.
Speaker 1: It's named after what goes on there primarily, right?
Speaker 0: I do like that style a little bit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like, you know, you could just call it med stadium, but they they never did that, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but yeah now, you know, it's like.
Speaker 1: but I can agree that you know a name of a person Even though even if it was originally just a rich person slapping their own name on there, right?
Speaker 0: Over time it's forgotten.
Speaker 1: people don't know who the person was or what it means or anything unless they look it up on Wikipedia, right?
Speaker 1: and so what ends up happening is that just ends up being a word that has no meaning.
Speaker 1: and Because it has no meaning it doesn't feel commercialized in any way shape or form especially that person's dead, right?
Speaker 1: Whereas a brand, you know the Citi Field or the MetLife Stadium here America Park Fucking.
Speaker 1: but they in LA they had the Staples Center which used to be something else and that was the crypto calm arena Which is the worst ever.
Speaker 0: that is actually the worst one on earth.
Speaker 1: That's the worst one, right?
Speaker 1: Because it has a Name that is a brand that you actually associate with something.
Speaker 1: now You have the sort of double association where it's like you're got a cup a brand Right and this building and that's what that's their intent.
Speaker 0: Obviously, that's work except it's Like if there was a comp USA or you know, that would just be really funny and they kept it that way forever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I like the ones personally where like you said Joe Louis arena where it's named after someone not because of money But because of worth right.
Speaker 1: the tennis over here is Arthur Ashe Stadium, right?
Speaker 1: Over in Australia, right?
Speaker 1: It's a rod lever state, right?
Speaker 1: It's like they named after someone who was fucking great at tennis.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: it's not named after the rich person or the company or what happened.
Speaker 1: It's not just called tennis arena As a name with a. it's like that.
Speaker 1: that's good Like if you had a hockey arena and you just called it Wayne Gretzky arena, right?
Speaker 1: That's what it's like.
Speaker 1: It's like that would be good.
Speaker 0: But in our in New York, you know Madison Square Garden That is it is its own company and venue and like media empire by itself Mmm owned by a piece of shit guy.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, that guy sucks like full disclosure.
Speaker 0: Fuck him.
Speaker 0: and also One thing I can say about MSG because every read is different and I got a lot of anecdotes about arenas I've been to with pros and cons and such.
Speaker 0: MSG is The hardest arena to get out of I have ever been to in my life.
Speaker 0: It takes it takes a while to get out of that place.
Speaker 1: It's pretty similar to a giant stadium.
Speaker 1: was in giant when you went to giant stadium with the one that doesn't exist anymore.
Speaker 1: basically, there were these spiral ramps on the corners right and they weren't stairs they were ramps.
Speaker 1: and Basically, it's like after the game you would exit.
Speaker 1: you just get what you had to get to one of the corners of giant stadium.
Speaker 1: I think there might have been some in the middle but you had to get to one of these ramps and Basically, you'd have to walk all the way down unless you were sitting way low I guess but you walked all the way down this big spiral.
Speaker 1: It took a long time And eventually you got to the bottom right.
Speaker 0: all the listener points out What about the NCAA and college arenas that often have like Michigan State like they're often just called like Spartan Stadium or something.
Speaker 0: I like that.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 1: But the other thing about the center.
Speaker 1: Well, at least the United States the college football stadiums are actually the biggest ones.
Speaker 1: they have the big capacity, right?
Speaker 1: It's like Madison Square Garden conceit, you know for hockey.
Speaker 1: It's 18,006 seats total for for basketball.
Speaker 1: It's a little bit more right the the college football stadiums.
Speaker 1: Some of them are like a hundred thousand plus like five Madison Square Gardens worth of people and they fill them up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so Giants the Giants play in an arena that holds 80,000 people right now according to my life stadium.
Speaker 1: Yeah, New York Giants football giant.
Speaker 0: Yes the Place that Michigan State football plays seats almost the same number of people.
Speaker 0: Yep, and other ones are way bigger than that.
Speaker 0: Michigan State is not the biggest or the best.
Speaker 0: Sorry drew My brother went to MSU, but most of my friends went to U of M.
Speaker 1: So Yeah, you know the.
Speaker 1: I think I really good.
Speaker 1: if you want to talk about college places Right a place that I'm familiar with because it was in Connecticut where I lived for 16 17 years right is the Yale Bowl, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like.
Speaker 1: basically that's like the ancestor of all the college stadiums in the u.s.
Speaker 1: Effectively like it's still there.
Speaker 1: They still use it But like it's basically like the old.
Speaker 1: you want to see what it's like old and busted right?
Speaker 1: It's like it's just like these.
Speaker 1: I Mean.
Speaker 1: if you look at a picture of it, you'll see it's literally just like a bowl, right?
Speaker 1: It's not like.
Speaker 1: You know an arena that's built up.
Speaker 1: It's like it's like cut out of the ground almost like this little dish and it's not very deep whatsoever.
Speaker 1: It's just wide Right.
Speaker 0: Oh, so I looked up because you know RIT, you know the hockey we talked about a lot and old gig nights.
Speaker 0: We we used to go see at the Ritter Which was free.
Speaker 1: they have a new one.
Speaker 1: They built a new one right after we left.
Speaker 0: So the Ritter's seated 2100 people 1600 sitting 500 standing.
Speaker 0: I went to many a game where I stood.
Speaker 0: I Have a lot of fond memories that place the gene Pulisani Center the one that they built right as we were leaving named after a rich guy who paid for it.
Speaker 0: Yep seats more than double that.
Speaker 1: Yep Yep, one consider much nicer.
Speaker 0: another consideration on the seating.
Speaker 0: That's interesting is that part of the reason why NCAA venues are just so big it's partly that They're gonna be filled.
Speaker 0: because of school spirit.
Speaker 0: They're often actually cheaper to go to or at least the tickets are sold cheaper and are often allocated to students Forget there is a secondary market and scalping and stuff up and all that stuff.
Speaker 0: but like tickets are generally directly cheaper because they just want to fill it.
Speaker 0: but like You don't build a hockey arena.
Speaker 0: That's not gonna mostly sell out on purpose.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of cities that build smaller arenas on purpose to make sure they sell out rather than having empty capacity For a lot of historical and capitalist reasons.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: All right, so let's let's go through some arena related topics, right?
Speaker 1: So the first of all talk about some dome action, right?
Speaker 1: So some of them got roofs and some of them don't got roofs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: and in my opinion, right?
Speaker 1: It's like I think some of the roofs, right?
Speaker 1: I mean having a roof is kind of good because you can play when there's bad weather but for game for certain sports Right.
Speaker 1: bad weather is charming like a man football who doesn't love a football in the snow?
Speaker 0: I have a lot of issues with American football But something I deeply respect about it is that the rules are basically they play no matter what?
Speaker 1: Almost no matter.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean if there's a tornado like barreling toward the arena It's a lot more tolerant than other sports to bad weather like football in the snow.
Speaker 0: that I got kind of like watching.
Speaker 1: actually Right, but if you have a dome you lose that charm right to.
Speaker 1: some of the domes can be ugly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, old old domes like a lot of the older shittier ones stopped working properly and stuff, right?
Speaker 1: That's that's not.
Speaker 1: there's a few big ones that have been stuck for a long time Yeah, but it's also kind of nice right like for baseball Let's say where they will just at the one drop of rain.
Speaker 1: They stopped playing baseball Almost right where it's like.
Speaker 1: you bought tickets.
Speaker 1: you want to go to the game?
Speaker 1: If they have the dome or roof, it's like great, you know, I've been to games so there's been a rain delay.
Speaker 1: We'd sit around waiting for hours or you have to leave and come back another day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's just nice to be able to ensure that you buy a ticket.
Speaker 1: you're gonna go and at that time You know, the game will happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right There's good ice hockey where you're really got to play indoors and climate change is only gonna make that worse.
Speaker 0: But occasionally you get like the winter classic like the special game that's in a like bespoke or one-time use.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my knowledge whether hasn't spoiled any winter classics yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah I feel like that'll come someday unless they just move them further and further north.
Speaker 1: It would be awesome if it.
Speaker 1: you know, there might have been one word wet bad weather, but I just didn't know about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'd like that.
Speaker 0: I feel like it snowed a little bit during one of them.
Speaker 0: Maybe I vaguely recall that but it wasn't enough to affect the game.
Speaker 0: I wish it had.
Speaker 0: I just like that.
Speaker 0: but There's the.
Speaker 0: how do you get to it and leave it?
Speaker 0: Cuz one big thing.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah arenas in big if all of cities that are dense and have mass transit are Fundamentally different in a lot of ways from a suburban stadium out in the middle of nowhere.
Speaker 1: Yep, so for just to give you an example or a most when you have a stadium that is not in a downtown of a city It's usually surrounded by parking lots that are empty most of the time and it's not great.
Speaker 0: I think it sucks.
Speaker 0: I think that actually mutes a lot of the benefits in arena could bring to a community because it is just this capitalist event outside of any community Fully surrounded by horrible parking lots and cars and nightmare traffic.
Speaker 0: It makes the lives of everyone who live near it miserable and it doesn't benefit them in any way.
Speaker 1: Yep, and it's like even look at you know over City Field over there and Shea Stadium before it you know with all those parking lots and it's like That's.
Speaker 1: you know, if there were houses on that land, you know, how many people you could house?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's about Valuable.
Speaker 1: that land is in housing there and raise the price of the houses.
Speaker 1: the seven train goes there.
Speaker 0: How about this?
Speaker 0: He's all houses there.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: every house gets four season tickets so they can lease them out or do whatever they want with them.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying it's like it's a. it's a real shame to not to just have that land be used on Parking but also flat parking lot.
Speaker 1: It's not even a parking garage.
Speaker 0: This leads to a much bigger externality that if you don't live in America, you might not realize.
Speaker 0: so Drunk driving in America is actually one of the biggest killers of humans.
Speaker 0: Like it is it is like up there.
Speaker 1: it is guns, right right now It's pretty much guns and cars are the two things that kill Americans the most.
Speaker 0: yep, but drunk driving is a huge problem in America and a Scary percentage of it is caused directly by the arenas We just described.
Speaker 0: because people there's no way to get to most sports venues in America except by driving there.
Speaker 0: a lot of people like to drink alcohol while they're watching sports and Then they stop selling it to you.
Speaker 1: after a certain point people will hold on to it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know the buy a whole bunch at the second intermission and then drink.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm not allowed to buy beer in like the last quarter of a football game But I can buy as much beer as I want two seconds before that quarter starts.
Speaker 0: like that doesn't make sense.
Speaker 1: It makes sense for the people who are making money.
Speaker 0: so does but even then, you know, I've had alcohol.
Speaker 0: One quarter of a football game is not enough time for all the beers.
Speaker 0: You're not even close to get back down to a blood alcohol.
Speaker 0: That is legal or reasonable?
Speaker 1: I wonder if we could do a study like comparing a number of DUIs after games with ot versus without ot.
Speaker 0: Oh, I Remember being stuck at that crazy like many ot game at MSG and of course, you know all the employees like they stopped serving food.
Speaker 0: I was desperately hungry.
Speaker 0: Everything was shut down.
Speaker 0: There's nothing to eat.
Speaker 1: Yep So just you know some interesting getting to and from stories right obviously mad square garden.
Speaker 1: It's like I guess you could drive to it and park in a parking garage.
Speaker 0: a lot of people scarily do.
Speaker 1: it's a bad idea mostly Jersey people right, but I Once drove to Fenway Park for the all-star game, right and the parking garage.
Speaker 1: This is a 19 maybe early 2000 I forget late 90s.
Speaker 1: You can look it up because that the all-star game hasn't been there that often right and The.
Speaker 1: I remember distinctly in that this is at least 20 years ago the parking garages that were right next to Fenway.
Speaker 1: We didn't park at those ones.
Speaker 1: We parked further away, right?
Speaker 0: Same large earnings games.
Speaker 1: They were charging Like city bucks in the nose that was a hundred.
Speaker 1: this is an all-star game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this wasn't a normal game.
Speaker 1: But even you know Boston parking is already out of control, right?
Speaker 0: It's probably $150 normally Those arenas I think 50 bucks just to park it packs not counting the valet charge for one by MetLife MetLife Stadium.
Speaker 1: Right these state it's like, you know, even if even though they're surrounded by parking lots They still don't have enough parking and you have to buy a separate parking pass permit Right to park your car at the stadium.
Speaker 1: Otherwise you to park at some other lot somewhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I take like a bus or walk like 20 minutes if
Speaker 1: you want to go see football New England Patriots football in Foxborough, Massachusetts Right, basically you get off the highway at this exit and there's this road and on the road It's basically nothing but like motels and stuff and people selling like parking spots on their grass.
Speaker 1: Right and as you get closer to the stadium the prices go up Right.
Speaker 1: and then eventually when you get all the way to the stadium, it's like well if you want to park at the stadium I hope you have a parking pass.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: and so basically there's this whole culture of you drive and this one road.
Speaker 1: everyone parks somewhere on that road, right?
Speaker 1: However much they're willing to walk before and after the game or whether they have a pass or not And the road is one way before the game starts and then sometime during the game They switch the road to be one way backwards.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I Don't know if they might keep one lane separately or something for you know But it's uh, it's like this weird at this whole weird setup for going to and from this thing.
Speaker 1: This is in the middle of nowhere by itself Right, just just for events.
Speaker 0: so that I remember as kids cuz you know We go to Red Wings games when we could like we weren't rich But we got to go to Red Wings games and when we go we drive.
Speaker 0: cuz while there was the mass transit within and around Detroit there's no way to get to go to where your house was.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we
Speaker 0: drive and the rule was We would either walk out in the last four minutes of the game to get to our contract to GTFO or We would just stay in our seats for like 40 minutes before even considered leaving Because if you left when the game ended you would sit in your car Slowly moving through the parking garage for and I'm this is zero exaggeration over an hour like minimum It was.
Speaker 0: it took so long to get out of that parking garage.
Speaker 0: it was just a nightmare You know, that's the thing.
Speaker 1: if you'd bring your car to the stadium We basically a game had to be like ridiculously close exciting for us to actually stay Right to the complete end if we card to the game because we had to get to the car early to get the hell out Of there, right?
Speaker 1: I remember distinctly one time where we went to.
Speaker 1: It was Patriot Saints in Foxborough, right and there was like almost no time left on the clock whatsoever, right and They the Saints were up and the Saints got an interception.
Speaker 1: Yeah, as soon as they caught that interception We're like it's over.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and we get.
Speaker 1: we just got up and left because there were not not much time left.
Speaker 1: Right and we go or get to the car we get in the car Right and we eat.
Speaker 1: whether eat whether you left a game early or not, right or you would customarily turn the radio on to the game Right.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah I have a lot of memories of sitting in that traffic in the parking garage Listening to the last few minutes of the game on the radio Right or sometimes it would just be the post game if you actually did stay to the end.
Speaker 1: But we're in the car and then we hear people outside the car freaking out Right and then after some short delay the radio is freaking out and it's like well, I guess you shouldn't have left that game Right.
Speaker 1: Tom Brady found a way with the the remaining time on the clock.
Speaker 1: somehow I'm sure someone can look up and see what game that was.
Speaker 1: But it's like if we didn't have to car that wouldn't happen.
Speaker 1: We would have seen the whole game even at MSG.
Speaker 0: So we Emily and I were at that crazy many overtimes game.
Speaker 0: a lot of people left after the first OT Because they had to catch their train back to New Jersey like or they don't have a good way to get home.
Speaker 0: So they had to leave.
Speaker 0: and even now like any game you're at a lot of people leave MSG early and it is almost Exclusively people who live in New Jersey who have to catch a train.
Speaker 1: Yep So let's talk about quickly seating right.
Speaker 1: so most arenas they got seats at different heights.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right Usually higher is and farther back is cheaper.
Speaker 0: But the seats themselves are also different.
Speaker 0: in a lot of arenas.
Speaker 0: the class depends depends.
Speaker 1: Yes, some of them outdoor ones sometimes even just have benches or whatever.
Speaker 0: I sat on metal hard bleacher.
Speaker 1: But we went to the game in Buffalo.
Speaker 1: We sat on the steel benches.
Speaker 0: I went a lot of tires game sitting on metal benches like behind the outfield.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there aren't a lot of metal benches these days in the newer places.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: It's mostly at least a plastic folding seat.
Speaker 1: Yeah minimum, but nowadays some of the places have put it in like squishy recliner expensive seeds with cupholders and massage.
Speaker 1: There's like, you know all kinds of non.
Speaker 0: But then different sports have different traditions and different setups like basketball has really close to basketball.
Speaker 1: You're in a folding.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is like they just set up regular like normal folding chairs like it ever on a poker table.
Speaker 0: Just yeah, cuz right next to the game like you could reach out.
Speaker 1: like other sports It's really safe to sit close to basket.
Speaker 0: Well, it's like worst case a heavy guy bumps into you and apologizes or a basketball bumps into you like, okay Wait, and most people think that's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, Jack like fell on me.
Speaker 0: I would just be like, sorry shack Sorry, I was in your way.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know people love that Hockey puck, I don't wanna I don't want that to hit me, you know, nothing to do with it.
Speaker 1: Baseball.
Speaker 1: you got a big net.
Speaker 1: Thank good.
Speaker 1: You don't want to get hit by that.
Speaker 0: if you're a little kid You probably have your catchers met with you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you still don't want to get hit by that.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's too dangerous.
Speaker 1: But not only that but you also have some luxury box action, right?
Speaker 1: I've been a few a few but work never never except for work.
Speaker 1: Yeah There's a few different kinds of luxury boxes these days.
Speaker 1: Most arenas have three kinds at least main three main kind.
Speaker 0: That's a good point.
Speaker 0: They are different now.
Speaker 1: There's there's one kind which is the.
Speaker 1: I Have I'm having a group event like a birthday party and I shelled out big and there's a special box just for that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's like a luxury box.
Speaker 1: That's Kez catering or whatever right and pretty much anyone can get that if you pay enough money and it's not like in the old RIT arena.
Speaker 0: there was one luxury box technically and you could just rent it like just pay money.
Speaker 1: Yep Yep, the second kind is the.
Speaker 1: there are many small luxury boxes and each of them is individually owned, right?
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 1: I've sat in like at various events.
Speaker 1: I was in like a Pepsi luxury box once right?
Speaker 1: Pepsi owned that box or at least it or whatever and basically no matter what event was held in that arena Stadium Right Pepsi there were some seats that were in the box, right?
Speaker 1: Pepsi had the rights to those seats.
Speaker 1: You couldn't.
Speaker 1: just no one else could buy those tickets except Pepsi the company.
Speaker 0: And that's something a lot of people don't know.
Speaker 0: that if you want if you own a luxury box Yeah, you got to buy tickets to anything you want to write kid.
Speaker 1: Just so it's like, okay, right?
Speaker 1: So let's say there's a BTS concert at the stadium, right?
Speaker 1: Pepsi doesn't just automatically get tickets to that.
Speaker 1: They just have these tickets for those seats that are set aside and they can either buy them or not.
Speaker 1: And if they buy them they can give them to whoever they like, right?
Speaker 0: But nobody said no one goes.
Speaker 1: that box sits there empty, right?
Speaker 1: Even though Pepsi can decorate the box all they want, you know They can get free catering in the box when they use it.
Speaker 1: They could all this, you know get all this bonuses along with the box.
Speaker 1: But you have to buy tickets to sit in your own box if you want to.
Speaker 1: you just basically have Guaranteed tickets to any event that were to happen in that space Unless you know I guess sometimes there might be like a concert and if the state your your box might be like behind the stage and not available In which case tough cookies.
Speaker 1: Yep, and the third kind right?
Speaker 1: There's a lot of places have this.
Speaker 1: it's basically the club.
Speaker 1: There'll be some kind of sponsored club or multiple sponsored clubs.
Speaker 0: I feel like there's a lot more of these lately like over there.
Speaker 1: They're very popular because they're all sponsored right and basically what these are.
Speaker 1: it's a way for a wealthy person To basically have a season ticket, but the season ticket is in this club.
Speaker 1: So it's like they share a luxury box with many other rich people that they don't know, right?
Speaker 1: They couldn't afford to just reserve a whole box just for themselves.
Speaker 1: But they're wealthy enough that they can get a season ticket that comes with like in a special zone With like their own bar and their own wait staff and their own everything Right and their own special luxuries and fancy seats and TVs and lounges.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like every airplane lounge deal.
Speaker 1: Right now you're in there.
Speaker 1: You have enough money to get special treatment But you're in there with all the other people you don't know that also have paid for special tree.
Speaker 0: They're a lot like airport lounges.
Speaker 1: Yes, you know, they're not bad though.
Speaker 1: They usually good seats.
Speaker 1: I've been in them a couple times and I gotta say I like.
Speaker 0: I Have pro.
Speaker 1: there are pros and cons.
Speaker 0: the luxury box if I was mega-rich, I might.
Speaker 0: I would also consider I could see Family luxury box and like just bring people to it and see games, but yeah gotta remember Luxury boxes are not necessarily the best way to see a sport if the sport itself is what you care about because they're fun.
Speaker 0: Like don't get me wrong.
Speaker 0: I don't I don't dislike a luxury box.
Speaker 0: If someone invites me to one like in May, I guess we're gonna get a big box for my team at Yankee Stadium.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna go there and see a game.
Speaker 0: I tried to convince them for the Mets and they were not here to me, but They aren't the best seats compared to like the actually expensive good seats Like.
Speaker 1: nope,
Speaker 0: if you want if you care about
Speaker 1: some some places they are but usually rarely
Speaker 0: like you really care about hockey And you want to sit like near the glass like if you like sitting close Sitting in the lower ring is way better than sitting in the luxury boxes.
Speaker 0: They're pretty high up.
Speaker 0: Some of them are even higher than where we sit.
Speaker 1: Hmm, you know, there's also, you know depends on the arena where the luxury boxes are exactly right, you know There's.
Speaker 1: there might be some on the end.
Speaker 0: It's like, okay I've seen places where there are a few like luxury boxes that are like right down at ice level.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you could you could be any.
Speaker 0: they're like stay like like.
Speaker 0: you see a little dip and then there's a glass wall and some.
Speaker 0: There's no way to get to those seats except through a basically a secret door from the actual luxury box that's there.
Speaker 0: But they always often have the same format of.
Speaker 0: there's the box area and then there's like a bunch of seats Outside the box like at the edge of wherever the luxury box is.
Speaker 0: Usually those are seats you technically purchased.
Speaker 1: Yeah now we did.
Speaker 1: I do want to talk about Stadium food, but I think we can make a separate episode.
Speaker 0: I think we'll have to because I have a lot of opinions on stadium food.
Speaker 1: So much going on there, but I do just want to close briefly talking about the non sports at the arenas, right?
Speaker 1: So, you know, I've seen like the circus at the arena, you know, it's like.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's fine It's a sir, you know, where else are you gonna put a sir?
Speaker 0: I saw Sesame Street live and Muppet Babies live at Cobo Hall when I was a little kid.
Speaker 1: I've seen some X on ice at various, you know, maybe Hartford Civic Center.
Speaker 0: I saw Chris cross perform at Cobo Hall once right?
Speaker 1: Yes, let's have a concerts at arenas, right?
Speaker 1: I am not a huge fan of Concert at an even if it's someone I really really really like like my favorite band in the universe or whatever Right at an arena to go see them.
Speaker 1: It's like Okay, maybe it might be good if it's like that time we saw tool in Albany, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you don't need to see tool, right?
Speaker 1: It's like what is there to look?
Speaker 1: you need to feel tool via all the people around you, right and having a giant You know general admission mosh pit.
Speaker 1: Okay, that works out kind of right.
Speaker 1: It's okay.
Speaker 1: I'd still rather have a smaller place though, right?
Speaker 1: But if it's like an act where I actually want to see them, right?
Speaker 1: I got something to look at maybe some dancing right or some.
Speaker 1: you know I'm really there to listen to them.
Speaker 1: the acoustics are not the best in the arena Not the way they would be at a concert hall, right?
Speaker 0: Brooklyn Steel if I want to hear I would be in like Lincoln Center, right exactly.
Speaker 1: So it's like an arena isn't the best for seeing.
Speaker 1: it isn't the best for hearing right and it's like, you know a lot of time the seeing is just gonna be like.
Speaker 1: You know these giant video screens a lot of people set up and it's like.
Speaker 1: well if you're I'm just looking at video screens Why don't I just get the concert DVD and watch it at home?
Speaker 1: Why should I be here?
Speaker 1: It's like and they charge so much more money because it costs so much more money to set this thing up Right.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: I'm just not a fan of any concert no matter how much I like the group.
Speaker 0: So what I am a fan of and you can't always do this is some concerts.
Speaker 0: you can get the luxury box tickets And if you go to a luxury box at a big stadium concert with a bunch of friends It just becomes a hangout.
Speaker 0: or our concerts happening.
Speaker 0: But that unless you get a good deal or get lucky that is a lot of money for a very relatively diminished return.
Speaker 1: Now I am gonna you know caveat by saying any time the few times I've gone to an arena concert It was always a general admission or a faraway seat or I was never paying big money to get close because I Didn't care enough to get close.
Speaker 1: I wasn't gonna I didn't have the money.
Speaker 1: I wasn't gonna spend that much right, but there is an upcoming K-pop concert right.
Speaker 1: mamamoo is coming to The islanders place EBS, right and I'm like, I'm like, alright, they've never come here before it's or they're probably not gonna come again.
Speaker 1: Right, we like them.
Speaker 1: they're like the best live ever right.
Speaker 1: so it's like let's pay to get close at least right.
Speaker 1: so We can see we're in like the 12th row.
Speaker 0: It cost a shit ton of money like the last time I went to Lincoln Center.
Speaker 0: It was a. it was a classical like piano act I was really interested in.
Speaker 0: so we sat in the second row and you know what those seats cost a lot more than a hockey game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but for that I could.
Speaker 1: you could have sit far away and it would be in the mezzanine.
Speaker 1: you'd be fine.
Speaker 0: Well, cuz it was I wanted to see too because this if you sit that close You're right next to the guy playing the piano like crazy.
Speaker 1: No, you want to see his hands?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, it was.
Speaker 0: it was something to see his hands like you could hear him hitting the piano.
Speaker 1: It was well, I mean with kpop you want to see someone dance.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: So it's I don't need I don't?
Speaker 0: you don't want to be so close that you just see like their legs Right, so I'm gonna find out.
Speaker 1: I guess for the first time I've lived this long and I still never sat close at an arena concert, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like is the arena concert acceptable if you pay a fortune to be fucking close as if you know You're as close as you would be in a smaller place?
Speaker 1: and I'll find out the answer to that.
Speaker 1: But again, it costs a fortune and probably isn't worth it very often at all.
Speaker 0: So the listener had a comment that made me laugh.
Speaker 0: quote.
Speaker 0: I bet the line for the bathroom at that crisscross concert was needlessly long due to all the backward pants and a lot of people wore their jeans backward to that concert and it was actually a problem because it's really hard to pee and Like backward jeans are not comfortable after about 20 minutes.
Speaker 0: But yes, I'm speaking from personal experience.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna pretend I wasn't all-in on that concert.
Speaker 0: but last thing bathrooms, uh Bathrooms in arenas are generally the worst possible thing and are to be avoided at all cost.
Speaker 0: I've been in the places where you if you're a man with a penis and peeing into a trough Surrounded by easily a hundred other men some of whom are facing you on the other side.
Speaker 0: That is that is not a great experience.
Speaker 1: Listen, I was like a teenager and I had basically that experience.
Speaker 1: I was peeing at a NASCAR race deal.
Speaker 1: You can't beat that one that Monster truck show.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying I think those are about equivalent.
Speaker 0: That is the.
Speaker 0: I was pissing into a trough Surrounded by men who were peeing as long as Tom Hanks in a league of their own because they had consumed more alcohol.
Speaker 1: I think that was the first time I saw a trough and like I wasn't totally sure.
Speaker 0: I was sure because there were like a Dozen men pissing into it like a racehorses.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was like really I Have stood in bathroom lines that were like 20 or 30 minutes long just to pee at sports events.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, you know, that's the thing is like on the one hand if the sport at the event You're at is so exciting.
Speaker 1: You don't want to miss any of it You might have to just wait in the line and go during the break in between quarters in between.
Speaker 0: That's why I see a lot of people get up and run With two minutes to go in a period because they're running to piss and then to buy more beer and get back to their seat Exactly, but sometimes it's like if it's really boring or it's a blowout.
Speaker 1: you can just go in between, you know, whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if it's really exciting then y'all you're just gonna have to deal with it.
Speaker 0: But I will.
Speaker 0: modern arenas are better and better at this like indeed even MSG is not that bad It is.
Speaker 0: it's not the bottom that I've encountered by a wide margin even if you move NASCAR and monster truck.
Speaker 1: I think you've also got different issues depending on Gender disparity and events.
Speaker 0: some events are heavily.
Speaker 0: I remember when we were at PAX.
Speaker 0: There's a huge line for the men's bathroom and all the girls we were with for the first time.
Speaker 0: We're like wow how the tables have turned.
Speaker 0: my dudes enjoy and they all peed and then they left while we were standing in line.
Speaker 1: Yep, that's that's how you know, sometimes you're at the monster truck event and One line is short.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, it's not a. it's not a sexist thing.
Speaker 1: It's just the reality of it, right?
Speaker 1: It's like that's just how it is.
Speaker 1: Go to the tail.
Speaker 1: I'm sure if you go to the Taylor Swift concert It's the office.
Speaker 0: when we went to that's a footy game in Australia way back that place had.
Speaker 1: I didn't go to the bathroom I did.
Speaker 0: and cuz I remember I made a bet that I didn't win.
Speaker 0: After that coming out of the bathroom on that kiosk and Fool that I bet like a couple Australian dollars.
Speaker 0: I don't remember when I bet on.
Speaker 0: I didn't understand the kiosk Understand the game.
Speaker 1: I did eventually understand the game.
Speaker 0: I kind of get it now, but kind of uh There were more Like.
Speaker 0: there was more bathroom capacity there than I have ever seen in my life.
Speaker 0: There was no line and there were a lot of people paying.
Speaker 0: there were just like it wasn't troughs either.
Speaker 0: There was like hundreds and hundreds and hundreds of urinals as far as the eye could see.
Speaker 0: it was amazing Yep.
Speaker 0: But also that place is huge.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that place was indeed.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know an AFL field is big and a cricket field is big.
Speaker 1: So it's like, you know, it's not like here, you know hockey even and you know people like oh how many football fields?
Speaker 1: NFL football fields aren't big compared to cricket fields.
Speaker 1: putting fields soccer fields.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night
Speaker 0: and the active picture on patreon has given us at least five dollars a month Therefore being listed in order of how much money they give us and I'm not sure how it determines The order when everyone's giving the same amount.
Speaker 0: But anyway, Alan Joyce linkage you driven the tenderbread case.
Speaker 0: care makes music.
Speaker 0: Chris the dog Clinton Walton Dex Finn Joel Hayes penny Reimer Rebecca Dunn Sam Erickson Shervin Von Harl and several people whose names I will not say.
Speaker 0: I'm real hungry I'm gonna stop right here and I'm gonna leave you with a classic.