Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, February 21st, 2023.
Speaker 1: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight, we are talking about gaming furniture, but not desk chairs for PC gamers.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So we're doing all sorts of new setup.
Speaker 1: We're actually streaming this episode live into a Discord stage in the official Geek Nights Discord.
Speaker 1: It's also streaming to YouTube, where I see some people watching.
Speaker 1: Though, YouTube viewership has dropped off precipitously now that we're in the Discord, which already says something about where people prefer to see this stuff.
Speaker 0: They finally added video and screen sharing to Discord stages, so I suppose we can now do all the things we shit-talked about doing.
Speaker 0: If they were to add that feature, they added the feature.
Speaker 0: Uh-oh, uh-oh, we might have to shit-talk.
Speaker 1: We both got into, and I'm assuming a lot of people got into it, but the Adobe Podcasts, like, alpha, I guess?
Speaker 1: Maybe beta?
Speaker 0: Early access.
Speaker 0: It's a beta.
Speaker 0: They said it's beta.
Speaker 1: They said it's beta.
Speaker 1: There's not a lot in there yet compared to what they said.
Speaker 1: this thing's gonna do.
Speaker 0: But it's not a lot in there, but it seems to have everything you need.
Speaker 0: It lets you record a podcast.
Speaker 0: It dramatically improves the audio quality with minimal effort.
Speaker 1: Unless you're us, where it actually degrades the audio quality by a tiny bit.
Speaker 0: But the point is, the terms of effort versus quality, right?
Speaker 0: Someone who doesn't know what the hell they're doing can get amazing quality.
Speaker 0: And then you can send really simple invite links to people.
Speaker 0: They click it, they join, and now they're in the podcast talking to you.
Speaker 0: All they need is, you know, a web browser, right?
Speaker 0: And to give it microphone permissions.
Speaker 0: And then, when you're done with your podcast, you can push save, and it will save just a WAV file of the whole recording, right?
Speaker 0: It won't be multi-track, I don't think.
Speaker 1: That's fatal to us.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But, and then, it makes a text transcript that you can edit in their nice UI, and when you push save to download the WAV, it also downloads the text file of the text transcript.
Speaker 0: Which is, that's the feature that, you know, we don't have at all right now, and we want desperately.
Speaker 1: Well, also, there's one thing, the synchronized recording, especially if they support multi-track at some point, and I want to give a lot of feedback to them.
Speaker 1: There is a step in the Geek Nights process that we only had to do when COVID happened, and we started doing the show remotely.
Speaker 1: Granted, it's actually, now it's easier to do the show remotely than in person.
Speaker 1: So, like, doing the show in person would be a special occasion.
Speaker 1: But Scott's clock on his audio interface is slightly jittery, and the tiniest bit, like, 0.1% slower than my clock, and all the clocks that I'm synchronized with.
Speaker 1: So, I have a step in the process to synchronize our audio, which is a minor step, but I have to do it, and I have to do it manually, because there's no good automatic way to do that, and it takes about 60 seconds.
Speaker 1: So, that would save me 60 seconds if I don't have to do that anymore.
Speaker 0: The point, I think what they would love to see them do is add a plugin for Audition for Adobe Podcasts.
Speaker 1: Oh, just give me fucking time code.
Speaker 0: Right, well, this is how I imagine it, right?
Speaker 0: One person opens Audition, and they make a multi-track session, and they send invite codes to people, and those people are using Adobe Podcasts.
Speaker 0: They don't even know Audition is happening, right?
Speaker 0: But then, each of those people shows up in the Audition on their own track, right?
Speaker 0: And then, in the Audition, they make, like, a new tab where the transcript is or some shit, right?
Speaker 0: And now, everyone except the one producer person is just using Adobe Podcasts, like, on the web like normal, but the one producer person has Audition open, everyone's on their own track, and you still get the transcript feature.
Speaker 0: And the recordings, all those people on their individual tracks are getting that, you know, improved quality automatically from Adobe Podcasts.
Speaker 1: And if they get to that point, I would say that would make Adobe Podcasts, like, it would become what cool that it was for the audio industry, for the modern podcasting industry.
Speaker 1: I think people would just ditch their pipelines for that.
Speaker 1: I think even Pro Studios would ditch their pipelines.
Speaker 0: We could probably talk about this in some other episode, but I think it's really interesting what's happening in the podcasting landscape right now, where, on the one hand, people who are trying to make money with podcasts, I think, are doing a little bit worse right now.
Speaker 0: Especially the companies that went into podcasting, like Spotify and whatever, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, it's not making them that much money, but demand for podcasts is up, it seems, from listeners.
Speaker 1: And I think podcasts, overall, is a way bigger space.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Sponsor money seems a bit down, and also professional podcast production quantity.
Speaker 0: It seems like there are less pro people making podcasts, and less, you know, amateur people, like us, making podcasts.
Speaker 0: I guess, technically, we're professional.
Speaker 0: Maybe we can get some listeners.
Speaker 1: It's funny, because I think, when I look at our old numbers, relative to the podcasting space, there was an era where Geek Nights was weird, like unduly big relative to the podcasting space, but then...
Speaker 0: I think a lot of those older numbers are also wrong.
Speaker 1: Well...
Speaker 0: A lot of those older numbers are wrong.
Speaker 1: I think there were podcatchers that were dodgy and were downloaded a bunch of times.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 0: Those are wrong numbers, you know.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: But, uh, there's a... Well, there's one risky thing in the setup, I'll just tell you.
Speaker 1: I'm using an out-of-spec, because it's so long, USB-C cable to connect the audio interface.
Speaker 1: That is, PreSonus says, "Do not fucking use
Speaker 1: extenders.".
Speaker 1: So far, it seems to be working fine, but I'm taking that risk.
Speaker 1: I tested this thoroughly.
Speaker 1: But this is the production test with the super long USB-C cable.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: So yeah, in the news... No, we haven't done a Tuesday episode since then.
Speaker 1: We did a Tuesday episode the day it was, like, right before it came out, so we speculated.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So anyway, what happened in that Nintendo Direct?
Speaker 0: Well, a bunch of stuff we don't really care about, right?
Speaker 0: Stuff we do care about, like the new Zelda game, but what are we gonna say about it?
Speaker 1: The new Advantage Wars game, guess what, RIM's gonna play again.
Speaker 0: Like... Yeah, it was already announced, but now they got a firm date.
Speaker 0: It's definitely coming.
Speaker 0: The biggest news was that they done the obvious thing that they should have did a long time ago, which is that they added Game Boy, Game Boy Color, Game Boy Advance games to the Nintendo Online emulator, right?
Speaker 0: So if you have a Switch and you pay for Nintendo Online, then for free, you can play a selection of Game Boy, Game Boy Advance, Game Boy Color games on your Switch in what's basically an emulator.
Speaker 0: And you might say, "Well, Scott, you know, why do you care about that?
Speaker 0: You have the upgraded GBA.
Speaker 0: You already have every single Game Boy, Game Boy Color, Game Boy Advance game ever, right?
Speaker 0: On an upgraded system with an IPS screen, and it's like, why the hell do you want this,
Speaker 0: right?".
Speaker 0: So there's two answers, actually.
Speaker 0: I think I'm gonna, you know, unlike the NES, SNES, N64 emulators that they have, which aren't really any improvement over, you know, the ones you might get illicitly.
Speaker 1: Well, except they have that really good rewind feature that I use heavily.
Speaker 0: That's, right, so that's the first thing, is that in some of the emulators, I don't think the N64 one has it, but they have this rewind feature, which is basically the emulator is constantly making save states all the time, and you can press L and R, like, together, and then rewind, like if you fall into a pit, you can just be like,
Speaker 0: "Whoopsie!"
Speaker 0: and come out of the pit and jump again immediately.
Speaker 0: You don't need to, like, constantly press save state, load state, save state, load state.
Speaker 0: It's like, just when you make a mistake, you go boop, and you rewind the game a little bit.
Speaker 0: And, is that cheating?
Speaker 0: Yeah, obviously, but I'm not gonna sit here and play Gargoyle's Quest legitimately in the year 2023.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm 41, I ain't got time for that.
Speaker 0: But, but playing Gargoyle's Quest with the cheating feature is actually a fun time.
Speaker 0: Like, that game has a lot of merit, it's just hard as balls, and if you make it easy, now it's like an okay, pretty good game with some interesting stuff going on.
Speaker 0: So, that's a good value.
Speaker 0: The second reason that these emulators, I think, are worth it, and I would prefer to use them over even my fancy upgraded GBA, is that, yeah, okay, the Switch is nicer, it's got an even better screen, even better Bluetooth audio, whatever, you know, whatever, but, they went to the effort of emulating the multiplayer.
Speaker 0: So, if you bust open the Mario Kart Super Circuit GBA ROM on the Nintendo Switch Online, you can play it wirelessly against your friends who also have Switches and also have Nintendo Online.
Speaker 0: That is huge, assuming it works.
Speaker 0: The illicit emulators don't have that working, right?
Speaker 1: Nintendo does not have a track record of that working.
Speaker 0: I think it works, and the one last thing, which isn't new for the Switch, but was news to me, is that, you know, on the Wii U, they had Virtual Console.
Speaker 0: So, they also had Virtual Console on the Wii, but on the Wii U, the Virtual Console did include some GBA games and such, you know, because the Wii U was kind of like a portable deal, almost like the Switch, right?
Speaker 0: And one of the games they released on the Wii U Virtual Console was Mario Advance 4, which is just a re-release of Mario 3 with different graphics, basically, but not quite the same as Mario All-Stars.
Speaker 0: And it's like, well, why do you care about a re-release of Mario 3?
Speaker 0: You could just play Mario 3, and Mario 3 NES version is already in the Switch Online emulator.
Speaker 0: It's because I didn't know until like a couple days ago that Mario Advance 4 Remake of Mario 3 for the GBA had an e-reader feature in which there were many, many levels, like a whole bunch of levels that you could only get if you had an e-reader and you had the cards, and a lot of those cards were Japan only.
Speaker 0: So, there's a whole bunch of Mario levels that I never knew existed that are official from Nintendo levels.
Speaker 1: I learned about this looking at that conversation.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the only way to play them until recently was to get a GBA, an e-reader, and those cards or replicas of those cards.
Speaker 0: When they released the game for the Virtual Console on the Wii U, which nobody had, they included all of those levels, all of them, even the ultra-rare Cocobean ones.
Speaker 0: And in the release on the Switch, I confirmed it, I played them myself, the levels are there.
Speaker 0: So, if you want to play these Mario levels that have basically been inaccessible to most people, right, in the US especially, open up Mario Advance 4 Remake of Mario 3 in the GBA emulator on Nintendo Online on your Switch.
Speaker 0: And when you go to make a new game, it's going to be like File 1, File 2, File 3, and there's going to be another option that says something else, like something else levels.
Speaker 0: And you click on that, and it'll take you to a different Mario, yeah, card level or something, I don't know, level card maybe.
Speaker 0: It takes you to another overworld map.
Speaker 0: that's not the normal one, where you can choose between Mario and Luigi and pick any of these e-reader levels and just play them.
Speaker 0: So, I plan to play all of those levels.
Speaker 1: Last thing I'll point out, of all the games in there, if you are younger than us, you may have never encountered or thought about the Super Mario Land games, but Super Mario Land 2 is like a top-tier Game Boy Mario that is overlooked by a lot of people.
Speaker 1: It is not a full Wario game, but it is the first step toward Wario-like games, and Wario makes his appearance there.
Speaker 0: It's interesting that they put out Wario 3, but not Wario 2.
Speaker 0: They gotta be coming out with Wario 2 and 4 soon, you gotta imagine that, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, Wario games!
Speaker 0: They also have Mario Super Circuit, but Mario Kart Super Circuit is the best, in my opinion, the best Mario Kart because there is no luck in that one.
Speaker 0: If you drive perfectly and drift around every corner and never touch the dirt and never bump into a wall and never get in the water or the mud or mess up in any way and drive perfectly, the blue shell or the red shell in that game will follow you right on your ass, but will not touch you until you decelerate or tap the brake.
Speaker 0: So it's a perfect skill game, if you can run every course perfectly, you will never get shelled in that game.
Speaker 0: And so I like that Mario Kart the best, I was really good at it.
Speaker 0: And if you haven't played Mario & Luigi Superstar Saga, that's an all-time great RPG on there.
Speaker 0: that's like a JRPG that you can actually play without lots of random encounters.
Speaker 0: And Game Boy Tetris on there, which is I guess empirically not as good as other Tetrises, but Game Boy Tetris, it hits different, right?
Speaker 0: You gotta play the Game Boy Tetris.
Speaker 1: That was terrifyingly revolutionary when it was first available, and it's easy to forget that.
Speaker 0: That Tetris movie they're coming out with apparently is like a ridiculous dramatization of what it took to bring Tetris out of the Soviet Union.
Speaker 1: I just can't imagine that as a hundred minutes of content.
Speaker 0: And I just saw in the trailer there was a scene where like in a jokey top secret lab and it's like, we're gonna show you something no one's allowed to see.
Speaker 0: This is the Game Boy.
Speaker 0: It's like, okay.
Speaker 1: So in some other Nintendo news, in a headline I never thought I would say ever in my life, Microsoft signs a 10-year contract to bring Xbox games to Nintendo consoles.
Speaker 1: Let that sink in a little bit.
Speaker 0: So the real deal here, and this is such a transparent move.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, I think we're- I saw this, when I first saw this I thought it was a fake, and then I saw it was real, and I realized that I had the exact same initial reaction you did.
Speaker 0: Every single news outlet has the same reaction.
Speaker 0: It's like this is the most obvious move.
Speaker 0: It's like you couldn't be more, it's like playing with an open hand in poker, right?
Speaker 0: So there is currently a lawsuit going down to block Activision, Blizzard, and Microsoft from all merging together into some- And Activision, Blizzard stock.
Speaker 0: I suppose I probably own everything indirectly through total stock market ETFs.
Speaker 1: Oh, I own it directly.
Speaker 0: Index funds.
Speaker 1: Actually, I also own a bunch of Nintendo, so yeah.
Speaker 1: Nothing I say is advice.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the FTC said that it would attempt to block this deal if it were to happen, right?
Speaker 0: So in order to look non-competitive, what they're gonna do is they're gonna be like, "Alright, well look, we'll get Call of
Speaker 0: Duty.".
Speaker 0: They promised they would have Call of Duty on PlayStation for some amount of time, and everyone's like, "Yeah, as soon as that deal expires, they're gonna cut it off," right?
Speaker 0: So Call of Duty would become Xbox only.
Speaker 0: So now they made another deal with Nintendo.
Speaker 0: that's like a binding 10-year deal.
Speaker 0: that's like guaranteed Call of Duty on Switch for 10 years, right?
Speaker 0: To basically say, "Look, look, we're not gonna be a monopoly anti-competitive using our very popular Call of Duty game to strong arm the whole game industry and force Xbox to become popular," right?
Speaker 0: "We're gonna keep the Call of Duty cross-platform.
Speaker 0: We proved it with this 10-year
Speaker 0: deal.".
Speaker 0: And it's like, "Dude, it's just an obvious long play to get the deal done, to keep the FTC away,".
Speaker 0: and then 10 years from now, shut down Sony and Nintendo and be like, "All you Call of Duty people gotta get Xboxes," right?
Speaker 1: And it just become Windows gaming, and the hardware doesn't matter anymore, but it's hard to speculate in that space, partly because no one's buying computers anymore.
Speaker 0: That's what Microsoft wanted to do with the first Xbox, and they never succeeded, and then they gave up on it.
Speaker 1: And now nobody, only turbo nerds even build gaming PCs anymore, so this might be good for Call of Duty long-term anyway, and even drive adoption, similarly to how Fortnite being on everything just gets more people playing Fortnite.
Speaker 0: So basically this whole article is like, "Here's all the countries that are trying to block it,".
Speaker 0: and at the bottom it's like, "Here's the countries that have approved
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 0: Chile, Brazil, Saudi Arabia, Serbia.
Speaker 1: The end of the list.
Speaker 1: That is some great company to be in right there.
Speaker 1: It's like when you see, "Who still uses the imperial system instead of metric for
Speaker 1: everything?".
Speaker 1: It's like, "Oh, the US, Libya...".
Speaker 0: The bad countries.
Speaker 0: All right, one last tiny news.
Speaker 1: Yeah, one little thing.
Speaker 0: So Magic the Gathering, a game I played for less than three years of my life, but it's left a major impact on myself and the gaming world, and we've talked about nonstop.
Speaker 0: They are coming out with some Lord of the Rings themed magic sets.
Speaker 0: It's a Middle Earth MTG.
Speaker 0: It's like, "You know what?
Speaker 0: That is a great move,".
Speaker 0: because even someone like me who would not collect magic cards, who would not get back into magic, who would not write for all the reasons, the gambling reasons, the collecting reasons, I could see that and be like, "You know, that magic set...".
Speaker 0: It's like you could do this with any old magic set.
Speaker 0: Just be like, "Just get together with your friends and be like, 'You know what?
Speaker 0: What's the new magic
Speaker 0: set?'"
Speaker 0: Some kind of... I don't know.
Speaker 1: Like, "Hey, that throws..." That's column.
Speaker 1: Like, whatever.
Speaker 0: No, not that, but you could just pick a magic set and be like, "Friends, let's play only that magic set, and that way we won't get sucked into the magic world," right?
Speaker 0: But when you make it with a different theme that's not in the theme and the setting of the rest of Magic the Gathering, it makes that some, you know, especially a setting you like or know about or care about or identify with, that makes that option even more appealing.
Speaker 0: Like, "Hey, friends, I know none of us play magic or like magic or want to do collecting or gambling on cards, but we could get these Lord of the Rings magic cards and play just those amongst
Speaker 0: us.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, we all agree.
Speaker 1: Nobody gets sweaty.
Speaker 1: No one uses a card outside of this set, and anyone who spends too much money buying, like, further Lord of the Rings expansions gets kicked out of our friends' circle forever.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You could just... You could even... Probably what you would do is just buy the box of boosters and draft a few times, right?
Speaker 0: And then maybe play some more with all the cards once all the packs are open, and that's it, right?
Speaker 0: Or you could recombine the cards to make a drafting cube after everyone got familiar with the cards from the regular draft.
Speaker 0: Anyway, that seems like a good option, but it turns out that because the demand is so high, the pre-order price for a 36-pack draft box is now close to $400.
Speaker 0: So, no.
Speaker 0: That will not be happening.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So, the other reason this is important, I think, is rather than making a separate Lord of the Rings game to try to capture that lucrative "nerds who like games who also like Lord of the Rings but don't already play magic" demographic... Just... It's magic.
Speaker 1: Like, you already got a stable of game designers.
Speaker 1: Like, you have a whole pipeline to crank these things out.
Speaker 1: I think this is going to bring a bunch of people to the table, literally, who only care about Lord of the Rings and barely even know this is magic.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: They had Transformers magic cards, and I don't know how well those did or anything.
Speaker 0: I feel like the Transformers... They definitely have decided to go all in with the intellectual... Because it used to be that, like, you know, the intellectual property was magic itself.
Speaker 0: And then any other intellectual property was a different game or a different company entirely, right?
Speaker 0: And now, it seems like finally, after 20, 30 years of magic, there's been a cave-in where it's like everything except Pokémon, basically, is going to be like, "Fine.
Speaker 0: Fuck it.
Speaker 0: We'll just put all the intellectual properties on magic
Speaker 0: cards.".
Speaker 0: Magic will be the only CCG and we'll just be like, "Alright,
Speaker 0: fine.".
Speaker 0: And now people are going to show up to play Magic the Gathering and they're going to be like, "Fucking, you know, I put down a forest and I summon Optimus Prime and Gollum and Rainbow Dash and fucking Mr.
Speaker 0: Monopoly and
Speaker 0: Gundam.".
Speaker 0: Not a Gundam, probably, but, you know, whatever intellectual properties...
Speaker 1: Any IP that's not owned by a Japanese company that's trying to make its own much less lucrative deals in similar card games.
Speaker 0: Basically, anything that's not Disney and anything that's not, you know, some Japanese CCG already, right?
Speaker 0: A GI Joe, a Ghostbusters, a Ninja Turtle, a Street Fighter, all that kind of stuff is going to be some... I mean, the only thing so far that I know about are the Transformers and the Lord of the Rings, but you have to imagine everything else that can is going to end up on a magic card.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: I feel like this is going to be very lucrative, especially based on that initial demand.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think so too.
Speaker 1: I'll leave out that Wall Street thing for another time.
Speaker 0: I wonder how long it can be lucrative for, especially if they add this to the MTG online.
Speaker 1: I thought magic was going to die after they released Fallen Empires because it felt like they were making expansions too quickly, and they were diluting the card pool, and tournaments were getting weird, and... Yeah!
Speaker 1: Middle School Rim was the wrongest he could have possibly been about how good magic was doing.
Speaker 0: Like... Yup.
Speaker 1: But anyway, things of the day!
Speaker 1: So, Paisanos, you might have watched the terrible Super Mario Bros.
Speaker 1: Super Show, the cartoon and the live action.
Speaker 1: Not going to mince words, like...
Speaker 0: There were some positive aspects.
Speaker 1: There were positive aspects, and as a kid, I watched every single episode, like, religiously.
Speaker 1: I made my parents, like, record it.
Speaker 1: Because it was on while we were at school, and we'd get home, and we'd rewind and watch that tape.
Speaker 1: Uh oh.
Speaker 1: We went to school the first day it premiered.
Speaker 1: We got home from school, and we were going absolutely apeshit.
Speaker 1: And when we get home, our dad, who had recorded it for us, is just like, "Kids, I got real bad news.
Speaker 1: I don't know how to break this to
Speaker 1: you.".
Speaker 1: And we're like, "Oh no, did you not record
Speaker 1: it?".
Speaker 1: He's like, "No, no, I recorded it.
Speaker 1: It's real bad.
Speaker 1: Like, it is so much worse than I expected that I just wanted to warn
Speaker 1: you.".
Speaker 1: And then, you know, us being, you know, stupid kids with KidBrain, we watched it, and we thought it was great.
Speaker 1: It was the best fucking thing I'd ever seen since Vampire Hunter D, so...
Speaker 0: KidBrain works... There were definitely some things... There were definitely some things that my parents thought were, like, you know, not good, right?
Speaker 1: Oh, he just thought it was badly done.
Speaker 1: Like, it was lazy and derivative, and the voice acting was bad.
Speaker 1: My dad had opinions.
Speaker 0: But there were, yeah, my parents also, they had opinions.
Speaker 0: They were like, "Oh, that cartoon is no good.
Speaker 0: That cartoon is, you know, is
Speaker 0: funny.".
Speaker 0: Whatever, right?
Speaker 0: And then there were other ones that they actually liked, and nowadays I see that, like, oh, you know, my dad, when I was a kid, and I thought every cartoon on TV was the best, right?
Speaker 0: My dad singled out, like, Rocko's Modern Life as actually being watchable.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: I remember my dad singled out, of all that anime I was watching, he was like, "Tenchi Muyo is way better than that Sailor Whatever you were watching
Speaker 1: before.".
Speaker 1: And my mom was deep into Ultraminer anime.
Speaker 0: And it's like, nowadays, I realize, it's like, yeah, they had the correct taste, right?
Speaker 0: So that was better than the other cartoons.
Speaker 0: I mean, KidBrain just...
Speaker 1: KidBrain has a serotonin hole, and you just cram stuff into that hole.
Speaker 1: Doesn't matter what it is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway, so what's your actual thing of the day?
Speaker 1: The day is a YouTube video I bumped into.
Speaker 1: that is the entirety of the first season of this show, both the live-action and the animated segments, including the Zelda segments, from 1989, in one long nine-hour video, just back-to-back with no commercials.
Speaker 1: It's like those Daykiller tapes of The Simpsons we used to watch at RIT.
Speaker 0: I remember this thing just being easily available on DVD, though.
Speaker 1: It is, I have... It's not hard to get.
Speaker 1: Hey, you want some DVDs?
Speaker 1: I got 'em.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: But this is, like, full quality on YouTube.
Speaker 1: Like, honestly, it looks better than the DVDs I've got.
Speaker 1: And if you wanted to see what I put into that serotonin hole in my brain when I was young and stupid, here's nine hours of it just mainlined, ready to go.
Speaker 0: Alright, so here's a thing of the day that crosses over between the technology, the gaming, and also the anime worlds, right?
Speaker 0: So in the anime world, there's a thing known as the Itano Circus.
Speaker 0: We've talked about it before.
Speaker 0: There's an animator, Ichiro Itano.
Speaker 0: He worked on things such as Macross.
Speaker 0: And whenever you watch an anime and you see some mech shoot missiles, and the missiles fly all over the place like a frickin' wasp hive, and then all explode, some of them hitting the target, some of them not, right?
Speaker 0: That's called an Itano Circus, right?
Speaker 0: Named after the person who animated that.
Speaker 0: This person just calls it Anime Homing Missiles, but they know who Ichiro Itano is because they have a link right here with his name on the caption of the image.
Speaker 0: And what they developed is a very small, with a very small amount of computer programming, all their code is here, they're showing you the math of if you were to develop a video game and you wanted to have missiles like that in your game that are rendered in real time, they have figured all that out for you in advance, and they have a cute little obvious Macross-ish demo game, you know, low poly count situation here.
Speaker 1: Shoot the Dippin' Dots on the beige thing with missiles.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And it's like, oh, there's the math of how to make that animation and how to make that work in a video game in a really nice way.
Speaker 0: If you're out there making, you know, a little video game and you want to include this effect, here's how to do it.
Speaker 0: And without having to, you know, do it the way Itano did it, where he animated each frame by hand, drawing on cells, you can just have a computer draw it for you.
Speaker 1: Good stuff.
Speaker 1: In the meta moment, the Geek Nights Book Club book was Leaf the Unseen.
Speaker 1: We read it, the episode is out.
Speaker 1: The upcoming current Geek Nights Book Club book, which I have purchased, but I have not started reading yet, is Simon Rushdie's The Satanic Verses.
Speaker 1: Deeply relevant to pretty much everything that's been going on in the world for the past...ever.
Speaker 1: So...
Speaker 0: Several decades?
Speaker 1: At least.
Speaker 1: It was either this or Foucault's Pendulum.
Speaker 1: I gave those two choices.
Speaker 1: Scott chose The Satanic Verses.
Speaker 1: I would have been happy with either.
Speaker 0: I still don't know how to pronounce...you say Foucault?
Speaker 1: I don't know how to pronounce that properly.
Speaker 1: It's Foucault.
Speaker 0: Are you sure it's Foucault?
Speaker 1: Are you sure?
Speaker 1: I am 100% sure.
Speaker 0: What percent sure are you that it's Foucault?
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: You could be right because I have no idea.
Speaker 1: C'est français!
Speaker 1: Also, Geek Nights will be live on Thursday, March 23rd at 2.30 PM Eastern Time in the Bumblebee Theater at PAX East with a panel that is brand new to anyone who didn't go to one magfest and go to one room at one particular time where we did an early trial version of this panel and never did it again anywhere and never uploaded it to YouTube.
Speaker 1: Partly because we didn't record it fully.
Speaker 1: I just recorded the slides and the audio just to workshop.
Speaker 0: Well, since we don't have a bunch of friends going to PAX East, I'm going to bring all kinds of video equipment there and we'll probably spend most of our time doing that instead of playing board games.
Speaker 1: We'll be there Thursday and Friday and not Saturday and Sunday.
Speaker 1: We're not enforcing.
Speaker 1: We're just going to be there doing this panel.
Speaker 0: Well, the listener in the chat has informed me that on the magfest channel, the magfest YouTube channel, you might be able to find it.
Speaker 1: Oh, I will find that later and post a link to it.
Speaker 1: That's nice.
Speaker 0: In a last meta moment, I have made significant progress on the Geek Nights website.
Speaker 0: We are now in the process of linking the few remaining episodes to the forum threads that go with those episodes.
Speaker 0: If I was not able to do it automatically and if those episodes actually still have forum threads because a lot of the old ones just don't have a forum thread to go with them.
Speaker 0: So once we fill out those numbers in the spreadsheet, then the data transferring ETL part will be basically complete.
Speaker 0: And then we can move on to just getting basically some remaining features just so that we have feature parity with the current website.
Speaker 0: And then we just got to get the front end polished up and finished.
Speaker 0: I don't know if the person I was working with will come back or not.
Speaker 0: We might have to get some help from someone else.
Speaker 0: We don't know.
Speaker 0: And then we can launch the new website and then we can work on adding new features that don't exist on the current website to the new website.
Speaker 0: Possibly just evolving it as a continuing process.
Speaker 1: Yeah, things like transcripts because Adobe Podcast might help us with that.
Speaker 1: There's going to be a lot coming out.
Speaker 0: Well, the existing website does have an unused transcript feature.
Speaker 1: It was used for a brief time.
Speaker 1: I paid for a few transcripts at one point.
Speaker 0: I should also mention that if you already follow us on Twitter, you've probably seen this.
Speaker 0: But because of the changes at the tweet company, we are no longer and never will again automatically pose, at least unless there are big changes.
Speaker 0: There could always be some sort of delicious revival of Twitter where it fails and then someone buys it.
Speaker 1: I did not delete my Twitter account.
Speaker 1: I just went private with it.
Speaker 0: No, no, no.
Speaker 0: But the point is, for the foreseeable future, we will no longer automatically be tweeting links to new episodes when they come out.
Speaker 0: And I'm not going to do that manually either because that's a fucking pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: So if you want to find out when there are new Geek Nights episodes, you must find another avenue.
Speaker 0: RSS, I would suggest, is the best one.
Speaker 1: Maybe someday we'll like post to a mess.
Speaker 0: We'll always be the best one.
Speaker 1: Or something like posting a bunch of places.
Speaker 0: When we get to the phase of adding new features to it, there will be many features like that, definitely, that is on the board.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Who knows?
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll run a Mastodon instance for the Geek Nights listener to use.
Speaker 1: But that's on me and I'm going to say it right now, the odds of that...
Speaker 0: That's on you personally.
Speaker 1: The odds of that, one, it would be on me personally and two, the odds of that, while not zero, are not super high.
Speaker 1: I am running my own Mastodon instance for me.
Speaker 1: It works, but I do not envision caring enough to administer it for anyone other than me.
Speaker 0: I have plans of running something else.
Speaker 0: Anyway, let's talk about the gaming furniture that is not gaming chairs.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: So way back, and I got a lot to say about this topic because there's a lot of different kinds of gaming furnitures.
Speaker 1: Some of which you all, the listener, might not be thinking about.
Speaker 1: But I remember we went to the first PAX that we'd ever been to in '08 and we saw, was it at that PAX or the next one?
Speaker 1: One of those two PAXes.
Speaker 0: It was either '08 or '09, I don't remember which one.
Speaker 0: It was one of the two.
Speaker 1: Back then, they let special guests, which we were, they gave us a perk that they just kind of got rid of like about eight years ago.
Speaker 1: And that perk was, they would let us into the expo hall on one of the days of PAX an hour before the sweaty masses were let in so we could just walk around and talk to everyone and see everything.
Speaker 0: And we availed ourselves of that.
Speaker 0: Nowadays, the only people who get into the expo hall early for the past many years, right, like decade plus since they changed that policy, are obviously exhibitors who need to go in there.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: The enforcers who actually work in there and need to be in there.
Speaker 1: Yup, and only while they need to be in there.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: The all-access people, because they have all access, the building staff, and the media get in.
Speaker 0: The people with real media badges get a very brief window, right, I believe.
Speaker 1: Which, I guess if we wanted to, we could get in addition to our regular, like they've offered that before, we weren't really doing a lot of coverage, so I didn't get it.
Speaker 0: We could talk about the much controversy of media people getting special privileges after that time period has closed, but that's up to individual booths and that's not a PAX policy.
Speaker 1: So we're walking around in there, and we saw something that, at least at the time, that we had never seen before in our lives.
Speaker 1: Late 2000s, Rem and Scott brains immediately coveted, just because it felt like it would solve a lot of problems in our lives, and it just felt like a really cool thing.
Speaker 1: They were dedicated gaming tables that were designed for the exact kind of nerd like us who wants to play a war game, or play a board game that takes a week, or play D&D with all the features that you might think would be cool to facilitate that.
Speaker 1: But also, you can put the top back on it, and it's a regular-ass dining room table for the rest of your life when you're not playing games.
Speaker 0: Yep, the main features of the gaming table would be the cup holders so you don't spill on your game, right?
Speaker 0: Dice pits built in.
Speaker 0: Little hidden, shielded areas so you can hide hidden information for games that require it.
Speaker 1: A giant pit that you can just put a whole game in?
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yep, some sort of surface that you can either whiteboard on, or cover with a piece of plastic, and then whiteboard on that, or a felt surface, like a casino table, or, right?
Speaker 0: And then in a pit, so that you can play the game, pause it, put the table on, the leaves on top, you know, eat dinner, take 'em off and play again.
Speaker 0: You know, all these sorts of things that, on paper, and if you're a nerd and you see those things, you're just like, "Aw yeah, that's the greatest thing I've ever seen, I want that, I need that, why did we just have a boring table?
Speaker 0: that's just a flat piece of
Speaker 0: wood?".
Speaker 1: Yep, especially when we still lived, like, in a house, not in a city apartment, and we lived together, and we just had imaginings of, "Hey, our D&D games would be so much easier to run if we had
Speaker 1: this.".
Speaker 1: Or, "We would play Ogre, or BattleTech, at all, 'cause it wouldn't ruin the table for a
Speaker 1: week.".
Speaker 1: And of course we never got one.
Speaker 0: Now, it is possible that, yeah, I mean, it is possible that there is someone out there who, for whom the gaming table is not merely aspirational, and when I talk about aspirational, I don't mean obtaining the table as aspirational, plenty of people have these tables.
Speaker 0: It's using the table as it was, you know, imagined, right?
Speaker 0: Who out there as a gaming table and is actually has a constant war game going on inside of it, right?
Speaker 0: I imagine, you know, I don't have numbers on this, but I'm guessing a very small percentage of people who have gaming tables actually have a game hidden in there going on, right?
Speaker 0: At any amount of the time, right?
Speaker 0: Who actually is, like, how much is the cup holder really improving?
Speaker 0: your experience, you know, and you're, you know, versus just having a normal, you know, how much is the hidden thing?
Speaker 1: Especially if 90% of people who buy these tables are just playing D&D anyway, what have you got to hide?
Speaker 1: A character sheet!
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like, how many people are actually, you know, hiding the GM stuff in a special area and it's that much better and cooler than if they just had a GM screen?
Speaker 1: Or what most game masters I know have these days, just a laptop that they're sitting in front of.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, the added expense of the gaming table, right, is it really worth it?
Speaker 0: I, in my opinion, no.
Speaker 1: I would say the concept would be worth it if you live that lifestyle and you're not lying about living that lifestyle.
Speaker 1: You are actually living that lifestyle.
Speaker 1: Like, you set up a war game.
Speaker 0: I think it's also very good for a gaming store to have, right?
Speaker 0: If you have a gaming store, many people will be playing D&D and what other games on the table daily, nightly, several times a day, right?
Speaker 0: And that, you know, can make your store a place more appealing for people to come play rather than at home.
Speaker 0: And there's a lot of value in that.
Speaker 0: If I had a gaming store, I would have all gaming tables, right?
Speaker 0: All over the place.
Speaker 0: Just, you know, I would probably get custom special ones to fit my store perfectly.
Speaker 0: But for a person at home, unless you're wealthy or whatever, it's like, really?
Speaker 0: Or playing that many games for real?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Of course, the problem is, and I'm going to studiously avoid saying the name of any specific company because there's a bunch of them and I don't want to get into that.
Speaker 1: There's even some news about one of them.
Speaker 0: For some reason, gaming table companies are rife with drama and we don't want to mention any of them.
Speaker 1: I think I know why.
Speaker 1: The market for these, for people who actually will buy them, is pretty small and that market is heavily segmented into people who have extremely specific wants, needs and desires.
Speaker 1: There is no way to have a sustainable industry of mass producing these.
Speaker 1: So they tend to be built either low rent and ad hoc and on demand, or they tend to be low build quality, or they tend to be as expensive as actual, for real, fancy furniture like the $10,000 table you get at the fancy furniture store.
Speaker 1: So that really makes it hard to have companies that are healthy and sustainable in this space.
Speaker 1: A lot of them relied on crowdfunding, a lot of them came up after these were a thing, and then people weren't happy with them, and then a bunch of them collapsed.
Speaker 1: There's been a big repeating boom and bust cycle of crowdfunding.
Speaker 0: A lot of companies have had slow deliveries because they can't churn them out that quickly.
Speaker 1: Or they deliver tables that suck and then they go out of business and you've got a bunch of nerds who have tables that break and can't be repaired because they were made with substandard products.
Speaker 0: Also, in my opinion, a lot of the tables are aesthetically...
Speaker 1: Ugly as shit or not put together very well.
Speaker 0: I have seen some good and nice ones that are quality built, but it's rare.
Speaker 0: A lot of them are just, you're better off just spending your money on a, go to a furniture store or a woodworker, a furniture maker, and spend that money on a normal table.
Speaker 0: that's just a big flat piece of wood, but is an amazing, big piece of wood.
Speaker 0: A really nice, normal table, and I think that will be a better experience than a fancy gaming table.
Speaker 1: There's a dichotomy.
Speaker 1: Half the people who imagine buying these things, imagine they have a place where they can only, they only have enough space to have one table, so they want a table that can do both things.
Speaker 1: Same reason people get a pool table.
Speaker 1: that's also a ping pong table.
Speaker 0: But a normal, you can play a game on a normal table just fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they're imagining that they will keep a game going.
Speaker 0: A normal table does both things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like they'll keep a game going under that little thing.
Speaker 0: You probably won't.
Speaker 0: And the other thing is that, you know, if you were to spend the gaming table money on a normal table, if you have, you know, we're assuming you have enough space, right?
Speaker 0: You can probably get a bigger table.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: The problem I have when playing games is often not that the table doesn't have a pit built in, but that the table isn't big enough for the giant game of Eclipse.
Speaker 0: So I would rather have a bigger, nicer normal table than, assuming I had the space for it, than a fancier, smaller gaming table.
Speaker 1: Remember the MagFest where we set up an auxiliary table that had all the science stuff and like all the auxiliary boards from that game of Eclipse that we were playing?
Speaker 1: We had two separate tables that we were walking around.
Speaker 1: But the other demographic, people who are making, who have enough space to make a dedicated gaming room, and I bring this up because it's a segue into other kinds of gaming furniture.
Speaker 1: A dedicated gaming room, you probably don't need a table like this either because it's the gaming room.
Speaker 1: The wargame, if it gets set up and stays up, can just stay set up.
Speaker 1: You're probably better off buying, if you want a pit, just buy like a giant casino pit from a company that sells that to casinos.
Speaker 1: That'll be way higher quality.
Speaker 0: Just get an actual crap stable and just play your game.
Speaker 1: And just play board games on it.
Speaker 1: That would actually, that would be pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Throw your dice in there.
Speaker 0: Bam!
Speaker 0: Also hire a dealer with a crop who can grab the dice for you and pull it back over.
Speaker 1: I want to cover, I want to talk about together, kinds of gaming furniture and furniture adjacent things that really only make sense in a dedicated gaming room.
Speaker 1: Like the whiteboard on the wall, just for gaming.
Speaker 1: The pull-down screen for projecting your stuff.
Speaker 1: The TV mounted on the wall that's dedicated to gaming.
Speaker 0: There is a lot of office, there is a lot of office stuff that is good for gaming as well, right?
Speaker 0: You know, a projector on the ceiling aimed straight down onto the table surface.
Speaker 1: Mount a table, mount just a big flat table on the ceiling like a ship's table and have a winch and a button that'll lower it down when you're playing a game.
Speaker 1: Like if you're making a custom gaming space, my advice to you is you'll probably be better served by customizing that space among things you can buy at normal stores rather than buying gamer focused specific shit.
Speaker 1: Like buying things aimed at an office.
Speaker 0: Just having a tiny, just a tiny crappy display up somewhere.
Speaker 0: It's like that's a scoreboard, that's a timer everyone can see, right?
Speaker 0: That's a place to look at for the tournament bracket.
Speaker 0: It's like that's a really, you know, that can really enhance a gaming day a lot more than, you know, a table that's different.
Speaker 1: Like, you know, like a Rumpus room that has the dartboard and the pool table and it has like the chalkboard kind of thing that's generically designed to be the scoreboard?
Speaker 1: Just make something like that but bigger?
Speaker 1: Holy crap, will that change your life more than a like $8,000 poorly built gaming table?
Speaker 1: The seating furniture is interesting because for tabletop games, they just have to be the right height and be comfortable.
Speaker 1: Like don't buy, never buy a chair that's aimed at gamers.
Speaker 1: They're almost always a ripoff just across the board.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's why we're not talking about chairs in this episode.
Speaker 0: But yeah, if you're going for the long game sessions, right, you might want to opt for more comfier chairs.
Speaker 0: But if it's a shorter one, it's like, you know, you got folding chairs at a convention and like they're not a problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or if they are a problem, I have my premium butt pad that I have brought to PAX before and I've sat on in tabletop on the folding chair and it was great.
Speaker 0: Right, but I'm saying it's like, you know, no one's ever been like, oh man, I can't play games all day.
Speaker 0: I mean, maybe someone has, but it's like the chair is not, you know, you go to a convention, it's like they got folding chairs and folding tables and it's no problem, right?
Speaker 0: What's more important is that like, you know, if you got a table, right, and let's say it's not a gaming table, a tablecloth.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: Way cheaper, way cheaper than a table, right?
Speaker 0: And it enhances, right, you get a nice, you know, some kind of velvety one or a felt one or something, right?
Speaker 0: It's like that, a tablecloth helps a lot.
Speaker 0: Do not underestimate.
Speaker 0: Especially, you know, things not sliding around.
Speaker 1: And like it even helps see the board better.
Speaker 1: It makes the lighting feel better.
Speaker 1: They're cheap and this sounds like old person advice, but like even if you're at like a PAX or something, bring your own tablecloth with you.
Speaker 1: They're not big and it'll make it easier for your friends to find you and it'll feel so much better to play.
Speaker 0: Now there is a kind of chair.
Speaker 0: Black is the best color for the tablecloth.
Speaker 1: Yeah, absolutely.
Speaker 1: If you're talking about video games, like you got a video game room, video game stuff, we're not talking about gamer chairs, but there is sort of a class of chair that actually is really good for gaming.
Speaker 1: Back in the day, we wanted these, but they were hard to get.
Speaker 1: They sold them at Walmart only.
Speaker 1: They called them a video rocker.
Speaker 1: There were a bunch of clones that came out later.
Speaker 1: They were aimed at little kids and they're basically like this little tiny rocking chair with no legs that would just sit on the floor.
Speaker 1: And they were like weirdly perfect to play console games in a small room on the floor comfortably with your friends while they're like sitting on the couch.
Speaker 1: And like, they're great.
Speaker 1: Like the floor pillows, things like that can really expand how many people you can get sitting around playing a game.
Speaker 1: Don't underestimate that kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: I think, right.
Speaker 0: Well, I think that those things mattered more for, you know, when you have more friends, like most people can only afford like a couch, right?
Speaker 0: Or maybe an L-shaped one, right?
Speaker 0: But it's not going to, unless you're like in a big old mega McMansion at least with a giant room, you're not going to have enough couch seating for if you have enough people over, right?
Speaker 0: So the floor pillows, the video rockers, those can give you additional seating that's more comfortable than just the floor at a low price point that you can then hide away when there isn't a big party of people coming over.
Speaker 0: It can also help you if you don't have a bunch of money and you don't have a couch at all, right?
Speaker 0: And you just want to not sit on your floor.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That's also a good option.
Speaker 0: But I think the video rockers biggest utility was actually in the older days, like, you know, 10, 20 years ago when controllers were still wired and TVs were still smaller.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'd often have closer to.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You wouldn't want to put your couch that close unless you had a really small living room.
Speaker 0: And so therefore you would get a different seating arrangement that you could use when you get close.
Speaker 1: When I was playing the Game of Q back in that day, I would sit on the video rocker right in front of the TV.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't sit on the couch.
Speaker 1: that was further back.
Speaker 1: Our friend who was just watching would sit on the couch.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: Nowadays, all the controllers are wireless and all the TVs are giant LCDs, even the cheaper ones.
Speaker 0: It's like you can sit on your couch and you don't need some different furniture to get closer.
Speaker 0: It really is.
Speaker 0: But it still has that good purpose of when a whole bunch of people come over.
Speaker 1: Yeah, especially because when they're on the floor, one, they're small, like easier to hide away.
Speaker 1: But two, on the floor gives you sort of stadium seating.
Speaker 1: More people can see the screen and interact with stuff.
Speaker 1: Like you got 12 people trying to play Jackbox together in a living room.
Speaker 1: That's going to save your butt, those video rockers and literally save your butt and those floor pillows.
Speaker 0: Yep, exactly.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I think something else I want to talk about is, you know, your coffee table, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, what, you just got a normal old coffee table.
Speaker 0: What's the big deal, right?
Speaker 0: The coffee table I have, right, is half coffee table, half footrest.
Speaker 0: It's like the right side of it is a cushion instead of a table because you don't need that much table space on the coffee table.
Speaker 0: It's like you're not doing, you know, you're just putting a drink on it or whatever, maybe.
Speaker 0: It's like you don't, doesn't need, so it's like you're going to put your feet on it more often than not.
Speaker 0: Why not have a squishy part instead of just putting your feet up on the wood?
Speaker 0: Then you don't need an ottoman.
Speaker 0: But the thing is that if you, the way mine's constructed is this actually storage inside.
Speaker 0: If you lift up the cushion, there's a whole compartment in there and there's another compartment on the left.
Speaker 0: And it's like, I store all the controllers and all the weird stuff.
Speaker 0: Like I got a Wii steering wheel and I got a fight stick and I got any S controller.
Speaker 0: I got all kinds of controllers and all sorts of video game accessories, all hidden inside the coffee table.
Speaker 0: Where you can't see them unless you need them.
Speaker 0: And then there they are.
Speaker 1: Now, you could similarly put this stuff in the entertainment center that you probably have your TV on.
Speaker 0: But then you got to get your ass up to go get it.
Speaker 1: But also increasingly as it's cheaper and easier to mount thinner and lighter fancy TVs on walls.
Speaker 1: A lot of people issue the entertainment center.
Speaker 1: Like you don't necessarily need that taken up space anymore.
Speaker 1: The coffee table is where you store all the stuff that used to be on your entertainment center.
Speaker 1: And whatever you're plugging into that TV, hide that somewhere else with cables in your wall.
Speaker 1: Like it's not that hard to do.
Speaker 0: Yup, I mean I've got, you know, I still have, it's not really an entertainment center so much.
Speaker 0: It's just a long sort of end table with like a compartment.
Speaker 0: I don't know what you would call it.
Speaker 1: I mean I guess it's serving the function of an entertainment center.
Speaker 0: Right, but it's not one of those ones you think of where it's got like big tall shit on the sides.
Speaker 0: It's just a flat one level deal.
Speaker 0: And you know like the HDPC is on it, the switch is on it, right.
Speaker 0: And that, you know, there's a Lego Voltron on it.
Speaker 0: And then inside of it is just like storage for stuff that is not frequently accessed.
Speaker 0: Like old, you know, GameCube games and DVDs and tiny board games and whatever, right.
Speaker 0: It's like the controllers are in the coffee table so you don't have to get up to get the controller, right.
Speaker 0: It's like you sit down at the couch and you can do everything.
Speaker 0: If I put that stuff in the entertainment center I'd be walking back and forth all the time, right.
Speaker 0: It's a pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: And that's probably, I don't think we want to talk about shelving.
Speaker 0: Is there any other gaming?
Speaker 1: Shelving is sort of like an adjacent topic I think.
Speaker 0: I guess.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, people talk all about how you got to get the Cal-X to store your board games, right.
Speaker 0: But it's like I just have a normal Billy bookshelf.
Speaker 1: Mine are just on two shelves in the closet and I made a very simple rule.
Speaker 1: I will not own more board games than fit in that closet at any point.
Speaker 1: If a game, so now it's totally full.
Speaker 1: Most of my shelves have books.
Speaker 1: A game's going away.
Speaker 0: Yeah, most of my shelves have books, but I got one set of shelves that have some games.
Speaker 0: But part of that bookshelf isn't games.
Speaker 0: It's only like maybe three of the shelves on the bookcase are games.
Speaker 0: And it's like, yeah, unless it's a tiny game, in which case it can go in that entertainment center thingy and inside hidden away.
Speaker 0: If it's a big game, there's no room for any more big games.
Speaker 0: So if I get a new big game, one of the ones that's on there has to go.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: There's no...
Speaker 1: Now one thing I do do is in that kind of place, I'll often leave like more accessible either two player games, because you know, me and Emily live together.
Speaker 1: So two player game, we might just play out of nowhere, like randomly.
Speaker 1: Or we even see it and think, oh, yeah, you want to play Seven Wonders Duel?
Speaker 0: Alright, let's do it.
Speaker 1: But two, you can almost, if you're the kind of person like us and you have friends over a lot, especially as hopefully we're in the long decreasing tail of COVID and things slowly start to get better in that regard.
Speaker 1: We see people more often.
Speaker 1: You can almost leave out one or two games in that like coffee table storage to be quickly accessible, or almost like a coffee table book where someone might be like, hey, I see that ozzel sitting there.
Speaker 1: You want to just play it?
Speaker 1: Like the coffee table game being visible?
Speaker 1: As long as it's just one or two games, don't put a pile out there because they don't run into the same problem.
Speaker 1: That is a way to attract attention and get people to maybe want to play the game you want them to play, instead of having the argument of let's stand in front of the shelf of every game and everyone vetoes everything.
Speaker 1: And then everybody goes home after three hours without having played any game.
Speaker 1: And I think any other furniture we might push off to another show.
Speaker 1: I almost think we could do a show around how to store your fucking board games like unboxing.
Speaker 1: Like I'm actually not unboxing games anymore.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's already 10 billion videos about that.
Speaker 0: I feel like an audio podcast doesn't really add much to that.
Speaker 1: That would just be my opinion already and ill-advised advice.
Speaker 1: That's all I got.
Speaker 0: And also, I think you would get that advice might be better coming from someone who does have a shit ton of games and doesn't constantly get rid of them.
Speaker 1: Well, because my advice would be don't have that many games.
Speaker 0: If you have that many games, you should have a game storage room.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: Do you really need- In general, I think, you know, the- Do you really need what?
Speaker 1: Oh no, I've noticed using this new Discord there is more delay on your audio coming to me than with the other Discord.
Speaker 1: Because the bandwidth is lower, I think that's playing a factor here.
Speaker 1: Because we're interrupting each other a lot more.
Speaker 0: Oh, maybe because we didn't boost it.
Speaker 1: I'd already had a conversation with the listener in the YouTube channel which has more viewers now than the stage as people have moved over there because the audio quality is better.
Speaker 0: Oh, interesting.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess the advantage of the Discord stage is that one day, maybe, we'd let someone else talk.
Speaker 1: I might just take some Patreon money and buy enough boosts to fully maximize whatever we need to maximize on the Geeknight server.
Speaker 1: That feels like a good use of Patreon money.
Speaker 0: I think it only needs one level of boost.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I think I threw one boost there, but all my boosts that I have are going at our own private server.
Speaker 1: Because I use that one a lot.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I think the final word on the gaming furniture is that really the best gaming furniture is really good normal furniture.
Speaker 0: The specialized gaming furniture is rarely a good idea.
Speaker 0: A couch from a good company.
Speaker 0: Even for gamers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a couch that is well designed and a table that is well designed from actual furniture companies 90% of the time are just going to be better for the same number of dollars you spend than any gaming specific thing across the board in every domain.
Speaker 1: Anything marketed to gamers is usually a ripoff.
Speaker 1: Unless it's a game.
Speaker 1: And even then, most games are ripoffs, but that's a separate conversation.
Speaker 0: So I would avoid the gaming stuff unless you have the specialized use case, like I said, gaming stuff.
Speaker 0: But yeah.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: And the Patreon patrons for this particular episode of Geek Nights who are giving us $5 or more per month because that is the arbitrary line I set like eight years ago for whether or not we'll say your name.
Speaker 1: For tonight are... Al enjoys Link, E.G, Dread, Lily, Tenebrae, Case, Care, Makes, Music, Chris, Haddad, Clinton, Walton, Dex, Finn, Joel Hayes, Penny, Rymer, Rebecca, Dunn, Sam, Erickson, Shervin, Von, Horl.
Speaker 1: What if everything you ever wanted came in a rocket cap?
Speaker 1: Power thirst!
Speaker 0: Rocket edition!
Speaker 0: With all new flavors like banana, fizz bitch, and gun!
Speaker 1: You've had the worst, now try the thirst!
Speaker 1: Squencher!
Speaker 1: Power thirst!
Speaker 0: Side effects include glowing sweat.
Speaker 1: Use your sweaty body to fuel sweet tea parties.
Speaker 1: Power thirst!
Speaker 1: Anything is possible!
Speaker 1: Fear Blasting!
Speaker 1: The sport you'll invent because you'll be too energetic for normal sports.
Speaker 1: You'll feel like a fighter jet made of biceps!
Speaker 1: What about me and my blue collar?
Speaker 1: Juice Bracey!
Speaker 1: Turn that everyman into a beveryman!
Speaker 1: Bevery stands for beverage!