Speaker 0: It's Tuesday, September 12th, 2023.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight Something we haven't done in a long time.
Speaker 0: We're gonna review a con.
Speaker 0: We're talking about PAX West.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So it's pretty rare.
Speaker 1: We get a legendary opening bit or maybe it just feels that way because of the dark times.
Speaker 1: Yep, yep, but I have a a legendary Open e bit.
Speaker 1: legendary a hellish a hellish open e bit.
Speaker 1: So he went to PAX and the weekend immediately following packs was my sister's wedding.
Speaker 1: not in Chicago where her spouse lit his family lives.
Speaker 1: they live in LA but yeah.
Speaker 0: So fun fact.
Speaker 0: of the last three times I have tried to go to Chicago in my life.
Speaker 0: No joke.
Speaker 0: No exaggeration.
Speaker 0: Two of them the flights were fucked up so badly that I gave up and just didn't go.
Speaker 1: Well, I have never before even attempted to go to Chicago in my life, right?
Speaker 1: Not even an attempt at any previous point in time.
Speaker 1: Not a place that I would mind going right.
Speaker 1: there was some stuff I wanted to see there right and so the wedding was Sunday night and my flight was Friday night.
Speaker 1: ish, right.
Speaker 1: and I was like I could have gone from PAX to Chicago or stayed in Seattle and then gone to Chicago Or something like that, but it was like the hotel nights in between.
Speaker 1: You know Seattle and yeah, Chicago would have been very expensive.
Speaker 1: it was actually cheaper to destroy the environment and Take four flights instead of three plus minimal gain.
Speaker 0: it's not like when we stayed around Boston and New Hampshire between PAX East and Anime Boston that one time I could have done stuff it.
Speaker 1: I could have done things in Chicago if I stayed there a week.
Speaker 1: I've never been there.
Speaker 1: I'm sure there's things to do there.
Speaker 1: I saw Alright and so I went back to New York and then just a few days later I attempted to go to Chicago on Friday night and Load bearing word there.
Speaker 0: You just said the word attempted.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, they said it's a hellish story.
Speaker 1: It's not a spoiler.
Speaker 1: Come on It's.
Speaker 1: Where did you think the story was going when I said hellish?
Speaker 1: to start to talk about planes, okay So go to LaGuardia and our flight is.
Speaker 1: so it's like everything's looking good, right?
Speaker 1: You know, there's a hurricane out in the ocean, but that's we're not going that way and still not here yet.
Speaker 1: So, you know, that's not a problem.
Speaker 1: There are some thunderstorms, but they're like over to the west so we should both like fly over them, right?
Speaker 1: I don't fuck know how that works.
Speaker 1: I'm not a pie.
Speaker 1: I don't anything about.
Speaker 1: you know, plain weather, whatever.
Speaker 1: And I guess I know that ice on the wings is bad, but it was not cold.
Speaker 1: It's the very opposite of cold.
Speaker 1: So that's not the issue anyway.
Speaker 1: So we're waiting for the as soon as we like get to LaGuardia like, you know, we're just getting over there, right?
Speaker 1: Suddenly the status changes to delay.
Speaker 1: It's like well, all right.
Speaker 1: I think I actually know that might have the first delay might have been as soon as we closed the door and left the apartment.
Speaker 1: Regardless it was that close to the wire that the delay started appearing.
Speaker 1: It's like, all right.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, it's not much of a delay.
Speaker 1: What are we doing today?
Speaker 1: Nothing, right?
Speaker 1: It's like let's go over there make sure nothing gets fucked up, right?
Speaker 1: you know we get there and we sit down and we're looking at the gate and it gets delayed again and delayed again and Then canceled because the plane that was gonna take us to Chicago was not going to reach LaGuardia.
Speaker 1: So We're like, okay So I go to get in line to talk to the person and figure out what the fuck to do And I get in line I get in line I get to the first of all.
Speaker 1: I'd get standby for the next flight right on the phone obviously, right?
Speaker 1: But I'm like way down in line right like 11th or something like that, right?
Speaker 1: So And it's I'm like, alright, I start asking them all the questions cuz you know I'm sure other experienced travelers have had this happen.
Speaker 1: I have literally never had a flight canceled.
Speaker 0: I have had this happen Several times.
Speaker 0: there was when I got to meet the Bundespolize in Frankfurt.
Speaker 1: as a result of that I have never had a canceled flight and also this wasn't just like.
Speaker 1: if it was PAX even I would have been like, alright I'll just go to PAX a day late or I'll just skip this PAX, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, not the end of the world, right?
Speaker 1: There's another PAX next year.
Speaker 1: It's like sister's wedding.
Speaker 1: It's like I'm going to Chicago.
Speaker 1: It's like we're going.
Speaker 1: we're gonna get there, right?
Speaker 1: So I had to go wait in the line.
Speaker 1: I get to the front of the line and I'm like, alright, he's like.
Speaker 1: I'm like, what would you do?
Speaker 1: He's like I would wait and stand by for the next flight.
Speaker 1: He's like a lot of people are gonna bail on that flight.
Speaker 1: It's still on time.
Speaker 1: Right, you're gonna be you know, you have a good chance of getting on it.
Speaker 1: And if you don't well then you can worry about that when it happens.
Speaker 1: It's just a few hours.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I'm like, I'm like, alright, well, I checked a bag.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: is that bag?
Speaker 1: if I make it on the standby flight are the bag?
Speaker 1: people outside, you know I'm not gonna find out.
Speaker 1: I get on the standby flight until like close to the time it takes off, right?
Speaker 1: So are the bag people gonna go get my bag from wherever it is and throw it on?
Speaker 0: that player is what they told you Because I have a heuristic for that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So what he told me was your.
Speaker 1: if that happens Yes, the bag will get to Chicago.
Speaker 1: But it will probably get to Chicago like later and you'll have to go to the airport to retrieve it with your little claim ticket.
Speaker 1: And so I'm like.
Speaker 1: so I'm like.
Speaker 1: so I'll be in Chicago.
Speaker 1: I'll go to the hotel.
Speaker 1: I'll have to wait for some notification.
Speaker 1: go an hour back to the airport.
Speaker 0: Right, but you believe I once bought clothes for an event when I landed.
Speaker 1: There's a reason this clothing stores and all the airports.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: I know the most expensive fucking shirt I ever bought in my life.
Speaker 0: What didn't even write.
Speaker 1: It's like I'm like the suit and the dress for the wedding.
Speaker 1: They're in the luggage.
Speaker 1: I need I need the bag.
Speaker 1: It's not gonna work if I don't get that right.
Speaker 1: am I gonna go clothes shopping tomorrow at a fancy?
Speaker 1: It's like that's not good, right?
Speaker 1: I need that bag and I'm like alright, so What if I have the bag sent to the carousel and then I get on the standby flight.
Speaker 1: Can I run down?
Speaker 1: Oh, by the way, LaGuardia, the security was instantaneous.
Speaker 1: There was no line whatsoever.
Speaker 0: Anyways, I haven't been to the new LaGuardia yet I bring.
Speaker 1: it was literally no line.
Speaker 1: Like I just walked through and I peep and then I threw my bag in.
Speaker 1: the thing went through the whatever.
Speaker 1: there I'm in the end.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so I'm like, alright you send the bag down there.
Speaker 1: What if I go get it and then check it in for the standby flight?
Speaker 1: He's like, well, that'll be good if you get on the standby flight But if you don't the bag will go to Chicago without you.
Speaker 1: Yeah Right, you'll basically be paying us 30 bucks to ship your bag to Chicago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right, but not ship you to Chicago You know.
Speaker 0: But that is where because I have the work status just cuz I fly so much the fact that I can just check bags free.
Speaker 0: Is that is the thing I usually do in that situation because if I end up not traveling The airline has to get it back to me at some point.
Speaker 0: I can live without the bag.
Speaker 1: But I mean if the bag was in Chicago and I got some other flight there I could go to the airport at the bag.
Speaker 1: The bag would be there first Not the biggest deal.
Speaker 0: and if I don't make it don't make it to Chicago at all.
Speaker 0: Then you were fucked anyway, and you didn't need that suit and it's gonna make it back to you.
Speaker 1: Well, I need all the shit in the bag though.
Speaker 1: I need that bag back.
Speaker 1: I need to ship that get it shipped back to me Eventually.
Speaker 1: I need it.
Speaker 1: I need it with me.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so I'm like, well, that's not gonna be very good Right, and then I see that the standby flight is delayed and I'm like and I see all these other flights getting delayed And I'm like this shit gonna be canceled.
Speaker 1: I know it is I know.
Speaker 1: so I'm like, oh, so I'm just like send our bag downstairs Right.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna buy another flight from wherever I can buy a flight from and I'll worry about this later.
Speaker 0: now There's the danger if I'll if one flight gets delayed like that happens.
Speaker 0: if a bunch of flights on the same carrier get delayed that also happens.
Speaker 0: get a different carrier.
Speaker 0: if a bunch of flights across a bunch of Different carriers all get delayed simultaneously in my experience That means you're fucked and you want to get the fuck out of that Airport and like you're you did is bad news.
Speaker 1: Apparently over the weekend, right?
Speaker 1: There were over four thousand delays and cancellations at the New York airports.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so anyway, it was.
Speaker 1: it was all the airports, right?
Speaker 1: They set a laguardia.
Speaker 1: The only reason they gave was air traffic control.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they didn't say any other reason, right?
Speaker 1: It's like they didn't give any details or anything.
Speaker 1: It's like why don't you like just tell me that all the information?
Speaker 1: It's like it's not gonna change anything.
Speaker 0: so like I just like to know if it's you gather that the Carrier like the government will say and the carriers will then say what the government said, but if the carriers fuck up They ain't saying anything.
Speaker 1: No, no, but I'm saying it's like if they say the read.
Speaker 1: the reason was air traffic control.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: well show me the report from air traffic control.
Speaker 1: I just curious.
Speaker 1: right like it's there's a storm in this location and therefore this flight path is unsafe because of it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Just give me I'm not an expert.
Speaker 1: I don't you know know anything.
Speaker 0: Why not if your subway stops this subway that the conductor always gets on he's like, yeah We're stuck because of and he tells you why and the only time exactly.
Speaker 1: Give me a more a better explanation in three words.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like it doesn't change anything the fly.
Speaker 1: No, I'm not going.
Speaker 1: I can't argue that air traffic controllers into letting the flight go.
Speaker 1: I know that But it's I'm not expecting any different result.
Speaker 1: I just want to know.
Speaker 1: right I deserve, you know I feel like people deserve explanations even if the result is not any different.
Speaker 0: general.
Speaker 1: Yes, so we try.
Speaker 1: we see that there is a jet blue flight, right?
Speaker 1: I know rims not happy with the jet blue.
Speaker 0: I mean, they are the worst performing airline in America.
Speaker 1: They're trying to.
Speaker 1: there's a whole drama.
Speaker 1: They're trying to buy spirits.
Speaker 1: So I try.
Speaker 1: I see there's a jet blue flight Crackadon the next day and I'm like.
Speaker 1: so I'm on my phone trying to buy it.
Speaker 1: trying to book a flight on your phone Sucks ass I die.
Speaker 0: I do not know how people live with just a phone because I don't know how they do it.
Speaker 1: Like I had to fill out this whole web form with names addresses all this shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right like when I like in flights I got like Delta in one tab and then I've got like my calendar and Google Maps in another browser open at the same time because I'm like I could have busted out.
Speaker 1: I was trying to bust out the iPad because it was so difficult anyway, but yeah, I tried to book that flight several times and I got.
Speaker 1: at first I got.
Speaker 1: there were only seats left for the extra money, you know, the legroom seats, but I'm like, yes Yes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's let's get whatever's on here, right?
Speaker 1: You know and I try to book them and I get to the end and I say give me that seat I got it.
Speaker 1: All right, and then it said hey someone got those seats.
Speaker 1: Sorry.
Speaker 1: I'm like, I'm like, what do you mean?
Speaker 1: Why did you let?
Speaker 1: shouldn't you have reserved them when I was in the process?
Speaker 1: Like even Ticketmaster does that?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: That is that is JetBlue.
Speaker 1: Yeah, wait, so here it gets even worse than that, right?
Speaker 1: So then I go back in again.
Speaker 1: those same seats are still fucking lit up, but I can pick them even though JetBlue see it's not.
Speaker 0: I am at a JetBlue one not just because they're.
Speaker 1: oh.
Speaker 1: and by the way It didn't just send me back to the seat picker.
Speaker 1: It sent me back to the beginning.
Speaker 1: I had to fill out the forms again.
Speaker 1: So anyway, I felt the forms again on my phone.
Speaker 1: I picked the two seats in front of the two I picked last time Right, and then I try to pay and it like basically just doesn't work.
Speaker 1: I just get like a white page and Nothing happens.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: and so then we try again and we use PayPal this time instead of credit card number, right and This time the PayPal goes through.
Speaker 1: we get a email from PayPal money taken $900 right and then we don't get any email from JetBlue and we don't have any tickets Right, and then I try one more time flights full.
Speaker 1: So we're not on that flight We are the PayPal money will come back because basically that happens.
Speaker 0: even take off for Chicago.
Speaker 0: or is that all?
Speaker 1: it was early enough in The morning, I think it actually did.
Speaker 1: Yeah So I go to the I'm like, alright fuck all this right?
Speaker 1: I'm looking at you know, the other options.
Speaker 1: I basically filter two people Non-stop flights to Chicago tomorrow, right and I see there's a Delta flight, but it's late in the afternoon.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, I'm like, it's like four and I'm like I wanted the early one in case shit goes down Right.
Speaker 1: I got all day.
Speaker 1: That's the thing right?
Speaker 1: But the only one that had any seats was that afternoon one, right?
Speaker 1: So I'm like, well, I guess that's what we got to do.
Speaker 1: We don't have some other choice here, right?
Speaker 1: I didn't even see anything in Newark.
Speaker 0: So well, you know Your New Yorker is desperate when they even think about taking this flight out of Newark.
Speaker 1: Some other people who had similar problems who went to the same wedding from New York did go to Newark But I think they were able to do that because they were one person and two people right anyway.
Speaker 1: So I go and we go to JFK and they were in terminal for again for the second time in that week at least for me.
Speaker 1: And we're waiting and the flight says on time right and I'm looking to some other flights.
Speaker 1: I'm seeing delays of seeing cancellations.
Speaker 1: I'm seeing people get bumped and be offered $1,600 to get off right, but I'm like man, I would love, you know, not our flight But some other flights were doing the bumping.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right and I'm like, man I would wish I get bumped on the way home, right?
Speaker 1: That would be right.
Speaker 1: I would take that if they said a thousand they started at a thousand.
Speaker 1: they worked up to 1600 before they got enough people bummed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I still think the law would have taken that if I was in Chicago already trying to Get home.
Speaker 1: I would have taken the thousand immediately.
Speaker 0: The law should be if a flight if someone's gonna get bumped they got to keep raising the price until someone accepts That's it.
Speaker 1: That's what they did.
Speaker 1: That's exactly what they did.
Speaker 1: They're like, we'll give you a thousand dollars if you get off.
Speaker 1: They said they were like they sit and they said how many people they're like, we need five people to leave We need three.
Speaker 1: All right, we they're like.
Speaker 1: we now need three people to leave.
Speaker 1: We're raising it to 1500.
Speaker 1: You know, I need one person to leave 1600.
Speaker 1: I guess the computer figures out how much they're supposed to offer right for them.
Speaker 0: See I say they have to raise it no matter what they did.
Speaker 1: They raised it until they bumped off the phone.
Speaker 0: They can't just bump people and just.
Speaker 0: Well, that's what they did though, so it was fine.
Speaker 1: It was some sort of reverse paying auction, you know to pay people to get off the plane.
Speaker 1: It wasn't our plane.
Speaker 1: regardless Says on time.
Speaker 1: our plane is never delayed.
Speaker 1: other planes around are getting delayed, right?
Speaker 1: I can't see out the windows in that particular area of the terminal So I can't tell if planes are taking off or landing But I see people getting off of planes and coming into the terminal or a. there's some activity Right.
Speaker 1: Our our flight is still on time.
Speaker 1: The crew is there.
Speaker 1: we get on the plane on time Right, we taxi out from the gate on time right much like a movie that is not in theaters yet.
Speaker 1: However, oh, yeah, we're waiting in line to take off right, you know behind all the other planes.
Speaker 1: and then we're sitting there and we're sitting there and They're like, alright this they said the pilots like alright, there's some weather situation.
Speaker 1: He didn't say what weather.
Speaker 1: He didn't say what any details yet again.
Speaker 1: He just said weather problem, right?
Speaker 1: No planes are taking off to the west.
Speaker 1: So we're waiting behind them.
Speaker 1: I'll update you in 15 minutes and I'm like, uh-oh.
Speaker 1: That's the end, isn't it?
Speaker 1: We're not gonna make it right.
Speaker 1: and then 15 minutes later.
Speaker 1: He's like, I still have no updates from air traffic control.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're still waiting.
Speaker 1: and then 15 minutes later.
Speaker 1: He's like, alright.
Speaker 1: Well, we still don't have any updates.
Speaker 1: It's we've been out here too long.
Speaker 1: We're gonna go back to the gate.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna sit out here that long.
Speaker 1: Right good on them.
Speaker 1: We'll go.
Speaker 1: he's like.
Speaker 1: we'll go back to the gate and we'll figure out what to do from the gate.
Speaker 1: The flight crew someone asked them they they were working until midnight.
Speaker 1: So as long as something was figured out by like say it was like around seven o'clock at this point, maybe I think right.
Speaker 1: As long as something was figured out by like, you know, the flight there is like two and a half hours.
Speaker 1: It's like by 930 that they could take off at 930 We could land and that wouldn't be breaking the law of the flight crew working past midnight, right?
Speaker 1: And so basically when we just about got back to the gate they were like, yeah, it's canceled.
Speaker 1: I'm like well That's that.
Speaker 1: So I'm basically giving up right.
Speaker 1: and then I'm like, well, there is one remaining option Right and that remaining option is to drive 12 hours.
Speaker 1: We will make it in time if we somewhat immediately drive 12 hours to Chicago.
Speaker 0: We got a full tank of gas half a pack of cigarettes So I could take.
Speaker 1: so I could take rims car.
Speaker 1: But the problem with rims car is I have no way to get it back from Chicago because that is a one-way trip.
Speaker 1: There is no way that I'm turning around.
Speaker 0: Yeah I would have to.
Speaker 1: but also you would have had to come with me and taking your car home and I would have taken a Plane home or paid to put the car on a truck for someone else to carry it back to New York.
Speaker 0: You didn't want to do two 12-hour road trips.
Speaker 1: No not that was not.
Speaker 1: no there was a line.
Speaker 1: right one 12-hour road trip was enough, so I'm thinking all right.
Speaker 1: I'll yell out to all these other people from the flight.
Speaker 1: We're all waiting in the same customer service line.
Speaker 1: Anyway, right?
Speaker 1: I'll yell out be like, all right Who needs to get to Chicago tomorrow?
Speaker 1: I heard one person saying they had a funeral to get to right?
Speaker 1: So I'm like, you know, we'll all rent a car together at the airport.
Speaker 1: You know a big one and we can drive like an even if we have 12 people in a 12 person like p-van or whatever We could drive like an hour each.
Speaker 1: It'll be really comfy that Drive before it sucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah with one person it sucks with two.
Speaker 0: It's doable with three or more.
Speaker 0: It's actually kind of easy.
Speaker 1: It's like if you got a driver's license then, you know, and and you're not the guy who was angry I'll judge I'll judge you.
Speaker 1: There were enough normal people there, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, we can make it something about to yell out.
Speaker 1: But then I overhear a conversation and the conversation is someone being like, yeah Oh, there's no cars left at JFK.
Speaker 1: I'm like Well That's it.
Speaker 1: That's the end right there the end.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna make it, right?
Speaker 1: So I call and I'm like, you know, I'm like I'm basically destroyed at this point, right and I'm like We're not gonna make it right.
Speaker 1: and they're like, well, I guess we'll FaceTime you or something.
Speaker 1: It's like the end.
Speaker 0: I we did miss my cousin's wedding Not that long ago.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know during the dark times, you know, my uncle missed his own mother's funeral, right?
Speaker 1: FaceTime Tim so but anyway and then You know the phone rings right and I pick up the phone and my mother says, all right, listen apparently My new my new brother-in-law's cousin who I've never met in my whole life Right, is that LaGuardia when I'm at JFK, right and if she supposedly has a car And is a nut job who was ready with this person I never met before was apparently fully prepared to drive the 12 hours alone in a car.
Speaker 1: They had rented I don't know.
Speaker 1: I guess LaGuardia had cars.
Speaker 1: I don't fucking know.
Speaker 1: right and I'm like, well That's crazy.
Speaker 1: But if that's real I got I got to shoot my I got to shoot that shot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can't right.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, if you're in the dark place and a the cloud opens the tiniest bit It's like I guess I had to do that even though I really don't want to.
Speaker 1: It's like that is the only path left open to me.
Speaker 1: It's like when you're playing a card game and it's like I guess cuz it's Tuesday, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you're playing a card game and it's like well I win if I roll exactly a 17 on a d20 and I draw exactly this card from that deck.
Speaker 1: It's like I'm gonna roll the dice and draw the card.
Speaker 0: always bet on an inside straight.
Speaker 1: any any other result bad times Right stuck somewhere between here in Chicago fall asleep and die in a car crash, right?
Speaker 1: Lots of bad results, but there is this narrow path to victory.
Speaker 1: There's.
Speaker 1: this is only happening one time.
Speaker 1: This isn't like, you know, I would not.
Speaker 1: hey, it's a unique circumstance Right.
Speaker 1: I only have one life.
Speaker 1: This is it?
Speaker 1: Alright, I'll call a contact this person.
Speaker 1: we get phone numbers are exchanged by the people in Chicago.
Speaker 1: Exchange our numbers, right?
Speaker 0: You've got like a situation room of the family like organizing.
Speaker 1: all They really only did was give us each other's numbers, right?
Speaker 1: So I talked to this person and sure enough they're in a very long line at Avis rent a car at LaGuardia and they say that they have a confirmation number, right so that they definitely have a car.
Speaker 1: and I'm like All right, we will just get our bag again.
Speaker 1: I'm having a bag that is sent down to the carousel, right?
Speaker 1: And we'll wait at terminal for JFK departures Or arrivals and if you get the car then we'll discuss right and if you don't get the car We'll go home.
Speaker 1: So then they're like, oh there's only 12 people vans left and I'm like, well, listen, I'm not gonna drive a 12 people van, right?
Speaker 1: That's not happening, right?
Speaker 1: I don't think that's gonna work.
Speaker 1: then they're like wait, I Bribe the guy Like.
Speaker 1: this is a person I've never met before.
Speaker 1: who's?
Speaker 1: my first interaction with them is they're bribing people.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: That's a positive sign.
Speaker 1: They bribed the guy and got a small SUV and it's like I guess they were trying to give out the vans and were hiding the SUVs, right So bribing works people.
Speaker 1: it was it really happened.
Speaker 1: So I'm like, I guess I guess this is happening right.
Speaker 1: the 12-hour overnight drive.
Speaker 1: Okay And that is exactly what happened.
Speaker 1: they came to JFK.
Speaker 1: we got caught in the car Right and we drove 12 hours on i-80 Farther west on land basically i-80 the entire way to Chicago a hundred percent of the way, right?
Speaker 1: I saw the I. at first I was like, I'd never been to Ohio and I and then halfway to Ohio I was like, wait a minute.
Speaker 1: I have been to Ohio.
Speaker 1: I went to Ohio con.
Speaker 1: That was what I've been to.
Speaker 1: And then I was like I've been to Michigan once right we went to You know Pango con.
Speaker 1: that and she was like was it Novi?
Speaker 1: and I'm like it was no it was no Bye, it was no by Michigan's near the boy graveyard.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: We saw the road to Detroit did not go.
Speaker 1: I saw Gary, Indiana, which is scary as fuck.
Speaker 0: the last time I drove to Chicago the purple Pontiac Sunfire Broke down and we we limped north in from Ohio into Michigan because that was the nearest mechanic We could find that was open and we got the car fixed and I wrote a bad check.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I saw lots of sad rest stops.
Speaker 1: We passed like a rest stop that had some you know, like compared to nothing.
Speaker 1: the choices were like bad, right?
Speaker 1: But then we're like, alright, we'll go for the next rest stop.
Speaker 0: worst choice.
Speaker 0: I could've warned you the further west you go the worse they get until you hit you like it right next to Chicago.
Speaker 1: This is like after the Sun came up around 7 a.m.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, listen, we all right It's breakfast time.
Speaker 1: Whatever the next rest stop is that?
Speaker 1: has anything Brett remotely breakfast related.
Speaker 1: We gotta go right.
Speaker 1: and the next rest stop had Hardee's and only Hardee's.
Speaker 0: That sounds about right.
Speaker 1: I ate a Hardee's Breakfast egg bacon on a vis.
Speaker 0: I am surprised you survived that I.
Speaker 1: that's all but it was the saltiest biscuit in the universe.
Speaker 1: I never.
Speaker 1: it was like a pretzel biscuit.
Speaker 0: It's like several tears below a bad McDonald's breakfast sandwich.
Speaker 1: What else was I got?
Speaker 1: This is already a desperate time, right?
Speaker 1: So anyway But sure enough at some point like some kind of miracle we arrived in Chicago.
Speaker 1: There were some other situations right like I had purchased before the first flight.
Speaker 1: I purchased tickets to the Cubs game and then sold them for a small loss.
Speaker 1: You know, I saw the word, you know the old things I saw in Chicago the the private highway with a toll.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, those are a thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah The the terrifying.
Speaker 1: the hell I was by the way was terrifying like 30 lanes.
Speaker 1: It was looked like some sort of like it was truly the heart like you think war on cars is bad in New York.
Speaker 1: It's like that was the worst time.
Speaker 1: It was like some sort of dystopian highway situation.
Speaker 1: But then I saw the outside of where the White Sox play.
Speaker 1: I saw buildings from far away.
Speaker 1: I saw the hotel I saw the wedding venue and I saw the train.
Speaker 1: I took the train back to the airport.
Speaker 1: train is very nice.
Speaker 1: They got an omni equivalent there.
Speaker 1: I just tapped my phone got on the train.
Speaker 1: It's it's very.
Speaker 1: it's a lot like the DC metro where every line comes in and then out of downtown.
Speaker 1: Right, so they're all like these u-shapes of each color.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're basically very easy for commuting and not like the Philly one I can't figure out was very easy to understand subway.
Speaker 1: It took me straight to those they would literally said Oh hair with a picture of an airplane on the side of the train I got on.
Speaker 1: it took me to the train.
Speaker 1: It took me to the airport And then I was like, all right the flight home Who is the last you know?
Speaker 1: Basically, we had these two round-trip tickets to United and I was all right.
Speaker 1: and I was.
Speaker 1: I was the only one who actually went In the car, right?
Speaker 1: You can't blame someone for not wanting to go on the 12-hour insanity road trip, right?
Speaker 1: And so I was only using one return trip out of four total trips and that that flight actually took me home.
Speaker 1: and I was like I actually kind of wanted that to be canceled so I could stay in Chicago for more than yeah 24 hours total like eight of which were spent sleeping, but
Speaker 0: I mean I won't flew to Omaha To do a meeting and then flew back and landed at JFK at the same gate the same day And that was a bad feeling.
Speaker 1: That's real bad.
Speaker 1: That was that was I took two sick, but I mean, but were you going to some like, you know?
Speaker 1: One-time thing can't possibly miss deal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was a very convinced a very rich person to sign a check situation, basically.
Speaker 1: But that's not something that you actually care.
Speaker 0: I didn't want to go I did.
Speaker 0: I could not have it wasn't it?
Speaker 1: So I wasn't a check for you.
Speaker 1: No, no.
Speaker 0: No, I could not have cared less Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is like, you know anyway.
Speaker 1: So that's that was the the the weekend from hell and now I am going to stay in New York until America United States Thanksgiving.
Speaker 0: Yeah Like the weekend after next weekend, so I have many nice safe.
Speaker 1: I have like a packed schedule in fact of many wonderful New York things to do and there's a few more I might want to cram in there, too.
Speaker 0: So if you're wondering out there like because a bunch of our friends have also had flight problems like just recently like us Yes flying in America has gotten very much worse relatively recently and there and according to WAPO there are two primary drivers.
Speaker 0: one the airlines just won't pay their employees anything and thus our short staffed by their own fault and To climate change is really fucking up air travel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this was definitely a climate change weekend.
Speaker 1: Oh, by the way that the Chicago looked pretty smoggy like the AQI was 66.
Speaker 1: It wasn't like super bad, but You know Wasn't great.
Speaker 0: No, it's not it's not great there.
Speaker 0: Michigan's way better than Chicago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Chicago was not as good But there was the the I did see.
Speaker 1: the best thing I saw in Chicago, which is basically right next to the wedding venue Was this park right on Lake Michigan.
Speaker 1: basically and it's like that was like I was like.
Speaker 1: Oh, I was like after seeing the highway, right?
Speaker 1: I was like and thinking Chicago was like a hell place.
Speaker 1: Seeing that park is like everyone was biking.
Speaker 1: There's basically a Exact equivalent of city bike with the different name.
Speaker 1: That's also owned by living entire.
Speaker 0: Everyone is riding it all around Most of all the lakes and they're all like that.
Speaker 1: It's just there was like all these, you know This whole park right on the the water in Chicago and I gave it was like the most wonderful park and I was like man.
Speaker 1: I wish I could be in this park for more than like, you know a couple hours.
Speaker 1: That would be nice.
Speaker 0: lakes like that or why I call everything a pond cuz.
Speaker 0: just growing up in Michigan like that.
Speaker 0: That's what I think of as a lake.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like they had.
Speaker 1: there was like it wasn't a. there wasn't sand next to it.
Speaker 1: There was like concrete.
Speaker 1: So it was sort of like getting in a pool, but there were like little ladders to go in.
Speaker 1: You know, no one was going in.
Speaker 1: it was You can you got that.
Speaker 0: that's why the cleaner lakes on there was.
Speaker 1: no there was no lifeguard.
Speaker 1: but you you know There were stairs there were ladders going right in the water anywhere.
Speaker 0: I ever swam as a kid had a lifeguard at any point?
Speaker 0: No like that anyway, that's just expected.
Speaker 1: So it was.
Speaker 1: there were parts of Chicago I saw that I would and parts I didn't see that I would like to see.
Speaker 1: so it's like Would I go back there just to see Chicago?
Speaker 1: maybe.
Speaker 1: But it's like if there's a reason to go there and like another reason convention, maybe they do have the C2e - right there's.
Speaker 1: Now I know someone right.
Speaker 1: I don't want to talk too much about this this individual right that drove me there but they were.
Speaker 1: I'll say that they were an awesome person who works in a very interesting business right there in Chicago area.
Speaker 0: So mom, right?
Speaker 0: You're telling me this is a mob snow.
Speaker 0: Interesting business Chicago area.
Speaker 1: Okay, no they worked in like, you know, they ran.
Speaker 1: they basically run videotrons at sporting events.
Speaker 0: Interesting job.
Speaker 1: I was like, oh can like the.
Speaker 1: I was like all that projector that's on to the ice.
Speaker 1: They're like, yeah, I could run that like, you know, we have we have that right?
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: but anyway, and then they I don't think like It.
Speaker 1: not only what like.
Speaker 1: I don't think most people would have been able to like do that drive.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: not only did I need that car?
Speaker 1: I don't think any other person besides that person Right or a person like them.
Speaker 1: It was gonna work out right?
Speaker 1: I could have done it by myself.
Speaker 1: That wasn't gonna happen.
Speaker 0: I mean I have done Several 12-hour drive solo in my life and while they're doable that is pushing the absolute fucking limit.
Speaker 1: Yeah But like this that person was a champion the exact person that I needed in the exact moment that I needed them.
Speaker 1: I'm very thankful to that person and they're in Chicago So if I go there, I'd probably see them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the funny thing was that you know at the wedding Everyone's like oh you you were you were the one you drive with that.
Speaker 1: You know all the people from the other family that I had never met before.
Speaker 1: We're like, oh you had to drive with that person.
Speaker 1: Oh, we're sorry.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that person's a bit much.
Speaker 1: They're so extra.
Speaker 1: It's like they were like talking down their own family member, right and then late into the evening that person's parents The person's father by the way was is a professional Santa Claus, but like literally Even the person's parents were like apologizing that I had to be in the car with their child Right, and I was like, I think the first you know, it's like I could see what they were talking about.
Speaker 1: The person talked a lot, right?
Speaker 1: They had a lot of energy, right?
Speaker 1: You know Right, but it was.
Speaker 1: it was a person who had correct opinions Right who complained in Ohio about it being a place where people don't have right.
Speaker 1: You know, it was a. it was a my kind of my kind of person, right?
Speaker 1: So my opinion of the person was better than their own their entire family's opinion of just You know.
Speaker 1: and that was that was the story.
Speaker 1: so now it's like yeah, I suffered Greatly and was you know had some dark times But now that it once I get more rest actually I'm not done yet the story will be just a good story.
Speaker 0: That will you always look forward to that moment when it just turns into a story you can tell and you're not like fresh from the wounds Exactly.
Speaker 1: It's a. it's a cool scar.
Speaker 1: Let me show you the cool scar when I got stabbed Right that kind of less less bad than being stabbed but you know bad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so, uh, all right That took up half the show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we go a little quick on the news, but this one is actually a pretty big deal.
Speaker 1: Why don't we go?
Speaker 1: Why don't we just go big?
Speaker 1: because we haven't done a show in a hundred years.
Speaker 0: And also I don't think we're not doing another show this week.
Speaker 0: I'll get back to our schedule next week.
Speaker 0: So, uh in the news there was this application, you know, we used to play counter-strike when you're in college and Getting updates to counter-strike in an era before the modern internet was terrible was it was almost as bad as flight cancelling Despite having two OC threes.
Speaker 0: This was like if a counter-strike point happening.
Speaker 0: You're like talking to people on campus using aim instant messenger or maybe ICQ and you're trying to find anyone who?
Speaker 0: Downloaded that exe so you can get a copy of it from them because you can't play counter-strike until you write the up.
Speaker 1: We had the best internet there was but the servers that were hosting game files did not.
Speaker 1: yo.
Speaker 0: So this cut there wasn't that company?
Speaker 0: a little company about a workout valve and they released a little app And all this app did was update counter-strike for you.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: And Scott installed this app like I did the media In fact, I installed it at.
Speaker 1: What was it?
Speaker 1: What did we say?
Speaker 1: It was nine twenty eight eight nine twenty six a.m.
Speaker 1: On September 12 2003. now I did not exactly 20 years ago today.
Speaker 0: I installed it 19.8 something years ago because I installed it a little bit after Scott on November 16th 2003 at 1 56 a.m.
Speaker 0: Which says a lot about me.
Speaker 1: Yes, the app is familiar to you.
Speaker 1: It is called steam and I am one of the few people on this planet.
Speaker 1: Just I don't.
Speaker 1: this doesn't really have any value.
Speaker 1: It's just kind of cool that like my years of service badge on my steam profile right now says 20 and like Almost nobody else says 20 like almost nobody right rim says 19 still.
Speaker 0: Yeah It'll say in a month and four days, right?
Speaker 1: Mine says 20 now and valve put up this cute page that tells you know to celebrate the 20th anniversary of steam.
Speaker 1: It shows the hit.
Speaker 1: it tells you the history of steam and the hottest games of each year and you should definitely check out that page.
Speaker 1: It's really nice.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So, you know, it's funny because we just did that panel of packs on games You can't play.
Speaker 0: and one point we made is that video games were invented in living memory.
Speaker 0: Like the first video games were made Before like before people who are alive today were born.
Speaker 0: But there are people who are alive today who were already alive and adult before the first video game was ever made.
Speaker 0: So This is still a very early thing.
Speaker 0: Steam's only 20 years old and yet if you were born after us Steam just feels like it's literally always been around because for a lot of gamers steam has literally always been around.
Speaker 1: Yep, people don't know what it was like to not be able to download the game, right?
Speaker 0: Yep, so, uh, we'll play some counter-strike when the new one comes out maybe in some other.
Speaker 1: see how much I play But it'll play.
Speaker 0: it will play enough to review it.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: in some actually breaking news the article I'm gonna link to was posted like an hour ago.
Speaker 0: Unity the game engine has had a lot of ups and downs.
Speaker 0: There's been a lot of interesting Situations with them lately, but they just changed their monetization model and on one hand There are a lot of people on the internet who are
Speaker 1: wrong
Speaker 0: about what changed and mad about things that are not real like they are Freaking out about literally made of bullshit.
Speaker 1: Well, I think first of all, right they wrote this article, you know They made an announcement and have a fact but they didn't unity to did not write all of the information and answer all the questions that people have.
Speaker 1: so some people just Assumed the worst or assumed what you would assume reading that the poorly communicated announcement.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you know reacted with.
Speaker 1: you know, some some FUD right.
Speaker 1: and then other people, you know Real and semi-real journalists asked and got answers to the the unanswered questions, right?
Speaker 1: And so there were some clarifications which resulted in some people being wrong Sort of not their fault, but sort of you know, whatever right?
Speaker 0: Yeah I see people who are still wrong Actively despite well because one particular person wrote an article very quickly.
Speaker 1: That's very.
Speaker 1: it's like a long.
Speaker 1: It's a long article.
Speaker 1: It was quickly published like a meet almost immediately after the official announcement and it's like they wrote it in much haste.
Speaker 1: They posted it on many sites.
Speaker 1: Not just one like they didn't just have their blog.
Speaker 1: It's posted on like two or three.
Speaker 1: I don't know what's up with that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then I saw it being spread around and shared and like Multiple discord servers and other reddit-type places and link sherry places like their article got viral right quickly.
Speaker 1: So and it has misinformation in it because that person did not do any journalism and like I said just assumed Whatever based on the poor communication right that unity put out.
Speaker 1: Yep, right.
Speaker 0: So now anyway, all of that said the actual changes are bad.
Speaker 1: Yo, yeah, they're they are bad.
Speaker 1: that this is that unity is doing bad things but they are not quite as bad.
Speaker 1: They're still way bad, but they're not quite as bad as some people were led to believe due to unity's poor communication and you know Reactionary unresearched blog posts.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the truth is actually bad.
Speaker 1: So what's actually bad?
Speaker 1: So First of all, let's you know, I still don't have a grasp on it completely all the details.
Speaker 1: But basically the way if you use the unity game engine to make your game The way you pay unity and how much you owe them is going to be different than it was before And it's based on how much.
Speaker 1: first item of bullshit Yes First item of bullshit right?
Speaker 1: is that even if you made your game and published it long ago right with unity You're subject to this new model Even if that was not the model when you made your game and you you might not even be making a game anymore.
Speaker 1: Right, you might be out of the gaming business, but you're still collecting like royalties from it.
Speaker 1: doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: You're subject to this new thing.
Speaker 1: That's horseshit, right?
Speaker 1: You didn't agree to this you didn't budget and and you know make your game under this assumption of this new model and they change It on you.
Speaker 1: All right, just a milk.
Speaker 1: basically just you know squeeze from your your trickle.
Speaker 1: of whatever games There's a bear.
Speaker 0: There's a Deeper story about unity's motivation, but we'll get to that at the end.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'm just saying what it is.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, right.
Speaker 1: the second item of bullshit, right?
Speaker 1: Is that?
Speaker 1: yeah It's.
Speaker 1: you're still free as long as you're under these thresholds.
Speaker 1: So if your game makes less than two million dollars or you have less than two hundred thousand downloads, you don't have to pay anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you have to hit both thresholds to be charged this extra fee.
Speaker 1: And yes So if you don't hit both thresholds Like if you sell 200 if you have 200,000 downloads But you make a dollar or your game is literally free you don't have to pay unity.
Speaker 1: Yeah thing right.
Speaker 1: if you make five hundred million dollars because you sold one copy that cost five hundred million dollars You don't owe you to do anything.
Speaker 0: also and that lower threshold the two hundred thousand like that one that only applies to like the home Personal version of unity not the professional.
Speaker 1: Yes Well, obviously if you use the professional or the pay if you pay them for a better version of unity your thresholds go up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so much closer.
Speaker 1: Real has yes, right.
Speaker 1: So that's sort of like.
Speaker 1: well you did pay them.
Speaker 1: You're still not free right, but you now have a bigger threshold.
Speaker 1: So it's like if you pay for the good unity Your game has to be quite successful like a million seller before you start owing them anything additional, right?
Speaker 1: So but if you pay them and you get a million seller, okay now you owe them something, right?
Speaker 1: okay, so This was the part one part that was miscommunicated.
Speaker 1: Was that like bundles?
Speaker 1: and charity?
Speaker 1: like doesn't count.
Speaker 1: So if you throw your measly little free game in a bundle and the bundle goes hog wild, you know That doesn't count right?
Speaker 0: The other thing that is this part that was lost.
Speaker 0: a lot of people didn't realize or notice and this seems like it was actually In the original release to that the revenue threshold only applies to a rolling 12-month period not like All-time revenue.
Speaker 1: I thought there was an all-time one and no it's all-time downloads.
Speaker 0: It's last months revenue.
Speaker 0: So if you sold a game a long time ago, and it's not making two hundred thousand dollars a year by itself The fees also don't apply.
Speaker 1: Okay, that's good.
Speaker 1: That's good.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So but here's the thing.
Speaker 1: Here's the real bullshit.
Speaker 1: is they want to charge Per download?
Speaker 1: right not per purchase per download like yes confirmed I let's say I bought rims game and I set up something to delete it and download Delete it.
Speaker 1: I could just download it and download it and download it and download it and download copies and copies.
Speaker 1: and they say That they have some model.
Speaker 1: they can detect these frauds or whatever.
Speaker 1: But it's like but they don't want to be transparent about how that model works.
Speaker 1: Oh, right, because they don't you know, they say well, we don't want people to understand the fraud detection.
Speaker 1: It's like well look if you want to invoice me for a million downloads.
Speaker 1: You better the fuck be able to have you know, an itemized invoice listing all million downloads.
Speaker 1: I want the IP address I want the time.
Speaker 1: I want everything Listing you to the service the URL the amount of bits.
Speaker 1: list for me every download just like on my credit card statement.
Speaker 1: It lists every transaction.
Speaker 1: you bet, you know when we did music.
Speaker 1: I worked in the music royalties business.
Speaker 1: We could list every fucking listen, right?
Speaker 0: We can list literally everything that ever happens to any.
Speaker 1: every micro penny song royalty that comes through was Itemized right.
Speaker 1: I could print out the whole statement for you if I had to and get it from the database somewhere.
Speaker 1: So you can't be sending me some invoice like a million downloads.
Speaker 1: I'd be like fucking prove it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: Show me the million downloads.
Speaker 1: Your model says I had a million downloads.
Speaker 1: show me each and every one what fucking moron made it.
Speaker 0: downloads as opposed to Active installs or like browsers can already uniquely identify Devices and web servers can often uniquely identify browsers and devices.
Speaker 1: kind of not really Better than just how about just fucking purchases.
Speaker 1: purchases like we will take you know one cent off anytime someone buys your game or we will take one cent anytime someone buys your game or buys a DLC or buys some skin.
Speaker 0: Yep Some broader context is required because there's that at least we have the invoice for so in the article I'm gonna link to that talks about what happened here.
Speaker 0: It has a read more link and the read more link points out another older article and the headline of that older article.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna read the headline Unity CEO calls mobile devs who don't prioritize monetization quote fucking idiots.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because unity Basically and I'm summarizing Vaguely because you know, you never know if someone's litigious and we're not I want to be guilty of any sort of defamation.
Speaker 0: They basically are trying to mostly target the shitware Demographic.
Speaker 0: they their best.
Speaker 0: their ideal customer is someone who makes shitware for mobile phones full of ads and they have their own ad Network and they want you to use their ad bullshit.
Speaker 0: That is their whole model as far as I can say shit.
Speaker 1: And if you use their if you use their ad bullshit you are exempt from this new model, right?
Speaker 1: Because instead they'll be milking you from the ad bullshit and they don't need the money that you would pay per down Three possible.
Speaker 0: now, this is me as a professional product manager giving my personal opinion on unity without any special knowledge.
Speaker 0: There are three core ways I could see to monetize you.
Speaker 0: well four ways to monetize unity.
Speaker 0: one is you make it a premium thing and you just charge big studios a ton of money and that's obviously not a great option for all the reasons but only makes you so much money because Only so many studios they would all pay for it.
Speaker 0: And then that's it That would pay that much.
Speaker 0: if they'll just pay for unreal instead.
Speaker 1: So well, I mean they could pay for whichever one's better.
Speaker 1: You'd have to compete and real and probably better.
Speaker 1: You'd have to get them to choose you right and then they pay for it and it's like, okay And how do you get more customers?
Speaker 1: There's only so many game devs and that are making big money anyway.
Speaker 0: So maybe it's not demographics.
Speaker 0: you have Indie.
Speaker 0: get indie developers who make games.
Speaker 1: you have they're only they're gonna only use something that's free zero dollar.
Speaker 0: you have larger series that make games.
Speaker 0: you have Lower budget television like you know how the Mandalorian was filmed with the volume and like the game engine type stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there are other uses of games and they could go after the beach here like instead of High-end TV and and Hollywood they go after lower end TV and like volume like stuff like.
Speaker 0: that's a demographic they could go after but now they're going after the absolute bottom of the shit where ad revenue barrel the what the the.
Speaker 1: The easy way to say it is that rather than try to get more customers and increase sales of software They're instead going to find ways to milk the existing customers for more money.
Speaker 0: Well, remember that article I was talking about is from 2022 When unity laid a bunch of people off and announced that they were merging with iron source.
Speaker 0: And if you don't know what iron source is there it talks about that when it was news.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's ads are basically the only thing unity cares about and that I don't trust them as a company anymore.
Speaker 0: Not that I've trusted them for some time.
Speaker 1: And so and I guess we can't neglect to mention the fact that they're counting downloads again, right?
Speaker 1: It's like people if you know gamers who evil ones are gonna know this and if they see a game that they know is made With unity and they don't like who made that game.
Speaker 1: They'll just keep downloading it to try to cost that person money.
Speaker 0: Yep, especially if it's a game that's at the upper end of the indie sphere often Right you pay.
Speaker 1: it's like if it costs per download, but you only pay for the game once.
Speaker 1: Alright, let's what did they say like 10 cents a download or something?
Speaker 0: Some 4chan dipshit is gonna have a botnet.
Speaker 1: I buy that I could buy the game for 20 bucks.
Speaker 1: I just have to download it like 200 times.
Speaker 1: and now you've lost money Even though you sold a copy of your game because you now Oh unity more than the price of the game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because it's per download Assuming they don't like detect the fraud or whatever kind of.
Speaker 0: meanwhile in big in big boy business land Let's say I want to have a pricing model that is related to I don't know some some cheering or banding like that.
Speaker 0: I got it.
Speaker 0: I got a announce and document things like.
Speaker 0: we consider one day to be between GMT double-oh double-oh double-oh one and GMT 23 59. here is the math we will use to determine what band you are in like.
Speaker 0: that is how big boy companies announce things like this.
Speaker 0: so anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: There's Bentley's the car and there's share the vehicle There's a. I guess there's a thing and I understand why I can imagine the kind of person who is into this.
Speaker 0: I am NOT into it.
Speaker 0: I find it capitalist and creepy for a lot of reasons, but it's basically Supermodels doing ASMR tick-tock style videos while they touch very expensive cars.
Speaker 0: Like it's a man.
Speaker 1: That's someone's thing for sure.
Speaker 1: It's someone I'm sure.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of people's thing for sure.
Speaker 0: Remember in our IT we learned about pedal pushers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we did.
Speaker 0: we did so, uh, that's the thing.
Speaker 0: people who maybe Think that that is ridiculous have meme-ified making videos in the exact same format But using things other than Bentley's and Ferrari's.
Speaker 0: So this video is the first one I saw and also the best one and it just cuts back and forth.
Speaker 0: It's very short between the Bentley ASMR and the stare ASMR.
Speaker 0: and if you don't know what the stare is Well, take a look sounds German the best.
Speaker 0: it is definitely German.
Speaker 0: The best part of this video is when the person doing the share video Bob ASMR Starts this device.
Speaker 0: and how long?
Speaker 1: oh, so it's not.
Speaker 1: it's not a staircase.
Speaker 1: Okay, it's.
Speaker 0: it's a tractor.
Speaker 0: It's a big old fucking tractor All right, uh how it starts and the amount of rust on it tell you everything you need to know about why this video is funny.
Speaker 1: Okay It's been a long time since we had a webcomic thing of the day But way long ago with the mocha.
Speaker 1: I discovered a person named Daisy McGuire who was doing a comic called gastrophobia about In ancient Greece, that was all cute Great, and I stopped reading it.
Speaker 0: cuz I read everything that was out at the time.
Speaker 1: You know that person still exists and is still comicking and they have a relatively new.
Speaker 1: they started it in April.
Speaker 1: They're gonna adapt some Oz shit with their own Twist on it of cuteness and whatnot and they're starting with book two because you've read book one already, right?
Speaker 1: So yeah I've actually never read any Oz book.
Speaker 1: I've just seen the movie and I've never read either.
Speaker 1: I've seen and I've seen wicked the play which doesn't count.
Speaker 1: That's not.
Speaker 1: that's written by.
Speaker 0: I have seen two movies and the second one that most people think is the weird one is actually way Closer to the Wizard of Oz type stories than the one that most people know.
Speaker 1: But anyway, this is a a you know, I don't know what the source material is, right?
Speaker 1: I vaguely know the source material, but you know what?
Speaker 0: There's a lot going on.
Speaker 0: I that might be a good book club candidate at some point I don't know maybe but this is One of the main characters of that universe is basically Princess Bubblegum.
Speaker 0: Like she was based on this character.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway loose adaptation starting with book two.
Speaker 1: It was very it's very fun and cute at least for someone who has not read.
Speaker 1: I mean it begins with like bringing a wooden donkey to life, right?
Speaker 0: So come on You don't even know the name of that donkey cuz that you did.
Speaker 0: you ever watch the second Wizard of Oz movie?
Speaker 1: The donkey in this comic, what did they call it?
Speaker 1: Let me get to the page doesn't matter In the meta moment.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, they bring a pumpkin head guy to life first then a donkey.
Speaker 0: Yep Anyway, the geek nights book club book the murder about Diaries.
Speaker 0: I have read for murder about Diaries.
Speaker 1: I have read every published murder bot diary including it the two things that were published like on the internet like no one.
Speaker 1: one was in Wired magazine and what which was Sort of like a same universe kind of you know, whatever.
Speaker 1: and then oh, no, the Wired magazine one was like a side story and the.
Speaker 1: There was another one that was in a short story Anthology that I got a PDF of.
Speaker 1: and I've read just that short story from the anthology that was Level of the Prince of Nothing.
Speaker 0: and then there's the atrocity tales.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like two of these random.
Speaker 1: You don't need to read those but I read them Every published murder bot diary thing.
Speaker 1: and then I saw the first book in a airport bookstore that I didn't on the you know The shelf of first volumes of things.
Speaker 0: so we'll give you all time.
Speaker 1: Read it read a bunch of murder bot Diaries read as many as you can But the bar is all of them because they're that easy to read.
Speaker 0: Yeah So far, you know pretty good though I read the fun.
Speaker 0: I read the third one before I read the second one because my Kindle sorted them weird And it actually didn't.
Speaker 1: I thought I had written read.
Speaker 1: So when I read the newest one the one that was published most recently I thought I had gotten the order wrong, but I did not.
Speaker 1: actually the third large the large one is the second most recent one and then okay final one.
Speaker 1: actually the Chronologically takes place prior to the large one but was published after the large one.
Speaker 0: but it's basically about an aliens kind of universe where a a Robocop situation has occurred and occurs that scale and that's just a thing that society does and one of the Robocops Really doesn't want to do its job and just wants to watch Netflix and then slowly Interacts with things.
Speaker 1: How about since we've read since we raised the bar so high so quickly Why don't we do this?
Speaker 1: the new one comes out in November?
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's do the book club then All right, but the new one will hit in November.
Speaker 1: coming in November At least that's what I think is gonna happen.
Speaker 0: Also The Emily Wilson Iliad, oh god, I feel like we got to pause the book club and do a special book club.
Speaker 0: I'm at.
Speaker 1: it comes out in two weeks.
Speaker 0: I'm real pumped about that.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: There was a. there was a piece with her in the New Yorker.
Speaker 0: Yes now I still.
Speaker 0: I still think about that Odyssey translation and how it like really changed how I viewed the Odyssey.
Speaker 1: Yep, so that's that.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Also we were of course at PAX West 2023 and we did a panel That was actually a brand new panel to an extent that Scott would not disagree that it was an entirely new panel.
Speaker 1: I Cannot disagree.
Speaker 1: That was a new panel.
Speaker 0: I think it was a pretty good pet.
Speaker 1: I was still some content of things that we always say because we always say the things we always say, you know What.
Speaker 0: I don't think it was a very realistic at any point.
Speaker 1: I don't think we did because it wasn't about that It was not.
Speaker 0: whoa, we've entered a new way.
Speaker 0: This is the first time in at least seven years We've done any panel where the word heuristic does not come up at least once.
Speaker 1: Well, you put the word there.
Speaker 0: I'm for because it's a really good word But games you can't play is on YouTube.
Speaker 0: We have a new pipeline to make high quality videos of our panels pretty quickly now with this equipment that we've got.
Speaker 0: It was also the first packs that we went to where we could do a panel not in masks full production value Kind of like normal and you can just watch it.
Speaker 0: It's on YouTube.
Speaker 0: I uploaded it and we filled the room so a bunch of people got turned away.
Speaker 0: So if you didn't see this panel in person Guess what.
Speaker 0: several people who didn't wanted to see it in person at PAX didn't get to see it in person.
Speaker 1: and we fun side Story.
Speaker 1: we discussed briefly sim refinery in the panel and immediately after the panel one of the people who came up after the panel said Truthfully, they had worked for Maxis on sim refinery.
Speaker 0: man I go off to take my camera apart and someone starts telling me about their vampire tag Which was cool and I come it over to this.
Speaker 1: that person also told me about their vampire tag.
Speaker 1: I'm coming up to stage like I found something they said in some church and I ignored them.
Speaker 1: Yeah Sorry, if that person became a geek that's it.
Speaker 1: But then you know, that's the kind of people we are here at geek nights.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I come over like I tell Scott I met someone who knew a thing and then Scott's like yeah sim refinery guy Hey, and I'm like fuck you win.
Speaker 1: Last thing the geek night's website, you know, you're probably like whatever but guess what that shit is Actually imminent like we are getting.
Speaker 1: we can need like one more patch of some bug fixes and is it done?
Speaker 1: No, is it releasable?
Speaker 1: Is it?
Speaker 1: does it do what the cart website does and is it better?
Speaker 1: Yes, therefore we should replace the current website with it and then continue to work on it Which will be much easier because it is written with modern up-to-date software So and has a CI pipeline and all this stuff that makes it very easy to work on Once we get it released.
Speaker 1: So it is going to be launched and open-sourced on github and you can actually send you know Poll requests - if you want to help work on it, you won't get credit or money other than the git log message, but You know, you can come help if you want to if there's features you want, you know, whatever and we're gonna sometime soon When we get a chance, we're gonna like sit down You know put it up get it perfect verify that it's correct enough and then move the DNS.
Speaker 1: and that's that.
Speaker 1: It's fine the old page the old websites in the Internet Archive and I also have backups of it.
Speaker 1: So it will not be lost historically.
Speaker 1: But the new website will replace it and all the URLs to my knowledge will continue to work At least the URLs to our website.
Speaker 1: No one's leaving our website.
Speaker 1: Most of those don't work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we know that.
Speaker 0: That's a blame capitalism for ruining the internet.
Speaker 1: for that one if you could find instant when once it goes up one thing you could Do to help is if there is links that point at front row crew comm slash something that no longer function properly.
Speaker 1: If you let me know that's like the highest urgency.
Speaker 0: as long as one of us lives We will try to make sure every link we've ever posted to our fucking website works.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's right That's.
Speaker 1: the highest urgency is to make sure the cool URLs don't change right and I don't believe that any of them do So.
Speaker 1: that's gonna happen soon.
Speaker 0: ish You may remember starting around 2008 when we saw and even before then but 2008 when we went to a PAX There was a time when women's god of geek nights went to a lot of conventions.
Speaker 0: Not a lot of taxes not a lot of gaming cons.
Speaker 1: I'm talking like a lot of conventions We would not just you know, we were going to enemy Boston.
Speaker 1: We would go to Connecticut.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right MagFest Which we're gonna go to again probably.
Speaker 1: Yeah We get.
Speaker 1: we also had some tiny conventions here and there.
Speaker 1: right, you know, we went back to RIT for you know The city con sometime I went to like an amazement even went to some Torah cons.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's right.
Speaker 1: That's what was called Torah con.
Speaker 1: Sitacon was the one we went to one time one time and never again.
Speaker 0: I don't think.
Speaker 0: I think it only happened one time.
Speaker 1: I think it also did only happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah we go to a lot of conventions and also we did eat nice four nights a week and We would review and talk about uber cons, yeah every convention we went to.
Speaker 0: I have a list of every panel We've ever done.
Speaker 0: There's like 400 panels okay, so we used to review conventions quite a bit and Then PAX has appeared and we started going to.
Speaker 0: PAX is one we stopped going to most other cons and two we would do like a Before PAX show and then a PAX show and then I'll post pack.
Speaker 0: should we do like mold?
Speaker 1: That was because we'd never been to the packs before.
Speaker 1: we never go to Seattle before right?
Speaker 1: We had a lot to say.
Speaker 1: a lot was going on comparing to other cons Done enough.
Speaker 1: It's like you're just gonna repeat yourself from the previous one, right?
Speaker 0: 2018 a decade of going to PAX is what new could we possibly have to say about a convention?
Speaker 0: convention center?
Speaker 1: They don't change that much year to year and even when they do all you have to talk about is the things that changed.
Speaker 1: There's no point in reiterating the parts that didn't change.
Speaker 0: Yep, but a couple things happen.
Speaker 0: So one There was a dark time, you know there's a global pandemic and a lot of people died and a lot of things didn't happen and We weren't going to conventions.
Speaker 0: and even when conventions started up again There was still a good year where conventions were happening, but they weren't the same.
Speaker 0: They weren't they were.
Speaker 1: inventions have not yet fully recovered.
Speaker 1: Oh, they have not ended.
Speaker 1: the they're not.
Speaker 1: the PAX West to my knowledge did not sell out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there were there were.
Speaker 1: there was a. we went into the you know to get our pick up our badges at the will call And there was a line for buying badges at the door something I had I do not recall seeing.
Speaker 1: I don't recall seeing that at any point between the years 2009 and I saw somebody walk up and I saw someone walk up and buy one.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, but this was the first
Speaker 0: PAX that did not require masks and that was widely like heavily attended
Speaker 1: the dark time
Speaker 0: up since the dark time and simultaneously the second thing that happened
Speaker 1: Seattle
Speaker 0: during the dark time built a new Convention Center because that old Convention Center was not big enough for PAX and hadn't been for a long time.
Speaker 0: So this was a the first PAX coming out of the dark time in a brand new Convention Center and a significantly updated format.
Speaker 0: Additionally, it was the first fax in a long time where the keynote was like S-tier.
Speaker 0: I will wait in line for this.
Speaker 0: I am NOT missing this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly, and it felt a lot like old PAX is for a lot of reasons.
Speaker 0: So I think it's time to review what PAX West 2023 was like because it is in many ways very different from the previous Decade of PAX's.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So The map of PAX that is new Convention Center, which was called they renamed all the different buildings.
Speaker 1: No We got used to be it used right used to be.
Speaker 1: there was the Convention Center and then there was the annex which is built Across the street from the Convention Center.
Speaker 0: around the time that we went to the first pack like that And it was brand new and unfurnished and tabletop was in there.
Speaker 0: in like this in 2008.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was in like this let us in there, but it was concrete.
Speaker 1: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 1: So 2009 2010 is when the annex was like done done and that they added the sky bridge to connect the two.
Speaker 1: Yeah So then it's you know PAX was using the convention center the annex and various buildings around the town.
Speaker 1: the Hyatt hotels the Sheraton Hotel the Benaroya Hall the the Paramount Theatre.
Speaker 1: Right all were part of PAX in different years.
Speaker 0: packs would be spread out across these various buildings More and more and more and getting more and more distributed like a lot of nerd cons are that we don't go to.
Speaker 1: Yep, so now they have renamed.
Speaker 1: They have a new building.
Speaker 1: The new building is like a block away.
Speaker 1: It's on the other side of the Paramount Theatre on the other side of the highway.
Speaker 1: It's a big tall building.
Speaker 1: It's like what?
Speaker 1: five five four god.
Speaker 0: Yeah, plus that basement.
Speaker 0: it I mean, I'll just straight up.
Speaker 0: it is I Don't know it's not.
Speaker 0: I can't say that it's the best Convention Center in the world or even in America But I think it's a tall rectangle.
Speaker 0: It is the best Convention Center.
Speaker 0: I Have experience with that.
Speaker 0: I can think of like.
Speaker 0: I got a really good convention centers Like packs.
Speaker 0: Australia is in a fantastic fucking Convention Center, but it's not better than this one, right?
Speaker 1: It's like I think.
Speaker 1: I look I think about the building on its own and I'm like, is this some building that amazes me?
Speaker 1: Wow, it's like.
Speaker 1: no, it's it's a. it's a good place, right?
Speaker 1: But then I'm like, well, let's look at all the other convention centers.
Speaker 1: I know is it better than the Javits?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Everything's better.
Speaker 1: Is it?
Speaker 1: is it better than the Gaylord?
Speaker 1: Fuck?
Speaker 1: Yes, it's better than the Gaylord, right?
Speaker 1: Is it better than the Connecticut one?
Speaker 1: The Connecticut one's pretty good, but this is bigger and better.
Speaker 0: Actually, I'd say a top-tier Convention Center limited only by being in Connecticut and being relatively small.
Speaker 0: They think it only have like a thousand person con, right?
Speaker 1: Is it better than the Heinz and the BCEC?
Speaker 1: Yes, and yes, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like.
Speaker 1: it's like I think about it and it's like I can't really you know Say that it's this amazing.
Speaker 1: Perfect.
Speaker 1: Wonderful place, but it's better than the other ones.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right And I think.
Speaker 1: but it's also brand new so, you know.
Speaker 0: But it's partly it's following modern design like contemporary design not modern.
Speaker 0: Oh, yes convention centers particularly in that I Guess to review it one.
Speaker 0: It has more sunlight than you would ever expect a convention center to have.
Speaker 1: somehow the gem only the basement only the basement was dark.
Speaker 0: Some sunlight access in that entryway because of those pits and the and the light wells.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's that's true.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: And This is even considering.
Speaker 0: the Javits is basically all glass yet somehow even the parts is a job.
Speaker 0: It's the Javits is dark in full sunlight through glass somehow.
Speaker 0: I guess it's just your soul leaving your body is what happens there, but it's also.
Speaker 0: there are no Choke points for crowds anywhere like.
Speaker 0: I have not seen places other than like professional sporting arenas Designed to such a degree to avoid human choke points.
Speaker 1: It was well, I was reminded this weekend that we have not been to the Chicago Convention Center, which is apparently enormous.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was I remember heavily suggesting two packs when they were talking about a new packs.
Speaker 0: It should be in the Midwest and Cobo I.
Speaker 1: Anyway, we haven't been to the San Diego one either.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 0: So but anyway, yep, it has Multiple sets of gigantic wide stairs and escalators and none of them broke down.
Speaker 1: It has a brand new.
Speaker 1: they better not fucking break down.
Speaker 0: It has a wide mix of different lots of bathrooms of spaces that all work Like they're just.
Speaker 0: it's a really wide variety of spaces small rooms big rooms high ceiling rooms Dividable rooms undivideable room and it's so big.
Speaker 0: packs Has some room to grow.
Speaker 0: there was a lot of space packs didn't even use and it has the thing.
Speaker 0: But I think the only other convention center I've ever been in that has an equivalent amount of this was the BCC in Baltimore.
Speaker 0: It has a ton of dead space that is not usable for like events Like.
Speaker 0: you can't have panels or events in it But it's there to absorb the crowd Tons of places for people just to hang out sit down do a cosplay photo shoot be out of the way.
Speaker 0: That is something that most conventional centers actually don't have right.
Speaker 1: if none of those areas were as far as cosplay friendly as the gazebo of the Gaylord but There were it was.
Speaker 1: they had much more square footage of those kinds of space.
Speaker 0: and I if you listen to geek night circuit like 2006 we would talk a lot about why the BCC was such a good convention center for Otacon.
Speaker 0: because it had all that dead.
Speaker 1: There's a fount that had the fountain area Otter Bean Lobby Yep.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So that's the building now.
Speaker 1: packs itself was mostly in that's new summit building but Half of the expo hall was in the basement of the summit and the other half was in the arch which was the annex Right.
Speaker 1: the original convention center contained zero packs.
Speaker 1: that right No packs was in the original convention center.
Speaker 1: There was however Nintendo live in the original convention center.
Speaker 1: We did not attend Nintendo live.
Speaker 1: We didn't get tickets to it.
Speaker 1: We don't go to it.
Speaker 1: from what I heard is that a There were a lot of lines even if you got tickets to it.
Speaker 1: be like there wasn't much content there, right?
Speaker 1: It was sort of like going to an in a big fancy Nintendo booth.
Speaker 1: There's some merch sales You know, there was some eSports tournaments going on there.
Speaker 1: But I think a lot a lot of people were generally not too excited about it, you know They would go to it see it and be like, alright, that's enough.
Speaker 1: Even the kind of people who like that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah But that's just the gist.
Speaker 1: I got that second third hand knowledge.
Speaker 1: I suggest if you care about how was Nintendo live good?
Speaker 1: because maybe you're thinking about.
Speaker 1: should you go To another Nintendo live event in the future, you know put forth the effort for that.
Speaker 1: You'll want to get the opinion of someone who was actually in there which was not us.
Speaker 0: Yep Nor is it for us, but no had we got over there?
Speaker 0: I was there.
Speaker 1: are people right there are?
Speaker 1: I am seeing online a lot of chatter Among the kind of person who cares a lot about the expo hall there were.
Speaker 1: some people were upset That it was split between the two places.
Speaker 0: I think we write the same reddit post where half the comments of people like dude.
Speaker 0: It's like right there.
Speaker 0: How is this?
Speaker 1: it was just right there?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but all I've also seen though Exhibitors, this is a real concern right?
Speaker 1: some exhibitors are like, you know They see the how many people are coming through and they're thinking shit.
Speaker 1: Am I in the wrong one, right?
Speaker 1: Should I have gotten a booth on the other half?
Speaker 1: right now is everyone in the other half and it's like.
Speaker 1: you might think The basement one was the hot one or you might but no but wait the annex one had the big companies in it, right?
Speaker 1: Maybe that's the hot one and it's like if you're working all day in one Right and then it closes they both close at the same time.
Speaker 1: You don't really see the other one You don't know.
Speaker 1: you might think shit.
Speaker 1: is my booth in the wrong, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know and like we said the attendance was down overall.
Speaker 1: So it's like.
Speaker 1: that's why you weren't seeing people, right?
Speaker 1: I think people were going to both.
Speaker 1: Yeah, some people were upset about it being completely split up into two things like that Because if you think about it in every previous packs even the ones that were super spread out the expo hall was always one contiguous space and So expo hall people would go to one place and that was it.
Speaker 1: They haven't had to move around now.
Speaker 0: great Is that one space was sprawling like you'd go over into the X. there were like shit where the Chessex booth used to be.
Speaker 1: Chessex booth was not there at all period as upsetting.
Speaker 1: Anyway, not that I need to dice.
Speaker 0: Always walk by the dice and look at him and think dice.
Speaker 1: That's what I do.
Speaker 1: So anyway, they'll be it unplugged.
Speaker 1: I bet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, come on.
Speaker 1: But the fact that packs was effectively all in one all the things that weren't the expo hall were entirely in the new building.
Speaker 1: Oh, except for the PC freeplay byo PC VR.
Speaker 1: that was in the annex also Oh and the merch booth.
Speaker 1: the merch booth is in the annex, which sorry arch it changes name to art.
Speaker 0: It was particularly fine because byo PC is almost like this.
Speaker 0: It's like a there's a velvet rope and it's its own thing.
Speaker 0: So it's actually that's one of the best possible things to put in the out-of-the-way space Because you can't go into it if you're not doing it.
Speaker 0: and if you're doing it you're hanging out there.
Speaker 0: It's like I'm just like your luxury box.
Speaker 0: So I guess packs Did suffer in my opinion as it had expanded into a bunch of venues because it reduced the cross Pollination like in the in the packs West.
Speaker 0: up until the dark times There was definitely this vibe that like when the years when tabletop was in the hotel by itself Tabletop people really only went there and didn't go anywhere else and all the people who were anywhere else Never came to tabletop.
Speaker 0: like it was almost like two different conventions The fact that everything was in the same room or in the same building.
Speaker 0: This is one of the first packs I've been to in a long time where when I wandered around the con I saw a lot of areas.
Speaker 0: all had a pretty good number of people hanging around in them and walking through.
Speaker 0: There was a lot of discovery.
Speaker 0: I found some things I didn't notice on the schedule just walking around.
Speaker 0: that Cross-pollination was the magic of when packs was smaller and fit entirely within the old convention center and they brought it back.
Speaker 1: Yep All right.
Speaker 1: So other things that were going down at packs.
Speaker 1: it had all the usual things that a packs has right steel battalion guy.
Speaker 1: He was there right, but they added some new stuff, right?
Speaker 1: They added the.
Speaker 1: there's this guy.
Speaker 1: He was thing of the day.
Speaker 1: once this guy he's collecting artifacts of Super Nintendo most the artwork and you know physical artifacts that were used in or photographed or included in Super Nintendo Super Nintendo Power magazine right and that guy who I had seen on the internet and made a thing of the day brought his collection to packs and had a whole room where he set it all up so everyone could enjoy it and he could share it because that's That guy is the eye.
Speaker 1: if you want to be a collector That's the guy you want to be right.
Speaker 1: be like that guy where you collect for the sake of sharing and having everyone.
Speaker 0: He's not a collector.
Speaker 0: He's a curator.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: He made his own basically like actual.
Speaker 1: he's doing it the way I'm using.
Speaker 1: He's one guy.
Speaker 1: All right, so That was awesome to actually see that stuff in person and out the guy who I'd seen on the internet and he had a whole Room to himself.
Speaker 1: people were lining up to see it.
Speaker 1: Good thing.
Speaker 1: We saw it right away didn't have to wait in a line Because it was less crowded on Friday when we saw it.
Speaker 1: packs was more crowded the other days.
Speaker 1: What else was going?
Speaker 1: oh the Alexandria tabletop RPG library was there.
Speaker 1: they had been there before But they had the best setup they've had yet, right?
Speaker 1: They had like a whole room going on.
Speaker 0: I was a big room and that's sort of a theme all the spaces that used to be crammed into like half Or a quarter of a panel room in the old boxes.
Speaker 0: They basically had big rooms with exterior windows and sunlight and plenty of space to do their thing.
Speaker 1: Yep, there was a room with like an actual arcade in it, but I think they could have put that in a bigger room.
Speaker 0: I think that was but it was the best arcade that's ever been at a PAX.
Speaker 1: Any pack of the of the PAX is that I have been to.
Speaker 1: that is the best arcade out of packs obvious.
Speaker 1: It was like someone cut out like.
Speaker 1: I took like one machine from every section of the magfest arcade Yeah, and put them into like one tiny room.
Speaker 0: I said you your machines because there were two at a pack that never thought I'd see a DDR machine at a PAX Yeah, and there were two there.
Speaker 1: It's like they had a little row of you know, the Japanese sit-down ones.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was like there's like a pinball one pinball some rhythm guys, you know It was.
Speaker 1: it was decent.
Speaker 1: There was some fun times in there, but it was also small cramped dark smelly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's an arcade warm really warm in there.
Speaker 0: I think it and Tabletop freeplay needed more space.
Speaker 1: I did not spend much time in there But I looked at the selection and I said that is quality.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I even spent some time in classic console.
Speaker 0: I got about halfway through Castlevania 1 while I was waiting for Like.
Speaker 1: I played some non duck hunt like gun.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah the balloon game.
Speaker 0: Yeah Tabletop had a fantastic space.
Speaker 0: It just wasn't big enough.
Speaker 0: like you could find tables on all the days, but Saturday.
Speaker 0: But it was actually completely full on Saturday.
Speaker 1: Yep, the way they set it up was they put all the freeplay tables in the middle and they surrounded it with vendors all around The edge which was all right kind of clever.
Speaker 0: But you know subject to change the packs arena had not been there and it had encompassed that entire space.
Speaker 0: I think it would have been about big enough based on that crowd.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah That would have been more than big enough.
Speaker 0: I think right I don't know if that would be big enough for a fully realized sold-out packs, but it would definitely been enough for that packs sure Yeah, and you know tabletop was its usual self right.
Speaker 1: free plays You know first looks turn of.
Speaker 1: everything was going down as usual, right?
Speaker 0: We even entered a tournament.
Speaker 1: Let's tell the story of the tournament.
Speaker 0: Oh god.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was just quickly.
Speaker 1: So cat in the box is a little trick-taking game cute little trick-taking game.
Speaker 1: We've did an episode on it that you can listen to.
Speaker 0: we both think really good at it.
Speaker 1: There's a cat and I think I'm pretty good at it.
Speaker 1: Then there was a cat in the box tournament.
Speaker 1: on the schedule, right?
Speaker 1: And I'm like, hey, we should enter that cat in the box tournament.
Speaker 1: And as long as it's it's only a 16 person tournament four games of four people each.
Speaker 1: Each of all the four winners play each other in one gate.
Speaker 1: You only have to play two games of cat in the box.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's not a big time investment.
Speaker 1: And if you lose the first game, you only have to play one game of cat in the box.
Speaker 1: It's like such a small time investment.
Speaker 1: we love this game.
Speaker 1: Let's just go do it.
Speaker 1: We went early.
Speaker 1: we got tickets to be in the tournament, you know Cuz only 16 people can enter.
Speaker 1: we came back after our panel.
Speaker 1: We entered the tournament.
Speaker 0: I was surprised that of the 16 people Most of the people had not played cat like I think me Scott and like two other people literally Had ever played the game before and everyone else didn't need like had knew nothing about it and expected to be taught.
Speaker 1: Right, it's like all right.
Speaker 1: who enters a tournament not knowing how to play the game?
Speaker 0: apparently almost everyone, right?
Speaker 1: But at the second on the other hand, it's like that's totally fine.
Speaker 1: It's like I'm cool with that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know a funny situation because they actually didn't really have enough enforcers to teach like at scale me and Scott.
Speaker 1: Everyone had to play like that.
Speaker 0: We both taught everyone between the two of us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so in the first game I played right.
Speaker 1: it was two people who didn't know how to play at a person who did know Same as my first game.
Speaker 1: And so I played and I was a. there was one.
Speaker 1: the one person who didn't know how to play was asking lots of questions.
Speaker 1: Right, the person who didn't know how to play was pro and the other person didn't know how to play.
Speaker 1: They understood the rules explanation perfectly.
Speaker 1: They played perfectly correctly.
Speaker 1: They did not play.
Speaker 1: Well, no person who was asking all kinds of questions all the time and act and like you thought they didn't know what the hell They were doing and they were playing poorly.
Speaker 1: They played extremely.
Speaker 1: Well, they were dominating.
Speaker 1: The person who was pro was playing as well as they could.
Speaker 1: they had this the worst luck after game one.
Speaker 1: They're just like after the second and third hands.
Speaker 1: They were just they had such bad luck They would have won.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because they played like the best I've seen like.
Speaker 1: they probably played better than I did honestly.
Speaker 1: And then me I played average with my conservative play and I got lucky in game four and I won by one point.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so how did?
Speaker 1: how did your first game so mine?
Speaker 0: Similarly?
Speaker 0: I had two people who had never played before.
Speaker 0: one person who?
Speaker 0: Expressed constant annoyance that nobody knew how to play in the tournament and like I expected to play with pros or police people who know What they're doing and he was kind of mad about it.
Speaker 0: And then me the guy who knew how to play and seems to really want to win.
Speaker 0: He failed and caused the paradox two out of the four rounds.
Speaker 1: Like he just I made one paradox, but it was a zero.
Speaker 1: so I was fine.
Speaker 0: Yep He crashed and burned into dust like it was.
Speaker 0: it was awful to watch.
Speaker 0: of the two people who had not played One of them the person who won and I lie.
Speaker 0: He beat me by one point.
Speaker 0: I Learned afterward.
Speaker 0: He had never played cat in the box, but this was a trick-taking game person.
Speaker 0: So I feel okay about that.
Speaker 0: But also I think it's noteworthy.
Speaker 0: I think we found broadly where the limits of skill are in cat in the box in that the scores were also closed despite This wide range of player skills.
Speaker 0: There is a lot of luck in cat in the box.
Speaker 0: You got to play a lot as a lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah to tease out pure skill The box.
Speaker 1: yeah this weekend that weekend I really unlocked and I feel like I have I won't say I've solved cat in the box.
Speaker 0: Oh coming into the final game.
Speaker 1: I've got it locked.
Speaker 0: I've got it locked down coming into the final hand in my round.
Speaker 0: I came into it up by like six points and I paradoxed Solely because of the hand I had like.
Speaker 0: there was no way out of that.
Speaker 1: But that happens.
Speaker 1: So I'm in the finals and we want we purposely played in separate games in the first round and hopes To take half of the seats in the final just like what happened with sir.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's right, but that did not happen.
Speaker 1: I went to the finals alone All right, and I this were me the person that beat rim another person.
Speaker 1: We're all sitting there chatting having a good time.
Speaker 1: They seemed like nice people, right?
Speaker 1: We're waiting for the fourth game to end.
Speaker 1: apparently in the fourth game There was five players.
Speaker 1: I think as they'd let an extra person in so that game was weird, right?
Speaker 1: And they were also taking a long time Which had me nervous that maybe one of the players over there was a slowpoke and I didn't really want to play with some slowpoke, right.
Speaker 1: Hopefully a fast person from over there won.
Speaker 1: So anyway, a person comes over finally from the fifth from the fourth and final game to play in the finals with us.
Speaker 1: They seemed chill.
Speaker 1: They were actually the partner of the pro cool person who should have won but was very unlucky in my first game.
Speaker 1: So I saw I was like, oh, this is great.
Speaker 1: It was not some shitty person that Came over.
Speaker 1: Well So we start playing right and everything's going great.
Speaker 1: and we're not.
Speaker 1: we're in the first hand like the third trick, right and The.
Speaker 1: the person to my left who may I think was the person that beat rim Points out that the person who was the the partner of the pro person right the last person to come over.
Speaker 1: He's like, hey, you only have four cars in your hand and everyone else has six and I'm like, oh who cares?
Speaker 1: It's I'm like, let's just start over.
Speaker 1: We just started two seconds ago, right?
Speaker 1: But we want to make sure the game is correct, right, you know Like.
Speaker 0: there's no way to recover from that kind of error in a card game, right?
Speaker 1: It's like all these cards are face down and hidden information like cards that we discarded at the start of the game.
Speaker 1: It's like we can't be looking at them trying to figure out which card went where right?
Speaker 1: It's like we can't be letting someone look at any card that's face down on the table.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: So it's like That you know, we can't like correct this without some asterisk bullshit.
Speaker 1: Let's just restart.
Speaker 1: We'll all have a fair game.
Speaker 1: It's just a cat in the box tournament at who gives a shit.
Speaker 1: It's like let's just restart right?
Speaker 1: and the guy the partner of the pro person was like no No, no, I could fix this.
Speaker 1: we could fix this.
Speaker 1: Let's figure it out, right?
Speaker 1: We can figure this out and I'm like, why do we need to figure?
Speaker 1: it's like we just started.
Speaker 1: What do you?
Speaker 1: why do you want to figure it out so bad, right?
Speaker 1: It's like we can't.
Speaker 1: I'm like just just chill out and we'll restart.
Speaker 1: and he's like no no no No, we could.
Speaker 1: we can definitely fix this.
Speaker 1: he starts trying to fix it and I'm like Why don't we just vote on it then if there's a disagreement, right?
Speaker 1: Let's let's have these other two people decide.
Speaker 1: we've already basically decided and he's like you're only voting to restart cuz I'm winning And I'm like, it's this is three tricks in to a four hand game.
Speaker 1: And I'm just like.
Speaker 0: I just stood up and I said I forfeit by which I think was the right call because that not only does this prove that you in fact were not advocating for this because you thought this guy was winning but it also Forces the correct outcome.
Speaker 0: anyway restart the game, right?
Speaker 1: It's like if though if the remaining people wanted to continue playing they're now forced to restart.
Speaker 1: So it's like I didn't care about winning.
Speaker 1: and not only didn't I care about winning?
Speaker 1: I definitely didn't want to play three more hands or four more hands of cat in the box with that guy.
Speaker 0: So I don't know if the game continued.
Speaker 0: I suspect I don't know either.
Speaker 0: I suspect the other players also forfeit or just gave up or were like like walked away because I Walked over like when I called over the enforcer I forfeited and it got up and I left before the officer got there.
Speaker 0: So I like.
Speaker 0: I went to pee after my game was over and then I like chatted at the table You're waiting for game to start and I walked away to do something else.
Speaker 0: I came back like
Speaker 1: pretty quick
Speaker 0: because I wanted to watch like the last hand and Based on how long I know cat in the box takes the game should have still been going and the table was empty and I Was just like wow either Scott just wiped the floor with them.
Speaker 0: I just assumed that you would like crush them or something.
Speaker 0: And then I come over and you're like.
Speaker 0: so I got a story.
Speaker 1: I guy came in last place in the finals I forfeited.
Speaker 1: It's like I could have done worse but I feel like you know, I mean I could.
Speaker 1: the alternative right was I could have sat there and been like I could have forfeited and Barrated the guy right and been like I am leaving because I don't want to play Three hands of cat in the box of the shitty person like you right, but that's only gonna get.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: They're not gonna do that at PAX, right?
Speaker 1: There's something out, you know You know, I just got up and forfeited and like bye Right see geek night's panel on quitting, right?
Speaker 1: It's like If it was this.
Speaker 1: and the thing is if it was a super if it was that guy was taking it way too seriously Right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if I was taking that tournament as seriously as that guy one you're in the right and two That's when the judge comes over and you raise your complaint, right?
Speaker 0: And there's well.
Speaker 1: the thing is I wouldn't have been if I was taking the tournament seriously.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't have been calling for a reset.
Speaker 1: I would have been calling for them to be disqualified.
Speaker 1: They fucked something up.
Speaker 1: They had four cards in the head.
Speaker 1: They should be disqualified.
Speaker 1: It's a super serious business, right?
Speaker 1: and you messed up.
Speaker 1: you're gone right.
Speaker 1: if it was like a magic tournament and I get the start of the hand like the other guy has like two cards instead Of the number he's supposed to I just make judge disqualify this guy and give him a loss at least right.
Speaker 1: MIT forced to forfeit.
Speaker 1: Right, because if it's a serious tournament, so it's like I didn't even go there with that guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because it was a non serious tournament like calm down Nobody in history if that game had completed.
Speaker 1: no one in history will remember or care who won cat in the box at PAX West.
Speaker 1: So that's another story.
Speaker 1: to help you with your gaming tournament.
Speaker 1: Behavior code I guess so.
Speaker 1: etiquette.
Speaker 0: I think we've gone on long enough.
Speaker 1: We got this.
Speaker 1: we gave you like three geek nights worth episode only one show this week.
Speaker 1: because of this Guys we didn't do.
Speaker 1: we just did a huge geek nights today.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and next week I think a lot we had a lot to go on.
Speaker 1: we could have.
Speaker 1: you know I could have just not told any of these things and held on to them and then forgotten them and they never be in a Geek night.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but now they are.
Speaker 0: so yeah that I don't know what it is about our brains.
Speaker 0: But geek dies.
Speaker 0: what it's like my buffer gets cleared.
Speaker 0: every time we do a show the cash is gone.
Speaker 1: Sakurai just an episode about that on his little YouTube channel.
Speaker 0: Oh I'll send it to you because I remember reading that the the doom door study of When you go there's a door.
Speaker 0: Yeah when you go through door similar but different.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you kind of forget the context of what was going on on the other side of that door.
Speaker 1: Yep all right, so Pax is coming back.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: The question is will the people come back enough to fill it the way they did before Without the huge triple-a industry presence?
Speaker 0: because I gotta say this level of crowdedness at a PAX Regardless of how healthy that is for PAX and the industry and the future of like these conventions?
Speaker 0: as an attendee This this was one of the better packs as I've ever been to like.
Speaker 0: it felt like yeah 2008 2009 2010.
Speaker 0: PAX West like it was here an expo hall Aficionado.
Speaker 1: you'd be disappointed right?
Speaker 1: there weren't that many big booths worth going to for triple even though for me This was a great expo hall.
Speaker 0: I saw a game.
Speaker 1: I saw.
Speaker 1: I saw a bunch of cool indie games.
Speaker 1: Not too many I could have seen would have been nice to see more But I saw enough to wish list on Steam and then take business cards from and write down in my notes and then leave And that was enough right?
Speaker 1: I need more than that.
Speaker 1: But if you're looking for more than that, you would have been disappointed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you want to wait in line if you were the average Pax East you would have hated this PAX West because one thing about this PAX West Tabletop was pretty full until the close.
Speaker 0: every night PAX East like is empty after the expo hall closes.
Speaker 1: Uh Well, I mean guess now, you know, there are times where it's hard to get a table at PAX East.
Speaker 0: Yeah but generally our out like within an hour or two after the expo hall closing at PAX East.
Speaker 0: because Almost everyone who goes to PAX East in our experience is one-day badge people.
Speaker 0: PAX East kind of just empties out at night.
Speaker 1: Hmm The tabletop zone does not which is where I work and you're also working.
Speaker 1: so you don't see it then.
Speaker 1: but that's you know It.
Speaker 1: basically it is it facing when the expo hall closes from like six to you know Eight nine.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: it's like this There's like this prime time where it's full but then when it gets later not everyone's in there till midnight.
Speaker 1: So when you start to get into like nine ten eleven twelve is when you'll get one walk like anywhere else in the con And it's just crickets.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah the rest of the con though.
Speaker 0: Yeah That's this has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand.
Speaker 1: Okay for the logos be sure to visit our website at front row crew dot-com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: and the patreon patreons for this episode of geek nights are Alan Joyce Linky G dread Lily Tenebrae case care makes music Chris Haddad Clinton Walton Dex thing Joel Hayes penny runs with Rebecca Dunn Sam Erickson Shervin Von Harl and a bunch of people who give us like a dollar I assume to get access to that sweet patreon RSS feed.
Speaker 0: so yeah unity shat itself and We haven't done a show for a bunch of reasons.
Speaker 0: We're not gonna do any more shows this week.
Speaker 0: So next week, we're gonna get back to a Tuesday Thursday and you might notice we did a Tuesday this week doing another Tuesday next week because we have decided that whenever we don't have a Great show idea.
Speaker 0: We're gonna swap the days around a little bit.
Speaker 0: But anyway for now, I'll just leave you with style brand new style.