Speaker 1: it's Monday April 10th 2023.
Speaker 1: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight we're talking about fonts from a technology standpoint.
Speaker 0: let's do this.
Speaker 0: it's finally not cold.
Speaker 1: oh my god.
Speaker 1: I biked to work this morning.
Speaker 1: I biked home just now.
Speaker 0: I thought it was.
Speaker 0: I looked at the weather reports.
Speaker 0: I thought Wednesday was going to be the day but it moved up and out Tuesday.
Speaker 0: I mean it was cold this morning but it's now not cold and it looks like even it even tonight.
Speaker 0: the low is that it says 59 so that's only a little cold.
Speaker 1: well it's fascinating to me is you'll notice if you go back to I bet if you go back to old geek nights episodes you hear us talk about the weather because you warm.
Speaker 1: today was.
Speaker 1: it was a geek nights meme for a reason.
Speaker 1: so about five years ago the climate in New York kind of had a radical sudden shift and I think this this this spring has been exactly what the last three springs have been and not how they used to be.
Speaker 1: where we have winter and then when spring starts spring is basically now in New York it's just like three weeks of radically shifting weather and then it's suddenly summer.
Speaker 1: it's like it'll be 70 degrees 40 75 40 80 20 and then it'll like settle into upper 70s.
Speaker 0: it says the high on Thursday and Friday will be 82 and 85. it's like all right you know anyway but actual non-weather open a bit.
Speaker 0: so we're sitting around this past weekend no plans whatsoever and I'm like I don't really want to sit inside all day even though it's a little bit cold.
Speaker 0: right let's you know I'm in New York City.
Speaker 0: there should be something to do right?
Speaker 0: I did should not be challenging to find something to do and I was like.
Speaker 0: you know I'm looking around and I'm like oh I saw on the subway there were some ads for something at the Brooklyn Museum some fashion guy right you know and it was like you probably seen them like this picture of a bug lady.
Speaker 0: oh yeah yeah yeah.
Speaker 0: and I was like hey let's do you want?
Speaker 0: you want to just go?
Speaker 0: maybe we went over there and basically there was a person I guess I don't know how to pronounce their name properly Darry Moogler.
Speaker 0: I guess it's t-h-i-e-r-r-y space m-u-g-l-e-r and there might be something on that.
Speaker 0: you but basically was a famous fashion person also even made perfumes and stuff and they passed away somewhat recently.
Speaker 0: but shortly before they passed away there was a exhibit put together by I think the Montreal Museum I guess and now it's moving around and it's at the Brooklyn Museum and for like another month or so.
Speaker 0: right and you know it's mostly like.
Speaker 0: you know runway fashions and you know theater fashions right the kind of ridiculous stuff that you see someone wear to like you know a red carpet or which I love that shit oh yeah.
Speaker 0: so you if you love that shit you should go head down there because they've got like hundreds of these like you know costumes and outfits and you know mostly dresses and stuff that have.
Speaker 0: basically you know we're worn once and then we're put into some storage some so fun fact bow at my two companies ago.
Speaker 1: so this is already a long time ago.
Speaker 1: that company sponsored Fashion Week and we got a lot of access and perks and things way back then that they gave to all of us.
Speaker 1: lowly regular employees.
Speaker 0: yeah but it's a lot different to see.
Speaker 0: you know it's.
Speaker 0: it's obviously one thing to see it.
Speaker 0: you know someone wearing it and you know moving around and whatnot.
Speaker 0: and there's videos and stuff in the exhibit you know showing you who was wearing it and when and photos and a lot of that.
Speaker 0: but you know the thing being on a mannequin and you can actually get close and look at it right and see what's up with it you know much more closely than you I guess ever could ever right?
Speaker 0: it's like you're not gonna get close to the famous person wearing it.
Speaker 0: you're gonna see it from from far away.
Speaker 1: you're not gonna close enough to be like wow I literally can't see the stitching.
Speaker 1: how the fuck did they do that?
Speaker 0: well no that's what I was actually gonna say right it's like the cosplayers should actually feel pretty good because I got.
Speaker 0: you know you get close to a lot of this stuff and it's like.
Speaker 0: you know the design of it and you know the way it looks is.
Speaker 0: you know is incredible but you get.
Speaker 0: it's like a lot of it.
Speaker 0: you get close to it and it's clearly very fragile.
Speaker 0: they they clearly made something that would only work one time right and it's held together by like you know.
Speaker 1: it's like it's the f1 car of a dress.
Speaker 0: exactly that's what this stuff like I saw.
Speaker 0: it's like when you get close to it it's like yeah you can clearly see that like this was not?
Speaker 0: you know some of the stuff isn't you know?
Speaker 0: perfect right and but you can't tell from from far away right that it's not perfect it's still just.
Speaker 0: you know some incredibly unique and amazing clothing.
Speaker 0: but the coolest section.
Speaker 0: I thought they had a section of you know very fembot styled clothing
Speaker 1: also a fan of fembot style
Speaker 0: of course if a lot of that was clearly you know uncomfortable boob armoring but you know that and you could see also by looking at the clothing how unrealistically small the person who wore it had to be.
Speaker 0: like it's like no like you know only a child or a model can fit into any of this stuff right.
Speaker 0: and then there was the be like animal section.
Speaker 0: we're like you know the bug clothing clothing etc.
Speaker 0: right the put this on and you look like a motorcycle.
Speaker 0: literally there was one cool.
Speaker 0: I think the only thing that was in there that I think I would have worn there was like these.
Speaker 0: there was a. there was a set of clothing you know one for a man body and a woman body shaped body yeah and it looked like the kind of clothing that someone would wear.
Speaker 0: and like you know some sort of a space station somewhere in between like a Logan's run and you know Cloud City right style with like you know people walk around in the space station with capes and whatnot.
Speaker 1: I was like.
Speaker 1: so I have seen occasional people kind of dressed adjacent to that as those handful of brands that make.
Speaker 0: you saw Lando Calrissian walking down the.
Speaker 1: it wasn't an anime convention or wasn't quite to the Lando level but it was like 40% of the Lando.
Speaker 0: this is the land level.
Speaker 1: yeah I want that style to come back for real.
Speaker 1: there is a few brands that actually make actual wearable clothes that are closer they like.
Speaker 1: they look like Assassin's Creed kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: I feel like we just need that trend to continue and we can dress like Lando.
Speaker 0: or we have money.
Speaker 1: you want to just get Lando stuff and just dress like that from now on.
Speaker 0: the other problem I don't think it would look good.
Speaker 1: I think we could pull it off.
Speaker 1: I think we could both pull it off.
Speaker 0: I think it only looks good if you're in the right setting.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: exhibit is that all the clothing is in you know an appropriate setting that matches.
Speaker 0: if you think if you take it out of that setting it just looks ridiculous.
Speaker 1: ah but if enough people start dressing like Lando Lando becomes the fashion.
Speaker 1: sure I'm just saying I'll Lando if you Lando but I'm not gonna Lando alone.
Speaker 0: it's also not really practical right.
Speaker 0: it's like this.
Speaker 0: shit doesn't have pockets that you can't.
Speaker 0: it's got like giant shoulders and other ridiculous stuff.
Speaker 0: you yeah it's like you can't.
Speaker 0: it's hard to go about.
Speaker 1: as much as I like capes.
Speaker 1: you know I saw why was my father where with a guy in a cape having worn an actual for real cape a lot in marching as a high school kid.
Speaker 1: capes are actually super fucking annoying to wear.
Speaker 1: they're right.
Speaker 1: they are such a pain.
Speaker 0: especially all of these clothings right are only practical to wear if you're on a runway at a red carpet at a gala or someone.
Speaker 0: you don't have to hold anything and you have like a someone to take care of your shit for you.
Speaker 0: the only thing get to hold us a drink.
Speaker 0: yes right all right you're not.
Speaker 1: no sitting no laying Scott I'll get packed with you now if there is ever a situation just saying where you and I are both attending something that qualifies as red carpet.
Speaker 1: if you want to
Speaker 0: go in fine well you can spend your money on getting some famous fashion design
Speaker 1: Orlando the both of us because I'm not doing by myself and I would love but I would like to Lando but it'll have to be an actual red carpet above the line.
Speaker 0: I think I mean the price that you have to pay to you know to to donate to the Met to get gala tickets in the first place.
Speaker 0: the cost of the clothing would not really compare.
Speaker 1: yeah I mean I don't think I would not be going to that.
Speaker 1: I can't.
Speaker 1: what kind of?
Speaker 1: what's the?
Speaker 1: what's the least red carpet that would qualify as red that you and I could get access to.
Speaker 0: that's it you would have to make.
Speaker 0: you would have to have premiere a movie or a show.
Speaker 1: there's minor red carpets.
Speaker 1: there's that red carpet to get into the lounge at London Heathrow
Speaker 0: but it mean it's like yeah there are red carpets about but it has to be one specifically where there's paparazzi waiting for this event those people crammed on the you know the size I feel like the
Speaker 1: best we could and you
Speaker 0: get to pull up and go down the red carpet and take
Speaker 1: a photo
Speaker 0: and go in because
Speaker 1: there is another kind of venue that does that and that is the club or the music venue where rich people are going in very specific circumstances like the fancy club that has the special concert.
Speaker 0: what if what if?
Speaker 1: oh maybe that's what our gaming con is the red carpet.
Speaker 1: gaming con is.
Speaker 0: no I mean it could.
Speaker 0: it could be a thing that happens at a con right like a special you know event at a specific time.
Speaker 1: we invite Friedman freeze and we make sure he's fancy.
Speaker 1: it's like comes in on the red carpet.
Speaker 0: we know we make a red carpet and you know cosplayers come up and get out and come down our.
Speaker 0: we basically set up a pretend red carpet but you know more achievable.
Speaker 0: it doesn't have to even be at a con.
Speaker 0: we could just be like spent you know event in New York right the red carpet for no reason at all right.
Speaker 0: it's like come you know buy a ticket.
Speaker 0: right and that funds the event and anyone who buys a ticket even better.
Speaker 0: anyone who buys a ticket can roll up and protect walk down the red carpet.
Speaker 0: well everyone will be people taking photos.
Speaker 0: they'll get interviewed and then they'll get a photo in front of the thing with our logo on it and then they can go in and then that's the end right.
Speaker 0: you buy a ticket just to do that and there's no other event.
Speaker 0: that's it just even better to come down a red carpet buy a ticket and you get to live that like we rented the front of Cipriani for a day just to do it.
Speaker 1: a crowd of people who don't know that it's just like a bit would.
Speaker 0: that's what makes it work.
Speaker 0: you don't have to hire extras to come in.
Speaker 0: we just need like a couple photographers right yeah the extras will make themselves.
Speaker 0: this is we could even make.
Speaker 0: we could even you know since it's not really harmful.
Speaker 0: we could also lie right.
Speaker 0: oh yeah we could send a press release to the news and we could as we could even you know let rim the expert on lying without lying write something like you know red carpet event you know etc.
Speaker 0: etc.
Speaker 1: yeah for the premiere of it'll be written in such a way that that halfling is definitely not going to be arrested by the wizard police.
Speaker 1: yeah so that that's actually a joke that the inside thing that predates you.
Speaker 1: but the the moment where my previous friend grew before I went to RIT realized that I can confabulate that well in the right circumstances without actually lying was specifically playing D&D at an event and I got out of being arrested by the wizard police entirely in character.
Speaker 1: so the listener suggests the fresh fashion by Friedman freeze.
Speaker 1: so in the news this is breaking news.
Speaker 1: it just happened.
Speaker 1: it was just announced.
Speaker 1: it said Al Jaffee an absolute legend basically like the art the illustrator that made mad magazine what it was.
Speaker 0: there were other people there was but Al Jaffee yeah is well I think Al Al was the guy who you know.
Speaker 0: he was the living embodiment of mad magazine and he live.
Speaker 0: he outlived them all.
Speaker 0: basically yeah right so in outliving them all he sort of you know in his name he carries the torch for for all the others yeah
Speaker 1: and if you don't know if you think you don't know who Al Jaffee
Speaker 0: talked about him literally every time it's his birthday
Speaker 1: yep click on this link.
Speaker 1: and if you since he was like 90 something if you see any piece of art that this man made himself you'll realize oh it's that guy like.
Speaker 1: you'll know who it is.
Speaker 1: you've seen this everywhere.
Speaker 0: yeah mad man does it does it fold together and then another image appears.
Speaker 1: so he died at a hundred and two.
Speaker 0: so he had a good run but that I can make it all.
Speaker 0: that means he was born in 1921. yeah mad magazine was in the 50s.
Speaker 0: in the 50s he was 30.
Speaker 1: yep mad magazine started in the 50s.
Speaker 0: I want to say he was looking 30 something in the 50s when he was our age it was still the 60s.
Speaker 0: there was still 20 more years before we were even gonna be born.
Speaker 1: yet yeah mad magazine first October November 1952.
Speaker 0: yeah but it's like not only did he live long and see all that shit that you could you know that you could see in a hundred years plus.
Speaker 0: right but he remained the person that he was after seeing all that shit.
Speaker 0: yeah and that's not even that right.
Speaker 0: just that alone is a is a noteworthy and significant life not even counting all of the artworks he created.
Speaker 1: yeah so it's like never mind the fact that mad magazine was surprisingly like important to pop culture in a way that modern people who are young might not recognize because it's long gone.
Speaker 1: but that magazine was an institution mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: it's not long gone it's somewhat recently gone.
Speaker 1: well it I would say it was effectively gone in the 90s like it really started to fall apart.
Speaker 1: you know there was mad TV which was actually better than people remember.
Speaker 1: it's kind of shame it failed but I digress.
Speaker 1: but anyway pouring out for a legend Al Jaffe God speed buddy hundred and two in much sadder news relatively recently what could be sadder than that?
Speaker 1: this is this is sadder than that in a in a very focused way.
Speaker 1: so in most of America for a long time pretty much in most states pretty the other majority of all cars on the road are trucks.
Speaker 1: that's just for reasons but technically classified as trucks.
Speaker 1: yes now for a long time that was mostly very rural places because most people in America the vast majority of humans in America did not ever own or drive a truck.
Speaker 1: they drove a regular small car on a car chassis and if you needed to carry a bunch of people with you you had a station wagon like that was.
Speaker 0: I think it was.
Speaker 0: there was a leveling up right.
Speaker 0: so it started.
Speaker 0: as you know if you were just one person you had like a two-door car cuz you'd occasionally have a passenger to be more expensive than two cars right.
Speaker 0: and then well cuz two.
Speaker 0: our cars are usually fast sporty cars right.
Speaker 0: and then you know when you were a family right your family got a Ford.
Speaker 0: you know Taurus a sedan a four-door car.
Speaker 0: right a lot a long one.
Speaker 0: you're a big family.
Speaker 1: you got a station wagon or maybe you right.
Speaker 0: eventually right the station wagon became a thing right.
Speaker 0: and then after that the minivan became a thing and like the 90s I remember all everyone had Ford Tauruses and when they all got rid of them and got Ford Windstar yeah it was either the Windstar or there was another.
Speaker 1: we couldn't afford the Windstar as a family so we got the fucking Astro like the bad one.
Speaker 0: yeah but it's like.
Speaker 0: basically everyone had Tauruses and then they changed to the minivan.
Speaker 0: right but the minivan was never even though it was so practical you know for a large family right if you had at least three chill if you only had two children you could go with the sedan.
Speaker 0: yeah it's not necessary right but if you had three or more right it was just you know and you were you know buying into cars.
Speaker 0: you weren't anti-car or anything.
Speaker 1: the practicality and convenience of it you know made sense and a lot of people to to their credit because something changed in America that really broke this situation.
Speaker 1: a lot of families that they could afford it would have a minivan that they only used when they had to take the whole family somewhere or move something.
Speaker 1: yeah like drive we had.
Speaker 0: yeah we had a big car and a small car.
Speaker 0: my dad would take the small car to work and the other car was right you know.
Speaker 1: so this article the Washington Post has a.
Speaker 0: and then SUV came along and was like hey all you minivan people you you've been riding those minivans because they're so practical and you can carry your whole family in them right even though most of the time even the minivan only had one person in it.
Speaker 0: right yeah it was only some.
Speaker 0: but then they were like but you know the whole time you've been driving that minivan you know it's not cool.
Speaker 0: no one feels cool driving it.
Speaker 0: and it's like we have made the SUV.
Speaker 0: it is it's just a minivan.
Speaker 0: it's just it's.
Speaker 0: it's a minivan.
Speaker 0: it's a worse minivan.
Speaker 0: all right it's a minivan or a pickup truck that we made a different shape so that you don't feel uncool riding it.
Speaker 0: but it's the.
Speaker 1: you know there's the same except you actually had less space in those SUVs than in minivans.
Speaker 0: so they were actually worse and they're higher up and harder to get into yep so and less fuel-efficient.
Speaker 0: it is more dangerous to everyone outside of them.
Speaker 0: it is true inside and we've talked about this on geek knives many times.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna lay with the point that the primary reason Americans pretty much buy exclusively SUVs to this day is because those are the most advertised cars and the car companies really push SUVs over all other forms of cars.
Speaker 0: yeah car ads work whether you believe it or not and basically they can tell people what to buy.
Speaker 0: people in a lot of places have to buy a car.
Speaker 0: they end up buying the one the advertisement told them to buy the one that's available.
Speaker 0: right and you know they might not you know admit that like I bought this.
Speaker 0: you know it's like.
Speaker 0: they say oh I got it cuz I like it.
Speaker 0: why do you like it?
Speaker 0: because an ad made you like that.
Speaker 0: yeah right.
Speaker 1: so so this article?
Speaker 1: because in America relatively recently now in every state SUVs and light trucks are the majority of all cars.
Speaker 1: the last holdouts were Rhode Island New Jersey New York and Connecticut mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: those were the only places in all of America where there were more cars than trucks on the road.
Speaker 1: at any given time they have fallen.
Speaker 1: trucks are the majority and in red states they're like 80 plus percent of all cars.
Speaker 1: now it is nuts.
Speaker 1: so this article is a very long form sort of explanation mostly because it has a lot of citations and links to other resources.
Speaker 1: if you want to like dig more into this about.
Speaker 1: it's not asking why did Americans buy SUVs?
Speaker 1: because we know why ads.
Speaker 1: it's asking the question why specifically did every car company in America so aggressively push SUVs to the exclusion of everything else?
Speaker 1: and the short version of this is it's a reason.
Speaker 0: it's a reason I already knew yeah but it's an old.
Speaker 1: yeah it's a reason that well a lot of people knew and there's a lot of data around it.
Speaker 1: but this brings it all together pretty succinctly.
Speaker 1: and also there's new evidence and specific data from recent years showing exactly how this went down.
Speaker 1: America regulates cars in a way where if something is classified as this truck it can be less safe and less fuel-efficient.
Speaker 1: so every car manufacturer said fuck the world fuck America fuck people fuck the environment.
Speaker 1: we are going to skirt the regulations to the maximum extent and act in bad faith and sell nothing.
Speaker 1: but like trucks we're gonna make sure every car we make is a light truck.
Speaker 0: well the quest right.
Speaker 0: the real question is like you know not that you know it's like those as loophole.
Speaker 0: basically right to say you know if you make a car that's class.
Speaker 0: you know there's rules that were in law that say this is what classifies a car in this category.
Speaker 0: this is what classifies a car in that you're not gonna like the answer but keep going yeah.
Speaker 0: and then they said all right you know well if a car is in this category it has to be X efficient right it's like if a car is in this category well obviously that's a big truck category that has to be less efficient.
Speaker 0: you know we can't.
Speaker 0: it's not reasonable to expect someone who makes a giant truck which does need to exist for the person who legitimately needs giant truck.
Speaker 0: you know we can't ask them to make giant truck 60 miles a gallon.
Speaker 0: it's just not going to be possible right?
Speaker 0: that would basically be legislating those vehicles out of existence.
Speaker 0: and so they wrote those laws in that way.
Speaker 0: now the question is right.
Speaker 0: when they wrote those laws in that way right?
Speaker 0: did they or did anyone who was involved in the making of those laws lobbyists you know representatives staff anyone right?
Speaker 0: was this just an oopsie?
Speaker 0: or was this somehow foreseen and intentional?
Speaker 1: you're not gonna lie.
Speaker 1: this answer cuz there's evil parties right.
Speaker 0: there were the car companies like you know.
Speaker 0: oh yeah you can pass that legislation yeah that one.
Speaker 0: actually we see the loophole already.
Speaker 0: that's not gonna stop us.
Speaker 0: you can pass that one.
Speaker 0: go ahead.
Speaker 1: so there are effectively three reasons why this happened.
Speaker 1: one of them you're not gonna like.
Speaker 0: it's easy.
Speaker 0: we know it's evil.
Speaker 1: no I mean you personally you Scott Reuben are not gonna like the third one when I say it and you're gonna go.
Speaker 0: I'm sure it's just an evil reason.
Speaker 1: but one reason is a lot of our regulations and laws and just things are old and some of the stuff dates back to the 40s and like chicken shit like chicken trucks and stuff and like tariff wars with urine.
Speaker 1: so and there's just a lot of inertia to change things like that.
Speaker 1: the second reason was basically all the politicians who are paid off by the car industry had to make sure there was a loophole or they would have lost all their donors from the car.
Speaker 0: why didn't they just?
Speaker 0: why did they just do nothing?
Speaker 0: why did?
Speaker 1: why did they you know just leave the victory of saying look we're gonna make cars fuel-efficient.
Speaker 1: and everyone celebrated because those rules also the safety rules were really important.
Speaker 1: cars used to kill.
Speaker 1: yeah as much as cars kill people.
Speaker 0: today they're the second most it's guns and cars are the killers.
Speaker 0: yep but anyway you want to know the real.
Speaker 1: the third reason the Senate is now paralyzed in a way that it wasn't when the but that's.
Speaker 0: that's a reason why you can't change it.
Speaker 0: now I'm talking about what happened when the most recent car safety car laws needed to be able to get past the Senate filibuster.
Speaker 0: when when were they made?
Speaker 1: 2004 seems to be the last time right.
Speaker 0: so what were the discussions that were had in 2004 where the lobbyists saying oh no that's public there's.
Speaker 0: I don't know that right but that's that's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: is that you know was this you know a a good-faith loophole like they didn't realize that the car companies would do that?
Speaker 0: or was it?
Speaker 0: hey hey the car company lobbyists already knew the strategy.
Speaker 0: I would argue they already were thick imagining the SUV world in 2004. as
Speaker 1: someone who is not an expert on car regulation but actually is an expert on capital markets regulation professionally uh in my personal professional opinion but not the opinion of my employer regulators usually do anticipate loopholes and in functioning regulatory frameworks they document them and they wait and see and as soon as the first person actually takes advantage of obscure loophole they immediately correct it.
Speaker 1: uh the reason none of these loopholes been corrected?
Speaker 1: because a lot of these laws are from 1978 and the Senate has been paralyzed since about 1994-95. so none of these regulations can ever be changed again.
Speaker 1: so the regulators who probably have a whole list of here's all the ways they're gonna try to get around it so we can play whack-a-mole when they actually do which is before anyone says why don't you just put those all in the law to begin with?
Speaker 1: that's too hard.
Speaker 1: that is actually too hard.
Speaker 1: you cannot deal with every loophole.
Speaker 1: it is better.
Speaker 1: like hockey hockey rules change all the time.
Speaker 1: someone figures out some bullshit and then they're like all right.
Speaker 1: there's a rule against that specific bullshit.
Speaker 0: I mean on the one hand you know there is some truth to.
Speaker 0: you can't possibly anticipate everything.
Speaker 0: you need to be have the ability to change the rules once you realize someone else smarter than you figured out something.
Speaker 0: yeah.
Speaker 0: but on the other hand I see this a lot in game design right is like the the game testers or like the pro players.
Speaker 0: oh yeah I agree you.
Speaker 0: they figure shit out on like not even day zero like minute zero as soon as like some new card in a card game or some new patch to an FPS comes out or a new map.
Speaker 0: like they figure out the exploit within five minutes.
Speaker 0: and it's like when they figure out the loophole that quickly.
Speaker 1: that is either incompetence or lack of effort with the regulatory whack-a-mole applies to the actual edge cases the things that are difficult to codify in law.
Speaker 1: not not like babies first.
Speaker 1: what if they just make a new class of car that's exempt from all regulations?
Speaker 1: like that's baby's first bullshit.
Speaker 1: but exactly the reason none of this has changed is because the Senate has been paralyzed and a lot of this stuff goes back to 1978. so this article should just radicalize you further against cars.
Speaker 1: in our final news tonight we were really excited about the Apple m1 and m2 chips and the whole world was excited about it.
Speaker 1: we're also up there.
Speaker 0: they're there.
Speaker 0: they're there m2.
Speaker 0: this at this MacBook Air m2 that I've been.
Speaker 0: I got for my new job new at least almost one year old job I guess.
Speaker 0: Oh ten times technology.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 0: it's like if I wasn't gonna play a video game in my life or run any Windows only software in my life.
Speaker 0: right it's like this.
Speaker 0: thing is unbelievable.
Speaker 0: it's better at the.
Speaker 0: you know the things that it can do right now that my my personal computer can also do.
Speaker 0: it is better at them right.
Speaker 0: the only thing is my personal computer can do additional things.
Speaker 1: yep but as it runs windows also in parallel we noted and some multiple recent episodes of geek nights that well basically the entire technology sector on earth has been laying people off like crazy.
Speaker 1: Apple somehow wasn't.
Speaker 0: well that's that's not true anymore.
Speaker 0: Apple laid off a little bit.
Speaker 0: they're like.
Speaker 0: you can see that Apple is like cutting costs in other ways and they're they laid off a few I think like some retail executive type people and some other thing.
Speaker 0: but it's like they are.
Speaker 0: Apple is at least holding back on the layoffs as much as they can which I think is wise.
Speaker 1: yep I mean my company my current company.
Speaker 1: we're hiring we're not firing we're hiring not a ton of people but we're still hiring.
Speaker 1: but McDonald's is also laying off a bunch of people.
Speaker 1: so watch out that's not a great sign either I don't think but that's a bad one.
Speaker 1: yep max sales are down 40% that's right.
Speaker 1: so wait so that right.
Speaker 0: well that's a trailing indicator right.
Speaker 0: so I think it's telling a story of something that's already happened right.
Speaker 0: so basically you know there was the pan doodle and people went to work from home.
Speaker 0: right and when people are working from home they all went out and bought computers.
Speaker 1: yeah a lot of my co-workers had to buy computers.
Speaker 1: a terrifying number of professionals do not own an actual computer at home right.
Speaker 0: well it's not just and I think it's not I think that individuals these days clearly are not buying computers in great number.
Speaker 0: the only people who are buying computers for themselves I think in large significant numbers right are gamers who aren't buying Apple computer.
Speaker 0: yep all right and you know creators artists developers people making games and making entertainment and the I think the largest number of computers now desktops whether Apple or otherwise besides the gaming ones yep that are being bought are actually being bought by companies.
Speaker 0: right companies are the ones you buy computers guess you just write everyone off.
Speaker 1: all the tech companies that were buying all these computers all these tech companies laid people off.
Speaker 0: they either just let people keep the computers or they get them returned to the company.
Speaker 0: there
Speaker 1: are so many cheap new computers for sale in the secondary market right so that
Speaker 0: so all these tech layoffs have resulted in a big glut of either people just got a free work computer that's now theirs and or right companies have their either remaining IT staff you know flashing and backing up all these computers from laid-off people and if any new employees come in they get one of those.
Speaker 0: so or they resell those used on the market.
Speaker 0: and now they're.
Speaker 0: so the demand for and people you know are going back to offices or whatever.
Speaker 0: I guess sometimes I don't know.
Speaker 0: but the point is overall the demand for desktop and laptop computers right now is a way down and it's been down for a while.
Speaker 0: and that down miss has caught up to the point where now right you're actually getting the reports of how down it's been.
Speaker 0: it's been so down that Apple says 40% less sales on Mac computers.
Speaker 0: right and also Apple has basically stopped making m2 chips.
Speaker 1: now they have.
Speaker 1: that is huge I really have.
Speaker 0: it's like they've made enough to satisfy the demand at.
Speaker 0: so they're rather than cut costs by laying people Apple employees off they're cutting costs by not making chips that no one's gonna buy.
Speaker 1: so my first real job you know when I worked at IBM this happened a while ago it's just now that you know.
Speaker 1: so my first real job was in a fab like an a chip fab making chips for like PlayStations and shit.
Speaker 1: that was actually my job.
Speaker 1: you listen to old geek nights I talk about it a lot.
Speaker 1: and but the technology that I was directly personally responsible for was stuff that would collect data to calculate yields like what percentage of these wafers actually like turn into a chip versus fail that kind of stuff there is.
Speaker 1: the difference between slowing down a production line and halting a production line is more enormous than you can possibly imagine.
Speaker 1: actually stopping a production line is a big fucking deal because they are not easy to start up again.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 0: well TS MC these are all you know.
Speaker 0: all these chips are made by TS M's yeah the most important company on earth.
Speaker 0: they're just they're gonna go there.
Speaker 0: they're actually.
Speaker 0: they're losing.
Speaker 0: you know they're not doing.
Speaker 0: they're down right now right because there's less demand for the chips.
Speaker 0: but they'll just have that line make something else.
Speaker 0: so it is in good time really.
Speaker 1: now again not one caveat is my knowledge of fab stuff is about a decade.
Speaker 0: the way TS MC works is basically every other company in the world your apples your Intel's your AMD's or whoever right?
Speaker 0: I guess Intel's their own fabs but everyone else right.
Speaker 0: who doesn't have their own fab?
Speaker 0: designs chips right and you send your designs to TMC and then they make the chip.
Speaker 0: they actually make the silicon wafer part for you right?
Speaker 0: so you know Apple designs the m2 chip sends it over.
Speaker 0: they produce it.
Speaker 0: obviously apples like biggest customer one of the biggest customers.
Speaker 0: right but it's like that fab isn't just like a dead fab that can't do anything at all now right it's like either a eventually Apple will put in a new order or and it'll take some time to get it going or B it can do some other customers work.
Speaker 0: you know it might not gonna be overnight right but but Rachel is within a large ship manufacturer like that.
Speaker 1: from my understanding retooling a line is a very lengthy I've very expensive process and yields tend to go absolutely into the gutter with a newly tooled line.
Speaker 0: well it depends what you mean by retooling.
Speaker 0: right?
Speaker 0: it's like.
Speaker 0: you know if you're talking about like changing it from one like X nanometers to a different nanometer it's like that's basically they.
Speaker 0: it seems like TS MC.
Speaker 0: when they do that they just make a whole new fab.
Speaker 0: they don't seem like.
Speaker 0: I've never seen a news that was like ah they've changed this fab from this many to this many usually.
Speaker 1: well usually you have a fab and within a fab you have multiple channels or pipelines and I think some of those stories of technology like they'll share the same centering furnace but not all of them will.
Speaker 1: some of them will have a specialized function that other ones if you reason the TMC SMC news right.
Speaker 0: it's always like they're starting up a new fab.
Speaker 0: in this place it makes these kinds of chips.
Speaker 0: it seems like they've split it up to where each building makes a certain category of chip.
Speaker 0: and so as long as someone designs a chip in that category then the fab seems capable of you know producing it.
Speaker 0: but when it's a customer like Apple they'll often dedicate the entire fab to like that one customer.
Speaker 0: so you know it's.
Speaker 0: it's possible for I guess that fab to do something else but someone else would.
Speaker 0: some other customer would have to order an m2 like chip.
Speaker 1: but that's sort of.
Speaker 1: what's actually worrying me is not the chip thing but like the chip fab side of it like the black start of a manufacturing line or whatever.
Speaker 1: but more that if the entire sector is collapsing then who is even gonna want that existing now idle fab capacity in the first place except militaries.
Speaker 1: and the only way out of this I see is if the whole Taiwan China thing actually blows up for real.
Speaker 1: then we'll see what happens.
Speaker 1: but this is that's not well.
Speaker 0: basically if China tries to go in right cuz TSMC is in Taiwan right most of it and most of their fabs are there right.
Speaker 0: basically if China goes in and tries to take the fabs it would.
Speaker 0: basically they would just ruin them right?
Speaker 0: not Taiwan would ruin them and be like oh you can't have now there I mean the u.s.
Speaker 1: is it war games?
Speaker 1: and they showed that pretty definitively.
Speaker 1: while the war would be horrific.
Speaker 1: there is no possible way to occupy permanently Taiwan right?
Speaker 0: nobody can take oh.
Speaker 0: the only way for those fabs to continue operating and continue to provide value is to leave Taiwan be right.
Speaker 0: if anyone tries to mess with Taiwan they'll just basically you know ruin their own shit and be like oh you can't make chips now.
Speaker 0: what'd you conquer?
Speaker 0: nothing you can't.
Speaker 0: a bunch of worthless crap right.
Speaker 1: good luck like in say oh here's my extremely unhappy city where I sold every building over the last ten turns.
Speaker 1: exactly so joy.
Speaker 0: that's not a concern right?
Speaker 0: the like you know.
Speaker 0: I guess it's a concern where if it happens that the then the chip supply will be in in in dire straits.
Speaker 1: well let's buy for everybody.
Speaker 1: yeah it's odd that that situation is actually pretty but I'm not.
Speaker 0: you know I'm not worried about that.
Speaker 0: I'm more worried about you know will companies continue to advance right for nerds who want and you know workers who want faster better desktop computers right?
Speaker 0: will Apple Intel Nvidia other companies continue to invest in improving that technology?
Speaker 0: is you know?
Speaker 0: are we gonna get to a point where Intel's like you know what 16th gen Intel CPU we're just gonna leave it at that the end?
Speaker 1: so uh the problem with that is this anger.
Speaker 1: Apple gets like m5 and they're like you know what capital will be extremely unhappy if that happens even if that might be the right thing to do.
Speaker 1: I mean look at the geopolitical situation of the world right now.
Speaker 1: look at the crisis of a number of rare earth metals and other specific things.
Speaker 1: we need for chip manufacturing and we need a lot of chips for things that don't have as good of a margin as this kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: so a in a general tacit agreement of we don't need faster workstations for a decade might be better for the world.
Speaker 0: because I'm using this right.
Speaker 0: they could just be like the m5 is so stupid.
Speaker 0: fast we'll make a bunch and then you know what.
Speaker 0: every once in a while it'll be like a book that goes out of print.
Speaker 0: it's like okay.
Speaker 0: when people need more computers we'll just make more m5.
Speaker 1: no workstation on do VR and play video games on is a sixth gen Intel i7 and a 1080 video GPU.
Speaker 0: yeah my computer is from 2018. it's five 8700.
Speaker 1: I think it's a 6700 K right.
Speaker 0: it's like it's like five four or five generations of Intel chip behind what's current right and it still works just fine.
Speaker 0: I've been having some RAM issues lately.
Speaker 0: I just add it.
Speaker 0: I had 32 gigs of RAM in there.
Speaker 0: I said you know what it's so inexpensive.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna add 32 more.
Speaker 0: I got 64 gigs of RAM in there.
Speaker 0: it cost me nothing to add that and that's probably gonna extend the life of this computer for like another year or two if it weren't for the fact that you cannot run Windows 11 on a sixth-generation Intel.
Speaker 0: yeah mine at my 8700 is the the oldest one that can run Windows 11. yeah mine is Windows 10 and Windows 11 aren't really and only the user interface is different.
Speaker 1: oh I don't even care at all other than security like I don't want.
Speaker 1: Windows 10 is still supported until 2025 so I got some time still.
Speaker 1: yeah so you got two years right until planning to build a new computer until like the end of next year or maybe the following year.
Speaker 1: we'll see but you know.
Speaker 1: uh if I could run Windows 11 on this existing workstation.
Speaker 1: with this current CPU architecture I would just replace the power supply in the video card and I'd be good for seven or eight more years easily.
Speaker 1: so maybe this would be a good thing.
Speaker 1: but as we discussed this angers capital and I don't know what happens when capital is angry in this regard.
Speaker 1: but anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: so I am a big fan of just one-off music videos that happen to be animated.
Speaker 1: I have a gigantic YouTube playlist that is just animated music videos not anime music videos that there are many a MVs in that list.
Speaker 0: I just have an actual music videos like the official music video for a song but it happens to be that it was animated.
Speaker 0: such as you know Take on me or yeah sledgehammer both
Speaker 1: of those both of those are in my playlist or one of the reasons to join the playlist
Speaker 0: of the those all basically every song by that that project group that came up again recently that I forgot about for 20 years.
Speaker 0: yep so uh uh uh Fleet Fox really has got a few.
Speaker 0: yeah uh.
Speaker 1: so what I present to you Jonathan Young's starship velociraptor and just watch it.
Speaker 1: this is anime homage macross bubblegum crisis Gundam Akira the music video a little bit of ghost in the shell in there on your mark qualifies.
Speaker 1: oh yeah on your mark definitely qualifies.
Speaker 1: it was what was the name of that band?
Speaker 1: I for anyway it was that was a music video commissioned for a specific band that was popular at the time.
Speaker 0: I guess all right my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: so you know keep it in the AI theme that's been going on and is gonna keep going on for I don't know what you're thinking today.
Speaker 1: is I opened it?
Speaker 1: but I haven't I didn't.
Speaker 0: Oh look at it.
Speaker 0: look at it.
Speaker 0: so you click on it and you're just gonna see a boring old in browser text editor and the top right it's like hey give us your you know open AI chat GBT API key right so that we don't have to pay the bills for you using this.
Speaker 0: and basically you give it your open AI API key in the top right and you can check a box for chat to use GPT for.
Speaker 0: and if you do that it'll obviously be better but also slower and I don't know how the pricing works on any of that.
Speaker 0: but basically what you do is you type in this box right English text and then this text editor Merlin editor dot verse l dot app will act as an editor so you don't have to hire an editor.
Speaker 0: hmm like you're talking like you know not just your spell checks and your grammar checks but like I've see you've used this you keep using the same word over and over again.
Speaker 0: try some different words like an editor like a human editor.
Speaker 0: it is quite.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: it's obviously imperfect as all the machine learning.
Speaker 0: you know it's equal parts impressive and imperfect as you would expect from any of your other experiences with chat GPT.
Speaker 0: yeah but you know I think this is a yet another example of a good use of it right?
Speaker 0: it's like most people out there right.
Speaker 0: this isn't taking work away from editors.
Speaker 0: someone who writes a novel isn't going to be using this right even if this improves tenfold.
Speaker 0: someone who writes a real book to be published I guess could use it if it was approved.
Speaker 0: tenfold maybe but I think it's more likely that an actual editor would use it to make their own job easier.
Speaker 0: yeah but also someone who writes English text or maybe text in some other language I don't know what language is it supports who doesn't have an editor?
Speaker 0: because you're just writing your own damn blog post your own damn newsletter your own comment on a someone else's blog.
Speaker 0: you could get a pass from a virtual editor and improve the quality of the text you put into the world.
Speaker 1: and you know what it won't be perfect just like you know.
Speaker 1: I was testing Adobe podcast.
Speaker 1: you know what.
Speaker 1: it's only 90% as good as I am doing it myself.
Speaker 0: that's a lot.
Speaker 0: how does that compared to doing nothing exactly?
Speaker 0: so if I do if I happen it's like yes it was.
Speaker 0: this compared to a real like the best editors on earth is obviously flawed.
Speaker 0: how does it compare to throwing up the text I wrote unedited?
Speaker 1: that is that point is something a lot of people are missing in the AI debate there there and they look at the flaws of these kinds of tools today and say things like yeah it can never replace you.
Speaker 1: oh it day it is definitely going to replace a human.
Speaker 0: yes it's like.
Speaker 0: you know this the artwork generator right.
Speaker 0: it's like is it taking a work away from an artist?
Speaker 0: and it's like anyone who is gonna pay an artist is still gonna pay an artist.
Speaker 0: but me I was gonna use some Google image search or I was gonna draw something really hideous.
Speaker 0: so replacing my hideous drawing with a generated drawing that is superior it's good.
Speaker 0: yeah as long as I'm not like lying about it or anything you know in the moment geek nuts book club book the satanic versus pretty good I'm more than halfway done and I know I got to say now not right is that?
Speaker 0: you know this is just.
Speaker 0: you know they I guess if you went to a library or a bookstore right they would just qualify this as like adult fiction.
Speaker 0: right it would be in that adult fiction section.
Speaker 0: we're like.
Speaker 0: you know the bestsellers are and such.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: but let's be honest with ourselves this is a fantasy novel right?
Speaker 0: oh yeah this is just.
Speaker 0: this is just a fantasy novel right this is very geek nights appropriate.
Speaker 0: this shit goes on the show.
Speaker 0: it's not a series fantasy novel where there's gonna be multiple books.
Speaker 0: it's just a one a one booker.
Speaker 0: but you know you can put this on the shelf right next to all your your dragon.
Speaker 1: oh if you had someone picked it up and did not know any of the context in the world of the creation of this book they would just that they would just think oh another fantasy novel.
Speaker 1: that was pretty good.
Speaker 0: and I think you know it's like William Gibson.
Speaker 0: he writes the same.
Speaker 0: he writes adult novels.
Speaker 0: they just happen to actually go in the sci-fi section.
Speaker 0: yeah right it's like William Gibson could easily try to get his novels in the adult fiction section that is separate from the nerd section of the bookstore.
Speaker 0: right and no one would question that.
Speaker 0: and I think
Speaker 1: you know what was the quote I just remember from like high school someone read a bookstore with like some friends the family or whatever and someone said something to the point of the adult fiction section is mostly books about people going through a messy divorce and finding themselves.
Speaker 1: yeah yeah pretty good.
Speaker 1: if you haven't started reading it yet because of the weighty history and like geopolitics of this book just pick it up.
Speaker 0: treat none of those.
Speaker 0: none of those things appear in the text of the book.
Speaker 1: yeah did you?
Speaker 0: did you read Wikipedia?
Speaker 0: yeah if you didn't read Wikipedia or the news or know who Rushdie was or anything before reading this book and I you could you would just read like you know a high quality fantasy novel.
Speaker 1: if you didn't know it'd be like if you read the Lord of the Rings and then found out that people were trying to kill Tolkien for 40 years because of it.
Speaker 0: right all right it's not but even though it's fantasy novel I think you know it's not adventury it's not a event.
Speaker 1: you know what.
Speaker 1: you know what this book is.
Speaker 0: it is allegorical with a capital a that's underlined like 10 times and also even though there is much magic and you know fantasy things happening it takes place in the quote present which is 1980 X of the real world right.
Speaker 0: so I think that might be what you know.
Speaker 0: almost every fantasy novel takes place in you know some imaginary world that's not earth or most of them right or some future or the distant past whereas this took place in the present at the time it was published and that'll help keep you out of the nerd section of the bookstore.
Speaker 0: yeah all right.
Speaker 1: so we're not gonna talk at least much about the aesthetics of fonts.
Speaker 0: we're gonna know about fun episode already I think so we don't need to though.
Speaker 1: at the very end I burned before the show I thought real hard and I made a list of my five favorite fonts.
Speaker 1: I'm sure I forgot something but I think I got.
Speaker 0: I got six favorite funds.
Speaker 1: I forced myself to cut it down to five and it was hard.
Speaker 1: someone didn't make the cut but anyway I bet we have exactly one that overlaps and only one but anyway.
Speaker 0: so anyway fonts technologically speaking right is okay.
Speaker 0: you want to you know have a computer and you want text to appear on the computer.
Speaker 0: right how the hell do we do this?
Speaker 0: well back in the day right there were basically like these hard coded pixel fonts in ROMs.
Speaker 0: you know what they were like.
Speaker 1: they were like sprite sheets in video games.
Speaker 0: basically well they were.
Speaker 0: it's like yeah what that's what if you whether you're using MS-DOS or you know you're a BIOS on an old 90s computer or Final Fantasy 1 text right it's like there is a space in the ROM of the game.
Speaker 0: right and there's basically a sprite sheet.
Speaker 0: right pixels that are like on and off and it's like this is what the letter a looks like.
Speaker 0: right it's you know these pixels are white and these ones are not white or black and the other ones are not black.
Speaker 1: that way the computer knows I'm rendering text I can.
Speaker 1: the letter a is gonna go here.
Speaker 1: let me just go fetch what a letter a looks like.
Speaker 0: right you have some.
Speaker 0: you have some binary.
Speaker 0: you have some binary code which is originally in the olden days ASCII.
Speaker 0: right I don't even know what ASCII stands for right but basically it's just a character mapping right.
Speaker 0: it says this series of ones and zeros equals the letter.
Speaker 1: a code for information exchange.
Speaker 0: okay interchange.
Speaker 0: why it's a CII?
Speaker 1: I mean the fixed protocol stands for the financial information exchange.
Speaker 0: so okay sure anyway but it's very much like you know.
Speaker 0: the number one is this letter.
Speaker 0: the number two is this letter.
Speaker 0: the number three is this letter.
Speaker 0: so you have a series of numbers right and then a string in the computer's memory and then a program comes along and says okay I have to draw that those text on this that that memory over there those bits.
Speaker 0: the program that I am says that those bits are text and I'm gonna draw that text on the screen.
Speaker 0: let me go look at that memory and it says number one and then I look up on the sprite sheet what letter that is and I make a light of those pixels on the screen and now you can see that letter right.
Speaker 0: and that's how fonts worked and still work in a lot of computer things.
Speaker 0: right it's it's really straightforward and simple but there's so much to do with human languages and human alphabets that that wasn't gonna work forever.
Speaker 0: right?
Speaker 0: you got different languages you got all sorts of different situations you know with different accent characters.
Speaker 1: we moved away from computers whose sole ability to interact with the screen was a grid of very large blocks.
Speaker 1: you could put sprites into.
Speaker 0: yeah computers had more memory and I could accommodate more letters.
Speaker 0: and also there's different type of graphic features.
Speaker 0: right where you're not where it's not necessarily true that just these are the X symbols.
Speaker 0: that's all the symbols.
Speaker 0: there are the end right.
Speaker 0: there's all sorts of situations that we can discuss at least some of them.
Speaker 1: yeah now it's very important to internalize that fonts are technical.
Speaker 1: the actual technology of fonts is very confusing and often obscure and that is absolutely true.
Speaker 1: don't feel like you're dummy because you don't know how fonts work.
Speaker 1: I barely know how fonts work.
Speaker 0: no it's the people who know how to make fonts work use this like it.
Speaker 0: you know difficult to use software and they craft fonts and it's it's very painstaking labor-intensive work and that's why they sell fonts for hundreds and hundreds of dollars.
Speaker 0: yeah and you know it's like is extremely difficult you know especially if you get everything right.
Speaker 0: and you know there's a lot of free fonts out there and free fonts.
Speaker 0: you know there's plenty of them and a lot of them are terrific but few of them are truly complete and comprehensive and totally correct etc.
Speaker 0: it's also.
Speaker 1: some of them are viruses.
Speaker 1: some of them are pirated.
Speaker 0: that's not that's you know.
Speaker 0: that's only if you go to weird shady websites.
Speaker 1: also.
Speaker 1: that's less of a problem now because one thing most of you listening to geek nights are probably young enough to just live in a world where fonts kind of just work.
Speaker 1: that is not how Windows computers were.
Speaker 0: they kind of just work until you try to do anything special with them and realize oh wait you know these fonts are actually super basic fonts that don't do anything fancy yeah like only rail.
Speaker 1: only in the last six or seven years did Adobe fonts just work to the point that it literally just works.
Speaker 1: I don't think about it anymore.
Speaker 0: there you you haven't tried to do any fancy font.
Speaker 1: this no but I have.
Speaker 1: I bought one.
Speaker 1: I studiously only use fonts that I can enable via Adobe because I pay for it and I just stay away from everything else for the most right.
Speaker 0: but I'm saying is even those fonts a lot?
Speaker 1: but I'm saying even that used to not work like Windows 3 1 1. good fucking luck.
Speaker 1: installing a font.
Speaker 0: well Windows 2 fonts are different.
Speaker 0: then yeah it was 95 they were different.
Speaker 1: Windows 2000 they were different.
Speaker 1: fonts are only relatively recently generally standardized in terms of how computers use them.
Speaker 0: well there's the open type.
Speaker 0: you know fonts right is.
Speaker 0: basically they came up with a standard called open type and whether it's a true type font or an OTF like they're slightly different in like the headers and some other reasons but basically they're all following like this open type font standard which is like the core of all modern fonts.
Speaker 0: and what a font is nowadays technologically is a file and in the file are you know shapes right.
Speaker 0: it's not just pixels it's like a you know a vectorized shape that matches a particular Unicode character code.
Speaker 0: right ASCII only had so many characters.
Speaker 0: Unicode encompasses all of ASCII and then a shit ton more including emojis and every character from every alphabet and every language and even more and there's empty space in it that for more characters that people come up with and that's why you see new emojis coming out occasionally.
Speaker 0: and so if you want to make a complete font your font has to in cap you know encapsulate every character from every alphabet in every language and all of Unicode.
Speaker 0: it's like almost no fonts actually cover all of it right?
Speaker 0: maybe there might even be zero fonts that I know.
Speaker 0: some fonts like fill in the let like.
Speaker 0: you know if a font is primarily for one language like that you know they'll like.
Speaker 0: just feel they'll just take an existing font that covers like all of Unicode and just redo the characters that they care about right in their language.
Speaker 0: and that way at least if characters appear in some other language in someone's text it'll font will just be different.
Speaker 0: that happens sometimes.
Speaker 0: but yeah you have to draw all these shapes and then you have to put special instructions right to handle all sorts of weird situations and some non weird situations non weird situations.
Speaker 0: being well bold right how do you do bold?
Speaker 0: a lot of times you just draw another shape that's like well this is the shape when it's not bold and this is the shape when it's bold.
Speaker 0: right just two different shapes and then it's like all.
Speaker 0: right it's italic.
Speaker 0: well okay I'm gonna draw the shape a third time.
Speaker 0: this is what it looks like when it's italic.
Speaker 0: it's like you're just drawing the shapes over and over again and then you get the weird situations right.
Speaker 0: we're talking about things like ligatures.
Speaker 0: right it's like.
Speaker 0: okay someone wrote the letter lowercase T. well okay good.
Speaker 0: and then they wrote another lowercase T. that immediately follows it.
Speaker 0: it's like well you know if you have two lowercase T's next to each other it's pretty common to like draw two sticks and have one line across both.
Speaker 1: now that's not gonna fly with like a monospace sprite sheet font right that that's what you know.
Speaker 0: if you just put two separate lowercase T's next to each other with like a gap in between it's like it's gonna look weird right?
Speaker 0: it's not wrong it's you know or anything like that.
Speaker 0: it just doesn't look right it's.
Speaker 0: that's not how typography works even though right that would be easy for computers to work.
Speaker 0: so there's a thing called a ligature which detects when you know there are certain combinations of characters adjacent to each other in certain patterns and in it will replace right the characters.
Speaker 0: you know the that those shapes that would normally be there with yet another shape right two T's next to each other or you know all kinds of other.
Speaker 0: that's just the first one that comes to mind.
Speaker 0: but there's there's quite a few of them right and that you got situations like there's capital letters and lowercase letters.
Speaker 0: some languages have uppercase and lowercase some don't.
Speaker 1: yep Turkish because I spent a lot of time in Turkey.
Speaker 1: you can have I with and without the dot and you can capitalize I with and without the dot.
Speaker 0: yep one of my favorite things that this is something I really you know once I learned about it it really bothers me because I want to use it.
Speaker 0: almost no fonts almost no fonts support it correctly right and but when you look at like professionally typeset text you see it all the time and it's like I want to be able to do that.
Speaker 0: but to get a font that can do it is usually either very limited in your choices or it's very expensive.
Speaker 0: and that is small caps right.
Speaker 0: so there's a in the open type font.
Speaker 0: you know format right.
Speaker 0: if you get an actual I guess Apple computers you can open up like the fancy font dialog and see these options.
Speaker 0: I know an InDesign.
Speaker 0: you could open it.
Speaker 0: I guess in your web browser if you CSS you can access all the open type font flags to enable and disable font features.
Speaker 0: but basically there's all these features that you can explicitly enable or disable on a font if the font supports those features right.
Speaker 0: so small caps is basically saying like okay here's the letter O lowercase here's the letter O uppercase.
Speaker 0: and but there's also small caps which is like okay you're gonna render it the way it's rendered as when it's uppercase which is not the same right.
Speaker 0: like you think a capital T the cross is on the top of the bar right it's whereas a lowercase T the cross is in the middle.
Speaker 0: but a small caps will be.
Speaker 0: the bar will be at the top because it's an uppercase letter but it'll be short because it's small.
Speaker 0: it won't be like this big T right.
Speaker 0: and it's common to use small caps for like a heading centered on like a section or table headers or other it's.
Speaker 0: if you look at if you read books you'll see and you start thinking about small caps like.
Speaker 0: you'll see them a lot and it's like.
Speaker 0: but now go try to type them on your computer.
Speaker 0: yeah go to your you go to your text editor you're in design even if you have it and you go to the open type for a CSS and you enable the open type font feature flag SMCP small cap right and you'll notice.
Speaker 0: okay all the letters are now capitals and they're clearly smaller than the actual capital letters.
Speaker 0: right but something is off about them.
Speaker 0: they don't look the way they do when people use small caps and books right and that's because almost all software when told to do small caps will just take the actual capital letters and shrink them down right which is actually not correct.
Speaker 0: the spacing will be off.
Speaker 0: basically everything about those will be off.
Speaker 0: actual small caps are another set of shapes with their own rules for spacing and whatever to look correct and almost no fonts come with actual small caps with and yeah you know.
Speaker 0: so it's like and that's just one of many many you know open type font feature flags.
Speaker 0: other ones are like old-style numerals you ever see.
Speaker 0: like like the threes hang low like you'll often see those used in a book.
Speaker 0: for like you know page numbers yeah right we're like the three will have a little curl at the bottom of it and it what they won't just be lined up straight like the numbers will be at different elevations some hanging low some up high.
Speaker 0: you know people do that for like the address on their house.
Speaker 0: they'll have like the numbers not in a straight line.
Speaker 0: so you need to have a font that supports old-style numerals.
Speaker 0: yeah it's just so much shit that goes into making a correct font right.
Speaker 0: and then even if you sort it out all that shit right then you got to worry about the hinting right.
Speaker 0: back in the day we had CRT monitors where all the texts were basically everything was a little bit blurry because every phosphor on the screen was a little bit blurry.
Speaker 0: right they weren't crisp right.
Speaker 0: so you could just render your font as straight-up pixels.
Speaker 0: and when it showed up on the screen it looked kind of nice and it was.
Speaker 0: it was all good.
Speaker 1: see also sprites.
Speaker 1: and why hard sprites on modern displays are not how anyone ever intended those old games to look right.
Speaker 0: but now we got an LCD screen and an LCD screen.
Speaker 0: everything is a square right.
Speaker 0: and even though we've made those squares really really really small nowadays there's still squares.
Speaker 0: and if you just render a font the old way with no anti aliasing no nothing.
Speaker 0: on an LCD screen it looks pixely AF and it looks bad.
Speaker 0: it looks awful right.
Speaker 0: so they've got this thing called hinting right where you know as the the font gets bigger and smaller right.
Speaker 0: well it's like.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: you're okay.
Speaker 0: there might be a diagonal in the font in the letter somewhere like a letter a capital.
Speaker 0: a has a diagonal right.
Speaker 0: so it's like okay well do you just make a staircase of pixels that are on and off.
Speaker 0: it'll look like it'll look bad right you got.
Speaker 0: you want to make it look like a smooth sharp angle right on both sides of the letter a or the V or the W or any kind of angular thing or curve thing as well.
Speaker 0: what you end up doing is you want to turn on parts of pixels right.
Speaker 0: the pixels in the LCD are arranged I get is it red green then blue or green?
Speaker 0: in order.
Speaker 0: there's three colors in order right.
Speaker 0: so it's like all right.
Speaker 0: well even though obviously the letter is all black against a white background what if on that pixel on that sort of angle there we just turn on the red part a little bit right?
Speaker 0: and it's like.
Speaker 0: we know the red you know we know that the blue is on the right side of the pixel and we know the red is on the left side of the pixel.
Speaker 0: so we'll just turn on those edge pixels some of the colors right and we can make the thing look really sharp without necessarily everything just being you know black right and a staircase.
Speaker 0: and so you have to put all this hinting information into the font so that the font renderer you know it has some knowledge in it whether it's like the Microsoft TrueType or whatever it has to have some hints right you're.
Speaker 0: that's why it's called a hint.
Speaker 0: you're sort of in the font you're giving a hint to the font renderer.
Speaker 0: here is the best way to make these letters look good on an LCD.
Speaker 0: help me out here.
Speaker 0: and if you don't do this everything looks like garbage.
Speaker 0: and that's why for many years and even still today a lot of people like hey why do fonts look so good on Apple devices and not so good on other devices?
Speaker 0: it's like they got.
Speaker 0: they were better at this earlier than other people.
Speaker 1: the rendering doesn't matter what good font you use.
Speaker 1: if it's rendered the wrong way it's gonna look weird.
Speaker 1: and beyond that what about the technology of like?
Speaker 1: if you want to put a font on a website that's actually way more complex than it used to be you can't just assume everyone has the font that you want.
Speaker 0: well it it depends right.
Speaker 0: so when you make if you're making a website in your CSS you can put the names of fonts you want to use right and if someone on their computer happens to have one of those fonts then sure enough the web browser if it's allowed to will try to use that font.
Speaker 0: yep I do give them a priority and it uses the first one on the list that it can do exactly but you can also provide a WAF file right which is basically just another sort of format of OpenType font right.
Speaker 0: you can even provide just OTF files if you wanted to but you use WAF files like the standard and as you put these font files somewhere available and you then put a in your CSS you say all right listen up web browser.
Speaker 0: there's a font.
Speaker 0: it's called Scott's font.
Speaker 0: the WAF file for it is here right and if you want to use it for this text right that's that's my top priority.
Speaker 0: you know you please use that one.
Speaker 0: you can't force them to but you sort of tell them to and you can also tell them.
Speaker 0: oh by the way enable these ligatures and you you know all your OpenType font flags also go in there.
Speaker 0: and the weight of the font the spacing of the font the kerning of the font the height you know line spacing all this you know.
Speaker 0: but you can put everything in there.
Speaker 1: but then some jerk in their web browser might have just said yeah use Arial for every website.
Speaker 1: I don't care and no one will ever see it.
Speaker 0: Arial?
Speaker 1: I've never heard anyone say the name of that font out loud before.
Speaker 0: Just Arial?
Speaker 1: It's a bad font.
Speaker 1: it's not like I use it.
Speaker 0: But yeah it's like.
Speaker 0: you know it's it's tough.
Speaker 0: and then there's the other problem.
Speaker 0: is it?
Speaker 0: nowadays a lot of people are there have been you know some various privacy issues right regarding fonts in web browsers right and there's two tricks that have been used that I'm aware of.
Speaker 0: I think there's probably others.
Speaker 0: the first trick is that they used to be able to figure out like what fonts were on your computer right and you know most people only have like the default system fonts and so all those people would look basically the same.
Speaker 1: Oh but you got a weird font.
Speaker 1: you're pretty easy to track now.
Speaker 0: Right if you install a different font it's like okay.
Speaker 0: well you know it's like if you have these fonts if you have the standard fonts plus this one extra weird font installed on your computer.
Speaker 0: that's probably unique among computers that caught that specific combination of fonts.
Speaker 0: so if the web browser can look up a list of the fonts that your computer has now they can uniquely identify you across the whole internet.
Speaker 0: it's like you visit another website and like oh that's Scott.
Speaker 0: we just saw him on that other website that has ad tracking.
Speaker 0: so as long as you block all ad tracking shit yes won't get you but if you don't and you installed even one custom font it's like that's not a uniquely identifying thing.
Speaker 0: I think web browsers may have also made changes to sort of prevent that maybe but it was a thing.
Speaker 0: if it's not still a thing.
Speaker 1: Okay cuz I got a third thing.
Speaker 0: No the second thing is that they'll make a website that just uses a weird font right and it's like you know.
Speaker 0: the font itself is now tracking right that you know the font.
Speaker 0: it's like your web browser.
Speaker 0: you told it.
Speaker 0: whenever I go to a website right download the fonts and use the ones that they tell me to use.
Speaker 0: okay well now these ten websites all use the same font file on the same font server and they see that you visit the website and that oh you've already got the font.
Speaker 0: you're not requesting it again.
Speaker 0: you must have already visited one of my ten shady website.
Speaker 0: yeah right clearly I now know who you are.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: mister already has my shady font right on the publishing side.
Speaker 1: a lot of people have been caught in shenanigans when Microsoft Word changed its default font to Calibri because that font didn't exist in public until 2007. so if someone purports to have a document from before 2007 and it is in the Calibri font.
Speaker 1: they're definitely lying and a lot not.
Speaker 1: a number of big court cases and big things have been solved by the fact that the default Microsoft Word font was in a document that was purported to be from before Microsoft released that fonts.
Speaker 0: yeah see it I guess you know the business of getting font files right.
Speaker 0: it's like there are free fonts which I already mentioned.
Speaker 0: you really want to get you know some open-source e ones.
Speaker 0: the thing is most of the open-source e fonts are gonna be you know mono space fonts that programmers made for themselves right the one font that you know.
Speaker 0: you go to Google fonts or whatever or you know something like that and you can find fonts there.
Speaker 0: but a lot of the free fonts are like not actually very good.
Speaker 0: there's a reason that they're free yeah and it's like sure you can use them and they might look nice for whatever small time thing you're doing.
Speaker 0: but as soon as you try to do anything that's serious and you want to enable any of those open type features you know you want to actually render you know produce an actual work of text that's somewhat fancy or you know typographically correct in any way and a lot of those fonts just collapse immediately.
Speaker 0: they're like no I can't do that nicely.
Speaker 0: I can't do that nicely.
Speaker 0: it doesn't matter how much you fiddle with me.
Speaker 0: it's never gonna look nice if you try to Photoshop with me because I'm not a fancy font I'm some free font.
Speaker 0: you got from somewhere right and the free fonts that support all those features are a few.
Speaker 0: you only have a few choices but one font that's free.
Speaker 0: that I can suggest.
Speaker 0: it's not one of my favorite fonts it's just a free you know sans-serif font that has a lot of features.
Speaker 0: not all of them.
Speaker 0: it doesn't have the small caps.
Speaker 0: yeah it's called inter by Rasmus Anderson.
Speaker 0: so if you just want some you know sans-serif text and you want a free font then you know there you go.
Speaker 0: but if you want fonts that look real nice you're gonna have and you you know you're actually gonna be doing some professional work with them.
Speaker 0: you know printing up something or working for a business or whatever.
Speaker 0: you got to pay for fonts and the prices are outrageous.
Speaker 1: yep now what outrageous I pay for Adobe and Adobe has Adobe fonts and you cannot do anything with every font.
Speaker 1: but the license terms are pretty good and pretty understandable.
Speaker 0: yeah most of those fonts most of those fonts though are just free fonts.
Speaker 0: also right they just happen to be in there with all the other ones but they do just work in the Adobe stuff.
Speaker 0: yeah but the problem is a lot of those fonts like I said if you actually try to do any serious typographical work a lot of them just don't support the fancy features.
Speaker 0: yeah they're.
Speaker 0: they're very bare-bones fonts.
Speaker 0: you you have to if you want fonts that actually do all those all the things correctly.
Speaker 0: your choices are limited if you don't pay money.
Speaker 1: so I guess as we've gone on long my my favorite fonts Calibri I actually do really like the default like word font like.
Speaker 1: it's a fine font.
Speaker 1: it's like very utilitarian.
Speaker 1: my favorite sans sans serif font is still source sans Pro.
Speaker 1: I've loved that thing for a long time.
Speaker 1: I use it a lot of stuff.
Speaker 1: I think it's a really good fun Berkeley mono the one that you let you.
Speaker 0: uh did you pay for that also?
Speaker 1: oh yeah it's a fucking amazing font.
Speaker 0: okay yeah I've been using that for my programming since it was a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: it's so stylish and it just feels really good.
Speaker 0: I can cross that off my list.
Speaker 0: they're gonna make a new font.
Speaker 0: at least they said they were.
Speaker 0: we'll see if they do.
Speaker 1: I do like Futura.
Speaker 0: it's like kind of a feature is also on my list.
Speaker 0: that's the 2001 Space Odyssey tell card font right.
Speaker 1: and my last one is one that is definitely not on your list and I like it for reasons highway gothic.
Speaker 1: that is the font of almost all road signs in the Western Hemisphere.
Speaker 0: okay no one cares about that.
Speaker 1: it's a cool font because it's designed for legibility and it's there.
Speaker 1: it's got some stuff going on like it.
Speaker 1: it is neat and I recommend reading about it.
Speaker 1: but to be clear do not use that in like your essay.
Speaker 0: hmm so the fonts that are on my list that rim didn't mention right.
Speaker 0: so there's charter.
Speaker 0: charter is actually a free font right.
Speaker 0: that is excellent it.
Speaker 0: I don't know if the free one has all the options in it but basically it's the text that looks like text you would find in like if you got a paperback novel.
Speaker 1: I was about to say this looks like body text in a textbook from 1978. that I would know.
Speaker 0: it's if you just buy a paperback novel off the shelf.
Speaker 0: right you know.
Speaker 0: and it's like you.
Speaker 0: look at the body text.
Speaker 0: it's very you know.
Speaker 0: it probably might not be exactly charter but it's really similar.
Speaker 0: it's like the you know and it's.
Speaker 0: it's a free easy to get you know designed in 1987 to be able to survive repeated faxings yep.
Speaker 0: so it's a. that's a good one.
Speaker 0: right is a good there's right.
Speaker 0: another one is you know the the probably one of the most classic and famous fonts is Cooper black.
Speaker 0: this is I am making a poster for my funky concert right but you have seen this font you know literally everywhere in your life right?
Speaker 0: the the sort of bulb II you know 70s disco II kind of style font.
Speaker 0: this is used everywhere you look.
Speaker 0: once you realize the name of this font and what it looks like it's one of those things were like.
Speaker 0: now you can't not notice it right?
Speaker 0: it was like a quiet part of your life.
Speaker 0: that was you know familiar to you.
Speaker 0: you just didn't have a name for it or recognize that thing.
Speaker 0: and once you know Cooper black you see Cooper black everywhere.
Speaker 0: but it's so.
Speaker 0: the reason you see it everywhere is cuz it's so good right it didn't become everywhere for no reason.
Speaker 1: wouldn't want to read a book written in it.
Speaker 0: but no that's not for that then right?
Speaker 0: so there's the Helvetica's of the world of which a rile is a bad one.
Speaker 0: right now.
Speaker 0: there are a lot of ones that are like you know newer like I guess Helvetica new and you eat right a big fan to be honest.
Speaker 0: but they're like yeah that they're.
Speaker 0: basically there's so many versions of Helvetica's right of things that people have done with it.
Speaker 0: you know tried to improve it you know update it tweak it slightly and it's to the untrained eye.
Speaker 0: it's really hard to tell any difference between a lot of them.
Speaker 0: you're like that's the same font and it's like well and then someone shows you the letters side by side and you're like okay I see that that one is crook slightly.
Speaker 0: so but you know the newer ones while I think they you know they've taken a lot of more recent.
Speaker 0: you know typographical learnings I you know at least for me and my my eyeballs I appreciate like some of the older ones I think are more stylin.
Speaker 0: so there's I guess the two are like universe which doesn't have an E at the end it's just you know it's just like universe right.
Speaker 0: and there's also accidents grotesque.
Speaker 0: they're basically like the old original real deal.
Speaker 0: you know Helvetica's and if you take the same text and put it in your regular everyday Helvetica next to the these older ones you'll see that they got a little bit more styling to them who apparently
Speaker 1: most of the the old-school ones you're talking about are classified as neo grotesques and serifs.
Speaker 0: that's yes that's correct.
Speaker 1: that's and almost all the ones that are popular were made by a small number of people in 1957.
Speaker 0: yep and then you know the the stylin font.
Speaker 0: my last font here is avant-garde gothic right which is basically you opened up a old stylin that is a good.
Speaker 0: or a fashion magazine right.
Speaker 0: or a magazine with some kind of cool spread right and the fanciness the fancy font is is all over it.
Speaker 1: this would be like the pull quote and the title but not in like the body of the text in the magazine right.
Speaker 0: the coolest thing is you know if you want to mess around with open type font features right if you want to mess around with the ligatures feature avant-garde gothic has a fuck ton of cool ligatures like if you put like certain like the letter P followed by the letter like R. I think there's a bunch of different letter combinations where you can make it do funky stuff by combining two like big letters at the start of your sentence.
Speaker 0: you can make it do like you know like the letter a with like a backwards like not italics but like weird slants.
Speaker 0: you know you could that way like you can make like the right side of the letter a straight vertically and then followed by let's say you know the letter H right.
Speaker 0: I don't know ahoy.
Speaker 0: you want to write ahoy.
Speaker 1: I mean go to the Wikipedia article about it and it just has the word avant-garde and it is showing off half the things you're talking about in one set of words.
Speaker 1: yeah the G is like overlapped with the a in such a perfect way.
Speaker 1: everything is lined up so nice everything is tighty.
Speaker 0: ITC avant-garde.
Speaker 0: yeah and you can see down here they show you all the companies that use it as their font right in there in their logo.
Speaker 0: I think the most famous one is remax the the US.
Speaker 1: well century 21 is what came to mind first and they both use it and they both compete with each other.
Speaker 0: right bike and remax you their logo.
Speaker 0: you can see the sort of slant aligning thing we're like.
Speaker 0: they have that letter M slanted forward right and then the letter a vertical on the left half.
Speaker 0: so it's it lines up.
Speaker 1: well century 21 the C is big and they have the C just merged directly into the the line that starts the E. that's at an angle.
Speaker 0: now yep but you even look at something like you know.
Speaker 0: the Macy's logo is using the same font even though it's just a lowercase.
Speaker 0: letters with a star instead of an apostrophe.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 1: oh I didn't know I didn't.
Speaker 1: I never clocked that PBS uses it because they don't use any of the fancy features.
Speaker 0: right it's like.
Speaker 0: well the thing is that one of the other things about the font is that a lot of the letters especially the lowercase ones right are circular and they're like the same circle.
Speaker 0: it's like the C are basically the same shape except the C has like a little bite taken out the right side of it right and then like if you put OCP the circle on the P will be that same circle right only with a stick hanging down.
Speaker 1: now that is bad for eligibility of long amounts of time but that is great for style right?
Speaker 0: it looks like you know a bunch of just circles in a row that are all exactly identical with like just one little thing different about them right and so it's a very fancy and clever clever font.
Speaker 1: this has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons were this episode.
Speaker 1: geek nights are Ellen Jocelyn gg dread lily 10 of our case.
Speaker 1: care makes music.
Speaker 1: Kristin on Clinton Walton Dex Finn Joel Hayes Betty Reimer Rebecca Dunn Sam Erickson turn about her and a bunch of people whose names.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna say I'm really hungry.
Speaker 1: something stuff right now and leave you with any.
Speaker 0: the most minutes will motivate up you Michael machine.
Speaker 0: each one has dramatic details perfect decisions a job plus incredible micro machine pocket place that says a police station fire station restaurant service station and more perfect pocket portables to take any place and there are many miniature place that's to play with it.
Speaker 0: each one comes with its own special edition micro machine vehicle and fun fantastic features that miraculously move raise the boat lift at the airport marina.
Speaker 0: man the gun turret at the army base.
Speaker 0: clean your car at the car wash raise the toll bridge and these place that's fit together to form a micro machine world micro machine pocket place that's so tremendously tiny so perfectly precise so dazzlingly detailed.
Speaker 0: you'll want to pocket them all.
Speaker 0: micro machines a micro machine pocket place that sold separately from glue.
Speaker 0: the smaller they are the better they are.