Speaker 1: It's Wednesday, March 15th, 2023.
Speaker 1: I'm Rim.
Speaker 0: And I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights Tonight.
Speaker 1: We're reviewing the new animated show Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur.
Speaker 1: You may know them from Marvel's Snap.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So uh, way back when Kickstarter like first came around, and even before Kickstarter, one thing that you and I were both into was having a really minimalist, thinnest possible wallet that wasn't like the traditional big ass leather George Costanza wallet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I still have a really tiny wallet, but my hope these days is that uh, they will, Apple, well New York will be one of the states that has, you know, the driver's license in your Apple wallet and then, cause literally the only two cards left in my wallet
Speaker 1: I do have to carry a MetroCard for one reason.
Speaker 1: AirTrain, there's literally no other way to pay for it.
Speaker 0: But if I want to go take the AirTrain, I would just buy one there, boop.
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah, so uh, fun fact, when I was going to London for this work trip, uh, I took the AirTrain and I get there.
Speaker 1: Every station, every machine that you could buy a MetroCard at, anywhere in that subway station at the end of the line where you get on the AirTrain, especially the ones that are near.
Speaker 1: the actual AirTrain entrance had like 10 to 15 people in line.
Speaker 1: It was like a mob you had to force your way through because nobody had MetroCards and nobody understood it and it was a gigantic shit show.
Speaker 1: The only reason I was able to get through that massive crowd is cause I happened to have a MetroCard in my wallet that I didn't even know I had.
Speaker 1: that I found when I dug through my wallet.
Speaker 1: It was like stuck between two credit cards and I happened to have some money on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, the AirTrain fare has increased to $825, right?
Speaker 1: Which is a weird, non-round number that I hate even more.
Speaker 0: Right, but let's say I'm about to go and use the AirTrain, right?
Speaker 1: Being a wise New Yorker Oh yeah, you go to a MetroCard other than the one in Jamaica, like obviously.
Speaker 0: Right, I would just, while I'm about to get on the E, I would go pick up a 1650 MetroCard precisely So London, similarly, they got something like Omniknight.
Speaker 1: Then I would throw it out In London.
Speaker 1: now, you just swipe a credit card or an iWatch or whatever just like you do in New York.
Speaker 1: So I have a bunch of OysterCards with money on them, so I'm just using them every time I go to London until they run out of money.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: But, so anyway, I decided because I had, we had those plastic wallets that we bought that I think we reviewed on Geek Nights and like made a big deal of that.
Speaker 0: That was a super long time ago, the plastic wallets Yep, I still have one of those.
Speaker 1: I use it as my, I call it my stash wallet or my secondary wallet.
Speaker 1: All the cards that I need to keep but I don't need to carry every day are actually in that other wallet.
Speaker 0: No, I have them in a Ziploc bag, I don't know.
Speaker 1: But, well I kickstarted a wallet a long, long time ago that I've been using like this whole time.
Speaker 1: I've been using this wallet for a long, long time and I really liked it, it was super minimalist Had that little carbon money clip on the end.
Speaker 1: I got a new credit card.
Speaker 1: recently I actually got a new card, like an Amex to get some rewards and all that biz.
Speaker 1: And I did a purge of my wallet and I discovered that I could reduce what was in my wallet by more than 50% And what I, but the prime, that was fine, that was great.
Speaker 1: The wallet I had kickstarted was so old and had slowly sagged and expanded because of the leather and time and my butt.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the cards, cards fell out if you didn't put them up in there.
Speaker 1: I took all the cards out of the wallet, I set the wallet on the table And a credit card just like popped out of the wallet and fell on the floor.
Speaker 1: And I was like, that can't stand, that's going to be a big problem immediately.
Speaker 1: So I bought what I hope is the last wallet I ever own And I found a really, really good wallet that is made of metal And it's only designed to carry a very small number of cards.
Speaker 0: Doesn't even have a money clip.
Speaker 0: There's a whole bunch of those.
Speaker 1: When we were early geek nights at those plastic wallets There were two, there was like that plastic wallet and one other company making a plastic wallet.
Speaker 0: The small wallet was like a brand new, I mean I'm sure it wasn't brand new.
Speaker 0: There had probably been some in the past because grandpa's all had money clips and whatever.
Speaker 0: But it's like the small wallet that only held a few cards and not like 100 photos of your whole family And a plastic window for your license and a whole area, a billfold area.
Speaker 0: Every single wallet I had up until then was that style The old style that held every fucking thing in the universe.
Speaker 1: I used to keep like five checks in my wallet just in case I needed a check.
Speaker 0: The small ones were just becoming a thing.
Speaker 0: We were ahead of the curve And now there's just hundreds of them, 10 to 1000 different choices.
Speaker 0: They're all pretty much the same.
Speaker 0: But I'm hoping that yes, the only two cards that are left in my wallet Even my insurance cards are in my phone now Are my driver's license, which New York could partner with Apple to get it in the Apple Wallet.
Speaker 0: Oh they could But they haven't.
Speaker 0: And then I have a credit card in there.
Speaker 0: But that credit card is also in Apple Pay And I very, very, very, very, very rarely actually have to swipe the card.
Speaker 1: I actually don't even need to carry this wallet and I would be fine most days.
Speaker 0: Yeah The only other exception is FSA card Which I was able to add the FSA card to Apple Pay.
Speaker 1: Whoa I would never have believed that would actually work Because FSA cards are all weird on the back end.
Speaker 0: That's exactly right.
Speaker 0: So I added it to Apple Pay.
Speaker 0: It showed up in the Apple Wallet just fine.
Speaker 1: That is amazing.
Speaker 1: Honestly I am astonished by that.
Speaker 0: I'm not done yet You're not letting me finish.
Speaker 0: I tried to go and actually use it.
Speaker 1: Okay Okay I'm less astonished.
Speaker 0: It showed up even the right picture.
Speaker 0: The picture in Apple Pay matched.
Speaker 0: It looked like the card.
Speaker 1: I got so excited.
Speaker 0: I thought it worked.
Speaker 0: There was no indication that it wasn't going to work.
Speaker 0: And then when I tried to use it It wanted like a PIN number And it's like it was fighting with me.
Speaker 0: And I was like what the fuck is this?
Speaker 0: Why isn't it just working?
Speaker 0: And I was like Now if I have to go buy an FSA thing I bring the actual card Which does not even have a chip in it.
Speaker 0: You have to swipe it like it's 19 2000 something.
Speaker 0: So Nothing much I can do about that But I use that so rarely.
Speaker 0: It doesn't need to live in the wallet.
Speaker 1: So I did my research.
Speaker 1: I looked around and I found what I think Is the best possible wallet And I really hope This is the last wallet I ever Own in my life.
Speaker 1: It's made of metal.
Speaker 1: I think it'll last forever.
Speaker 1: It's way thin It's way comfy.
Speaker 1: It's called the Vulkit And based on all my research I'm just going to say I think it's the best one.
Speaker 1: There were some that all Looked equivalent but they were way more expensive.
Speaker 1: And there were some that looked equivalent That were so cheap With brand names that I did not trust That were only sold on Amazon And didn't seem to have websites That I also did not trust.
Speaker 1: This seems to be like the perfect storm of money And it's pretty good.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So also It's finally warm.
Speaker 1: I biked home from work today.
Speaker 0: How warm could it be?
Speaker 0: It's like 45 out It's 43, that's cold.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's bike weather That's cold.
Speaker 1: That is, let's bike to Poughkeepsie Let's go, it's biking and hiking season That's, don't even go outside At 43 At Fahrenheit Which is Ah yes, Fahrenheit.
Speaker 1: So I got 6 degrees.
Speaker 1: I did get a bunch of European co-workers to come around On the whole Fahrenheit vs Celsius thing And with one exception One of my teams over in Germany They all agreed, they're like Oh, Fahrenheit actually makes more sense And they're like kinda into it.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: Okay They like the argument of It's a scale from 0 to 100 And 100 is really hot and 0 is dangerously cold And it's the human scale of temperature.
Speaker 1: And they were kinda into that.
Speaker 1: But anyway I got a little mini Geek bite of something I did not watch Which I think this is more.
Speaker 0: How can you geek bite something you didn't watch?
Speaker 0: Isn't that just prejudice?
Speaker 1: I mean I did this once, long ago.
Speaker 1: You might remember an anime that was popular For a few minutes called Attack on Titan That had a really great first season And then kinda just goes nowhere And isn't worth watching at all after that point.
Speaker 1: So there was an anime we were watching Way back, we watched one season of it.
Speaker 1: We even reviewed it Made in Abyss.
Speaker 1: And the only things you need to know about Made in Abyss Are the person who made.
Speaker 1: the manga Is definitely A bad person who likes bad things.
Speaker 1: I think I can elaborate on that.
Speaker 1: You can look at this thing And you will know exactly what I mean.
Speaker 1: This is bad stuff.
Speaker 1: This is definitely a bad person.
Speaker 0: It's a bunny drop scenario.
Speaker 1: Yup And the anime was Way less of that Than the manga.
Speaker 1: Though if I had known what was in the manga Before I had watched the anime I don't think I would have even watched the anime.
Speaker 1: But we're here, we watched that first season And it was alright, not the worst.
Speaker 1: I was moderately intrigued by the usual Terrible secrets.
Speaker 0: Not the worst, I think you liked it a lot more.
Speaker 0: If we go back and listen to the episode You're probably like, oh this is great.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm pretty sure I actually did go back and listen to some of that episode Because I have.
Speaker 1: I put a bunch of our anime reviews on YouTube a long time ago Like a few years ago During COVID when I was bored And we were both really into it.
Speaker 1: But we also both spent like 15 minutes Talking about how we think the creator is creepy And how the show Is like right on the line Of.
Speaker 1: maybe nobody should watch this And maybe we should just burn this creator's works.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe the listener will go back To that episode and verify For him is lying or not.
Speaker 0: I'm too lazy.
Speaker 1: I was vaguely curious.
Speaker 1: Just like with Attack on Titan, I wanted to know what was in the basement And turns out the answer sucks.
Speaker 1: I kind of want to know What's at the bottom of the abyss.
Speaker 1: I am confident the answer sucks But the reason I'm warning all of you is If you had any intention Of watching the newer Season of this show.
Speaker 1: A friend of ours Said some words About what happens In part of this season And I looked at a wiki and confirmed Unless you are really into Underage anal glands.
Speaker 1: Do not watch Made in Abyss season 2.
Speaker 1: Just assume that it is Not to be seen That the show just was never made.
Speaker 0: Just forget about it Alright, well those three words Have definitely turned me off From watching that show ever again.
Speaker 1: I read a couple paragraphs of a wiki And those were the least Disturbing three words in that paragraph.
Speaker 1: I'm done Do not engage.
Speaker 0: So I guess the manga creeped into the anime even more.
Speaker 0: Is what you're saying.
Speaker 1: I think that was inevitable.
Speaker 0: It's not inevitable.
Speaker 0: You can do a full on rewrite.
Speaker 0: It's like back in the day.
Speaker 0: we used to complain That the anime versions of things were nothing like the manga.
Speaker 0: It's like the anime is nothing Like Ghost in the Shell.
Speaker 0: The animated versions of things Were like huge divergences From the original source material.
Speaker 1: But sometimes, like with Trigun That is literally just better.
Speaker 0: That's another great example.
Speaker 0: But then, you got these cases.
Speaker 0: It seems like the past decade or so.
Speaker 0: It's like a lot of the animes Are very, very just literal Reproductions of the manga.
Speaker 1: And it's like, on the one hand You want a monster manga as an anime.
Speaker 1: Guess what, it is literally just monster Scene for scene, line for line, shot for shot.
Speaker 1: That sucks, doesn't it?
Speaker 0: Right, it's like.
Speaker 0: on the one hand I have this purist Urge of like a nerd.
Speaker 0: It's like I see something like a Spiderman movie And they'll change something.
Speaker 0: It's like Spiderman has biological webs Instead of a device The web shooter device that he makes.
Speaker 0: And it's like, I'm mad about that But it's like, it doesn't need to be Frame for frame the exact same thing As a Spiderman comic.
Speaker 0: Because then what's the purpose of even making it?
Speaker 0: I've already read that.
Speaker 0: Why would I read it again?
Speaker 1: There is a window that's not explored here And that window is what a few of those High budget But brief anime OAVs Would do in the 90s and early 2000s.
Speaker 1: Where?
Speaker 1: what if you just faithfully recreate Some scenes from a manga But you animate the ever living fuck out of them?
Speaker 1: You can do that And that's fine, I'm down with that.
Speaker 0: The other thing you can do is If you really care about Purism and sticking to the canon Don't make your adaptation a retelling.
Speaker 0: Make your adaptation An additional story In the same universe With the same characters.
Speaker 0: possibly It's almost like.
Speaker 0: Obviously you wouldn't want to make it A sequel to the manga Because the people who haven't read the manga Can't watch it.
Speaker 0: But you can definitely make A side deal Or something that would still be Entriable For people who haven't read it.
Speaker 1: We've talked about it on Geek Nights a lot.
Speaker 1: Sometimes if the source material Is S tier Then remakes of it Are just going to be a Degraded form of it in some way.
Speaker 1: Like Monster, no matter how good it is That manga is just like A work of art to be treasured by humanity.
Speaker 1: And that's not it But something that's not actually That good, like say the Trigun manga.
Speaker 1: The perfect storm Is when you take the good parts out of it And you just rewrite the rest.
Speaker 0: Well the other thing is that You can sometimes Even if you don't really change Too much from the source material You can enhance If your medium The way you tell the story In the different medium is transformative enough That it can be worthwhile.
Speaker 0: For example You have Initial D the manga But Initial D the anime Is basically the same fucking thing.
Speaker 0: It's really close Except Eurobeat.
Speaker 0: It's like you added some value With that Eurobeat in there.
Speaker 0: That actually then Feeds and enhances It's existence enhances the manga Because now someone goes to read the manga.
Speaker 0: Eurobeat plays If you just read the manga.
Speaker 0: before the anime existed No Eurobeat would play When you read the manga But now you open up to any page And music plays.
Speaker 1: So The moral of this is Do not watch any more Made in Abyss However much you watch.
Speaker 1: just declare bankruptcy On that and move on.
Speaker 1: Got any news?
Speaker 0: Yeah so The NHL and Disney Did a thing right because Hockey is on ESPN now And it was a really New thing.
Speaker 0: it happened yesterday.
Speaker 0: I was at in person at Madison Square Garden At the actual hockey game.
Speaker 0: That was the one that went with this Thing.
Speaker 0: so what they did is apparently There's some kids cartoon on Disney Something called Big City Greens.
Speaker 0: I never heard of this show before.
Speaker 0: If it wasn't for this I still wouldn't know about the show.
Speaker 0: I don't know about the show.
Speaker 0: It's a kids show Kids cartoon.
Speaker 0: it exists right.
Speaker 0: And what they did Is for this one NHL game that was on ESPN Right yesterday March 14th They took The tracking data.
Speaker 0: There's already tracking data for basically Every NHL game in the players Equipment and in The puck right.
Speaker 0: They just have it already.
Speaker 0: so They didn't add anything new To that.
Speaker 0: but what they did is they Collected that data in real time something They were already doing for every game And they fed it into Basically a video game Effectively speaking As the controller inputs Right.
Speaker 0: so each player by playing Hockey without even thinking about This.
Speaker 0: other thing that was happening Right was unknowing To them.
Speaker 0: I guess they might have known About it but that's not like they were thinking about it While they were playing.
Speaker 0: they were just playing hockey.
Speaker 0: But Their body movements and the Location of the puck were the Inputs into a video game And in the video game There were basically Representations of many of the players.
Speaker 0: Some of the players the goalies and a couple others Were replaced by characters From the cartoon show.
Speaker 0: I don't know who got Replaced.
Speaker 0: besides the goalies.
Speaker 1: I don't actually know anything about the show.
Speaker 1: Big City Greens.
Speaker 0: I mean I said that already.
Speaker 0: They had different Commentators so Kevin Weeks and Someone else I think were commentating This video game As opposed to commentating on the Actual game.
Speaker 0: there was.
Speaker 0: There was a normal broadcast of the game on ESPN Also right but on Disney Disney XD.
Speaker 0: I think you could watch On ESPN Plus also.
Speaker 0: They basically had an alternate Broadcast of the game where instead of Watching video footage of the game You were watching this video game To which the inputs were the real Players.
Speaker 0: so the game played out The same way as it played in real life Except for the referee.
Speaker 0: that was Also a chicken that Would disappear and reappear To do puck puck drops and disappear Again and Could only say buck buck buck buck.
Speaker 0: And it was pretty cute chicken.
Speaker 1: It was overall pretty cool.
Speaker 1: I love This idea of telemetry driven visualization.
Speaker 0: Yeah so the graphics Of it were you know you look At it and you're like wow that's not great right.
Speaker 0: And there was even a big goal where like the Puck teleported and teleported Right.
Speaker 0: it was like everyone's making jokes like that's Offsides.
Speaker 0: maybe Right you know but You know for as much as people were Like ah this is stupid right whatever I think.
Speaker 0: actually the Response to this not just from You know there were those kind of fans who were like Ah this is dumb it's not funny.
Speaker 1: The article I found all the comments You know the part of the internet you should never look at On a website are old men who were like If the NHL wants to grow the game They shouldn't do this technological mumbo Jumbo kids are distracted with their phones.
Speaker 0: Right it's like You know.
Speaker 0: am I gonna watch this?
Speaker 0: No Right why would I watch this?
Speaker 1: I watched a few minutes Of it just to see if it worked.
Speaker 0: Yeah but the point is is that Was it successful?
Speaker 0: I don't have the numbers So I can't say how to what degree It was successful but anecdotally There were people Who said that their kids Were into it and Wanted to watch the whole thing And those kids would not sit.
Speaker 0: Their kids were not you know watching Regular hockey games right.
Speaker 0: So that's a positive.
Speaker 0: And secondly Secondly the hockey people Right in the you know like Even though you know in advance They might have been grumbly grumbly.
Speaker 0: In the social media Among hockey fans A lot of people were posting Clips from this game.
Speaker 0: Right the video game version Like everyone wanted to see.
Speaker 0: like oh What did that goal look like?
Speaker 0: They're like.
Speaker 0: you know I was at the game and there was actually a great play Where You know Igor the goalie Had an assist right with a big long pass And so everyone was like.
Speaker 0: I think there was a character called Granny Or something that was taking the place of Igor.
Speaker 1: I might have caused A minor disturbance In our Blaze in the Dark game because I had the game on On the other monitor and that happened.
Speaker 0: Yeah I forgot to view myself But everyone was like oh Granny with the huge assist.
Speaker 0: Oh right it's like This was you know in its really Somewhat you know shabby Implementation.
Speaker 0: Pretty good Right you know.
Speaker 0: it made a bigger Splash than anticipated at least Within hockey circle.
Speaker 0: Cool thing to do And this was only the first one.
Speaker 1: This was like baby's first MVP.
Speaker 0: You give this shit.
Speaker 0: A few years and like this is gonna be Some hot stuff Right And I think it'll be pretty exciting Actually.
Speaker 1: so It's interesting because I remember way back when I was a kid We went to some like Red Wings Fan access event Cause.
Speaker 1: you know my family.
Speaker 1: we were like really into hockey My mom and brother even way more than me And you're hitting autographs and stuff.
Speaker 1: And they had a little exhibit Where you would sit there you put on headphones And you would hear A hockey game commentary like an old hockey game And you would have to draw In a series of little like storyboards What the fuck happened in these plays.
Speaker 1: And then You would see the video of what was Actually being commented on to see how accurate You were based on hearing the commentary.
Speaker 1: And the thing that always struck me about hockey Was that The only thing that a lot of people would get wrong Is they'd have like the left side or the right side wrong.
Speaker 1: But in terms of how the play evolved You can.
Speaker 1: You know a lot about what's going on Just from that very simple commentary.
Speaker 1: that's leaving A lot of information out At least on a broad level.
Speaker 1: I bet you could even train an AI model to listen to commentary And animate a hockey game pretty well.
Speaker 0: I think that you know.
Speaker 0: The final form of this Really is just full VR sports right where a person Isn't on ice they're not wearing Skates.
Speaker 0: they're not right.
Speaker 0: it's like They're just somewhere where there's Enough tracking on their bod Right and they make the movements And they're wearing some kind of goggles.
Speaker 0: So it looks like hockey to them Right but they're really just playing a video game.
Speaker 1: There is already Installation level tennis where you have A person on each side of a full sized tennis court.
Speaker 0: There's golf simulators.
Speaker 1: Yeah no you have people standing on the On either side of a full sized indoor tennis court Wearing VR helmets but not Consumer.
Speaker 1: this is like installation VR where it's using the room And like it's not technology we could get And you run at full speed And play for real tennis But you're in a virtual fucked up World.
Speaker 0: I don't see the Point of that though?
Speaker 1: Well cause there's like pits don't fall In them and there's stuff happening and it's Oh okay it's not.
Speaker 1: It's not just like You put on the VR helmet and everything looks the same.
Speaker 0: It's VR Mario Tennis.
Speaker 0: That's what you're saying.
Speaker 1: This also For sportspectation like imagine Just if you had a VR headset If you could buy a really cheap hockey Ticket and just watch the game like you're Sitting in the front row or sitting in any fucking Seat you want or you're in Igor Shostakin watching what he sees.
Speaker 0: Right it's like they.
Speaker 0: Instead of having to put cameras All over they just need to put enough Tracking yeah telemetry.
Speaker 0: And then for the broadcast of the game.
Speaker 0: It's like right now.
Speaker 0: you know if you're watching A live broadcast of a sporting event They can only put cameras You know in certain places right It's like they have to not block the views of the Spectators they have to not get in the way of the players.
Speaker 0: They can only go where they're like mountable.
Speaker 0: Right it's like this limit.
Speaker 0: You know how big is the camera that they're putting in different Places and you know you can't just Put cameras in you know but with if you Have if you're just recreating the Game exactly in a Digital world you can just put A camera in fucking anywhere because the camera is Virtual.
Speaker 1: yeah right and telemetry data Is cheap like if any of you are video gamers because This is Wednesday.
Speaker 1: we don't talk about this stuff that much.
Speaker 1: When you're playing an FPS with a bunch of other people The only data that's Going back and forth between these clients Is the telemetry data of where all the Objects are and how they're interacting.
Speaker 1: Every end point is Rendering a view based on that Pure telemetry data.
Speaker 0: So yeah I think that this is.
Speaker 0: you know Most people don't have any idea.
Speaker 0: this even Happened but this is Like a first of its kind deal.
Speaker 0: it happened Yesterday while we were at the game.
Speaker 0: they were showing Some clips of it on the scoreboard In the arena after the Fact.
Speaker 1: but a good idea.
Speaker 0: this is Sort of like you know if you think about like Hatsune Miku version 1 and where it is Today.
Speaker 0: like this is gonna Evolve right along that.
Speaker 1: I think a lot Of people are distracted by all the AI, ML, GPT whatever nonsense Going on and people I think A lot of people aren't.
Speaker 1: They're drastically underestimating What this is and what it's Going to be.
Speaker 0: I'm hopeful for this right especially you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah Maybe some kids out there are gonna Watch hockey.
Speaker 1: now We gotta get more people watching hockey.
Speaker 1: And last little news in case you were unaware You know Gkids the masters Of you wanna see some good animation In theaters in America.
Speaker 1: They're doing once again this year Like in March End of March, April, May, June, July A bunch of the Ghibli movies Including the live action Spirited Away play Are just gonna be in theaters all over America.
Speaker 0: well they do this.
Speaker 0: they do This every year but the play is the New one because the basically the live Action you know theatrical Spirited Away is gonna be performed In Japan and there will be a Live stream of it to Movie theaters.
Speaker 1: you know in the US April 23rd and April 27th we can Just go see it at the start of Kauffman like right by us.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm gonna probably go to the movie Theater nearby and you know watch It the same time.
Speaker 0: people in Japan Are in the theater seeing it right Which is uh People don't realize this.
Speaker 0: it's like.
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: I went to the.
Speaker 0: I've known for a while that they do the Fathom events.
Speaker 0: Yeah basically one of the things that they do Also along similar lines is They'll show the Metropolitan Opera On the screen either live Or recorded.
Speaker 0: and It's like I went to the opera recently And that shit's expensive and a movie Ticket is way cheaper.
Speaker 0: And it's like they don't sell a lot of DVDs of that or put it on YouTube.
Speaker 0: A lot right.
Speaker 0: so um It's you know maybe there's pirates out there I guess probably.
Speaker 0: but Um that's probably the least Expensive way to see It like value wise right.
Speaker 0: So if you don't have a world Class opera house where you live but you have A movie theater Maybe you should go to one of those.
Speaker 0: It would probably be worth it.
Speaker 1: But anyway things Of the day.
Speaker 1: so uh Do you ever wonder like On a modern ship like when we take the ferry Even uh over to uh Sandy Hook There's lifeboats you ever Wonder like how they work and what's in them And like what a modern boat looks like.
Speaker 0: Harry doesn't have a big fancy lifeboat like this.
Speaker 1: Uh they have.
Speaker 1: they have some that are only A step down from this.
Speaker 1: they have the ones that Roll out from the side of the boat.
Speaker 1: I found this video.
Speaker 0: A lot of things have the inflatable ones A little triangle in front yep.
Speaker 1: But uh imagine if you're on like a cruise ship in the middle of the Pacific And there's those gigantic Orange lifeboats the ones that are basically Just boats like.
Speaker 1: I realized when I found this video I didn't know anything about them like I Couldn't.
Speaker 1: even I didn't even know what they looked like Inside how they worked Nothing.
Speaker 1: and this video.
Speaker 0: we've never been In one.
Speaker 1: why would you know why would you be?
Speaker 0: they're not gonna Let me unless you unless you had some boat training Or something right or I Guess to people when they go on cruises Never been on a cruise.
Speaker 0: they don't know they.
Speaker 1: They have a muster thing where all they do is make You stand where the lifeboats are gonna be And tell you that you might have to get into Them but they don't teach you anything about them.
Speaker 1: Okay I learned this because During COVID When for some reason capitalism Cruises were still happening Cruises didn't have to do that muster Because that got too many people together in the same place At the same time and they relatively recently Had to start doing that again.
Speaker 1: And uh that's why I learned About this because that was in the news.
Speaker 1: and then I Found this video because I remembered like wait lifeboats The fuck's even in those?
Speaker 0: It seems like you know a cruise should do more Than like a flight but Oh you would think that.
Speaker 1: but uh no Cruises suck.
Speaker 1: uh you know My feelings.
Speaker 1: on cruises you have similar feelings.
Speaker 0: I'm not a fan of going on a cruise.
Speaker 0: There are kinds of cruises that could be cool.
Speaker 0: I have thought about the buy a home On a cruise that goes around the world and you Spend three years of your life doing that and nothing else.
Speaker 1: I've also thought about just book a birth On a cargo ship and spend a month going Across the Pacific like kind of want to do that For real not even joking.
Speaker 0: I mean it depends on the.
Speaker 0: you know You might go into it with uh rose colored Glasses and then you know a week in you're like That's enough of that.
Speaker 0: they're like well you're stuck in this Uncomfortable ass boat with us now.
Speaker 1: But worst case scenario one I know They're pretty comfortable.
Speaker 1: I've watched a bunch of Documentaries on this and two Oh no I have to just play Video games and hang out with Emily and drink And eat food and like Okay this is way Better than my working life And it costs like six dollars A day alright.
Speaker 1: Anyway So this is a video that will tell you what the deal Is with modern Lifeboats and it's Way cooler than I thought.
Speaker 1: there's a lot going on.
Speaker 0: There is a sponsor on this video.
Speaker 0: I Dislike the sponsor.
Speaker 0: you should not Patronize the sponsor of the video.
Speaker 1: So the secret if you don't know This I assume Scott knows this.
Speaker 1: A lot of internet people know it.
Speaker 1: ad block Can block between ad block and just Paying for YouTube.
Speaker 1: you don't see ads but That doesn't block the natural ad.
Speaker 1: read Where you're watching like a SciShow video And they pause for a second and then they're like Speaking of blah blah blah Brilliant something You know.
Speaker 1: the old timey ad read Can't?
Speaker 1: it's hard to block those.
Speaker 1: The way you block those on YouTube Is if you've noticed if you hover Over the timeline on a modern YouTube video You see the heat map of what Parts of the video people have watched more or watched Over and over again.
Speaker 1: and in any video With ad reads you'll see a huge hump.
Speaker 1: Occasionally that hump Is all the people trying to skip the ad read.
Speaker 1: So hover Over look for the hump Click on the end of the hump And you'll always be past the ad read Well you also.
Speaker 0: there's an extension I think With community submitted time Codes that will automatically skip The ads for you.
Speaker 0: but I just You know I just yeah Whenever an ad read starts I just click forward until it's gone.
Speaker 1: But the hump is the way to find it Especially if you watch weird videos that no one Bothered to put time codes in for where the ad reads are.
Speaker 1: So anyway what do you got?
Speaker 0: So If you ever go see an old timey Silent film right You know.
Speaker 0: like if you Go on YouTube and look for a silent film It won't actually be Silent right?
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: yeah there's gonna be like title cards for all the Dialogue if there is any And you won't hear anyone talking.
Speaker 0: But there's like a little old timey Music playing like do do do do do do Like on a piano probably right.
Speaker 0: Maybe a few sound effects that whistle Like if there's a car It'll go like honk honk or a ooga.
Speaker 0: Right it's like there's noises Going on even though it's a silent Film.
Speaker 0: where were those noises Coming from?
Speaker 0: well sometimes the noises Were coming from just people In the back right making noises Sometimes you know it depends on Where you saw the silent film and when and All kinds of things.
Speaker 0: but it's not like.
Speaker 1: It's not like they had a and they're just watching the movie With you and they're like they have a sheet that says Make the gunshot noise around this time And they watch the movie.
Speaker 1: they kind of just like Bang on something.
Speaker 0: yep.
Speaker 0: But there was apparently an instrument That I never knew about Until recently called the photo player.
Speaker 0: And what is a photo player?
Speaker 0: it's basically A non portable one man Band plus player piano in one Machine yep with a Very important addition Of the sound effects generators.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: well so it's basically A player piano right With one additional modification.
Speaker 0: Is that you can?
Speaker 0: you can get Like.
Speaker 0: you can get two rolls going on there.
Speaker 0: So you can seamlessly go from roll one To roll two to roll three without a gap Because you can.
Speaker 0: you can get that because the role Of player piano music is Shorter than the movie right.
Speaker 0: so you need to Be able to queue up rolls back and forth Between the two rollers right.
Speaker 0: And then it's got An organ in addition to a piano.
Speaker 0: So it's a it's a it's.
Speaker 0: you know you got This one keyboard going but you can play the organ Or the piano or kind of both right.
Speaker 0: So you get all kinds of more Noises going on there.
Speaker 0: you know The main feature of the organ that the piano doesn't Have is sort of the infinite sustain Which you kind of need for a lot of things.
Speaker 0: And then You got foot pedals and pull Levers and all sorts of things because next To the piano organ Is a box and in that box you got a Drum and a cowbell And horns and Toot flutes and chimes And all sorts of fucking
Speaker 1: That you hear in a lot of old cartoons.
Speaker 0: Yeah just all sorts of fucking things In there.
Speaker 0: right and the person operating Since the player piano role Is you know you could play the piano With your hands but the role is Taking care of that.
Speaker 0: you're using your hands To like change the organ settings You know and and pull the Things and honk the horns right.
Speaker 0: And as long as you know if you know the film Well which you're if it's your job to Operate this instrument then yeah Yeah you're gonna do this over and over again Like a hundred times for every night.
Speaker 0: you probably You probably practice with the movie like once Or twice before you do it for real right?
Speaker 0: It's like the scene where the horn comes in.
Speaker 0: you reach over And go honk honk right.
Speaker 0: if there's two Cars you use the second horn For car number two.
Speaker 0: It's like so there's this guy Joe Renato And on YouTube you will find.
Speaker 0: I'm just linking to one of the videos but you just Search for this guy.
Speaker 0: basically This old guy has made Photo player like his thing.
Speaker 0: He is the photo player guy.
Speaker 1: in fact The video you're picking he's got one.
Speaker 0: there's not that Many left in the world.
Speaker 1: the video you play It real well as your thing of the day.
Speaker 1: The first comment on it is from him Explaining how he got that Photo player and it is way Better of a story than I expected.
Speaker 0: Yeah but he's basically you know The photo player expert.
Speaker 0: dude there's tons Of videos on YouTube with this one guy Being the photo player guy.
Speaker 0: You can learn all about.
Speaker 0: you know He's there sharing all the information There is to know about this instrument Where it came from who made it Other versions of it how many are left How it works etc.
Speaker 0: etc.
Speaker 0: So if this one Video doesn't satisfy You can search for his name And you will be inundated With everything you need to know about this.
Speaker 0: And I think the moral here Is that there's a lot of you know White nerdy comic book guys out there Who are collecting various Things simply For the sake of You know collecting and materialism And etc.
Speaker 0: etc.
Speaker 0: Right whether it's baseball cards or board games Or comics or whatever.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: If you are going to collect something And you are not Actually a museum Right you're just a person.
Speaker 0: You should aspire To be like Joe Renato Right who has collected A photo player Right but really has collected Knowledge of the photo player And shared it and acted as A museum.
Speaker 0: right if you just got A collection in your house it's like Uh I'm not a fan.
Speaker 1: Indiana Jones has some words for you.
Speaker 0: That's right but if you do It the Joe Renato way right Then I'm going to be a huge fan.
Speaker 0: Complete opposite right.
Speaker 0: so if You got a big ol' collection Of something right Start you know acting Like Joe Renato does with that collection And that would be totally awesome.
Speaker 1: In the meta moment The Geek Nights Book Club book Is the satanic Versus.
Speaker 1: having read The first couple of chapters This is an S tier book.
Speaker 1: It is S tier literature.
Speaker 1: It is.
Speaker 1: there's a lot going on here.
Speaker 0: I haven't even read one word yet.
Speaker 0: Satan is not The latest fan upon me.
Speaker 1: Honestly read the first page Before you don't even bother.
Speaker 1: Just read the first page and you'll see what I mean.
Speaker 0: I got a lot of shit to do.
Speaker 0: we'll see.
Speaker 0: Also we will be on Thursday March 23rd.
Speaker 1: next week.
Speaker 0: That's real soon.
Speaker 1: At 2.30pm eastern time in the Bumblebee Theater we will have a panel That very few people have seen And even the people Who have seen it saw an early Prototype version of it either at a Magfest where we did it once Or in the video that Magfest uploaded Or the patrons Saw an audio only version of it With the slides.
Speaker 1: I've already been planning a lot of changes to this Before next week.
Speaker 1: Can competitive and casual coexist?
Speaker 1: And the spoiler answer Is in the same game?
Speaker 0: Fuck no Absolutely not Probably not right.
Speaker 0: it's tough.
Speaker 1: If you can make them coexist You will be a billionaire.
Speaker 0: Yeah it's one of those things where it's like.
Speaker 0: does P equal NP?
Speaker 0: and it's like?
Speaker 0: well you know I can't say for sure.
Speaker 0: otherwise I'd be Like a zillionaire right?
Speaker 0: I'll be famous Forever but we're pretty sure What the answer is right?
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: so Marvel.
Speaker 1: As you know Marvel Marvel's made a bunch of stuff.
Speaker 0: When's Marvel?
Speaker 1: So I'll be honest I wasn't familiar with The Moon Girl or I guess originally Moon Boy or Devil Dinosaur Like.
Speaker 1: that was not a part of the Marvel universe I knew anything about.
Speaker 0: I knew I knew that they were characters In Marvel comic books but I had never Read a single comic book or seen Anything that contained them.
Speaker 1: I don't think I knew that Devil Dinosaur Existed until I saw it in Marvel Snap.
Speaker 0: to be honest Devil Dinosaur is a character that I knew existed in the Marvel universe But I had never read even a single Comic book or seen any cartoon or any Anything that had Devil Dinosaur in it.
Speaker 0: I didn't even have a collectible card with Devil Dinosaur on it.
Speaker 0: but I knew there was a Marvel character called Devil Dinosaur And that character was indeed A literal dinosaur And that was the extent of my knowledge.
Speaker 1: I spent before this show About 45 seconds Reading about The origin of Devil Dinosaur And the origin of Moon Boy Which came before Moon Girl.
Speaker 0: I didn't know anything about this.
Speaker 0: so tell me All I knew was that they were characters That existed with those names in Marvel comics.
Speaker 0: The end So it's.
Speaker 1: I don't want to say it's bad But it's not good.
Speaker 1: Okay It's Jack Kirby.
Speaker 1: Jack Kirby was the one who brought this out.
Speaker 1: This is 70's Marvel.
Speaker 1: Moon Boy is a Monkey man who comes from a Dinosaur planet And Devil Dinosaur is smarter than him And I lost interest after that point.
Speaker 1: So I don't actually know anything else Okay But they come from a planet where there's a bunch of terrible crap going on And it sucks.
Speaker 0: Maybe I will go read The first issue of Wherever that happens and know the deal.
Speaker 1: That should only take me like Five minutes.
Speaker 1: So at least it is in it's own comic called Devil Dinosaur volume 1 Alright Written and drawn by Jack Kirby in 1978.
Speaker 0: Alright well I'm sure that I can read that In about five minutes.
Speaker 1: I don't think Literally anything From the entire history Of Moon Boy or Devil Dinosaur In any way matters to The modern Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur.
Speaker 0: They might as well be Completely separate things.
Speaker 0: There's no way for me to know if there are Callbacks or connections Between the two obviously because I didn't even Know anything about the original.
Speaker 0: but If there are they don't matter.
Speaker 0: You don't need to know them And they might not even exist.
Speaker 1: The only other thing I learned which If you watch Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur Is pretty apparent within about Four interactions with the Devil Dinosaur.
Speaker 1: Devil Dinosaur Is canonically as smart as or smarter Than a human like straight up Just day one.
Speaker 1: the Devil Dino Knows his shit.
Speaker 1: So Marvel released Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur animated show And the cool thing is the First episode which is a straight Up Marvel origin Story of a character Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur Two characters.
Speaker 1: I guess It's just free on YouTube.
Speaker 1: you can just watch it.
Speaker 1: It's like a double episode.
Speaker 1: The second episode of the show is also Just free on YouTube.
Speaker 1: I think you have to subscribe To something to see more.
Speaker 1: but those two Episodes are just free.
Speaker 0: I imagine it's Disney Plus right?
Speaker 0: They're on Disney Plus?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Okay I watched the free Episodes and then I stopped.
Speaker 0: I watched one free Episode the big The big long first one And it's pretty good.
Speaker 1: there's a lot going On here.
Speaker 1: we're going to review it right now.
Speaker 0: There are eight episodes in one Season and It premiered on Disney Channel and was released On Disney Plus Five days after that.
Speaker 1: alright there we go.
Speaker 1: You can watch.
Speaker 1: at least You can watch 66 Minutes of this free And honestly.
Speaker 1: if nothing else I think it's worth watching the first episode Cause one free like Who can't argue with that?
Speaker 1: and two.
Speaker 1: It's basically kind of a stand alone Movie.
Speaker 0: I think there might be 11 episodes If you watch that first episode.
Speaker 1: It's kind of a 44 minute like mini movie.
Speaker 1: That ends at a pretty satisfying Place and if it's not your jam You can stop there and still be satisfied.
Speaker 1: I guess we can talk about.
Speaker 1: The plot is pretty Simple.
Speaker 1: the show is definitely aimed at Young children like.
Speaker 1: it is Extremely simple Very straightforward.
Speaker 1: The dialogue is doing its job.
Speaker 1: Is what I would say?
Speaker 0: Ah so I'm reading about The moon girl comic from 2015.
Speaker 0: Ah And that is also I think significantly what I'm reading On Wikipedia at least is that There are also.
Speaker 0: it's significantly Different from what's happening in this Cartoon.
Speaker 1: yeah so this cartoon what's The deal?
Speaker 1: we're in New York City Modern place Modern times.
Speaker 1: Marvel universe Exists like all that.
Speaker 1: stuff is out There and Spiderman lives there.
Speaker 1: Right yeah Marvel so and Moon girl just a cool girl Who is into science with a cool Family living in a Cool part of the city running a roller Rink which does not exist.
Speaker 0: there is no Roller rink in the Lower East Side no room.
Speaker 0: This is.
Speaker 1: The problem is I feel like The New York City portrayed here is the New York City from Into the Spiderverse the Not actual New York City Because that is a way cooler Lower East Side than what we got going on.
Speaker 1: But Yeah she's there.
Speaker 1: she's super Into science.
Speaker 1: she's super smart She's a secret Almost super hero.
Speaker 1: Who's going through?
Speaker 1: her origin story Coming of age?
Speaker 0: basically Yeah basically it's a little bit Dexter's lab going On right.
Speaker 0: it's like she goes in her bedroom She goes in like the closet and it goes down Underneath to like an abandoned subway tunnel Or some shit.
Speaker 0: yup and she's got You know her shit down there right.
Speaker 1: It is very obvious that her entire family Knows what she's up to and Approves like.
Speaker 1: that is that is Telegraph from a mile away That they all know the deal and She doesn't know.
Speaker 1: her family knows because she's A naive child but Everyone knows and she's basically Living in the cool Lower East Side The cool family.
Speaker 1: it's a pretty Good representation of an idealized New York City though it's Not a hundred percent real Because there's a bodega that's called A bodega.
Speaker 1: now that's bodegas In New York don't have names.
Speaker 0: unless you look at city Records and those names they do have a name Sometimes printed on the awning.
Speaker 0: sometimes No one calls.
Speaker 0: nobody calls them by the Name that they have on there and there's Often a real name.
Speaker 1: And the name of a business Is they Are not what you would expect.
Speaker 1: They are kind of random.
Speaker 1: they're all over The place.
Speaker 1: there's bodegas but there's No bodega called bodega.
Speaker 1: but in this Universe the bodega is called bodega Okay But otherwise She is obsessed with This astronaut who I guess Disappeared or something and left some tech Behind and she's trying to figure out the deal.
Speaker 1: And she accidentally summons a gigantic dinosaur Who is Totally cool and an awesome Pet and then she Becomes a superhero and that's pretty much what Happens.
Speaker 0: The thing I like the most about This show was that In which he's in school Right.
Speaker 0: there was this Other student who's like the friend student Right and in the first scene with The friend the friend is Portrayed as first of all not A friend right as Some sort of popular girl Who is you know the exact opposite of Moon girl
Speaker 1: living for the tiktok
Speaker 0: Who is all into like tiktok social Media ing and that sort of biz.
Speaker 0: And you know Is like.
Speaker 0: you know you think that's Gonna be like a villain or a bully Of some kind.
Speaker 0: right Following the typical tropes of a school Story right it's like nerdy Girl.
Speaker 0: and then social media Popular girl and they're gonna be at odds Right and In you know.
Speaker 0: indeed I think after That first scene they are Sort of you know at odds but Basically like the second Third time it's like actually No right They sort of team up And they team up in a positive Way right.
Speaker 0: it's like.
Speaker 1: You know like immediately and they team up In a way that is very modern to kids And this is something I do appreciate too.
Speaker 1: This show Definitely acts like.
Speaker 1: it Understands how kids use technology And how their lives work and the fact that Social media and smartphones exist And the you know The way they portray the using Of social media is In a positive way right?
Speaker 0: it's like.
Speaker 0: It's like yes they're using it To like get themselves out there and be You know popular you know Get clout or whatever right And bring attention to things But they're not doing anything with it that would Be considered like.
Speaker 0: You know the bad behavior that You usually see from.
Speaker 0: You know those sorts of people right get it you know Annoying people with it getting people In there who do you know don't want to be on There harassing people Invading people's privacy Doing you know Too much capitalisms right You know anything like that.
Speaker 0: it's like They're just using it in a. You know they're using it perhaps too much Yeah But they're using it in a Good example of at least How to use it somewhat responsibly.
Speaker 1: The show is largely a lot of kids And adults being pretty good role models For kids which Is a good portrayal.
Speaker 1: the the villains Are appropriate To the stakes.
Speaker 0: I think I mean the villain really Felt like a a spider-man villain You know which is appropriate for one.
Speaker 0: a New York story.
Speaker 1: definitely I feel like if she'd actually killed All those people spider-man would have showed up.
Speaker 0: Yeah probably I don't know Someone would have showed up but it's like.
Speaker 0: Um Yeah but I think if You are if you're a kid who is?
Speaker 0: Perhaps you know I don't know if it's a. I guess it would Be about the same age target As a My Little Pony maybe a little bit older.
Speaker 1: Yeah maybe a little younger actually Could be.
Speaker 0: it's like around the same.
Speaker 0: I guess you know young kids.
Speaker 0: It's like you understand English.
Speaker 0: You're too old for Sesame Street But you know you're too young for.
Speaker 0: You know The Simpsons I don't know.
Speaker 1: But especially too it is very It is.
Speaker 1: it is not Centering whiteness In like very directly And that is clearly a big part of the show.
Speaker 1: It is.
Speaker 1: it is de-centering that To a strong degree and it's a very Very diverse cast for a reason.
Speaker 0: The voice acting I think it's a. It's a you know New York cast Yeah and the voice acting.
Speaker 1: Even though the dialogue is extremely simple The voice acting is spot on like it's Very well done even if the actual words They say are very simple Plot moving Dialogue.
Speaker 1: But the thing that stands out the main reason I would say you as a Geek Nights listener I don't think we have any like nine year old Geek Nights listeners Is that the animation Is fantastic.
Speaker 1: you know Spider-Verse Like captured a very particular Style.
Speaker 1: well this Really captures 2D newspaper Print comics.
Speaker 1: the backgrounds are Very flat.
Speaker 1: the characters are very flat.
Speaker 1: The special effects are done in A really interesting way.
Speaker 1: this is visually On the edge of stunning.
Speaker 1: Regardless of anything else I would watch Anything animated in this style.
Speaker 1: That is that is it's so Well done right?
Speaker 0: so perhaps the coolest Thing about this show is not anything in The show itself but the story of How the show came to be Because none other Than Morpheus the Lawrence Fishburne
Speaker 1: I was about to say because he He plays the Beyonder in this Show in one of the episodes
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: so he Read the comic book that Rym thinks is probably bad the Moon Boy When he was a young right.
Speaker 0: And he found out that the Moon Girl Comics from 2000 whatever Existed.
Speaker 0: and then He read those and he says Oh this should be a cartoon.
Speaker 0: And so he was the executive producer For it.
Speaker 0: right but it wasn't one of those situations Where like you just slap in your name on something But you get no credit.
Speaker 0: he clearly like believed.
Speaker 0: He's like right he was like.
Speaker 0: He was like.
Speaker 0: oh I like.
Speaker 0: you know let's make this happen.
Speaker 0: And he you know he made it happen.
Speaker 0: the other Big name involved Which makes obviously perfect sense Is Steve Loader Right.
Speaker 0: you know Who is a Kim Possible you know Key person.
Speaker 0: so and that Makes perfect sense because you look at the show and you're like Oh yeah I can see the I can see the Connection definitely see it.
Speaker 1: so I would say anyone Who listens to Geek Nights it is worth It to at least watch the first episode Because it ends at a satisfying point.
Speaker 1: treat it like a Mini movie.
Speaker 1: the animation is great There's a lot of good stuff going on.
Speaker 1: But if you got kids this show I feel like it'll just hit.
Speaker 1: It'll hit them.
Speaker 1: I think they'd be into It.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I'm gonna watch the rest of it aggressively But I feel like at some point I'll watch it all.
Speaker 1: There won't be that much of it I imagine.
Speaker 0: Yeah I don't think this is something that I'm gonna Like.
Speaker 0: go and spend my time Watching a whole bunch of but like if it was on I would watch it right?
Speaker 0: Oh absolutely And then I would tell someone else To watch it.
Speaker 0: but uh Especially if they are a child In this year.
Speaker 0: but am I Gonna watch it you know?
Speaker 0: Eh maybe.
Speaker 0: But that doesn't mean it's no good.
Speaker 0: that just means I got no time.
Speaker 0: I'd watch lots of television.
Speaker 1: The Devil Dinosaur himself is just extremely Cute and very well done.
Speaker 1: like They have the right amount I think he's great.
Speaker 0: I mean who isn't Gonna love?
Speaker 0: you know A dinosaur that is Intelligent.
Speaker 1: also like a little kid you know A 13 year old girl who has a Gigantic extremely powerful magical Pet dinosaur.
Speaker 1: She names him Devil Dinosaur because it's a cool name and I like that.
Speaker 1: they just.
Speaker 1: that's how they handle.
Speaker 1: Where does he get his name?
Speaker 1: she's just like Yeah Devil Dinosaur.
Speaker 1: fuck it let's roll.
Speaker 0: Yeah it's like that's a.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music Kat Lee for web design and Brando K For the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com For show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember Geek Nights is not one But four different shows SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays And Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live With no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: And for tonight I simply leave you with Here's one.
Speaker 1: Can you see that That's a perfect Hamster burrow?
Speaker 1: And then if I come over here Just on the corner There's one here As well, see that That's perfect For hamsters.
Speaker 1: so Definitely in the right place There's a hamster, that's a hamster.
Speaker 1: Oh my, oh my god There's a hamster, there's a hamster.
Speaker 1: There's a hamster standing up Over there, right I'm gonna try and get A little bit closer.
Speaker 1: Oh my goodness.