Speaker 1: It's Tuesday June 27th 2023.
Speaker 1: I'm rim Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We are talking about worker placements the game mechanic.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So today I was just thinking random thoughts Like you do like me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I was like, hey, you know what?
Speaker 0: You know, there's a. there's an animal called a an anteater, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and we know we've seen anteaters, right?
Speaker 0: They get a long snooty and they get their long tongue.
Speaker 0: that comes out and they stick it down the hole where the ants live And they ant the ante Hill and they eat all the ants.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of other animals that he dance, but they're not called anteaters.
Speaker 1: They are.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but there's also anteaters.
Speaker 0: We call the anteater an anteater.
Speaker 0: It eats ants a lot.
Speaker 0: It's like a favorite food.
Speaker 0: It didn't get its name for no reason.
Speaker 1: We got other animals like that.
Speaker 1: There's all the egg snakes.
Speaker 0: Sure, but I'm talking about anteaters here.
Speaker 0: an anteater is specially equipped for ants, right?
Speaker 0: It's like got a built-in ant hill eating mechanism.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right and I was thinking you know What if an anteater goes to eat ants but they turn out to be like those fucking nasty-ass fire ants who are like all You know bitey bitey Is he gonna get bit all on the tongue and or like get ants all over its face and get and get bit up by?
Speaker 0: The ants, you know, who's gonna?
Speaker 0: who's gonna win that fight?
Speaker 1: this, you know Covered with thousands of tiny hooks which are to hold the insects in place covered with a large amount of saliva.
Speaker 0: but so I did a little research and apparently I am NOT the first person far from the first person to have this question of anteater verse Fire ant who wins right?
Speaker 1: I started googling it as soon as I realized what you were asking.
Speaker 0: So I was curious to save you to save you a Google.
Speaker 0: Here's the answer right?
Speaker 0: Is that the fire ant?
Speaker 0: I mean the anteater doesn't really have a special tool.
Speaker 0: Like if it gets bit by fire ants it still fucking hurts Right, but he has.
Speaker 0: the only special tool it has is his fur.
Speaker 0: if the ants get on the fur It'll take them a little while to get down to the skin and start biting.
Speaker 0: I guess it could get bit on the tongue But I guess he could eat those and kill them pretty quick by sucking him in suck him into the desert, right?
Speaker 0: But the main technique the anteater has for dealing with nasty ants instead of regular old Ants know is he just doesn't see.
Speaker 0: he goes in he starts eating ants real quick before they notice and when they realize when the ants Realize what's happening and they get into bite mode.
Speaker 0: He runs away.
Speaker 1: Ah Smart anteater.
Speaker 0: He just goes in and he's like, you know, ooh fire ants, huh?
Speaker 0: Well, you can't just sit around a feast.
Speaker 0: We got to be like nom nom nom nom nom nom and that's that's how.
Speaker 0: or maybe he waits like the first ant to bite him and then runs it just as a reaction, but That's how ant eaters deal with fire.
Speaker 0: and so in the battle of ant eater verse fire ants who wins the ant eater could eat them all if they are patient enough to Be like, is he gone now?
Speaker 0: All right back to chill mode.
Speaker 1: Oh no For you nerds the anteaters probing and then kiting the ants to make sure you can get them without getting.
Speaker 0: if the anteater was a Dumb dumb and we just kept on eating the fire ants could mess up the the anteater pretty bad with their their nibblies Depending on which kind they are.
Speaker 0: All right So, uh, so if you have a fire ant infestation on at your house You wouldn't go and like rent an anteater.
Speaker 0: That would not be a good technique.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know what to do if I'm fire ants.
Speaker 0: Uh, I am now live where fire ants live.
Speaker 1: fire ants live is creeping north fast You what else is creeping north?
Speaker 1: There have been a bunch of malaria cases in the US now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I heard about that too.
Speaker 0: And the answer is if the malaria reaches, Virginia, we'll go get malaria vaccines.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's.
Speaker 1: uh, it's funny because way back in the Roman times No, Rome was the like the city and The rich people would live there Except in the summer.
Speaker 1: if them if there was too much malaria They would all head north for the summer and they come back down to Rome and like.
Speaker 0: that was a thing All my grandparents they went south In the winter, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess we're gonna do the opposite.
Speaker 1: We're gonna head north in the summer, right?
Speaker 0: So we'll still be further south in the colder time.
Speaker 1: but Yeah We gotta do something about climate change.
Speaker 1: because I the other thing I saw is so, you know the other week we had the the sky turned blue blocker orange for a couple days in New York and Apparently that happened in Chicago.
Speaker 1: now exact same situation.
Speaker 1: Chicago got hit just like we did.
Speaker 0: The fundamental thing is if you want to solve climate change, we are going to need a lot of people.
Speaker 0: We're going to have to suffer Large or perhaps even we don't even have to suffer that much in convenience.
Speaker 1: I want to.
Speaker 1: there will be.
Speaker 0: there will be some amount of noticeable Inconvenience that you must in less than we'd expect because from what I've seen There is a. it is still not zero and the problem is even the most minor inconvenience.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Fight in any government in any country on earth.
Speaker 1: tell it American Their car has to get one more mile per gallon 20 years from now and they'll pull out a gun.
Speaker 1: But the stat was basically if Americans just Americans ate like 4% less beef just beef a year.
Speaker 1: that would make a Material impact on climate change almost immediately like that would be better.
Speaker 0: We could do that.
Speaker 0: we could do that by just you know mandating by law beef Production and import oddities or even just to force secretly force McDonald's.
Speaker 1: Yeah, take 4% on all your burgers.
Speaker 1: That would actually save the planet Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, never mind.
Speaker 1: Not even kind of quarter-pounder.
Speaker 1: It would be 96 percent times point two five Like if we told the average American we're gonna reduce your McDonald's by 4%.
Speaker 1: some percentage of them would decide that a gun is The answer to that.
Speaker 0: it would be a point.
Speaker 0: Oh six to five pounder.
Speaker 1: Well, just call it.
Speaker 0: I know it would know that's not right.
Speaker 0: That's not right.
Speaker 1: We'll just call it a Royale and walk away.
Speaker 1: Redefine what a quarter pound is Or it still weighs a quarter pound.
Speaker 1: just fill it with fake meat.
Speaker 1: Saw.
Speaker 1: it would be.
Speaker 0: it would be a point to four pounder Instead of a point to five.
Speaker 1: so, you know way back we did a review of Marvel snap and it's pretty good game.
Speaker 1: But it was pretty simple Scott.
Speaker 0: I think you said yeah when I mean when it came out I was like, you know, hey, this is my kind of game.
Speaker 0: But right now at the time it was released we did you know, I was like this is just.
Speaker 0: you know It's got this micro transaction nonsense and it's sort of grindy and it's just a ladder and there's no multiplayer.
Speaker 0: There's no competitive scene.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna play it if it doesn't have those things.
Speaker 0: and then it added those things I'm like, well they added the things.
Speaker 0: so I started playing.
Speaker 1: when they added I gave them one unit of money once which I actually Regret because it got me like modok and a bunch of stuff I needed for a deck and now I'm you don't they're never Getting.
Speaker 0: you know, we could talk about the microtransactions more.
Speaker 0: I guess we did already.
Speaker 0: But the thing I've learned about the microtransactions that is not.
Speaker 0: I'm not to say they're good, right?
Speaker 0: But they're less evil than some of the others.
Speaker 0: Is that basically they top out?
Speaker 0: It's like you can actually sort of get all or most of the cards and then it's like you actually get Diminishing returns like if you have.
Speaker 0: I went and threw hundreds of dollars at the game.
Speaker 0: I would get basically nothing for my money, right?
Speaker 0: It's like it's pointless to spend more than like this certain reasonable ish amount You know and it's it's cheaper than netrunner, right?
Speaker 0: So if you see if you pay anyway They add that the big news is that they added this conquest mode and that's a even though he did a whole show on this Game.
Speaker 0: the conquest mode is a bit, you know, there's a lot of other news about the game, too.
Speaker 0: But at this mode is a big enough deal to be a news, right?
Speaker 0: So at the conquest mode is it is very similar along the lines of what Richard Garfield suggested what I heard from Richard Garfield and then modified and also suggested right they have done an implementation of Sort of automatic tournaments in sort of yep.
Speaker 0: It's better than any car online digital card turn based kind of game And I know of.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna give you this point in history Just like how Scott was like, yeah spider-man My is good enough to where we could say it's a classic for all time right now.
Speaker 1: Like I got to say something about mark cuz Marvel snap.
Speaker 1: That was a pooping game for me.
Speaker 1: I got a poop.
Speaker 1: I'll play a snap like that's just.
Speaker 1: I really didn't play it other than when I was bored idle.
Speaker 1: I like waiting for something pooping.
Speaker 1: I didn't have it installed in steam.
Speaker 1: I looked at on my phone conquest mode Reinstall it on steam.
Speaker 1: I will sit at my desk and play conquest mode the way I would play overwatch or counter-strike Cuz.
Speaker 0: basically it's like a game of Marvel.
Speaker 0: snap is not a very, you know deep game.
Speaker 0: It's pretty it's a lot very random.
Speaker 1: It's very it's really.
Speaker 1: just do I snap or do I retreat?
Speaker 0: Right, but when you have to play a car a whole conquest mode right where you're playing to get to ten points against the same opponent in repeated games That L that entire battle is about equivalent to a whole game of like Magic the Gathering, right?
Speaker 0: so Already that is significant that you're playing the sort of battle mode not just against friends, but against strangers, right?
Speaker 0: But they put it in the context of the conquest is you're basically playing in a tournament whenever you want.
Speaker 0: So here's how it works.
Speaker 0: The first genius thing they did is the proving grounds, right?
Speaker 0: So in other card games they have like or other online multiplayer games this casual mode.
Speaker 0: Right a casual mode in most games means play meaningless game.
Speaker 1: Yep, overwatch casual mode Literally worthless like not playable.
Speaker 0: right in Hearthstone they had casual mode and it was just play a meaningless game against a random opponent.
Speaker 0: and the thing is Even for people who want to play and not competitively.
Speaker 0: casual mode is kind of air because people aren't trying.
Speaker 0: People are just not caring.
Speaker 0: you're not like getting the real game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, people aren't even trying to win half the time, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like not you know, it's like not.
Speaker 0: the results don't matter.
Speaker 0: But also the game is not the same game.
Speaker 0: It's just peacely people playing cards.
Speaker 0: nonsense, right?
Speaker 0: It's you're not actually playing the game even if you don't care about competing.
Speaker 0: So the proving grounds is an effect a casual mode where there are no Consequences for losing therefore and you can play it infinitely.
Speaker 0: It could play it as much as you want.
Speaker 0: So you could just battle up random opponents as much as you want with no consequence of losing.
Speaker 0: and therefore that's casual mode.
Speaker 0: You could just play whatever rando deck with.
Speaker 0: you can test out decks.
Speaker 0: You can experiment you could just play a fun.
Speaker 0: I only play fun decks in proving grounds.
Speaker 0: I don't play serious ones because you know, why right and so.
Speaker 0: but the thing is when you Win in proving grounds you get a silver ticket.
Speaker 0: So because there is a reward for winning and no a real reward for winning and no punishment for losing People still try.
Speaker 0: they play Properly, right and you sort of care if you win a little bit, right?
Speaker 0: but if you don't care if you lose and I Can't think what other game is there that that's like that.
Speaker 0: We're like, you know, usually it's like when you have a prize for winning Let's say a cash prize like losing feels bad.
Speaker 0: You don't want to lose but they somehow perfectly tuned it to where Winning is okay.
Speaker 0: You get a silver ticket and losing you don't give a shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: And so perfect casual mode is the first aspect of and that's just a subset, right?
Speaker 0: so you get the silver ticket and you can get as many as you can get and You use the silver ticket to enter the silver conquest.
Speaker 0: and now the silver conquest is now serious business.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 1: alright now you're gonna win something.
Speaker 0: good you spend a silver ticket.
Speaker 0: You can't get it back.
Speaker 0: You could spend gold instead of a silver ticket.
Speaker 0: That is a sucker's game.
Speaker 1: Just hang out in the proving ground for like a couple never do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, never.
Speaker 0: you would be a fool to do that.
Speaker 0: You got an absolute fool.
Speaker 0: And so you play.
Speaker 0: you have to beat you to play basically two battles against two opponents.
Speaker 0: But as you pace one opponent, yeah, if you don't beat them, you just you're out of the conquest.
Speaker 0: All right, you lose your ticket.
Speaker 0: if you beat them you face a second opponent, right if you lose to them again You just lost your ticket.
Speaker 0: you're out.
Speaker 0: But if you beat that second opponent, so two in a row you get a golden tickets Right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, then when you use the golden ticket, it's the same thing But you have to beat three opponents in a row in order to upgrade your golden ticket to the infinity Ticket.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: So it's like you now are.
Speaker 0: you've just played in a tournament that effectively was a single elimination tournament like a NCAA bracket, right and it had five rounds.
Speaker 0: if you have five rounds That's basically against 32 people who put in a silver ticket.
Speaker 0: One of them will emerge with an infinity thing Right.
Speaker 0: So it's like playing at a tournament of 32 people.
Speaker 0: now if the thing is you don't have all 32 people like lined up At the start committing to play at the same time It's just when you choose play.
Speaker 0: you play against someone who is currently at the same Bracket level that you're at.
Speaker 0: And this is brilliant.
Speaker 1: because right why are ladders?
Speaker 0: It's someone who's made it through four rounds.
Speaker 0: just like you you've made it through four rounds.
Speaker 1: ladders are popular Just because it's very easy to have matchmaking in.
Speaker 1: like overwatch or something - I want to play a serious game.
Speaker 1: It'll just put me in a serious game and it'll give me ladder rewards.
Speaker 1: This just lets me have a tournament But I still just click a button and get into a serious game and you can play the games whenever you want.
Speaker 0: You can switch decks each round.
Speaker 0: who cares right?
Speaker 0: It's just when once you commit it's like, alright you're gonna play someone who's at the same distance through the bracket that you are and You are gonna spend your ticket and you your deck is locked in and you're gonna play a ten cube game.
Speaker 0: And if you retreat from this game, that's it.
Speaker 0: You're lost.
Speaker 0: And if you win congrats you go you can get play again.
Speaker 1: I am surprised of how many people concede Against me in matches when there's literally no reason to Yeah fight to the end.
Speaker 1: I have come back.
Speaker 1: I came back from.
Speaker 1: I only had two health left and they were fucking me up All the way to victory just by being patient.
Speaker 0: Maybe they got a good.
Speaker 0: it's a phone game.
Speaker 0: I don't care I take the win.
Speaker 0: and then what?
Speaker 0: the golden ticket upgrades to the infinity ticket, right?
Speaker 0: Now the infinity ticket is special because you can't use the infinity ticket whenever you want Just like the other tickets you can use whenever you want the silvers and golds.
Speaker 0: The infinity one can only be used in the final week of the season which has just begun.
Speaker 0: the very first infinity ticket Season has just started right?
Speaker 0: So this week is the only chance to use your infinity tickets next week.
Speaker 0: You won't that's it closed.
Speaker 0: You got to wait a whole nother set of weeks like four weeks to use them again if you gonna start from scratch, right?
Speaker 0: so It's like during this time period you got to use as many infinity tickets as you got.
Speaker 0: Maybe try to get some more and if you can to get the infinity ticket you and upgrade it You have to win five in a row.
Speaker 0: So that's basically another 32 player tournament.
Speaker 0: so you have to beat.
Speaker 0: let's see a 32 player tournament a 10 round tournament.
Speaker 0: 10 is 2 to the 10th power.
Speaker 0: Is that how many players are in there?
Speaker 1: right and I love how it feels like the old golden ticket raffles at RIT anime Like hold on to that ticket for the end of the season.
Speaker 0: I do the math here to to the.
Speaker 0: This is not a good calculator.
Speaker 1: That's why I have one infinity ticket.
Speaker 0: Yeah, two to the fifth power is 32.
Speaker 0: So two to the tenth power is 1024. so out of every 1024 players Right who start in the and win approving grounds and throw a silver ticket down One of them will emerge as an infinity conquest champion.
Speaker 0: Right and they get basically their up avatar that they were using on the deck that they were playing gets a fancy shiny cosmetic thing to prove that they were that good and that lucky that they made it.
Speaker 0: and Now it's just a cosmetic prize.
Speaker 0: who cares right, but that's like It's so hard to get that right to win it.
Speaker 0: imagine it an NCAA tournament bracket with 1024 people and you win without losing once.
Speaker 0: no losers bracket, right?
Speaker 0: And it's like yeah, you could enter the tournament as many times as you want But it's like even if you held how many of those tournaments would you need to enter to win one of?
Speaker 1: I mean even getting the winner winner chicken dinner equivalent in whatever like Battle royale game you're playing feels pretty good.
Speaker 1: This is rarer than that, right?
Speaker 0: It's like it that you can enter this tournament as many times as you like.
Speaker 0: We'll just keep holding brand new tournaments for you all the all day long as many as you want as long as much time as you're willing to invest.
Speaker 0: every Tournament has a thousand and twenty four entrants.
Speaker 0: You're one of them.
Speaker 0: Can you even win one of these tournaments, right?
Speaker 0: That is so hard.
Speaker 0: So you getting that avatar and then displaying it is like walking into the boxing ring when your manager is holding belts, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, you intimidate anyone you will ever play again and unlike a lot of the grind Achievement type things that a lot of games have.
Speaker 1: this one is a skill based thing like luck.
Speaker 0: There is there is luck.
Speaker 0: It's a game of luck.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the luck does fact less luck because each opponent you're not playing just one game You're playing ten cubes work.
Speaker 0: so you can overcome luck.
Speaker 1: but with lots of games or luck you know filters out with with lots of repeated games or two decisions you made like I made a deck and I happen to bump into someone who has the Absolute paper to my deck like I'm my deck is a rock happens.
Speaker 0: Yep, it happens.
Speaker 0: But yeah, this is like.
Speaker 1: this is pretty pretty great and the games are good like the games are.
Speaker 0: When you get to the goal If you spend a gold ticket you're playing against somebody who is already won a round of 32 like a big turn, right?
Speaker 1: This is someone like they see in round one that I don't know A car just automatically discards from your hand.
Speaker 1: They're like, oh they're playing a discard deck.
Speaker 1: They're probably playing a hella discard deck and then they play.
Speaker 1: I don't know they play Sunspot.
Speaker 1: You're like, alright Yeah, that doesn't tell me anything about what deck you're using.
Speaker 0: So anyway the whole month so far I earned three infinity tickets and then they let you buy one for free kind of.
Speaker 0: and then So I used one of them so far and I got to the fourth round and then I lost in the fourth round.
Speaker 0: So I would have had to beat that Opponent and one more opponent to get to the top.
Speaker 0: and I so I was that close on my first infinity ticket.
Speaker 0: I don't know anyone who's made it so far to the top.
Speaker 1: I just want to have my default avatar with the infinity banner around it.
Speaker 0: I just I just want to you know be the champ right or a champ one of the one of the chance.
Speaker 1: You want to be the very best like no one?
Speaker 0: There are some people out there who might have who might have done it twice already.
Speaker 0: I'm sure there's some streamers who play snap all day who've probably done it.
Speaker 1: I mean in the fact one of the questions was can I earn multiple avatars?
Speaker 0: and the answer is yes Absolutely as many as you can get.
Speaker 0: good luck You know.
Speaker 0: So that's it's pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: No other game that I know of has this.
Speaker 0: This is really good.
Speaker 1: So speaking of microtransactions and avatars and stuff battle passes Which are there is a battle pass sort of equivalent in snap that you could care about or not care about.
Speaker 1: I just don't bother with it.
Speaker 0: Uh, I don't.
Speaker 0: it's like the only good value for your money though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you're gonna spend money, that's the thing to spend money on but I'm not spending money.
Speaker 1: But if you're gonna I'm not judging you do it that way.
Speaker 1: So a lot of games have battle passes.
Speaker 1: battle passes are not all equivalent.
Speaker 1: They are made with season passes battle some kind of pass and they're all made with different levels of success.
Speaker 1: But valve the story was valve is ditching battle passes because most players Literally to never buy one and that was the headline everywhere.
Speaker 1: But yes the actual details are valve which also has battle passes for counter-strike and I don't think they're getting rid of those is Ditching their battle passes for dota 2. and while it is true that basically they shared the data Nobody buys this thing.
Speaker 1: You have to be an absolute sucker to buy this thing because it basically doesn't get you anything.
Speaker 1: But it also might have been the first battle pass.
Speaker 1: So in some ways it broke ground, but basically valve is just saying it didn't work.
Speaker 1: It didn't make us money But the buried lead.
Speaker 1: that's interesting.
Speaker 1: Is that the number of people?
Speaker 1: Inside of valve that they said we're basically wasting their time with weeaboo like wasting their time Trying to come up with good stuff to put in the battle pass.
Speaker 1: They were like we just saved a ton of money and are probably doing better by just killing this whole fucking thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think you know I don't know much about how that battle pass and dota to work because someone told me that some of the rewards are Temporary and you lose the yes.
Speaker 0: I heard someone told me that as well that some of it.
Speaker 0: They're all cosmetic rewards.
Speaker 0: There are no real rewards because it's not it's only cosmetic stuff and that some of the cosmetic things you get like go away.
Speaker 0: So it's like you can get a fancy costume But you can don't like a Halloween costume that only works on Halloween and then it goes away and you can't get it again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: why would you pay money?
Speaker 0: Why would anyone pay money for that when it's like?
Speaker 0: I feel like you know this?
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 0: if I knew how it worked I could make a better commentary on it.
Speaker 0: But I feel like they probably could have just not done stupid shit like that and people might have wanted Yeah, cuz I counter-strike as its equivalent really want them But the variant cards in Marvel snap.
Speaker 0: people really want the hats and tf2.
Speaker 0: people really want the skins on guns and counter-strike that They'll gamble with them and spent piles of money for them.
Speaker 0: Why wouldn't people really want cosmetic shit in dota - yeah.
Speaker 1: and meanwhile?
Speaker 1: Something was wrong definitely has similar stuff And I assume people are buying those because they didn't cut that.
Speaker 1: But no, I know a little bit about how the counter-strike ones work, and they're absolute garbage.
Speaker 1: There's nothing there like.
Speaker 1: the cosmetics are really sad, and I can't know.
Speaker 0: I think the only reason people want the counters for the gamblings Because they're literally worth money to somebody.
Speaker 0: therefore They're worth money to like.
Speaker 0: if someone's gonna spend a thousand dollars for one and suddenly Everyone else wants one because they think they can sell it and get a thousand They don't want the skins they want the thousand dollars.
Speaker 1: fact late last year Scott and I were talking about selling old crap in the valve like steam marketplace And I was poo-pooing it because I didn't want to spend.
Speaker 0: I bought a lot of Marvel snap stuff selling young car.
Speaker 1: I didn't want to click even once if it was just gonna get me like a cent or two But I did go look and I had a counter-strike skin that was worth like 20 bucks And I sold it and someone
Speaker 0: someone
Speaker 1: paid like 19 real Dollars for a skin.
Speaker 0: that valve took a cut and you got the rest.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 1: So I got like 16 bucks for nothing.
Speaker 0: Yep, literally nothing for playing counter-strike.
Speaker 0: They paid you to play counter-strike.
Speaker 0: Yeah And click a button afterwards But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: So what do you got?
Speaker 1: because I thought you had something different until I actually clicked on this link, and this is way better.
Speaker 0: I'm sure this is old news to many, but it was new news to me that apparently Yellowstone National Park, you know the place where Yogi Bear is from right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess Jellystone is.
Speaker 0: You know I knew that it was.
Speaker 0: I knew it's general geography But I didn't know it's specific geography and that it takes up a lot of a big chunk of Wyoming.
Speaker 0: But it actually takes this sliver in Montana on the north and west sides And also takes this tiny sliver and the southwest in Idaho right and but most of its in Wyoming right?
Speaker 0: It's basically the northwest corner of Wyoming But a sliver of Montana and a little like an l-shape and a sliver in Idaho.
Speaker 0: now There's a in the u.s.. Right the the law is.
Speaker 0: Constitution says that you know if you commit some crimes there in a national federal land that you States can't do anything about that.
Speaker 0: That's a federal crime for federal courts to deal with.
Speaker 1: yeah This comes up a lot in DC.
Speaker 1: Which is not in any state exactly.
Speaker 0: now if you also You know commit a federal crime you have to go to federal court Which is one of those district courts, and you obviously there's a district court that covers any spot.
Speaker 0: You are in the US and its territories.
Speaker 0: There's gonna be a district court that covers that area.
Speaker 0: yeah If for some reason there wasn't which there is that you could I guess avoid, but there is right.
Speaker 0: So the district that covers that area right is in Wyoming obviously?
Speaker 0: and The thing is is that you also when you go to federal court you need to get a jury and the people on that jury Have to live in that district right and they also have to live in the same state where you did the crime.
Speaker 0: So if you do a crime so you rob a pick a nick a basket Yellowstone, Wyoming right well There's people who live in the district and also in Wyoming.
Speaker 0: not a lot of them, but enough to make a jury right there's.
Speaker 1: There's.
Speaker 1: there's nine angry people who just live there the only people they're on.
Speaker 0: if you go to that little sliver in Montana right It's like there are a few people living there.
Speaker 0: There's like in those inhabited areas.
Speaker 0: it would be tough to make a jury, but they could.
Speaker 0: there's enough people right.
Speaker 0: someone did a crime there and They basically plead on the condition that they don't try to fight this condition.
Speaker 0: right, but the sliver in Idaho No one lives there.
Speaker 0: No one.
Speaker 0: so even though there are people living in the district in Wyoming You commit the crime in the Idaho part of Yellowstone Park where no one lives except a bear right?
Speaker 0: We can't be on a jury because he's not your peer.
Speaker 0: There's no one to make a jury because no one lives in Idaho and also in the district in which the court is.
Speaker 0: So it's called the zone of death because theoretically You could kill someone there and get away with it because it's this note.
Speaker 0: They could never make a jury to do anything about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's only like one person wrote a work of like a short story or something where this happened.
Speaker 1: There was one case with a poacher that tested this but that was it.
Speaker 0: that was in the Montana.
Speaker 1: It was only a few people but even worse the Idaho part has no people but even that one It looks like in the end.
Speaker 1: They never got appealed up.
Speaker 0: I said that already.
Speaker 0: Yes, so it was about that.
Speaker 1: So we mentioned the whole thing, but our religion is record never got to rule out it.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, they made them plea on the condition that they wouldn't fight it.
Speaker 1: I Someone's got some day.
Speaker 1: I would love to see it.
Speaker 0: Well, hopefully no one kills anyone except maybe Yogi bear.
Speaker 1: But we got to go there and go run a casino not being killed.
Speaker 0: Oh Or this is bling in the zone.
Speaker 1: Piracy.
Speaker 1: run the run the pirate bay there.
Speaker 1: hide a server in the woods with the satellite uplink.
Speaker 1: Mmm, that's how you do this.
Speaker 1: forget zone of death.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's do some moral morally acceptable crime.
Speaker 1: an underground bunker Hundreds and hundreds of petabytes of pirated streaming media.
Speaker 0: billionaire graveyard Hey suck, I got.
Speaker 0: you know, hey musk I got this cool place you got to check out.
Speaker 0: we can do your fight here.
Speaker 0: Come on, it'll be really.
Speaker 0: we don't have to worry about gambling commissions.
Speaker 0: We can fight here.
Speaker 0: No one will stop you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can both fight dirty.
Speaker 1: convince them both.
Speaker 1: It's a real good idea for them.
Speaker 1: Yeah So, uh, my thing of the day is real short, this is an eight-second YouTube video and I Saw it and it looked like the cute kind of thing.
Speaker 1: I would like like.
Speaker 1: it's a random YouTube video I would click on but I did not Expect it to be about what it was about and I laughed out loud when I saw it.
Speaker 1: It was cute enough to where I think everyone should see this.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 0: I don't know who thought of this, but they're pretty genius.
Speaker 0: It was pretty good.
Speaker 1: I kept posting it around because if you click on it, you're like, all right spider-man joking.
Speaker 1: They're like, oh, haha.
Speaker 1: That's cute Spider-man, it's spider-man.
Speaker 0: Also as I guess one more spider-man note I only recently realized all the spider-man multiverse OSTs are on your favorite streaming services As well as some official remix album.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz we both we both realized we've all realized simultaneously that we really like elephant sounds.
Speaker 0: Oh Once you realize how many elephant sounds are in those movies you won't unhear them In the meta moment.
Speaker 1: the geek nights book club book is.
Speaker 1: this is how you lose the time war Bye.
Speaker 1: Oh, where's the author?
Speaker 1: I gotta click on this.
Speaker 0: Bye I Put it on the website now.
Speaker 0: So I that was your excuse for not having the the author's name.
Speaker 1: It does so the only place.
Speaker 1: Oh, there it is by Amal El-Mothar and Max Gladstone.
Speaker 0: There you go, it's really short.
Speaker 1: I imagine The the next Thursday's show.
Speaker 1: we do other than the one this Thursday.
Speaker 1: So you have enough time.
Speaker 1: like you can read the book.
Speaker 1: in two weeks I'm probably ready to read the whole book.
Speaker 1: I did not because I've been busy doing other stuff.
Speaker 1: this book looks like it is a Light evening reading like one night.
Speaker 1: read it after dinner Maybe me or maybe a pleasant afternoon at most if you're a slow reader, but what one?
Speaker 0: one or two beaches?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so this will be the next Thursday episode.
Speaker 1: the following Thursday episode will be this episode.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, we will be in the other meta on Sunday with a actually all-new panel Details TBD.
Speaker 1: you'll see an update soon.
Speaker 1: got some thoughts on the panel?
Speaker 1: be a fun one.
Speaker 1: We also have some pretty good ideas for some unplugged content that I think you would all appreciate.
Speaker 1: so stay tuned for that.
Speaker 1: But Ignites panels live stuff YouTube videos lectures.
Speaker 1: It's all coming back baby kick knives back in the real world and Gonna get right into it.
Speaker 1: because this you might remember way way back in 2011 2012. this was a long time ago.
Speaker 1: We did a panel in the tiny tiny panel room.
Speaker 1: This was a PAX East where we did three panels, but two of the panels were in this tiny workshop room Seated like 100 people tiny tiny little room.
Speaker 1: and we did two back-to-back panels that we didn't think would be super popular compared to our big stuff.
Speaker 1: one was called Mastering game mechanics and one was called practically in theory People line the fuck up to see mastering game mechanics.
Speaker 1: almost no one got to see it in the room completely packed.
Speaker 1: but mastering game mechanics was about Game mechanics, like let's talk about a bunch of game mechanics and explain their deal.
Speaker 1: and Scott had the brilliant idea Why don't we do a show?
Speaker 1: it's easy easy content farm idea Yeah, but it's such a good idea because we got a lot to say about this time.
Speaker 0: Let's just do one panel slash episode slash whatever each video for each game mechanical.
Speaker 0: break it down even more.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can go deep go deeper.
Speaker 0: instead of doing all these game mechanics and one in one shot We'll just do one at a time.
Speaker 0: Yeah And the right of ideas, that's what I got.
Speaker 1: But worker placement seemed like a good one to start with partly because I we have a lot of thoughts about it.
Speaker 1: It's all.
Speaker 1: that's a game mechanic.
Speaker 1: I like.
Speaker 1: but I also realized something important because the problem with talking about game mechanics is that it's very easy to say that any X-act thing in a game could arguably be classified as a bunch of different kinds of game mechanics based on how you look at it, like you could argue that a lot of things in games are Effectively worker placement, even if they don't look like it.
Speaker 1: So I want to get out of the way that I think we can do something clever.
Speaker 1: It's the same thing you do in math Where you multiply something by one to make it look different for the purposes of a conversation.
Speaker 1: I think even if a mechanic could arguably be worker placement in effect to talk about it as worker placement We should multiply it by one so that it looks like worker placement to have the conversation.
Speaker 1: Then we were always talking about it the same way.
Speaker 0: Well, I think one of the things is that a lot of people, you know Can't align game mechanics with each other so easily.
Speaker 0: even me I have a problem because especially tabletop You'll have the same mechanic implemented with different components.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that will confuse like physical components, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like someone would be like, oh no, this is a card game.
Speaker 0: Look, I'm playing cards and someone's like well putting a meeple on a space.
Speaker 0: That's not the same thing as playing a card.
Speaker 1: arguably action and worker placement are the exact same thing Right.
Speaker 0: It's like if they're mathematically equivalent if they're functionally equivalent.
Speaker 0: If you if you make the game into just a spreadsheet, right?
Speaker 0: Is it the same in on the spreadsheet?
Speaker 0: and it's like if it is the same on the spreadsheet then is the same game mechanic?
Speaker 0: Regardless of you know, rolling a dive or spinning a spinner verse.
Speaker 0: They're all RNG on the spreadsheet, right?
Speaker 0: So they're all the same mechanic that way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but at the same time Worker placement is something I think that's very easy to engage with because this concept like a lot of the games We like the most use worker placement as a primary mechanic.
Speaker 1: It's often the primary mechanic of a game.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So what is worker placement?
Speaker 0: So worker placement is you have a game and there are a set of actions that a player may take on their turn Right.
Speaker 0: Usually those are the only things players do in the game are this set of actions and you can choose some subset of those actions to perform.
Speaker 0: as You know your as your agency in the game is basically choosing which of those actions you will take in which order when the opportunity presents itself to you the player right and Typically for a worker placement game, right?
Speaker 0: The actions will usually almost definitely be Exclusive or at least limited so that when you choose to take an action You will also be denying other players from taking that action at least for the that turn.
Speaker 1: I think that's our future.
Speaker 0: very good way to define it because that right because if everyone can take all the same actions That's a cut that fundamentally changes like everything that is just action drafting or action points.
Speaker 1: Like action drafting.
Speaker 1: action points are almost a superset worker placement to put some constraints on it, right?
Speaker 0: But it's like such a significant constraint that it makes it a completely different game.
Speaker 0: Definitely all the heuristics are different.
Speaker 1: all the wit everything's did like about every worker placement games Most people know like Agricola.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if I put my guy on the baby, you can't make a baby this round.
Speaker 1: That's that's the game.
Speaker 1: is who gets the baby first exact.
Speaker 0: That's the whole game.
Speaker 0: Yeah Which is a lot of work or at least some limit right like only two people there's only two spots on that action.
Speaker 0: It's three spots on that action and that action has infinity spots and that one has only one spot.
Speaker 1: sometimes as long as there's some Sometimes you get the limit is is more abstract or different like a limit.
Speaker 1: I've seen games where I'd still think this is worker placement.
Speaker 1: the first person to go there gets the good version But all the second person gets the crappy version.
Speaker 0: third person can't get anything exactly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've seen that.
Speaker 0: So yeah It's there's some set of actions and on your basic the main thing that players do is Choose which of those actions they all perform.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and that's a worker placement game.
Speaker 1: I think it I think it is drizz lens itself toward Being a primary mechanic in a game as opposed to something that is just there in a much bigger game.
Speaker 1: There aren't.
Speaker 1: there aren't that many good games where?
Speaker 1: Placing workers is one of many actions you can take like that turns into those turn into salad games pretty quickly and get weird.
Speaker 1: I feel like most of the games that I would consider good personally that include worker placement.
Speaker 1: worker placement is Primary or it's very prominent in the game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean you could just have like a little sideshow where it's like, okay you play this whole game That's actually somewhere else.
Speaker 0: and then one of the bonus parts of the game is like, you know You have these workers that you put into spots, right?
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: but choosing workers to go into spots, even though it's a simple mechanic It's easy to understand you can teach it to anyone pretty quickly right?
Speaker 0: even people aren't super gamer II, right?
Speaker 0: It's that those choices are.
Speaker 0: So there's so much that goes into those choices.
Speaker 0: if you're actually trying right that It takes so much of your cognitive energies Even in such an even in a simple worker placement game right that you can't be having that as a sideshow.
Speaker 0: It needs to be the focus.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, it's just sort of a pain in the ass like ah I got to do figure out all this just for the side bit for ten bonus point over here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right It's like not work.
Speaker 1: No, that's right.
Speaker 1: I'd also have to say I would actually put another constraint on it because there's I forget what it's called But in like Hansa to a tonic, uh, you can put the worker or the token in the place.
Speaker 1: They get you victory points and there's a limited number of them.
Speaker 1: There is a constraint.
Speaker 1: It looks like worker placement.
Speaker 1: in some ways.
Speaker 1: I would argue that if The only actions the only result of placing workers is victory points or an equivalent as opposed to other Impacts to the game.
Speaker 1: It's not worker placement.
Speaker 1: That's something different.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now if there is a worker location that gets you a victory point But there's other worker locations that do something else mechanically.
Speaker 1: I think that's fine But if they only get you victory points, it's not worker placement.
Speaker 1: It's something else that I'd struggle to come up with a name for.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the the first worker like the first game that we knew was worker placement.
Speaker 0: like when we played it and I think Historically, we're still trying to figure out is Kayla's right?
Speaker 1: Yep, Kayla's was my I literally encountered the concept of worker placement.
Speaker 1: That was one of the early German board games.
Speaker 1: We got into.
Speaker 1: I spent a lot of money in that fucking game.
Speaker 1: Or did you one of us bought it?
Speaker 0: I had I think you bought it when it was Brent when it was brand new There was a big a big rave about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I bought it.
Speaker 1: I bought El Grande early and and Decker.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the thing is so.
Speaker 0: you came at this like one of the first ones if not the first one.
Speaker 1: bus is arguably the First one which I hadn't played it away later.
Speaker 0: So what introduced right as sort of this the the features of the worker placement, right?
Speaker 0: Was that?
Speaker 0: you know, obviously you only had a few a limited number of workers, right?
Speaker 0: I don't think there was a way to get more and Kayla's I think just everyone had the same number, right?
Speaker 0: I think so Yeah, but it definitely had the okay.
Speaker 0: certain actions sort of go together and overlap a little bit.
Speaker 0: But there are like these Pat.
Speaker 0: there are some that like you said generate victory points that have certain inputs, right?
Speaker 0: It was like some of them generate resources and then some of them shift resources and some of them turn resources into victory points, and so you basically Had to sort of pick which of the victory point ones you were gonna go for it.
Speaker 0: There was like a jewelry one and the castle right and the favors and so you couldn't with the number of workers You had you couldn't you do all these things at once right or at least not.
Speaker 0: Well, you had to pick one to really go for big time And I think that sort of holds true.
Speaker 0: and basically even though worker placement games have way different shapes You know how many years?
Speaker 0: 10 to 20 almost how many years of development since then?
Speaker 0: That that sort of still holds true and that you know, there's different the the the actions sort of.
Speaker 0: you know Different paths and you're trying to combine sets of actions together That don't overlap the other players because then you end up blocking each other and not getting ahead so much But then lead to one of this, you know being able to play the strong actions that actually win the game.
Speaker 1: Now I think another interesting discussion point and we can't be exhaustive here.
Speaker 1: I don't think even in multiple panels or writing a book we could be exhaustive.
Speaker 1: but Much like how trick-taking games or trick-taking is a mechanic We there's like different characteristics like must follow suit versus may follow suit.
Speaker 1: are there Trump's?
Speaker 1: are there multiple trumps?
Speaker 1: there are a lot of characteristics that in combination are what I think make worker placement so compelling because I Bet there's at least 30 or 40 unique definable Characteristics that could be applied to worker placement and every few games have the exact same Characteristics together because I think they tend to become very likely the same game if they do that.
Speaker 1: One example would be are all of the player worker of the places workers can go?
Speaker 1: Are they all available from the start?
Speaker 1: are they revealed in some way?
Speaker 1: Are they ownable by players in some way?
Speaker 1: Like do I put a worker on the board and I get a baby?
Speaker 1: or Does Scott build a place and if I put a worker there Scott gets a dollar?
Speaker 1: those are red.
Speaker 0: Some games allow players to like choose what the available actions will be.
Speaker 0: like you have cards in your hand Yeah, like and you play the card, right?
Speaker 0: And now that card is now an action.
Speaker 0: So you're choosing which actions are available to everyone or choosing which actions are available to yourself.
Speaker 0: Right rather than just.
Speaker 0: here's a set of actions that are pre-prescribed by the game and That's it right Agricola.
Speaker 0: They're pre-prescribed, but the order they come out They're available in is slightly randomized.
Speaker 0: Hey, this game is a little bit different.
Speaker 1: a player will build the building and that's a worker placement spot But also they get a privilege if they use it and other players have to pay them if they use it.
Speaker 0: Yep, another characteristic kinds of variations on the controlling of what are the actions right some permanent actions some random actions Right because you know a game might not work is like you might have a bad deal.
Speaker 0: We're like all none of all the if you randomize just everything it's like well No one can play the game because no there's no basic action available.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's no way to get wood wood powers everything else Softlock you need to have.
Speaker 0: usually you need to have some sort of basic area.
Speaker 0: That's like yes This action is always available in the game no matter what.
Speaker 0: so you can no matter what happens you can play and I think that Is a common mechanic.
Speaker 1: most worker placement games I can think of off the top of my head have like Some base things like Everdell.
Speaker 1: There's the base actions that are like get some wood and then there's the advanced stuff And then there's the win.
Speaker 1: more stuff like.
Speaker 1: there's different Classes of the types of actions you could take.
Speaker 1: win more tends to be a pile of victory points instead of an in-game advantage.
Speaker 1: Another aspect is the immediacy.
Speaker 1: like some games put a worker out get the thing.
Speaker 1: other games put a worker out Next turn or at some point in the future the worker comes back with the thing.
Speaker 1: some games worker stays there Even after you got the odd like after the thing happened until some future event happens.
Speaker 0: Yep, yeah, it's all kinds of stuff like that, so it's like you're managing right?
Speaker 0: you know how do you have workers available?
Speaker 0: You know do you throw them out too early?
Speaker 0: You hold on to them too long?
Speaker 0: you could have gotten more stuff right, but I think you know the majority of these games Right are games in which you put a worker to get stuff right there.
Speaker 0: resource Collections as well, but worker placement does not have to be Resource collection even though the majority of tabletop games that are worker placement games are Resource collecting games.
Speaker 0: for example you could make Tetris, and there are Three actions.
Speaker 0: actually there's flip left flip right slam it down and Like.
Speaker 0: is that it?
Speaker 0: oh no the next right you know swap put the piece in the storage right.
Speaker 0: So those are your four actions.
Speaker 0: now imagine playing a Tetris where you've got like two workers Right and those are your four choices.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: and now it's not a resource collection game anymore But it sure is the worker.
Speaker 0: Oh move left and move right those you need.
Speaker 0: those also right yeah And maybe I'll give you three workers with this.
Speaker 0: so it's like you know and you got to choose Right.
Speaker 0: it's like that could be considered a worker placement game.
Speaker 0: You're really limited.
Speaker 0: you might not be able to put the piece in the spot you want because You know yeah work right?
Speaker 0: It's like maybe I draw a piece that I want to put in the left side of my board.
Speaker 0: Rim draws a piece he wants to put in the left side of his Tetris board.
Speaker 0: I go first and I move mine left.
Speaker 0: Rim's got to now find a place to put his piece on the right or the middle.
Speaker 0: yeah Trouble.
Speaker 1: and there's also you know one at one common thing.
Speaker 1: I'm thinking about is that Typically the danger of designing a worker placement game is if your game allows for players to get more workers that Tends to be overpowered and it is rare.
Speaker 1: There is a game that successfully navigates that challenge without Giving everyone more workers or having extreme constraints on more workers.
Speaker 0: Well, I think one thing I've thought about that in the past right is that it's sort of obvious right like okay Taking at if all the actions don't change.
Speaker 0: the actions are what they are right.
Speaker 0: so being able to do more of them is like Taking more turns than other players, and that's just.
Speaker 0: it's obvious that like no matter what other rules there are in your game Taking actions is good.
Speaker 0: There's never.
Speaker 0: there's no action.
Speaker 0: That's like hurt myself.
Speaker 0: Every action brings you closer to victory so taking more actions is Necessarily more powerful than anything else that you could possibly conceive of.
Speaker 0: so games that allow you to get more workers Agricola right it's like you are aiming for.
Speaker 0: that is above all else right strategically right.
Speaker 0: But I do think there is an interesting design to be had where you could Scale the actions be give everyone ten workers right like go wild everyone.
Speaker 0: you get ten workers right but If you the how strong each action is will be Proportional to the total number of workers you choose to use.
Speaker 0: so if you put one worker on gather wood And that's it that's effectively the same as having all ten workers gather wood.
Speaker 0: therefore you get a fuck Simple makeup rules.
Speaker 1: now you get ten wood.
Speaker 1: if I put two workers out one on wood and one on stone I get five Wood and five stone.
Speaker 1: put ten workers out.
Speaker 0: So it's like you can choose how many workers to place and how many things you want to do.
Speaker 0: but the more you do the shittier you do each one.
Speaker 0: and then now you sort of solve that problem of.
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: okay, you know having more workers is just better.
Speaker 1: I can't think of it.
Speaker 1: does that?
Speaker 1: no
Speaker 0: I can't think of any game that does that either But at the same time you're still giving the players the choices of okay You don't need to do that many different things for your strategy because you've thought of a way to get by with just a few Types of actions.
Speaker 0: good you'll boost all those actions.
Speaker 0: Oh, you thought of a way to do.
Speaker 0: well But it requires diversification.
Speaker 0: you can diversify a whole lot and get all kinds of stuff going on But you're gonna do each of those things more weekly.
Speaker 0: so you're better take advantage of that Diversification to get ahead of the person who's only got a few things But has a lot of them now right and that could even out.
Speaker 0: if you did the math properly it would be still be fair.
Speaker 1: Two other ways to address that one I've seen and One I haven't but I have an example from what I would argue is not a worker placement game.
Speaker 1: what I've seen is you can get more workers, but either there is an extreme cost to that or Workers have to.
Speaker 1: there's some cost to placing a worker.
Speaker 1: thus having more workers has a higher burn rate of your Resources and that could be tuned and balanced.
Speaker 0: I've seen I mean a grickle.
Speaker 0: you have to feed your family Appropriately though they don't they don't scale it well.
Speaker 1: having another worker is So much better and so much more valuable than any amount of eating you have.
Speaker 0: because?
Speaker 1: well because inherently for that mechanic to work Right I think you need more workers and more stuff going on for that mechanic to work well.
Speaker 0: So here's the thing right.
Speaker 0: it's like let's say you need X resources to like maintain a work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: so therefore even if you have just one worker And that's it You still need the game has to be structured in such a way that the one worker can produce enough stuff to maintain themselves and Also more than that right.
Speaker 0: therefore Having ten workers will also produce enough to feed the ten workers.
Speaker 1: the board is Constrained or there's something else going on where you don't with you.
Speaker 1: You know you need multiple currencies multiple resources would need.
Speaker 0: you would need to make the cost to maintain a worker Exponential Relative to the number of workers so that cost it so that the maintenance for ten workers isn't just ten times the maintenance of one Worker.
Speaker 0: it would be like you know one to like.
Speaker 0: you know some power right.
Speaker 0: so that way.
Speaker 0: But then even if you did that everyone could just do the math and realize oh if I have five workers That's the sweet spot where they produce more The margins they produce versus.
Speaker 1: I feel like you're right Like a Pareto frontier of like three four or five workers in this particular game are the good ones.
Speaker 1: more than that You're very likely going to lose less than that.
Speaker 0: having a very likely having a cost on the workers is basically just Setting.
Speaker 0: you might as well just say okay Well the limit is five because buying six workers now they cost more to have than to use.
Speaker 0: so why would anyone ever get it?
Speaker 1: So I think it's possible, but it requires very good design and balance and requires likely Multiple independent currencies and some worker actions might require One or more resources from those different currencies.
Speaker 1: you can try to.
Speaker 0: I think you could have.
Speaker 0: Think you could have things where like if you're playing the game with this strategy the woods Strategy that like six workers is perfect.
Speaker 0: But if you're going down the the gold strategy then maybe you need seven workers because you need seven dwarves Gold right and it the way those actions are constructed.
Speaker 0: and then but that still would just be Figure out the optimal number of workers for each strategy, and I guess the point is everything we discussed.
Speaker 1: but if you can get more workers, or you can use more workers than someone else then Figuring that out becomes the most important skill in the game.
Speaker 0: Yes What the one way you can balance it is the way you can balance anything.
Speaker 0: which is that if there are going to be?
Speaker 0: Additional actions you know hand it out above the other and it's not symmetrical between all players.
Speaker 0: Then you have to use an auction of some.
Speaker 1: auction is the escape edge for almost any balance problems.
Speaker 0: You need some auction or something right and it's like okay?
Speaker 0: If you let someone buy the extra worker for a dollar and you lose because of that well It's that was your own fault right.
Speaker 0: but people if you had to bid in Agricola for with food to buy the baby Right at the baby market.
Speaker 0: It's like the game would be.
Speaker 0: that's it.
Speaker 0: the game is not balanced right?
Speaker 0: No one's gonna run away with the extra baby and win the game because the food they had to pay to get it Would even out.
Speaker 1: now a third way to go And I'm thinking some spitball in this partly because I can't think of a worker placement game.
Speaker 1: That's done this but Hansa toy tonica does this.
Speaker 1: it's a run actions not workers.
Speaker 1: You can spend resources to upgrade your actions and have more actions.
Speaker 1: But you can also spend resources to do other things in the game that are equally powerful to having more actions And thus it actually does create contention like if multiple people are trying to get more actions.
Speaker 1: You can almost do better by doing other less contentious things and level up other similarly powerful actions.
Speaker 1: But I struggle to apply that to worker placement in this context, but I feel like there's something there.
Speaker 1: But humps is a weird and other things that other games haven't done across the board.
Speaker 0: Another thing that's really simple to do is just have a way for people to lose workers One time use or dead work.
Speaker 1: Oh great.
Speaker 1: I forget the victory points.
Speaker 1: What if a curricula was?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, you couldn't feed that kid.
Speaker 1: They're gone.
Speaker 0: That sucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah shit like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just like, you know, okay, so You know you can still.
Speaker 0: people can get more workers.
Speaker 0: They put resources into that.
Speaker 0: but you know It might not be a huge impact if that worker like isn't just some permanent upgrade that makes them 20 25% stronger than the everyone else for the whole rest of the game.
Speaker 0: if it's just okay You're 25% stronger for a turn or two.
Speaker 0: It's like then it's not as big a deal and now it's not obviously so strong because that you would just have to go.
Speaker 1: I've seen games where you can't get an extra permanent worker, but you can like get a temporary worker.
Speaker 1: That's good for some number of uses.
Speaker 1: Yeah seen games like that So, huh now I'm thinking about because one thing that I think is really important is worker placement Even if the game does it some other way.
Speaker 1: I Like the physicality of having some sort of token that I put in a public place like place it out there.
Speaker 1: It's visible It's physical.
Speaker 1: I think that's important.
Speaker 1: But I also think it's underused.
Speaker 1: There are so few worker placement games where our worker is so many way to know where a worker Might have to.
Speaker 1: what if the worker placement the worker has to move around the map to get to the place Like in a grid?
Speaker 1: what if Whoever has the most workers in a place is the only one that gets to do the thing?
Speaker 1: It's a colonel blotto mixed with worker placement.
Speaker 0: I mean you have like Genoa Genoa moving around a little.
Speaker 0: you're moving around the town Yeah, or it's like you could even consider clue sort of like that, right?
Speaker 0: It's like yeah, you know You can only inquire about the study if you're standing in the study the action.
Speaker 0: It's like you might.
Speaker 0: you might know it was the conservatory But you can't guess the conservatory unless you roll and walk your ass over to the conservatory.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just think that it's important.
Speaker 1: if someone's thinking about worker placement It is useful and worthwhile to think about it in the context of placing physical markers in a shared space.
Speaker 1: I think that physicality matters Even though like you can argue a lot of things that don't have any of that Could mathematically be worker placement, but even if you have a game like that, that's why I get back to that first point I feel like it's worthwhile to think of it in those physical terms Or at least describe it in those physical terms.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, you know a lot of things, you know, you could somewhat argue right our sort of worker placement Right, like, you know or at least part like.
Speaker 0: think about I don't know magic the gathering the everything game, right?
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: is there any?
Speaker 0: there's?
Speaker 0: no there's no worker place in a magic the gathering, right?
Speaker 0: But it's like.
Speaker 0: well if you can think about your mana as like those are Every mana is a worker and you when you play it, you know, you could either have workers build new cards Which are then themselves actions, right at least if the cards have mana activation costs, right?
Speaker 0: Not creatures wouldn't count right but because creatures could act on their own without workers.
Speaker 0: Yeah But you know you spend two mana and the bill do you send those two workers to the builder area?
Speaker 0: Right the two red mana.
Speaker 0: and you summon this You know artifact that has a two mana activation cost and then you move two more of your mana workers onto the artifact.
Speaker 0: Yeah, take that action, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you're.
Speaker 0: you know, it's not really a worker placement because You're not playing like on the same actions as the opponent and blocking them Right, and like I said, you can summon creatures that just act on their own, right?
Speaker 0: Not everything has as this worker cost to do things.
Speaker 0: but you can see how like it looks nothing like a worker placement game.
Speaker 0: but that aspect of You have a limited resource to take actions with you You're.
Speaker 0: what actions you can take are determined by the state of the board, right?
Speaker 0: And you allocate your resources of playing to which of the what the actions you will activate in which ones you own.
Speaker 1: So I think if we did like say we did a panel or we went deeper on this topic overall I feel like there's a place for taking a few specific worker placement games and we'd have to play a lot of newer ones.
Speaker 0: if anyone people noticing people who know have been listening to this 15 years almost every game we mentioned was designed at least seven years ago Because we basically didn't play.
Speaker 0: we stopped playing a lot of worker placement games, you know We sort of played so many of them that we haven't played too many since then.
Speaker 0: like crown of Amara is like the lady So good there I think they'll.
Speaker 0: actually there was the the Well, we did an episode of those dude imperium and the other one.
Speaker 1: Yeah Dude, imperium is listed on this list of worker placement games I pulled up and there's the archaeology one where we're with our next.
Speaker 0: they were Yes, they're combining the worker placement with the deck building into sort of a combo deal, right?
Speaker 0: And it's like those like the newest ones we played but we've only played those like once or twice each like not enough.
Speaker 0: So if we're gonna do it We had to play a bunch of newer ones to see what more recent Developments are and then part of the panel is just gonna be going over a few not too many.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right, but just highlighting, you know different aspects.
Speaker 0: I feel like you go over a few and then also highlighting the specific strategies for games and then maybe Contrasting.
Speaker 0: but like look in this game the strategy to win is this and this they changes one thing.
Speaker 0: And now that the way to win this game is completely different
Speaker 1: I think
Speaker 0: as they change the one
Speaker 1: along the way me hopefully we can build the beginning of a lexicon similar to how trick-taking games have a very good lexicon of the characteristics of trick-taking games so that once you learn one like Everybody kind of speaks the same language of explaining.
Speaker 1: Oh and this one, you know follow suit.
Speaker 1: There's two Trump's and there's a coalition and like they have this language Trick-taking games don't quite have that language yet.
Speaker 1: But most gamers who play board games if you think about it You can start bucketing worker placement games pretty easily based on the kinds of things they include.
Speaker 1: But we don't have a shared language to describe all those things.
Speaker 1: We tend to describe them and not have a word for them.
Speaker 1: I don't know if we're gonna be good at making up words for them But I think we can at least start to describe What are the primary types of characteristics of worker placement games?
Speaker 1: If nothing else that'll we'll have to do that ourselves just while trying to write this panel Even if that's not in the panel.
Speaker 1: if that's just what we did to figure out the panel Maybe yeah thinking a lot about worker placement.
Speaker 1: I'm also desperately hungry and I gotta go vote.
Speaker 0: So I already voted early.
Speaker 1: and often like This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brand ok for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night
Speaker 1: and the patreon patrons for this episode of geek guides are Alan Joyce Linky G dread lily teddy break case care makes music Chris a dog Clinton Walton Dex Finn Joel Hayes penny rhymer Rebecca Dunn Sam Erickson shirvin Von Harl and a ton of people who give like a dollar or a euro per month.
Speaker 1: So yeah, uh geek nights is back at conventions.
Speaker 1: Look forward to our panel games.
Speaker 1: You can't play.
Speaker 1: I just have to Because Scott is extra pedantic and weird about panel names.
Speaker 1: Sometimes I know he never listens to this.
Speaker 1: He does not want to talk about games that could possibly under extreme circumstances Maybe be played without changing the title.
Speaker 1: and I'm not gonna change the title.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna lie to him about the title and he won't notice and it'll be fine.
Speaker 1: But anyway tonight I leave you with Megan Megan.
Speaker 1: we need your help, Megan Megan what?
Speaker 1: We need your help Megan.
Speaker 1: again.
Speaker 1: all the flutter ponies have been captured Again.
Speaker 1: will you come back and help us defeat the people and free our friends?
Speaker 0: can't the other ponies help?
Speaker 0: They have also all been captured.
Speaker 0: You're the only one who can help Megan.
Speaker 1: We need your human mungus brain and dextrous fingers to rescue them.
Speaker 0: Okay Hey, nah crap, let the ponies go fuck.
Speaker 0: Are you supposed to be?
Speaker 0: No, I said let the ponies go now.