Speaker 0: It's Thursday, October 5th, 2023.
Speaker 0: I'm Rym.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights Tonight.
Speaker 0: We are reviewing the Warwick Applefest.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So, uh... I don't have an opening bit about biking.
Speaker 0: Like, nothing weird happened.
Speaker 0: Nothing squirrelly.
Speaker 0: But I spent my lunch hanging out in Bryant Park.
Speaker 0: And, uh, do you know what's going on in Bryant Park right now?
Speaker 1: Uh, it's springtime.
Speaker 1: There should be a movie screen up.
Speaker 0: So, uh, they have torn up all the grass.
Speaker 0: And are already putting the skating rink together.
Speaker 1: Oh, right.
Speaker 0: They are the skating rink...
Speaker 1: I was like, "Oh, it's
Speaker 1: spring.".
Speaker 1: It's like, "No, it's not.
Speaker 1: It's
Speaker 1: fall.".
Speaker 1: Like, "It's spring.
Speaker 1: They should be putting...".
Speaker 0: So, they have already gotten about halfway through building the skating rink and the winter Christmas village in Bryant Park.
Speaker 0: So, as a result, there's, like, nowhere to sit because the whole park is fucked up with this construction and all this nonsense.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, it was 78 degrees and sunny.
Speaker 0: So, everyone in Midtown was trying to hang out in Bryant Park like you would.
Speaker 0: And it was packed to the point that it was like a PAX Expo Hall pre-COVID.
Speaker 0: Like, people trying to get into the park and then, like, failing and nonsense and chaos.
Speaker 0: But, I guess what stuck out to me is that I feel like places like New York City, whatever part of the bowels of New York City's government is responsible for planning, the day the Christmas village starts getting built...
Speaker 1: The parks department?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: At no point has considered whether or not that day should move based on climate change and the fact that it's not going to be cold enough for that skating rink to work probably for a month or two.
Speaker 1: It's going to be built... You would be actually shocked at the high temperatures that a skating rink can operate at.
Speaker 1: Obviously, it takes more energy for the cooling system, right?
Speaker 0: Well, but also, it's wet ice, which, like, yes, technically you can skate on it.
Speaker 0: But, and I guess that's fine if it's, you know, public skating in New York when really it's just a bunch of tourists waddling around.
Speaker 1: I think I had a thing of the day once about the company that does portable skating rinks.
Speaker 1: They set one up at, like, a ballroom at, like, you know, Georgia University, right?
Speaker 0: But, more importantly, they've taken up a huge percentage of the park with the Christmas village and the shopping nonsense.
Speaker 0: now at a time when the weather is going to be nice and people want to hang out in the park on the grass for at least another month or two the way things are going.
Speaker 1: So, I gotta figure... The Christmas village opens... When does it open?
Speaker 0: It's mostly built.
Speaker 0: Like, a bunch of the huts are fully functional and there's merchandise in them already.
Speaker 1: I'm just looking at the park's department website to see, like, the day that it's supposed to start.
Speaker 1: Because it's like, yeah, it's like if they're gonna, you know, open it on a certain day, then it's like obviously you have to start building it far enough in advance that it's ready on that day.
Speaker 1: I just don't know what the day is.
Speaker 0: Surprisingly close to being done based on the work they're doing, meaning the park is basically useless to people now until Christmas.
Speaker 1: I mean, usually that thing is still open in, like, early January, too, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: If you want some really overpriced stuff.
Speaker 0: And some actually pretty good food.
Speaker 0: The food there is actually... Every year, the only complaint I have about the food is that there are very long lines to get food at it and the food tends to take a while, but...
Speaker 1: Here we go.
Speaker 1: Bryant Park Event Club.
Speaker 0: The food in there tends to be pretty good and I feel at least I can... If it's gonna be open early, I can go over there and get that melted cheese for lunch.
Speaker 1: Anyway... The park event calendar does not say which day the thing starts.
Speaker 0: Anyway, in the news, something historic, and usually when you say something historic happened in American politics, in the current era, that means something very bad happened.
Speaker 0: and that is true once again.
Speaker 0: Something historic has happened.
Speaker 0: For the first time in the history of America's democracy, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, which is the lower chamber of our Congress, has been ousted, meaning they were kicked out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this happens in other countries.
Speaker 1: They oust their prime minister with the no-confidence votes, basically the same thing.
Speaker 0: It's a very different kind of thing because of the structure of the elections there and the fact that a prime minister serves at the pleasure of a coalition.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm just saying it's...
Speaker 0: They're very different too in that they happen commonly because there is a process around it where if the coalition falls, then the prime minister gets booted basically automatically through a no-confidence vote.
Speaker 1: I think the biggest difference is that when that happens, you usually have elections.
Speaker 0: Well, that's it because the process is you need an election to restructure the parliament and then, based on the results of the election, a new coalition has to form and that coalition appoints a new prime minister.
Speaker 1: It sure would be great if this triggered an election.
Speaker 1: That would be nice.
Speaker 1: That would fix things maybe a little bit.
Speaker 1: It doesn't.
Speaker 1: We have the problem where we have the no-confidence vote and then no election, so you're stuck with the same people and those people just figure it out.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's even worse than that because in America, because there's basically... Due to the nature of what our speaker is responsible for, because the Speaker of the House in America is paradoxically one of the most powerful political positions on earth because our government is designed very stupidly in this regard.
Speaker 0: So if you're not a U.S.ian, basically the House only ever votes on things that the Speaker personally, with zero oversight, decides come to the floor to a vote and no one can supersede them except in extremely narrow circumstances that are almost impossible to trigger.
Speaker 1: It doesn't have to be that way, but that's the rules.
Speaker 1: the House has decided for itself.
Speaker 0: Well, the only way to change... Well, some of that is constitutional because there's some other things going on.
Speaker 0: The Speaker of the House is also in the line of succession for the President.
Speaker 1: But basically, it literally is.
Speaker 1: There literally is a file cabinet that has all the bills that everyone's... Let's say even if everyone in the whole House, all those hundreds of people, they wrote a bill, they worked together in committees, and they edited it, and they... Even both parties are in love with this bill.
Speaker 1: Everyone is going to vote yes.
Speaker 1: It could just sit there, and the Speaker of the House could be like, "I don't feel like we're not going to have a vote for this,".
Speaker 1: and it doesn't become a law, and it just sits there.
Speaker 1: And then if the Congress ends, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, this is the thing that really bothers me, not just about the federal House, but the federal Congress, but most of the state ones, maybe all of them.
Speaker 0: Oh, that they can just now finish their business and then go home on vacation?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like that there's these sessions that end, and there's clocks.
Speaker 1: It's like the New York State budget every year.
Speaker 1: It's like, "We've got to get the budget done by this
Speaker 1: date.".
Speaker 1: And it's like, "What the fuck are you talking about?
Speaker 1: Shouldn't you be working every week of the
Speaker 1: year?".
Speaker 1: I'm not saying you shouldn't get no vacation ever, because you're still laboring, and it's difficult labor, indeed.
Speaker 1: But my company doesn't shut down when I'm on vacation.
Speaker 1: Let people take their vacations.
Speaker 1: They can proxy vote or whatever when they're away.
Speaker 1: And then it's like, don't stop legislating ever, and don't have weird deadlines.
Speaker 1: Just always be legislating all the time.
Speaker 0: Okay, so I think I wanted to respond to almost every few words you said, but that last one's an important one.
Speaker 0: So in the House right now, this was all triggered by a budget vote based on one of those deadlines.
Speaker 0: That deadline is fucking made up by Republicans to make sure we have this crisis on a regular basis.
Speaker 0: So it's a made up deadline.
Speaker 0: They can just vote to get rid of it.
Speaker 1: They're all made up.
Speaker 1: All the deadlines are made up.
Speaker 0: This one is extra made up.
Speaker 0: It is the most made up deadline.
Speaker 0: And it's solely because of our Republican Party.
Speaker 0: But it gets worse.
Speaker 0: The vast majority, like almost every member of the House, was more than happy to vote on a bill that just continued our current funding to get past the deadline.
Speaker 0: And it was eight motherfuckers who didn't want to vote for it in the Republican Party.
Speaker 0: These eight people are basically literal Nazis.
Speaker 0: They are the worst people in our government.
Speaker 0: And one of them literally looks like Butthead from Beavis and Butthead.
Speaker 0: He is the instigator of all of this.
Speaker 0: There's so much going on here.
Speaker 0: So everyone wanted to pass this.
Speaker 0: It's an obvious thing to pass.
Speaker 0: And passing it is only required for bullshit made up reasons.
Speaker 0: And yet they couldn't pass it because the Speaker refused to put it to a vote.
Speaker 0: because the Republicans only ever want to pass bills with only Republican support because they don't want to ever, they've said this out loud, make any compromise with the Democratic Party under any circumstances ever.
Speaker 0: Either pass something with only Republican votes or never bring it to the floor.
Speaker 0: That is like the most sacrosanct rule of the Republican Party.
Speaker 0: So the Speaker of the House, who is a dipshit, like don't get me wrong, I'm not praising him at any point, he is a fascist, he is a horrible, he is a very bad person, McCarthy.
Speaker 0: But after he tried to get the Republicans to pass a bill on their own and these eight dipshits said no, he actually did the reasonable thing and brought the generic bill to the floor to say, "Look, we're all going to vote on this and if Democrats vote for it, it'll
Speaker 0: pass.".
Speaker 0: And guess what?
Speaker 0: All the Democrats voted for it except like one and like a hundred Republicans voted for it.
Speaker 0: And it passed immediately and we avoided a government shutdown.
Speaker 0: The dipshit caucus then immediately removed the Speaker from power and now the U.S.
Speaker 0: House has no Speaker and cannot do anything and is completely powerless.
Speaker 1: Well good, if it can't do anything, it can't do anything bad.
Speaker 0: That's true, except that deadline, the bill that got passed.
Speaker 0: the deadline just pushed the deadline off a month.
Speaker 0: So we're going to have this exact crisis soon and it's going to be bad.
Speaker 0: Awesome.
Speaker 1: It'll be hilarious.
Speaker 0: Even funnier, the dipshit, the butthead guy, who is the instigator of all of this, the House was working to kick him out of the House actually.
Speaker 0: Like the Republicans want to kick him out of the House for ethics violations.
Speaker 0: Guess what they can't do until there's a new Speaker?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And guess who can prevent them from voting on a new Speaker?
Speaker 0: It's a game of chicken where there's literally no way out of it except a coup or a huge percentage of the Republicans allying with the Democrats.
Speaker 1: You don't need a huge percentage.
Speaker 1: You need like four or five.
Speaker 1: I haven't counted.
Speaker 0: That's the fun part.
Speaker 0: There's a tricky way this could go because the Democrats are playing this very smart.
Speaker 0: Their plan is that every time there's a House vote for the new Speaker, which is the only thing the House is allowed to do until they have a new Speaker, the Democrats are going to vote for Hakeem Jeffries, who is an awesome dude.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 1: That's what they did the last time, which is the right thing to do.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And the Republicans either have to get 100% of their members to vote for somebody, and that's not going to happen.
Speaker 1: Or Hakeem Jeffries wins.
Speaker 0: Or five of them have to vote for Hakeem Jeffries.
Speaker 0: And Jeffries would probably be more than happy to make some concessions and work with the people who decided to do that.
Speaker 1: Jeffries would be probably the best Speaker of the House ever.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Hakeem Jeffries is odd.
Speaker 0: Just go read about his deal.
Speaker 0: He is one of the best politicians in America right now, like Hakeem for President, for real.
Speaker 0: Yeah, sure.
Speaker 1: That's great.
Speaker 1: That's an easy vote.
Speaker 0: So, despite all of this, this is a crisis, partly because this has literally never happened, and there are a lot of constitutional questions, and there's a lot of unclear steps on how this all is going to go down.
Speaker 0: During all of this, the temporary Speaker of the House, the person whose only job is to be the fake Speaker, whose only power is to elect a new Speaker...
Speaker 1: Yeah, he can't go and bring up some other laws or anything to vote.
Speaker 1: See what he did?
Speaker 1: He kicked...
Speaker 0: A bunch of Democrats, who he personally hates, out of their offices in the Capitol to put Republicans in them.
Speaker 1: That's the kind of petty, childish things that they do.
Speaker 1: That's not new.
Speaker 0: Just to be a prick.
Speaker 0: And while that could be its own...
Speaker 1: Get ready to lose.
Speaker 1: Get ready to see what happens to you when you're not in charge.
Speaker 0: So, the Democrats who were kicked out, actually, to their credit, instead of making a big stink and fighting a lawsuit and all this sort of nonsense, they basically just said, "That's exactly what the Republicans are like.
Speaker 0: I can't believe how petty this is.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 0: Tell me what my office is.
Speaker 0: You have to give me at least
Speaker 0: one.".
Speaker 1: Eh.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 1: Be like, "All right.
Speaker 1: Go.
Speaker 1: I don't
Speaker 1: care.".
Speaker 0: This is newsworthy in that this is historic, and this is the most dysfunctional thing that has happened in the House of Representatives ever.
Speaker 1: It's gonna get more dysfunctional.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like that Simpsons meme.
Speaker 0: The most dysfunctional thing to ever happen so far.
Speaker 1: Eh.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 1: At least it's entertaining.
Speaker 1: It'd be boring if everything was just normal.
Speaker 0: I don't like that.
Speaker 0: some people, especially people who claim to be centrists, which is just a coward's way of saying you're actually conservative, but I don't like people who treat horse trading politics as direct entertainment because people die based on these decisions.
Speaker 0: Racist governments cause racist actions that hurt people.
Speaker 0: But this is entertaining partly because the Democrats are actually using their power to its fullest extent and pointing out what a clown show the Republicans are.
Speaker 0: They're both doing the right thing with the full extended power.
Speaker 1: They're doing all they can do without trying to break the rules or anything.
Speaker 0: The only thing they can do more than they are doing right now is literally start a coup.
Speaker 1: Everyone is doing what is within their power to do.
Speaker 1: That's what I fully expect, right?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's heartening and we'll see how this goes.
Speaker 0: So speaking of clown shows, you want to talk about Travis Scott?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, so everyone knows, we talk about this frequently on Geek Nights, right?
Speaker 1: That even though we hate capitalism, there is a reality in this world that some things have necessarily, not unnecessarily, we hate it when it's unnecessary and false scarcity, artificial scarcity, but some things are literally scarce, right?
Speaker 1: And the easiest example to go to that a lot of people encounter in their lives are tickets to concerts and other such venues because the event happens once.
Speaker 1: We're not going to play World Series Game 4 several times so that everyone can see it, right?
Speaker 1: It's like it's happening once.
Speaker 1: There are only so many seats in the stadium.
Speaker 1: That's it, right?
Speaker 0: You can't just magically make more appear.
Speaker 0: There's even a culture book about that.
Speaker 0: You didn't read this one, but that culture book has an event where a supernova is going to happen and there's a limited radius where people can see it directly with their own eyes and the culture accidentally reinvents money just for the sole purpose of people being able to go to this show because it'll literally only ever happen once.
Speaker 1: Yep, exactly.
Speaker 1: So, people get mad because what happens is the people who run concerts and other events sell tickets at too low a price even though the demand exceeds the supply.
Speaker 0: Too low by economic standards.
Speaker 0: We're not talking about society.
Speaker 0: We're not talking about whether or not this is good or evil or whatever.
Speaker 1: And when you do that, inevitably, there's nothing you can do about this, is that somebody will buy the tickets and sell them for a higher price and basically make a margin on that.
Speaker 0: This is called arbitrage.
Speaker 0: If Scott buys something for $20 that RIM is willing to buy for $50, Scott can sell it to RIM for $50 and make a profit, and that is expected.
Speaker 0: That is like mechanism design 101 that that will happen.
Speaker 1: The only way to avoid this, which people, I guess, would also be upset about, would be if the original ticket price was the highest price the market would pay, in which case people would be mad because Taylor Swift tickets would be like $5,000, $10,000, right?
Speaker 1: On the face value, and people wouldn't go for that, right?
Speaker 0: You're talking about when MagFest sells out.
Speaker 0: If they just sold MagFest at the maximum price that would sell out MagFest at all the hotels, I would pay several hundred dollars to go to a MagFest, but not everyone can afford that, but that's what the price would be.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Regardless, so the problem is because of this scenario, a lot of people get into this business of being ticket brokers and using bots and other various means to scoop up tickets, right?
Speaker 1: And then resell them and make a profit.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: We know all that story.
Speaker 1: It is an additional story, right?
Speaker 1: People in the United States and around the world have credit cards, and when you pay for something with a credit card, the person you bought something from has to pay a fee, the merchant's fee, right?
Speaker 1: And that merchant's fee goes to the bank, right?
Speaker 1: If it's like a Chase Bank credit card, Chase gets some money.
Speaker 1: If it's a Visa credit card, Visa gets some money.
Speaker 1: And to encourage you, right?
Speaker 1: Because that's where they make all their money, is from you swiping their credit card, right?
Speaker 1: They get the merchant, the person you swiped at pays them.
Speaker 1: They want you to use that credit card all the fucking time.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's a reason why I am very willing to be the one who swipes my credit card when I rent a big Airbnb for all my friends.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: When you're swiping a credit card, right?
Speaker 1: And so when you swipe your credit card, they encourage you to do this by sharing some of that with you, right?
Speaker 1: So basically, every time you swipe your credit card at any business, that person who runs that business pays MasterCard or whoever the fuck, and then they, in turn, pay you back some of the money with rewards.
Speaker 1: And the only person who gets screwed by credit cards are businesses that accept credit cards.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: I got status on an airline solely from one swipe when I rented that beach house for everybody.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, you can, the airline, basically airlines make more of their money from people swiping airline credit cards all around the world than they do from selling plane tickets, right?
Speaker 1: Because they're getting a trickle in of all those little bits of money from all these swipes everywhere, and those swipes turn into points, and as long as the points aren't spent, which a lot of them aren't, they just sit in a pile of money like a bank.
Speaker 1: And that's where all the wealth of airlines is, not in selling plane tickets.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so here's the thing, if you are someone who has a credit card, if you knew for certain, absolute certain, that you could buy something and then resell the something at or higher than the price you bought it for, even if you had no interest in that something.
Speaker 1: So if I knew for certain that I could buy a Taylor Swift concert ticket and resell it for more than I paid, which I do know that.
Speaker 0: If you could even resell it for as low as slightly less than you paid, you'd still break certain.
Speaker 1: Right, but that's besides the point, right?
Speaker 1: If I know that I can buy a Taylor Swift concert ticket with my credit card and then sell it, and at the same price or greater or slightly less, like Rym said, right?
Speaker 1: Then I will profit because even though I didn't keep the ticket and I didn't make any money on the arbitrage, I got points for using my credit card.
Speaker 1: So there is a community of people online who basically are trying to constantly max out, get lots of credit cards, max them out, but then max them out by buying things that they then resell.
Speaker 1: So basically they can always pay off their credit card in full.
Speaker 1: They didn't actually lose any money, but they got shit tons of points and rewards and cash back.
Speaker 1: And they're profiting just by buying things and selling things that they don't even fucking want, right?
Speaker 1: And so this is a perfect storm because concert tickets set up systems to try to stop bots, but individual people with credit cards, legitimate actual people, not bots, right?
Speaker 1: If you can organize those people and say, "Hey, I'm putting the word out.
Speaker 1: Anyone out there who has a credit card, if you buy Taylor Swift tickets, I will buy them from you at like a 10% markup guaranteed, I swear, right?
Speaker 1: If you do this, you'll get credit card points.
Speaker 1: Let's all team up and I'll be the one to sell all the tickets.
Speaker 1: You won't have to take the risk of trying to find a buyer, right?
Speaker 1: I'm guaranteeing you this markup, right?
Speaker 1: And then I'll take on the risk of finding actual
Speaker 1: buyers.".
Speaker 0: And that is how capital markets arbitrage works is a series of steps like this where someone assumes a risk and then someone else basically underwrites that risk by saying, "No, I'll assume that
Speaker 0: risk.".
Speaker 0: And everyone's taking a piece along the way.
Speaker 1: So there's a company that did exactly that.
Speaker 1: They would put out the word and they would say, "Hey, all you people who want to max out your credit cards and get points, buy this and I will buy it from you, right?
Speaker 1: Do it
Speaker 1: now.".
Speaker 1: And so people would go buy the tickets, they sold it to the company, it worked.
Speaker 1: Those people got credit card points.
Speaker 1: That company got tickets, they resold the tickets, they made money.
Speaker 1: It actually worked.
Speaker 1: People don't like it, but that was happening.
Speaker 1: It's a thing, the only solution is the one we discussed.
Speaker 0: I can't even actually argue that it's particularly unethical.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying, that's a thing that's happened.
Speaker 1: So here's the funny part, right?
Speaker 1: That risk was never eliminated, right?
Speaker 1: You think that sounds like the least risky thing ever.
Speaker 1: Of course you can resell the Taylor Swift tickets, right?
Speaker 1: Well, the company said, "All right, let's do the Travis Scott
Speaker 1: tickets.".
Speaker 0: Now you might remember, there's an important piece of information.
Speaker 1: Travis Scott, who is incredibly popular, he's like insane popular.
Speaker 0: But he had a concert in 2021 that, due to poor crowd control and fucked up, there's a whole report on who is responsible for this, 10 people were killed by a massive crowd crush.
Speaker 1: No, that's true.
Speaker 1: But regardless, this guy is still insanely popular.
Speaker 1: He's chart-topping, streaming, big, big popular artist.
Speaker 1: You got to imagine his shows are going to sell out.
Speaker 1: And the demand will be higher than the supply.
Speaker 1: So the company says, "All right, everybody, go buy the tickets with your credit
Speaker 1: cards.".
Speaker 1: And guess what happened?
Speaker 1: Uh-oh, the demand, we don't know why.
Speaker 1: It could be the reason Rims suggested people are afraid of dying.
Speaker 1: It could be that he's not as popular now.
Speaker 1: Who knows?
Speaker 1: But the demand was not there.
Speaker 1: And the company that assumed the risk cannot resell the tickets.
Speaker 0: People are buying good tickets for as low as $14 on Stuff Hub right now.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So basically, people bought the tickets with their credit cards, and some of them were not able to get paid back from the company that's centralizing all this.
Speaker 1: And now they're trying to, people trying to max out their credit cards got hosed.
Speaker 1: And then the company that told everyone to max out their credit cards is also getting hosed, sitting on a pile of tickets that they can't sell for even face value because no one wants to go to the concert.
Speaker 1: And, you know, the winner in this case would be Travis Scott, who sold out, he sold out his concert, whereas if there hadn't been people trying to arbitrage, he would not have sold out his concert and made less money.
Speaker 1: So he's very happy about this whole situation, even though his concert won't be that crowded, but his concert wouldn't have been crowded anyway.
Speaker 1: Even if this didn't happen, his concert still would have had the same audience.
Speaker 0: And his concert might now actually get more crowded if people could buy tickets for $14.
Speaker 1: Yeah, more people might actually come now that the prices are tanked.
Speaker 1: But all the people trying to do the scam have gotten screwed, which is just kind of hilarious.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, because that is, you know, capitalism, I guess, as a professional in capitalism, based on my day job, I would say that one of the most important controls on a capitalist system, one that the lack of such controls is one of the main reasons why capitalism tends to hurt people so badly and concentrate wealth so profoundly, is that if you are making a profit and all you are providing to make that profit is an assumption of risk, then if the risk comes to pass,
Speaker 1: you
Speaker 0: must get fucked.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, you are making a profit for nothing.
Speaker 0: So these people getting fucked is good by most measures, by moral measures, by capitalist measures.
Speaker 0: Capitalism would be less cruel if more people who were only paid by assuming risk got fucked more often by that risk.
Speaker 1: Yep, the bad parts of capitalism, it's usually a situation where people fucked around and did not find out, or someone made someone else find out when they're the ones who fucked around, right?
Speaker 1: Like all the banks that got bailed out instead of when they should have gone to prison.
Speaker 0: Or big brain theory, situations like the existence of 401(k)s, which was a big part of why pensions went away, where that basically guarantees that anyone who makes money is throwing money into the stock market, thus perpetuating a cycle of the number has to always go up.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Anyway, this is just a hilarious situation, and it's a topic that we talk about often, and I'm sure we will talk about again, but it's a new twist.
Speaker 1: But it does make me think, though, that the credit card part of it is not really the worst idea, and if you do come across something where you are absolutely certain, like, you have to be really certain, right?
Speaker 1: Like a Taylor Swift concert.
Speaker 1: If you're only 90%, that's not good enough, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, remember those guys who pooled in the $10,000 to bet on a cricket match while it was going, and the team was up by like 100, and then they lost?
Speaker 1: Right, it's like, you gotta be so certain that the thing you are buying is going to be able to be resold at, or at least at the value you paid.
Speaker 1: If you're that certain of that, even if it's a thing you don't want, if the value of it is high enough, it may be worth it to buy it with your credit card and then resell it just to get points, and it's like, if that doesn't take too much effort that it's, you know, worth your time, maybe do it?
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: It's better than casino.
Speaker 1: It's, you know, it's probably less risky than the stock market if, if, the biggest.
Speaker 1: if, you really have that certainty.
Speaker 1: Like, so certain.
Speaker 1: We're talking, like, Super Bowl ticket certainty.
Speaker 1: Like, you know you can resell them.
Speaker 1: No question.
Speaker 1: But I guess even there, there's a risk that the Super Bowl can be cancelled.
Speaker 0: It might not necessarily work out if the team, like...
Speaker 1: No, it might not.
Speaker 1: No, it has to be really... But it's like, even the Super Bowl can get cancelled.
Speaker 1: There's always a risk.
Speaker 1: But I think Super Bowl cancelled is a less risk than...
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day!
Speaker 0: So, a long time ago, like, a decade or more ago, I had a thing of the day that was, like, an AMV that implied that Speed Racer was actually a bad person who hurt people.
Speaker 1: Speed Racer is a bad person who hurts people and has monkey labor.
Speaker 1: Child and monkey labor.
Speaker 0: I mean, how many people...
Speaker 1: In his employ.
Speaker 0: There are so many episodes of Speed Racer where he just rams someone off the road and the car explodes, and no one seems to hear shit.
Speaker 1: This car has guns that shoot people, and it's like...
Speaker 0: But, uh, I have found an entire corner of the internet of people who basically just make long-form, relatively high production value videos, really highlighting the violence and the evil of Speed Racer, and this is the best of them that I have seen.
Speaker 1: He's really evil.
Speaker 1: Cars.
Speaker 1: Bad.
Speaker 0: This is titled "Speed Racer's Vehicle of
Speaker 0: Violence.".
Speaker 1: Well, you know, as my news suggested, we on Geek Nights love to discuss gambling and how you shouldn't do it, ever.
Speaker 1: Even though we'll talk about it constantly.
Speaker 0: I'm playing this gambling game right now while we talk.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And one of the gamblings that you should never, ever, ever do, under any circumstance, is video poker.
Speaker 1: Video poker is, like, one of the worst things you can put money into.
Speaker 1: Basically, like, it's 'cause it has this illusion that you have some sort of control or skill involved, right?
Speaker 1: 'Cause you're actually deciding to hold cards and draw other cards, right?
Speaker 1: But, a video poker machine is just a slot machine in disguise.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: And the payouts are terrible.
Speaker 0: Well, you know what it is?
Speaker 0: It's a slot machine where you can't be better at it with skill, but if you are very stupid, you will somehow be worse at it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can misclick or make a mistake.
Speaker 0: It measures a slot machine where, if you pull the lever too slow, you're less likely to win.
Speaker 0: That's what video poker is.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Video poker is just avoid it at all costs.
Speaker 1: But, video poker, the game, I guess, right?
Speaker 1: If you take away the real money part of it, is just sort of this aesthetic thing, right?
Speaker 1: Like, sitting at a video poker machine.
Speaker 1: It's sort of a unique kind of machine with a unique display and art style and sounds.
Speaker 1: And, you know, it's this kind of experience of just playing it.
Speaker 1: So, somebody, it's kind of awesome, they made this classic video poker on a website.
Speaker 1: So, you go to this website and just, like, this perfect, like, scanline, CRT-looking, like, video poker just loads.
Speaker 1: And you can play it with, they give you $25.
Speaker 1: It's just the number 25 is on the screen, right?
Speaker 1: And you can just play, and if you run out of money, you can reload and go back to $25.
Speaker 1: It's just a video poker clone, basically, but it's just the feeling of playing it.
Speaker 0: The sound effects it makes are real good.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's just on the money and, you know, if you have any urge to play video poker, just play this.
Speaker 1: Hooray.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's about all you're going to win.
Speaker 1: Just play this and you can sort of get all of the good parts, you know, whatever good parts video poker has are here.
Speaker 1: And the "guaranteed you're going to lose your money" part is not here because it's free.
Speaker 0: It's just the website.
Speaker 0: Alright, in the meta moment, the Geek nuts book club book, the murder bot diary.
Speaker 0: Once diaries, once we, the next one comes out, we'll read that and then we'll give you guys a few weeks to read it and then we'll do a show on it.
Speaker 0: I am five murder bots in.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I am all the murder bots in.
Speaker 0: Yep, you've gotten a little more murder bot than me.
Speaker 1: Literally all of it, except for what's going to be published very soon.
Speaker 0: They are very, very fast reads.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, we're going to be at PAX with not one, but two panels.
Speaker 0: Well, two events and it looks like the schedule just got published, so I'll make a post about it now.
Speaker 1: But only one of our events is on the schedule.
Speaker 0: Oh, I guess the learn and play schedule is not published yet.
Speaker 1: Oh, I think that is the event.
Speaker 1: I think the other one is not on the schedule.
Speaker 0: Well, there you go, because we're definitely doing two.
Speaker 0: We are doing on one day, I had the note up, I got to post later.
Speaker 0: Anyway, one of the days we are doing a brand new panel, mastering game mechanics, worker placement.
Speaker 0: Rem and Scott talking about nothing but worker placement mechanics for 59 minutes.
Speaker 0: It's going to be glorious.
Speaker 1: And that is not on the official schedule yet.
Speaker 0: We are doing a learn and play and win.
Speaker 0: We're going to teach you all how to be good at Wist, Hearts, and Wizard.
Speaker 1: That is on the schedule.
Speaker 1: That is on the PAX website.
Speaker 0: It's going to be exciting.
Speaker 0: I'm looking forward to that one.
Speaker 0: We're not going to actually play Wist.
Speaker 0: We're going to do one hand of Wist with everyone because Wist is not worth playing.
Speaker 0: It's basically just how to learn to do trick taking.
Speaker 0: But we will teach Wist.
Speaker 0: Wist is a pretty simple game.
Speaker 0: Any other meta?
Speaker 0: I guess we can talk about the website.
Speaker 1: We are going to attempt to launch the New Geek Guys website on Saturday, October 2 days from now.
Speaker 1: 7th?
Speaker 1: 7th.
Speaker 1: We'll see how that goes.
Speaker 1: It might fail.
Speaker 1: We could revert.
Speaker 1: Rem is obsessed with this new noise he found.
Speaker 0: That new noise I found is the announcement sound anytime I join a Discord voice chat now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, mine is much better than that.
Speaker 0: I made it as long as possible to be as annoying as possible.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see mine is this one.
Speaker 0: That's a real good one.
Speaker 1: That's as bad as good as it gets.
Speaker 1: I couldn't think of anything better.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: It's the elephant sound.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: I'm coming in like an elephant.
Speaker 0: Watch the fuck out.
Speaker 1: It's a spider elephant.
Speaker 1: Elephant bit by radioactive spider.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: So yeah, it might work.
Speaker 1: It might not.
Speaker 1: You might like it.
Speaker 1: You might not like it.
Speaker 1: That's tough cookies.
Speaker 1: We like it.
Speaker 1: We're going with it.
Speaker 1: It does enough that it can replace the current website.
Speaker 1: We're going to continue to work on it because the code is so updated.
Speaker 1: It's actually very easy to work on and update this website since the code isn't 10+ years old.
Speaker 1: It's modern.
Speaker 1: It auto deploys all kinds of fancy shit.
Speaker 1: And that code will be on GitHub.
Speaker 1: And you can send us pull requests or whatever and help work on it for no money if that's what you want to do.
Speaker 1: And yeah, that's exciting.
Speaker 1: Finally, we talked so long and shit talking.
Speaker 1: But no, it's going to be for real.
Speaker 1: And if there's any, you know, you can even just send suggestions in the GitHub issues if you want, you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And from there we can start to do it.
Speaker 0: Once we've got it live and all the kinks are ironed out.
Speaker 0: That's where we can start to do some new stuff.
Speaker 0: We can dig into the hopper.
Speaker 0: The Geek Nights hopper.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: We kept talking about it, but we never actually did it.
Speaker 0: We didn't add the new bit we were talking about at the end of the show.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, we talk about a lot of things that we don't do.
Speaker 0: We do talk about a lot of things.
Speaker 1: But then sometimes we do them.
Speaker 0: And our worker placement panel is on.
Speaker 0: I actually pulled it up from this internal.
Speaker 0: Saturday 2.30 PM in the Crab God Theater.
Speaker 1: All right, let me see.
Speaker 0: Feel free to announce it to the world.
Speaker 0: It is by no means a secret.
Speaker 1: I see.
Speaker 1: The Crab God Theater is not yet listed in the list of locations.
Speaker 0: Ah.
Speaker 0: I wonder what other secrets the Crab God is hiding from us.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So on Geek Nights we've reviewed things like video games.
Speaker 0: We've reviewed conventions.
Speaker 0: We've reviewed concerts.
Speaker 0: I don't see why we can't review an Apple Fest that we went to upstate.
Speaker 1: So I've been to this Apple Fest before.
Speaker 1: New York is the Empire State.
Speaker 1: Apples are sort of our thing.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of fucking apple orchards here.
Speaker 1: Apple Seasons.
Speaker 0: If you live out of the U.S.
Speaker 0: I feel like a lot of people who live outside of the U.S.
Speaker 0: At least have this impression that like Yeah, Americans.
Speaker 0: There's something with them and apples.
Speaker 0: Because apples are very...
Speaker 1: New York is the big apple.
Speaker 0: Johnny Appleseed is a full hero in America.
Speaker 0: Even though the Disney movie is very wrong about what he was doing.
Speaker 0: Spoilers.
Speaker 0: He was making fucking apple whiskey.
Speaker 0: He was making alcohol.
Speaker 0: He was not making apple fritters or apple pies.
Speaker 1: Places have their local crops.
Speaker 1: You go to Columbia, get some coffee.
Speaker 1: Go to New York, get some apples.
Speaker 1: It's apple season.
Speaker 1: And there's a town in New York State.
Speaker 1: It's not part of New York City.
Speaker 1: It's New York State called Warwick.
Speaker 1: And it's a cute little quaint country home kind of town.
Speaker 0: It's about an hour north of the city.
Speaker 0: Unless there's typical traffic.
Speaker 0: In which case it's two and a half hour.
Speaker 1: It's just north of New Jersey and Pennsylvania.
Speaker 1: A little bit west and a little bit north.
Speaker 0: Yep, Emily and I got some family out there.
Speaker 1: And that place is all about apples.
Speaker 1: There are many apple orchards in range.
Speaker 1: Short range of the little town of Warwick.
Speaker 1: And so every year they have an apple festival.
Speaker 1: That apple festival I think might have been cancelled during the dark times.
Speaker 1: But I went to it once before.
Speaker 0: I had been to it zero times before.
Speaker 0: Because relatives, the same relatives we met when we went up there.
Speaker 0: And we asked them this past weekend, "Hey, do you want to meet us
Speaker 0: there?".
Speaker 0: And their response was, "Fuck no.
Speaker 0: That's a crowded
Speaker 0: nightmare.".
Speaker 1: Well I know you've been to Warwick, but you didn't go to the apple festival.
Speaker 0: No, I have never been to the apple fest before.
Speaker 0: Because in the past, I had the perception that it is extremely crowded.
Speaker 1: It is crowded, yes.
Speaker 1: So, we went to the apple festival again.
Speaker 1: A second time.
Speaker 1: Because I needed some fucking apples.
Speaker 1: Apple season was coming to an end.
Speaker 1: And usually you can go to the apple festival and then go to a nearby orchard.
Speaker 1: Load up on apple, donuts, and cider.
Speaker 1: And then go home and that's a lovely day on the weekend.
Speaker 0: You want to talk about that first?
Speaker 0: Because I was really looking forward to both of these aspects of this trip.
Speaker 0: And after we're at the apple fest, and we'll review it in a moment.
Speaker 0: You know, good old time.
Speaker 0: We decide, let's go to an orchard.
Speaker 0: And we look and we figure out which one to go to.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of different orchards and all the orchards are different.
Speaker 1: Some of them have tons of apples, but not too many exciting varieties.
Speaker 1: Some of them specialize in having lots of varieties, but there's not a lot.
Speaker 1: They're all different.
Speaker 1: One of them's got this pizza.
Speaker 1: One of them is like, you know, people are just partying out in the orchard.
Speaker 1: Bringing out folding tables and letting their kids run wild.
Speaker 1: And some of them, it's like, no, people are there for picking.
Speaker 1: To get, you know, because they got to go make some apple shit.
Speaker 1: And they don't let you hang out in the orchard and do other stuff, right?
Speaker 1: You got to hang out in their, you know, hanging out area.
Speaker 1: So each orchard has a different kind of specialty.
Speaker 1: That they, you know, that's their thing.
Speaker 1: To separate themselves from the competition.
Speaker 0: Yup, and so we just, we pick one.
Speaker 0: The one that we wanted to go to.
Speaker 1: The one we picked was the one I've been to before, twice.
Speaker 1: It's a really happening one.
Speaker 0: Yup, I'm 90% sure.
Speaker 0: I've been to that one too.
Speaker 0: I guess, the line of cars.
Speaker 0: To get into this orchard, however long you think I'm going to say.
Speaker 0: Like, put it up in order of magnitude.
Speaker 0: It was like blocking traffic so far that we weren't sure if we could even get back toward the other side of where this orchard was to go to a different one.
Speaker 1: It was hard to, it was hard to tell because it's like people are in line on a two lane road that, but it's not one way.
Speaker 1: So it's like, yeah, everyone's lined up.
Speaker 1: And it's like if you just wanted to continue down that road and go straight and not turn into the orchard.
Speaker 1: You had to just wait in this line of cars that were all turning right into the orchard.
Speaker 0: Yup, double yellow line.
Speaker 0: You can't pass there safely or legally.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like now.
Speaker 1: there was a way to escape from that.
Speaker 1: thanks to Google Maps got us out of there.
Speaker 0: Yup, we took a serpentine path through a subdivision.
Speaker 1: If you wanted to go in the same direction as those cars and you were beyond the turn, it's like you couldn't get it, you know.
Speaker 1: It's like I thought about trying to pull a scam where it's like, well, if we're on the side road trying to pull in and make a left, someone's going to let us in eventually.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: We're not just going to sit there for infinity.
Speaker 0: I do think we would have sat there for infinity unless I took aggressive driving actions, the likes of which I am not personally willing to do.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So it's like, you know, yet so you have to let someone cut in line eventually.
Speaker 1: And I bet you could lie and be like, no, no, no, I'm going to go straight.
Speaker 0: Here's the problem, though.
Speaker 0: Let's say we did.
Speaker 0: We cut in line where we would have cut in.
Speaker 0: I think the line was it was really long.
Speaker 0: It was still very, very far, but at the point where we would have had to go into the orchard.
Speaker 0: Now, the person who we told that we are just passing through would then see that we have, in fact, turned into the orchard and they are changed our minds.
Speaker 0: They're now right behind us in traffic and they might have a gun.
Speaker 1: Fight me, bro.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But I mean, on the one hand, the line was really long, but on the other hand, it was a car line.
Speaker 1: And the thing to remember about a car line is that it's much longer than it appears to be, because most of the space in the line is taken up by car.
Speaker 1: The actual number of people in that line could have been like one hundred, like one hundred people waiting in line.
Speaker 1: It takes up almost no room.
Speaker 1: One hundred people in cars waiting in line is as long as one hundred cars.
Speaker 0: But it's a long as, you know, based on looking at that line, it did not appear that it had moved any appreciable amount at any point.
Speaker 1: Well, no.
Speaker 1: See, that's the thing is like if we could have physically gotten to the orchard, we would have been fine.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But the because there's plenty of room for people at the orchard and parking was the reason for the line.
Speaker 0: Even the orchard we ended up going to, we pull in and the parking guy like stand in there and he basically is like, yeah, you're fucked.
Speaker 0: There's nowhere to park.
Speaker 0: You should just drive all the way in and turn around and get out.
Speaker 0: And we did park and it was fine.
Speaker 0: The guy was just really harried.
Speaker 0: And I think he was just trying to get people to turn around.
Speaker 1: I never saw somebody didn't want customers.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: The other orchard with the mega line, you know, this orchard we went to didn't have a mega line.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 1: The one that did have the mega line.
Speaker 1: They were turning people away.
Speaker 1: They were like, yeah, keep this mega line going.
Speaker 1: Give me that money.
Speaker 1: Let's go.
Speaker 0: I just I don't believe most of the people in that line based on how long it looked like it was.
Speaker 0: And especially when I looked at Google and it showed a red line going off miles and miles and miles down that road.
Speaker 0: I don't think most of those people could have even gotten into the orchard before it closed at five.
Speaker 1: Who knows?
Speaker 0: Because we we bailed.
Speaker 0: We're not stupid.
Speaker 0: We went to a different orchard.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: A further an orchard further away from the festival.
Speaker 1: Just like a restaurant further away from the convention.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Has less.
Speaker 0: Way less.
Speaker 0: We basically just got right in even despite the dire warnings of the parking lot attendant.
Speaker 0: We got right in.
Speaker 1: We got it.
Speaker 1: But it was a. it was a not as good orchard.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It seems like that orchards main deal was apple alcohol, which fine.
Speaker 0: Like I'm here for that.
Speaker 1: I think if you were interested in alcohol that the orchard we went to would have been excellent, I assume.
Speaker 0: Except the problem is the poison.
Speaker 0: I was driving us.
Speaker 0: So it's not like I could partake of the alcohol.
Speaker 1: You could have bought some to take home.
Speaker 0: But I wouldn't want to hang out in the orchard and drink the alcohol.
Speaker 0: But also inside of this orchard, there weren't lines to do most things.
Speaker 0: And there wasn't even a big line for the donuts.
Speaker 0: It's just they.
Speaker 0: they started selling the donuts at a specific time.
Speaker 0: And Scott got into near the front of that line.
Speaker 0: So we were good there.
Speaker 0: The line to get the apple poison was so long that I basically couldn't.
Speaker 0: So I didn't.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't bother.
Speaker 1: Also, the donuts were not you know, they were fine, but they were not the best.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, even a bad cider donut is still good.
Speaker 0: And those were like.
Speaker 0: those were, I'd say, B B level cider donuts, which is still great.
Speaker 0: Like I will eat twelve B level cedar donuts.
Speaker 0: Cider donuts have no complaints.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: Now, there is also Fishkill Farms, which is in Fishkill, New York, up near where we used to live in Beacon.
Speaker 1: And that farm, the way they solve their problem is they make you buy picking apple picking tickets in advance and they sell out.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So you could use some arbitrage and sell.
Speaker 1: you sell your apple picking tickets.
Speaker 0: I think that is going to be more and more prevalent in the US in general, because something I've noticed post covid, things that used to be crowded, but not like terminally crowded are way more crowded lately.
Speaker 0: And I think it's partly people who were stuck inside for three years, kind of just going apeshit and doing stuff.
Speaker 1: There are many there are many, many reasons for these sorts of things.
Speaker 1: But anyway, the Apple Festival.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: So the Apple Festival is about the scale of the equivalent non Apple Festival called Farm City Week that I used to go to every year as a kid in Michigan.
Speaker 0: And I haven't been to a festival like that in a long time.
Speaker 0: So I was kind of here for it.
Speaker 1: It's like it's basically like the whole town is taken over by this Apple Festival.
Speaker 1: Even businesses like that are not directly connected to the Apple Festival and are thus cut off from most of the foot traffic are still putting stuff out and setting up tents.
Speaker 0: And in every direction, like in the parking lot of the CVS, there was like a giant festival going on under a tent like.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like it's like none of those things are on the official festival map or are part of the festival technically.
Speaker 1: But like every single business that was within range of the festival was getting involved somehow.
Speaker 1: And it was effectively part of the festival because, you know, they got something going on.
Speaker 1: They're trying to.
Speaker 1: you know, everyone's just.
Speaker 1: it's like shit.
Speaker 1: Tons of people are coming to our town.
Speaker 1: We're going to squeeze every last drop of money out of them that we can.
Speaker 0: So I wonder how many people attend this thing?
Speaker 0: because a lot.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I wonder how many.
Speaker 0: Let's see.
Speaker 0: Attendance at.
Speaker 1: It's going to be thousands, right?
Speaker 0: I could guess 10,000.
Speaker 0: A lot of people roll into a thing, leave, and New York City people are all coming.
Speaker 0: New York, Warwick, Apple Fest.
Speaker 0: What is the estimate?
Speaker 0: It's the largest Apple Festival.
Speaker 0: They don't give me a number.
Speaker 0: It was a lot of people.
Speaker 0: The population of this entire town is only 6,000 people.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So I feel like a multiple of this town might have showed up for the day or at least for a portion of the festival.
Speaker 0: But, you know, in terms of the poisonous aspects of cars in America, there is no way to get to this town except by car.
Speaker 0: And there is not enough parking even for the people who live in this town, let alone thousands and thousands and thousands of New York City folk all driving up to go to this Apple Festival.
Speaker 0: So they set up gigantic parking lots on the edge of town and a constant line of school buses taking people from their cars to the festival.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's very intelligent of them.
Speaker 1: It's like, well, you know, we need a parking lot, but we only need it once a year.
Speaker 1: And no one's going to school on fucking Saturday, even if school season has started.
Speaker 0: And the school, because everyone gets to the school and cars, has a massive parking lot.
Speaker 1: Correct.
Speaker 1: So it's like they just use the school's parking lot and they bus people to the festival and they charge ten bucks for it.
Speaker 1: And yeah, that's like.
Speaker 1: that's just smart.
Speaker 1: I think that's actually something that bothers me a lot that I see.
Speaker 1: And even in New York City is that, for example, you have a school in New York City that has many facilities, lots of facilities that are all paid for and are run by the Department of Education.
Speaker 1: But those are facilities even in the summer when they are not in use at all.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Or at night when they are not in use at all by any school.
Speaker 1: And there's no students.
Speaker 1: there are basically off limits, even though they are public property.
Speaker 1: No other members of the public can make any use of them because it's only for school.
Speaker 1: And in the summer, you have like a huge field that's just empty and unused.
Speaker 1: that could be like temporarily handed over to the Parks Department.
Speaker 1: And then if somebody wanted to put the effort in, but in a small town, right, where there's less resources to manage and there aren't so many separate departments, right, managing everything.
Speaker 1: It's like, yeah, we can just use our school building for fucking everything that we put a lot of the town's money into building this building.
Speaker 0: Okay, I found a number.
Speaker 0: The Warwick Applefest claims 30,000 people go on average.
Speaker 1: Not bad.
Speaker 0: Not bad.
Speaker 0: So several, many times the population of the entire town.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So yeah, you go there.
Speaker 1: And what do they have?
Speaker 1: Obviously, delicious foods of many, many varieties.
Speaker 1: Even in New York City, right?
Speaker 1: Obviously, if you take all the food of New York City, the Apple Festival can't compete.
Speaker 1: But there is in New York City, the street fair.
Speaker 1: There is a street fair that basically is always in existence.
Speaker 1: It just moves constantly.
Speaker 1: And it has mostly the robot carnival.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it has mostly the same vendors, but not always.
Speaker 1: But it mostly they basically every different weekend day holiday, you could just there's a website that tells you exactly where it's going to be.
Speaker 1: But even if you don't check that website, if you just bike around New York City, you're likely to run into it.
Speaker 1: If it's not a weekday.
Speaker 0: Every now and then it's near my office and I walk outside and I bump into it and guess where I eat lunch?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's in my neighborhood frequently.
Speaker 1: But the food, it has, you know, carny festival food.
Speaker 1: The Warwick Apple Festival food is better than the New York every weekend street fair food.
Speaker 0: Absolutely better.
Speaker 1: By a lot.
Speaker 0: In fact, my only regret is that I did not eat more of the food, but I am 41 years old and my stomach can only hold so much food.
Speaker 1: The problem is it's like I really, really want to try all the different foods at the at the festival.
Speaker 1: But unlike, say, the the night market in the night market, it's like everyone's making small dishes for like five bucks each.
Speaker 1: You can get a lot of them and you can share them if you go to the Apple Festival and you don't have a lot of people with you.
Speaker 1: It's like you get one thing from one cart and it's like more.
Speaker 1: it's like ten bucks or more and they give you a pile of food.
Speaker 0: And it's like, I guess the amount of Polish food they handed me when I ordered one plate of Polish food that is intended for one person was that was three people of food.
Speaker 1: That was two and a half at least.
Speaker 0: That was that was a terrifying amount of food.
Speaker 1: It's like, don't you want me to like, you know, give more money?
Speaker 1: It's like you should be giving out less food.
Speaker 0: If you had given me a third of the food on that plate, it's still for the same price, for the same price.
Speaker 0: And I would not have complained.
Speaker 1: And you would have gone to some other booth and also patronize them as well.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so, yeah, lots of delicious foods.
Speaker 1: You can get doughnuts, you can get pies, you can get apple poison, you can get cookies, you can get Polish food and your barbecue and fucking everything.
Speaker 0: There's also a lot of quaint small town charm vending, but it seems to be almost exclusively.
Speaker 0: I'm going to say I don't mean this uncharitably low tier arts and crafts.
Speaker 1: Yes, that's what it is.
Speaker 0: Or candles.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Well, anytime you go to any craft fair, including the Every Weekend New York Street Fair, any kind of fair, the things you will always see a lot of are people who make candles, soap, jewelry.
Speaker 1: Those are the big pottery.
Speaker 1: Those are the big four.
Speaker 0: Now the pottery was some of the better pottery I've seen at a festival like this.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: The quality of those varies wildly.
Speaker 1: But like those are the four things you're going to see the most frequently.
Speaker 1: There's like the most, you know, small time, you know, independent little crafty people.
Speaker 0: How many candles can people burn?
Speaker 0: If I have a bar of soap, it lasts like two or three months.
Speaker 1: People like, you know, I think.
Speaker 1: the other thing is you got to think people have like big houses, right?
Speaker 1: Not like us.
Speaker 0: I only have a closet full of soap.
Speaker 1: Well, if they got a lot of bathrooms, right?
Speaker 1: You ever go into like some suburban house?
Speaker 0: Oh, and they got the bad, the unused bathroom.
Speaker 1: There's like some bathroom that like is not used too often.
Speaker 1: And you go in there because you're a guest and it's a convenient spot and you go in there and they always have a weird soap in there.
Speaker 1: It's like, should I use this soap or is it a decorative soap?
Speaker 0: My aunt literally like got mad at us when I was a kid once because we use the like the bathroom that nobody uses.
Speaker 0: that had the fancy towels and the fancy soap in it.
Speaker 0: And we use the soap that was supposed to be decorative.
Speaker 0: That was a long time ago, but the candles too, like it takes a long time to burn a candle down and nothing.
Speaker 0: And yet candles seem to be the hottest commodity at this festival.
Speaker 1: Well, I think people love to make candles.
Speaker 1: And also, you know, you can make a candle even if you are just making candles, you can come up with like a smell that isn't exactly like anyone else's candle.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Because there's so much variety you can do.
Speaker 1: So even if you're small time in the candle game, you can get, you know, you might be able to make a sale if someone comes along and they're like, wow, I never seen, you know, that particular smell.
Speaker 0: Plus, it's way easy to make soy candles in the year 2023, like without a lot of skills and equipment compared to more traditional kinds of candles.
Speaker 0: And what I did not see were any traditional candles.
Speaker 0: It was only like modern, quick to make soy candles.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And the other thing is that there are people out there who literally are burning at least one candle just fucking all the time.
Speaker 0: That is true.
Speaker 0: That is not me.
Speaker 0: But I know you're out there.
Speaker 1: There are candle people out there who just have a candle going always.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: I like a candle occasionally, but also if a candle's burning, I got to turn off all the air filters because all the air filters are like, what the fuck?
Speaker 0: Everyone's going to die.
Speaker 0: Nine, nine, nine.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, maybe burning a candle all the time isn't that good for you.
Speaker 0: Who knows?
Speaker 0: Probably not.
Speaker 1: Anyway, but yeah, you know, it's one of those things where it's like.
Speaker 1: I look at all these crafts and some of them are meh and some of them it's like, ooh, look at that.
Speaker 1: But I end up not buying basically anything.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: You know what, though, is I actually?
Speaker 0: it's about the same thing that I do in artist alleys and conventions.
Speaker 0: The odds of me buying something at an artist alley in a convention are effectively zero.
Speaker 0: Like you're going to see me buy a lottery ticket more often than I buy anything at an artist alley.
Speaker 0: But I really like to look around an artist alley.
Speaker 0: I'll spend all day looking at every single booth to see what their deal is.
Speaker 0: And that's the same thing.
Speaker 0: I like a good time to walk around.
Speaker 0: I'm not too jaded as a fancy pants rich New York podcast dude to head upstate and go to a quaint town festival and mooch around for a few hours.
Speaker 1: So there's two other things about the festival.
Speaker 1: One of them is that since it sort of sprawls over the whole town and not just this main area, there's one like road that is basically they remove the cars from the road because it connects like the main festival area from the town park, which has like a pond.
Speaker 1: And so they are a road that connects them.
Speaker 1: They basically block that road so that people can walk between the two locations.
Speaker 1: And everyone who lives along that road is setting up booths and shit.
Speaker 1: Even people who just live there are putting like that's the day they come out with their tag sale trying to sell their shit.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like everyone is getting in on, you know, the church is on that road or like getting in on it, setting up booths.
Speaker 1: It's like they're all like, whoo, people are foot traffic is going to be here today.
Speaker 1: Therefore, this residential road is now a commercial road.
Speaker 1: Let's go.
Speaker 0: The thing is, imagine how cool that town would be if that road just didn't have cars on it.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm just saying, but it's like, I'm just, it's really cool to like, sort of like.
Speaker 1: imagine if everyone in the street you live on one day, just.
Speaker 1: everyone goes up and sets a booth up outside their house and you have like a, you know, not just a block party.
Speaker 0: So that actually used to happen when I was a kid, you know, I lived in Detroit.
Speaker 0: So we had a neighborhood tag sale day where everyone did their garage sales on the same day.
Speaker 0: So it became like, but we also had a couple, every year we had one or two, uh, basically like block parties where every house put a booth with something going on in front of their house.
Speaker 0: Like some houses did an arts and crafts thing.
Speaker 0: Some houses would do like a haunted house thing.
Speaker 0: Some houses would just have food that was free.
Speaker 0: Some houses would do a garage sale.
Speaker 0: Some people would sell stuff, but every house like did a thing on this day for this like local block party festival.
Speaker 1: And the last thing I want to say, which will probably make someone mad at me, but whatever.
Speaker 1: It's just the truth that I can't deny.
Speaker 0: I can't wait to hear what you have to say.
Speaker 0: Cause I actually don't know.
Speaker 1: So the Apple festival has many live musical performances, which is great.
Speaker 1: That's terrific.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: They were like, there's way more than you think.
Speaker 1: Like the park has one.
Speaker 1: Then the church has gone as like, it's like a random fiddling guy on the main street.
Speaker 1: And then there's a, I think a Z-Boat is another performance.
Speaker 0: The fiddling guy was better than the average fiddler I hear in New York.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: It could actually fiddle.
Speaker 1: People were jigging, doing a jig.
Speaker 0: I jigged a little walking past him.
Speaker 0: I could not help.
Speaker 0: It was, it was too powerful.
Speaker 0: The jig.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: They had a person on a horse and a headless horseman costume you could photo with.
Speaker 0: An S-tier beautiful horse too.
Speaker 0: Like this was a particularly good looking horse.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: There was a rock band that was in the park by the pond.
Speaker 1: That was pretty good actually.
Speaker 1: Um, you know, I didn't listen to every performance and hang around all day, but one, the one, when we got, we first arrived and we got off the school bus after the parking lot.
Speaker 1: There were clearly people who were either community theater or high school theater drama club people singing show tunes.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: Now they were quite good singers, right?
Speaker 1: They could sing about 10,000 times better than I can.
Speaker 0: About 20,000 times better than I can.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, they were, and they, they were singing the show tunes properly.
Speaker 1: They had talents and skills and their performance was enjoyable.
Speaker 1: And, uh, I was not upset that they were there.
Speaker 1: We, we, we ate the Polish food in, in their vicinity to hear them.
Speaker 1: Uh, it was very nice.
Speaker 0: However, we live in New York, however, I live in New York.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And I realized it made me realize it was like riding the small roller coaster after riding only the big roller coaster.
Speaker 1: I, I had become spoiled and taken for granted that like the only shows I've been to in recent years are.
Speaker 1: Metropolitan opera, actual Broadway theater, right?
Speaker 1: Radio city music, right?
Speaker 1: It's like touring bands that are huge jazz band.
Speaker 0: We see it at Lincoln center.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, I've been spoiled living in New York city, basically only feasting on the foie gras of music.
Speaker 0: When I ever talk about Cedar point, cause once you've been there, like no other roller coaster is even like it's there.
Speaker 0: They're fine roller coasters, but they're beneath the scale of notice to someone who has even been to Cedar point.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But it's like, I had forgotten.
Speaker 1: The difference.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And so it, it, it provided this stark reminder that like, yeah, you know, you went to the opera and it sounded like someone was playing a CD, but even better somehow.
Speaker 1: And it's like, you know, whereas this had a little bit of that karaoke sound in it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: That wasn't so great.
Speaker 1: And it's like, you know, it didn't ruin it, but it's just like, you could tell the difference right between the S tier that you had and the maybe a or B plus tier that you're having now.
Speaker 1: And it reminded me, Oh, right.
Speaker 1: I am very privileged to live in New York city and enjoy the finest that the world has to offer.
Speaker 1: You know, there, there is a difference.
Speaker 1: It's not the same.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And I can, we can enjoy that finest writing a few stops on a subway two hours north, but it was valuable because in fact I'm going to the opera a week from Saturday.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And so I will not take for granted.
Speaker 1: Uh, you know, the difference between rubbing, I guess, honey on my ears and just raw sugar.
Speaker 0: But, uh, yeah, I'd say the Warwick Apple Fest is a perfectly fine, fun town festival.
Speaker 0: I'd like, I, I like town festivals.
Speaker 0: I like that kind of thing.
Speaker 0: I like that five.
Speaker 0: I like seeing a community of people like putting on a thing and being proud of it.
Speaker 0: Like I just, I enjoy everything about that.
Speaker 0: My only worry is that it's going to only get more crowded because Warwick can't get bigger yet.
Speaker 0: New York city's influence grows evermore.
Speaker 1: I mean they could block off more of their roads and expand, right?
Speaker 1: The festival that way.
Speaker 1: Um, so yeah.
Speaker 1: Would I go back to the Warwick Apple Festival?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Would I go every year and like make a point of it?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's kind of a hassle to get out there.
Speaker 0: I want to try to like bring all our people and like, yeah,
Speaker 1: I think what I'm going to do next year is I'm going to go back to the, the Fishkill Orchard, um, you know, which where you make the, where you make an appointment because they have the, the top tier donut.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I could use an, I like the donuts we got, but I could use an S tier donut.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of Geek Nights are... Ellen Joyce, Link Ege, Dredeling the Tenebrae, Case Care Makes Music, Chris Hadad, Christopher Orr, Clinton Walton, M. Defnek, Finn, Joel Hayes, Panty Rhymer, Rebecca Dunn, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Harl, and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure what the stinger is going to be.
Speaker 0: I'm going to go eat some dinner first, and then I'm going to pick something weird, and I'm going to stick it right after the point where I stop talking.