Speaker 0: It's Monday, July 31st, 2023 on RIM.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights Tonight, where we're talking about when, how, why, and if to upgrade your tech.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So Emily is off in Michigan with family for about a week, week and a half, maybe two weeks in determinate length.
Speaker 0: As much as I wanted to go, I have too much actual work to do and I don't know if vacation day is to just disappear for two more weeks, considering I've disappeared for several weeks along the way.
Speaker 0: And unlike certain individuals, I don't get every Monday off.
Speaker 0: That's a shame.
Speaker 0: That's a damn shame.
Speaker 0: But the thing I did last night is there's a confluence of all these factors.
Speaker 0: And some of what I'm about to talk about briefly in our opening bit is not for the benefit of Scott.
Speaker 0: It's for the benefit of the listener who might not understand how different parks are in a place like New York City compared to pretty much any other place in America, but especially non-cities in America.
Speaker 0: So when I was a kid in Michigan, there was one really good thing about living in Michigan.
Speaker 0: And that was the fact that that time zone is the same time zone as New York City.
Speaker 0: And what does that mean?
Speaker 0: It stays light for almost an hour longer at night because you're on the other end of the same time zone.
Speaker 0: So when it's dark here, there is still sunlight where I grew up.
Speaker 1: So, you know, I'm always, you know, if you're in a time zone, it's best to be on like the westish side of it no matter what.
Speaker 0: Because I remember as a kid, like it doesn't get dark until like nine forty five at night in like the peak of summer.
Speaker 0: And that was just something that I really missed when I moved to New York.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's because we didn't do like gradual time.
Speaker 1: It's for good reasons.
Speaker 0: Gradual time does not work as America discovered.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It would be logistically impossible to be.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm on the east side of Queens and you're on the west side.
Speaker 1: So I'm a minute earlier than you as a technically you are.
Speaker 0: That turns into I'm heading upstate to one hundred and twenty fifth street.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll be there.
Speaker 1: It's like, yeah, exactly.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, so because of that, it's like time zones have to have a width of about an hour of sunlight.
Speaker 1: And so you can get an extra hour of sunlight on the west side or an hour earlier sunlight on the east side.
Speaker 0: So I was reminded of this because, you know, Emily is off.
Speaker 0: I had finished a day of travel and I'm.
Speaker 0: I'm in the park because I'm out night biking, which is my real opening bit.
Speaker 0: I'm just biking around at night in New York because it's real fun to do that.
Speaker 0: And Emily calls me and we're chatting.
Speaker 0: And yeah, she reminds me that the sun is still visible where she is.
Speaker 0: And it is dark out where I am.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, fuck.
Speaker 1: And it's the same.
Speaker 1: But it's the same time.
Speaker 0: Exact same time.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So which reminded me of something else.
Speaker 0: When I was a kid, I was something I was very angry about, like kid.
Speaker 0: angry about, like in middle school and high school, that all the parks and every suburb and subdivision and even Detroit that I ever lived in closed at night.
Speaker 0: Like cops would check to see if kids were hanging out in the park and they would fucking come after you if they saw you.
Speaker 0: Like you could not openly hang out in a park at night.
Speaker 1: Or at least they'd ask you to leave.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So for a brief time, Sterling Heights had a curfew.
Speaker 0: They would write kids tickets and like take them in the cruiser.
Speaker 0: And it was a whole thing.
Speaker 0: Statute of limitations ran out.
Speaker 0: I might have run from such police on numerous occasions because I figured a teenager on a bicycle, what are the odds?
Speaker 0: the cops are going to shoot me or run me over as opposed to giving up?
Speaker 0: Now, in retrospect, not the best bet to take against American cops, but here I am.
Speaker 0: But I just remember being really mad about the fact that these are public spaces, but yet they are denied to people who are busy during the day or up at night.
Speaker 0: Like if you're, imagine you're lonely or you can't sleep.
Speaker 1: I mean, Central Park is closed at like, what, 1 a.m.
Speaker 1: I think.
Speaker 0: Something like that.
Speaker 0: There are parks in New York that close at night.
Speaker 1: Like you're technically not supposed to go in there after a certain time.
Speaker 0: But then there's parks like Queensbridge Park or Rainy Park where there is a party going on there until like 3 a.m.
Speaker 0: most weekend nights.
Speaker 1: Technically, Queensbridge Park closes, I guess, at 9 a.m.
Speaker 1: according to the park's website.
Speaker 0: But according to the signs at the park, it doesn't seem to close because the lights are on all night in that park.
Speaker 1: It effectively doesn't close even if there is some technical closing time.
Speaker 0: Because regardless of the law and the procedures and the nonsense, the reality is you go to Queensbridge Park or Rainy Park late at night, especially on like a Thursday, Friday, Saturday in the summer.
Speaker 0: And there are, if you're not from New York City, way more people hanging out in that park than you would ever expect.
Speaker 1: There are more people in the park than the population of some of the small towns in those parks.
Speaker 0: So in biking around last night, just, you know, in the evening on a New York summer night, I encountered several small scenes I want to briefly share and then we can move on.
Speaker 0: Because it was just a birthday party.
Speaker 0: So there was a family having like a gigantic barbecue.
Speaker 0: But they had all paused because one of the kids had their cell phone held up and it was sending audio to a Bluetooth speaker.
Speaker 0: And this was all in Spanish, but it was obvious.
Speaker 0: this was a prank call show, like a classic crank call show.
Speaker 0: And the entire family was like listening to this as an event while they're cooking.
Speaker 0: It was great.
Speaker 0: You can hear the moment where the dial tone happens because the other guy hung up.
Speaker 0: And like, it sounded like a comedy club, the amount of laughter coming out of this family.
Speaker 0: There were two baseball teams having a hella fucking party, I assume their championship.
Speaker 1: Are you sure it wasn't softball?
Speaker 0: It might have been softball.
Speaker 0: I didn't inspect too closely.
Speaker 1: I know Queensbridge has a lot of softball going on.
Speaker 0: I could definitely tell which team had won the game and which team had lost the game based on the way the two parties were evolving, which was really funny.
Speaker 0: A whole bunch of fireworks were going off from Roosevelt Island, like shit tons of fireworks.
Speaker 0: But then I hit in Rainy Park, I'm biking around up there, and I see a whole bunch of purple lights move around like crazy as I'm coming up toward the park.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, "What's going on over
Speaker 0: there?".
Speaker 0: Some sort of like kid rave at night.
Speaker 0: It was, and this is normally, you know, I might exaggerate.
Speaker 0: So older might say, or exaggerating might say, "There were 30 bikes
Speaker 0: there.".
Speaker 0: So I'm going to give the exact number.
Speaker 0: There were more than 10, as far as I could count, like directly no exaggeration, white e-bikes with punk kids on them, doing tricks and hurting themselves, going crazy with these e-bikes on that big playground structure with the rock climbing thing on the left side of the park.
Speaker 0: Like, it was a situation where on one hand, a parent should probably have shown up to stop this, but on the other hand, props to you kids, I do the same fucking thing when I was your age.
Speaker 1: The structure is basically like a manufactured hill.
Speaker 1: It's on a real hill, but then there's like a manufactured hill on the real hill.
Speaker 0: This would be dangerous on a BMX bike.
Speaker 1: The slide is built into the hill rather than a slide sort of freestanding.
Speaker 0: This would be dangerous on a BMX bike, even for someone like me.
Speaker 0: This is beyond dangerous.
Speaker 1: As a slide though, it's a little safer than a regular slide because you can't like fall off the edge to your doom because it's just sort of built into a hill.
Speaker 1: So if you fall out of it, you're just sort of on the side of the hill.
Speaker 0: Not like that slide at the park.
Speaker 0: I remember as a kid being like terrifyingly tall and then as an adult visiting Michigan, I went to that park thinking there was no way that slide was as tall as I remember.
Speaker 0: That slide was so fucking tall.
Speaker 0: I still cannot believe it.
Speaker 0: It's allowed to stand and kids are allowed to play on it.
Speaker 0: It wasn't the giant slide, which I have also written.
Speaker 1: It was just the big slide, not the giant slide.
Speaker 0: It was the big slide, the giant slide I have written.
Speaker 1: The ginormous slide.
Speaker 1: You go down it, your friend's neck breaks.
Speaker 0: The kid you ain't even had's neck breaks.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: One of your ancestors' necks break.
Speaker 0: So, uh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, that's a long way of saying.
Speaker 0: if you're ever in New York City and you're capable of it, I highly recommend just renting a city bike and just biking around on bike paths at night, especially in the summer.
Speaker 0: It is a fun, pretty safe, wild time, and you're not going to experience this.
Speaker 1: It's just the same stuff you see during the day only at night.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but a little more shenanigans.
Speaker 0: Like, the kids on the e-bikes would not have been able to get away with that during the day.
Speaker 0: They would have gotten away with it for maybe an hour, but eventually a cop would have rolled up and gently scootled them.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 0: So, you got any news?
Speaker 0: Because there's one big news that is permeating every tech conversation.
Speaker 0: if you're an internet person.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the news we're going to talk about.
Speaker 1: We might have to do a whole show on it.
Speaker 0: We're definitely going to have to do a whole show on it.
Speaker 0: This will not be comprehensive.
Speaker 1: We're going to have to blow the whole load, right?
Speaker 1: But basically, Google, the Chrome people, they might add this feature.
Speaker 1: And the name that they have for the feature, what do they call it?
Speaker 1: Web Integrity something something?
Speaker 1: The problem is Web Environment Integrity is what Chrome is calling it, right?
Speaker 1: And what this is, it's a form of attestation.
Speaker 1: So to make a good, you know, a classic analogy here, right?
Speaker 1: You go to the club and you want to get in the club, but there's a bouncer at the club and the bouncer doesn't know who the hell you are, right?
Speaker 1: And now, but if there's someone standing there, maybe the owner of the club, maybe an alcohol vendor or a famous person or the act that's performing at the club or someone the bouncer knows, they can attest for you and say, no, no, no, this guy's legit.
Speaker 1: Let him in.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And if there's no one there to attest for you, the bouncer is like, who the hell are you getting in?
Speaker 1: End of story.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So the way this feature would work in Chrome is that you would visit a website and the website would say, hmm, who is this person coming to visit my website?
Speaker 1: And they would say, who is the trusted person?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Because obviously not a human isn't doing this.
Speaker 1: So the website says, who can I trust to see if this person is legit?
Speaker 1: Well, fucking Google.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So they go to Google and they're like, hey, Google.
Speaker 1: Is this Web visitor with this browser?
Speaker 1: Are they legit?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Should I let them visit my website?
Speaker 1: And then Google will say yes or no.
Speaker 1: And the way this is done is with some cryptographic biz.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, Google contacts your computer and basically says, are they using Chrome?
Speaker 1: Is the Chrome a legit Chrome?
Speaker 1: Has it been modified?
Speaker 1: Hacked?
Speaker 1: Is this a bot?
Speaker 1: Is this right?
Speaker 1: And then the website would let you or would either send you HTML or if it doesn't like you, send you just an empty 401 response.
Speaker 1: It's like unauthorized.
Speaker 1: Get the hell out of here.
Speaker 0: Now, before we go any further, I think I should point out that this concept, while it may have broad use cases and there's value in certain specific kinds of things, it is pretty directly antithetical to what the World Wide Web was intended to be.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, it's you have a Web server, you send it bits and then at its discretion, it sends you bits or it sends you different ones.
Speaker 1: It's their choice.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, it's.
Speaker 1: you know, it's obviously in spirit.
Speaker 1: You're right.
Speaker 0: But technically it's like because on the other hand, it is not fundamentally necessarily different than a Web site that requires a subscription or a password or some sort of exact access token.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So the good parts, this this technology does have good parts.
Speaker 1: So Safari has already implemented this.
Speaker 1: They call it.
Speaker 1: what do they call it?
Speaker 1: Public something, something private.
Speaker 1: They call it private private access tokens.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And what's the?
Speaker 1: if you look at the Apple documentation for the feature in Safari, the way it works is you?
Speaker 1: the way that they they suggest developers use it?
Speaker 1: is that, you know, you go to a Web site.
Speaker 1: The Web site goes to Apple and says, hey, is this Safari browser legit?
Speaker 1: And if Apple says yes, that's a real Apple user with like, you know, who's using real Safari, then that means not that that Web site should just let you in, period, but that they could be like, oh, I know you're so legit because of the attestation.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to show you any captures.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And that's what Apple suggests.
Speaker 1: They're like, hey, reduce captures for our users.
Speaker 1: use if you're going to capture someone.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Instead of doing that, do this first.
Speaker 1: And if you don't like it, if that gives you a bad result, then show a capture.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And theoretically, if people implement the feature, users would get less captures, which is good for usability, for people who can't even solve a captured people with disabilities.
Speaker 1: It's, you know, makes the Internet just better overall.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like that's a very good thing.
Speaker 1: If Apple vouching for you means captures are gone or Google vouching for you means captures are gone.
Speaker 1: There are other legitimate uses as well.
Speaker 1: But obviously the illegitimate use would be I have come to this Web site and Google says, ah, this person is using Chrome, but they got ad block.
Speaker 1: So don't let them visit your Web site because you won't make any money.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And then they block you because you have ad block.
Speaker 1: Now, that's sort of you know, it's sort of like this slippery slope doomsday scenario.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And it's like on the one hand, it's like, yeah, that's way bad.
Speaker 1: But is anyone actually going to implement it that way?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Is the slope going to slip to the bottom?
Speaker 0: And that's a really important question, because historically these things have not gone down that road because nerds just won't use services that go down.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like it's like, sure, Google might put this feature in their browser.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And so might everyone.
Speaker 1: All the major browser vendors might all implement this.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But will major Web sites, you know, important Web sites actually go through with, you know, implementing the harshest, you know, situation of block anyone who is using any modified browser of any kind.
Speaker 0: I do think there's one class of Web site that likely will.
Speaker 0: But I think that class of Web site is the kind of Web site that today aggressively attempts to block people are using ad blockers already.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And it's like if you're if you're blocked from going to those Web sites, I don't see much loss there.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Why go to the unified Web site that's telling you it's unified.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: Now, a big major Web site.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Like maybe like a news, a big major news Web site.
Speaker 1: If they start blocking all the people who have ad blocks, it's like they're already not blocking people who are bypassing their paywalls with special tools.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, but even if they did, I don't think they will.
Speaker 1: Because, number one, there's going to be a lot of false positives.
Speaker 1: Anyone using any older technology, any weird is suddenly going to be able to go to like New York Times, CNN.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, their numbers that they see in their metrics of like how many people visit their Web sites would drop precipitously because right now they're benefiting.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Marketing people love fake numbers.
Speaker 1: That are falsely inflated.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: I mean, I could legitimately give a extremely wide range of the number of listeners to geek nights based on all perfectly plausible mathematical models.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Think about other.
Speaker 1: you know, it's like they love to tell people that, you know, a huge number like this.
Speaker 1: How many people visited our Web site this month?
Speaker 1: That's why you should buy ads.
Speaker 1: You'll get so many eyeballs if they actually had to give a real number because they actually blocked all the bots and all the other.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: If they had to give an honest number, it's like they might like to know that number.
Speaker 1: They might implement the technology just to count to see the truth.
Speaker 1: How many actual humans with unmodified browsers are uniquely visiting us, you know, on a whatever time period basis.
Speaker 1: But to actually block everyone else, that means they would have to go tell advertisers.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Only like one million people actually only for real, only like one million.
Speaker 1: And they'd be like, that's way smaller than number.
Speaker 1: You've been telling us for years.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Why would we buy ads from you to only get that many eyeballs if that's the true number?
Speaker 1: They don't want the true number to be out there.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So I don't know if anyone will actually do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because that's that's an arms race.
Speaker 0: Once that true number is revealed, then that is probably equally harmful to the advertising ecosystem as ad blocks are.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: There's also the situation of like.
Speaker 1: you could use this technology in reverse.
Speaker 1: You could block anyone who doesn't have ad blocks.
Speaker 1: You could be like, oh, you've got an unmodified Chrome.
Speaker 1: Guess what?
Speaker 1: You can't visit my website.
Speaker 1: You better have some kind of modification.
Speaker 1: So I know you're a nerd.
Speaker 1: Nerds only.
Speaker 0: That's why I would say I'd love to be able to go down the opposite route directly, like all the people who blocked every checkmark on Twitter back when Twitter is still usable slightly block anyone who doesn't have ad block from your website.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: There could be other security things going on to write like a bank website.
Speaker 1: Now, the banks haven't even implemented to F.A.
Speaker 1: properly.
Speaker 1: So are they really going to implement this right?
Speaker 1: But even if they did implement it, it's like, are they really going to block all their customers and deal with the customer support problems that they're going to have as a result?
Speaker 1: I don't think they're actually going to do that now.
Speaker 1: And even if they went that far, there's a good way they could do it.
Speaker 1: They could say, look, your browser's out of date.
Speaker 1: We're only allowing people with up to date browsers to visit the bank website.
Speaker 1: And just if you if you're not up to date, they'll give you a message, update your shit.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: That could be positive, actually.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: They could give you the message to update your shit and still let you in to at your own risk.
Speaker 0: My theory is what the direction.
Speaker 0: This is almost a sideshow.
Speaker 0: I worry because the direction every company I think is actually going to go is trying to not have websites and force everyone into apps.
Speaker 0: Like that's been the dream of capitalism forever.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But it's like, you know, if it's app only, it's like, all right, you know what you do.
Speaker 0: I mean, I generally avoid app only things because, you know, reasons mostly.
Speaker 1: I mean, if there is a thing that is app only, I will avoid that thing generally.
Speaker 1: Like there's a lot of, you know, we've seen a lot of social networks crop up that are like app only websites.
Speaker 1: But for example, my bank, it's like I can use.
Speaker 1: I can use the website or the app and it's like I use both depending on when I'm doing.
Speaker 0: But they're different use cases.
Speaker 0: I use the app for like very specific things when I have my phone.
Speaker 0: But if I'm doing like banking, like anything complex at all, of course, I have a website open because I'm probably moving money around between a bunch of accounts or doing something complex.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, it'll take a long you know, the Web would have to like really collapse for big companies to actually, you know, turn that shit out.
Speaker 1: I think that what's in my eye estimation, what's actually going to happen if this goes through and actually becomes a thing is the websites that will block you are websites you didn't want to go to anyway.
Speaker 1: And you'll be happy that they block you.
Speaker 0: You know, I'm going to make a ticket.
Speaker 0: master is going to implement it.
Speaker 1: Maybe, maybe.
Speaker 1: But the other places right there, there will be workarounds, right?
Speaker 1: You'll be able to set up like.
Speaker 1: you'll either just have like a chrome on the side that's unmodified that you can use in those special cases.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And then you'll have your other browser used for everything.
Speaker 0: Real browser.
Speaker 1: You'll have like a proxy.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You'll have some sort of proxy browser.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Or it's like and I don't think this piehole kind of ad blocking will be stopped by this.
Speaker 1: It's like you verified that my iPhone has been unmodified and has the legit safari on it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And I haven't modified it in any way.
Speaker 1: I'm attested by Apple.
Speaker 1: Show me the website.
Speaker 1: And then they send me the HTML and then all the DNS requests to all the advertisement sites are returned up with no result because I have a piehole in my house.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like that's not going to stop that.
Speaker 1: So there's plenty of workarounds for this.
Speaker 1: It's not like the end of the world, but people are acting like it's the end of the world because they're looking at the.
Speaker 1: you know, I'm not saying like it's good.
Speaker 1: Like I would be.
Speaker 1: I think I would be happier if they just.
Speaker 0: I think part of what's happening is that the kinds of people who even know like the FSF exists and like no are capable of understanding the possible dangers of things like this.
Speaker 0: are the kinds of people who have had to raise alarm bells for lots of dangerous tech for so long.
Speaker 0: that kind of like with climate change, unless you describe an apocalyptic scenario, nobody gives a shit.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So it would be much better if the people, you know, crying that the sky is falling one were on their side.
Speaker 1: Even though there are some positive uses, like I said, getting rid of captions that I would enjoy and would be good overall.
Speaker 1: But the apocalyptic scenarios that they're describing, I don't think are unlikely.
Speaker 1: I think it will be a. you know, it will be a a slope, but they will.
Speaker 1: The reality is that if it goes through, we will not go to the bottom of the slope.
Speaker 1: We will go somewhere down the slope, but not to the bottom.
Speaker 1: And it'll be sort of some good things will happen in some things will happen.
Speaker 1: And, you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: One thing I did see, not that I am advocating the Brave browser, because I do not personally trust any niche.
Speaker 1: I don't trust that shit.
Speaker 0: But they did announce they will never support web environment integrity APIs.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's really not going to be decided by the browsers.
Speaker 1: It's going to be decided by the websites.
Speaker 1: Will the web, you know, each and every different website can choose for itself.
Speaker 1: Are you going to allow people to visit or are you going to keep things the way they are?
Speaker 1: Are you going to check attestation, you know, to, you know, are you going to like a bouncer could just look at you and let you in?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Are you going to tell your bouncer to check everyone to see if they're legit?
Speaker 1: And maybe let them in and meet.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like it's up to you.
Speaker 1: So it's like what the majority of websites do.
Speaker 1: And if and how they implement this, that will determine what's going on.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But if the major browsers.
Speaker 1: If they safaris already has it, but if Google doesn't do it, if they will.
Speaker 1: They win their battle and Google doesn't implement it in Chrome, that takes the decision out of the website's hands because now they can't do it.
Speaker 1: They'd be right.
Speaker 1: blocking every Chrome browser in the universe.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: So which is probably short term is a better option just to avoid even having to address.
Speaker 1: But if Chrome does add the feature and deploys it in a stable release to every Chrome browser out there, then it will be in the hands of the websites individually and then and also collectively.
Speaker 0: I would bet money fucking Ticketmaster ad implements it as fast as possible.
Speaker 1: If we get to that point, maybe that's the kind of website that might want to attest.
Speaker 0: visitor, you know, some of that anyway.
Speaker 0: So not to blow our load, but we'll probably talk about this as a whole show at some point, because there's a lot of details to unpack.
Speaker 1: I think well, I think, you know, rather than do it right away, let's wait until we see how it pans.
Speaker 1: Oh, absolutely.
Speaker 1: This is not like the next time there's a big shift in the news.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Of like a decision point.
Speaker 1: that actually happened, like it's deployed in Chrome everywhere.
Speaker 1: Then we can do a whole episode.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's a good line.
Speaker 0: So in some other news, I think we both talked about how this would be the absolutely best idea for any news organization to do as Twitter has.
Speaker 0: Well, the app formerly known as Twitter has collapsed into ruin and the BBC did it like earlier today, less than 12 hours ago.
Speaker 0: The BBC just went live with social BBC, which is the BBC's own single official Mastodon instance, and the only accounts on it are official BBC content.
Speaker 1: What if a BBC person who is on there loses their job?
Speaker 1: Are they just managing it the same way you manage, like email accounts at the BBC?
Speaker 0: I think they're managing it just like that right now.
Speaker 0: It looks like it is only official official accounts.
Speaker 0: They've started just with studio.
Speaker 1: I see.
Speaker 1: So they don't have an individual account for each reporter and journalist.
Speaker 0: Now, if they do down the road, I am confident they'll do it the way a lot of organizations do.
Speaker 0: You know, like I work at a big organization.
Speaker 0: If you have a public account to use for social media, that account is owned by the company, not by you, because you're obviously creating content.
Speaker 1: I think there could be an interesting tech setup, though, where like you have a BBC, like you're a journalist to the BBC.
Speaker 1: You have a you have an account on this instance.
Speaker 1: You start, I guess, tweet messaging where you start posting messages.
Speaker 0: I refuse to say to.
Speaker 1: Yeah, posting messages from the field.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And then rather than them going public immediately, there's some editor whose only job is to like look at a feed of all the journalists sending all the messages until I click.
Speaker 1: Yes, yes, no, yes, no, yes, no.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Like fact checking and spell checking and, you know, like every all the messages getting checked at some central place by like it would only take a handful of people.
Speaker 1: How many messages are there really going to be?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: So the other cool thing about this, they're very open about how this is an experiment and they're the research and development team is running it publicly to try this out.
Speaker 1: And I think the problem that what I worry, I think they're going to do a great job.
Speaker 1: I think the problem is they might not get enough traffic right now.
Speaker 1: It's like it's one of those things where like they dip the toe in the water and like, oh, too cold.
Speaker 1: Never mind.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, no, no, no.
Speaker 1: It doesn't work.
Speaker 1: You have to go all the way in the water and stay in there and acclimate.
Speaker 0: Kind of like all.
Speaker 0: Then you can decide the news orgs like the BBC that in the early days of Twitter doubled down on Twitter back when nobody used Twitter.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: it's like you have to make a real effort, stick with it for a long time, you know, and then once, you know, other people follow and then that will make it.
Speaker 1: You have to make it work.
Speaker 1: You can't just see if it works like it's someone else doing the making it work part.
Speaker 1: It's like, no, you're part of the making it work by going all in.
Speaker 1: And that's the only way it can happen.
Speaker 1: So now the cool part would be the next because their numbers are going to be low for a long time.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: But the next step would be one, if these other apps and meta start implementing activity feed, then that's going to start driving this ecosystem.
Speaker 0: And two, if activity pub pub that provides a feed of activity.
Speaker 0: But two, if another, like the second, the first follower, the next news org makes theirs and they cross federate and they start retweeting each other or like having the journalism conversations between each other that used to happen on Twitter.
Speaker 0: Because the beauty of that, if the BBC and unnamed news organization to do it that way, their reporters can verify stories and discuss with each other publicly the same way they used to do on Twitter.
Speaker 0: But Joey Jojo crypto fascist can't butt in and won't show up on either of their feeds if he's coming from his bullshit Nazi Mastodon server.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: They can implement Mastodon however they want.
Speaker 0: So I've been whispering in the ear of a few friends I have for a pretty senior at several news orgs, not BBC, but other ones.
Speaker 0: I have already emailed them being like, look, the BBC did what I suggested.
Speaker 0: You should seriously try this out.
Speaker 0: So let's see.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I want to see some, you know, associated press, some Reuters, you know, and some, uh, you know, even, even fucking news Corp.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, I could block your server, but it's like, you can make one.
Speaker 0: I want you to make one for me to block.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: That's a healthy internet.
Speaker 0: So one last news.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to dwell on it because we've gone on a little long, but, uh, it's a big deal.
Speaker 0: The first new nuclear reactor in the U S that was built from scratch in several decades has entered commercial operation.
Speaker 0: It is live.
Speaker 0: It is generating 25% of the total power output of Georgia power, the largest power company in like the Atlanta area.
Speaker 1: Let's fucking go.
Speaker 0: This is huge news.
Speaker 0: This is as best I can tell, uh, I didn't read all the details of the reactor, but it is a generation three reactor, a light water reactor, which is so basically all the reactions.
Speaker 1: It is a good kind.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Generally, basically generation one is like a pile.
Speaker 0: Like that's, that's just, that is no, no, uh, honorable or esteemed deeds are commemorated at a gen one reactor.
Speaker 0: Gen two is what almost every nuclear power plant on earth is, except in like France.
Speaker 0: And they're the ugly bad ones.
Speaker 0: Like Indian point generation three are the same basic technology as gen two, but built with modern ideas and modern designs and they are ludicrously safe.
Speaker 0: Now you're going to see some stories complaining about how this project was like $17 billion over budget and took a lot longer than we expected.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Uh, I'd say that doesn't only sound cheap.
Speaker 0: It is cheap because the biggest mistake anyone advocating for realistic policies around energy or the environment in America has, or even Europe has ever done is talking about the dollars.
Speaker 0: something costs because where it's not, we could spend those dollars somewhere else to do something different.
Speaker 0: And it's more, what are the externalities of this power versus other kinds of power?
Speaker 0: The dollars are just a fiction of how you expend capital to make it happen.
Speaker 1: So if you don't do it, if you, if you're going to generate that power, the people of Georgia, I either, what will be the damage of not generating the power of the people of Georgia?
Speaker 1: not having enough power, right?
Speaker 1: How much damage will that be that you just averted?
Speaker 0: How many more coal and oil power plants would I have to spin up to cover this load?
Speaker 1: Maybe if you use some other kind of power, right, uh, to generate that, those megawatts and you keep the people of Georgia powered, how much damage will be caused by that other kind of power you chose?
Speaker 1: Now, maybe you chose wind or something that's not coal, right?
Speaker 1: But it's like how much.
Speaker 1: then it's a question of, okay, neither, you've got more options that all don't really cause significant damage at least, right?
Speaker 1: Like coal does, uh, which one gets you the most power per dollar, right?
Speaker 1: And having 25% of an entire state's power with one facility sounds like efficient design to me.
Speaker 1: How many, how many wind, you know, it's not that I don't like wind, right?
Speaker 1: China just made like the wind's biggest world, right?
Speaker 1: It's the biggest wind turbine in the world.
Speaker 0: I mean, in New York, unless something blocks it, we're going to get that ridiculous array feeding through Raven's Woods.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll see.
Speaker 1: Not, you know, but not that I'm against wind, but like how many turbines would you know, and how much would they cost?
Speaker 1: Well, also there's more to the point.
Speaker 0: We need, humans need a variety, like a heterogeneous environment of how we generate power so we can innovate in all these different areas simultaneously.
Speaker 0: And so they can compliment each other because they're all good at different kinds of power.
Speaker 0: And if you're a nerd and you want to learn about how much more complicated than this, then you can imagine.
Speaker 0: Look up reactive power versus non-reactive power and why it's so hard to generate the amount and kind of electricity we need to power society.
Speaker 0: No one type of power generation technology will solve our problems for the foreseeable future of the Earth.
Speaker 0: So things of the day, an old standby in Geek Nights, I liked to find, you know, there's, we're really into anime music videos.
Speaker 0: I'm still into anime music videos, like AMVs and like that sort of stuff.
Speaker 0: I just, I enjoy them.
Speaker 0: I even made one.
Speaker 0: But I used to try to find whenever a different fandom has a similar culture.
Speaker 0: Like I found all those Horatio Hornblower fan videos.
Speaker 0: There were a lot of them.
Speaker 0: This one's pretty good.
Speaker 0: I just bumped into this.
Speaker 0: It is a music video just made by a fan to the movie Metropolis and the song Feed the Machine.
Speaker 1: Which Metropolis?
Speaker 1: The original Metropolis?
Speaker 0: Yeah, for playing Metropolis.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if this was just an AMV to what anime, who was all involved, I forget who directed that.
Speaker 1: Was that a Rintaro one, I think?
Speaker 1: Was it?
Speaker 0: Anyway, I'll look it up.
Speaker 0: We reviewed it.
Speaker 0: God, how long ago saw that thing?
Speaker 1: It was a Rintaro joint, yes.
Speaker 0: But this is a music video by a fan to Fritz Lang's Metropolis.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: It's real good because that movie, pretty prescient to everything that's happening in society right now.
Speaker 0: If you've never actually watched Metropolis, you should see it at least once.
Speaker 0: If you don't get the metaphor of what's going on in this music video, capitalism is just going to eat you, buddy.
Speaker 0: So what do you got?
Speaker 1: Well, so in July 2020, I think, 1973, Bruce Lee, you know who Bruce Lee is, right?
Speaker 1: That was when he died.
Speaker 1: It was 50 years ago, right?
Speaker 1: I wasn't even alive then.
Speaker 1: And at the time that Bruce Lee died, he was 32.
Speaker 1: And a basketball player, Kareem Abdul-Jabbar, was 25.
Speaker 1: And I don't know how many people know this, that Kareem Abdul-Jabbar and Bruce Lee, they were buddies, right?
Speaker 0: I learned this one second ago.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It is a famous scene in Game of Death where they fight each other, right?
Speaker 1: But Kareem was training with Bruce Lee at the time because he was like,
Speaker 1: "Hey.".
Speaker 1: Bruce Lee was getting famous.
Speaker 1: Kareem saw him and was like, "Hey, look at how that guy's moving his body.
Speaker 1: I'm a professional athlete.
Speaker 1: That is relevant to what I
Speaker 1: do."
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: "That can help me.
Speaker 1: If I go and learn from that guy, that will help my
Speaker 1: basketball.".
Speaker 1: And well, he was excellent at basketball, so maybe he wasn't entirely wrong about that.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so here's on the anniversary of the death of Bruce Lee, right?
Speaker 1: Kareem uploaded to his blog/newsletter, right?
Speaker 1: Basically, a thing that he had written about Bruce Lee, right?
Speaker 1: Basically, there was a chapter in Kareem's autobiography about Bruce Lee.
Speaker 1: So he took the chapter from his own autobiography and put it on his newsletter, right?
Speaker 1: And so here you can read that chapter without having to buy his whole book.
Speaker 1: It's not very long post, but the best part was a quote of Bruce Lee that I had not heard before, right?
Speaker 1: Where Bruce Lee said, what's the actual quote?
Speaker 1: "Ah, I fear not the man who has practiced 10,000 kicks once, but I fear the man who has practiced one kick 10,000
Speaker 1: times.".
Speaker 1: So I think that was the big takeaway for me, is like, figure out that one kick you want to become perfect at, and just kick 10,000 times, right?
Speaker 1: And then it's like, sure, you know what kick I'm going to do, but how are you going to stop it?
Speaker 1: It's such a good kick, I've practiced it 10,000 times, it's going to hit you in the face every time.
Speaker 1: Obviously it's a metaphor and not actual kicking, but it could be actual kicking, maybe that's what you're doing.
Speaker 0: Being real good at kicking is a reasonably valuable thing to know.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying, it's like I've practiced computer 10,000 times, right?
Speaker 1: I've practiced winning a board game 10,000 times.
Speaker 0: In the meta moment, the Geek Nights Book Club book, this is how you lose the time war.
Speaker 0: We didn't do the show on Thursday last week, even though we both read the book, because I had a conflict to do.
Speaker 0: that came up last minute for reasons.
Speaker 0: But we will do this show on the next Thursday episode, or if we don't have a Wednesday show, partly because we can't cover any SAG-AFTRA strike struck works, maybe we'll just-.
Speaker 1: How many struck works are we even seeing?
Speaker 0: I mean, I am.
Speaker 0: Anything we talk about is not going to be as- I mean, Nimona, top tier animated movie on Netflix, that's a struck work technically.
Speaker 1: I don't even have Netflix right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean you're not watching stuff that I am.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: You ain't watching anything, so we might- No, I don't watch television.
Speaker 0: We might just do the Thursday show this week.
Speaker 0: so we can get this book club out of the way and I can announce the next two book choices.
Speaker 0: If you haven't read this book yet, it is a short read, like a few hours tops.
Speaker 0: It reads quick, there's stuff going on, I got some stuff to say.
Speaker 1: Let's go back to some more substantial books for the, you know, because we had a few short ones.
Speaker 1: We had Binti and we had this one, right?
Speaker 0: But let's keep it to like .6 Genji's or lower.
Speaker 1: Satanic versus is a fine length.
Speaker 1: I can read that, I can check it out of the library and read it before I have to return it without extending it.
Speaker 0: I was learning a lot of detail about the Crimean War lately, which led me to
Speaker 1: have a
Speaker 0: strange feeling to read a book I have never actually read and I'm not going to pick it as the book club yet, but I kind of want to at some point, but I'm not going to put War and Peace on the list this time.
Speaker 1: No, at least War and Peace is fiction.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I do want to read it.
Speaker 1: I tried to read Crime and Punishment one time.
Speaker 0: Crime and Punishment, that's a short read.
Speaker 0: I read that in like a week.
Speaker 1: I've read it twice.
Speaker 1: I didn't stop reading because of the length.
Speaker 0: Ah, Crime and Punishment is actually one of my favorite novels.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: There's a lot going on.
Speaker 0: Good ol' Ross Kaldenkopf being a dipshit and then learning his lesson.
Speaker 0: He committed a crime and then he accepted his punishment.
Speaker 1: Dun dun.
Speaker 1: Spoilers.
Speaker 1: It was in the spoilers in the title.
Speaker 0: Alright, so we have done a show a while ago on like upgrading computers and workstations specifically, but that was a very narrow show.
Speaker 1: But there's a lot of shows on like updating your software and this isn't, you know, but upgrading and stuff is a topic we have covered in the news and other times, but we haven't done a show on it and we need show ideas.
Speaker 1: So let's go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but also I think there's a, there's a good topic here because there is, I would argue, a very distinct difference between replacing something, possibly because it has failed in some way.
Speaker 1: Or you broke it on purpose.
Speaker 0: Or upgrading something when you already have a thing that solves that kind of problem to have a better thing that solves that problem.
Speaker 1: Just today in the Geek Nights Discord server that you can join, right?
Speaker 1: We were discussing mechanical keyboards because 8BitDo came out with those new Nintendo Famicom style keyboards.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I almost made one of those my thing of the day because they look real stylish.
Speaker 1: They look real stylish, but they look real impractical, especially the mouse, which we were commenting on.
Speaker 1: But I think, I think they could be useful for some cool installation or special projects.
Speaker 1: But regardless, it's like I talked about, hey, hey, look, I have a mechanical keyboard.
Speaker 1: It has Cherry MX Brown switches.
Speaker 1: It has USB cable, right?
Speaker 1: It works.
Speaker 1: It has backlights.
Speaker 1: I replaced the keycaps to much better keycaps.
Speaker 1: But it's like, well, now it's like I see and I covet, actually, not going to lie, all these fancy mechanical keyboards that I keep seeing popping up in my feeds all the time.
Speaker 1: I'm like, oh, that's cool.
Speaker 1: That's a sweet one, right?
Speaker 0: Do not upgrade because you are covetous.
Speaker 0: That is almost always a bad idea.
Speaker 1: And then I look down at my keyboard and I'm like, all right, in what way is that keyboard that I'm coveting really better than this one?
Speaker 1: It's a different style, maybe.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But it's I guess it's newer.
Speaker 1: Some of them are wireless.
Speaker 1: That's a slight improvement, but not much for a keyboard that never leaves the desk.
Speaker 1: It might actually be a negative in some cases.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like there's nothing about them.
Speaker 1: that is actually going to improve my day to day keyboarding.
Speaker 1: And this one works just fine.
Speaker 1: It works terrific.
Speaker 1: In fact, now it's so awesome.
Speaker 1: And those and it's like and those ones that I covet, they ain't cheap.
Speaker 1: They're expensive.
Speaker 0: Now aesthetics could could in some situations be a reason to upgrade.
Speaker 1: For example, let's say if I had so much money that it didn't matter that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, sure.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But even then, having so much money that it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: That edges into the externalities of being wasteful by upgrading things too often, which is something you should consider as a person.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But maybe let's say you street live streamed a lot more often with multiple camera angles and your keyboard was highly visible in those.
Speaker 0: Then for aesthetic reasons might actually make a lot of sense.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 0: But for your use case does not make a lot of sense.
Speaker 0: And meanwhile, I similarly that keyboard looks great, but I bought one hundred and eighty dollar DOS keyboard a long time ago.
Speaker 0: And guess what?
Speaker 0: It is in perfect condition.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So I guess that's the first case when, you know, we're not talking about broken things.
Speaker 1: So when you should upgrade, it has to actually be an improvement.
Speaker 1: You should be able to point and explain this will improve my life in a certain way.
Speaker 1: And if you can't name that way, then you're just throwing money.
Speaker 0: I'm going to throw out a doctrinaire product management term.
Speaker 0: The idea of a market problem, which abstractly just means is there a problem that someone out there has where they would be willing to spend some amount of money ostensibly on you to solve or mitigate that problem in some way.
Speaker 0: And that is a good way to frame.
Speaker 0: any time you are purchasing anything in your life that isn't inconsequential or like food, though even then food, arguably.
Speaker 0: My problem is I am hungry.
Speaker 1: But yes.
Speaker 0: Do you need a keyboard?
Speaker 0: Like what are you going to use a keyboard for?
Speaker 0: If you need a keyboard, buy a keyboard, and then you have to evaluate what keyboard best solves your particular problem, because unlike product management, you're not trying to find the best keyboard for the abstract person out there.
Speaker 0: You're trying to find the best keyboard for you in your exact specific situation.
Speaker 0: Money is a factor.
Speaker 0: Aesthetics are a factor.
Speaker 0: Quality, workflow, what you do with your life are all factors there.
Speaker 1: Now, I think a good category to look at is cameras, because in the camera world, they have this thing called Gear Acquisition Syndrome.
Speaker 1: They call it GAS.
Speaker 1: That's like the term they use.
Speaker 1: Because photographers love to buy new cameras and keep upgrading.
Speaker 1: And since even in film cameras, camera companies are coming.
Speaker 1: You think, look at computers, how much are they coming out with?
Speaker 1: It's like there are new cameras all the damn time.
Speaker 1: They just keep updating those things constantly.
Speaker 1: And you can switch brands to upgrade.
Speaker 1: Photographers love to sell all their shit in a huge pile and get a pile of money and then buy all new shit from a different company.
Speaker 0: You know who else sells this?
Speaker 0: Audio engineers, podcasters, and DJs.
Speaker 0: If you need any of this kind of technology, just go on eBay and you'll find pristine equipment for nothing.
Speaker 1: So I was watching some camera YouTube videos where they were interviewing photographers for reals.
Speaker 1: These are people who spent all day photography-ing.
Speaker 1: It's like their number one hobby.
Speaker 1: They do it more than I bike.
Speaker 1: That's how much they do it.
Speaker 1: And there were two different people who had the exact, seemingly, the exact opposite opinions, and they were both very, very convincing.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: One photographer, when discussing gear acquisition syndrome, said, "Are you better than your
Speaker 1: camera?".
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: It's like, sure, there is a better camera than your camera available because it literally, your camera is already old and this other camera is new.
Speaker 0: I heard that exact same phrase in the context of, "Are you better than your golf
Speaker 0: clubs?".
Speaker 1: Right, exactly.
Speaker 1: It's like if your skills aren't so great that the limiting factor is the equipment, you're taking the best photo you can take with that camera.
Speaker 1: And if you had a newer camera, you could take a better photo.
Speaker 1: That means you're better than the camera and therefore you should go get a new one because you'll take a better photo.
Speaker 1: But it's like if you could improve yourself, your own photography skills, your own eye, and take a better photo than the photos you've already taken with the camera you still have, why are you spending money to upgrade the equipment?
Speaker 1: That's not going to get you.
Speaker 1: You're not going to take a better photo with that one because your skill is still the limiting factor.
Speaker 1: So that's very convincing, right?
Speaker 1: Now, another person had a different opinion, right?
Speaker 1: Which is also very convincing and their opinion was this.
Speaker 1: There's the scene in Indiana Jones where the guy has the sword and Indiana just shoots him, right?
Speaker 1: And it's like if you're going into a fight and you show up with a sword and the other person has a gun, it's like, it makes no sense, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you should get, if you're going in to do a thing, you should bring the strongest, most powerful thing available, right?
Speaker 0: Well, case in point, I got my really nice pancake lens.
Speaker 0: Like I love that lens, but it's not a zoom lens, just pancake lens.
Speaker 0: Like it just, it does, I got a, what's the term?
Speaker 0: Zoom with your feet?
Speaker 0: So I can take real good pictures with this thing, but you know what?
Speaker 0: If I spent a lot of money, I could have a really good zoom lens that would be just as good as that lens for most use cases.
Speaker 0: And it would save me a lot of hassle and I could take this equivalent photos with way less physical effort and mental effort.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, so the thing there is I think that argument is true, but only in that person's context was like actually trying to be a photographer, like a published professional photographer.
Speaker 0: I think you hit on the.
Speaker 0: both perspectives are equally compelling.
Speaker 0: This is an ambivalent situation.
Speaker 0: It really depends on your situation, right?
Speaker 1: If you're going to sell photos to try to get them in a magazine, to try to make, print a book and sell copies, to put photos in a gallery and sell them, right?
Speaker 1: And it's like, if someone else has taken photos with like the latest, greatest camera, right?
Speaker 1: They're ultra high resolution and their autofocus is better.
Speaker 1: And you've got one that's, you know, five years old, three years old, right?
Speaker 1: Let's say you got two sports photographers next to each other at the Olympics.
Speaker 1: Someone's got a brand new one.
Speaker 1: Someone's got the two year old one.
Speaker 1: It's like they're going to have, they're going to get the shot.
Speaker 1: They got more frames per second.
Speaker 1: They got better autofocus.
Speaker 1: They got better megapixels, right?
Speaker 1: They're going to get, they got more likely to get the shot and they're more like, and their shots going to look better in the high res.
Speaker 1: And it's going to get into the newspapers and they're going to buy from that photographer and not from you.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: So in that sort of situation, it's like, you got to get better.
Speaker 1: You upgrade, get better stuff, right?
Speaker 0: I think there's another argument for that side in some cases.
Speaker 0: And that is when the technology you have is old enough to where the workflows around it are materially obsolete.
Speaker 0: and thus learning to use that technology better, which photography is not as much of a thing, but it could be like, especially certain kinds of film photography, but in a lot of other areas, like learning how to use a camcorder from the nineties is not going to teach you anything useful.
Speaker 0: No, you will learn nothing.
Speaker 1: Do it for retro.
Speaker 1: You can do it for fun.
Speaker 1: You can do it for, you might actually want to have a project where like, that's part of the, you know, that's, it's supposed to look like that.
Speaker 0: But like learning the pipeline to record a two person podcast, like geek nights on a purely analog setup, that is a nearly worthless skill that is not marketable and will not likely be useful to you at any point in your life compared to the share ease of a modern, pure digital workflow.
Speaker 0: But look back at geek nights as an example, when we first started geek nights, the Logitech stick microphone was not the limiting factor on geek nights, us being good at talking continuously for an audience.
Speaker 1: Were we better than that microphone?
Speaker 0: No, for at least a year, a while, we were not better than that microphone, but as soon as we got better than that microphone, we rapidly had to evolve our technology.
Speaker 0: But that was, we had a sort of a separate problem that I didn't want to get into, even if like we would have gotten the correct tool for the job, but back then we did not have enough money to afford the best tool for the job.
Speaker 0: So we instead had to make do with the best tool we could afford.
Speaker 0: Remember those Radio Shack mics?
Speaker 0: We recorded geek nights for a while on those things and they sucked and they were a problem, but that was the best we could do.
Speaker 0: We still had to upgrade, but we upgraded not to the top of the line, but to like this middle of the road milestone along the way.
Speaker 0: And that is often a good option if you're not a professional or don't have unlimited money.
Speaker 0: Of course, you also got to avoid the sword problem of if you have unlimited money, don't buy the $5,000 microphone.
Speaker 0: There is no possible use on earth for that.
Speaker 0: And if you can think of a use, you're either a professional in a industry other than radio and podcasting or you're lying and you're a golden ear audiophile type.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, there are things you can upgrade to, right?
Speaker 1: If you look at any product category where it's like, yes, there is something better, but it's very expensive.
Speaker 1: And then it's like there's actually something that's even more expensive.
Speaker 1: that's not actually better.
Speaker 1: It's just there to take money from people.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like if you go to the store with a fancy jewelry and look at the watches and like for some reason you want a mechanical jewelry watch that cost a shit ton of money.
Speaker 1: It's like they have them.
Speaker 1: You know, there's Rolex.
Speaker 1: is that cost, you know, tens, maybe even hundreds of thousands of dollars, maybe even millions.
Speaker 1: Who knows?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But it's like there are also like, you know, other luxury watch brands right that are out there that aren't Rolex or maybe they're cheaper Rolex.
Speaker 1: It's like and it's like, are they going to be really worse?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, probably not.
Speaker 0: And that's where you can't upgrade too high on the cost path, regardless of how much money you have, until you have enough understanding of the thing you're buying to understand where is the point beyond which it's diminishing returns and stealing money from foolish rich people.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: Like if I had like if I won the lottery.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And I, you know, which is like, you know, I'm basically my bicycle.
Speaker 1: I have no reason to upgrade it whatsoever.
Speaker 1: But like, you know, it's I have nothing to change on it, like no complaints whatsoever, except that the change is broke.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Besides that.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: but if I were to go and like I got a huge pile of money, it's like, why not buy a new bike?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like they sell twenty thousand dollar bikes.
Speaker 1: Thirty thousand.
Speaker 0: I've written the 20 ish.
Speaker 0: Actually, an eighteen thousand dollar bike once.
Speaker 0: And was it ten thousand dollars better than the eight thousand dollar mountain bike I rode?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: But was it better?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But I'm not a professional mountain biker running right here.
Speaker 0: Money.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: So I like your trek domain.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I guess sort by price high to low.
Speaker 1: So they have the.
Speaker 1: OK, so they have the trek domain SLR nine access.
Speaker 1: Gen four is thirteen thousand dollars.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like even if I won the lottery, I probably would not choose that one.
Speaker 1: I might choose, you know, something like, I don't know, the domain SL seven Gen four for sixty eight hundred dollars.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: that's much much more reasonable.
Speaker 1: And am I better than that bike?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, I'm not you know, I just choose the bike that I'm the cheapest bike that I am not better than.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Is where I would go even if money was no object.
Speaker 1: They're just handing out free bikes.
Speaker 1: Pick any model you want.
Speaker 1: I still wouldn't pick the thirteen thousand dollar.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Now, some cases you do get the absolute best thing.
Speaker 1: And that's usually in product categories where no one's trying to milk the high end.
Speaker 0: So, for example, I had water filters.
Speaker 0: No, we hike and camp a lot.
Speaker 0: Me and Emily and one don't fuck around with drinking water you found outside.
Speaker 0: That's just a general rule of life.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: So no matter where I guess, if if it's like a natural fucking spring or like you took some glacier and you melted it or something like I mean, natural springs, that's still going to test like you did, but obviously.
Speaker 0: But so I there are perfectly like effective ways to filter water that are pretty cheap, but they either make the water taste like ass, like it tastes like bleach.
Speaker 0: You just drinking bleach or they're not ninety nine point nine nine nine nine percent effective.
Speaker 0: They're only like ninety nine percent effective.
Speaker 0: So, of course, I bought the three hundred dollar like military grade for real filter because I'm not going to fuck around with my own personal safety, especially drinking water within one hundred miles of New York City out in the woods.
Speaker 0: But I did upgrade from the life straw because while the life straw is also super effective, it you cannot get enough water through that quickly if you are thirsty, let alone if you're going to cook with water.
Speaker 0: Like I need to be able to pump like a couple of gallons of clean water quickly to then go cook with out in the woods.
Speaker 0: So let's see.
Speaker 0: I guess we could talk about a few examples like right now, TVs are actually a really good topic.
Speaker 0: I have a TV that I should replace one because it's dying, but it's been dying for a couple of years now.
Speaker 0: But it's at the point where the brightness is at max and it's slowly dimming beyond the point where I could probably repair it and replace just the backlights.
Speaker 1: And you'll be all good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's also.
Speaker 1: the problem is, is that TVs are so cheap now, especially if you weren't getting an OLED.
Speaker 1: Like if you went for like, you know, like one of those like high sense and like and we're like one of those QLEDs and like not the highest end model for like the second best model.
Speaker 1: It's like we're talking hundreds of dollars right now to get a new TV that would be way better, at least visually than your TV when it was new.
Speaker 1: So it's like, and I guess how much is it going to cost to repair the backlights?
Speaker 1: Maybe also hundreds.
Speaker 1: So why would you do that?
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: But I had been I'd been wanting to upgrade my TV to a 4K TV because, well, there aren't a lot of streaming things to use that.
Speaker 1: How much 4K content is available to you?
Speaker 0: Games in the living room, HDPC, stuff like that.
Speaker 0: Like I have use cases, but the reason I have not upgraded is that I have a well, until very recently, now that the TV is toward its death.
Speaker 0: I had a perfectly good TV that covered 90 percent of everything I cared about.
Speaker 0: That slight bump in quality was not worth the extra cost when it still worked.
Speaker 0: And it was not worth the externality of.
Speaker 0: I'm replacing something that theoretically I could keep using, bad for the environment.
Speaker 0: But also by waiting a couple more years instead of upgrading when I originally wanted to, two more generations of OLED TVs have come out.
Speaker 0: I can get a TV that is way better than the one I could have gotten a few years ago.
Speaker 1: And did you suffer really for those two years?
Speaker 1: Were you like, you know, now the only time I suffered the only the opportunity cost of the past two years, the shitty.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So you know what the opportunity cost was?
Speaker 0: A couple of shows we watched were too dark, but wasn't that big a deal.
Speaker 0: And playing Disco Elysium together on the couch, not ideal because of the 1080p text instead of 4K text.
Speaker 1: But you didn't die.
Speaker 1: You live.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it wasn't.
Speaker 0: It was it degraded the experience, but to a degree that was not material.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, if you need more brightness, right.
Speaker 1: The OLED TVs, right, which obviously.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, I only need more brightness.
Speaker 0: compared to this TV is like dimming rapidly.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, especially since, you know, you have that new building that went up blocking all the sunlight.
Speaker 1: You're probably you know, the OLED is the good choice, right?
Speaker 1: You usually need the LCD.
Speaker 1: these days if you want to, A, save money or B, you want to like overpower some other lights because you're watching in a bright.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The OLED is the use case.
Speaker 1: Your apartment is now very dark.
Speaker 0: But to talk about a very similar situation, remember we were in RIT and one day my computer stopped working.
Speaker 0: And that was, you know, being a nerd at RIT, that is that is that is the second worst possible thing that can happen to you.
Speaker 0: The worst being like getting cancer or something like my computer breaking was existential.
Speaker 0: It was the capacitor problem I had.
Speaker 1: Oh, right.
Speaker 1: That one.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So I had a motherboard and it had an AMD K7-800 in it.
Speaker 0: So when it died, my options were replace it or use this as an opportunity to upgrade.
Speaker 0: And that was actually a difficult decision, because on one hand, I could buy a new motherboard, put the same CPU I had into that motherboard and probably keep going, because it was very unlikely that CPU was damaged.
Speaker 0: Only the motherboard was damaged.
Speaker 0: However, A, the industry had just shifted again from CPUs and sockets, which in retrospect didn't last that long, to slots again.
Speaker 0: And when the slots happen, that was clearly going to be the future of CPUs basically forever after that point.
Speaker 0: So if I got a slot instead of a socket, I would have to also upgrade the CPU, but I could get a gigahertz CPU, which going from 800 megahertz to a gigahertz in the year 2002.
Speaker 1: That's a huge improvement.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that is a significant material improvement.
Speaker 0: And that was an era where you could upgrade CPUs one to one point five times before the socket changed and the motherboards were incompatible.
Speaker 0: That is not the case now.
Speaker 1: Now the socket changes like, you know, a lot.
Speaker 0: So like nowadays, I would pretty much say if your motherboard dies, replace that and the CPU.
Speaker 0: If the CPU dies, replace the mother, like replace the whole fucking thing.
Speaker 0: Just build a new computer, use your existing non-core components.
Speaker 1: Save your hard drives.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's about it.
Speaker 0: But in the year 2002, it was materially better to use the opportunity to upgrade.
Speaker 0: The incremental cost difference actually gave me a computer that lasted a lot longer.
Speaker 0: It saved me money in the long run and gave me a better experience.
Speaker 0: I did have to convince my dad to give me a few hundred bucks because I couldn't afford it, but it all worked out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, that's the thing is when the upgrade is not replacing an entire object, right, but is replacing a part of a whole.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like that.
Speaker 1: And if it can extend the life span or the useful lifespan of the larger, more expensive object, you might actually be saving money by upgrading.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Even if it's something extreme, like a new engine in the car, there are times when, you know, as expensive as that is, where that could be better than new car.
Speaker 1: Maybe you maybe you found the engine and like at the junkyard from a similar car that got hit and then you were able, you know, a guy who swapped it in.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, and that was they crashed.
Speaker 1: their brand new car engine was hardly used.
Speaker 1: It's like there are situations you can get away with in life.
Speaker 1: If you're resourceful.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, when the CD player in the radio of my 1998 Pontiac Sunfire that barely ran broke, even replacing it was not worth it.
Speaker 0: So I just wired up my iPod mini or micro, whatever the small iPod was, into the car with a bootleg adapter and made it work and just made do.
Speaker 0: I didn't upgrade or replace because if I had bought a nice radio or a CD switcher or something to put in that car, that thing probably would have been worth more than the whole car.
Speaker 1: Probably, yeah.
Speaker 0: You remember that car toward the end of its life, it was decrepit is the word.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, I do see a lot of people out there.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's common in all fields of nerdery and geekery who have the gear acquisition syndrome or the upgrade fever.
Speaker 1: It's like new Nvidia car.
Speaker 1: They just keep upgrading it all the time.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, new cameras.
Speaker 1: They get the new ones all the time.
Speaker 1: TV is new TV every year.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like I have a computer professional for whom video gaming is a primary hobby who does VR.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: I still have a 1080 in my computer and I do.
Speaker 0: And that is in there on purpose.
Speaker 0: So think about that if you're about to buy a 4080.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: is it, you know, if you went into someone's house who just upgraded like the 2080 or the 3080 to a 4080 and you switched it back to the 3080.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And you just if they never looked at any benchmarks or they never looked at it, they even know.
Speaker 1: if they never looked at their frame rate or anything, would they know?
Speaker 1: They wouldn't know.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: There's no way they would know.
Speaker 1: It's still running a 3080, still runs every game at max settings, full frames.
Speaker 1: And so it is a 4080.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And like if unless they do something like try to render some ridiculous video or mine bitcoins or something stupid like that.
Speaker 1: It's like they will not know.
Speaker 0: But meanwhile, remember, but when I got I upgraded to 4K monitors a while before you did.
Speaker 0: You came over one day back when we were playing auto chess.
Speaker 0: that lasted a hot minute.
Speaker 0: And I remember you sat down and you were like, why?
Speaker 0: You said out loud, wow, auto chess looks great.
Speaker 0: Like, what are your settings?
Speaker 0: That was just like, that's just 4K.
Speaker 0: It's not even max settings.
Speaker 0: That's just 4K.
Speaker 0: And you basically were like, well, fuck.
Speaker 0: And you upgraded to 4K not too long after that.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't think it was around then.
Speaker 1: When did I buy these monitors?
Speaker 0: Because I could check it quite a while, actually.
Speaker 0: And meanwhile, our house, we have three of the same Dell 4K monitor between me and Emily.
Speaker 1: I actually have two different monitors.
Speaker 1: I got a Dell one.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: That's only 60 hertz.
Speaker 1: But has really good color replicate.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And then I have a LG one that the color is meh.
Speaker 1: It's a little bit off.
Speaker 1: It's not bad, but it's not great.
Speaker 1: But it goes to 144 hertz.
Speaker 1: The thing is, my my GPU doesn't support 144 hertz.
Speaker 1: It only supports like 92.
Speaker 0: I mean, I lock all my monitors at 60 because my 1080 is that 60 is what you're getting.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But if I you know, that is one reason to get a new video card is to get more hertz.
Speaker 1: But actually, what do I do that needs more hertz?
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: Are you playing?
Speaker 0: are you playing competitive FPS's for real and seriously?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, do I actually need those extra hertz, you know, the extra refresh rate?
Speaker 1: It's like I will eventually.
Speaker 0: But meanwhile, look at me.
Speaker 0: I'm playing competitive FPS is seriously with intent to be good at them.
Speaker 0: And I'm still sticking around at 60.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, yeah, that's fine.
Speaker 0: Because I am not I mean, I'm still upper silver logo like I am not better than my refresh rate at Overwatch.
Speaker 1: So so the TLD of upgrading is don't be wasteful.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: With your money or with the environment or with things that still work and are perfectly serviceable.
Speaker 1: Don't upgrade fruitlessly if there's no reason for it, if it's not actually going to result in an improvement of something meaningful,
Speaker 0: I think
Speaker 1: in your life, most
Speaker 0: importantly, lead your life in terms of the acquisition of things from the perspective of useful things from the perspective of is there a problem, a difficulty, a hole in my life that this will fill in some material?
Speaker 1: I have a goal I'm trying to achieve and the tools are.
Speaker 1: the reason that I am not achieving the goal is that tools are inadequate or is it or not?
Speaker 0: Because never forget, when I bought my skis, when I was first learning how to ski again and I was like, why are those what's what's better about those skis?
Speaker 0: And the guy was like, there's several hundred dollars more and they're blue and you clearly don't know the difference between them.
Speaker 0: So you should buy these skis.
Speaker 0: And he kept pointing at the cheapest skis they sold.
Speaker 1: It was a very wise a person whose job it is to sell skis telling you to buy the cheaper one so that you know that that's the store that you should go back to.
Speaker 0: Guess where I went back to buy expensive skis like eight years later when I knew what the fuck I was doing and I went in and I was like, I know exactly why those skis are better in detail.
Speaker 0: And the same guy was there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was the ski house upstate by Fishkill.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, that one.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion, news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows, SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of Geek Nights are Alan Joyce, Linki G, Drea, Lily Tenenborough, Case Care, Makes Music, Krista Dodd, Clinton Walton, Dex, Finn, Joel Hayes, Penny Rhymer, Rebecca Dunne, Sam Erickson, Sherman Van Horl and a bunch of people who give like a dollar or have otherwise indicated that I should not say their name.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, Geek Nights is just plugging along mostly like usual.
Speaker 0: And I got nothing.
Speaker 0: I'm just really hungry.
Speaker 0: So anyway, here's.
Speaker 0: There's the Oasis.
Speaker 0: It's not much, but it's a safe haven from soul fangs in the husks.
Speaker 1: How does it keep them out?
Speaker 0: Surrounded by obelisks that create a circle of protection.
Speaker 1: It's a magical barrier around the Oasis.
Speaker 0: Anyway, here's the Wonderwall.
Speaker 0: Today, day, day, day, day, day, day, day, day, day, day.
Speaker 0: By now, now, now, now, now, now, now, I don't believe that anybody feels the way I do.
Speaker 0: Doo doo doo doo doo.