Speaker 0: It's Wednesday, January 4th, 2023.
Speaker 0: I'm Rym.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, we are talking about Keanu Reeves, Berserker.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: It will, it won't hit you like a truck, but, uh, I don't know, it's basically just Keanu Reeves as Wolverine.
Speaker 1: Just jumping out a little bit on the review.
Speaker 1: He's a little more than Wolverine.
Speaker 0: He's a little more than Wolverine, but there's big Wolverine vibes, and I just read an interview right before the show where someone was like, "So, your character's a lot like
Speaker 0: Wolverine.".
Speaker 0: And Keanu Reeves' response is like, "Yeah, I fucking love Wolverine.
Speaker 0: I wanted to play Wolverine.
Speaker 0: Wolverine's
Speaker 0: awesome.".
Speaker 0: Which, yeah, I like it.
Speaker 1: I don't think he, I mean, I guess he could kind of do Wolverine, but...
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, the interviewer was very much like, "Oh, you would be a great
Speaker 0: Wolverine.".
Speaker 0: Depends on what kind of Wolverine you were going for.
Speaker 1: You don't tell anyone anything negative when you're interviewing them, but, you know, you're trying to be good with famous people.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: [laughs] You only say bad things to a famous person if you're trying to provoke a reaction from them, or you're about to drop the bomb of, like, "Let's talk about the scandal that you don't know
Speaker 0: about.".
Speaker 0: [laughs] Anyway...
Speaker 1: You don't actually ask that to the person to their face.
Speaker 1: Come on.
Speaker 0: Depends.
Speaker 0: It depends on the exact situation.
Speaker 0: [laughs] But, uh, anyway, so, uh, you know, it's Wednesday, not Tuesday.
Speaker 0: Not gonna dwell on hockey too much, but, uh, there was a, the hockey game last night between the Rangers and the Carolina Hurricane was actually, like, that was a fucking great hockey game other than a really weird call at the end that I understand now, but it kind of gave the Rangers the game
Speaker 1: in... Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 0: And I have seen...
Speaker 1: I mean, they were already ahead, but it sort of, it was like a, it was like a free-sealed deal.
Speaker 1: It's like, you're up by one, and they just give you one more so they can't win.
Speaker 1: They can't catch up.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: But it's, on one hand, I gotta preface this, because as a Rangers fan, it always feels like the Rangers, like, are usually on the wrong side of iffy calls, but...
Speaker 1: It does, it does feel like that, yet so many Rangers fans... I don't do this, right?
Speaker 1: I call it out.
Speaker 1: But so many Rangers fans are always saying, "Ah, the league has it in for the
Speaker 1: Rangers.".
Speaker 0: But no, the league does not have it in for the Rangers.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: And I'm like, "What the hell is wrong with
Speaker 1: you?".
Speaker 1: If anything, the league wants the Rangers to win.
Speaker 1: One of the biggest, most expensive teams with the most fans.
Speaker 1: It's like, the league wants the Rangers to win real bad.
Speaker 0: They make a lot more money overall if the Rangers win the Stanley Cup than if, like, Buffalo wins it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much, like, if the league had their way, it would be all New York-Toronto all the time to make the biggest one, right?
Speaker 1: They wouldn't...
Speaker 0: There's a way to do a hockey league.
Speaker 0: You have a league that's, forget original six, original two, it's just two teams, it's the best players, and it's just this, like, 50/50, like, nonsense game.
Speaker 1: All-star game, but actually that's the only...
Speaker 0: All-star game, but that's it, and like, every player...
Speaker 1: You could just make a league that only has two teams, and they play seven games a year, and that's it.
Speaker 1: The end.
Speaker 1: You know, I would... Up to seven games a year.
Speaker 0: I would watch that, but also that would be an okay way, if you got an esport that's, like, not big enough to have a real ecosystem.
Speaker 0: That's the kind of league you make to get some buzz without, like, having to make a full league with a bunch of teams.
Speaker 1: I mean, you think about it sort of the way the individual sports work.
Speaker 1: It's like tennis.
Speaker 1: There's four tennises a year that really matter, and the rest are lower tennises.
Speaker 0: That's true, and, like, the tennis nerds pay attention.
Speaker 1: It's like, yeah, there's a lot of people, but it's still tournaments with, you know, individual champions, and that's, you know...
Speaker 0: Yep, but basically there's this play at the end of the game where the ranger... So, one of the members of the Carolina Hurricanes was holding a hockey stick, and the stick just broke, which happened.
Speaker 0: Well, someone...
Speaker 1: It was against the boards, and someone banged into it, and yeah, it broke.
Speaker 0: But they break.
Speaker 0: Like, these are extremely dangerous, powerful people.
Speaker 0: The kind of person where if they, like, if one of them punched me or Scott, we would just die, probably.
Speaker 1: Hockey sticks break often.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Like, I broke hockey sticks when I was a kid, like, especially, but these are, like, special hockey sticks.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the rule in hockey is you can't play with a broken stick.
Speaker 0: So, if you play with a broken stick, because that is extremely dangerous, a broken hockey stick is basically a super sharp spear.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So, the rule is if your stick breaks, you have to drop it immediately, and it is a penalty if you play at all with it.
Speaker 1: So, but in my entire life of watching hockey, that's been the rule, right?
Speaker 1: And just about any hockey game you watch, you're gonna see at least once, if not more than once, hockey stick broken and someone throwing it away, right?
Speaker 1: Immediately, like a hot potato, like, get that shit away from me, right?
Speaker 1: Because you don't want a penalty, and you don't want to hurt someone also, right?
Speaker 1: Both.
Speaker 1: So, and that's every single time in my entire life of all the hockey I've watched at every level, there's been many, many, many broken sticks in every single time.
Speaker 1: So, it immediately throws the stick away, and I've never seen the penalty called because it never needed to be called.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Nobody ever actually tried to play with the broken stick.
Speaker 0: The average NHL player will go through about 200 sticks a season.
Speaker 1: But that's not that they break 200 sticks, it's that sticks wear out, or they just change a stick every game, or whatever, right?
Speaker 1: And that's 80 something games, so that's like two sticks a game, two to three sticks a game, no big deal.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So, in this situation, the penalty got called, and it's a situation where by the letter of the rules of hockey, that was the right call,
Speaker 1: but simultaneously- The guy didn't realize the stick was broken for like about a second, maybe one second at most, but longer than usual, right?
Speaker 1: In terms of-.
Speaker 0: But that would have been fine, because it turns out the rule is, if you are holding a broken stick, and the stick itself affects the play in any way, that is the penalty.
Speaker 0: So, whether or not you know it's broken does not matter.
Speaker 0: So, in the end, I mean, I feel like the game is broken anyway, but it felt good, even though I'm sure my perception that luck goes against the Rangers more often than for them is wrong.
Speaker 0: I'm sure that every hockey fan on earth believes that about their team, but you know what, I'll take it when luck goes our way, because how many pucks not stop that fucking-.
Speaker 1: I mean, I would be super mad if that call was made against my team, I would be super mad if a Carolina fan said that was a bullshit call.
Speaker 1: I'd say, "Yes, you're right, but I'll take
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: I feel like I'll take.
Speaker 0: it is a very hockey response, not other sports.
Speaker 1: Unlike earlier in the season, right, when Makar got a tripping penalty.
Speaker 1: He drew a tripping penalty, but he fell on his own, and he told the ref, "No, no, no, don't call the penalty,".
Speaker 1: and the ref didn't.
Speaker 1: And it's like, "I wouldn't do that.
Speaker 1: If it was just a whatever game-".
Speaker 0: No, that is too honorable.
Speaker 1: That is like a Klingon letting another Klingon just kill them because of Yeah, it's like if it's just a whatever game, you know, yeah, I would do that sportsman-like behavior of saying, "No, no, no, don't call that penalty,".
Speaker 1: but this is a professional game where winning matters, and it's like, "Yeah, the ref was wrong.
Speaker 1: I'll admit the ref was wrong if someone asked me, but I would never try to not win when it's an important for serious
Speaker 1: game.".
Speaker 0: I mean, what's the game we watch where the dude reaches into the goalie's mitt, pulls the puck out, and throws it into the net?
Speaker 1: And then pretends like it was a goal, right?
Speaker 1: It's like he didn't get away with it, but I would absolutely can't blame him for trying.
Speaker 0: I screencapped the screen on the HDPC because there's this moment where like the ref is talking to him, and he's like kind of laughing, and the ref just has this look on his face like, "Are you
Speaker 0: serious?".
Speaker 1: You're gonna waste every tens of this to maybe 20,000 people in just here and all the people at home watching.
Speaker 1: You're going to take away this goal when you just threw the puck in the net with your hand.
Speaker 0: So anyway, in the news, this is too big a deal to not talk about, but I'm not going to dwell on it because it's Wednesday.
Speaker 0: We're going to talk about comics, but something just happened in the U.S.
Speaker 0: House of Representatives that has not happened in a hundred years.
Speaker 1: It's happened more than once before, though.
Speaker 0: No, so it has happened 14 times.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's more than I thought.
Speaker 0: It has happened 14 times in American history, and the last time it happened was in the year 1923, and in 1923 it was kind of a like ridiculous circumstance.
Speaker 0: Every single other time that it happened was in the lead-up to the Civil War.
Speaker 0: Like, it was sort of a sign that the Civil War was about to happen.
Speaker 0: Like, for real.
Speaker 0: Every single time it happened, other than 1923, was in the lead-up to the Civil War and was about slavery.
Speaker 0: So it stopped happening after the Civil War.
Speaker 0: It happened once in 1923 with some weird fucked up nonsense, and now it just happened.
Speaker 0: And as of today, they voted six times and failed.
Speaker 0: There is no Speaker of the House in the United States.
Speaker 0: And the short summary of this, because this is like arcane rules that even American politicians don't super know.
Speaker 0: Like that football game where like there was a tie and like not everyone really knew how ties worked.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like that, but for once, for you non-USians, the rule is actually like so simple.
Speaker 0: it's almost ludicrous.
Speaker 1: It's one sentence in the Constitution.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's literally the actual Constitution.
Speaker 1: It's not even like some other obscure law.
Speaker 1: It's literally one sentence in the Constitution.
Speaker 0: There's no like regal room for interpretation.
Speaker 0: It's really straightforward.
Speaker 0: Every time there's a new Congress, which is every time we have a vote for the House of Representatives, the first thing they do is they bring in all the new members like, "Hey, you're all here.
Speaker 0: We formed our new house.
Speaker 0: We're starting a new
Speaker 0: Congress.".
Speaker 0: The next thing they do is the whole house just votes on who the Speaker of the House is.
Speaker 0: The thing is, political parties don't exist as far as the American Constitution is concerned.
Speaker 0: They're just a thing that people do.
Speaker 0: There's no rules about them.
Speaker 0: Like they don't exist in our government.
Speaker 1: You can vote for whoever you wanted.
Speaker 1: At least you can vote for someone who's in the room, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You can't vote for me.
Speaker 0: Actually, you can.
Speaker 0: They don't need to be in the room.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of nonsense.
Speaker 1: Wait, hold on.
Speaker 1: I didn't know that.
Speaker 1: That's new information here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it can be anyone.
Speaker 1: Let's say that everyone in the House voted for me.
Speaker 1: You're the Speaker of the House.
Speaker 1: You can resign.
Speaker 1: Okay, that means obviously I'm in line to be President, right?
Speaker 0: If you're eligible.
Speaker 1: But sure, I guess I'm not eligible to be President.
Speaker 1: Am I?
Speaker 0: No, you are.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: You absolutely are.
Speaker 0: Unless you were not born on U.S.
Speaker 0: soil.
Speaker 1: Well, that's the age qualification.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're definitely qualified.
Speaker 1: Okay, anyway, the point is if I became Speaker of the House, but then I would conduct the business of the House and do all the Speaker's roles and have the Speaker's office.
Speaker 0: Which basically would mean you have unlimited power to decide.
Speaker 1: I could be the boss of the guy with the mace over there, right?
Speaker 0: You have basically unlimited power to decide what the House does.
Speaker 1: Sure, but when it came time to vote on a bill on whether it would become law or at least send it to the Senate to maybe become law, I would not have a vote because I would not be an elected representative from a state.
Speaker 0: But you could do things like the House tries to pass a bill and you're just like, "No, you don't want...".
Speaker 1: I mean, I could do things much more powerful than voting, but I wouldn't have a vote.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 1: So, okay, the fact that anyone can... Has anyone who is not a House representative been elected Speaker of the House ever?
Speaker 0: It's either happened zero or one times, and if it happened, the one time it happened was like 1700s.
Speaker 1: Could they vote for someone who was like... Could they vote for the person who's already the President making themselves in line for their own job?
Speaker 0: I don't think there's a rule against that, but I'm pretty sure there are rules against the situation that causes... But I don't actually know.
Speaker 1: Could they vote for a Senator to have that job?
Speaker 0: I don't... Well, I think, again, they could vote for anyone.
Speaker 0: The problem...
Speaker 1: Could they vote for the Governor of a state to have that job?
Speaker 1: So someone would be Governor of a state and also...
Speaker 0: I am pretty confident, based on everything I've read, they could vote for anyone.
Speaker 0: They could even vote for someone who is not a citizen and who is not able to be President because they weren't born on US soil.
Speaker 0: All that means is they get skipped in the line of succession.
Speaker 1: But anyway, they can't agree on anyone right now.
Speaker 0: So basically, because the vote is the entire House, and our fascist party only holds the House by a few seats, if any four Republicans don't vote for...
Speaker 1: No, three.
Speaker 1: Three.
Speaker 0: Four.
Speaker 1: They have a lead of four seats, so if three people vote otherwise... Yeah, so they... I guess three means they're voting for the Democrat.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so basically, every time we vote, there are 212 votes for a Democrat, because that is actually the person who keeps winning these votes, but you need a majority to become Speaker.
Speaker 0: So the Democrats all vote for a really good person, Akeem Jeffries.
Speaker 0: 200-ish Republicans vote for an absolute dipshit guy, and then like 20 Republicans vote for an even fashier dipshit.
Speaker 1: It's the even fashier dipshit.
Speaker 1: It's like, "How much worse can you
Speaker 1: get?".
Speaker 0: But the reason this is happening is that the 20-ish people who are basically saying, "Nope, we're not going to let it
Speaker 0: happen."
Speaker 0: They're the kinds of people who do not care what happens to Congress at all, and they were elected by people who don't believe the 2020 election was fair and who are just crazy.
Speaker 0: So their base loves this, meaning they'll get re-elected into the House forever, and they benefit from the Republicans and the Democrats failing to do anything.
Speaker 0: So they're basically holding the Republican Party hostage, and they're holding America hostage, because guess what?
Speaker 0: Until the House has a Speaker, the House cannot do anything.
Speaker 0: It can't even pay its members.
Speaker 0: It can't hire aides.
Speaker 0: It can't hire staff.
Speaker 0: It can't process payroll.
Speaker 0: It can do nothing, and the rule is...
Speaker 1: Well, they could theoretically still pass a law.
Speaker 0: No, they can't.
Speaker 1: It doesn't say that in the Constitution.
Speaker 1: It still says they could get a majority.
Speaker 1: They could vote for a law.
Speaker 0: The House needs a Speaker to bring the bill to the floor.
Speaker 1: I thought that's a rule that they would have to elect a Speaker and pass rules to make that a rule every time.
Speaker 0: The House needs to elect a Speaker to have a rule.
Speaker 1: Right, but you don't need to have a rule of making a law is in the Constitution, so that's the one rule you don't need to vote into being a rule.
Speaker 0: The Speaker... So there are extremely arcane things that could happen, but effectively, the way this works is now playoff hockey overtime rules.
Speaker 0: They just keep voting, and the dipshit caucus, which actually a few reporters are even calling them now.
Speaker 0: on the Republican side, they basically said, "Nothing will convince us.
Speaker 0: We're going to vote against this guy forever.
Speaker 0: We will not
Speaker 0: negotiate.".
Speaker 1: Good.
Speaker 1: Do nothing for two years.
Speaker 1: That would be amazing.
Speaker 0: That would be the best possible outcome compared to the alternative of the fascist party doing anything, literally anything.
Speaker 0: So this is unprecedented territory that we have not been in since before the Civil War.
Speaker 0: It is worth reading up the details of this because this is ongoing, and it's a shit show.
Speaker 0: This is an absolute clown circus fuck-up.
Speaker 0: Nobody expected this.
Speaker 0: I even didn't think this would actually happen.
Speaker 0: Like, this is the kind of thing...
Speaker 1: I just want to put this out there.
Speaker 1: I mean, sure, someone else has already put this out there, but if you know, if we only need...
Speaker 0: Oh, the Democrats are heavily, heavily trying to convince a few Republicans who aren't even going to run for re-election, like they're on their way out.
Speaker 0: They're in the current Congress, like not the new one that's coming in.
Speaker 0: Just vote for someone good and then retire.
Speaker 1: That's one way out.
Speaker 1: There's another way out, right?
Speaker 1: Go convince three states to recall their Republicans.
Speaker 1: Or even better, and if they send Democrats instead, right, then that's enough votes for the Democrats.
Speaker 0: Scott, it's even easier than that.
Speaker 0: The rule is not the majority of the House.
Speaker 0: The rule is the majority of the members present.
Speaker 1: Oh, you just trapped someone outside.
Speaker 0: So guess what?
Speaker 0: If a small number of Republicans don't show up and quorum gets called, Democrats just win.
Speaker 1: How do you call the quorum without the speaker?
Speaker 1: Who's in charge?
Speaker 0: So the actual procedure is first, the teller, like the administrative staff, do a vote to see if there is a quorum.
Speaker 1: What if those people aren't present because they're not being paid and they just go home?
Speaker 0: Then there can't be a quorum and we have a constitutional crisis and that has never happened and nobody knows what to do.
Speaker 1: What if Mace Guy is just like, "Fuck this
Speaker 1: shit.".
Speaker 0: I hope Mace Guy just fucking leaves.
Speaker 0: See, it's funny, if this was the UK, you know there'd be like, in the wimbly dimbly of 1840, the Mace something something and by their grace and his pleasure.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, you gotta say a point in favor of the monarchy is that, you know, there is a fallback.
Speaker 1: You have this sort of on-paper autocrat that doesn't actually do anything and just lets the democracy happen, but the democracy really collapses, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, technically, the monarch can be like poke, right?
Speaker 0: You know what I would say?
Speaker 0: This is a total aside, but this is actually a real opinion I have.
Speaker 0: Stopping Brexit would have been like the moment for a monarch to do something and the fact that they chose not to ended even that power of the monarchy.
Speaker 1: Yes, well, that particular monarchy, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying I would, I mean, this is a point in favor.
Speaker 0: There are a surprising number of...
Speaker 1: While I have spoken a point in favor of monarchies, I am not in favor of monarchies.
Speaker 1: The con list is much longer than the pro list.
Speaker 0: Like, if you list all the pros and cons of heroin, there are some pros, but there are thousands and thousands of cons.
Speaker 1: Yeah, heroin feels great.
Speaker 1: If I just say that and I don't talk about all the cons of heroin, I just don't want someone to think I'm pro-heroine.
Speaker 0: We did that panel a long time where we were like, "What's the most fun game on Earth?
Speaker 0: Just take
Speaker 0: heroin.".
Speaker 0: Doesn't mean you should play it.
Speaker 1: There might be better games than that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm mega-heroine.
Speaker 1: I haven't tried any of those, that whole genre, on purpose.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that and MMOs, never once.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: I played some months.
Speaker 0: It's some animation news, because I don't dwell on that.
Speaker 0: You can read an article that'll be way more informed than I am about the arcane procedures of the American house.
Speaker 0: MF Ghost, the anime that's just more Initial D. We have our third trailer.
Speaker 0: It has Eurobeat in it.
Speaker 0: This is the trailer that actually has Eurobeat in it.
Speaker 0: This is the final actual confirmation.
Speaker 0: Initial D2 has Eurobeat.
Speaker 0: That is all I needed to hear.
Speaker 0: I literally don't care.
Speaker 1: I mean, technically, this isn't Initial D2.
Speaker 1: They've already had Initial D1, 2, 3, however many Initial D's.
Speaker 0: I watched through, like, Fourth Stage or whatever?
Speaker 0: Anyway, I watched a lot more Initial D than you do.
Speaker 1: This is the point at which, basically, you know, MF Ghost manga, to my knowledge, has been around a while.
Speaker 1: But basically, the same guy who made Initial D is like, "Okay, I can't do anything more with these characters.
Speaker 1: Times have changed, right?
Speaker 1: I will just, rather than make more Initial D, I'll just make another car manga with new characters, new cars, new
Speaker 1: everything.".
Speaker 0: So, Scott, I'm gonna name some names of characters who are now confirmed to be in the manga and the show.
Speaker 0: Takahashi Ryosuke, Takahashi Keisuke, Ikitani, Itsuki, Kenji are all in the show.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: It literally is following the dream project that they started in Initial D, so it really is kind of just... Are they this old?
Speaker 0: It is, I guess.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, this is gonna be the dumbest show that I watch.
Speaker 0: You got any news?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so let's talk about something, you know, good being made.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, I'm so excited about this.
Speaker 1: Right, so Cartoon Saloon, who we are big fans of here at Geek Nights, the Irish animation studio that brought you the Irish trilogy, as well as many other amazing works, and as well as many other works that we don't really pay attention to, like some kids' TV shows like that, Puffin Rock, or whatever, which I'm sure if I had a child, I would show it to them, but...
Speaker 0: Yeah, one of the rare batting a thousand entities on Earth.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so they're, you know, they gotta make some more movies now, right?
Speaker 1: They finished that Wolf Walkers, they gotta go to the next, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, what are they gonna make now?
Speaker 1: You know, it's like, well, wisely, they're not like, "Okay, guy who's directed everything we've made, make something
Speaker 1: again.".
Speaker 1: You know, it's like, let's get some new people in here, we'll animate what they want instead, right?
Speaker 1: So, someone I've never heard of, but has an Oscar nomination named Louise Bagnall, I hope I'm pronouncing their name correctly, they made a short called Late Afternoon, which I think was the Oscar-nominated thing.
Speaker 1: I think they also made, let's see, cartoon development, Oscar-nominated, debut feature, Julian.
Speaker 1: Right, okay, so there's a book called Julian is a Mermaid by Jessica Love, and Louise Bagnall is going to direct the full-length animated feature adaptation of Julian is a Mermaid, but it's only called Julian, and Cartoon Saloon, the same studio that did the Wolf Walkers and the Song of the Sea and all that, is going to be the studio receiving that direction.
Speaker 1: We got it sorted.
Speaker 1: The point is, Julian is a Mermaid is like an awesome story, it's obviously a kid's book, right?
Speaker 1: But it's an awesome story about New York, so it's like, yep, they finished their Ireland, and like, where are we going next?
Speaker 1: New York, that's right.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Let's go.
Speaker 0: Right alongside, we're both reading, or I'll be imminently reading, as I finish and leave the unseen, the world we make, which seems like I'm just gonna burn through that thing pretty quick.
Speaker 1: So yeah, who knows when this is coming out, or how it's coming out, or anything.
Speaker 0: Whenever it comes out, I imagine we will be in the theater seeing it in New York, because you can see any animated movie in New York when it comes out, and I highly encourage you to see this sight unseen.
Speaker 0: You don't need a review to know to go see this movie.
Speaker 1: I mean, this is in a super early stage, right?
Speaker 1: It says they're gonna pitch it in March at a French event or whatever, so it's in the pitching phase, I guess.
Speaker 1: They're trying to get some monies and whatnot, but it's like, so far, usually when I see a news about a movie, especially movies, that early, you can't say it's gonna happen, because Mouseguard had people animating it, and it didn't happen, right?
Speaker 1: They filmed whole movies, and they never got released, but Cartoon Salute has never failed to release it.
Speaker 1: It's a thing that they have mentioned publicly.
Speaker 1: They've always found a way, so I'm confident that within maybe a few years, we will see this, and that'll be pretty good.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day!
Speaker 0: I try not to use, we both try not to use the same channel or the same website like more than once.
Speaker 0: Obviously, you know, a lot of gig nights.
Speaker 0: We started in 2005.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, it'd be easy to just do practical engineering like every fucking week for me, but I realized I've used SciShow and a bunch of other things that John and/or Hank Green have made over the years, so I can't use those channels.
Speaker 0: I have never used the Vlogbrothers as a thing of the day, so this video from a year ago that's new to me.
Speaker 1: Is it the vlog?
Speaker 0: Yeah, Vlog or Vlog, Video Log.
Speaker 1: You mean vlog?
Speaker 0: Vlog.
Speaker 1: Vlog?
Speaker 1: I mean, I gotta post an article on my Vlog.
Speaker 0: I was thinking it was the guy in that video who calls it his home page.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so this video is titled "So Orange Juice Isn't What It Seems" and one, it's really funny.
Speaker 0: Like, Hank Green definitely has evolved and extremely...
Speaker 1: Eh, I watched it.
Speaker 1: It's a YouTube yelling guy.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's funny.
Speaker 0: I think Hank Green's style is extremely funny.
Speaker 0: I actually very much like his evolved current, like the style he grew into about five years ago.
Speaker 0: Did not lol.
Speaker 1: No lols.
Speaker 0: You don't laugh at anything.
Speaker 1: I laugh at it, it's actually funny.
Speaker 0: But the more important thing is that this video sort of condenses all the things I think about orange juice very succinctly into a video and none of this is new to me or Scott, but if you drink orange juice and you think you know anything about the orange juice you're drinking, you're probably wrong.
Speaker 0: And also, orange juice is not better for you than just fucking soda.
Speaker 0: Like, I still drink orange juice.
Speaker 0: I love orange juice, but in the words of Hank Green, it's just candy water.
Speaker 1: Well, the one thing he doesn't mention, which is what I did to basically stop drinking orange juice, which is, you know, he compares, you know, the fresh orange juice, right?
Speaker 1: Get oranges and squeeze them, right?
Speaker 1: Whereas what I just do is I just eat oranges.
Speaker 1: You don't have to squeeze them, just eat the or- Oh, peel.
Speaker 1: You don't have to peel, but you take the- Peel it and fucking eat it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the problem is that slows you down like a pistachio.
Speaker 0: You got to open each pistachio and eat them.
Speaker 1: Drinking orange juice is like- No, no, no.
Speaker 1: You open a pistachio and you get, like, one little nut and you have to open a bunch of them.
Speaker 1: An orange, you can open one orange and you get a ton of orange.
Speaker 0: But I can drink orange juice and it's like the equivalent of just funneling a bag of pre-shelled pistachios directly into my mouth.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a bad idea.
Speaker 1: It's a good idea.
Speaker 0: It's a great idea.
Speaker 1: It's a bad idea.
Speaker 1: I eat like 5000 calories a day in the summer, so.
Speaker 1: At least in North America, it's orange season like now-ish, right?
Speaker 1: Go and just buy a sack of oranges.
Speaker 1: That's the cheapest way to get them.
Speaker 1: And just eat oranges every morning.
Speaker 1: And that's- You'll get fiber and everything and there's still delicious juice in there.
Speaker 1: You still experience plenty of juice flavor, but you take in much less candy water into your body.
Speaker 0: Thing is, I'm seeking the candy water because remember, I'm all- I'm pretty much always at a calorie deficit.
Speaker 0: Like, I got to keep eating or I have trouble.
Speaker 1: Eat more oranges.
Speaker 1: Eat the whole sack.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if I eat the whole sack, I could also juice the whole sack and drink it.
Speaker 1: You're throwing away all that useful delicious fibers.
Speaker 0: Nah, but I also- I zest them all for cocktails.
Speaker 0: Anyway, what do you got?
Speaker 1: What do I have?
Speaker 1: So, I didn't know this sport existed, which is very rare.
Speaker 1: It's underwater hockey.
Speaker 1: Apparently, people in the UK play it.
Speaker 1: I don't know if anyone else anywhere else plays it.
Speaker 0: I kind of want to try to play it.
Speaker 1: I thought this was one of those fake concocted documentary videos, but no, it's real.
Speaker 1: This may be among- first of all, the notable things about this sport, right?
Speaker 1: So, it's underwater hockey.
Speaker 1: There's a puck just like a hockey- ice hockey puck and you have a little tiny sticks and the puck is at the bottom of the swimming pool and you're trying to get it into a goal.
Speaker 1: It's- the rules are what you think they are.
Speaker 1: The problem is, it's at the bottom of the pool.
Speaker 1: It's three meters deep.
Speaker 1: Meters, right?
Speaker 1: You can't- you got to dive to get down there.
Speaker 1: Everyone's got flippers and goggles and everything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's going to be no Shaq situation where someone's so tall they can just kind of kick it or something.
Speaker 1: But, good luck staying down there that long, right?
Speaker 1: It's like even if you're the Wayne Gretzky of swim hockey, pool underwater hockey, like you go down there, you can be amazing, but it's like there's no way you're going to get the puck all the way from one end of the pool to the other.
Speaker 1: It's a full-size pool.
Speaker 0: And even more, the harder you play, the more you use up your oxygen and the less time you can spend down there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like you basically must have like teamwork to be any good at this game.
Speaker 1: You cannot- it's not an individual- it's like the least individual sport ever, right?
Speaker 1: Like your whole- you could have a team- like one person in the video even says you could put all the best players in the same team and they would suck.
Speaker 1: The team that wins all the time is this team.
Speaker 1: that's like been together for 12 years.
Speaker 1: They all know what everyone's going to do.
Speaker 1: They've got all their systems worked out, right?
Speaker 1: You know, and they've had very few lineup changes and that team dominates, right?
Speaker 1: Because that's- it's all about- you talk about coordination of like, you know, some FPS team in Overwatch.
Speaker 1: It's like comes nothing close to, you know, the underwater hockey.
Speaker 1: And the second thing is that the underwater hockey may be the most physically demanding sport I've ever seen.
Speaker 1: Like it doesn't look physically demanding like, you know, a weightlifting or a sprinting or a, you know, a gymnastics.
Speaker 0: I'll give you an example.
Speaker 0: I can run- I can run a half marathon without even breaking a sweat in under two hours.
Speaker 0: Like I just feel great at the end.
Speaker 0: I can't swim more than like half a mile without being fucking wrecked.
Speaker 1: But it's like just swimming.
Speaker 1: But like, no, this isn't just swimming.
Speaker 1: This is- you're going underwater and holding your breath for a significant amount of time, coming back up and then trying to go back under as soon as possible.
Speaker 1: And when you're down there, swimming with flippers as hard as you can, right?
Speaker 1: And it's like, if you're the goalie, it's like the goalie I think is the most fascinating thing.
Speaker 1: They didn't talk about it in the video, but I sort of noticed like, do you have a goalie even?
Speaker 1: It's like, why bother, right?
Speaker 1: But the goalie can't just stay down there and wait the whole time.
Speaker 1: The goalie has to stay up and look into the water with their goggles and their snorkel.
Speaker 1: Like they have snorkels, short ones.
Speaker 1: And like, see if the puck is coming close to the goal and when it does, time their dive, right?
Speaker 1: It's like the goalie might go down, make a save, right?
Speaker 1: Run out of breath and be like, "Am I gonna die or are we gonna get scored
Speaker 1: on?".
Speaker 0: Yep, go down too early and you gotta come up and then undefended goal, empty net.
Speaker 1: Yeah, do you have two goalies like rotating?
Speaker 1: Like what are you gonna do?
Speaker 1: It's like, I don't know.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I would never play this.
Speaker 1: I would never watch it.
Speaker 0: If it were easy to play, like I would want to play a game of this.
Speaker 0: This would be really fun, I think.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I would play in a much shallower pool.
Speaker 0: I play in a deep pool, but I would want to play it with people who are...
Speaker 1: Not three meters.
Speaker 1: It had to be like three meters to be fun.
Speaker 0: I just want to, I would play it against people who are as bad at it as I expect I will be.
Speaker 0: I don't want to play against people who are good.
Speaker 1: The problem with the three meter pool is that like I would have a hard time even getting to the bottom period.
Speaker 0: Blow on flippers.
Speaker 0: make that real.
Speaker 0: Have you ever swum with... They help, they help.
Speaker 0: Have you ever swum with flippers?
Speaker 0: It is like quadruple speed.
Speaker 0: Like it is, it's hacks.
Speaker 1: But also I could only stay down, you know, the amount of time it would take me to get to the bottom.
Speaker 1: I'd be able to hockey for like a few seconds.
Speaker 1: It's like, give me the one and a half meter, two meter pool.
Speaker 1: Then I can actually do some hockey.
Speaker 0: How long can you hold your breath?
Speaker 0: I'm curious.
Speaker 1: I mean, the problem is I could, you know, okay, so I do a little bit of hockeying and then I come up.
Speaker 1: It's like, how long until I can go down again?
Speaker 1: It's like, my time at the bottom is decreasing.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: Because you can train yourself with hypoxic training to be able to work harder with less air.
Speaker 1: Well, doesn't that significantly shorten your life?
Speaker 0: No, there's no evidence of that.
Speaker 0: In
Speaker 1: fact, people who dive for, you know, clams and so
Speaker 0: people who do extreme diving like that, it probably is not great for their brains, but people, if you don't do that kind of stuff, you can train yourself to hold your breath, like double the time a normal person could without any significant injury, according to my physical therapist.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I'm not messing with that, but anyway, in the meta moment, the geek does book club book.
Speaker 0: I leave the unseen.
Speaker 0: I'm going to be out of town next week for a work trip in Germany.
Speaker 0: So we'll either do the show the following week, which would be an off day because that's another Monday, Wednesday week, or, uh, right after I get back from a separate unrelated ski trip in Vail.
Speaker 0: So finish, I'll leave the unseen in January because we're going to do an episode at the latest in the first part of February.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Uh, we have a forum.
Speaker 1: We've talked about it on every episode of this show ever, basically, but, uh, I just upgraded the forum, which I do whenever there's up upgrades.
Speaker 1: But today there was a somewhat bigger upgrade.
Speaker 1: Uh, and so I went through all the settings on the forum and I rejiggered them all, not too much, but enough.
Speaker 1: Uh, and now the forum is as a nude, it's got a little sidebar going on, which I think is much nicer.
Speaker 0: I like that little sidebar.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So I'm like, all right.
Speaker 1: I don't know if anyone's mad about that.
Speaker 1: They can go kick rocks.
Speaker 0: If Twitter's got you down and you don't know how the fuck Mastodon works, because good luck actually knowing every detail.
Speaker 1: Mastodon is not hard to describe how it works.
Speaker 1: It's just email.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: The same thing as email.
Speaker 1: I have found understand how email works.
Speaker 0: I have found that most of the people are saying Mastodon is complicated are just not like getting that basic concept.
Speaker 1: You understand email, you understand Mastodon.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: Same thing.
Speaker 0: Federated timeline is harder for people.
Speaker 1: Mastodon does, but it's not necessary.
Speaker 1: It's not.
Speaker 0: part of what I don't understand is people are really, really butthurt about that tab, but you don't even have to look at that tab and not all the Mastodon does even have that tab.
Speaker 1: There's a difference between the protocol that Mastodon uses and the Mastodon software and the decisions it made.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Imagine if you had email, right.
Speaker 1: And you chose Gmail as your, your email provider.
Speaker 1: And there was a tab in Gmail that showed you like other people's emails, other people's emails that were not emails to you or from anyone, you know, or like, or it showed you like your friends' emails to other people.
Speaker 1: And it's like, what?
Speaker 1: It's like, that's how it'd be messed up.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, just cause you're on Gmail, you're seeing all these other emails and that's Mastodon's choice.
Speaker 1: Gmail could do that.
Speaker 1: Google could show you someone who could, if they wanted to, they could, they could just show you all the emails on Gmail between everybody.
Speaker 1: Um, you know, they just choose not to,
Speaker 0: but just saying if that's
Speaker 1: all got you down
Speaker 0: the geek nights forum launched before Twitter and is still going for red forums are, uh, are art that has come
Speaker 1: and gone over the years,
Speaker 0: but I think they do something that other things don't do.
Speaker 0: And I would like to see a resurgence of forums again.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I like forums, forums are how, how you can type a lot of words without C C annoying all your friends.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 0: So berserker, uh, if you look at the cover, berserker is just Keanu Reeves, uh, the berserker.
Speaker 0: And it's a comic by Keanu Reeves and about a character who is clearly played by Keanu Reeves.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure how much he's actually contributed to the writing, but he's listed as a co-writer.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The other writer is Matt Kent from, you know, what was it?
Speaker 1: The spy thing.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And, uh, what's the other one, the one that even had a board game.
Speaker 0: Oh God.
Speaker 0: Uh, I got to look at Wikipedia now.
Speaker 1: Mind MGMT.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Pistol whip super spy super spy.
Speaker 1: That was the first time I heard of Matt Kent.
Speaker 1: I got that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And mind MGMT is the one that also had a board game and people love that.
Speaker 1: Um, but yeah, since that super spy book that we got way long time ago, there's probably geek nights episode about that.
Speaker 1: Matt can't exploded.
Speaker 1: So now it's Matt Kent and Keanu Reeves co-writing, right?
Speaker 1: Uh, the artist is Ron Garney, uh, who I haven't heard of the cover.
Speaker 1: Your artist is Raphael.
Speaker 1: Grandpa, who I have heard of thinking and coloring bill Crabtree.
Speaker 0: And it's just a 12 issue comic about Keanu Reeves.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't know if there's going to be more issues maybe, but there's two volumes, two trade paperbacks.
Speaker 1: I have both of them.
Speaker 1: I read both of them and yeah, it's litter.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know how much Keanu Reeves himself contributed to the writing.
Speaker 1: It's like, it's basically.
Speaker 1: take what would have been a movie with him in it.
Speaker 1: The cliche movie you expect him to be in, but it's like exact like typecasting him and just make it a comic book instead.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: What if John Wick was 80,000 years old and actually invulnerable.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: But he's, he's actually invulnerable, but it's like, I mean, John, maybe John Wick is just the berserker.
Speaker 0: Like he went through a, I'm going to be a mob hit man.
Speaker 0: He's not invulnerable.
Speaker 1: He's immortal.
Speaker 1: It's different.
Speaker 0: Well, he is both invulnerable and immortal.
Speaker 1: He's not invulnerable.
Speaker 1: He takes lots of damage.
Speaker 1: He just always heals all the damage.
Speaker 1: They're very Wolverine like, but, uh, yeah, like it's like 10 X Wolverine, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, he could be turned into like, like one cell of his body remains.
Speaker 0: It's like, I mean, there are definitely multiple arcs where Wolverine comes back from a few cells or some DNA like that is, but not this quickly.
Speaker 0: Not quickly.
Speaker 0: I want to say the last time I saw Wolverine and already I haven't read comics in like a decade, at least X-Men comics.
Speaker 0: The last time I remember Wolverine coming back from almost nothing was like early 2000s.
Speaker 1: And the other thing is that Wolverine's skeleton, right?
Speaker 1: Is like somehow always, even though, you know, the Adam, at times the metal was removed from it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's still, I assume it's Wolverine adamantium right now.
Speaker 0: I assume Wolverine is still alive.
Speaker 0: I don't know what's going on with the X-Men.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, it's not going to be Marvel comic books.
Speaker 1: If there's no Wolverine in any of them right now, they would, why would they do that?
Speaker 0: So I guess the story of this, like what this is about, I've read the first volume and about a third of the second volume.
Speaker 0: Scott's obviously read all of it.
Speaker 0: We're not going to spoil things.
Speaker 0: It's short.
Speaker 0: Like this sounds cool to be more volumes.
Speaker 0: It's not over, but if this sounds good, like just read it.
Speaker 0: Cause there's not that much of it out yet.
Speaker 0: And it's pretty good.
Speaker 0: And I like it.
Speaker 0: But basically the story is just, there's this super soldier currently working for the U S government who is like a berserker, like a classical, like I am a berserker.
Speaker 0: I go berserk and kill people.
Speaker 0: I'm invincible.
Speaker 0: And I have spent 80,000 years being an invincible berserker.
Speaker 0: This is my story.
Speaker 0: We're currently at a stage where the government is studying him ostensibly to help him become mortal because that's all he wants in the world.
Speaker 1: And really it's like, yeah, he knows, he knows that they have their own secret purposes.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But he doesn't give a shit cause he's immortal.
Speaker 0: That's something I really like about this character is that he gives no fucks, what anyone thinks.
Speaker 0: And he's super open.
Speaker 0: The government's like, we're trying to help you.
Speaker 0: He's like, no, you aren't.
Speaker 0: You're just trying to make a super soldier, but you know what, whatever.
Speaker 0: I actually don't care.
Speaker 1: Like he is just very direct and he's like, look, I don't want to die.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I just want to be able to die.
Speaker 0: And that is a nuance that I think a lot of immortal like stories about immortals miss is the, a lot of them are either I'm an immortal who wants to die or I'm an immortal who doesn't want to die.
Speaker 0: And there's a secret trick to kill me cause I'm evil.
Speaker 0: You don't often see the, I don't want to die, but I would like to at least know that I could in case in the future, I get bored or for any reason.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, he knows like, you know, it's like, he's already lived so long since caveman time.
Speaker 0: He's probably worried that like earth will blow up in the distant future and he'll just write the sun explodes.
Speaker 1: He could just be floating out there in space, painfully suffocating repeatedly for eternity.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, that's the kind of thing you might have to worry about.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So it's like, even if he's sitting there thinking, well, like, Hey, even if the U S you know, this government, you know, succeeds where, you know, Roman, whatever previous governments failed, he's like, they'll all be dead and I'll still be around and I'll do.
Speaker 1: some other government will be here in 200 years.
Speaker 1: What do I care?
Speaker 1: But I also like, he's like technology, he's seen all of technology advance.
Speaker 1: He's like, Oh, maybe these people advance the technology enough that they could help me.
Speaker 1: Let's find out.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So he's going to like, he probably tries the same thing with like blood letters and leeches hundreds of years earlier.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Going to shamans.
Speaker 0: You definitely see in that one montage that he probably spent like a hundred years in a monastery just to see.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Like, is this going to work?
Speaker 1: Is this going to work?
Speaker 0: But I guess one thing that's fun about it, uh, he is not just a humorless prick.
Speaker 0: Like you might expect between the character design and like that description of he gives no Fox and he's immortal and he's a berserker.
Speaker 0: He's like clearly tried everything.
Speaker 0: Like he spent time just doing nothing.
Speaker 0: He spent time, basically he's doing nothing but having sex.
Speaker 0: He spent time like doing every possible thing.
Speaker 0: He sort of tried everything and nothing works.
Speaker 0: And he's just trying to figure out what to do next.
Speaker 0: And it's just a, a moderately complex and fun take on that kind of immortal, super powerful character and the practical reality of what it would be like if you were just invincible effectively.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Volume two, right.
Speaker 1: Gets into like, how did he become this way?
Speaker 1: Uh, you know, and it's sort of nice in that I won't tell you what the explanation is, right.
Speaker 1: But it's sort of nice in that they're not like doing the one punch man deal where it's like, Ooh, was it this?
Speaker 1: Was it that?
Speaker 1: Who knows?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And they're not doing the terrible secret of space.
Speaker 1: Like, here's a hit, but we're not going to tell you.
Speaker 1: They're like, they're like, this is what it was.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Absolutely.
Speaker 1: This is the thing that did it.
Speaker 1: We're not going to tell you all the details of, you know, exactly how that works, but it was definitely this thing right here that made this happen.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Uh, so there you go.
Speaker 0: So, uh, if it's not obvious, this comic is hyper violence and it's sort of half of the panels are hyper violent, like intestines and blood just flying everywhere.
Speaker 0: And the other half of the panels look like an introspective two thousands comic.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So it's like, it's not violent the way that like each of the killer is violent where it's trying to make you cringe or be grossed out or anything like that.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: What it is is imagine there was an action movie, right?
Speaker 1: But when someone got shot, what happened to their body is what would happens to a body when it gets shot or cut in half with a sword, but the body just keeps moving.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But the camera doesn't move away.
Speaker 1: They're actually drawing, you know, it's a still image.
Speaker 1: I think if this was like a movie, I'd probably get sick.
Speaker 1: Maybe I don't, even though usually fake stuff doesn't affect me, but it's like, it's a, it doesn't bother me because it's a drawing.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But it's like the camera doesn't cut away and they draw what would happen to a body somewhat.
Speaker 1: Well, he's close to what would happen to a body if that horrible thing happened to it.
Speaker 0: This is an immortal berserker.
Speaker 0: So if you were fighting, say an army of people and you are literally immortal and you know that they can't actually hurt you, like how would you fight?
Speaker 0: And this kind of leans into what that might look like pretty hard.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: He's like, he gets shot.
Speaker 1: He keeps going.
Speaker 1: He gets a sword in him.
Speaker 1: He gets his arm cut.
Speaker 0: There's one scene where someone has a grenade and he just like grabs the grenade and just holds it in front of the guy and just waits for it to go off.
Speaker 1: Like, yeah, that's, you know, that's the kind of thing, you know, you have this core concept and it's like, Hey, how can we play around with this?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: What stuff can we make happen?
Speaker 1: You know, even that core conceit.
Speaker 0: And there's a bunch of characters and they're all like interesting enough.
Speaker 0: Like it doesn't really zoom in on a lot of the characters.
Speaker 0: It seems like it mostly zooms in on him, the researchers working with him.
Speaker 1: I think it's, I think that's on purpose that a lot, you know, the only really characters to get any time are like, you know, the therapist and the scientist, right.
Speaker 0: Or people in his backstory, but even they aren't around long.
Speaker 1: Well, there'll be some backstory people, you know, from you know, origin story.
Speaker 1: that gets a lot of time.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But it's like, I think that's on purpose and it actually normally I'd complain and be like, ah, there aren't any other really cool characters other than the one guy.
Speaker 1: But it makes sense.
Speaker 1: Like being an immortal guy, anyone else in all of history is basically insignificant from his eyes.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, there'll be around for like two seconds.
Speaker 0: Like who do you pay attention to?
Speaker 0: the handful of people who are heavily involved in your biz right now, or the handful of people who are so memorable that they stand out in 80,000 years of being a human running around being a berserker.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Like Eve, let's say in, I don't know, some ancient time, say like, I don't know, Sumer in ancient Sumer, right.
Speaker 1: He was hanging out and he had a, he had a best friend at that time.
Speaker 1: I just making something up, but it's like, and that was like their best friend for 80 years.
Speaker 1: And from like befriended them as a child and they died old and he's still just this dude, the whole time he was a middle-aged dude for the 80 years of this other person's life.
Speaker 1: That's a long time to live in an ancient time.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, it's like that person would be like barely a footnote in this dude's life.
Speaker 1: So like, Yup.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Well, think about, think about how many awesome people you've met.
Speaker 0: Either of us have met in our lives.
Speaker 0: We live about 40 years, maybe 20, like 30 of those.
Speaker 0: We were mostly sentient, like 30, 35.
Speaker 0: How many cool people have we met now?
Speaker 0: extrapolate how many cool people who are just as cooler or as cool or cooler that we would meet in 80,000 years.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: So the book is sort of mirroring his own feelings of like, none of these other people are, are of any significance.
Speaker 1: So we're only going to spend time on them.
Speaker 1: as much as their significance is, you know, makes them worthy of being on the page, getting any character development or anything like that.
Speaker 0: But the character, like he is, he's more complex and nuanced than you might expect.
Speaker 0: His he's not evil.
Speaker 0: Like he's not malicious.
Speaker 0: He's just kind of like, he's seen everything and he's kind of mostly done with stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: He might've had an evil time, you know?
Speaker 1: Oh, let me try being an evil dictator one time.
Speaker 1: Let me know.
Speaker 1: But that time isn't at least the present, as far as the book is concerned.
Speaker 1: Like when the therapist comes over to his house, he's just like, I mean, I guess he's kind of evil doing like, you know, military, you know, whatever, but.
Speaker 0: But when she comes over, like he's still like, he has, he drinks some scotch and hangs out.
Speaker 0: Like he still lives his life.
Speaker 0: It's not like to that extreme.
Speaker 0: And it's honestly, it's a pretty compelling concept, especially because it's not that long so far.
Speaker 0: And I don't know how long it's going to be, but I've enjoyed it.
Speaker 0: I'm going to read volume two.
Speaker 0: And if there's more, I'll keep reading it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, they think the, the, uh, the effort to read this compared to what it is, right.
Speaker 1: Makes it a good value.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's like Eisner award winning worthy or anything like that, but you'll get more.
Speaker 0: Imagine if you want a Wolverine ish story and you don't want to figure out what Wolverine to read right now, this is almost like a mainlining, a take on Wolverine played by Keanu Reeves.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it'll like, um, it's, it's a, it's an interesting thing to think about if someone's going to make like an adaptation of this.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Cause it's like, well, I saw like a whole point of this.
Speaker 0: I saw some talk that Keanu actually said he wanted it to be a comic because he wanted to do a kind of story that's hard to tell in a traditional movie, like having those juxtapositions with the panels.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But it's almost like, you know, the dude could already as, or has already made at least two or three, many movies that are basically right along this line.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So it's like, you could have just gone directly to movie.
Speaker 1: It's like the fact that he went to comic instead, it makes it seem like this isn't one of those plays where you make the comic to make the move to sell the movie up.
Speaker 1: It's like, it seems like they just wanted to make the comic.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: And then Keanu Reeves went to a studio and said, took this as a script and said, I want to make this movie and star in it.
Speaker 0: They would said, yes, they would say yes, please.
Speaker 0: And they would get funding cause it would definitely make money.
Speaker 0: Like they would just do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So it's like, I think it's going to be comic only.
Speaker 1: It's like, Hey, you know, you got one of those, you know, I think every person in the movie biz, right.
Speaker 1: Sorta has a huge pile of scripts and ideas and things that didn't get released.
Speaker 1: And when I, you know, things that, probably like maybe a hundred movies die in some fashion in order for one to actually get made.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So this is just, you know, what way to take one of those hundreds and put it into the world somehow in a published form.
Speaker 0: But I love this, this note from this interview with Keanu, cause the way the interviewer is like, I couldn't help, but think a lot about Wolverine long.
Speaker 0: Like, were you thinking about Wolverine?
Speaker 0: And he started Keanu Reeves response with, I mean, for me, it's one of my favorite characters.
Speaker 0: that a strong influence on me.
Speaker 0: It's impacted me, but we're also stepping into werewolves and vampires.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: So I do think that if there's any chance of adaptation, it would be like, uh, like an animated Netflix dealy kind of, you know, you could do something cool with.
Speaker 0: it could happen.
Speaker 0: You can, or I could see, you know, the tie in video game.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of other ways they could go.
Speaker 0: if they wanted to like have adjacent properties, the video game would be like Wario.
Speaker 1: You can't.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's just make it like a dynasty warriors, but you can't, you literally just can't die.
Speaker 0: And it's Wario like up the Chinese empire collapse.
Speaker 1: No, the whole, your goal is to die.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Try to die.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Well, all these guys are attacking you.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm trying to die.
Speaker 1: I'll let you know.
Speaker 1: I'd make it.
Speaker 1: You can't tell you.
Speaker 0: And if you quit the game, it ostensibly just keeps running.
Speaker 0: And when you come back, you're just laying there dead and you reform and like the clock has just moved forward.
Speaker 1: You can't fast forward when you're reforming.
Speaker 0: Maybe you're going to click a button to be reformed.
Speaker 0: Like when is the next point?
Speaker 0: I'll be reformed.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's come back in 12 hours and we can play.
Speaker 1: If you ever click that button and you know, you have to keep the game running for the 12 hours.
Speaker 0: Just make it one of those idlers.
Speaker 0: It's just him killing people and you just wait.
Speaker 0: You just get a kill count.
Speaker 1: Oh, it never ends.
Speaker 1: I don't.
Speaker 1: Number goes up and history progresses like civilization.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes, discussion, news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Sci-Tech Mondays, gaming Tuesdays, anime comic Wednesdays, and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution.
Speaker 1: 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night and the patron patrons for this episode of geek nights are Alan Joyce, Lincoln G dread lily, Tenderberry case.
Speaker 0: care makes music.
Speaker 0: Chris, the dog, Chris Reimer, Clinton, Walton decks, Finn, Joel Hayes, Rebecca Dunn, Sam Erickson, Shervin, Vaughn, horrible, stop all the downloading and a bunch of people who have wisely changed their pledges to $1.
Speaker 0: They can still access this custom RSS feed.
Speaker 0: I leave you with something that I hope you're familiar with.
Speaker 0: And those of you are probably saw this coming a mile away.
Speaker 0: You could come with me.
Speaker 0: My love for you is like a truck berserker.
Speaker 0: Do you want to making berserker berserker?
Speaker 1: Did he just say?