Speaker 0: It's Thursday, August 3rd, 2023.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 1: And I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is the Geek Nights Book Club.
Speaker 0: Tonight we are talking about This is How You Lose the Time War by Amal El-Motar and Max Gladstone.
Speaker 1: Let's do this!
Speaker 0: Yeah, we were going to do the show a little earlier, but I had a work thing that came up, and because, one, we didn't have a good Wednesday show idea, and two, we don't want to cover, or really give any promotion to, any struck works that would cross the picket line of SAG-AFTRA.
Speaker 1: I don't watch any struck works to begin with.
Speaker 0: You don't watch anything.
Speaker 1: No, that's right.
Speaker 1: Television is not... It's weird, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, on the one hand, I'm like, "Yeah, way to go, all you writers and actors.
Speaker 1: You deserve it.
Speaker 1: You're doing all this hard, creative work, and you're so talented, and you should get paid, and all those Hollywood execs are taking all your money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm totally 100% on your side.
Speaker 1: You think we're so talented and great, do you watch any of our work?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: I mean, meanwhile, you did... None of it entertains me, personally.
Speaker 0: You did go see Asteroid City in the theater.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, that's, you know, the director was there, right?
Speaker 1: And that's the kind of thing that I actually do like, right?
Speaker 0: Yep, and actually, you know, the thing I would have reviewed on Wednesday...
Speaker 1: Television is the thing I mostly don't like.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but, uh, Nimona is not television.
Speaker 0: That is a movie.
Speaker 0: It just happened to be on Netflix because it was saved from the whole blue sky being destroyed by capitalism situation, and they somehow actually made the movie instead of just burying it forever.
Speaker 0: But, uh, anyway, this is an experiment to... If we don't have a good idea for a show, and we have a good topic for a different day of the week, we're gonna change out the Geek Night schedule a little bit.
Speaker 1: I mean, do we have to, you know, I mean, people didn't even notice when we switched from, like, you know, this was supposed to be a Tuesday/Thursday week, and now it's a Monday/Wednesday week.
Speaker 0: We kept the Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday, Thursday alternating schedule consistent for so many years.
Speaker 0: It's shocking.
Speaker 1: It flipped one time, but Google Calendar is what made it consistent, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, I can just look at the calendar and say, "Oh, this is a X week," right?
Speaker 1: But I guess nobody, nobody's even listening, so who even gives a shit if we stick to that anymore, right?
Speaker 1: It's, we'll just, you know, we'll do no more than two episodes a week of whatever days we happen to do, you know?
Speaker 0: Yeah, there are the listener and the listener.
Speaker 0: We got two right now.
Speaker 0: Three!
Speaker 0: A third one appeared in the livestream.
Speaker 1: It's the same person with three, two sock puppet accounts.
Speaker 0: Well, it's tricky because the book clubs definitely get the lowest engagement of anything we do.
Speaker 1: That's why they're the most necessary.
Speaker 1: People ain't fucking reading any books.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You know, good or bad, read a book.
Speaker 1: Jesus Christ.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know.
Speaker 0: What bothers me the most is they don't even have a super long tail.
Speaker 0: Like, people read the book and come back to it.
Speaker 0: We're going to keep doing them because I like doing them, but you guys got to read.
Speaker 1: This book is so short, too.
Speaker 1: It's not even, like, you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's sort of the first thing.
Speaker 0: So, this is how you lose the time war.
Speaker 0: As, you know, we discussed when we announced it, Scott was the one who brought this to the table.
Speaker 1: Okay, so I chose because it was, when we chose the books, it was June in Pride Month.
Speaker 1: It's now no longer Pride Month, but, you know, Pride is all the time.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 1: And, you know, so I chose two LGBTQ+-ish novels for Rym to select from, right?
Speaker 1: And he selected the one that was in a recent news because a person by the name of Bigelas Dickolas Wolfwood, which is a name where anyone with that name must be a trustworthy, immaculate individual.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's a rare, perfect username.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so that person going by that name suggested this book, hyped it up on the internets, and many people concurred and obeyed and such, and so we said, "Well, something must be going on there," right?
Speaker 1: That's a thing that we do is, like, you know, we hear about a thing, right?
Speaker 1: I think the first time we talked about this on Geek Nights was, like, the Madoka days, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Which was already a really long time ago.
Speaker 1: When Madoka came out, it was like, you know, I knew there was an anime called Madoka Magica, and I didn't know anything about it.
Speaker 1: I just knew there was an anime by that name.
Speaker 1: But then I kept hearing the name come up again and again and again, and I said, "Well, if this name keeps coming up and it didn't just disappear, there must be something to it,".
Speaker 1: and I checked it out.
Speaker 1: So this book, it just kept coming up, right?
Speaker 1: And it came up big with, you know, Biggles Dickles.
Speaker 1: there's recommendation, which was viral, I guess would be the term.
Speaker 0: It was surprisingly viral.
Speaker 0: Like, that one short internet thread caused so many different communities to talk about this book, even if they didn't know what generated that buzz.
Speaker 1: Yep, and so it's such a short book.
Speaker 1: You know, I made it one of the two choices.
Speaker 1: Rym selected it, not the other one, and it was so, you know, we read it to see what the hype was, and so here we are.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I will say right now, you know, of course this is the Geek Nights Book Club, so we're gonna talk about this book between two people who have read it and know that we've both read it, and we are assuming that you have also read it, so not even, I don't care about spoilers anymore.
Speaker 0: Like, if you listen to a book club podcast and you're mad about a spoiler, that's on you.
Speaker 0: But I would say more that if this is hard to follow or you're confused, that's your fault for not reading the book.
Speaker 1: -The best--.
Speaker 1: -Yeah, obviously.
Speaker 0: Like, one of the best things about reading a book at the same time as someone else is being able to discuss the things that happen in the book or the meta around the book.
Speaker 0: You can talk about the book knowing that you both come from the same first principles or at least this basic understanding of what happened in the book.
Speaker 0: As we saw way back when our entire collected crew kind of read The Prince of Nothing books around the same few years, and thus it just became this ongoing, constant conversation.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, I don't know what it is, but there's something about-- I actually don't really get any value from going online to media publications or journalists and hearing what they have to say about various works that have come out, video games, movies, whatever.
Speaker 1: But if I've already seen the work in question or played the game in question, suddenly what they have to say is like-- Yeah, I don't care
Speaker 0: what some nerd said about Evangelion before I saw it, but after I saw it, I weirdly really wanted to hear what nerds had to say about it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I don't know what that is, but it's like, you know, this book, thankfully, this is a podcast, so if you gain any value from this for some strange reason, if you read the book at any point in the rest of your life, this will still be here waiting for you to listen to.
Speaker 0: So I liked it.
Speaker 0: It's not a perfect book.
Speaker 0: Some of the hype was justified, but also some of the hype was-- I feel like some of the hype came from people who never read a Bradbury at any point and have never encountered this kind of science fiction before.
Speaker 1: I mean, I think I'm in agreement in that I was disappointed, not that my expectation was high, but I do not think the quality of the book met the hype level, but that's not to say the book had no positive or redeeming qualities.
Speaker 1: I think, not for the shortness of the book, it may have been worse off, but--
Speaker 0: The book definitely benefits from the fact that this is a couple hour read, like three hours tops, unless you have difficulty reading,
Speaker 1: and
Speaker 0: what I got out of it relative to how little time it took from my life made it an upper-tier book, whereas if it had been longer, it would have been a lower-tier book.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I have no regrets about reading this book, but it's like if someone were to start a discussion about the book, I'd be like, "Eh, it's all right, but it does not meet the hype level that you have heard in my
Speaker 1: opinion.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, but at the same time, we are jaded older people in that we've read a lot of books over the years, just like we've seen a lot of anime and seen a lot of movies, and to even get my attention takes a lot now that I'm 40.
Speaker 1: Okay, so here's the deal with the book, right?
Speaker 1: There is a time war, as the title would suggest, and the main combatants in the time war are two time and space-spanning civilizations.
Speaker 1: One of them is sort of a cyber hive mind deal, right?
Speaker 1: I guess it would be a cyber-- What's the word for it?
Speaker 1: Singularity, yeah, right?
Speaker 1: And the other one is more of a biological hive mind.
Speaker 0: A biological singularity.
Speaker 1: Right, so basically there are these two singularities of intelligence, but within them, there are still individual beings that have independent thought and whatnot.
Speaker 1: It's not a complete single entity, right?
Speaker 1: It's just like a colony of bees, right?
Speaker 1: Just the cyber bee colony and the literal elf bee colony, I guess, right?
Speaker 1: And so there's a time war happening.
Speaker 1: So basically there are trained, highly skilled agents working for both of these groups, societies fighting each other, basically traveling throughout history and manipulating history to change the future, and they keep doing it back and forth to each other in an increasingly elaborate fashion so that the future that each one of these two different societies wants will be the one that comes about.
Speaker 0: So from a naive perspective, this is an existential war.
Speaker 0: Regardless of if you sympathize with one or both of the sides or the people involved, one side, much like in some anime we've seen over the years, is going to be destroyed utterly if they lose this war.
Speaker 0: This is an existential fight.
Speaker 1: Right, so one hive mind just simply won't-- --exist, right?
Speaker 1: The other one won.
Speaker 0: Now, from a meta perspective that I-- I guess I'm not going to speculate on whether or not the authors intended any of the things we're talking about.
Speaker 0: I'm not talking about this from a 100%.
Speaker 0: The author is dead, God is dead, we have words to work with.
Speaker 1: I learned some stuff about the-- but anyway, keep going.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I don't want to presume whether or not they intended any of these readings or ideas, but there's definitely a meta concept that if these societies are fighting, then they can coexist and do coexist directly.
Speaker 0: And because time travel is possible, then time travel is irrelevant.
Speaker 0: There's no such thing as time travel, there is just one long system of interactions, and in that system there is a state where both of these societies do in fact exist.
Speaker 0: Which implies that the war is stupid and pointless, or it implies that the war is necessary, because the war is the only thing that keeps these societies existing together at the same time.
Speaker 0: I don't think that was quite the intent or the point of the book.
Speaker 1: There also don't seem to be any other societies.
Speaker 1: I guess those are the ones that have completely lost the time war.
Speaker 0: There do not seem to be any other possibilities in the observed universe as far as this book is portrayed.
Speaker 1: It's hard to tell if it's even on one planet or multiple planets.
Speaker 0: It's definitely not just on one planet, they talk about multiple timelines though.
Speaker 0: But they definitely imply that Earth is hyper pivotal to all of this.
Speaker 1: And so, with the two societies, one of them has an agent, Red, who's from the Cyber Society, and Blue is from the Elfie Bio Society, and I believe that it's Blue that sends the first letter, right?
Speaker 1: I had to keep looking this up every time.
Speaker 0: Well, that is actually a hard question to answer, sort of, because it's a time travel story, and of course, there's a Final Fantasy 1 garland-style time loop that occurs, and as a result, Red initiated the situation Blue was in.
Speaker 0: that led to Blue writing the first letter down the road, is what I would say.
Speaker 0: Meaning, who wrote the first letter is an impossible question to answer.
Speaker 1: Of course, but at the start of the book, the word for it was, what, is it epistolary?
Speaker 1: I keep having to look up this work, right?
Speaker 1: Yes, epistolary format, which is when you tell a story with letters.
Speaker 1: So this isn't actually completely epistolary as some other works are, which are just letters between characters and you just read their correspondence and that tells the story.
Speaker 0: Which I would say this book would have been better if it had stuck to that and not mixed.
Speaker 1: I agree, but basically you get a brief one or two page chapter of a character doing their mission that they're currently on, and then that character receives a letter, and then you read the letter the character received in the next couple pages, and then it switches to the character who wrote that letter, and they're on some mission, and then they receive the response to the previous letter, and you read that.
Speaker 1: So it's sort of this alternating between brief narrations of missions and the letters.
Speaker 1: But, as Rym just said, it would be better off if it was just the letters, and I agree, because quite often the missions don't really add much besides setting, dressing, and flavor, right?
Speaker 0: They do add some important but subtle color to the societies, but I don't know, again, how intentional that was, but also most of the plot is in the letters, right?
Speaker 1: That the plot is not advancing so much in the part where they're on some mission.
Speaker 1: You can't even really tell the overall status of the time war in the mission part, except for this one big mission where they meet and fight in the middle somewhere.
Speaker 1: But on the majority of the mission parts, it's just like describing some mission in a cool way, like setting a cool fantasy or sci-fi scene up just to be cool.
Speaker 0: The missions do add something very important, though, because they portray the extreme nature of the violence and pain that is involved in these actual fights.
Speaker 0: that is not referred to materially in really any of the letters to near the end.
Speaker 0: So on one hand, like reading this, it is hard for me to see the person who, throughout the book, is consistently thinking the red side is a better society to live in, because the blue side is often portrayed as being more pleasant in a variety of ways.
Speaker 1: Well, I think there's just a natural tendency of, you know, sort of a ghibli-esque thing to always portray, you know, biology, nature as good and technology and industry as more evil, right?
Speaker 1: It's like token-esque situations where the elves are good and the orcs all have machines and the elves don't really, they have magic or something, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, that's just a common trope.
Speaker 1: And I don't know how much the existence of that trope in your mind is painting that, versus the book is also agreeing with the trope and trying to paint the same thing.
Speaker 1: I sort of viewed both of the societies as sort of equal in terms of goodness and evilness, right?
Speaker 1: The mother of the blue side didn't seem super benevolent to me, right?
Speaker 0: But there's a broader point about that.
Speaker 0: that is Evangelion-adjacent and related to a scientific concept of self-domestication that I want to address later in our conversation.
Speaker 1: There's very, you know, what's it called, instrumentality stuff going on, right?
Speaker 0: But I feel like if we talk about that now, it's going to derail our whole conversation, so I'll say I'm going to derail the train later.
Speaker 0: But the red side is often portrayed as more directly violence.
Speaker 0: But the blue side, like very subtly, whenever the blue side is doing stuff, it's always things like, oh yeah, they made sure World War II happened because you need that, like that's natural that that had to happen.
Speaker 0: Like blue is killing as many people as red, maybe even more people.
Speaker 0: And blue is often the one destroying a city or destroying an entire civilization to prevent them from accomplishing some goal.
Speaker 0: Or, like, making sure the zombie apocalypse happens in the alternate Russian front of World War II.
Speaker 0: Like, I think I want to say one of the stories specifically implies that blue prevented Hitler from being killed on purpose.
Speaker 1: Could, uh, yeah, I don't remember.
Speaker 0: It's hard to say because an annoyance with the writing in this book is that it makes very specific references to pop culture, but all, like, broad pop culture.
Speaker 0: Like, it references songs from the 70s and 80s, and it references television shows from, like, between the 50s and, like, modern times.
Speaker 0: But the references, and this is, I mean, no disrespect to the authors, they were done in the same ham-fisted manner that Ready Player One did.
Speaker 0: The references use proper nouns and assume that you know what the fuck those proper nouns are.
Speaker 0: And if you don't, you will not make the reference.
Speaker 0: In the same way that Chesterton and The Man Who Was Thursday, I still think it was a great book, but it had a lot of specific proper noun references that you would only get if you were deeply enmeshed in the, like, Christian societal thought and literature of the era.
Speaker 0: And if you don't know those references, authors, and stories, you'll just miss all that.
Speaker 0: You'll miss all that in this book, too.
Speaker 0: And if you miss it, there's entire sets of sentences that are just meaningless and worthless to you as a reader.
Speaker 1: So the other thing that bothered me, right, is that, you know, you're alternating between red, blue, red, blue, right, as you go throughout the book.
Speaker 1: And I learned, so I don't know how true this is, but it's, as someone said, it was from, like, interviews, or so it's like, it seems like I have no reason to just believe that this is true, is that the two authors, one was writing the red and the other author was writing the blue.
Speaker 1: And so you would think them two authors being two different people, right, would naturally have, like, a different voice in the text, right?
Speaker 1: And especially when they're writing different characters.
Speaker 1: But I just couldn't tell, a lot of chapters, I just couldn't tell.
Speaker 1: And I had to, like, flip backwards until I could find the word red or the word blue to figure out who was the current chapter.
Speaker 0: I had the same problem.
Speaker 1: And it's like, I kept flipping back to the beginning, like, who wrote the first letter?
Speaker 1: It was the blue, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, shouldn't, they should have been two extremely different voices, right?
Speaker 1: So that you could really tell immediately which character was which and who was doing what.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, maybe that was intentional, but it really, I don't know, that did not work.
Speaker 0: It really worked for me.
Speaker 0: And it's hard to say if an editor was involved in that, like, normalizing the voice.
Speaker 0: It would have worked better structurally, because I'm a big fan of form and function being unified, if the writing style of the two sets of stories started radically different and converged to have the same voice toward the end of the book.
Speaker 0: Because that would have fit with how it actually goes down.
Speaker 1: That would have matched the plot, yeah.
Speaker 0: And that's the kind of thing that...
Speaker 1: You could say that it foreshadowed the plot with the voice being the same, but it really made it harder to read.
Speaker 1: It's like, for such a short book, that slowed me down a lot.
Speaker 1: I could have finished even faster if I didn't have to keep flipping back.
Speaker 0: I would say that is the kind of thing that differentiates a B-tier novel from an A-tier novel.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: S-tier is, and it also makes you think about something profound that you've never thought about before.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Which, this does not make you think about anything you've never thought about before.
Speaker 1: No, that's another thing I gotta criticize here, right?
Speaker 0: For us, it didn't.
Speaker 0: But again, if someone has never read a lot of science fiction, or hasn't read a lot of books, I think, much like The Matrix, this was brand new concepts to a lot of people who read it.
Speaker 1: The thing is, I don't see the science fiction parts as being the primary part of this book.
Speaker 1: I think the primary part of this book is literally just another Romeo and Juliet story, right?
Speaker 1: There's two people in love, and they can't get together because, you know, they're from the opposite worlds, right?
Speaker 1: They're from a Hatfield and a McCoy, right?
Speaker 1: Or whatever, right?
Speaker 0: I actually see it as a science fiction story.
Speaker 1: They're from a Sharks and a Jets, and they can't, so they gotta be separated.
Speaker 0: I think it's actually, it is a very science fiction story, and my argument here is that reading this, we've got two singularity civilizations, and now I guess we're gonna derail.
Speaker 0: An instrumentality-style civilization like that, a singularity, and if you're not familiar with these concepts, I'd suggest...
Speaker 1: It means that all the conscious sentient beings in the society have sort of merged their consciousness together to some degree, right?
Speaker 0: Now, it can be more complex and subtle than that, so an example would be, a very specific example, a real example that is being studied by real scientists today and is a hot topic in sociology.
Speaker 0: Individual humans arguably have agency.
Speaker 0: I am a human, Scott is a human, you are all humans listening to this.
Speaker 0: I hope someday a non-human listens to this.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna discuss if free will exists or not right now, right?
Speaker 0: Nope, we're not.
Speaker 0: We're avoiding that part.
Speaker 0: So, we have free will, we're agents, we make decisions, we live in the world, but we are a collection of a bunch of smaller, complex machines that are making decisions but don't necessarily have free will.
Speaker 0: Cells in our body don't have any meaningful say on what our body does.
Speaker 1: That we know of.
Speaker 0: I mean, they have input into it, but they are suppressed and subsumed into the causality of what our brains decide they're going to do.
Speaker 0: So, imagine a society, a country.
Speaker 0: The United States is a great example.
Speaker 0: The United States is arguably acting in the world as an entity that is larger and more powerful than any human and often acts to a degree disentangled from the will of any particular individual human.
Speaker 0: The collected decisions of the people within that society and the power structures within those people are what decide what that society does.
Speaker 0: If you take that to the ultimate extreme, humans in a society become analogous to cells in a human.
Speaker 0: And domestication is a concept that leads to this.
Speaker 0: So, in this book, we have two individuals who were not at a complete and total singularity.
Speaker 0: These red and blue have not been turned into mitochondria yet.
Speaker 0: They still think and feel and have agency and make decisions.
Speaker 0: But they are in mutually exclusive societies that are themselves almost like two different meta-beings.
Speaker 0: It's like two different meta-humans that are constructed of humans.
Speaker 0: And these two individual humans within those structures want to continue to exist.
Speaker 0: And they've met each other and want to continue to exist apart from their own societies.
Speaker 0: And it's a struggle between instrumentality and individuality.
Speaker 0: Oh shit, it's the same story as Evangelion.
Speaker 1: But yeah, it's a Romeo and Juliet story, right?
Speaker 1: They start writing each other.
Speaker 1: The initial letters between each other are very antagonistic, right?
Speaker 0: If they're trash-shocking, like, "Yo, dawg, you can't beat
Speaker 0: me."
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: And then they, you know, surprise.
Speaker 1: They fall in love.
Speaker 1: And it's important to note that they are clearly both women.
Speaker 1: This is a lesbian love story, right?
Speaker 1: And I think for a lot of people, unsurprisingly, that's a major selling point.
Speaker 1: It's like if you're an LGBTQ+ person, right?
Speaker 1: Many that I know, it's like whenever they get any representation, like fucking anywhere, they're just so happy about it.
Speaker 1: I would say anything.
Speaker 0: Any work that doesn't center the archetypical societal experience.
Speaker 1: Or does it leave it to vagueness, right?
Speaker 1: They're like, "No, this is absolutely..." Right?
Speaker 1: And in fact, this was optioned for television, I think.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it'll happen.
Speaker 0: This could be adapted into a TV show or a movie pretty well if you loosely adapted it.
Speaker 1: But they said on Wikipedia, it says that the genders of the characters in any such adaptation are not up for negotiation.
Speaker 0: That is important because you know what else did that?
Speaker 0: Steven Universe.
Speaker 1: This is all in on being explicitly gay, right?
Speaker 1: Big time.
Speaker 0: So there is an allegory within this that I think is very poignant to current society as well.
Speaker 0: Take, for example, the current war between Russia and Ukraine.
Speaker 0: Nations can be at war with each other, but think about in all of history, like in World War I with the Christmas truce, the individual people fighting that war are separate from the societies that are fighting that war.
Speaker 0: And these are two soldiers who meet each other on the battlefield, and while they may have a lot of reasons to be sympathetic toward and fight for the societies that spawn them, they also don't have any particularly good reason to fight between each other as individuals.
Speaker 0: Which is a classic--.
Speaker 1: Other than that, their orders make them, right?
Speaker 1: Because they're not quite just soldiers on a battlefield, it's more like James Bond and the enemy agent, where they're directly against each other and they're such high-level agents that actually fall in love with the other agent.
Speaker 0: But they are soldiers on a battlefield just at a different level with a different set of tools in the same way that during World War I--.
Speaker 1: But if two people are just infantry and two opposing armies and they fall in love, that's not really a huge scandal.
Speaker 1: Where if you're a real CIA agent and you actually get it on with the Russian agent for real, that's going to be like treason level.
Speaker 1: Whereas if you're in the infantry in Ukraine and you're in love with someone from the infantry in Russia, that's not really treason level.
Speaker 1: It's not great, but it's not--.
Speaker 0: I guess what I want to focus on more is this idea that there's a very human sentiment and a very human emotional problem around.
Speaker 0: societies will have conflicts that are separate from and independent from the individual people that comprise those societies and the people lose a lot of agency in terms of how they navigate those conflicts and fight them with the weapons available to them because, you know, we talked about another book a long time ago, Use of Weapons.
Speaker 0: This is a book of two people passing a chair back and forth.
Speaker 1: I mean, you could also, you know, if you look further into the LGBTQ angle, right, you could imagine that both of these sort of singularity-ish societies, right, are conservative societies, right?
Speaker 1: And so it's like they're worried about dying, you know, getting killed by their commander, whatever they have, right, mother, whatever it is, because of the traitorism.
Speaker 1: But it's like it could also be viewed as, yeah, you're going to get killed because, you know, you come from a conservative society that doesn't believe in this, right?
Speaker 1: It's also, you know, like the found family angle, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you found your family with this other person, not with the society you grew up in, but you still have feelings for the society that you grew up in even though it mistreated you so badly.
Speaker 0: I know you didn't watch it to the end, but Centaurworld, because it's a short show, the actual very specific meta-plot of that is that the warriors, like the horse and the rider character, the warriors, they're only warriors because of the circumstance of the society they live in.
Speaker 0: And when they are both introduced to a different environment where they're not forced to fight and forced to fill this role, they become very different people because what they truly wanted to be was not what the society they lived in allowed them to be.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So, a completely separate thing.
Speaker 1: The thing that I actually liked the most about this book, of all things, right, is that there's a particular feeling, at least I've experienced this feeling, I'm sure other people have as well, of when you're communicating with someone you care about, right, you want to hear from them, right, but you don't hear from them often, right, and you're awaiting hearing from them, right, and then you actually like hear from them, right, and it's like, oh, right, and it's like.
Speaker 1: this book encapsulates that feeling, I think, maybe better than any book I've read.
Speaker 0: I think back to ancient times when I would be in like high school and ICQ was open and certain people on my contact list, you know, I was a high school kid and I was a nerd, were people I might have had some affection toward that.
Speaker 0: I didn't talk to that often.
Speaker 0: And when certain sounds played on the computer, that meant that one of those people who has not reached out to me in a while has sent me a message, and that feeling is embedded in my soul from the year 1997.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And so, in this book, right, it's like, you know, these characters, it's like, you know, once they're in love, it's like they're waiting so hard to get a letter, right, and then it's actually kind of fun, I think, the way the letters come, it's always like, ah, yes, the person put the letter in a gust of wind, and that way their own societies would never detect that, but somehow they knew the other person would be there at that moment to feel that gust of wind, know that it wasn't a normal gust of wind, and find the message in it every single time they never missed.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, and it's like just, it must have just been fun to come up with all the different ways to deliver the message, right, and it was fun to read them, you know, and it showed, I guess, how strong of their secret agent powers were, that they could pull that off every time.
Speaker 0: Though, along those lines, too, from the beginning, like before I got to the end, this is a short book, my first suspicion was that red and blue are, in fact, the same person, and the time travel loop, like it is the same person, end to end,
Speaker 1: and
Speaker 0: that is almost true, actually, when you get to the end, but not in the way that I expected it to be.
Speaker 0: My second guess was that the seeker that was following right around, I assumed that that was one of the two of them, but I wasn't sure which, and I was right about that.
Speaker 1: That's what I thought also, and we were both right about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it made the most sense, and I felt like it was foreshadowed by the first letter that was titled "Burn Before Reading," because the messages get burned before they're read by the seeker every time.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But yeah, so there's this seeker character who's basically, after every letter is, you know, read by the recipient, the seeker, right, just sort of eats it, and like gobbles up the remains, and it turns out that the seeker is read, right?
Speaker 1: I didn't get that wrong.
Speaker 1: Right, and basically by consuming all these letters, you know, Red is absorbing, you know, Blue into herself, and being some sort of combined being, and then once Red has enough Blue in her, she is then able to infiltrate, you know, the center hive area of the bio-society, right, and bring things to their climactic conclusion at the end of the
Speaker 0: book.
Speaker 0: Now this also addresses a concept that, again, is brought up in such works as Evangelion, and also a lot of science fiction, that there's the version of you that's in your own head, and the version of you that exists as a sort of simulacra in the heads of everyone you've ever interacted with, and if those simulacra are high enough fidelity, they could effectively be equivalent to the real you, because whatever's going on inside your head, your only impact on the world is how you interact and communicate with the outside world.
Speaker 0: If you communicate with someone deeply, and with enough detail, you could theoretically create a version of yourself in their head that is as high fidelity as your appearance in the real world, and be predictive, and that is not explored too deeply, but that is definitely implied that that is a big part of how Blue and Red survived and were reborn.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, you basically get your typical time loop scenario, right?
Speaker 1: Red and Blue merge into one being, effectively, and then Red goes to the birth of Blue to ensure that Blue turns out the way Blue turns out.
Speaker 0: Which Chekhov's a fucking tree from the very beginning, when Blue's like, "Oh yeah, when I was a kid, I had a weird sickness, and it went away one day, and they checked me out, and I seemed fine, but that was weird, wasn't
Speaker 0: it?".
Speaker 0: I was like, "That was fucking Red, that's the entire plot right there, in that one sentence, you just told me everything about this
Speaker 0: book.".
Speaker 1: And that was not wrong.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I think, you know, while those positive aspects are there, I think, you know, what Rym said before about, you know, what it takes to be, you know, an S-tier book, right?
Speaker 1: Is like, make you think about something you had never even thought about before.
Speaker 1: It's like, this book doesn't do that really, at least.
Speaker 0: I think this book will do that, at a similar level to how-- For someone who hasn't read any books.
Speaker 0: Well yeah, in a similar level, and I don't mean this to disrespect Ray Bradbury, but he is important, and he has written many great things, but he also wrote a lot of okay things, like, to be brutally honest, sorry Ray.
Speaker 0: But I feel like it was about the same level of the average or median Ray Bradbury short story, in terms of introducing a concept to someone who may have never encountered it before.
Speaker 0: So if someone has never read any Bradbury, and this is the first book of about that level they read, I could see this introducing a lot of really important concepts.
Speaker 0: If I'd read this book when I was a kid, and then later in my life I read some of the lower tier Ray Bradburys, I'd be saying, "Wow, Bradbury just didn't tell me anything new.
Speaker 0: I didn't learn anything from this short
Speaker 0: story.".
Speaker 1: Well, the other thing is that, whether you learned anything or not, right, is anything in this book abstract?
Speaker 0: I didn't consider anything new that I hadn't already considered.
Speaker 1: Nothing in this book is really abstract, right?
Speaker 1: There's no questions of, like, what happened.
Speaker 1: It was all literal, like, this is what happened, right?
Speaker 1: It's fully explained, right?
Speaker 1: Just like, you know, the Christopher Nolan movies, right?
Speaker 1: He's hot right now again, right?
Speaker 1: It's the same reason I don't like his movies as much as everyone else's.
Speaker 0: He just kind of explains everything.
Speaker 0: That is what sort of bothers me in that it raises this idea of instrumentality and self-domestication and hive minds, but it doesn't interrogate that aspect deeply enough.
Speaker 1: It interrogates the relationship more.
Speaker 1: Right, well, it's fine to interrogate the relationship, but, like, what did it have to, you know, what is its argument?
Speaker 1: What's the argument that it's making about either the love story or the sci-fi story?
Speaker 1: It's like, I don't think it is making an argument.
Speaker 1: I think it's just literally telling this story, and it's like, there is no argument to be made.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like, here were these characters, they fell in love.
Speaker 1: It's like, what does this have to say?
Speaker 0: It could be arguing that if a sentient entity...
Speaker 1: Love conquers all?
Speaker 1: That's what Romeo and Juliet said the same thing.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know...
Speaker 0: If a sentient entity believes it still has agency, it should fight to retain that agency rather than being subsumed into a meta-structure like a society and being dissolved into a full singularity.
Speaker 0: That arguably the sentient or sapient actor has a vested interest in remaining sapient, even if that is to the detriment of the greater, and I'm making quote fingers, thing that it could create a society.
Speaker 0: Humans forming a singularity will arguably destroy a lot of the things that individual humans enjoy about being alive.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think it's definitely leaning harder on.
Speaker 1: the love conquers all, which is not a wrong message, right?
Speaker 1: Or a bad message is just not an interesting one and it's made in like half of books ever.
Speaker 0: I think it does make this bigger point.
Speaker 0: I just don't know how intentional that bigger point is.
Speaker 0: Because a slightly more eloquent, like elegantly written story would have been a little shorter and would have really woven.
Speaker 0: what is the argument it's making about singularities and instrumentality into that story.
Speaker 0: The fact that that is there, but not interrogated itself deeply, is what leaves me slightly unsatisfied.
Speaker 0: Because Evangelion, and I'm not saying Evangelion is the pinnacle of instrumentality works, but many works have explored that concept more deeply and forced me to give it more pause.
Speaker 0: This book did not at any point give me any significant pause.
Speaker 1: No, it was not paused by anything.
Speaker 1: It was just like, yep, that happened and that happened in the end.
Speaker 0: So I guess if this book blew your mind, go read five random Ray Bradbury short stories.
Speaker 0: They're like seven pages long, some of them.
Speaker 1: Go read something longer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but just read some Ray Bradbury and I'm just curious your thoughts.
Speaker 0: If this book didn't blow your mind, then I don't know, I guess you're pretty well read.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe.
Speaker 1: But yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, okay.
Speaker 1: So do we have anything else to say about this book?
Speaker 0: I actually don't have a lot else to say about it.
Speaker 1: I mean, it was really short.
Speaker 1: I mean, how else could we?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So to get back to the beginning, because traditionally, whoever's turn it is to bring the two offerings, the two options for the next book club, has to bring them to the table.
Speaker 0: And you said something very important at the very beginning.
Speaker 0: Why did you put this book on the list of two?
Speaker 0: Because, not just because of Pride, but also because you kept hearing about it.
Speaker 1: So there's a book you kept hearing about.
Speaker 0: So my two options for the next book club book are two books that in the last six months, I have been hearing about repeatedly in more than two of my social circles.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's a thing.
Speaker 0: These two books have come up so much that I kept a lid.
Speaker 0: These are the two.
Speaker 0: They have come up more than any other books outside of one specific social circle.
Speaker 1: Have I heard of them?
Speaker 0: Either Gideon the Ninth by Tamsin Ware or The Murderbot Diaries by Martha Wells.
Speaker 0: So The Murderbot Diaries.
Speaker 1: Have I heard of either one of these?
Speaker 0: So I'll give you a little bit of a brief pitch for both.
Speaker 0: The Murderbot Diaries is sci-fi.
Speaker 0: It is about a part robot, part human construct designed as a-.
Speaker 1: So The Murderbot Diaries is several books.
Speaker 1: Are you going to pick one of them or are you taking this box set deal?
Speaker 0: I see.
Speaker 0: I feel like we should just read the first bit.
Speaker 0: All systems read for the book club.
Speaker 1: Okay, one of seven.
Speaker 1: It's one of seven.
Speaker 1: If we want to go further, we can.
Speaker 1: These are both series, so we know whichever one, Rym's going to read the whole series.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, I'm going to read them all anyway, but the book club, we'll keep it confined.
Speaker 1: Gideon the Ninth is a three book series?
Speaker 0: Yup, we're reading the first one.
Speaker 0: So, but Murderbot Diaries is broadly about this murderbot, like a security unit that is a murder robot that's a human-robot hybrid of some kind.
Speaker 0: And it overrides its governor and develops independence and ostensibly free will.
Speaker 0: And what it does with that and whether or not it continues to be a murderbot and why.
Speaker 0: And this book has come up in surprising conversations among people I consider to be very smart that I am friends with.
Speaker 0: And I am very interested to see if this book lives up to some of the assertions I have heard about it from people you and I both know and trust.
Speaker 0: Gideon the Ninth has just come up over and over and over and over again.
Speaker 0: When I finally looked up what it's about, it's about...
Speaker 1: But the first line of the description on the internet says the emperor needs necromancers.
Speaker 0: Oh, and the star system dominicus.
Speaker 1: And the ninth necromancer needs a swordswoman.
Speaker 0: There are nine planets.
Speaker 0: Each of these nine planets is home to a great house, like Dune style, that practices its own school of necromancy.
Speaker 1: I see that.
Speaker 1: It's called the Locked Tomb series.
Speaker 1: Each book is someone the ninth.
Speaker 1: So the second book is Harrow the ninth and the third book is Nona the ninth.
Speaker 0: So space necromancy, already I am down, but I can't say that would be good.
Speaker 1: Space necromancy.
Speaker 0: So here's the rub.
Speaker 0: Gideon the Ninth was named one of the best books of 2019 by all of NPR, Vox, the New York Public Library, Wired, Polygon, Bustle, Paste, Book Riot, and Gizmodo Australia.
Speaker 1: That is a list.
Speaker 1: It says here that All Systems Red won the Hugo, Nebula, Alex, and Locus award in 2018.
Speaker 0: And you know who's...
Speaker 1: Gideon the Ninth won the Locus, Hugo, and Crawford award, but it was a finalist for a different Hugo award.
Speaker 0: Oh, I got even more for you.
Speaker 1: It was a finalist for two different Hugo awards, a Nebula, a Dragon, and a World Fantasy award.
Speaker 1: So they both have basically a big trophy chest.
Speaker 0: They both have equivalent gigantic trophy chests, but Gideon the Ninth is specifically publicly highly recommended by one of the authors of the book we just read and by the author of the Murderbot Diaries, Martha Wells.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: So there is a big confluence here.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling it seems likely we're going to read both of these at some point in life.
Speaker 0: I feel like that's true, but you have the unenviable task of deciding which of these reread as the next book club.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm looking here at all this data.
Speaker 0: You don't have to decide right now if you don't want to.
Speaker 1: No, no, I think I could decide right now.
Speaker 0: I do like the idea of trying to force the decision at the end of every book club.
Speaker 1: It's more fun that way.
Speaker 1: So, you know, I like a necromancer and I like a Murderbot.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: And it's like, it's like, Oh, should I eat this steak or the other steak?
Speaker 1: Oh, no.
Speaker 1: It's like, uh, but yeah, so according to the, on the one hand, what I think, you know, if you, it's hard to compare the quality levels, right?
Speaker 1: We can't be looking at that.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And we can't really be comparing how cool is necromancy versus how cool is Murderbots because space necromancy and Murderbots, that's equally cool.
Speaker 1: We can't compare that.
Speaker 1: And they both have a pile of awards.
Speaker 1: We can't use that to separate them.
Speaker 1: They both have a 4.2 on Goodreads.
Speaker 1: Can't separate them.
Speaker 1: One of them has 14,000 ratings on Amazon with a 4.5 score.
Speaker 1: The other one has 40,000 ratings on Amazon, which is a lot more ratings, but a 4.4 score, so 0.1 less.
Speaker 1: Um, I think the separator is going to be that one of these books on with Kindle unlimited is $0 so I don't have to go.
Speaker 1: I don't have to go to the library or pay money.
Speaker 1: And the other one on Kindle is a mere $2 and 50 cents.
Speaker 0: Considering I am ambivalent between these books, not in that I don't care in that I find them equally compelling.
Speaker 0: That's better than a coin flip.
Speaker 0: That's how you're going to choose.
Speaker 1: Alright, so the $0 book on Kindle unlimited, for those of you who I guess use Kindles, for everyone else just go to the library and it'll still be $0, is the Murderbot one.
Speaker 1: It is $0.
Speaker 0: Alright, then the next Geek Nights Book Club book will be The Murderbot Diaries All Systems Red by Martha Wells.
Speaker 1: Read for free at the library or Kindle.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And the Patreon patrons for the Geek Nights Book Club tonight are Alan Joyce, Linki G, Jared, Lily Tenebrae, Case Cairn, Mix Music, Chris Haddad, Clinton Walton, Dex, Finn, Joel Hayes, Rebecca Dunne, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Horrell, and a ton of people who are not saying, they are asking me not to say their names.
Speaker 0: I'm real hungry and real tired.
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah, stay tuned for regularly scheduled, but possibly rotating days of Geek Nights for the foreseeable future.
Speaker 0: With the tiny extra caveat that I might have to go to Germany for a week, uh, in a few weeks, and if that happens, there will definitely be no Geek Nights that week.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I leave you, tonight, with...