Speaker 1: It's Monday, March 13th, 2023.
Speaker 1: I'm Rem.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight we are talking about e-waste and old tech and what to do about it.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So yeah, there wasn't Geek Nights last week because I was in London for work doing a bunch of stuff.
Speaker 0: Going to London.
Speaker 1: It's, uh, I do post that Snatch GIF in the internal chat every time I have to go to London.
Speaker 1: It's kind of a thing.
Speaker 0: I mean, if I went to London, I would post it also.
Speaker 1: And every time, nobody has any idea what it's referencing and I have to explain it over and over again.
Speaker 1: Nobody's seen Snatch.
Speaker 1: Nobody knows that movie.
Speaker 1: I don't know how, but that's how it is.
Speaker 1: But it's an interesting time in London.
Speaker 1: I went to a conference.
Speaker 1: The con was as big as pre-COVID times.
Speaker 1: It was just completely packed and business as usual in London.
Speaker 0: Compared to New York.
Speaker 1: So far I seem good.
Speaker 1: I seem fine despite spending a week.
Speaker 0: I'm feeling a little like I want to go outside because I see the number is in the hundreds instead of the thousands it's been in.
Speaker 1: For a couple of months we've been doing indoor dining, but we avoid places that are crowded.
Speaker 0: But I feel like I could just go wherever now.
Speaker 1: I went to a multi-thousand person conference and literally zero people masked at this thing at any point.
Speaker 1: I gave some talks and so far I seem fine and we have no word of anyone getting COVID from it.
Speaker 1: So we'll see.
Speaker 0: It's clearly far from eliminated.
Speaker 0: There's immunocompromised people out there.
Speaker 0: There's just one more thing for them to worry about in addition to all the other things.
Speaker 1: Indoor dining you can't wear a mask because you're taking it off to eat.
Speaker 1: But I do still wear my mask specifically when I'm on public transport or when I'm in the public areas of an airport.
Speaker 1: Because the airport feels like there's so many people from so many places the odds are just higher.
Speaker 1: And on the subway the air is actually really shitty down there anyway.
Speaker 1: So wearing an N95 on the New York subway is probably good for you even if you're not worried about COVID.
Speaker 0: It's not like it doesn't cost you anything to wear.
Speaker 1: It's not like I'm talking to strangers on the subway anyway.
Speaker 1: If anything it makes me feel more likely not to talk to me though.
Speaker 0: I've been wearing it outside just because it keeps my face warm when it's cold.
Speaker 1: I actually never wore them outside unless I was in a dense crowd at any point.
Speaker 0: Sometimes my face is cold.
Speaker 1: I got a beard.
Speaker 1: My face never gets cold.
Speaker 0: My face is cold.
Speaker 1: You have the cold sensitivity of a 90 year old and you've had that for as long as I've known you.
Speaker 1: And that has not changed.
Speaker 0: It's cold.
Speaker 1: So yeah there's a bunch of news.
Speaker 1: We're not doing a tech news roundup.
Speaker 1: Sorry listener.
Speaker 1: If you have any complaints about the low frequency of our tech news roundups.
Speaker 1: Well Scott is the dire taskmaster who says I can only do one a year.
Speaker 1: So take it up with him.
Speaker 0: You did two in 2021 which means you took a low nap in 2022.
Speaker 1: That's not the fault of me doing the tech news roundup.
Speaker 1: That is the fault of you the regulator failing to enforce our policies.
Speaker 0: If anything I might not be your fault that you didn't come into work that day.
Speaker 0: But I'm still going to charge you a PTO.
Speaker 0: So you accrued.
Speaker 0: It's been a year since 2022.
Speaker 0: So there is now one roundup accrued.
Speaker 1: We'll do a tech news roundup in April.
Speaker 1: It's coming.
Speaker 0: You can just accrue if you just wait until 20, 30 something.
Speaker 0: You'll be able to do a roundup the whole year long if you accrue enough roundups.
Speaker 1: Is Twit even still podcasting?
Speaker 1: Did we outlast them?
Speaker 0: I think it is.
Speaker 0: Yeah I don't know.
Speaker 1: Let's see.
Speaker 1: I'm going to look it up right now.
Speaker 1: Tech podcast from people you trust.
Speaker 1: This Week in Tech.
Speaker 1: Twit.tv.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure it's still around, right?
Speaker 1: What if it even has the same people on it?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Silicon Valley Bank collapsed.
Speaker 0: It's still going.
Speaker 1: They started April 17, 2005.
Speaker 1: And they're still going at their same rate.
Speaker 1: They only started a couple months before we went public.
Speaker 1: And actually they went public after we started doing Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: So a little news before we get into the news.
Speaker 1: In New York City, as you know, we have one of the oldest subway networks on Earth.
Speaker 1: We also have the best subway network on Earth.
Speaker 1: And I say this having used the subways in a lot of countries around the world.
Speaker 0: It's like if you look at your scoring rubric, they're not first.
Speaker 0: New York isn't first in every category.
Speaker 1: Oh no.
Speaker 1: Cleanliness, we are like near the bottom.
Speaker 0: Train technology.
Speaker 0: We are in bad situations in a lot of the places on the scorecard.
Speaker 0: But the total score, we're in first place.
Speaker 1: Because you've got to understand, I've got to remind people.
Speaker 1: Because even in London, people just don't realize this.
Speaker 1: And they think it's insane that we do this.
Speaker 1: The New York City subway never stops.
Speaker 1: It runs 24/7.
Speaker 1: And it could be 3
Speaker 1: a.m.,
Speaker 1: 45 a.m.
Speaker 1: on like Christmas Day.
Speaker 1: On the least used, shittiest subway line in the city.
Speaker 1: And within 15 minutes, a train's going to come and get you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you might say, well, Tokyo's got to be the number one.
Speaker 0: And it's like, oh, it's up there.
Speaker 0: It's up there.
Speaker 0: But they've got like five different train companies.
Speaker 0: And you never know which one to use.
Speaker 0: I'm sure the people who live there, it's fine, right?
Speaker 1: No, the people who live there complain, too.
Speaker 1: And also, the last time we were there, we had a pass to ride a city-run bus.
Speaker 1: And we got on a bus that showed up at the city bus stop around the time we expected the bus.
Speaker 1: But it was some private bus, and then we had to pay because it wasn't covered by the city pass.
Speaker 1: So New York City has for a long time been working on new subway cars.
Speaker 1: We talked about it on Geek Nights a bunch of times.
Speaker 1: The first of them are on the A train, like the A train in New York.
Speaker 1: If you're lucky, you will be on one of the brand new subway cars in New York City subway.
Speaker 1: We have not had new subway cars like this in a long time.
Speaker 0: Well, I think we have had them.
Speaker 0: But what happens is basically, when the MTA gets money, they put an order for subway cars, right?
Speaker 0: The subway cars show up, but they don't order enough cars to replace every train in the whole subway system.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that alone would cost more than the 10-year budget of most of the rest of the cities in America.
Speaker 0: One train car is over a million dollars, and a train is several of those, right?
Speaker 0: It depends on which line it is.
Speaker 0: But what they do is they'll order enough for one line.
Speaker 0: And then whichever line has the oldest trains, which right now is the 1 and the A, I think.
Speaker 1: The C, I think, actually has the worst trains in the subway.
Speaker 0: Well, A, C, E is all sort of the same.
Speaker 0: The blue ones.
Speaker 0: But yeah, they basically replaced, they took the oldest trains out of the blue lines, and they put the newest train in on the blue lines.
Speaker 0: And now there'll be a new line that has the oldest train.
Speaker 0: And that one will get the next upgrades whenever that is.
Speaker 0: The coolest part.
Speaker 0: The thing is, because of this rolling system, you always have a mix of, like, there's always a line with the oldest trains, there's the lines with the middle-aged trains, and the lines with the new trains.
Speaker 1: Also, depending on whether or not which of the ancient subway companies ran the line when it was built, numbers versus letters, with a few weird exceptions, they upgrade on different cycles because their tracks actually have different specifications for what the car's gonna be.
Speaker 0: Well, it's like, you know, we talked about Tokyo has different train companies, like New York used to have different train companies, now it has one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you know what?
Speaker 1: One company run by the government way better than a bunch of private companies!
Speaker 1: So anyway, these new trains, the biggest deal about them is they reflect the modern needs of New York City.
Speaker 1: in that one, they have an open gangway format, meaning they are just one long open train.
Speaker 1: There's no more, like, doors between cars, it's just a long train, you can walk anywhere.
Speaker 0: Now in the showtime in a car, you can't really avoid it, well you can, you can get away immediately, but the showtime was gonna sort of come through the little gangway.
Speaker 1: Now, even worse, in New York, there's a common knowledge, if there is a packed subway, and a train rolls in, and you see that the car that you can get into is pretty empty, there is a reason it is pretty empty.
Speaker 1: There is some dire shit going on in that car.
Speaker 0: Possibly some bardle, or something.
Speaker 1: Now, it'll be a dire train, a train's gonna roll in empty, and you're gonna wonder what's up with that train.
Speaker 0: I think even in those cases, you could just be in a car far enough away from the direness to...
Speaker 1: Yeah, depending on the direness, but the other thing, they've gotten rid of a lot of seats in the format that I like that a lot of the London Underground has, where they have seats that'll come down if you want to sit in them, but they're up by default, which is good for two reasons.
Speaker 1: One, this makes way better areas for people in wheelchairs and with other accessibility accommodations to be able to get into the car, like they have a space that's better for them.
Speaker 1: And two, the reality is, in most of the subway lines in New York, during a rush hour or a crowded time, you can't really sit anyway, and actually, studies showed if they got rid of those seats, they could cram so many more people in the train than those seats could accommodate.
Speaker 0: I think it matters less on the A, but the 6 is the one where they gotta rip the seats out, right?
Speaker 1: Oh, the 7!
Speaker 1: The 7 should not have a single seat, except one special car that is for...
Speaker 0: The 7 needs seats, maybe not on the Express 7, but the local 7 needs seats, because that shit is long, and there's a lot of old people riding that, right?
Speaker 0: The 7 almost needs... The Express 7, you could take the seats out.
Speaker 1: The 7 could do a thing, you know what, India has, a lot of the trains in India, what they do is they have, one, they have woman-only cars.
Speaker 0: Isn't that?
Speaker 0: where people ride on the outside of the train?
Speaker 1: Depending on where you are, but in Mumbai and some of the cities, while that will happen, they'll have woman-only cars, but it's for people who identify as women, and it's mostly because of systemic, extreme assault and harassment issues, but sometimes they will also have cars dedicated for old people only.
Speaker 1: Whole car of old people.
Speaker 1: We could have the old person car with the seats, and everybody else, you don't get a seat.
Speaker 0: We should have a bike car.
Speaker 1: We should have a bike car.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, if you live in New York, you can try one of these on the A train.
Speaker 1: I will, if I have an opportunity to take the A train, because it would be equivalent to something else, I'm going to try to check out one of these cars, because...
Speaker 0: Yeah, but where do you go that the A goes?
Speaker 1: Nowhere, I guess, coming home from a Rangers game, sometimes the E doesn't run, and then the A to 42nd street is actually the fastest way home.
Speaker 0: And then you would have to swap, though.
Speaker 0: I'm going
Speaker 1: to swap to the 7, which I got to walk on the ground, which is a pro in the early part of the hockey season, but is a con in the late part of the hockey season, because it's warm out, and usually I'll take a city bike, so we'll see.
Speaker 0: Why don't you just do what I do and take the F to, you know...
Speaker 1: Well, usually what I do is take the E, which takes me directly home.
Speaker 1: It's the literal fastest possible way.
Speaker 0: I feel like the Queensbridge is closer than the...
Speaker 1: Nope, nope, nope, the E. Queensbridge is slightly further away than E, and also the E is so much faster.
Speaker 0: The F is pretty fast.
Speaker 1: The F is pretty fast.
Speaker 1: E is faster, believe me.
Speaker 1: I am 100% sure I would bet my life and my fortune on that.
Speaker 0: Anyway...
Speaker 1: Anyway, the big news.
Speaker 1: Two banks collapsed for completely unrelated reasons.
Speaker 1: One of those banks that collapsed was...
Speaker 0: Three banks.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe more.
Speaker 0: Only the second one is one that we have to spend time talking about.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and there might be more collapses coming.
Speaker 1: There's a lot going on here, but...
Speaker 0: But it's really just the second one that's a meaningful...
Speaker 1: Yeah, because the first bank that collapsed was some bullshit crypto bank.
Speaker 1: Fuck them and fuck everyone who worked with them.
Speaker 1: Like, I just do not care.
Speaker 1: The funniest thing...
Speaker 0: They failed because crypto was bad, and they were bad.
Speaker 0: It's not really complicated.
Speaker 1: So, crypto is up on this news, like, by a lot, and I'm not giving financial advice.
Speaker 1: I'm not a registered investment advisor.
Speaker 1: One, I firmly personally believe that Bitcoin and every e-cryptocurrency will go to zero.
Speaker 1: It's a matter of when, not if.
Speaker 1: That's a personal opinion.
Speaker 1: But two, they're up partly because people who are, in my personal opinion, extremely stupid... ...are believing that the collapse of these banks means putting your money in crypto would be safer, which is hilarious to a degree that I can't wait for them to lose their money.
Speaker 1: Like, I actively want to cyberbully them when they lose their money.
Speaker 0: It's like, these banks... The story here is that the banks are insured, and the crypto is not.
Speaker 0: So, it's like, what?
Speaker 1: Nobody who has money in the bank we're about to talk about is losing their money.
Speaker 1: The only people losing anything are the people who invested in the bank itself or were senior executives at the bank.
Speaker 0: So, effectively, the people who owned the bank are the people who are losing.
Speaker 1: So, Silicon Valley Bank.
Speaker 1: If you're not aware of this bank, which funnily enough...
Speaker 0: I was not aware of this bank until I got to my current job, and I learned that basically, not only my employer, but many, many, many tech startups, and I was even told Apple uses this bank...
Speaker 1: Probably, honestly, the majority.
Speaker 1: Like, the actual majority.
Speaker 0: A very large number.
Speaker 0: So, this bank started in the 80s, it's as old as we are, for Silicon Valley tech companies.
Speaker 0: Like, that was what they were about.
Speaker 0: It's just a regional bank.
Speaker 0: Like, whatever... You know, not like the big national banks, like your Chase's and your Banks of America's, right?
Speaker 0: But, like, those regional banks that, no matter where you go in the country, you'll always see some kind of bank that's, like, only in that town.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: You know, I used that kind of bank.
Speaker 0: There was some Connecticut bank I used until I moved out.
Speaker 1: The Hudson Valley Credit Union, and when I closed my account... Perfect example.
Speaker 1: So, fun fact, this is a while ago.
Speaker 1: Scott messaged me, and he was like, "Yeah, apparently the government owes you some
Speaker 1: money.".
Speaker 1: Because he was looking at that website, and I looked, and sure enough, the government owed me some money.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's a completely unrelated thing.
Speaker 1: Yup, because I used this local bank, and I closed my account, and I guess something went wrong, and they had a bunch of money of mine, so I got that money back.
Speaker 0: Right, so Silicon Valley Bank was a completely normal bank of that nature, just a regional bank.
Speaker 0: You can make a checking account there, you can get an ATM card from there, you can get a credit card from there, right?
Speaker 0: But, the vast majority of their customers were two kinds of people.
Speaker 0: Number one, there were Silicon Valley startup companies with business checking accounts, right, and money market accounts, and those sorts of things.
Speaker 0: And, the VC funds that invested in those startup companies, and often a lot of times you would even have the funding people tell the startups they were funding.
Speaker 0: Like, "Yeah, if we're going to fund you, it's going to be conditional on you using this
Speaker 0: bank.".
Speaker 1: Now, why would they do this?
Speaker 1: Convenience.
Speaker 1: It's just convenience.
Speaker 1: Imagine you have a bank where the people who work at that bank, they just really are used to and know the deal with how startups operate, and how the money gets transferred.
Speaker 1: They have specialist knowledge that makes them better at doing this, whereas a standard, generic bank might ask questions that are easily answered, or not understand, or be surprised by you cashing a $10 million check.
Speaker 0: If you were a startup, and you tried to go use some normal old bank, right?
Speaker 0: You know, your cash flow is going to be, you get funded, and millions and millions of dollars enter your account very quickly, right?
Speaker 1: And then no more money goes into your account for possibly years.
Speaker 0: And then money does not enter your account at all, barely, because you have almost no revenues, but you're spending like mad, and it's like, someone looks at that, and they're like, "Money laundering?
Speaker 0: Fraud?
Speaker 1: What's happening
Speaker 1: here?".
Speaker 1: And you just proceeded to spend like a million dollars every few months, just constantly, just grinding that down to zero as fast as possible.
Speaker 0: You know, normal small businesses, when they have a business account at a bank, their local bank or whatever, it's like, you know, they might get financing from that bank for various things here and there, right?
Speaker 0: If a startup tried to go get financing from one of those normal banks, they'd be like,
Speaker 0: "What?".
Speaker 0: No, no, this isn't, you know, it's like, normally, it would be like, I don't know, a deli wants to renovate or something, and they want to finance it, right?
Speaker 0: And that would be, a normal bank would figure that one out really easily, right?
Speaker 0: Now, the other thing is- A startup was like, "Yeah, we're going to need to, we need some financing
Speaker 0: person.".
Speaker 0: They'd be like, "What?
Speaker 0: No, we're not going to give you that," right?
Speaker 0: So, Silicon Valley Bank specialized in helping out these companies.
Speaker 0: They would also, another one of their side businesses, I guess, it's not a side business, but another thing they specialized in was mortgages.
Speaker 0: For wealthy, you know, startup people who were buying expensive houses in Silicon Valley.
Speaker 1: Which makes sense, because that's probably the same person they're talking to, cash, that's a million dollar check.
Speaker 0: Exactly, so this bank existed and operated as a completely normal, above the table bank, just a US bank, nothing weird about it for as long as we've lived, basically.
Speaker 1: And to be clear, the bank was not investing in dodgy startups.
Speaker 1: The bank was taking the money from other people who invested in dodgy startups and just managing that money for the dodgy startups.
Speaker 1: So, if a dodgy startup goes under, that doesn't cost the bank anything.
Speaker 0: So, you know, just the sheer basics of banking, right, is people put in money, people take out money, like you're just a mattress, but you need to make more money, because like, how do you pay your employees?
Speaker 0: It's like, the only ways a bank can make more money to pay its employees, to buy buildings, to do all, you know, to make the executives at the bank wealthy, right?
Speaker 0: They had to get money, more money than was deposited.
Speaker 1: Short of having a nationalized banking system, even if a bank was a non-profit, it still needs money to operate, and banking employees are not cheap bank tellers and people who do banking stuff.
Speaker 0: That's a good job, it pays well.
Speaker 1: It pays real well, and it's real hard.
Speaker 0: So, where does the bank get more money from?
Speaker 0: There's really two ways a bank gets more money.
Speaker 0: Number one, fees to customers, right?
Speaker 0: That's one way.
Speaker 0: What's the other way is, well, people deposited the money, but people aren't gonna like withdraw all their money immediately, they're gonna let most of the money just sit in the bank.
Speaker 0: So you take people's money and you invest it in whatever, right, as long as it's not too shady, and you get interest, or you get dividends, or you buy and sell low and sell high, or you get bonds and then they mature, and you get more money by investing all the money that's just sitting in the bank doing nothing.
Speaker 0: And that's the revenues of the bank.
Speaker 0: is that extra on top, and if you get a whole bunch extra, you can share it with your customers, right?
Speaker 0: And the other way, which is also technically investing, is to give out loans to people with interest, and they pay back the loans, right?
Speaker 0: You've invested in someone's house when you give out a mortgage, you invested in someone's car when you give a car a loan, and then they pay it back with interest, and the interest is where the bank gets money from.
Speaker 1: Now one of the superpowers of the United
Speaker 0: States
Speaker 1: and a few other countries is that our banks really don't fail, like you can assume,
Speaker 0: regardless
Speaker 1: of everything else going on in the world, that if you've got money in a bank account, that money is there in that bank account and you can get it at any time if you want to.
Speaker 1: That is like, even as an extreme, radical communist who hates the idea of capitalism, that is a really important function for society.
Speaker 1: That is table stakes for a functioning society.
Speaker 1: Even communist countries need banks.
Speaker 0: Now being a bank, there's one other superpower that a bank has, which is that it can go to the Federal Reserve, the big bank, and borrow money from it at an interest rate that they had to pay back.
Speaker 1: You know when you hear the news like, "Ah, the Fed raised the rate by 50 basis points," or something, that's what they're talking about.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you are a bank, and it's like, yeah, people deposited money with you, but you want even more money, you can go and borrow some, right?
Speaker 0: And then you could use that.
Speaker 0: Let's say RIM wanted to buy a house, and I'm a brand new bank, I just started, right?
Speaker 0: I don't have any deposits, but RIM comes in and my first customer wants a mortgage.
Speaker 0: It's like, shit, no one deposited a million dollars for the RIM house yet.
Speaker 0: How am I going to give RIM a loan?
Speaker 0: I borrow money from the Federal government, from the Federal Reserve, right?
Speaker 1: I just charge me more interest than the Fed charges you.
Speaker 0: I charge you more interest on the mortgage than they charge me to pay that back, and boom, I'm making money at the bank, the government's making money, RIM's getting a house, it's gonna work out, right?
Speaker 1: I want to point out, right-wing nut jobs have a weird thing about the Federal Reserve, and they say that this is evil in some way, they often put religion into it.
Speaker 1: This is actually an extremely important and foundational lever on all economic interactions of any kind.
Speaker 1: The idea that the Federal government can set this minimum interest rate, and that is a guaranteed rate that banks can borrow money, that is how the government can control the economy and prevent extremely bad things from happening.
Speaker 1: Without that lever, we are so screwed.
Speaker 0: Right, so when we want to make lots, we want to put money into the economy, we want people to spend money on things, the government lowers the interest rate, and banks go, "Ooh, a low interest rate?
Speaker 0: That means I could give money to people who want loans to go buy houses and cars and start small
Speaker 0: businesses.".
Speaker 0: We pump money into the economy, and people start spending it and doing stuff, right?
Speaker 0: Because the bank is getting money really cheaply at a low interest rate, and then they can charge a moderate interest rate to the customers, and it's good.
Speaker 0: Now when the interest rate goes up at the Fed, the bank's like, "Well, listen, you know, RIM wants this house, but I can't be giving RIM a loan because I've got to pay back the
Speaker 0: government.".
Speaker 0: Well, like, how many percent interest now, right?
Speaker 0: So that means I need to charge RIM a really high interest rate, and I've got to be sure that RIM is even more sure than usual that RIM has good credit and is actually going to pay, because otherwise I'm fucked because I won't be able to pay back the interest to the Federal Reserve, right?
Speaker 0: So they wanted to slow down the economy, because there's inflation.
Speaker 0: They've raised the rates recently, and they're still raising them.
Speaker 1: Yup, because inflation is a big problem right now globally, not just in the U.S Yup, there's too much money out there.
Speaker 0: Money's worth less.
Speaker 0: Okay, we raise interest rates, and then there'll be less loans and less money going out.
Speaker 0: Pretty, you know, that's the absolute most basic thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, take, like, economic 101 in college, and this is what you learn.
Speaker 0: Right, so Silicon Valley Bank, what happened there?
Speaker 0: Well, all the money that comes into Silicon Valley Bank is VC funds, right, funding startups.
Speaker 0: That activity has slowed down, right?
Speaker 0: Not a lot of funding of startups going on in this economy.
Speaker 1: I would say not even slowed down.
Speaker 1: It is mostly ground to a halt.
Speaker 0: It's really slow, right?
Speaker 0: Dramatically slow.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, the startups still have accounts there, and they still exist, right?
Speaker 0: That is the ones that exist now.
Speaker 0: New ones aren't appearing, but there's the ones that already existed, right?
Speaker 0: And those startups were still spending like mad, because that's what they do.
Speaker 0: They're startups.
Speaker 0: They buy, they pay Amazon bills and Slack bills, and they pay employees hundreds of thousands of dollars a year to make software.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're not putting any money back into that bank right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no, and the startups don't have revenues, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, they're not bringing in money.
Speaker 0: They're just spending the money.
Speaker 0: It's like, okay, so, you know, the bank, you know, at some point in time, right, all the money that came in, came in, right?
Speaker 0: But how could the bank go under?
Speaker 0: Well, the bank, as we said at the beginning, needs to make more money than that somehow, and it does that by investing.
Speaker 1: Now, that is perfectly fine.
Speaker 1: There's nothing actually wrong with this.
Speaker 0: That's how it's supposed to work, right?
Speaker 0: And what the bank did, right?
Speaker 0: What the bank did is they bought treasury bonds, 10-year treasury bonds.
Speaker 0: That was their investment.
Speaker 0: It's a very safe investment.
Speaker 0: It's a guarantee in 10 years that you buy one.
Speaker 0: It'll be worth more than it was when you bought it in 10 years from now, and you sell it, and you give it back to the government.
Speaker 0: The government gives you the money, and you have more money than you bought it for, and you even beat inflation.
Speaker 0: It's like, it's great.
Speaker 0: It's congratulations.
Speaker 0: You bought a bond and gave it back, right?
Speaker 0: It's, you know, it's like a savings bond, only way bigger.
Speaker 1: And the rules are basically, banks have to, they can invest some percentage of their money, and they have to keep some percentage of it in directly liquid cash to cover just day-to-day operations.
Speaker 1: Those regulations mostly came out of the '20s, and then the '30s, and the economic collapse, and Great Depression, and we regulated the banks a little bit.
Speaker 0: So really basic math, right?
Speaker 0: Investor Rim puts a million dollars into the bank, right?
Speaker 0: He's going to invest in some startups, right?
Speaker 0: A startup comes along.
Speaker 0: Rim says, "I like that
Speaker 0: startup.".
Speaker 0: He gives that startup the million dollars.
Speaker 0: It's now in the million-dollar checking account.
Speaker 1: Scottco, make me a social media app that's going to make me billions of dollars.
Speaker 0: All right, I'll do that.
Speaker 0: So I got a million dollars in my checking account that I'm spending at a good clip.
Speaker 0: The bank is like, "All right, the million came in.
Speaker 0: We got the million.
Speaker 0: It's going out, right?
Speaker 0: But we're a bank.
Speaker 0: We need to make more money.
Speaker 0: Let's take, I don't know, 250K of that
Speaker 0: million.".
Speaker 0: Scott's not going to get down to 250K that fast, right?
Speaker 0: And we'll buy a 10-year bond, and in 10 years, by the time Scott needs that 250K at the bottom of his account, we'll sell this bond, and we'll have the 250K, and unless Scott goes to the ATM and closes his account right now, we're going to be good.
Speaker 0: And
Speaker 1: if somehow, Scott and a bunch of other people that close the account or pull all the money out of some shenanigans happen, they can borrow money from the Fed, or they can do other things like sell more stock in their own bank, because banks are often public companies you can invest in.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So that's what the bank did.
Speaker 0: And what happened was the interest rate went up, which means, you know, and then people started withdrawing money and weren't depositing money.
Speaker 1: Now, this is the backdrop of nobody's putting new money into the bank because nobody's investing in tech right now.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So what happened was, even though the total assets of the bank were enough to cover all the accounts that people had, right, what happened was people were drawing so much that the liquid assets of the bank, the cash they had that they could immediately use, was running out.
Speaker 0: And all their assets were these bonds, their own shares of the own stock in the company, I guess the assets of the company, like, you know, the chairs and the buildings and real estate, whatever the bank owned, right, it's still a company, right?
Speaker 0: And it couldn't really get more money from the Federal Reserve easily because the interest rate was really high.
Speaker 0: So when people started withdrawing and then creating a panic about withdrawing and their stock value went down, which meant even less cash for them, right, it was like, oh, shit, people want to withdraw money, we don't have enough.
Speaker 0: And then as soon as you're underwater, it takes about like the government comes in overnight and shuts you down.
Speaker 1: You ever see the movie It's a Wonderful Life out there?
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's called our bank run.
Speaker 1: It's not uncommon.
Speaker 0: Or Mary Poppins, you see that one?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: The reason this isn't a problem generally in the U.S.
Speaker 1: and in fact, still isn't a problem, because honestly, the government stepped in and did exactly what they needed to do, basically perfectly within the bounds of what Democrats are allowed to do.
Speaker 0: All of the bad things, all of the bad things that happened here happened before the bank run and then all the actions basically taken in response were the best actions that could have been taken given the circumstances.
Speaker 0: I don't know what you could have done better, government.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: This wasn't a bailout, like a lot of people are saying, even people who should know better on the left.
Speaker 0: No, this was not a bailout.
Speaker 1: I've seen multiple people complaining that, oh, government can't forgive student debt, but they're bailing out this bank, one.
Speaker 0: That has nothing to do with this whatsoever.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So the government already insures banks.
Speaker 1: The U.S.
Speaker 1: government already says up to what, like $250,000.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: There is a company called the FDIC, the Federal Deposit Insurance Company.
Speaker 0: You see every single bank in the
Speaker 0: U.S.,
Speaker 0: you're going to see this thing like FDIC insured.
Speaker 1: Pro tip, do not put your money in a bank that is not FDIC insured.
Speaker 0: No, never do that.
Speaker 0: But the FDIC, even though it's part of the U.S.
Speaker 0: government, it's a government agency, is just an insurance company like Lloyd's of London or Geico or Allstate or, you know, Master Keaton.
Speaker 0: I think he was at Lloyd's of London.
Speaker 1: He was an insurance underwriter, I want to say.
Speaker 0: Inspector.
Speaker 0: He was an inspector.
Speaker 0: But the point is, it's just an insurance company, right?
Speaker 0: So you're a bank and you pay insurance premiums to the FDIC the same way you pay insurance premiums on your car or your, you know, renders insurance.
Speaker 1: So that if a bank gets fucked or something bad happens, the FDIC will just cover not the bank employees, not the investors in the bank, but the regular ass people who have money in that bank.
Speaker 1: The FDIC will make sure that their money still exists.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So if a customer of the bank, you know, you go to the bank, you deposit 250K, right?
Speaker 0: At least up to 250K.
Speaker 0: If you deposit a million in the bank in your one checking account and the bank fails utterly, there's a chance you might lose 750K.
Speaker 1: Now, that 250K is an obsolete number that was created a long time ago.
Speaker 0: And really, it should be a million.
Speaker 1: It should be maybe 10 million.
Speaker 1: I would say that banks are at least one.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I agree that 250K could be changed.
Speaker 0: I don't know if changing it is just a policy or needs a law to change.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, a big sort of side problem is that in the United States, there are some politicians like Elizabeth Warren who tried to run for president who have been pointing at the current system.
Speaker 0: This is definitely Elizabeth Warren's like the exact center of her wheelhouse.
Speaker 1: Elizabeth Warren has been basically saying this exact thing is going to happen a hundred percent.
Speaker 1: It is trivial to prevent.
Speaker 1: We just have to pass some basic modernization of banking law.
Speaker 1: And the fascist side of the American government said, no, that's just not right.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so the point is, if you deposit money in an FDIC insured U.S.
Speaker 0: bank as a normal old customer, no matter what happens, the FDIC, because it's an insurance company, they will come in and guarantee that 250,000 of your dollars are safe, even if the bank turns out to be the worst criminal, garbage, fuck-up bank that ever fucked up.
Speaker 1: And then they will deal with, via the government, how to fuck over the bank that fucked over its customers.
Speaker 0: So what about the rest?
Speaker 0: If I put a million in the bank, I get the 250K, what happens to the rest of my 750K?
Speaker 0: Well, what happens is the FDIC will sort of give you a note.
Speaker 0: It's like a promissory note, kind of like, you know, sort of.
Speaker 0: And it basically says, it's a note that's like, you used to have 750K in this bank that wasn't insured.
Speaker 0: And the FDIC will then take all the assets the bank has left, right, whatever is left, and it will say, all right, what can we sell this for?
Speaker 0: And it will try to sell everything the bank has, usually to another bigger bank or, you know, whoever.
Speaker 0: It'll find ways to just turn the bank's remaining assets into money.
Speaker 0: And at the end, it'll look at that pool of money, and it'll divide it up, and everyone can cash in their note for whatever that amount of money is.
Speaker 0: That might take a while.
Speaker 0: That won't happen quickly.
Speaker 0: You could try to sell your note to someone else, usually at like a discount.
Speaker 0: So it's like, I got a note for 750K, it probably won't even be worth 750K if I wait a long time.
Speaker 0: Maybe someone will give me 500K for it right now, and that person can afford to wait for the 600, and they're happy to make free money, and I need money immediately because I have a business and I got to pay my employees.
Speaker 0: Stuff like that.
Speaker 0: What happened here?
Speaker 0: The FDIC did its normal deal.
Speaker 0: It came in.
Speaker 0: It's like, they operate so fast, and it's like people talk about bureaucracy and the government sucks, and it's like, yeah, a lot of agencies in the government suck, whatever, right?
Speaker 0: The FDIC is like the example that shows if you fund and well train and support a government agency, it can operate like, you know, like German trains.
Speaker 0: Like the FDIC is the German train of the US.
Speaker 1: Imagine if FEMA was funded properly when we had Hurricane Katrina.
Speaker 1: There would have been a literal army of people helping.
Speaker 0: Just put FDIC in charge of FEMA.
Speaker 0: But they come in to the bank, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, it literally is like a movie.
Speaker 1: They do it like they show up at the bank store and they're just like, yeah, we fucking, we're taking over.
Speaker 1: Fuck all of you.
Speaker 1: Let us in.
Speaker 0: They go through all the computers.
Speaker 0: They talk to all the employees.
Speaker 0: They go to all the, they find all the cash.
Speaker 0: They, you know, bag it up and count it.
Speaker 0: And it's like, they're, they, they basically raid the bank and take everything and sell it.
Speaker 0: And it's like this shit, right?
Speaker 0: We're, we're talking on the show on Monday, right?
Speaker 0: These banks failed what, Thursday?
Speaker 1: Thursday, Friday, right?
Speaker 0: By Sunday night, they were auctioning the banks, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, they come in and it's like, they work around the clock.
Speaker 0: They fly in.
Speaker 0: It's like, it's like, on Monday morning at the start of business, right?
Speaker 0: We, you know, my company, right?
Speaker 0: Just, you know, they, our money was in that Silicon Valley bank.
Speaker 0: They couldn't get the money out because the bank was closed.
Speaker 0: Sure enough on Monday morning, there's the money.
Speaker 0: It's like, there it goes.
Speaker 0: They made it work.
Speaker 0: I'm going to get paid, I guess, which is good because I wasn't going to work if I wasn't going to get paid.
Speaker 1: So the government basically did everything right here.
Speaker 1: The bank will see exactly the situation that happened.
Speaker 1: But regardless of if any of the executives foresaw this or sold their stock early or anything that we'll see in the coming, those are separate, those are separate issues.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The real buried lead here to turn this back into a tech story is that nobody's fucking investing in dodgy tech startups anymore.
Speaker 1: Like that ship just hit a reef and that is the actual, I'm not going to say problem.
Speaker 1: That is a big deal because a huge part of the modern American world relies terrifyingly too much on tech startups that have no revenue.
Speaker 1: And the only reason those companies exist is because they either always expected like Amazon or Google would buy them, which guess who's not doing that anymore.
Speaker 1: or VCs will come in with more rounds of money or new VCs will fund new companies that replace them.
Speaker 1: None of that's happening anymore.
Speaker 1: There is way more rot in American capitalism and this is a symptom of a far more wide reaching problem.
Speaker 1: And as a secondary point, this would have been trivially presented by basic modernization of banking regulation, which our government is incapable of right now.
Speaker 0: So the end result is the FDIC treasury and federal reserve came in and they did something, I guess, slightly exceptional, but at no cost to taxpayers whatsoever.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: They're basically guaranteeing that everyone who had deposits, even above the 250K, right, your whole deposit, if you were at this bank or, or also the signature bank, which went down today.
Speaker 0: Um, but basically all your money that was in that bank, even above the 250K, it's there, you didn't lose anything.
Speaker 0: You don't have to worry about the promissory note, whatever they call it.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You know, you're, you're.
Speaker 0: all the money is there.
Speaker 0: You're good to go.
Speaker 0: And the people who's, you know, it's like, well, someone lost on this deal, right?
Speaker 0: Who lost money?
Speaker 0: The owners of the bank, the shareholders in the banks got fucked.
Speaker 0: No one's bailing them out.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: If you own shares in Silicon Valley bank, they are now worthless.
Speaker 0: There are some people who claim that they sold short cause they saw it coming.
Speaker 0: And those people, I guess, are very wealthy now.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And whoever let them borrow shares is in the shit now.
Speaker 1: Just to make sure they didn't know anything that wasn't public and allowed to be used to make that kind of decision.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And you know, they think on the one hand that's good because, you know, some of those shareholders were evil capitalist people who deserve to get fucked.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And that's good news that they got fucked.
Speaker 0: They found out, but in bad news, you know, some of those investors were like, Hey, Ed's retirement plan and Ed got his retirement plan is losing value.
Speaker 1: Of course, I would say that predicating retirement on investing in capitalist structures via markets feels like a extremely fucked up way to do that.
Speaker 1: But that's a separate topic.
Speaker 0: But yeah, this rocked the world.
Speaker 0: If this hadn't gone this way, it might have been a truly devastating news.
Speaker 1: If they had not stepped in on this, this could have turned into, you'll hear a lot of finance.
Speaker 1: people would call it a contagion.
Speaker 1: There's still a low key contagion happening, but we would have seen more banks fail like by today.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But not even that, but like literally every startup would not have been able to make payroll and all the software engineers wouldn't have gone to work.
Speaker 0: And then there would all those, like all these websites to just shut down overnight.
Speaker 1: Imagine if I'm going to make up, cause I don't know who uses the bank and how much exposure they have, but imagine if like square payment processing and Grubhub and Uber just stopped working today.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Well, to give you two examples, right.
Speaker 0: Etsy had to like basically stop making payments out to people who sold stuff on Etsy.
Speaker 0: And I guess they were able to probably continue them now.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But Etsy had a lot of money in that bank, their bank, and they couldn't like, if you sold your shit on Etsy and then, you know, whoever bought your shit paid Etsy and Etsy then was going to pay you the craft person.
Speaker 0: They had to delay those payments until I presume today.
Speaker 0: Also, I saw a report that said Roblox, the child labor company, right.
Speaker 0: Had like a hundred million plus in the, in that bank.
Speaker 0: And so Roblox would just could have, if they, if they lost all but two 50 K Roblox would just disappear off the face of the earth.
Speaker 0: If they lost $999 million.
Speaker 1: Imagine what would happen if Roblox disappeared right now, like overnight.
Speaker 0: Roblox is there last week.
Speaker 1: in this today, they just got millions of parents who are not terminally online.
Speaker 0: All the people who have Robux, they're worthless now, you can't use them.
Speaker 1: Millions of parents who don't know about how the internet works would suddenly be confronted with children who are screaming and crying and having an existential crisis that they one do not understand and two have no way to fix.
Speaker 0: That could have happened.
Speaker 0: We could, it could have been if the, if the government of the United States in this one area was not as competent as it is.
Speaker 1: The moral of this.
Speaker 1: large, large, competent governments that are actually beholden to the people are very effective at solving large, difficult problems.
Speaker 1: Contrary to the popular belief of people who don't know better.
Speaker 1: Anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 1: So I grew up, Scott grew up, many of you probably are too young to remember an era when every car didn't have air conditioning.
Speaker 1: Like now, like pretty much any car has air conditioning.
Speaker 0: In the US.
Speaker 0: In my early life we had cars that had air conditioning.
Speaker 1: We had the good car with air conditioning and the other cars that didn't.
Speaker 1: At RIT, my first car didn't have air conditioning, my second car did and then it didn't when it broke at one point as we discovered driving a Wildwood one time together.
Speaker 1: But air conditioning actually makes cars more efficient because the reality is you're driving a car, let's skip the whole, like we actually have to ban cars fundamentally, but assuming they're here.
Speaker 1: Cars get extremely hot in the sun, like dangerously hot.
Speaker 1: They have to be cooled.
Speaker 1: Rolling down the windows and just like doing things like that don't actually cool cars that much and actually make them even less efficient.
Speaker 0: Aerodynamically speaking.
Speaker 1: Yeah, air conditioning, modern air conditioning is extremely efficient at keeping cars cool and reasonable, but that didn't exist a long time ago in the way we have today.
Speaker 1: So this video was making the rounds.
Speaker 1: It's a short TikTok.
Speaker 1: It's less than a minute long.
Speaker 1: that explains one of the ways you could cool a car in the 1950s and actually it's a pretty effective way of cooling a car with an asterisk.
Speaker 1: It only works in places that have low humidity.
Speaker 1: It's basically a swamp cooler that hangs out your window and it's a pretty cool thing.
Speaker 1: My grandpa had a truck from the 50s that he kept until near the end of his life and he kept it functional.
Speaker 1: It had two notable things going on.
Speaker 1: One, it had two gas tanks and you could flip a switch to flip between the two gas tanks and two, it had vents in the front of the car that you could open that would funnel air from intakes in the front of the car into the cabin directly and had exhaust in the back.
Speaker 1: because it was designed, this car was actually from the 40s.
Speaker 1: So this is just a pretty cool thing that I don't think any of you have ever seen.
Speaker 0: My favorite old school way to cool a motor vehicle that doesn't have its own cooling is still the super old school butcher delivery truck where they would go to the slaughterhouse, they would get all the meats, hang them up in a truck and just throw a bucket of dry ice in there and close the door.
Speaker 1: That only works for the back of the car where the dead meat is.
Speaker 1: If you put that in the front of the car with the live meat, you'll have two compartments full of dead meat.
Speaker 0: That's correct.
Speaker 0: But it's great for the back of the truck.
Speaker 0: Just a bucket of dry ice, close the door.
Speaker 1: Even when we were in college and there was no air conditioning in our shitty apartment and then we were like, "Why don't we just get a bucket of dry ice?
Speaker 1: That would solve
Speaker 1: things.".
Speaker 1: And then it took us about 10 seconds to realize that was a terrible idea.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: My thing of the day, thanks to the listener for this excellent thing of the day.
Speaker 0: If you are old enough to have used cassette players, CD players, DVD players, these sorts of things in the 80s and 90s, maybe even 2000s before, I guess, basically the pre-LCD era, before iPods, basically, all those devices typically had what's known as a VFD display, a vacuum fluorescent display.
Speaker 0: Once you see one, you'll say, "Oh, that kind of
Speaker 0: display.".
Speaker 0: And this person on YouTube named Posey made a great video about VFDs.
Speaker 0: And I really like this video because it's a combo video.
Speaker 0: On the one hand, it's educational about VFDs.
Speaker 0: How they worked, zooming in on them with a microscope, looking at how different filters and colors and different designs and all sorts of educational things, but also is an aesthetic video with music playing and showing you them in a very nostalgic feel.
Speaker 1: The style of VFDs, like the kinds of displays you can make with that tech is a style that speaks to me personally and viscerally.
Speaker 0: I want to make like, you know, it's like, hey, these were designed that way because of the technology, but it's like, it's a great design.
Speaker 0: I would love to have user interface.
Speaker 0: You know, people have done, Winamp skins have done this, right?
Speaker 0: But it's like, what if your whole, you know, the, you know, Star Trek, actually, all the Star Trek user interfaces are the same aesthetic as this.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Even the newer, we're watching a lot of the newer Star Treks and same kind of thing.
Speaker 1: And also there was an era when LCDs got good enough.
Speaker 1: There were a bunch of LCDs that would be designed to try to look like VFD styling.
Speaker 0: You know, like how cool would it be if your whole computer operating system had this aesthetic?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Vaporwave me up, Danny.
Speaker 0: It's an S tier video.
Speaker 0: Thank you, the listener.
Speaker 1: In the meta moment, the geek nights book club book is the satanic versus by Sam and Rushdie.
Speaker 1: I read the beginning.
Speaker 0: The fact that this didn't even get the book yet.
Speaker 1: So what I'll say is I've never read anything from Sam and Rushdie other than some essays.
Speaker 0: Me either.
Speaker 1: His prose is, this is S tier prose.
Speaker 1: I'm just going to say it right now.
Speaker 1: Read the first chapter, read the first paragraph and you, anyone who would try to kill this man for having written this prose is, is just vile and dangerous to society.
Speaker 1: But also, uh, you know, the, the trope of a good angel and a bad angel, but they're also kind of buddies and they're kind of like the evil ones, not actually that good or not that bad.
Speaker 1: And the good ones not actually that good.
Speaker 1: Like, yes.
Speaker 0: Uh, this is also that, uh, this, uh, I go, I haven't read one of those in a while, but I know the type.
Speaker 1: I like that type.
Speaker 1: I like that type a lot.
Speaker 1: That's a trope that, uh, I've enjoyed my whole life.
Speaker 1: And, uh, yeah, this book is, uh, right in that.
Speaker 0: Neil Gaiman is good at those, right?
Speaker 1: Uh, the first chapter is one of the best opening acts of a long novel I've read in a long time because it hits you hard.
Speaker 1: It doesn't give you time to process what you're reading the pros.
Speaker 1: It's just going to pull you along.
Speaker 1: I am already deeply invested in this book, having read 18 paragraphs.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Uh, the final metamoment bit is the website is progressing, uh, rapidly.
Speaker 0: It is still, there's still some work to do, but we are nearing the end of getting the things done we need to do to replace the current website.
Speaker 0: Um, and then there's still many other things to do after that, but we may hit that time.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: So, so we went on long as we do when we skip shows.
Speaker 1: So to get right into the main bit, e-waste is a big problem.
Speaker 1: One of the biggest problems in society right now.
Speaker 1: Uh, mostly e-waste, the burden of e-waste is borne by the poorest people on earth in the least supported places on earth.
Speaker 1: Uh, and we're going to try to talk about what you in an industrialized society where you are insulated from the consequences of not dealing with it.
Speaker 1: Well, kind of how to deal with it, because if you're listening to Geek Nights, you're probably, I imagine, you have at least one of every kind of cable you have ever owned in your entire life, just in case.
Speaker 1: I imagine you've got a box or a bag or a bin somewhere filled with a whole bunch of shit that you have collected through the years of owning and building computers that you keep around because you might need it.
Speaker 1: And you might have like a monitor.
Speaker 1: that's kind of shitty, but no one wants it and you don't want to throw it away because you feel bad, but literally no one on earth wants this monitor.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, for example, I'm currently was doing a lot of cleaning of electronic stuff, right?
Speaker 0: And I had a bunch of hard drives and it's like, you know, I got an S.A.T.A.
Speaker 0: six gigabit per second magnetic hard drive.
Speaker 0: that's 500 gigabytes.
Speaker 1: I've got a three gigabit per second 500 gigabyte hard drive.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying like it's 500 gigabyte hard drive, a big three and a half inch magnetic hard drive.
Speaker 0: And it's like you could get terabyte hard drives for like nothing.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: These days, very low prices.
Speaker 0: And it's like even if I try to give it away for free, it's like, why would someone at least in New York City want it?
Speaker 0: It's like they would have to be extremely desperate for like any amount of storage because like you could get vastly much more storage in much smaller like an SSD for less money.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And it's even worse.
Speaker 1: Like if you there are people in the world, if you look globally, who could definitely use that hard drive, but the cost of getting it to someone, not even just not even the transportation.
Speaker 0: Find me finding that person, making a connection with them.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And agreeing to it is the harder even than the transport, which would which would still be extreme for the cost to send them the hard drive.
Speaker 1: And not even the dollar cost, but the external cost, like the carbon cost of that shipping is worth talking about the total cost.
Speaker 1: that is probably worse than just giving them money so they can buy a modern hard drive.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: It would be cheaper for me to wire them money to buy a better brand new hard drive where they live in most places on earth than for me to somehow package this hard drive and deliver it to them.
Speaker 1: Now, I will say, too, while it is not illegal in many parts of the US because America has a fucked up system to throw things like that away, it is illegal here to just throw that away.
Speaker 1: Like in New York, it is illegal to put that in the regular garbage as it should.
Speaker 1: Correct.
Speaker 0: Correct.
Speaker 0: So how do I have this thing?
Speaker 0: I don't need it.
Speaker 0: I have no use for it.
Speaker 0: It is functioning.
Speaker 0: I erased all my data from it.
Speaker 0: That's a separate issue.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And there's there's no economical way for me to find someone who wants it and give it to them.
Speaker 0: I mean, I put a posting online to see if anyone wants it.
Speaker 0: And some of my larger drives for terabytes, two terabytes, I was able to give those away occasionally, even for money to local people.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: The best possible result.
Speaker 0: But some I found a listener to take some for free.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Which is very fortuitous.
Speaker 0: But that's really.
Speaker 0: nobody else wanted to take them at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And that listener only wanted them as like, you know, hobby extra drives or whatever.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Like they weren't useful in any way.
Speaker 0: But it's like if no one really.
Speaker 0: what the hell are you supposed to do with this thing?
Speaker 0: Well, you can take it for e-cycling right to your local e-cycle state.
Speaker 0: I think, you know, Staples take stuff.
Speaker 0: Best I take stuff.
Speaker 1: They'll take some stuff.
Speaker 1: That's sort of the crux of this.
Speaker 1: The first thing you should try to do is just check out all your social media and free tables and just see, is there anyone in your orbit who for relatively low effort wants the thing?
Speaker 0: Because the closer they are geographically, the better.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Handing it to someone just who lives near you is like the best possible thing.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But to after that, look at big box stores, even though they're disappearing, like.
Speaker 1: it's amazing that Staples and places will even take this stuff because they even sell electronics.
Speaker 1: But while they still exist, try to find a place that will take it.
Speaker 1: But you'll have to do some research because there's a lot of different kinds of waste and every kind of place you could take it to will have different rules and what they will and will not take.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Very important.
Speaker 1: And it gets hard because like a lot of e-waste, like I have a lot of e-waste in the apartment and most of it is stuff I've had for a good chunk of my life.
Speaker 1: And I'm finally deciding to just get rid of it.
Speaker 1: So a lot of it is like cables that no one will take that are useless to anybody to the point that some of this stuff I got to hold out until one of those amnesty days that New York City has that most of the world doesn't have where they'll fucking take anything.
Speaker 0: It's not an amnesty day, it's Safe Disposal Day.
Speaker 0: What's actually happening on Safe Disposal Day is that private e-waste companies that have partnered with the Department of Sanitation are setting up shop in the park.
Speaker 0: It's not like an amnesty.
Speaker 1: But what their hope is that people who have dodgy stuff will just take everything there, no questions asked, because they can then sort it into all the different types of companies that could take and deal with different kinds of things.
Speaker 1: Because the way you deal with an old light bulb is very different from how you deal with an old battery or an old CRT or an old hard drive.
Speaker 0: So what the e-waste companies in your area are doing varies greatly, right?
Speaker 0: Some of them might be doing things like, "Oh, this still works.
Speaker 0: Let's see how many computers I can put together and we'll put those in schools for the kids to learn
Speaker 0: on.".
Speaker 0: Or give them to people who are so unfortunate that they can't even buy the cheapest computer.
Speaker 0: It's like, "Alright, well, here's a computer that goes on the internet.
Speaker 0: It has a web browser.
Speaker 0: It's better than absolutely nothing.
Speaker 0: It's slow and weird, but hey, it's a computer for nothing.
Speaker 0: Here you
Speaker 0: go.".
Speaker 0: Some of them are like, "Alright, this TV only needed a new capacitor.
Speaker 0: We fixed it and now we'll resell it and get some
Speaker 0: money.".
Speaker 0: Some of them might be doing that sort of stuff.
Speaker 0: Some of them might be saying, "Alright, this doesn't work.
Speaker 0: There's no way we can make it
Speaker 0: work.".
Speaker 0: But inside of it, there is a valuable magnet.
Speaker 0: We can harvest the valuable materials.
Speaker 0: "Ah, there's some tungsten in this
Speaker 0: one.".
Speaker 0: Stuff like that can happen.
Speaker 1: And in the worst case scenario, they might even just still be like, "Yeah, they're just going to throw it
Speaker 1: away.".
Speaker 1: But instead of just putting it in the general stream of waste that ends up in a landfill or an incinerator or something, they are regulated, at least depending on where you are.
Speaker 1: Watch out if you're in certain states.
Speaker 1: They're regulated, they'll follow the laws, and they will dispose of it in the way that is required or at least that does the least harm.
Speaker 1: And if they don't, they can get in trouble.
Speaker 0: And now the worst possible result is not even just it ending up in the regular trash and going to Staten Island to sit in a heap.
Speaker 0: That's real bad.
Speaker 0: But even worse is if it goes to a heap somewhere else in the world where there are child laborers digging through looking for something that has a trace of gold on it.
Speaker 0: And then there's some horrible, environmentally damaging process where they extract the tiniest amounts of rare, valuable elements from all the electronic waste that gives everyone there gets cancer and poisons all the land nearby.
Speaker 0: And that's happening in a lot of places.
Speaker 1: Yep, because the reality is recycling is a complex process and e-waste is a new threat to society that we we haven't really dealt with the last four or five major threats in this type of space.
Speaker 1: And this is just yet a newer one.
Speaker 0: So what can you, you know, the best thing you can do?
Speaker 1: Not buy useless shit, buy as little as possible.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: The the real solution is to avoid the problem in the first place.
Speaker 0: You want to not you know, if something is still good.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Don't replace it.
Speaker 0: I was some fool.
Speaker 0: I was buying iPhones every two years.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And for those first few years, I would like take the old phone and give it to someone I knew who didn't.
Speaker 0: It was better than the phone they had.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But then it's like once I got the iPhone seven, it's like, you know, who wants it?
Speaker 0: I'm trying to sell an iPhone seven on eBay right now.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: it's like five bucks.
Speaker 0: Like no one wants this.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like keep it and use it for as long as you can.
Speaker 0: When iPhone eight, nine, ten came out, I was like, you know what?
Speaker 0: The seven is still working fine.
Speaker 0: Why would I buy a new one?
Speaker 0: for no reason?
Speaker 1: I'm not going to get a 14 because this thing works fine.
Speaker 1: I'll get iPhone 12 mini.
Speaker 0: And it's like I'm paying Apple for Apple Care.
Speaker 0: Like every month, you know, the app, the two year Apple Care on the iPhone 12 mini ran out.
Speaker 0: I'm paying Apple like nine bucks a month.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But you know what?
Speaker 0: That's going to extend the life of this iPhone 12 mini.
Speaker 0: Hopefully five, six, seven years.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Avoid having to buy another new phone.
Speaker 0: The phone, you know, by the time if they come out with, I don't know, six G and the phone isn't, you know, I need.
Speaker 0: I want to get a new one, then I could probably find someone who would take it right for more than five bucks.
Speaker 1: I brought the same ancient Android phone for like four years.
Speaker 1: And the only reason I upgraded was because the battery didn't last at all anymore.
Speaker 1: And so multiple spectrum changes happened to the point that the phone actually did not work anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like there's usually a way to find a way to keep something going.
Speaker 0: It's like especially in the current climate where there's all these incremental upgrades instead of significant ones.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like, do you really need the switch OLED?
Speaker 0: Because if you already if you don't have a switch, yeah, get the OLED one.
Speaker 0: Obviously it's better.
Speaker 0: But it's like if you got a switch and I guess you could find someone to take an old switch pretty easily still.
Speaker 0: But it's just a good example of like.
Speaker 0: you don't need that minor upgrade.
Speaker 0: You can skip on that.
Speaker 1: Well, I have the same.
Speaker 1: Now, one thing you can do if, you know, you're listening to geek nights, if you're the kind of nerd who has money, the philosophy that we talked about an old geek nights and it comes up time and time again is if you can, if you're going to buy something by the minimum viable thing necessary to accomplish your goal or by the best possible thing.
Speaker 1: So what I've always done, and this is this is only something you can do if you have the privilege of having piles of money.
Speaker 1: Every time I build a new computer, I overbuild it so that I will not have to upgrade it or replace it for as long as possible.
Speaker 1: I'm still rocking an Intel i6, not i6, the K, the six, whatever, six generation 6700K, the one that everyone bought like six years ago.
Speaker 1: Windows 11 won't even run on this thing.
Speaker 0: Now, what can the industry do?
Speaker 0: Well, what the industry can do is really, you know, I guess this has been unpopular in some places.
Speaker 0: I know there was a thing in Brazil, but like Apple stopped putting chargers in there and cables.
Speaker 0: I think that's a good thing.
Speaker 1: I have so many USB charges that are just garbage because I don't need them.
Speaker 0: I have an anchor.
Speaker 0: I got a whole bag of like cables and stuff that like I don't need.
Speaker 1: I filled three fresh Shurex bags with old cables I didn't need.
Speaker 0: Three?
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: I've got like half a bag.
Speaker 1: Well, some of that was like cables for old Atari's that no one wanted, like literally no one wanted them.
Speaker 1: Some of that was old audio cables that didn't work anymore, but I kept them because I kept having ideas of fixing them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got like, you know, I just had too many HDMI cables.
Speaker 0: HDMI cables are still useful, but it's like I don't need that as many as I had.
Speaker 0: I didn't need that many.
Speaker 1: I also finally bit the bullet.
Speaker 1: I had every combination of AV cable on earth and I did an audit of every format that's actually obsolete.
Speaker 1: Like I had a lot of HDMI to DVI adapters.
Speaker 1: Like that's never going to get used again in my life.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I had some very weird cables that like I couldn't even tell what they were for.
Speaker 0: And like basically I thought about my actual use cases, right?
Speaker 0: I look anytime I found the thing, I'm like, is the scenario that I'm going to actually use this, is that even like remotely likely?
Speaker 0: Like at one point, like even if it was just, you know, if it was just once, like if I could imagine like, yeah, there's going to be that one time I need this, right?
Speaker 0: And there's no other way for me to do the thing without this, then I kept it.
Speaker 0: But everything else, like, no, there's no way I would need this many HDMIs.
Speaker 0: There's no way I would need this specific cable, right?
Speaker 0: There's nothing I own that's going to use it, right?
Speaker 0: Get it out of here.
Speaker 0: And I had a whole bag of stuff.
Speaker 0: And the way to prevent that is, like I said, A, give people less stuff, right?
Speaker 0: That way it's like if they already have a cable, then they can use it again.
Speaker 0: They don't, you know, got an iPhone, you got a new iPhone.
Speaker 0: You still got cables lying around.
Speaker 0: You don't need new ones.
Speaker 0: And people can always, if they need one, buy the one that they need, right?
Speaker 0: You know, or get a used one from someone else who has too many.
Speaker 0: Two standards!
Speaker 1: Like the fact that we're forcing Apple to go to USB-C, even though they're kind of doing it in a bullshitty way, by giving us USB-C to lightning cables, which literally defeats the purpose.
Speaker 1: But I digress.
Speaker 1: That is a good thing.
Speaker 1: Fuck that lightning cable.
Speaker 1: USB-A and USB-C should be the only cables we use, especially for power in the modern era.
Speaker 1: Maybe the third one is that regular old black cable that goes into the power supply of your computer.
Speaker 1: A lot of stuff standardized on that over the years.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I had a lot.
Speaker 0: That was the cables that I got rid of, basically the top 15 of those, because I was always keeping them.
Speaker 0: I had a lot of micro and mini USB cables.
Speaker 0: And it's like, I have devices that use mini and micro USB still.
Speaker 0: And I'm not going to get rid of those devices because I don't want to, they still work great.
Speaker 1: I kept two of each of those cables that I still use and I already have the rest.
Speaker 0: But I don't need that many.
Speaker 0: I had so many.
Speaker 0: And then I had the black standard power cables.
Speaker 0: It's like, what do I have that uses those?
Speaker 0: Like a handful of things.
Speaker 1: I have a lot.
Speaker 1: All the audio equipment uses those, thankfully.
Speaker 1: Like they standardize.
Speaker 0: But everything that you, most of the things that use them are already plugged in.
Speaker 0: So it's like, how many extras do I need?
Speaker 0: I kept like two or three.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I didn't need, I had like separate.
Speaker 1: You got to have, generally a good idea is have at most of that kind of thing, the one extra that you use, like, oh, hey, I bought a new computer and I need to be able to set it up or something.
Speaker 1: And then the backup, just in case.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, if I buy a new computer, it's going to come with a power supply and the power supply is going to have another one of those fucking cables.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And it's like, I don't need another one of those.
Speaker 0: You just give me the power supply only.
Speaker 0: I don't even need the internal cables.
Speaker 0: My old power supply had a bag of them.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: In fact, internal power supplies, the fact that there are modular ones, we should mandate by law that power supplies like that should be modular and standardized.
Speaker 1: That way I don't even need to get more like that rat's nest of cables.
Speaker 1: I only use three of them, two for the video card, one for the motherboard anyway.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: And then by the standards, if we have standards and they don't change, right.
Speaker 0: When we change the standard from mini to micro to whatever USB, when we change the right, it's like HDMI to display ports, USB-C.
Speaker 0: It's like, what happens is over time, it's like I got the, you know, oh, you know what?
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: A cable.
Speaker 0: I had a lot of the, the USB, a, uh, AB ones where it's big on one end.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: I've got a lot of A to B and A3 to B3.
Speaker 0: The only thing I have that still uses the big one is, oh, there's two things that still use the big one.
Speaker 1: All the old hard drives I'm getting rid of.
Speaker 0: I have a HDMI capture card uses one and the, my scanner uses one.
Speaker 0: So I needed two of those and I had like 10.
Speaker 1: But there was an era where cables were changing a lot because technology was advancing rapidly.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: I would argue now we're at a point where there is a long plateau where we should standardize on, I would say very simply that big old mains power cable that goes in the back of power supplies that keep that standard.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 1: The standard that take in America, that takes mains power into the little left, right?
Speaker 1: The little black that plugs into the back of like an anchor.
Speaker 1: Like that's fine.
Speaker 1: USB-A to C and C to C and display port at most.
Speaker 1: Fuck all the other cables.
Speaker 0: Display port can go on USB-C now.
Speaker 0: It could.
Speaker 1: So we should deprecate regular old display port over time.
Speaker 1: But USB-C is a magic cable that honestly can do everything we're going to need for like a decade to come.
Speaker 1: And if you think I'm wrong, what the fuck are you going to do that USB-C can't do?
Speaker 1: Go read that spec.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So what, you know, unless someone invents something totally new, which hopefully they won't.
Speaker 1: And if they invent something that new and that revolutionary, then technology and society change again, just like they changed when we invented USB-C.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But it's like as if we don't change standards, then people buy stuff.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And they can use that stuff for a long time until it actually breaks, until it's actually no longer working.
Speaker 0: And they don't then we can even start to get more.
Speaker 1: We don't need to give people more of that thing when they buy commodity equipment.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You just don't have to include the, you know, we had to include the cables when you roll stuff out.
Speaker 0: But it's like, I think even at this point, it's like there's enough USB-C cables out there already.
Speaker 0: And if someone goes to a store, like if you go to the store and buy a television, I don't think it comes with an HDMI cable.
Speaker 1: It shouldn't go with any cables by default, I would say.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Best Buy sells HDMI cables, overpriced ones, like Monster Cable.
Speaker 0: That was a whole business, right, of selling bullshit cables.
Speaker 0: But it's like, if you've already got some, don't force some on the people.
Speaker 0: And it's not just the cables, but like, you know, I've already got SD cards.
Speaker 0: You don't need to include one with my digital camera.
Speaker 1: People, the companies do include this partly because they see it as a customer service thing, because people who buy technology often don't know a lot and they like don't know how to deal with cables.
Speaker 0: A non technology person who goes to a store and buys a camera and might be upset, like, oh, because this person in the store has now got to upsell them and all this other shit.
Speaker 1: By default, no technology comes with those commodity cables anymore.
Speaker 1: But when you buy something, kind of like how if you go to a website like Grubhub, there's a checkbox of I want plastic silverware with this order.
Speaker 1: You don't check it.
Speaker 1: You don't get the plastic silverware.
Speaker 1: You should have to say, I want all the cables.
Speaker 1: And if you don't want them, you don't even have to make it cheaper.
Speaker 1: The TV could cost the same either way.
Speaker 1: Just let me the nerd who knows I don't need the cable, not get the cable and start to teach society to keep the cables that work and not expect the new ones with everything they buy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but basically all the accessories that go around a thing need to only, you know, basically should be sold and manufactured separately and distributed and reused for extended periods of time.
Speaker 0: People who buy technology don't end up with a enormous glut of just extra crap that's unnecessary that they then have to redistribute.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So the moral of all this, if you got a ways one, don't buy useless shit you don't need.
Speaker 1: But if you got a bunch of it, which a lot of you probably do, especially if you're a nerd, you were hoarding it and now it's time to get rid of it.
Speaker 1: It's OK to bite that bullet and get rid of a bunch of stuff at once, because as long as you accumulated that over like the last 20 years and you're not continuing to buy useless crap from this point forward, just rip that Band-Aid off.
Speaker 1: You'll be happier.
Speaker 1: But two, throw it away the right way.
Speaker 1: Google, use Google and figure out how to get rid of the things you've got and follow those instructions.
Speaker 1: If you choose not to do that, you're a bad person.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And also your life will be so much better without all that crap line.
Speaker 1: Oh, do you know how good it felt to get rid of the gigantic cabinet that I had filled with worthless cables?
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I got my whole corner of my room here on the floor that no one can see was like a big mess.
Speaker 0: It looked like a like a rat king lived down there.
Speaker 0: And now it's neat and tidy and I have more floor space.
Speaker 1: I threw away a lot of cables that I could not identify what they even fucking plugged into.
Speaker 0: I was able.
Speaker 0: There were some close ones, but I was able to identify all of the weird ones.
Speaker 0: Some of them, some of them are going to go because I don't need them.
Speaker 0: And some of them got put in a bag called Weird USB.
Speaker 0: That's the name on the bag.
Speaker 0: Because one end is USB and the other end is what the fuck is that?
Speaker 1: I got one that was USB on one end and what looks like a headphone jack on the other end.
Speaker 1: I don't know what the fuck that was for.
Speaker 1: Probably something bootleg.
Speaker 0: One of the good ones I had was the HDMI on one end.
Speaker 0: and what the fuck is that on the other end?
Speaker 0: And it was actually the tiny HDMI that goes in a GoPro.
Speaker 0: So I saved two of them.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: Tiny HDMI.
Speaker 1: Also people forget there's mini display port.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of weird cables out there.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I don't have any of those.
Speaker 0: Those are for old Macs.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I did not have a single VGA cable.
Speaker 1: I am proud of myself.
Speaker 0: I have exactly one VGA and one DVI and I got rid of all the other ones a long time ago.
Speaker 1: I got rid of DVI and VGA too.
Speaker 1: Fuck them.
Speaker 0: I still have a couple things that have a VGA port on them.
Speaker 0: Oh, that is true.
Speaker 0: They're not in regular use, but it could always happen.
Speaker 1: I decided if I am in a situation where I need a VGA cable and I do not have one.
Speaker 0: You can use my VGA cable.
Speaker 0: I will lend it to you.
Speaker 0: That will be the most eco-friendly option.
Speaker 1: But let's say you got rid of it too.
Speaker 1: I would say that I would accept that fate.
Speaker 1: Like a Greek hero, a Greek hero who's like, I am going to hubris against the gods.
Speaker 1: And then when the gods strike me down, the only response is, you know what?
Speaker 1: A hubris?
Speaker 1: I welcome this lightning bolt.
Speaker 0: Well actually, but that's it, right?
Speaker 0: So UK, you're hubris.
Speaker 0: You need the VGA cable.
Speaker 0: You don't know me and I don't, you can't get mine.
Speaker 0: Guess what?
Speaker 0: You're going to find someone else in the neighborhood who's got one.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And if you're at a convention.
Speaker 0: You could be on the receiving end of helping someone out.
Speaker 0: Do you need a 200 megabyte hard drive?
Speaker 0: You could find someone who's just going to give you one for free.
Speaker 0: Go on your Craigslist or your Facebook marketplace or your local, whatever.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: Don't go buy one.
Speaker 0: I found a one.
Speaker 1: I found a, uh, a 500.
Speaker 0: That would be a fun, this, I guess this, this would be really fun.
Speaker 0: How many getting, if you only collected free stuff from people where you live, how many, regardless of performance or quality, how many functioning computers could you construct with free stuff from the neighborhood?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Pick some minimum line.
Speaker 1: Like could it launch a web browser?
Speaker 0: Can you install a Linux distribution and boot it?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Can you boot a Linux period by any means?
Speaker 1: I think I could build a couple of computers just out of shit laying around the house, to be honest.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 0: I don't have any egg motherboards lying around.
Speaker 1: I did get rid of some motherboards that I had.
Speaker 0: I don't have any.
Speaker 1: I'm down to.
Speaker 1: every motherboard I got is in a computer and currently powered.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: And the Patreon patrons for this specific episode of Geek Nights, which was a long one because that's what happens anytime.
Speaker 1: Scott and I don't do a show for a little while, are Alan Joyce, Linki G, Dread, Lily, Tenebrae, Case, Care, Makes Music, Chris, Hadad, Clinton, Walton, Dex, Finn, Joel Haze, Penny Reimer, Rebecca Dunn, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Harl, and many, many people who give less than five dollars a month.
Speaker 1: because while I won't say your name, your support is appreciated and you get access to all those custom RSS feeds and other nonsense without having to pay more than a dollar a month.
Speaker 1: But anyway, tonight, first what I'll tell you is Scott and I were talking about doing a panel at Zenkai Con Online, and Scott wasn't super-feeling it, so I just recorded the whole thing on my own.
Speaker 1: So it'll be on YouTube at some point, but it'll be premiered at Zenkai Con Online, and it's just a panel about what goes on behind the scenes at cons.
Speaker 1: And I have a call to action, so I'm going to post a link in the description of this episode.
Speaker 1: If you do anything at conventions other than attending or being in the artist alley, I say we don't care about the artist alley because people have talked about that artist alley to death, like there's no new stories there.
Speaker 1: If you do anything else for a convention, like you're staff, you're a janitor, you work in a hotel, you're like event staff, you're the cop who has to stand outside of cons, we want to hear from you.
Speaker 1: I've got a link to a survey, we are real interested in what it's like for you, or the people who do those kinds of jobs, when nerd conventions are happening.
Speaker 1: But beyond that, I simply leave you right now with...
Speaker 0: Bum bum bum, ba dum ba dum, a duck walked up to a lemonade stand, and he said to the man running the stand, "Well Seymour, I made it, despite your
Speaker 0: directions.".
Speaker 1: The man said, "Ah, Superintendent Chalmers, welcome.
Speaker 1: I hope you're prepared for an unforgettable
Speaker 1: luncheon.".
Speaker 1: The duck said,
Speaker 1: "Eh.".
Speaker 1: Then he waddled away, waddle waddle, 'til the very next day, bum bum bum bum bum bum bum, when the duck walked up to the lemonade stand, and he said to the man running the stand,
Speaker 1: "Seymour!".
Speaker 1: Bum bum bum.
Speaker 1: "Why is there smoke coming out of your oven,
Speaker 1: Seymour?".
Speaker 0: The man said, "Oh, that isn't smoke, it's steam, steam from the steamed clams we're having.
Speaker 0: Mmm, steamed
Speaker 0: clams.".
Speaker 1: The duck said,
Speaker 1: "Eh.".
Speaker 1: Then he waddled away, waddle waddle, then he waddled away, waddle waddle, then he waddled away, waddle waddle, 'til the very next day, bum bum bum bum bum bum...