Speaker 0: it's Tuesday July 25th 2023.
Speaker 0: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight we're talking about can't stop and all my diamonds let's do this.
Speaker 0: oh yeah I haven't done a show in a minute.
Speaker 0: we uh we had a vacation.
Speaker 0: we actually went away.
Speaker 1: well you know it's uh.
Speaker 1: we thought hey you know we're not doing anything but working but actually you know stuff keeps happening right and run out of show ideas.
Speaker 1: also holidays and yeah whatever.
Speaker 1: no one's paying us to do this.
Speaker 0: so indirectly via YouTube premium and advertisers people are paying us dozens of dollars to do this.
Speaker 1: yeah okay well you know I'm not seeing any of that.
Speaker 0: it's got its cover in the Libsyn and a couple other things.
Speaker 0: but yeah we uh that was a longer hiatus than we've taken in a while.
Speaker 0: so everything that happened whatever we don't talk about today is gonna be forgotten.
Speaker 0: we will never think of it again and we'll be struggling to come up with what to say at the start of the next geek night.
Speaker 1: the next to the next show will only have two days of material to look back at.
Speaker 0: we're like a cue that flushes itself on access every time.
Speaker 0: if we pull stuff out of the stack the rest of the stack gets dropped?
Speaker 1: yeah pretty much it's only what has happened since the last time we spoke.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: but I mean you know that's not it's really how.
Speaker 1: radio era.
Speaker 1: if we were some morning radio show yeah you would only talk about even if they took a hiatus and came back.
Speaker 1: it's like you'd only talk about what happened yesterday unless it was something that was so big.
Speaker 0: but the line for what is so big is so high for geek nights or for me and Scott in particular at least right.
Speaker 1: I mean you know you would only talk about the past if like your topic was.
Speaker 1: you know if you had a main bit you know it's a anyway yep.
Speaker 0: but so where we where we vacation was actually moderately interesting because I did just on Airbnb.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: it's not like don't think that I pulled strings or anything but on Airbnb I was looking for a place that would fit like you know 20 ish people.
Speaker 1: well here's the thing is if you want to have a part if you want to get an Airbnb that has a lot of people right and it doesn't get you kicked out for partying and cramming in too many people yeah you really only have two choices.
Speaker 1: choice number one is like big mansion for a lot of money right?
Speaker 1: oh there's three choices actually.
Speaker 1: the second choice is some sort of compound campground cult place right where there's many small houses and like maybe a main meeting house.
Speaker 0: I should see if we could rent an old cult compound some year.
Speaker 1: oh there's plenty of those you can get like in the Catskills.
Speaker 1: yeah all kinds of anyway.
Speaker 1: and the third option which is the option we tend to go for is basically building that used to be a brothel even though no one says so.
Speaker 1: the read.
Speaker 1: the way you can tell that the building used to be a brothel is that the bottom floor right will have large social rooms big dining rooms living rooms a big kitchen that can serve many people.
Speaker 1: right that that's kind of place.
Speaker 1: and upstairs right we'll have many small bedrooms right.
Speaker 1: the place we stayed at technically was like what civic hat?
Speaker 0: right?
Speaker 0: so it was.
Speaker 0: I actually know the full history of this house.
Speaker 0: this was not brothel though it has the similar format to a bra.
Speaker 1: I think it was a brothel and they just refused to say so.
Speaker 0: well it was sort of a rate.
Speaker 1: they have scrubbed their history - right I'll go a little.
Speaker 0: why?
Speaker 1: why would a civic house have all those bedrooms upstairs?
Speaker 1: that makes no sense.
Speaker 1: so why would have any bedrooms?
Speaker 0: while I am confident that brothel like things have occurred at many points in this house's history this type of beach house was very common in America on the Jersey Shore and basically rich people like the guy who built this house.
Speaker 1: yes brothels were common.
Speaker 0: no this was his house.
Speaker 0: he was the first mayor.
Speaker 0: basically he founded Wildwood and this was his house.
Speaker 0: but he structured it as a civic club because he would invite prominent politicians and famous people.
Speaker 0: they felt hey New Jersey come stay in my house like Woodrow Wilson wasn't president.
Speaker 0: when he was staying there he was like the governor of New Jersey.
Speaker 1: yes he was visiting a problem just like everyone did.
Speaker 0: this was not a brothel that stage.
Speaker 0: well I see the pattern because the stage now a stage stage but this house was used in the 30s and 40s for a lot of weddings and also civic clubs would basically have their meetings there with the blessing of whoever owned the place at the time.
Speaker 0: there was all.
Speaker 0: there's all history to it.
Speaker 0: yes but no finding a. finding the house.
Speaker 1: it was many small bedrooms upstairs.
Speaker 0: I mean they weren't that small.
Speaker 0: this was more like think of it more like there was a.
Speaker 1: there was it.
Speaker 1: there was a hallway off the main hallway that had like three tiny bedrooms in it.
Speaker 0: well that's like that's for like the valleys of the rich people who were staying here.
Speaker 0: this is brothel adjacent.
Speaker 0: this was rich.
Speaker 0: people are coming to Wildwood and staying there as part of political shenanigans.
Speaker 0: this is this is grass and against stages and shenanigans.
Speaker 1: all right anyway anyway.
Speaker 0: but the water.
Speaker 1: the point is we've gotten at least two if not more air B&Bs of this name I mean the waterfall house was not best one because the waterfall house waterfall house was the same exact.
Speaker 1: it wasn't the same exact layout but the same principle of at the bottom there were large large spaces and upstairs many small bedroom.
Speaker 0: well I think the key was that upstairs the many small bedrooms were all connected to a room that had a large stage on it and the bedrooms were about the size of a small twin bed each and the owners were like yeah this was a fucking brothel.
Speaker 0: you want to know the history.
Speaker 0: but to give you all a vision of this that house that waterfall house not the one we stayed in a wild with the waterfall house.
Speaker 0: it looked a lot like the house in phantasmagoria
Speaker 1: like yeah if you want to stay an Airbnb with all a lot of many friends right find a house an old one that used to be a brothel and everything about it will be great except for the fact that it's old.
Speaker 1: but you're not staying there that long.
Speaker 1: so who really cares?
Speaker 0: yep it was a pretty cool place.
Speaker 0: I would stay there again.
Speaker 0: and of course we're worried like oh it's a face of semi-famous historic house and the owners are really like oh you guys are old right and I literally described like look I work in capital markets.
Speaker 0: we're a bunch of aging sedate nerds.
Speaker 0: we're not gonna throw a party.
Speaker 0: and afterward they sent me a message that was like holy shit you guys took care of this house like you.
Speaker 1: mess up our hat what you didn't.
Speaker 0: mess up our house.
Speaker 1: yep it's just like it was when we left.
Speaker 1: it can great.
Speaker 0: they also while they were like no parties no like strict everything we found when we got there several packages of glow-in-the-dark ping-pong balls yet no ping-pong table which is some environmental storytelling as to what whoever stayed there last use this house for.
Speaker 0: so in the news you know I'm a big fan of overwatch the game but you might have noticed I don't talk a lot about overwatch league like I'll watch games.
Speaker 1: well you know we talked about it a bit back in the day.
Speaker 0: yeah but in terms of like I guess I am not a back in the day like one two years ago.
Speaker 0: I have never been a fan of an eSports team or person to the degree that I've been a fan of even like an amateur sports team like real physical hitting people type sports at any point.
Speaker 1: none of them have really done anything to like.
Speaker 1: you know engender you know loyalty history like all I care about them.
Speaker 0: like overwatch league literally didn't care who won I just watched the matches because I wanted to see the top tier of play.
Speaker 0: like that is all I wanted out of a professional league.
Speaker 1: they're like there was a New York team and I was like oh sure yeah and I was like oh we should check out that New York team.
Speaker 1: but then there was really nothing New York about them except their name.
Speaker 0: nope because almost all the players were from overseas anyway and all the games were having on the West Coast for reasons.
Speaker 0: and then COVID happened and long story short overwatch league for a previous economic era.
Speaker 0: when I say previous I mean like just recently because things have shifted radically just in the last couple of years they were doing everything right like many eSports leagues were in terms of you mirror what professional sports are doing.
Speaker 0: yeah act like it's bigger than it is till it becomes bigger.
Speaker 0: you get the money from the sponsors like they were structuring it like sports and they were trying to emulate the things that make sports fandom successful and in that previous economic climate I don't think that was a bad bet.
Speaker 0: the problem is that entire ecosystem in both real sports and eSports relies on exactly one source of dollars.
Speaker 0: that matters and that source of dollars is sponsorships and advertising.
Speaker 1: and guess what you could also you can also get a TV deal but the TV.
Speaker 1: no one's gonna give you the TV deal unless they can get the ads.
Speaker 0: yeah all the ways you can think of to monetize this other than direct selling merch which being in the t-shirt business is not the way you want to be.
Speaker 0: being in the other way is the way you want to be.
Speaker 1: the other thing you can do with sports is sell tickets to attendance but eSports can never really do that like once a year for like their lol dota championships and I don't know how if that's still any of it then like as much as I like.
Speaker 0: overwatch is my favorite multiplayer competitive game right now by a wide margin but even there there is zero reason to see that in person.
Speaker 0: I want to sit in a room with a bunch of people watching people sit on a stage where otherwise I could be sitting at home with five camera angles.
Speaker 1: right it's like you need.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: regular sports.
Speaker 1: it's like yes you can watch it with ads and then we can we actually have a superior way to experience spectation.
Speaker 1: yeah right that cannot be rivaled and cannot be pirated or duplicated unless you pay money.
Speaker 1: and that is coming to see it with your own eyeballs.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: and even if it's not better it's at least different.
Speaker 1: yeah in a meaningful way that you might be willing to pay.
Speaker 0: like American football it's kind of objectively worse unless you're looking for specific things out of the experience.
Speaker 0: or you are very rich but or your team's terrible.
Speaker 1: but you know hockey is just better.
Speaker 1: tennis is usually just better not that it's bad on TV right baseball is not so much better but different and has charms.
Speaker 0: it says that is a very diplomatic way to put that.
Speaker 1: but yeah it's like there's.
Speaker 1: there are reasons to attend live sporting events and pay money for it and it's not a waste of.
Speaker 1: but attending eSports in person might actually just be worse than watching at home on your computer yep.
Speaker 0: so uh Overwatch League was doing everything right but the advertisers dried up.
Speaker 0: advertising in sports is down from the data I was able to pull up preparing to talk about this.
Speaker 0: advertising in eSports has except gambling ads yeah gambling ads but that's it's gambling ads car ads beverage ads pretty much nothing else.
Speaker 0: actually the bifurcation of the advertising market is kind of nuts.
Speaker 0: total aside gold ads like invest in gold literally only exist in Fox News and no other networks.
Speaker 1: yeah that makes sense.
Speaker 0: yep that makes a lot of sense and the more you think about it the more sense it makes.
Speaker 0: so.
Speaker 0: but meanwhile Google just announced Google search making more money than ever.
Speaker 0: their ads are doing better than everyone else.
Speaker 0: so I think and now it's speculation.
Speaker 1: here's what I move with all their even though search results are getting worse.
Speaker 0: yeah search results are getting worse.
Speaker 0: I think it's just my suspicion is very specific but this is just speculation.
Speaker 0: my bet is across the board.
Speaker 0: everyone is reducing advertising for a lot of reasons but I think they're sending a higher percentage of their remaining advertising to the small number of advertising venues that they believe have the highest return which I say it's like our places that buy ads decreasing their ad budget.
Speaker 1: or are they redirecting it?
Speaker 0: yep or both.
Speaker 0: and I do think both because I saw a lot of numbers arguing that the overall advertising spend in America is dropping and consolidating right cuz.
Speaker 1: see this is the thing is like when you have a big company.
Speaker 1: it's like they just sort of decide like at the beginning of the year or me you know.
Speaker 1: maybe if the quarter if they're really micromanaging it like we are going to spend X dollars on buying ads the end right and it's like then the people who in the marketing department their job is to spend all of those dollars right.
Speaker 1: so it's like if they're left with like a million dollars at the end it's they're just like oh what should we do?
Speaker 1: let's go let's just fight.
Speaker 1: there's constantly finding ways to spend that money right.
Speaker 1: it's like they're not.
Speaker 1: you know they are to some extent trying to measure the effectiveness and get the most bang for their buck but in a lot of cases not really.
Speaker 1: they're just trying to spend it all.
Speaker 0: but so eSports we're kind of a bubble for advertising in that they're unlike other places you could put an ad that is an untested place like I. personally don't think ads are very effective in a lot of venues.
Speaker 0: but eSports don't even have the the veneer of a history of generating a return on investment.
Speaker 0: and the kinds of people who are into eSports and AGDQ type things like video gaming in any capacity in a serious or elevated context are also the kinds of people who block ads or don't want to see ads and done
Speaker 1: oh maybe but I mean I think it's just simple.
Speaker 1: is that like hey you know the eSports had a bunch of viewers right the viewership was a big enough number that they could go to a sponsor and say hey do you want to sponsor this?
Speaker 1: no one else's.
Speaker 0: and the viewership is huge.
Speaker 0: the viewership remains high despite the drop in advertising right.
Speaker 1: so someone says all right no one's ever advertised on this before right?
Speaker 1: we don't know if it's gonna work or not.
Speaker 1: but we see the eyeball numbers are big.
Speaker 1: so yeah I'll give you some money I'll be I'll put my logo up there big time I'll sponsor you big time and we'll see what happens.
Speaker 1: and then they see what they give it some time right they don't?
Speaker 1: they you know and they see what happens and then they decide hey this wasn't worth it I'm gonna not renew this deal bye-bye right.
Speaker 1: and then they're in trouble because it's like.
Speaker 1: well they didn't renew the deal and now getting someone else but like bye I get you know you know you can't get that person to buy.
Speaker 1: to getting anyone else to buy is not much more difficult right?
Speaker 1: if the first person had renewed everyone else would say oh that must be a good deal.
Speaker 1: I got to get in on that too.
Speaker 1: right and it's.
Speaker 1: it's a very snowball.
Speaker 1: one direction or the other.
Speaker 1: it snowballs uphill or now.
Speaker 0: so I did see another number.
Speaker 0: this was from a news source that I don't have secondary car like this.
Speaker 0: I'm reporting a direct number.
Speaker 0: I saw from a disclosure but I haven't read like reporting around it yet.
Speaker 0: but it's stated very specifically that viewership of twitch and YouTube game streams are both significantly down in 2023 compared to 2022 2021 2020 and it seems to correlate specifically to when people started going out and doing things again after COVID winds down slowly and the streaming were like.
Speaker 0: people are streaming less now than they did before COVID.
Speaker 0: in the context of video games at least now that is hard because this is like a disclose a financial disclosure type number.
Speaker 0: it's hard to like twitch and YouTube like you could probably make up numbers based on their data to say any story you want about trends and viewership.
Speaker 0: but I feel like we might see that the streaming world has shrunk a little bit as people go outside again.
Speaker 0: hmm so there's even worse stuff going on in eSports because independent of that Overwatch League was already in trouble for a bunch of other reasons.
Speaker 0: remember a while back like we basically said Blizzard games can't be in China anymore because of that drama with NetEase.
Speaker 0: so the Chinese Overwatch teams were kind of in a pickle because how are they gonna practice if the game is not available legally in their country?
Speaker 0: so one of the Chinese teams just said fuck it and quit the league like they just gave up.
Speaker 1: yeah they can't.
Speaker 1: why waste your time right?
Speaker 1: it's like you got.
Speaker 1: you got life to live.
Speaker 1: you got to go.
Speaker 1: you know eat get food.
Speaker 1: yep you got to go play.
Speaker 1: if you're gonna play games you gotta at least play.
Speaker 1: pick a different game right?
Speaker 1: you got to start practicing.
Speaker 1: every day you don't play a different game you're falling behind.
Speaker 0: what are you gonna do like go to a camp like in the US or Europe or like Singapore to train for your video game for your right for your whole you know to invest your life like that.
Speaker 1: it's like you know you can't.
Speaker 1: you know there has to be some sort of you know light at the end of the tunnel to for to be worth that investment.
Speaker 1: some people do that for something like an Olympic gold medal which you know ends up not actually getting you much money or any money like there's a.
Speaker 0: I feel like a lot of people think it's worth it to be able to doing it right but but other people?
Speaker 1: well yeah I'll dedicate my entire life to playing baseball because if I if I do it right yeah I'll make tens of millions of dollars and you'll get Michi flower power who dedicates his entire life to Super Mario 3. all right it's like you know.
Speaker 1: but if you if dedicating your life to overwatch has no way of paying out why the fuck you know would you do it?
Speaker 1: I beyond the level to which you simply enjoy play?
Speaker 0: I love overwatch and I think it is an expertly designed game but at the same time I spend like several hours a week playing it tops and it's my top competitive game.
Speaker 0: so not high not super high on the priority list of trying to get better than like silver or gold.
Speaker 0: but anyway overwatch league is in trouble for unrelated reasons.
Speaker 0: it hasn't been going well for all these different things that I'll link to some articles you can read.
Speaker 0: but basically they are the all the teams have to vote on whether or not they're going to continue the league under an amended operating agreement.
Speaker 0: and basically to summarize the teams can either vote to continue to be an overwatch league or they can vote.
Speaker 0: they can decide individually to accept a six million dollar termination payment from Blizzard and then shut.
Speaker 1: it's pretty good.
Speaker 1: well pretty good.
Speaker 0: so that's six million payable to each one of these teams is as best I can tell sort of a consolation prize to make up for the fact that they all paid significantly higher fees to be a team in the first place.
Speaker 1: and now the week is.
Speaker 1: I thought they were I thought it was all.
Speaker 1: all the teams were.
Speaker 1: oh I didn't realize.
Speaker 1: the teams that individual ownership.
Speaker 0: oh there's.
Speaker 0: there's the whole franchise agreement and there's a lot.
Speaker 0: there's a lot.
Speaker 0: they really doubled down on structuring this like quote real sports which well that's the thing is that you know.
Speaker 1: but real sports there are two different ways to do real sports.
Speaker 1: one is where the league owns all the teams and the other way is where all the teams are individually owned and usually when you're just starting out you'll have the league own all the team until they have lots and lots of value.
Speaker 1: right and it's like you know.
Speaker 0: and then what will the rich person be like?
Speaker 0: I would like to have an eSports team.
Speaker 0: here's four hundred million dollars.
Speaker 0: give me one right.
Speaker 1: or imagine if you know.
Speaker 1: just think of a sport a league.
Speaker 1: you already know baseball right.
Speaker 1: it's like okay the major league baseball owns every single.
Speaker 1: this never worked that way but major league baseball owned all the teams and then it's like the Yankees become the fucking Yankees.
Speaker 1: and it's like hey someone comes along and it's like yeah I can buy the Yankees.
Speaker 1: it's like now you can.
Speaker 1: it's like oh shit.
Speaker 1: and then people start bidding for it.
Speaker 1: right and then the league ends up just selling off all the teams.
Speaker 0: and that's sort of like the IPO yeah of the league because you're hoping in the secondary market potential expansions down the road league fees like all the monitors.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of a lot of ways.
Speaker 1: well the league itself would not be you know that's.
Speaker 1: the other thing is that you know sports leagues are usually nonprofits.
Speaker 1: right it's the teams that are supposed to be profitable right and the league is just sort of this governing body.
Speaker 1: but when you have it an e-sport there's a and you have the company that makes the game running the e-sport.
Speaker 1: the e-sport is a marketing arm that's supposed to make money for the company by you know selling copies of the game.
Speaker 1: but also they're hoping to make money off the e-sport part directly and it's like if you're the governing body it's like no you're just sort of running a league and the teams are supposed to make money.
Speaker 1: and if you're a video game company with a profit motive you can't really operate something like that.
Speaker 1: but so reporting sport always has to be a specific game which is gonna be a game made by a for-profit.
Speaker 0: come reporting from the second half of last year claims that Activision Blizzard was owed four hundred million dollars in unpaid franchise fees for overwatch and Call of Duty leagues and they had postponed all those payments due to kovat.
Speaker 0: but now the leagues aren't doing well and like more nonsense is about to happen.
Speaker 1: yeah I think you know eSports in general.
Speaker 1: I don't know how well I'm not paying attention to all the eSports but what it feels like to me based on you know the eSports that I do see is that you know no individual there are some legal edges is still big.
Speaker 1: the fortnight's are still big right.
Speaker 1: there's still.
Speaker 1: there's still big one.
Speaker 0: they're not big like the league's wanted them to appear.
Speaker 0: they're not big like sports sports.
Speaker 1: they're big in some places to some audiences.
Speaker 1: the fighting games are big right but I think what's happened is that people are competing at lots and lots of games right in small highly organized communities.
Speaker 1: if you go on twitch you can see competitions and tournaments and all kinds of things.
Speaker 1: forget the random.
Speaker 0: look at the randomizer communities.
Speaker 0: those are fully formed eSports leagues.
Speaker 0: they're just tiny right.
Speaker 1: they're just tiny and I think there's just.
Speaker 1: there's an extremely long tale of very healthy eSports that are not in any one of them individually is not enough to make money for real.
Speaker 0: it could make plenty of money for humans and life but not enough money for capital to give a shit right.
Speaker 1: so it's like competing at video games is maybe healthier than it's ever been but making a single video game that is a you know thing unto itself with it with a professional competitive thing that provides careers for athletes and a whole bunch of other people as a whole industry.
Speaker 1: I don't know we would need a new game to come around for that to happen.
Speaker 1: and could that game have enough staying power right?
Speaker 0: no game has done it and at this point.
Speaker 0: well also the final news.
Speaker 1: I mean some games have done it.
Speaker 1: you know your counter-strikes and your lols.
Speaker 1: but it's like you know and they have.
Speaker 1: the numbers on the viewers are big but you yep.
Speaker 0: so Blizzard also.
Speaker 0: they seem to have just given up.
Speaker 0: they laid off like their entire eSports division.
Speaker 1: well they've like they've keep it.
Speaker 1: see I don't know how many eSports people they have left because it's like years ago.
Speaker 1: they laid off eSports people.
Speaker 1: they did 50 more and it's like how many are left.
Speaker 1: you look at the Blizzard website.
Speaker 1: it's like they still have eSports events scheduled.
Speaker 0: how many people are left there?
Speaker 0: so an insider who did wasn't to be named in one of these articles said yeah with the few people they have left I don't know how they continue to operate any of this.
Speaker 1: it's gonna be a skeleton crew to shut down right I think that's what you're gonna see within a year or some chain.
Speaker 1: yeah right this they're just gonna.
Speaker 1: I stop doing.
Speaker 0: I think eSports are gonna have to come back in a very different form and I still think those the communities are strong because gaming is very popular and very important to humans.
Speaker 0: but monetizing games and gaming is not compatible with capitalism in a way that works today I think.
Speaker 1: I think if I was if I was a game maker right and I wanted there to be a competitive scene to you know as it's as a marketing thing right it's the competitive scene only exists because I only really make money by selling the game right.
Speaker 0: so more play is clearly selling.
Speaker 1: the league is not gonna make money right and there are players who will play it for competitive reasons and I can get money from them.
Speaker 1: so what I would do is I would just build in features in the game you know to make competitive play good right.
Speaker 1: and then I would create you know I'd spend some a marketing budget on prizes and then I would see the players would naturally organize right their discord servers it and I would pick the well-organized players and I'd be like that tournament there his prizes official prizes for that tournament.
Speaker 0: that's all I would do is I would just if one of those right I would just exponential back off if one of those little leagues like makes it big.
Speaker 0: you approach them you acquire them you use that to try the other business model.
Speaker 1: you don't need to go that far I think they.
Speaker 1: just you think you they don't cost you anything to run but you just provide prizes to them as legitimacy and that brings in players and brings you know another way to go.
Speaker 1: you're gonna make all your money by selling lots of copies of that game.
Speaker 0: I think there's two other like broad ways to go that are better crazy ideas because the next way would be.
Speaker 0: people have attempted this but never really at a good scale.
Speaker 0: but the cross games Olympic style eSport run by a nonprofit that like decides what games are part of the event like the Olympics like.
Speaker 0: no one's really tried that effectively.
Speaker 0: I also don't know if it's basically GDQ.
Speaker 1: we already have GDQ.
Speaker 1: it exists.
Speaker 0: it's like except you know you make it more you know like structured kind of like the Olympics.
Speaker 0: hmm the way that I think could make the most I don't know.
Speaker 1: if the cult you know I don't know.
Speaker 1: if there's enough people who have the culture of caring about who wins you know - well the thing is that's where the year I think you're raising point.
Speaker 0: that's where the Olympics a big chunk of the audience are people who have nationalist or personal reasons to care who wins.
Speaker 0: but like when I watch the Olympics there's a subset of people I just want to see these exhibitions of skill like I want to see the human.
Speaker 1: that's but that's that's what GDQ does.
Speaker 1: they just think so there you go the end.
Speaker 1: they don't need the competition part and they don't have it and the competition could in a way be strong as strong as ever.
Speaker 0: yeah the third way to go the way that I think would be the coolest and I would love to see someone try it.
Speaker 0: I don't have enough money to do it or I would try it.
Speaker 0: you got to combine in equal parts the Harlem Globetrotters the WWE and eSports.
Speaker 1: in some WWE part is definitely the part that's missing right.
Speaker 0: I want to see the.
Speaker 0: I want to see the GDQ person exhibiting the extreme skill in the same way that a WWE wrestler is exhibiting.
Speaker 1: extreme of them do a few but yeah not.
Speaker 0: but I want to see that coupled with the narrative.
Speaker 0: it's not really a fair competition.
Speaker 0: you are setting up the experience to be amazing like you're setting up the eSports.
Speaker 0: have the crazy thing happen and then you mix in the Harlem Globetrotters like someone pulls off the glitch in the middle of the match and you'd like you make it enter script semi scripted entertainment.
Speaker 0: that involves exhibitions of skill but I do not have the money or the connections to push that.
Speaker 0: nor do I have the energy to try to push that.
Speaker 0: somebody's gonna do it someday and I'd say there's a 15 or 20 percent chance they make a lot of money and an a 75 to 80 percent chance they lose everything.
Speaker 1: it's and I think it's just hard to do that in a video game.
Speaker 0: well that's where you got to cross things a little bit.
Speaker 0: you got to be clever I don't know.
Speaker 0: maybe it's like chess boxing biathlon.
Speaker 0: you're playing airsoft and overwatch or airsoft and counter-strike.
Speaker 0: you got to do both.
Speaker 1: you need to devise some special game that like someone's controlling behind this.
Speaker 1: yeah that's right.
Speaker 1: or just pre record the game and two people sit there with controllers.
Speaker 1: however you do is two actors yet two actors pretend to push buttons while the video plays.
Speaker 0: you script it to the level that the WWE is scripted like you go all out on.
Speaker 0: the entertainment is the goal.
Speaker 1: competition is the fiction right but I'm saying is that there is some improv element to the.
Speaker 1: you know professional wrestling that you can't have with a video game because the video game itself is rigid.
Speaker 0: unless those people with such high skill imagine if two of the best a GDQ runners who both know one game really well we're doing a fake competition where they are working with each other to make interesting things happen on purpose.
Speaker 1: it's like yes they might but it's like if it's live.
Speaker 1: then it's like even those people are not perfect because it's so difficult right.
Speaker 0: so well it might not have to be perfect.
Speaker 0: I mean the.
Speaker 1: the kayfabe survives despite wrestling being hyper telegraph because you're just a human being and you can fudge it.
Speaker 1: the ref can be like you know count slowly or you know you can wait before you slam somebody right.
Speaker 1: it's like in Street Fighter.
Speaker 1: it's like the timer is ticking but the health meter is there right.
Speaker 0: maybe you know.
Speaker 0: open-ended fortnight.
Speaker 0: in the event where you know the things coming in you have an agreement.
Speaker 0: look this person's gonna win.
Speaker 1: don't kill them that's yep sure but it's like you know things can happen.
Speaker 0: I mean things can't like a WWE.
Speaker 0: sometimes the wrong person wins because whatever was failed and they have to do a backup plan and they like have to do some shenanigans.
Speaker 0: last minute I just watched it's.
Speaker 1: that's pretty rare.
Speaker 0: it's pretty rare but I watched a documentary recently about this old ladder match for like someone fell off the ladder and they changed.
Speaker 0: who won like a mid-match to make it work anyway?
Speaker 0: anyway?
Speaker 0: got any news that should we get into?
Speaker 1: and we talked too long.
Speaker 1: sports is a doing poorly things of the day.
Speaker 0: so I work with a lot of German engineers.
Speaker 0: I spent a lot of time in Germany.
Speaker 0: I did my current job and I've always enjoyed Germany.
Speaker 0: but this YouTube channel Kelvin and Habs is great because it's basically.
Speaker 0: the conceit is you've got an American and a German and they explain the less well-known cultural or societal concepts in their respective cultures to each other under the auspices of their roommates like hey I moved to Germany I'm an American.
Speaker 0: well what do I need to know?
Speaker 0: or I'm German I'm living in America.
Speaker 0: what the fuck is AC and why do you have it like?
Speaker 0: it's funny but it's kind of talking about the things you wouldn't know unless you moved to Germany.
Speaker 0: let's say and then we're confused by the culture and had to realize that if you rent an apartment the kitchen doesn't come with any appliances like.
Speaker 0: that's just not a thing in Germany like bring your own appliances.
Speaker 1: and if that sounds like I'd like to bring my own appliances yeah that would be nice.
Speaker 0: yeah yeah but how the fuck would you have even thought about that until you're like talking to an agent over there like hopefully you're like hey I'm dumb American.
Speaker 0: is there anything I'm missing?
Speaker 0: but this one is a good one because it's about the Schreiber gardens.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of unspoken cultural norms in Germany that I transgress upon accidentally constantly and my teams are very good at like politely pointing out like oh yeah that's not how it works here but the Schreiber gardens are really fun concepts.
Speaker 0: that's my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: it's a 60-second video.
Speaker 0: this will explain to you what a Schreiber garden is and how that's different from a regular gotten and why you are not allowed to fucking talk in Schreiber gardens.
Speaker 1: you sit there and quiet is three but just mean quiet.
Speaker 0: basically they're private gardens.
Speaker 0: so imagine in New York okay you got Central Park Bryant Park all these meds.
Speaker 0: they're public.
Speaker 0: people can kind of do their private their private one.
Speaker 0: oh yeah but in the public parks people can kind of do whatever they want.
Speaker 0: like people tend to be loud.
Speaker 1: rules yeah but yeah people are loud.
Speaker 0: there are not a lot of social conventions in these parks.
Speaker 0: but like you can't play ball games in Bryant Park but you can play ball games in certain parts of Central Park for example the private gardens these Schreiber gardens.
Speaker 0: they're like the private gardens in New York except the people who share them.
Speaker 0: they tend to be used in a very particular way and this video does a very good job of explaining this particular German concepts.
Speaker 0: so what do you got?
Speaker 1: so here's this website that I guess who knows how old this website is and I just never came across.
Speaker 0: it looks well it looks old but that is definitely on purpose.
Speaker 1: yeah it's a chiptune dot app.
Speaker 1: it looks like a DOS command-line GUI with the blue background from some old IBM ps1 or something.
Speaker 1: but it's it's all JavaScript and you just click on search or browse and they have over 200,000 chiptunes to listen to from all the old video games just right there.
Speaker 1: so if there's some like video game ost from I don't know some old Famicom or sharp X 68,000 MDX or this folder called jazz MIDI oh wow it's more than just like what I was thinking about in chiptunes.
Speaker 1: I gotta poke around in this more because under that meeting directory that whatever whatever foul browsh v2 is I could Google and find out but so can you.
Speaker 0: this looks a lot like the stuff that was on Vikram's in the day.
Speaker 1: there's 200,000 plus audio files to listen to of chiptune enjoyment just in a little JavaScript player in your web browser for free with no ads all right.
Speaker 0: so like I got to make a cocktail and spend an evening poking around in here yeah the fine.
Speaker 1: find some buried treasures in there and then there's a favorites tab where you can save your favorites to go back to them quickly.
Speaker 0: if the Vikram stuff is in here died this will.
Speaker 0: this means I don't have to try to get the data off of the one hard drive I ever had that died and it looks like it is based on my memory.
Speaker 0: anyway I'm at a moment the geek nights book club book.
Speaker 0: I gotta reopen the geek nights website cuz I closed the tab.
Speaker 0: it is this is how you lose the time war by Amal El-Mothar and Max Gladstone.
Speaker 0: we should be doing this show on Thursday.
Speaker 0: it is a very short book.
Speaker 0: you have not read it by tonight and you're listening to geek nights.
Speaker 0: I think you could read this book in.
Speaker 1: you got time.
Speaker 0: two to three hours tops.
Speaker 1: like you'll you'll make it in time for the Thursday two nights from now.
Speaker 0: it's a quick read and I got some things to say about it mm-hmm and I'll leave it at that.
Speaker 0: but yeah then I guess we're gonna have to pick the next book club book.
Speaker 0: it's gonna be on me to do a choice again.
Speaker 0: do I bring back Uber to echo and I gotta figure out what I'm gonna make the choices?
Speaker 1: yeah you could.
Speaker 1: you could just keep bringing back the same one and only you know.
Speaker 1: loser or winner walks loser keeps trying again like the Omega thon or whatever trying to figure out what my personal rules are gonna be for that.
Speaker 0: like if I bring a book more than n times and it doesn't get picked I feel like that is a sign from the heavens.
Speaker 1: I just decided that you know what I'm gonna always come with some.
Speaker 1: I'm not just gonna have two things that are random.
Speaker 1: right I got to make it interesting.
Speaker 1: I'll just have some sort of logic.
Speaker 0: oh whatever the logic is I picked two books that were famous that neither of us had read that were published in the same year.
Speaker 0: last time.
Speaker 1: I just as long as I have some sort of logic to keep it interesting yeah and that's fine.
Speaker 1: who cares right?
Speaker 1: because if I try to make something more rigid it'll just be difficult.
Speaker 0: yeah this is supposed to be fun.
Speaker 0: the whole point is that it's fun.
Speaker 0: otherwise we will be at PAX West doing a panel on games you can't play.
Speaker 0: we will pretty definitely be at PAX unplugged doing some amount of content.
Speaker 0: PAX unplugged is still my favorite PAX so stay tuned for that.
Speaker 0: we'll definitely be there.
Speaker 0: I do have a hotel room for magfest and uh I guess I can share this.
Speaker 1: I don't know about magfest.
Speaker 0: I'm going 100% absolutely going to magfest.
Speaker 0: but I talked to the people who run mages.
Speaker 0: they it was running in a limited form during the COVID times.
Speaker 0: it is coming back in full glory and we are invited to return to its full and former glory.
Speaker 1: are the people running it different people than before?
Speaker 0: there seemed to be a lot of different people involved in the email list that I am now on again but seems a little more streamlined.
Speaker 0: uh I don't know.
Speaker 0: I think I think the people we enjoyed doing panels with all appear to still be around.
Speaker 0: I can say that.
Speaker 1: well we'll see.
Speaker 0: so I will be at magfest.
Speaker 0: if Scott decides not to go it's just gonna be for him.
Speaker 0: I'd like six or seven panels but I think I'm gonna even though I have a room in the Wyndham.
Speaker 0: if I can get a Gaylord room I think I just want to stay in the Gaylord if I'm going back to a magfest.
Speaker 0: I'm spending a lot of time hanging out with randos in the con and less they sold out.
Speaker 1: yet.
Speaker 0: hmm they're not available.
Speaker 0: remember the lottery.
Speaker 0: you've never done the lottery have you?
Speaker 0: you can't know.
Speaker 1: because yeah.
Speaker 0: so guess what you can't book a Lord rooms.
Speaker 0: the way Gaylord rooms work is if you buy a magfest badge then you can get into the Gaylord room lottery.
Speaker 1: oh but how could I?
Speaker 1: I'm not buying a badge though I'm getting a free one.
Speaker 0: uh yes so if you're getting a free badge then the only way to get a Gaylord room is shenanigans or talking to mages and joining me rejoining mages in some capacity.
Speaker 1: well can I can I like you know try to get try to play the lottery and then just not go?
Speaker 0: if I lose the lottery I think you'd have to buy a badge to do that.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna find out.
Speaker 0: but regardless I did book a Wyndham suite just for me and Emily.
Speaker 0: that has a bedroom in it so theoretically we could put more people in it.
Speaker 0: we'll see we'll see.
Speaker 0: I'm uh I miss magfest.
Speaker 0: I miss magfest a lot.
Speaker 1: look at the look at the calendar.
Speaker 0: you know it's not over New Year's.
Speaker 0: it's like way later than usual.
Speaker 1: yeah they made it later this year.
Speaker 0: yeah which kind of makes it better for me timing wise.
Speaker 0: I kind of want to do New Year's like more like old times.
Speaker 0: I don't really want to do New Year's magfest but anyway that was the meta moment.
Speaker 0: we've talked for a long time.
Speaker 0: we were going to review not one two games tonight because they are games that are really good but with some caveats and there's not that much to say about right.
Speaker 0: but it is a sign that we will be doing a lot more board game reviews in the future.
Speaker 0: because uh while we were on vacation I think we played like seven board games that all are worthy of a review at least.
Speaker 1: maybe played seven games we haven't played before.
Speaker 1: it does.
Speaker 1: it doesn't matter how worthy they are.
Speaker 1: but anyway there was a person named Sid Saxon right who is the person who designed the game acquire which you may have heard of.
Speaker 1: he was a famous legendary figure in the gaming world.
Speaker 1: I think we mentioned him on geek nights when his massive lifelong game collection was broken up and sold thousands individual games in this collection.
Speaker 1: yeah and all of his papers collected were put into the strong museum.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: so if you have your papers put in a museum you know that you are a significant figure in whatever field your field is.
Speaker 1: his field was games.
Speaker 1: this is the guy Sid Saxon was like his old dude.
Speaker 1: he was just all in on games his whole life right.
Speaker 1: he would write books about games and you know he was born in 1920.
Speaker 0: his most famous game is probably acquire that was published in 1964. so he was older than us when he published his first like super notable game like the one that if you didn't know acquire was from the 60s and we just got a modern copy of it and brought it to the table.
Speaker 0: you would probably assume it was made more recently than 1964. it's a solid game.
Speaker 1: yeah I mean it's not perfect but you know.
Speaker 1: but you know this was alleged.
Speaker 1: you know and I think you know his biggest works actually were his books.
Speaker 1: right if you buy one of the Sid Saxon books it's like it's just page after page and like every couple pages has another game.
Speaker 1: they're all games.
Speaker 1: most of them are just using like standard pieces like you know.
Speaker 1: here's another game you can play with a deck of cards.
Speaker 1: here's a game you can play with a bunch of dice.
Speaker 1: it's just like you you buy one book and you get like a hundred fucking games in there.
Speaker 1: right it's like you know this guy.
Speaker 1: really he compiled you know all the gaming knowledge there was and that's why it's in a museum yep.
Speaker 1: but anyway we played two of his games that we had not played previously even though the first of which is like a game that like everyone's played and that game is can't stop which I had.
Speaker 0: actually while I was aware of it I had never played it until right I had.
Speaker 1: I knew of it for many many years.
Speaker 1: I just hadn't played it.
Speaker 1: actually for reals by I knew how to play it and basically can't stop is almost the purest form of push your luck game.
Speaker 1: there is.
Speaker 1: that's all there is to
Speaker 0: its first push your luck
Speaker 1: yeah and the thing about can't stop that separates it for I think from the other push your luck games is that an other push your luck games there is like this steady sort of reduction of the odds right when you can feel yourself getting squeezed and you're like.
Speaker 1: you're like okay.
Speaker 1: I got like a hundred percent chance to still be in.
Speaker 1: I got a ninety percent chance to still be in.
Speaker 1: I got a fifty percent chance.
Speaker 1: I'll still be in.
Speaker 1: all right I got a less than I'm out right.
Speaker 1: it's like you can feel it.
Speaker 1: the squeeze coming on and back out and the only time you don't back out when the squeeze comes on is when you're way behind and you sort of have to go for the onsides.
Speaker 1: kick yeah and right.
Speaker 1: and now that same thing still holds true and can't stop but in can't stop.
Speaker 1: the odds never really squeeze you so tightly.
Speaker 0: oh it is notable.
Speaker 0: both me and Scott despite being I would say very good at statistical heuristics in games like this we pushed our luck to failure way more often than anyone would expect either of us to.
Speaker 0: but it felt.
Speaker 0: but I felt good about those decisions which means this game has got something going on right.
Speaker 1: it's like it never squeezes you so tightly numbers wise that you feel like you're gonna be.
Speaker 1: you're gonna lose.
Speaker 1: you have to stop now right.
Speaker 1: and the way the way it works is you're all about 46 right?
Speaker 0: yeah?
Speaker 1: a small number of dice yeah 40 46 and you can combine them any which way into two sets of two dice each right.
Speaker 1: so if you're rolling 46 it's like you know what are the odds like a seven is gonna be in there somewhere among two dice.
Speaker 1: really it feels yeah I've never done the math.
Speaker 1: that feels like you can't miss.
Speaker 0: it feels like that craps tables.
Speaker 1: of course it's like but you know what?
Speaker 1: what are the odds of four ones coming up?
Speaker 1: it could happen.
Speaker 1: what are the odds of four sixes coming up?
Speaker 1: it can happen right.
Speaker 1: it's like you're not gonna get.
Speaker 1: it's not.
Speaker 1: nothing is guaranteed.
Speaker 0: but to make it even better it's not too independent 2d sixes it's 4d six.
Speaker 0: because the next step of the game is you look at the four numbers you rolled and you arrange them into an arbitrary combination of two to six.
Speaker 1: yeah it's any which way right.
Speaker 1: so you're like you feel like even when you know you need a particular you just need like to hit one of the numbers right of that are possible between two and twelve.
Speaker 1: it's like yes I just need to hit one of these numbers between two and twelve.
Speaker 1: it's just like you're rolling for d6 and feel you never feel like I'm gonna.
Speaker 1: there's no way I'm gonna get.
Speaker 1: and I think that feels like yeah my chances are good I'm going for it.
Speaker 1: I've got.
Speaker 1: you can't stop right?
Speaker 1: you had to you feel like you're gonna make it.
Speaker 1: you keep rolling and then you miss and then you're fine.
Speaker 0: and I feel like that is the brilliant of this game.
Speaker 0: we didn't get into the specific mechanics but the brilliance is you are more likely to be fine than get fucked most of the time.
Speaker 0: but what that causes is this letter ride feeling where I got an 80% chance that's fine.
Speaker 0: 80% chance that's fine.
Speaker 1: and yeah yeah 80% chance is fine as long as you.
Speaker 1: what?
Speaker 1: as soon as you try eight times yeah like that's all you're gonna miss one of those times.
Speaker 1: I can you really it's like it's gonna.
Speaker 1: you know even if you only try five times like okay one of them is gonna miss.
Speaker 1: yep you've already tried.
Speaker 1: you already got four in a row.
Speaker 1: you really want to try the fifth time on the 80% chance.
Speaker 0: so mechanically like the specifics the way this works is you've got this big pattern I got.
Speaker 0: if you're on the live stream I got a board up you can look at but basically it's just a.
Speaker 1: it's just a racetrack.
Speaker 0: yep just a racetrack but there's a. it's a square but you're approaching it diagonally.
Speaker 0: so you're trying to get all your good all your pips all the way to the end.
Speaker 0: so if I roll two sevens I can move a pip up to on the seven track the seven tracks in the center corner to corner.
Speaker 0: it's the longest path but so I gotta get one easy to get.
Speaker 1: numbers are of a long path right.
Speaker 0: so I gotta roll 13 sevens without stopping or stopping at an appropriate point.
Speaker 0: but you can't stop.
Speaker 0: you got to keep going fuck you.
Speaker 0: or at the very edges.
Speaker 0: if I just roll two three times I get to the end of the two track.
Speaker 1: and if right now it's like two is pretty hard you need to get two ones.
Speaker 1: but it's like two ones.
Speaker 0: on 4d6 it's like hmm yeah it's a it's a. hmm it's not a like.
Speaker 0: calculate the strict odds in your head situation.
Speaker 0: you look at that.
Speaker 1: you know it was 2d6.
Speaker 1: you'd be like hell.
Speaker 1: no I get it.
Speaker 1: what are the odds of me rolling snake eyes too low.
Speaker 1: 46 it's like.
Speaker 1: I'll eventually make it three times.
Speaker 0: feels good to like advance advance that if it comes up because that's a nice safety yeah.
Speaker 0: but so even if you got something on seven you got to keep rolling seven once you've got all your pips moving on the board.
Speaker 1: right you have three pips.
Speaker 1: so you eventually assign your pips to three different numbers on the board and once they're all out there right if they're not out there yet you can sort of assign them to any number that you've rolled and put together from 2d6 out of your four.
Speaker 1: but once all three of your pips are out there let's say I got it on seven eight and ten.
Speaker 1: yeah right I roll my 46 among the four dice.
Speaker 1: I have to put together at least one seven or one eight or one ten and advance one of my pips at least one space.
Speaker 1: if I can't with any combination of the dice make a seven and eight or a ten and I can't move any of my pips.
Speaker 1: I busted yeah and all my pips got to go back.
Speaker 1: yup but where they started before I started my turn.
Speaker 0: but that's the key.
Speaker 1: if you stop but you don't want to if you have the guts to stop then they lot that it's like a save point.
Speaker 1: they can't there wherever they are they they're set and they can't be pushed any further back and you can make.
Speaker 0: I gotta tell ya locking in a good run is really really really powerful.
Speaker 0: but even me and Scott you look at it you've rolled 11 times in a row when things are going great.
Speaker 0: you got something on seven.
Speaker 0: so you know you're safe.
Speaker 0: you just look at it.
Speaker 1: how can I not get a seven?
Speaker 1: I'll just keep going till I win the whole seven track.
Speaker 0: yeah good I think I busted back to zero like four times in a row and I consider myself a smart person.
Speaker 1: so I think I think that this is a model that some other push your luck games should try is don't squeeze you know keep all the rest of your game is just fine.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of good push your luck games out there.
Speaker 1: like you we play it we like to play.
Speaker 1: no thanks right I'll put the tokens on the card right.
Speaker 1: that games all.
Speaker 1: eventually the card has so many tokens on it you're like.
Speaker 1: of course I'm just gonna take the card right.
Speaker 1: but imagine if no thanks like never squeezed hard enough and it's like you just always like didn't want to take the card even when there was a mountain of to you know and you just kept pushing it.
Speaker 1: I don't know it'll be more.
Speaker 0: that's it the game.
Speaker 0: so simple like poking around a board game.
Speaker 0: geek people just make this game by drawing it or printing it out of.
Speaker 1: yeah all you need is for all you need is 4d6 and a piece of paper.
Speaker 0: yep right and some and some some number of objects to put on this piece of paper.
Speaker 1: you really yeah I mean that guys it you know it.
Speaker 1: but what's the rating on board game geek?
Speaker 0: I think let me let's go back to can't stop.
Speaker 1: oh it's low people don't.
Speaker 1: people don't like wouldn't like this game this game.
Speaker 1: you talk about fun economy this I get board game geek gives can't stop.
Speaker 1: from 1980 a six point nine.
Speaker 1: I give it like a nine.
Speaker 0: I was gonna say nine as well because this game unless you're playing with an intolerable spiders your type person this game takes maybe 15 minutes to play and it feels real good the entire time.
Speaker 0: yeah like this game is so fun for how simple it is.
Speaker 0: it takes so little time to teach this game.
Speaker 0: yeah so yeah play this game.
Speaker 0: there's no reason not to play this game.
Speaker 0: it would be an a-plus Omega thon game at PAX unplugged like S here.
Speaker 1: oh yeah.
Speaker 1: so the next game was one that's from one of his books that I went and I found an excerpt from on the Internet Archive and then transcribed and then prepared all the pieces for it.
Speaker 1: all it needed was a deck of cards in a stack of chips and the and it's game is called all my diamonds and it's a very modern art adjacent selling auctioning game bidding game right which of course we love right.
Speaker 1: and the way it works is you get a deck of cards and you throw the tens out.
Speaker 1: you get the tens out of there.
Speaker 1: so you got 48 cards and if you got those 48 cards with no tens there are basically eight sets of 12.
Speaker 0: you got a matrix of the suits and exactly.
Speaker 1: so there's the diamonds the hearts the clubs in the spades.
Speaker 1: those are 12 cards each as the tens are out.
Speaker 1: and then there's the lows the aces twos and threes the the mids the fours fives and sixes the highs the sevens eights and nines and then the faces the Jack Queen Kings right.
Speaker 1: and so therefore you've got eight sets of 12 and your goal of the game is to in your hand have 10 cards that are all in the same set of 12. so 10 clubs 10 diamonds 10 lows 10 faces right and as soon as you get 10 of one of the sets you put it out there.
Speaker 1: you're like boom and you collect the pot right of chips that have everyone anteed.
Speaker 1: it is a big ante and so then you continue playing.
Speaker 1: everyone continues playing and there's a second pot and the second pot is comprised of taxes.
Speaker 1: because the way you acquire cards is that on your turn you must look at your hand and pick one of the eight sets and take all the cards that you have in that set at least one card also.
Speaker 1: you can't just pick a set you don't have and sell it to everyone else right?
Speaker 1: so you might say all my diamonds right.
Speaker 1: I'll take all the diamonds out of your hand and sell them as a lot at auction.
Speaker 1: or you might say all my faces.
Speaker 1: and you take all the face cards out of your whole hand and sell them at auction.
Speaker 1: and you get right all the money when you sell the cards except one cards worth of money is paid in taxes.
Speaker 1: so if you sell five cards you keep 80% of the money right.
Speaker 1: if you sell two cards you keep half the money.
Speaker 1: if you sell ten cards you keep 90% of the money right.
Speaker 1: so and the rest of the money you don't keep goes to the second pot.
Speaker 1: that will be for the winner of you know the second winner basically and it could be the same person who wins both times.
Speaker 1: right now the thing with this game is that all that matters is who has the most money wins.
Speaker 1: so you could actually not win either pot and just sell.
Speaker 1: be so good at selling and we're buying low and selling high that you end up making more money by being a card seller right then by being a winner and that's the thing.
Speaker 1: so that's the whole.
Speaker 1: that's the whole game.
Speaker 0: this game is worth playing to explore the concept.
Speaker 0: but we devolved into a giggling fit in our game because this game when confronted by what I would say is a group of stone cold pros who have very good understandings of bidding and valuation.
Speaker 0: the bidding breaks down into a disaster and the game falls apart.
Speaker 0: and it was to watch the game just like collapse around us.
Speaker 1: right so Sid Saxon says all my diamonds is a game I conceived as a change of pace from poker.
Speaker 1: although there is no similarity in the play it satisfies the same urge for speculation.
Speaker 1: it's basically an auction where players must decide whether they can earn more by buying or by selling.
Speaker 1: right but yeah when we played it it's like you could sort of imagine worlds where like other lines of play might have been possible there's obviously some luck element.
Speaker 1: you could just be dealt some amazing hands something right.
Speaker 1: but the the initial pot is just so much bigger than anyone who's willing to bid for anything.
Speaker 1: and it's like you think well a bit more.
Speaker 1: but it's like.
Speaker 0: but if you bid more like your winnings are so capped by the nature of the game that it won't work out for you.
Speaker 1: so yeah it's like if I'm gonna wait if we got four players right and everyone puts in you know 15 anti.
Speaker 1: so that's 60 right.
Speaker 1: it's like all right.
Speaker 1: so I have to buy with my money a winning hand right for less than 60.
Speaker 1: I'm not willing to pay out a total of more than 60 to get a winning hand.
Speaker 1: if I buy something and I don't either a win or B sell those cards I bought for a higher value I just lost right money.
Speaker 1: so it's like every move has to be profitable.
Speaker 1: so it's really tight and there's not a lot of winning lines right.
Speaker 1: and it's sort of like.
Speaker 1: are you gonna try to be a seller or are you gonna try to be a winner?
Speaker 1: if you try to be a winner you're gonna spend very.
Speaker 1: you know very little which means the people who are trying to be sellers can't make.
Speaker 1: it's like basically whoever got that first pot ended up.
Speaker 1: that was it was so much money because we were all so cheap.
Speaker 1: but if you weren't cheap if you just tried to spend it all it's like well there you go you want.
Speaker 1: you didn't make that.
Speaker 1: you're in the modern art situation of.
Speaker 0: I spent $40 to win $32.
Speaker 0: great yeah.
Speaker 0: and the only strategy at that point is you would take a loss to prevent someone else from getting a pot.
Speaker 0: but if it would be profitable for them.
Speaker 0: but that breaks down to and the game just kind of fell apart.
Speaker 0: and it was just I still.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 1: so I think there were.
Speaker 1: there was a lot to learn from the concepts going on here.
Speaker 1: I just think it needs some tweaking in like the numbers department and also in the auction department.
Speaker 0: but I feel like if you do those tweaks will you just end up in modern art and you might because modern art kind of did this like as best you can do without adding more complexity which isn't necessarily a thing in a game like that.
Speaker 1: yeah so this is a case where I mean this game does predate modern.
Speaker 0: yeah right I did I think pretty sure.
Speaker 0: 1969 versus modern art board game by kinesia.
Speaker 0: yep modern art.
Speaker 0: let's see 1992.
Speaker 1: yeah so you know it's like playing the proto version of a game you know is great right as opposed to usually.
Speaker 1: you know these days we're playing like remakes and polished redone versions of games right like we're playing the small world.
Speaker 1: after the vintage is we've already been playing the Vinci.
Speaker 1: this is the opposite.
Speaker 1: it's like imagine if he only ever played small world.
Speaker 1: I mean I guess that's a bad example cuz he like Vinci better.
Speaker 1: so it's like you know if you had only ever played you know Resident Evil remakes and then one day you go back and try to play the original.
Speaker 1: it's like you can.
Speaker 1: you can see what was going on there.
Speaker 1: there's a lot to learn.
Speaker 1: there's value in that.
Speaker 1: but also it's not as good.
Speaker 1: yeah it's just not as good.
Speaker 0: I do think it is absolutely worth playing.
Speaker 0: if you were interested in game design at all just because the experience of playing it and then seeing how the bidding breaks down or you might have a friend who's bad at bidding games and it doesn't break down and that'll be funny for different reasons.
Speaker 1: but I think you could also tweak the numbers and if you got a bunch of people to play it multiple times that you might be able to develop.
Speaker 1: you know a meta right.
Speaker 1: that could work.
Speaker 0: I think so it's possible.
Speaker 0: the problem I think the problem we ran into is that the game as written I feel like the meta we encountered in our first playthrough is an extremely strong attractor for people who are skeptical of the value of the second pot.
Speaker 0: yes and I do not imagine a world where the first pot is sold for so much.
Speaker 1: anyway I suppose there's a world in which you sort of try to shoot the moon in which you pay a lot to get the first pot on like a break even and then get your money back in the second pot.
Speaker 1: also because you've got all these cards left over that you like you're buying for the first pot and you've got so many cards left over you can get the second pot also to get your cash back but that would be tough.
Speaker 0: this has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand.
Speaker 0: ok for the logos.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at front row crew dot-com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech mondays gaming tuesdays.
Speaker 0: anime comic wednesdays and indiscriminate thursdays.
Speaker 1: geek nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: and the patreon patreons for this episode of geek nights are allen joyce, linky, g-dread, lily tenebrae, case care makes music, chris hadad, clinton walton, dex, thin, joel hayes, petty rimer, rebecca dunn, sam erickson, sherwin von hurl and a ton of people who give like a sweet sweet patreon customized RSS feed.
Speaker 0: we're back from woodrow wilson's house.
Speaker 0: we did not find his skeleton though we did find a large chest filled with an array of shoes of various sizes.
Speaker 0: but I leave you tonight simply with.