Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, February 7th, 2023, I'm Rym, I'm Scott, and this is Geek Nights, tonight we're talking about, not dead games, but mostly dead games.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So, uh, just a little while ago, Emily and I ended up, Emily saw this was happening and was just like, I'm gonna get tickets, and we just went, and it was pretty cool.
Speaker 1: But, uh, if you listen to Geek Nights, remember that in ancient, ancient times, we did listen to and talk a little bit about J-Rock, we even interviewed TM Revolution with the help of that guy, I forget his name.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, you know, back in the days, right, the earlier anime times, it's like, I still like J-Rock, right, but it's not like I listen to it on purpose that often.
Speaker 0: You know, but it's good.
Speaker 0: We've been to a few J-Rock concerts in our day.
Speaker 1: Well, I just tried, I mean, we saw Hyde at Otacon when they did the full stadium set, I just tried to Google for Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Well, and then we saw it in the small place, too, right?
Speaker 1: I just Googled for Geek Nights TMR, and it was like, did you mean Geek Nights Rym?
Speaker 0: Yeah, we saw TMR at Otacon, and then at the bookstore, which I was at the Kinokuniya bookstore yesterday, they didn't have the fountain pen I wanted, so I didn't buy anything.
Speaker 1: I gotta see, there's probably some video out there somewhere of us, like, helping that guy ask questions and do that stuff, and... I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but, so, we ended up seeing, there were originally only two iterations of this concert, then they expanded to three, and then they expanded to four, so once in LA, once in Tokyo, and then because it sold out so fast twice in New York City, so we went to the second night, The Last Rockstars is a supergroup that was formed suddenly late last year by Yoshiki, Hyde, Miyabi, and Sugizo, so...
Speaker 0: Right, so basically what happened was, you know, somebody involved in their, one of them, or someone involved in their business was like, "Hey, I need
Speaker 0: money.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, Miyabi's the leader, and it's very clear Miyabi is the stage, like, leader of the band.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay, alright, but maybe Miyabi was like, "Hey, listen, I need some
Speaker 0: money.".
Speaker 1: Wait, no, a fan said that, the Wikipedia says Yoshiki's the leader.
Speaker 0: Okay, but it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: Regardless, the point is, somebody was sitting around, this is what I'm guessing, right, which is an educated guess, was like, "Hey, pandemic times really hurt us, right?
Speaker 0: You know, we need
Speaker 0: money.".
Speaker 0: All these guys are real famous, but the people in their bands aren't as famous.
Speaker 0: You know, that happens in a lot of bands, right, where there's one person who's more famous than the other members.
Speaker 0: Sometimes you have a band where everyone's equal famous, or even if they're not equal famous, they're all famous enough on their own.
Speaker 1: You get the band where one person thinks they're more famous than everybody else, but they're not.
Speaker 0: Right, but there are several bands, many, where one person is significantly famous and the other people can be replaced and nobody would know except hardcore fans, right?
Speaker 0: And so, they're not quite in that category, right, I don't want to disrespect the other band members, right, because they are quite good, but these people are significantly more famous than the other members of their band, mostly.
Speaker 1: You know, I always think back to that moment in "That Thing You Do" where the band's having the, you know, pseudo Beatles problem, and there's just a random scene where, like, they don't have, I think, their bassist, maybe one of the guitar players anymore.
Speaker 1: So, they go to a studio session and the studio's like, "Oh, we got a guy, don't worry about it," and some random guy just plays and they're skeptical and then he's way better than any of them ever were at the guitar.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, if you're looking for someone who's just really good at, you know, music, right, and you don't care about, like, their star power, you're probably going to find someone better than someone who's in, right?
Speaker 1: If I needed people to play instruments, I would literally hire a bunch of house and studio musicians.
Speaker 0: I mean, you mentioned Beatles, right?
Speaker 0: There's that guy who's, like, you know, his whole life is like, "I could've been in the Beatles," right?
Speaker 0: He's, like, out there doing shit in the UK and he's on TV once in a blue moon, like, trying to, you know, be like, "I could've,".
Speaker 0: he's like, "Ah, Ringo, that guy took my
Speaker 0: job!".
Speaker 0: He's like, "It could've been
Speaker 0: me!"
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: But it's, like, first of all, Ringo's a better drummer than, you know, people who don't understand drumming understand.
Speaker 0: Like, "Really?
Speaker 0: Could it have been?
Speaker 0: Really?".
Speaker 0: And second of all, you know, Ringo has, you know, 10,000 billion star power and that guy is cranky old guy, so it's, like, there was no way that guy was going to conduct a train or anything like that, right?
Speaker 0: So, but yeah, they said, "Hey, all these guys, you're all super mega famous, you haven't made money in a while because pandoodles and other problems, you know, someone, let's all get together and we'll just tour and do,".
Speaker 0: I don't even know what music, just do something.
Speaker 0: If all of you are together.
Speaker 1: And they seem to be trying to, like, do a bunch of different kinds of songs and a bunch of duets and, like, they're really- I
Speaker 0: think they don't know, you know, it's no surprise that there's no creative direction, it's just, "Let's all get together and if we are all on stage at the same time and sell tickets, we'll make money, so let's figure all the rest out later, we can make it
Speaker 0: happen.".
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: We're musicians, we can do it.
Speaker 1: And I think it was the first concert I went to since the pandoodle began and it was actually, they did a long, full set, including the, "We won't come out to do the encore until you yell, but we also won't turn up the house lights at any point, so you'd better yell or we're not coming
Speaker 1: out.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, we've been to mostly, you know, I don't want to call them concerts, but, like, you go there and people play, you know, DJs play music.
Speaker 0: But it's not the club, it's at a concert venue, so I guess you call that a show?
Speaker 0: I don't know what you call that.
Speaker 0: This was, like, a packed- But we've- I've been to, I guess, a handful of pandoodle concerts.
Speaker 1: But what was really interesting is, it was at the Hammerstein Ballroom and that's a fine venue.
Speaker 0: I've been there one time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's okay venue.
Speaker 1: But, uh, because it was J-Rock, it attracts, like, you saw, we were walking toward the venue and we assumed there'll be, like, a line because, you know, nerds really got to get in to get the exclusive merch and, like, be at the very front and, like, flip out about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't care, but I just ignore people who do that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we were fine just being in the bag.
Speaker 1: We didn't care.
Speaker 1: We just wanted to go to the concert.
Speaker 1: So, uh, we see the line.
Speaker 0: It sounds the same in most areas of the room.
Speaker 1: I would say the line looked identical to the line at every single anime movie we've ever seen in the city.
Speaker 1: It looked like it might as well have been an anime con, but that line was the longest line I've ever stood in in a New York City street.
Speaker 1: It looks like, based on the detritus on the street and all the hand warmers, people had been lined up probably all day.
Speaker 0: Why would you, I don't know.
Speaker 1: We got there, like, 20 minutes before doors opened and it took us an hour to get in just because it took that long for the line to get through security.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, some, I don't know how long ago it was, months, weeks, I don't remember exactly, but it was cold, so it was either, I think it was December or January.
Speaker 1: Oh, this was so cold, I expected to be outside for maybe a half hour.
Speaker 1: I was 20 minutes away from Frostnip on my toes because I was just wearing, like, my running shoes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we had tickets to go see a concert, this girl, Beck Yeddon, alright?
Speaker 0: And the tickets only said on them, right, 7 o'clock.
Speaker 0: It didn't say anything else on it.
Speaker 1: Ooh, that's dangerous!
Speaker 1: Is that doors?
Speaker 1: Is that, like...
Speaker 0: Exactly, right?
Speaker 0: But, you know, I got there and I'm like, alright, we went to, it was in the place near Union Square, right?
Speaker 0: I forget the name.
Speaker 0: It's not the best place, but it was fine.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but, you know, we're just eating and it was, oh, it was definitely during holiday times because I remember the holiday market was open.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, we went to the holiday market, you know, we're eating in the park, you know, got some pizza, you know, and then we go to try to get in the line, you know, go see what's doing.
Speaker 0: And the line is, like, wrapped around the entire block and I'm like, what the fuck is this?
Speaker 0: I'm like, it's almost 7, what's going on, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, um, but yeah, we ended up waiting in the cold and if I would have known, I would have shown up later.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: Rather than wait in the cold.
Speaker 1: But it was a good time.
Speaker 1: I, uh, it's not like I forgot how much I like live music.
Speaker 1: It's more that no matter how much you think you like live music, when you're actually at a venue listening to live music, it's always better than you remember.
Speaker 0: Mm, depends.
Speaker 0: I've been to some...
Speaker 1: I mean, the band is bad or the roadies are bad.
Speaker 0: There is bad live music.
Speaker 0: That can happen.
Speaker 0: It's a thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, let's assume the band is good because I will never forget the moment.
Speaker 1: This was, like, years before the pandemic.
Speaker 1: Emily and I went to Wildwood, like, by ourselves just for, like, a weekend for fun.
Speaker 1: And we got into town kind of late.
Speaker 1: You know, Wildwood, there's not a lot of restaurants open late.
Speaker 1: So, we're walking around and we hear down the street what sounds like some of the worst karaoke I've ever heard.
Speaker 1: And we're talking, like, "Well, that place is clearly open and probably has, like, a late night bar menu.
Speaker 1: We can suffer through the bad karaoke and get some
Speaker 1: food."
Speaker 1: And then we get there and that is not karaoke.
Speaker 1: That is not just a band, but a band that has their name on the marquee outside.
Speaker 0: There's that, um, is it still open?
Speaker 0: I guess it's still, yeah, I guess it's still a thing.
Speaker 0: One of the touristy things in Times Square in New York is Ellen's Stardust Diner or Eileen's.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Ellen's Stardust Diner.
Speaker 0: It's basically a diner that has, you know, like, a 50s Greece style kind of show, right, while you're eating or whatever.
Speaker 1: Like the kind of thing you'd see in an amusement park.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And it's, I think, I guess it's still there when I walked past it and I just checked.
Speaker 0: I don't, but I haven't seen, like, a line or anything at it recently when I, the Times I've walked past it.
Speaker 0: But they're, apparently, the internet says it's open, so I guess there are times when you can go to it.
Speaker 0: And I always remember my family was in New York City at one time and we were gonna eat there and we went in and we were seated, right?
Speaker 0: And we sat down and just, like, it was so loud and obnoxious in there, we stood up and left within, like, a minute.
Speaker 0: It was like we waited in a short line, we were seated, it was very crowded and loud, and then a minute later we're just like, "Let's not eat here.
Speaker 0: Let's get out of
Speaker 0: here.".
Speaker 1: So one of the last shows I saw before the pandoodle was, we randomly went with some family friends to Cafe Wa, which is, if you're in New York City, it is an infamous venue.
Speaker 1: They put on a great house show, but it's basically a house band playing a variety of random music.
Speaker 1: And they're all individually good musicians, but it is also a loud, raucous place and it is definitely not managed well as a venue, is what I'm gonna say.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of places that are not managed well as a venue, right?
Speaker 1: So yeah, that was a fun time.
Speaker 0: Those are the ones that make the noise complaints from the neighbors, right?
Speaker 1: I mean, I still remember the one time I went to an actually illegal venue that was in the basement of a random brownstone in Brooklyn where I needed to go outside to get some fresh air.
Speaker 1: And as me and Chase walk outside, there's a guy who clearly works for the venue who's telling anyone who walks out, "Yo, disperse.
Speaker 1: You cannot let the neighbors know there's a concert going on in
Speaker 1: here.".
Speaker 1: Meanwhile, there's like a hundred people loudly smoking outside of this random brownstone in Brooklyn at like 2 a.m So it's the kind of venue where you're sitting there and you're like, "Wow, if there's a fire, literally everyone in here is going to
Speaker 1: die.".
Speaker 1: Anyway, it was fun.
Speaker 1: So a lot of news.
Speaker 1: So before we get into that, I want to start by giving a quick review.
Speaker 1: This is relevant to the main bit too.
Speaker 1: As you know, I still play DDR.
Speaker 1: I'm real good at DDR for being over 40.
Speaker 1: And I can't pass Max 300 anymore, but I can pass pretty much everything else.
Speaker 1: And I play DDR a lot.
Speaker 1: It's like one of my main exercises, especially in the winter.
Speaker 1: It's a lifestyle hobby for me.
Speaker 1: And one of my two remaining legit soft but serious good quality DDR pads died.
Speaker 1: The second one's dying.
Speaker 0: Not repairable or reinforceable?
Speaker 1: One of them, irreparable.
Speaker 1: It is dead dead.
Speaker 1: The second one, dying.
Speaker 1: But I am doing heroic measures to keep it going.
Speaker 1: Because when I thought to myself, "Oh, one
Speaker 1: died."
Speaker 1: Let's one, stabilize the second one and try to extend its life.
Speaker 1: And two, let's buy some new ones.
Speaker 1: There really aren't DDR pads to buy anymore.
Speaker 1: You're going to see bootleg of a bootleg of a bootleg on Amazon.
Speaker 1: Go on eBay and people are selling garbage-looking pads for a hundred bucks.
Speaker 0: Right, because the number of people out there in the world who are going to buy a DDR pad is so small.
Speaker 0: It's not worth it to do a production run.
Speaker 0: But I think, I was thinking about this.
Speaker 0: I was like, "You know, the mechanical keyboard people, they do their keycaps, whatever.
Speaker 0: And they'll do these pre-buy deals, a group buy, where people commit and commit their money.
Speaker 0: And then when enough people commit, then they get
Speaker 0: manufactured.".
Speaker 0: Even though there's a lot of people who are into mechanical keyboard keycaps, people who want that specific design is like, "How many
Speaker 0: people?".
Speaker 0: So I think somebody could, if they had the means to manufacture DDR pads, could get some sort of group buy and be like, "All right, we're not going to just make DDR pads all the time because no one's buying
Speaker 0: them.".
Speaker 0: But when 5,000 people want DDR pads, we will make 5,000 DDR pads all at once.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: And that'll be that.
Speaker 0: And I think that is a way that that sort of thing could be manufactured.
Speaker 1: So I looked around and I basically gave up.
Speaker 1: I do not think there are soft pads, even like thick foam, like high quality.
Speaker 0: No, because anyone who still cares about DDR doesn't want a soft pad.
Speaker 1: So I decided, you know what, instead of buying bootleg of a bootleg of a bootleg, let's just get the fucking Cobalt Flux that I wanted my whole life because I made a DDR pad at RIT.
Speaker 0: Do they even still exist?
Speaker 1: So they do, except I went to their website and one, it says they're sold out.
Speaker 1: They sell parts, but not the pads.
Speaker 1: And they have a warning out that says, "Currently, we do not have an estimate of when new Cobalt Flux pads will be available.
Speaker 1: If you're looking for a pad, go to Eltech.
Speaker 1: We can't help
Speaker 1: you.".
Speaker 0: When's the last time this Cobalt Flux website was even updated?
Speaker 1: I don't know, but the prices...
Speaker 0: Like who runs that company?
Speaker 0: and do they still exist, right?
Speaker 1: So the website is up and they're still selling everything else they got, including replacement parts for Cobalt Fluxes, but they won't sell the pad itself.
Speaker 0: But if you buy one of those, if you put an order in, will you actually receive the order?
Speaker 1: It looks like it based on the digging, but I looked on eBay.
Speaker 1: A used Cobalt Flux pad goes for like more than what they list a new one for, so that ain't happening.
Speaker 1: So I go to this Eltech thing and it's 400 bucks.
Speaker 1: So I read reviews, I looked around, I think it is one of two options that remain.
Speaker 1: The only two options left, unless you're going to build your own, which I advise you not to, unless you know what you're doing.
Speaker 1: It is a difficult and challenging thing to do.
Speaker 1: well.
Speaker 1: Like you're going to struggle.
Speaker 1: So it's either buy the Eltech X-Pro 2 for 400 bucks, or just get a fucking arcade machine, like those are your two options.
Speaker 0: I'd say buy the whole arcade machine, they still make them.
Speaker 1: They do, and I got nowhere to put it, and I looked.
Speaker 1: $14,000 plus industrial shipping, and the weight would be a problem for an apartment possibly.
Speaker 0: Well, move to Japan, might be cheaper.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or I could just buy a house in the suburbs, or we could all pool in and buy one to put in other Scott's house.
Speaker 0: But if you live in Japan, you wouldn't need the shipping.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you would, you still need industrial shipping, it's an arcade.
Speaker 0: But not international industrial shipping.
Speaker 1: I don't think it'd be that much cheaper, the problem is not...
Speaker 0: They could put it on a small truck instead of on a boat or a plane.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the problem is still, this is not like, FedEx delivers your package.
Speaker 1: This is, industrial shipping is a whole fucking thing, but also...
Speaker 0: I'm sure it still costs more to do it from Japan to US than from Japan to Japan.
Speaker 1: So I don't have room for a real arcade machine.
Speaker 1: Also, real arcade machines can't easily be modded and increasingly have dangerous DRM, where if you run them outside of Japan and fuck up, they'll break themselves.
Speaker 0: Right, but there are people out there who are like, you know, figuring that out, that's the whole thing.
Speaker 1: And I'm gonna trust those people to bring those machines to future magfests.
Speaker 1: I live in a New York City apartment.
Speaker 0: Usually when they do that, the machines won't be plugged into the internet.
Speaker 0: You won't be able to register your high scores, or you know.
Speaker 1: So I just bought the Eltech pad, and I tried it out.
Speaker 1: And it's great.
Speaker 1: It is, if you want a DDR pad, this is it.
Speaker 1: And the only thing at all I could say negative about it...
Speaker 0: Is the $400 price?
Speaker 1: Which honestly, that seems like a deal considering what it costs to get just the pad from an old DDR arcade machine.
Speaker 1: It's worth $400 easily.
Speaker 1: I think I spent more than $400.
Speaker 0: You gotta play a lot of DDR.
Speaker 1: Which I do, but also I spent almost $400 on the parts to build my two orders of magnitude lower quality DDR pad.
Speaker 1: And that took me like a month to build.
Speaker 1: So my sole complaint is that it does not use ribbon switches like arcade machines do.
Speaker 1: It uses the two metal pads, like two metal sheets under the arrow, that when they touch each other set off a sensor method.
Speaker 1: Which is fine.
Speaker 0: And this is what, there's like springs separating them or something?
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're separated by stuff inside that I don't really want to try to describe.
Speaker 0: But I mean, over time, couldn't like be in permanent contact and then you need to like bend them or something?
Speaker 1: So according to all reviews, that really doesn't happen.
Speaker 1: And these are trivially repairable yourself.
Speaker 1: They're easily open.
Speaker 1: They give you all the documentation they need.
Speaker 1: They sell you parts.
Speaker 1: People make parts.
Speaker 1: But they have zero sensitivity problems.
Speaker 1: Like I can do the thing where you run in place on a single arrow at high speed and it doesn't fucking miss a beat.
Speaker 1: It's perfect.
Speaker 1: But it makes the slightest of sort of a like squelching settling noise that normal people wouldn't hear, but I definitely hear.
Speaker 1: That ribbon switches don't do.
Speaker 0: Normal people wouldn't hear it, but I hear it.
Speaker 1: As in, I think most people who play.
Speaker 1: DDR would not even think about that noise.
Speaker 1: It is so quiet.
Speaker 1: But I hear it and I just acknowledge that it's there.
Speaker 1: It is louder than a soft red octane style inch thick foam pad.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, unless you make a DDR pad yourself that uses ribbon switches or you do something crazy like laser sensors, it's not going to get quieter than this.
Speaker 1: This is the best damn DDR pad money can buy and I'm getting a second one because I'm a life styler and I do not want to be in a situation where there are no options for me.
Speaker 0: But how long will this thing last?
Speaker 1: I imagine forever.
Speaker 1: I think they will outlive me.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty confident in that.
Speaker 0: It remains to be seen.
Speaker 1: I mean, either this thing will outlive me or I'm going to be 70 and we're going to be doing geek nights and I'm going to do an episode where I am mad as shit that this thing stopped working.
Speaker 0: I'll be like, buy a DDR arcade machine already.
Speaker 0: Buy 20, buy 500th mix or whatever.
Speaker 1: So in the news, of course, the Nintendo Direct is coming tomorrow and we can all speculate about what they're going to say.
Speaker 0: If you're listening to this, I imagine most people it'll be like today that the Nintendo Direct already happened.
Speaker 1: There are 20 people who are listening to this right now live on YouTube.
Speaker 1: So those 20 people it's tomorrow.
Speaker 0: There's a Nintendo Direct tomorrow, everybody.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: There's no reason to speculate on what they're going to talk about because almost everyone who reports on what Nintendo is going to cover is lying or making educated guesses.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the educated guesses are going to be right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's see.
Speaker 1: They're going to say something about Breath of the Wild 2.
Speaker 0: They'll talk about their Mario movie.
Speaker 0: They'll talk about the Breath of the Wild 2 that's coming soon and then a whole bunch of stuff that nobody knows.
Speaker 1: Pretty sure.
Speaker 0: I'm like, oh, you know what?
Speaker 0: Here.
Speaker 0: Except the developer.
Speaker 1: I'll play that game.
Speaker 1: They're going to finally announce a release date for Advance 4 as 1+2.
Speaker 0: They'll give us, uh, I'm just going to, you know, I'll put it out there, right?
Speaker 0: We'll just, we'll speak it into existence.
Speaker 0: F-Zero, let's go.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I would not be shocked if there's some sort of Mario Kart announcement only because we just had in another Discord a long conversation about how SNL has never been funny.
Speaker 1: Like, if you statistically analyze SNL, it has never been funny except for rare extreme exceptions.
Speaker 1: And right after that conversation, the next day, SNL released a digital short that was a trailer for a grimdark HBO reboot of Mario Kart.
Speaker 1: And the timing seems suspicious.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: They just put, I mean, Mario Kart is still like their top game.
Speaker 0: I don't feel like they need to refresh it to get sales up because sales have been up the whole time.
Speaker 0: It's the number one selling game on the Switch.
Speaker 0: And they did just release, if you have Nintendo online with expansion pack, there's a DLC for Mario Kart that I think you can also buy individually.
Speaker 0: That gets you every track ever, like from every Mario Kart or whatever.
Speaker 0: So it's like, yeah, they just upgraded the current Mario Kart rather than, I don't think they're going to make a new one so soon.
Speaker 1: Nah.
Speaker 1: I mean, I figure some announcement, I don't know what it could be.
Speaker 1: The one thing I know they won't do, Nintendo will never be capable of launching a for real esports presence of any kind, even though Mario Kart is such an obvious slam dunk.
Speaker 0: Well, I think the big, you know, the bigger news is that, you know, it's like, yeah, Nintendo has directs all the time.
Speaker 0: It's time for them to announce whatever.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But, you know, I guess if they announce something, it could be a big news.
Speaker 0: But as of now, the news that we know is that the Nintendo Switch is now officially the third best selling game console worldwide of all time.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So the number one most selling game consoles, the PS2 all of all time period.
Speaker 0: Number two is the DS and number three is the switch.
Speaker 1: So that is actually amazing on it.
Speaker 1: Not unexpected, like tracks with everything you would think, but actually for real hitting that number is kind of a big deal.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So number four is the PlayStation four and number five is the oh, no, sorry.
Speaker 1: Number four is the OG Game Boy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's number five is the PlayStation four.
Speaker 0: I think the Wii is up there too somewhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Nintendo is always asleep or just crushing it with actual sales, despite what any fanboys might say.
Speaker 0: But the other thing that I think is interesting about the Nintendo Switch that people aren't focusing on, right, is that the Nintendo Switch came out a long time ago.
Speaker 0: It's old.
Speaker 0: It came out in twenty seventeen March.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So it is six years old basically right now.
Speaker 0: Twenty seventeen plus six is twenty twenty three.
Speaker 1: And there is basically I see people who are like buying switches who never had one that one of my coworkers literally now that I think about it right around Christmas was asking like, hey, so I'm buying like I'm buying all the nephews switches for Christmas.
Speaker 1: What games should I get them?
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's like there are children who are, you know, who are too young for a switch, who then become old enough for one and then their parents get them one.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And it's like they still get a switch.
Speaker 1: There's also households.
Speaker 1: I've seen a common cause of buying yet another switch household as a switch.
Speaker 1: Parents are mostly playing it.
Speaker 1: Kid gets old enough, wants to play it a lot.
Speaker 1: Got to get a second switch because you're not you're not letting the kid play when you want to play the Spire Breath of the Wild two or whatever.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so it's like the switch is still selling, but under the normal right schedule.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: What what came before the switch, a dark age, the Wii U or whatever.
Speaker 0: The Wii U came out in twenty twelve.
Speaker 0: So that was five and late twenty twelve.
Speaker 0: So less than five years between Wii U and Switch.
Speaker 0: You know what I would say?
Speaker 1: I'm going to see our past.
Speaker 0: We are well past do well past already do a new Nintendo console, but there's.
Speaker 0: I don't think there's going to be one.
Speaker 0: I think the Switch is going to just last many, many years.
Speaker 1: I'm going to back up even further.
Speaker 1: Let's zoom out.
Speaker 1: The idea that there is a cycle and cadence to consoles coming out is there was I think it is solely an artifact of the fact that consoles appeared from nothing in recent living memory.
Speaker 1: And that was just the early evolution.
Speaker 1: And that was not predictive of the future of consoles in any way.
Speaker 1: They kept releasing new consoles all the time back in the day because hardware changed over the course of even two fucking years in the 80s.
Speaker 0: There were significant and major advancements that required, you know, that where you could put out something new that would blow the previous shit out of the water.
Speaker 1: I got sixty four fucking bits for you right here.
Speaker 1: I don't know where.
Speaker 0: significant advancements, but now you look at a switch and it's like what technology that we have available today would allow someone to make something that is a big upgrade from a Nintendo switch.
Speaker 0: It's like they put an OLED screen in and released a slightly better one.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like you can't.
Speaker 0: it's like you can't make something better than that.
Speaker 0: That's significantly.
Speaker 0: it already has USB C or it's like, you know, what do you get?
Speaker 0: Other than nerds who say it should be 4K, 120 FPS, whatever.
Speaker 1: That's nonsense.
Speaker 0: That's nonsense.
Speaker 0: That will not improve.
Speaker 0: That won't sell more switches.
Speaker 0: It won't.
Speaker 0: All it'll do is raise development costs.
Speaker 1: I mean, think it is a console that Breath of the Wild ran on like just natively and worked.
Speaker 0: They could release.
Speaker 0: Well, the Pokemon game didn't run on it very well.
Speaker 1: But that part there's a lot of reasons for that.
Speaker 1: I think the Pokemon game is a little bit glitchy.
Speaker 0: They're game free, but upgrading the switch isn't going to fix that problem.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: But if they sold Breath of the Wild level games and just kept cranking games of that caliber out, this console generation could last another decade.
Speaker 1: Probably that that's a decade.
Speaker 0: But I think you got several more years of switch without any other new Nintendo console.
Speaker 0: You might see an upgrade.
Speaker 1: I'm saying more games with that level of graphical quality, that level of polish and that level of gameplay are perfectly feasible on a switch.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, I think what is the question is, is there are certain games that Nintendo has done in the past, right, where they've done them like sort of like.
Speaker 0: they have series of games and they'll like be like one per console.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And then there are other times where they get a game and it's like hot and they'll like put out multiple iterations of it, you know, quickly.
Speaker 0: So like a good example might be like the Mario and Luigi.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: They put out Mario Luigi Superstar Saga for GBA and they're like, oh, that's a hit.
Speaker 0: And they put out like a couple more of those GBA DS, whatever, like they sort of and then they're like, it got it didn't keep going.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So then they sort of stop those all together.
Speaker 0: It's like, whereas, you know, you look at something like Mario Maker, it's like, well, they put out a Mario Maker on the DS and the Wii.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Wii U, I think.
Speaker 0: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: And then they put a Mario Maker 2 on the Switch.
Speaker 0: It's like, well, if you don't have a new console, we're well past due for Mario Maker 3.
Speaker 0: But are you going to do a Mario Maker 3 or are you just going to let Mario Maker 2 just be there and be that's the Switch Mario Maker.
Speaker 0: We're just not going to make a Mario Maker 3 until whatever console comes next and however many years that takes.
Speaker 0: So, I mean, on the one hand, it's like it's good and that you're not going to sort of like, you know, put out too many games and then sort of burn people out on that series that you put out too many instances of.
Speaker 0: But on the other hand, people who are big fans of that series, right, have been waiting a real long time for another installment.
Speaker 0: And are they just going to have to wait a super even longer time because you won't put out a new installment without a new console?
Speaker 1: But also, remember, there's super fans who have exhausted Mario Maker 2's capabilities because they're ultra fans.
Speaker 1: Then there's regular people who just play it because it's great.
Speaker 0: Don't think about it.
Speaker 0: Will the Breath of the Wild 2, even if it's great, exhaust the like, you know, even if it's great, would a Breath of the Wild 3 do well or would it be just sort of like?
Speaker 0: that's enough of that, right?
Speaker 1: I mean, it's hard to say because right now, Breath of the Wild 2 is one of the best executed single player video games I have ever played.
Speaker 0: You mean one?
Speaker 1: Yeah, one.
Speaker 0: Breath of the Wild 2 doesn't exist yet.
Speaker 1: Two is not out yet.
Speaker 0: It's coming soon.
Speaker 1: If it is just more of the same, I'm pretty deeply here for that and I don't know when I run out of steam.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but Nintendo also, you know, doesn't like doing, you know, even when they have games in the same series, they don't like doing the exact same.
Speaker 0: They always gotta mix it up.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I mean, Zelda 1, Zelda 2, then Zelda 3.
Speaker 1: Three radically different games.
Speaker 1: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 1: Speaking of that Nintendo, this video just got uploaded like a couple weeks ago and it was pretty good.
Speaker 1: It is a 20 minute exploration of the lore of Wario, like where he came from, like how he was developed, like the whole deal with Wario.
Speaker 1: Which, one, is really well put together.
Speaker 1: It's a great video.
Speaker 1: Two, I learned some things I did not know, including some games I did not know existed because they were brief and Japan only.
Speaker 1: And three, uh, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't think many kids or even people listening to Geek Nights ever actually played the Super Mario Land games that evolved into Wario down the road.
Speaker 0: I played all those games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're old.
Speaker 1: I don't think most people have.
Speaker 0: I beat them all too.
Speaker 1: I would say Super Mario Land 2 on the Game Boy would hold up today unchanged.
Speaker 0: I've played it.
Speaker 0: It holds up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, absolutely.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's not as good as like Mario 3 or Mario World, right?
Speaker 0: But I mean, you know, it's better than, it's way better than Mario Land 1.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: Mario Land 1 feels like a pre-MMC NES game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's, you know, anyway.
Speaker 1: So what do you got?
Speaker 0: So another game series that I think is very forgotten these days is Turrican.
Speaker 0: If you never played Turrican, Turrican is sort of like a shmup, sort of like a platformer.
Speaker 0: It's a lot like Contra, but like super, like even like ridiculous Contra, right?
Speaker 0: Like it's, it's wild, fast and dangerous Contra.
Speaker 1: The kind of game as a kid you'd rent and just like immediately lose, never get past the first level.
Speaker 0: You were probably playing, right?
Speaker 0: The version for like, you know, I think there was like a mega Turrican on Super Nintendo.
Speaker 1: Super Turrican I think is the one I played.
Speaker 0: Is it Super Turrican?
Speaker 0: Super Turrican, right?
Speaker 1: Yes, it was Super Turrican for SNES in 1993.
Speaker 0: But Turrican actually is a game from 1990 that was on like the Commodore 64.
Speaker 0: That was the original one.
Speaker 0: But the best rendition of the original Turrican was actually an Amiga game, right?
Speaker 0: Called Turrican 2.
Speaker 0: And that's like, that's like, that's the, that's like the Turrican, right?
Speaker 0: Is that one.
Speaker 0: But playing Turrican 2 in this day and age is difficult to do.
Speaker 0: You would need like an Amiga emulator or some shit and a ROM at least, right?
Speaker 0: So some people went about their business and they made, this is not an emulated ROM, right?
Speaker 0: They basically did a complete remake of the PC DOS version of Turrican 2 for the Amiga, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, I guess what that means is that the game, the original Amiga game was ported to PC DOS and they remade that game.
Speaker 0: And they're not associated in any way with the people who made, you know, the original anyway.
Speaker 0: But you can get the game on itch and download it and play it for no money.
Speaker 0: And it just, you know, just, it just runs, right?
Speaker 0: It's not an emulator or anything.
Speaker 0: And you're good.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 0: Oh, no way.
Speaker 0: I figured out, I figured out what this is.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: I didn't, I didn't really understand it because I didn't actually try to run it.
Speaker 0: I just read about it and I didn't fully understand what was happening, right?
Speaker 0: It's even more amazing than what I understood.
Speaker 0: So it's Turrican 2.
Speaker 0: This game was originally released for PC DOS.
Speaker 0: I guess it might've worked on MS-DOS also anyway.
Speaker 0: This is a remake of that, right?
Speaker 0: The remake is for the Amiga.
Speaker 0: You have to run this remake on an Amiga.
Speaker 0: They made, they remade a DOS game as an Amiga game.
Speaker 1: That actually makes this even better.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm saying is they've made an Amiga game that is a remake of a DOS game.
Speaker 0: And so you would need in order to play this, an Amiga emulator, an FPGA or an Amiga.
Speaker 0: It's not for Windows, it's for Amiga, but it's a remake of a DOS game.
Speaker 0: The best way to play the PC version of Turrican 2 is on an Amiga.
Speaker 1: So before we get into the better moment, one listener actually asked and the answer is a laughable no.
Speaker 1: Could the Steam Deck overtake the Switch?
Speaker 0: Not a chance.
Speaker 1: Like zero, negative percent chance.
Speaker 0: So here's the thing about the Steam Deck, right?
Speaker 0: It's like there are people who really love the Steam Deck because the games, they're mostly PC gamers, right?
Speaker 0: And it's a way for them to play those games on the go.
Speaker 0: And they might not already have an iPad or something that lets you use Steam Link.
Speaker 0: And that's a pain anyway if you're not home.
Speaker 0: And I see the value there if those are your games and you want to play them on the go.
Speaker 0: And you don't have some other devices that can play those games on the go.
Speaker 0: I see the value there for those people.
Speaker 0: But number one, I learned recently the Steam Deck is heavily subsidized by Valve, right?
Speaker 0: Which makes it a good deal to buy actually because you're getting way more than you're paying for.
Speaker 0: But it's not sustainable.
Speaker 0: And B, the sales numbers on the Steam Deck are horrifyingly low, right?
Speaker 0: It's like not low for the Steam Deck, but low compared to other consoles.
Speaker 0: Like this is like in PSP territory.
Speaker 0: This is not a, you know.
Speaker 0: And finally, there's no such thing as an exclusive game for the Steam Deck.
Speaker 0: No such thing.
Speaker 0: And there never will be such a thing.
Speaker 0: It's like, it runs PC games.
Speaker 1: It's also, literally, anyone who's not already a turbo nerd has never heard of it.
Speaker 0: Yes, it is not a thing.
Speaker 0: If you've heard of it, congratulations, you're a turbo nerd.
Speaker 1: Like you are already outside of the realm of what the vast majority of humans on Earth ever think about on a day to day basis.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: you're not gonna, you know, even if Valve does like a bunch of work to get Steam Decks on the shelf at like Target.
Speaker 0: It's like, why would they?
Speaker 0: Because those aren't gonna sell, right?
Speaker 0: People are gonna be like, what the hell?
Speaker 0: Someone might buy it for their kid by accident.
Speaker 0: That's what's gonna, right?
Speaker 0: It's like...
Speaker 1: And we got the Nintendo Direct prediction.
Speaker 1: F-Zero is going to have a crossover with 18XX.
Speaker 0: Okay, I hope so.
Speaker 0: I'll bet we'll own stocks in gravity maglev car racing companies.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: That one's more likely, I think, than ever getting a 4K switch.
Speaker 1: So, in the meta moment, Geek Nights will be live on Thursday, March 23rd at 2.30pm Eastern Time in the Bumblebee Theater at PAX.
Speaker 1: East 2023 with.
Speaker 1: Can Competitive and Casual Coexist?
Speaker 1: If the name of a panel asks a question, the answer is probably no.
Speaker 1: Or at least no with an asterisk.
Speaker 0: There are yeses.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess.
Speaker 1: Mostly when I see panels, usually that question is a no or it's a trap.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I'll leave the unseen.
Speaker 1: The Book Club book will be doing it on Thursday this week.
Speaker 1: We both read it.
Speaker 1: It was pretty good.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna announce the choices for Scott of the next two books.
Speaker 1: One of them's long and I'm still debating the second one and I'm curious which one you pick.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 0: I'm working on the website still.
Speaker 0: I did actually do a work on the website.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna shit talk about the future.
Speaker 0: I'll talk about the present and the past, right?
Speaker 0: I'm working on basically converting the data from the current website to the new website, right?
Speaker 0: And I've converted all of the Book Club related data.
Speaker 0: So, we're gonna move on to the episode related data, which is the hardest part.
Speaker 0: I also did all the news related data.
Speaker 0: So, how about that?
Speaker 1: Not bad.
Speaker 1: And otherwise, you know, check out our forum.
Speaker 1: Follow us on places that you can find us.
Speaker 1: Type the word "geek knights" into a bar pretty much anywhere in your computer and it'll probably eventually take you to something that we made.
Speaker 1: So, I was thinking about this main bit quite a bit, mostly because I tried to buy a DDR pad and found that they were in short supply and panicked and that's a big part of why I bought that hard pad.
Speaker 0: I mean, we've talked about it, you know, several times already in the news and things of the day, right?
Speaker 0: You know, the Turrican and whatever.
Speaker 0: But, yeah, there's a lot of games out there in the world that are, you know, we talk about game preservation.
Speaker 0: Like, "Oh, what do we do when these games aren't unplayable
Speaker 0: anymore?"
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: But, you know, and there's a lot of talk about the people who are doing the hard work of game preservation.
Speaker 0: But there are some people out there who they're not really in it for, like, the historical preservation aspect, but it's like they are players of a game and they are keeping that game, like, alive but barely somehow.
Speaker 0: And there are actually a lot of instances of this around the world that I encounter a lot for some reason where there's a game that's not very popular, but out of the billions of people on Earth, there's still some handful of people that care about that game a lot.
Speaker 0: And someone out there is doing work to keep that game going, right?
Speaker 0: Maybe they're doing the extra work to get the game to, like, grow, but a lot of them are just, like, subsisting.
Speaker 0: And it's quite interesting, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and there's so many different kinds of games and, like, every one of these is almost its own case study.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, it's not just video games, which are the first thing you're going to think of, but it's also, you know- All I can think of is, like, baseball.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's like, there's that county fair that has, like, the husband-calling contest, right?
Speaker 0: Or it's like there's some organization that runs that, and it's like, you know, it's probably a handful of old people somewhere who, like, organize it and get judges to get- Like, it takes work to make that happen.
Speaker 0: It doesn't just happen automatically, just because it's a tradition, right?
Speaker 0: Someone has to do it, and those people are doing it.
Speaker 0: So, examples of this that I've seen also go in the tabletop world, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, when Netrunner- well, Android Netrunner died, right?
Speaker 0: These people, they brought up their Project Nisei, and they're keeping, you know, they're making cards, they're printing cards, they're, you know, trying to avoid any legal complications, which it seems they've done so far successfully.
Speaker 0: The game is nowhere near its prior popularity, right?
Speaker 0: But it's like, if you want to play it, they got you, right?
Speaker 0: It's covered.
Speaker 1: But it's interesting, because those situations, like the Android Netrunner kind of situation, I suspect, not always, but many times leads to an interesting distillation of the community.
Speaker 1: Like, basically, all you've got left are either the people who are deeply invested in it as their sole game or as a lifestyle game, people who can't find that kind of game anywhere else, people who are super serious about playing it seriously or well.
Speaker 1: Like, you get a very almost different zoomed-in fan base compared to a more mass-market game or a game that still has commercial support outside of that kind of community.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, I mean, because even in that case, right, how hard is it to go to their website and click buy and buy some cards?
Speaker 0: Not hard at all, right?
Speaker 0: But even if you do that, okay, you got the cards, you got to get people to play with, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, well, it's like when the game was in the game stores and there were tournaments at the game stores, you know, that the game stores were running because the game stores were selling the product, it was a lot easier to get some, you know, to get people to come, right, to know about it, right?
Speaker 0: Now, the people who are doing the Project Nisei, some nerd might run some Project Nisei event at their local game store, but the local game store doesn't have Project Nisei stuff for sale, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you buy it from the website.
Speaker 0: So that already makes it so difficult to get people in on this thing and to care about it and to invest their time in it and to get, right?
Speaker 0: And, you know, how regular and reliable are the releases, right?
Speaker 0: It's like in some ways more reliable because the company that, you know, Fantasy Flight was the Shambles.
Speaker 0: But in other senses, it's like they're not coming out with packs constantly, right?
Speaker 1: Which leads to a different kind of interaction and a different kind of community.
Speaker 1: I think it also leads to possibly catering to one very specific part of that community to the possible detriment of any other parts of that community that might have existed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it becomes basically, it's like, yes, we've kept it alive.
Speaker 0: It still exists.
Speaker 0: You can still play it.
Speaker 0: It's still going.
Speaker 0: But this is barrier to entry of like having to know about it.
Speaker 1: It's like- Well, like Advance Wars is a good example.
Speaker 0: So to play it, you still have to, you know, even though they've done a lot of work to keep the game up, it still takes more work as a player to do it, even though they've already done so much than it did when the game was alive.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: So like Advance Wars would be a decent example here, too, because that game, there haven't been Advance Wars in forever.
Speaker 1: And also there is the new one that's coming out possibly soon.
Speaker 1: We'll find out tomorrow that was delayed, which is just a reboot of really old Advance Wars from a shockingly long time ago.
Speaker 1: But there was the single player like aspect of the game.
Speaker 1: There was the multiplayer aspect of the game.
Speaker 1: The community that's been keeping Advance Wars going only cares about multiplayer, only cares about extremely serious competitive Advance Wars.
Speaker 1: And if you go in there, imagine if I, the Advance Wars not, is literally one of the worst players because the meta and the kinds of maps they want to play and the way they like to play.
Speaker 1: this game has evolved so far beyond what could be even possible on the original actual releases with a custom platform they built just to support it that it's honestly almost unrecognizable to how Advance Wars multiplayer works in any original format.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean if you're an Advance Wars fan who wasn't interested in multiplayer, right?
Speaker 1: You got nothing.
Speaker 1: There is nothing for you in this community.
Speaker 0: It's like you've probably already beaten every, and you care a lot about it, you've probably already beaten all of the Advance Wars and gotten S-rank at every single thing.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: And you've played all these games that are like Advance Wars.
Speaker 1: This community has got a meta where they play competitive, serious games in maps that utilize a glitch that causes units to teleport around with like null tiles.
Speaker 1: And that's like a whole category.
Speaker 1: Like that is how deep down the rabbit hole of nonsense this community has gone.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: So it's like, yeah, they're keeping it alive, but it's like that's not, you know, they're keeping it alive for the people who care so hard about it to keep it alive.
Speaker 0: They're not keeping it alive for everybody, right?
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: Another good example is we always talk about Steel Battalion Guy because he saw them at PAX so many times.
Speaker 0: I don't know if they're still at PAX these days, but there was a game for the Xbox, the original Xbox, I don't know how many nerds remember it, called Steel Battalion.
Speaker 0: It was a mech piloting game, like MechWarrior, and the thing about this game was that there was a special controller for it that was like a big fancy dual joystick like whole thing, right?
Speaker 0: Go look it up on the internet, you'll see what it looks like.
Speaker 0: It's like a big arcade level interface with sticks and buttons and switches.
Speaker 0: And like when you played, you had to push these buttons to like start up the engines and, you know, flip like a switch to self-destruct, eject, all these different buttons everywhere, not just like a normal controller.
Speaker 0: You know, and it was pretty cool.
Speaker 0: It's fun.
Speaker 0: But obviously, right?
Speaker 0: How many people bought that thing when it was new?
Speaker 1: Not a lot of people.
Speaker 1: How many of that peripheral still exists even remotely workable in the year 2023?
Speaker 0: When it came out when we were in college, like we knew one or two people who got it and that was it.
Speaker 0: You know, those people who spent all their money on game and stuff, right?
Speaker 0: We all know those people.
Speaker 0: And that was it.
Speaker 0: And then there was a guy who got enough of them because you could play multiplayer, right?
Speaker 0: With a lot.
Speaker 0: You could make teams of like was eight on eight or something like that.
Speaker 0: Something I forget the exact numbers, but you could play a big team multiplayer with if you had enough controllers and enough Xboxes, right?
Speaker 0: But it's like the Xbox one is dead.
Speaker 0: This game is dead.
Speaker 0: You can't buy the controller anymore.
Speaker 0: It's like now think about the hurdles.
Speaker 0: One person collected enough equipment and did all the work to make this playable.
Speaker 0: But it's only accessible to people who go and find this person at an event where they set it up for you to play.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, you can't do it at home, right?
Speaker 0: It's like a good luck copying what that guy did.
Speaker 0: Where are you going to find it?
Speaker 1: You know, eight steel battalion control battle tech pods, DDR, like Guitar Hero, anything that had a special para para.
Speaker 1: Good luck playing para para paradise at home in twenty twenty three.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like there you might be able to find like a controller for Guitar Hero is probably easier.
Speaker 0: People are given those things away, right?
Speaker 0: But it's like it's not easy to get games that need a special equipment, especially if it's a big arcade rare equipment.
Speaker 0: But it also means to play, at least to play in the way that they were originally intended.
Speaker 0: Like you can play them in like a you know, without that you could steal the time with the Xbox.
Speaker 1: I mean, a lot of people play DDR just with their fingers on a keyboard because I guess that's a completely.
Speaker 0: that's.
Speaker 0: I mean, that's a completely different game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that is a big part of the community.
Speaker 1: It looks like I I've been doing a lot of DDR reading lately.
Speaker 1: Go to God.
Speaker 1: OK, well, but DDR like is dead at home because the last console release was in 2011 on the Wii.
Speaker 1: So there's really the only way anyone can play.
Speaker 1: it is in the arcade with specialized equipment.
Speaker 1: Imagine if you are in that community, your community will over time only shrink because there is almost no way to bring new people into that community.
Speaker 0: You bring people in very slowly, right?
Speaker 0: But it's hard.
Speaker 1: You have to think about how can someone even practice the game or like spend the hour to learn how to play?
Speaker 1: Even when I played Steel Battalion, I had to sit down at that guy's set up and they don't like.
Speaker 1: they're not going to explain how everything works.
Speaker 1: You play like baby's first intro mission to be good at that game.
Speaker 1: You got to play it by yourself a bunch.
Speaker 1: Imagine trying to play TIE Fighter in 20 minutes knowing nothing about it.
Speaker 1: Imagine trying to play Star Wars Squadrons in 20 minutes knowing nothing about it.
Speaker 1: You sit down at a hot ass.
Speaker 1: You've got a laminated paper that tells you 50 different buttons.
Speaker 1: Good luck.
Speaker 1: Have fun.
Speaker 1: You get to play for 20 minutes.
Speaker 1: That's your sole interaction with this game until next year at this convention.
Speaker 0: I mean if you look, for example, I remember when on GDQ there were those people playing like the scariest extreme Tetris, right?
Speaker 0: Whatever it's called.
Speaker 0: The Terror Instinct, right?
Speaker 0: Tetris Masters series.
Speaker 0: And it's like those people who were like.
Speaker 0: that's their game?
Speaker 0: They have arcade boards that they use to play the game for real, right?
Speaker 0: Because that's the only one that counts.
Speaker 0: It doesn't count if you use some emulator, right?
Speaker 0: But people see that and they want to join, you know, they get the recognition that their community exists and their game exists.
Speaker 0: And they attract people to the game.
Speaker 0: And then people want to play it and there's at least an easier way to play it with like MAME or something, right?
Speaker 0: It's not the correct way.
Speaker 0: And then people who get serious about it will try to acquire an arcade board somehow, right?
Speaker 0: But there's only so many of them and there aren't new ones.
Speaker 0: But someone might, you know, have played it and like fall out of it and not be that interested anymore and pass it on to someone who cares more.
Speaker 0: But there ends up sort of being like this hard cap on the number of like truly serious participants in the community.
Speaker 0: Because yeah, at some point there is no more boards.
Speaker 0: It's like there might be thousands of them out there, hundreds depending on what game it is.
Speaker 0: But at some point it's like that's it.
Speaker 0: Like if you somehow grew your community, there is not enough equipment out there for everyone in the community to play this game the way that, you know, the most correct best original way.
Speaker 1: Even harder are games like MMOs, games where the server is proprietary or inaccessible or unavailable.
Speaker 1: Those games die and the community of people who even have the capability to run like their own rogue instance after a game like that dies.
Speaker 1: It's so small, yet somehow they survive.
Speaker 1: The first graphical MMO in American history, in fact world history, it was released slightly before Meridian 59, was the one I played, Sierra Online's The Realm.
Speaker 1: And guess what?
Speaker 1: Not only is it still running, fans bought this shit officially and have been running it for subscription fees.
Speaker 1: It is still up to this day.
Speaker 1: There was a hotfix on December 3rd, 2022.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, I'm pretty sure that like the Meridian 59, we saw someone at PAX who was still keeping that alive somehow.
Speaker 0: I think Ultima Online, I think someone is keeping that alive somehow, right?
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 0: I'm not 100% sure on that one, but it's like there's people out there who are like, they somehow managed to get this server to run or made a fork or who knows what they did.
Speaker 1: I mean, these people bought it from Sierra like outright.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, people do that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: And they're like, the game is running, but even though the game is running, the number of people playing the game is so, so small, right?
Speaker 0: It's like if you were to log on to that Meridian 59 somehow or that Realm, it's like, are you going to see anybody?
Speaker 0: If you see one person, holy shit, a person, right?
Speaker 0: Whereas like back in the day, it was like, you log into MMO and it's like people everywhere, people.
Speaker 0: It's like, that's, you know, so are you really playing the game when there's like no people there?
Speaker 0: It's more like a single player game, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can't imagine there's more than a few hundred people in the Sierra, the Realm game.
Speaker 0: I'd be very curious to see like their daily login numbers.
Speaker 1: Right, their forum has like 12 posts like in the last few days.
Speaker 0: So I did see, I forget which game it was.
Speaker 0: It was one of those very old MMOs that's still alive.
Speaker 0: And very recently, somebody like saved up like a million, like a huge pile of like XP tickets.
Speaker 0: Like, and then spent them all on agility all at once.
Speaker 0: And it was like, it was like, you know, one of those funny deals.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But it was like some ancient looking MMO.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I forget which one.
Speaker 1: And then there are the games like tribes two that are only runnable via not a rare piece of hardware, but a dodgy exe file that kind of just makes its way around the internet.
Speaker 1: And you got to just trust it.
Speaker 0: There's a runescape runescape play.
Speaker 0: So this person in runescape, which still exists, they for eight years, they were grinding eight years to get tickets.
Speaker 0: And then after eight years, they spent all the tickets on agility all at once.
Speaker 0: Ah, I mean, I guess as long as this person enjoyed themselves, uh, but it's like you look back on your life and it's like, remember those eight years of my life I spent on runescape grinding agility tickets for agility.
Speaker 1: I mean, I regret at least two thirds of the time I spent grinding the realm, which I only actually played for like four years.
Speaker 1: Like that wasn't that long a timeframe in my life.
Speaker 1: Kind of like how magic loom so large in my childhood.
Speaker 1: I look back, I've played 0.1% of magic.
Speaker 0: Like, yeah, but it's like, I just always have that, you know, look at my life.
Speaker 0: I'm always like, you know, thinking about it from on high.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like you look at my whole timeline and it's like, all right, well, I can't control the past at all.
Speaker 0: It's already done.
Speaker 0: It's already written.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And it's like, you know, how do I choose, you know, what do I want to spend the rest of my time on?
Speaker 0: You know, is it that I want to spend, you know, an hour a day for the rest of my life on X?
Speaker 0: and that'll be, it's like, that's what I live for.
Speaker 0: I lived to grind that slot machine.
Speaker 1: Of course, then you get people, the people who commit to a lifestyle game that has staying power, like Counter-Strike 1.6 might be the best example of this ever.
Speaker 1: It never even got mostly dead.
Speaker 1: Counter-Strike 1, like the original Counter-Strike just never died.
Speaker 1: It just continued with hundreds of thousands of players into the year 2023.
Speaker 0: Well, that doesn't, nobody's like keeping it alive.
Speaker 0: Valve is keeping it still there.
Speaker 1: You can still just play.
Speaker 1: But it also has such a huge player base, which is amazing.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, it's, that's what happens when the original company doesn't dump it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But especially considering there are two other versions that came out after it that are objectively better that also are still played.
Speaker 1: I just can't get over that Counter-Strike 1.6 is still playable.
Speaker 1: In fact, there's that thing we just saw.
Speaker 1: You can play it in a web browser.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, well, it's not legit, but of course it's not legit, but it works.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I think there's somebody out there whose job it is still to work on Counter-Strike 1.6.
Speaker 0: Like that's their job.
Speaker 0: There's a full-time employee at Valve somewhere, at least one, who's like a Counter-Strike 1.6 developer.
Speaker 0: And it's like, that's what they do.
Speaker 0: So several such people.
Speaker 0: So
Speaker 1: yeah, I guess if you, if you play a game that is deeply important to you, like to the point that you would consider it as some aspect of your identity or it's like, it's something like it's a lifestyle game, like me and DDR, like game I kind of want to play my whole life.
Speaker 1: And you see it starting to decline.
Speaker 1: You have to internalize the fact that with the exception of Counter-Strike 1.6, nothing lasts forever.
Speaker 1: And you have to either decide when and how to give up on that game, decide if and how you will try to keep it alive.
Speaker 1: Maybe there's a community.
Speaker 1: Maybe you could be the person who saves competitive AeroBiz supersonic before it dies completely.
Speaker 0: Before it never existed.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Like you could be the one who keeps it going, but you should also, to Scott's point, think about, should you really?
Speaker 1: Do you want to be the person who is still spending 20 hours a week playing Counter-Strike 1.6 in the year 2053?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's not like a book, you know, sometimes it is sort of like a book, right?
Speaker 0: Something like an NES game.
Speaker 0: It's like the ROM exists.
Speaker 0: We're good, right?
Speaker 0: It's like the game is out there.
Speaker 0: It doesn't need people playing it to be alive.
Speaker 1: I can play any NES game that was ever released anytime I want by myself or with a friend on the TV.
Speaker 1: That's enough.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Someone wrote some book, it got scanned.
Speaker 0: It's in a library somewhere.
Speaker 0: It's like, no one's read it.
Speaker 0: No one might read it for decades.
Speaker 0: No one might read it for the rest of human existence.
Speaker 0: Does a tree fall in the woods?
Speaker 0: Does anyone hear it?
Speaker 0: But that book is still there.
Speaker 0: It's not about, you know, do we preserve them?
Speaker 0: It's like they've been preserved, but it's like they're, they're mostly dead, but they're not dead, dead.
Speaker 0: It's like they're there, but good luck.
Speaker 1: And remember, we, the people alive today and over the next many decades are going to figure out how this works and how to interact with this question.
Speaker 1: Because video games, just as an example, are a brand new medium.
Speaker 1: They have existed for effectively zero time in the span of human history.
Speaker 1: They're an utterly new form of entertainment and communication and interaction.
Speaker 1: And just like the console thing, we're still in like the earliest days of this stuff.
Speaker 0: I think the thing, you know, that I think recently has been like the biggest problem is in the mobile gaming area, right?
Speaker 0: Is that people, there were a lot of mobile games starting around 2008 iPhone 3G times, you know, Android and also for flip phones, right?
Speaker 0: All those like little J2ME games going down, but Blackberry games.
Speaker 1: Nevermind Flash games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the iOS games in particular, it's like, you know, even if you could like, it's hard to get a device running an old version of iOS that has the old game installed that it's like, you know, and then even then it's like, okay, you got to get a working iPhone 4 running an old iOS that'll run this old game and the app store won't, you can't connect to the app store.
Speaker 0: You can't download that old game.
Speaker 0: How are you going to get it?
Speaker 0: It's like there's, there's a lot of stuff that has been washed away there.
Speaker 1: Yup, like tears in rain.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: I simply leave you right now with something that I'm actually going to decide later because I'm going to eat dinner and play Blades in the Dark.
Speaker 1: I'm going to come back to editing this episode and I'm going to stick the first thing I think of right after the words I'm about to say, which have concluded now.
Speaker 0: It's baby.
Speaker 0: Forget it, man.
Speaker 0: Let's try something else.
Speaker 1: No, no, no.
Speaker 1: This gave me an idea.
Speaker 1: Jump action.
Speaker 1: You can break anything with the time.
Speaker 1: I can't resist her.
Speaker 0: Cars, trees, bricks, houses, her own space.
Speaker 0: It's the end of the hour.
Speaker 0: Commercial break.