Speaker 0: It's Monday, June 5th, 2023.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 1: - I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: - And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight we're talking about technology adoption and where that line is.
Speaker 0: Mostly for us.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Ah, do I have an opening event?
Speaker 0: Anything happen?
Speaker 1: I mean, I can, but it's not...
Speaker 0: Ah, we went biking.
Speaker 0: Ahh.
Speaker 0: Biking home from work the other week.
Speaker 0: A crazy guy just threatened to kill me kind of randomly and I just got away from him.
Speaker 1: Why does this happen to you, whereas I biked to work so many times?
Speaker 0: It was the weirdest, like, it was the weirdest thing that ever happened.
Speaker 0: No altercation, this wasn't even like a car honks and I flip him off.
Speaker 0: It was like I'm sitting in the bike lane on a city bike, like, in an actual separated bike lane just waiting at a light.
Speaker 0: And I hear a person talking and I'm just not thinking, I'm ignoring them.
Speaker 0: And then I realize that the person's talking to me and it's a dude just in a car that's in the lane next to me.
Speaker 0: Just, the car has no license plates on it at all.
Speaker 0: And the dude is like looking at me through his closed front window, but the rear window is open and he's just like talking at me and gesticulating.
Speaker 0: And then he's like, pay attention to me when I'm talking to you.
Speaker 0: So I look at him and then he just starts saying, you fucking bikes got to get off the road.
Speaker 0: You're going to get people killed and just starts going off on a weird rent.
Speaker 0: And I tried to bike away and he started to follow me like through the red light, right at, right at, uh, like near the UN.
Speaker 0: So I just got out my phone and pretended to call the police and he booked it.
Speaker 0: And that was the end of that.
Speaker 0: It was just, it was weird because I didn't, I just heard a voice and I didn't think anything of it.
Speaker 0: And then the guy was getting increasingly agitated that I wasn't looking at him.
Speaker 0: The no license plate thing was the cream of the crop.
Speaker 0: So I figured I could just like the, the pretend to call the police.
Speaker 1: This is why we need Spider-Man.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That's the exact kind of thing Spider-Man could deal with effectively.
Speaker 1: Spider-Man could deal with that so perfectly.
Speaker 1: That guy would be hanging by a web, right?
Speaker 1: Spider-Man would throw his car in the East river.
Speaker 1: Spider-Man's strong enough to pick up a car.
Speaker 1: He can take the dude, even if the dude has a gun or whatever.
Speaker 1: No problem.
Speaker 0: Uh, that was the most, that was the most exciting thing that happened to me other than just like biking normally.
Speaker 1: If I find a genie, I'm going to wish to be Spider-Man.
Speaker 1: We don't need to be Superman.
Speaker 1: We can keep it easier than that.
Speaker 0: Which Spider-Man?
Speaker 1: Regular Spider-Man.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess it could be Scott Spider-Man like whole new Spider-Man.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: As long as you're strong enough to pick up a car and you get web shooters.
Speaker 1: What else do you need?
Speaker 1: Oh, there's a couple other things you need.
Speaker 1: You need Spidey sense.
Speaker 0: You need Spidey sense.
Speaker 0: Like you need, but those are, that's just part of his powers.
Speaker 1: Those three things.
Speaker 1: That's all you got.
Speaker 0: I'd argue there's two more things, but both of these, well, one of these might just be another Spider-Man power.
Speaker 0: And the other one I think is the plot of this overall into the Spider-Verse world.
Speaker 0: You need S tier wise cracking skills.
Speaker 0: You have to be able to wise crack in any situation at all times and never stop.
Speaker 0: Not all the time.
Speaker 0: Able to do it.
Speaker 0: A few Spider-Men.
Speaker 1: Deadpool does it all the time.
Speaker 1: Spider-Man only does it at the beginning of the comic book.
Speaker 1: And then he doesn't do it at the opening scene where he catches some normal bad guys when he does it.
Speaker 1: And then maybe when he fights the mainville and he does it a little bit, but then he's serious the time.
Speaker 0: I guess you got to be able to wise crack in any moment if you need to, because occasionally there's a Spider-Man where the wise, it's really just, you have to be able to say, you know, it's like.
Speaker 1: The wise cracking is mostly for the entertainment of the reader, but if you're an actual Spider-Man in the real world, you just need to be able to say something to make the opponent angry and, you know, flustered, combobulated.
Speaker 0: So the listener has a question for you.
Speaker 0: Would Spider-Scott work on Fridays?
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, with great power, great responsibility, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, I don't have a very important job, so why?
Speaker 1: But if I'm from Spider-Man, well, first of all, right.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, if somebody dies on Friday and I'm Spider-Man and I could have saved them with no effort and they die because I didn't want to work that day and I wasn't fighting a super villain or something more important that was going to kill more people.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Then in a way, I killed them so that you can't have that.
Speaker 0: And the other important thing is Spider-Man always has to try to save both people.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, you got to try.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you got to try.
Speaker 0: That's the.
Speaker 0: I think that depends.
Speaker 1: Depends what's going on.
Speaker 0: So, you know, I feel like Spider-Man always tries and I feel like that's where Spider-Verse is going.
Speaker 0: But anyway, there's, uh, you know, I haven't done a Monday show in a hot minute because a bunch of reasons and we're back and it turns out today is Apple Day.
Speaker 0: And also there's a ton of tech news.
Speaker 1: So we're only going to talk about two things.
Speaker 1: Everything was timed well for us.
Speaker 1: Not like some other times where there's been big tech news on Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we got big tech.
Speaker 1: I think it's because it's a WW.
Speaker 1: I think there's always, if I look historically, I don't remember.
Speaker 1: But I, you know, cause I only really remember that like the iPhones are always in September, October for back to school.
Speaker 1: But, and the WWDC is in the summer.
Speaker 1: I don't remember exactly when, but I get the feeling WWDC probably is always on Monday because it's a conference for all the devs and they start and do a whole week.
Speaker 1: So I bet if we look historically, WWDC has been kind to our Monday shows.
Speaker 0: Of course, I also have this feeling that I remember us always saying, man, why couldn't this have been yesterday?
Speaker 1: But was that just because I mean, it could be that I'm just guessing wrong because I didn't actually look up when these things happened, but I'm betting that those are all not WWDCs.
Speaker 1: Those are all other, you know, tech announcements on other days, right?
Speaker 0: Anyway, so there's a bunch of really long show.
Speaker 1: Let's, let's talk about all that.
Speaker 0: There's a bunch of minor Apple updates, which, you know, always happens.
Speaker 0: Like the one that actually stood out to me, stood out to me was that they're removing the hay from hay Siri.
Speaker 1: And really?
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: I don't think that it's not that significant.
Speaker 1: Who cares?
Speaker 0: In that Siri, when I do have it enabled, likes to chime in.
Speaker 1: I never have it enabled.
Speaker 0: I tried it out.
Speaker 0: And what I found is that Siri likes to chime in and try to answer.
Speaker 1: I don't think I've used it since the day Siri launched.
Speaker 1: Whenever, whatever day that was.
Speaker 0: But it does that a lot.
Speaker 0: And I see other people who have it enabled all the time, like at work or it'll just chime in all the time.
Speaker 0: So I feel like removing part of the wake you up thing is not the best idea.
Speaker 0: Cause I don't think they've got a technological advancement that enables this.
Speaker 0: I think it's just ease of use.
Speaker 1: It's just a UI change basis.
Speaker 1: It's just a UI change.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: But it's a UI that is a new type of sort of trigger UI to cause an audio interaction.
Speaker 1: But really, I just think.
Speaker 1: I don't see this as any different as like, oh, they changed where the icons are, right?
Speaker 1: It's just because it's an audio interface instead of a visual interface.
Speaker 1: It's, you know, it seems different, but.
Speaker 0: I bet we'll see people having it activate more often and complaining about it.
Speaker 1: Meh, I just never had it on since the day it launched.
Speaker 1: I tested it once.
Speaker 1: I turned it off and I have never turned it on again.
Speaker 1: I guess the only of the minor Apple news is number one, the next iPad OS is cutting off the first gen iPad pro, which I had, but no longer have.
Speaker 1: I think it was Emily's mom has it or something.
Speaker 0: I forget where that ended up.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But I have the third gen one.
Speaker 1: So I assume I've got two years left on the third gen iPad pro, which does not have an M CPU in it.
Speaker 1: It's got the old a whatever.
Speaker 1: So I think I've got two years left of the iPad pro and I could still, I could see, you know, the plan I've been thinking is that, you know, when, cause right now I got the iPad and also the, you know, desktop computer, right?
Speaker 1: I could see a world still in which Apple either, you know, I get a, some Mac book or they make a Mac book that flips over or something.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And I use that to replace both my iPad and my desktop, but only my desktop for my everyday computing biz.
Speaker 1: And then I go out and get a tiny computer.
Speaker 1: That's basically just a GPU in a box.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The dedicated play steam games box.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: Anything, anything I need the GPU for.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I can remote desktop or steam stream or even KVM to use that box that has an Nvidia something in it.
Speaker 1: And then do everything else on some sort of, you know, iPad Mac book pro something, something.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And I think that's where I'm personally headed.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: It's tough cause I bought a surface laptop three pretty much when they came out.
Speaker 0: I got the top spec one and it's still totally fine.
Speaker 0: So I can't imagine buying a new laptop or tablet or anything at least for the next four or five years at this point.
Speaker 0: So I'm just waiting.
Speaker 1: I'm thinking, yeah, I mean, well, two years from now, I assume I'm going to get cut off from iPad iOS updates and I think so I'll have to do something.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: So, and the iPad is my primary computing device.
Speaker 1: when I'm, I guess, I guess I have that phone and desktop, right?
Speaker 0: When I'm traveling, I use my laptop just as my primary device.
Speaker 0: Like when I'm sitting down typing stuff, homework, anything.
Speaker 0: But the only thing I use that laptop for seriously is geek nights panels.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But I'm saying like, I use my iPad a lot seriously.
Speaker 1: So, but I could save money basically by sort of combining it, you know, and you, you know, anyway.
Speaker 1: Uh, the other thing that I think re people really glossed over, but I thought was really cool was, you know, and the Apple watch, they got these new watch, the new watch face.
Speaker 1: They showed this Snoopy one.
Speaker 1: Did you see that?
Speaker 0: Oh, I didn't see that part.
Speaker 1: They got a new Snoopy watch face.
Speaker 1: That is like the most dynamic like watch face I've seen.
Speaker 1: Like they were having it like, oh, if it's raining, then Snoopy and Woodstock will be all sad getting rained on.
Speaker 1: And like, you know, he'll, he'll like be sitting there on his typewriter during your work hours.
Speaker 1: And like, he throws a crumpled up paper and it lands on the watch hands.
Speaker 1: And it's like, anytime you look at your watch, like there would be some like something fun, you know, happening.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And, uh, I mean, I don't think there's any other watch in history that does to that level.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, kids watches just have a character with two arms.
Speaker 0: All the faces I got today, just if I look at it, one thing happens when I look at it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like, so that's, I mean, I probably won't use that watch face, but it's still, I just thought that was really fascinating sort of a new idea that hadn't been done.
Speaker 0: They did add that Apple password and passkey sharing among Apple devices.
Speaker 0: So like I could share a password for a thing with you or someone in my family, but keep it end to end encrypted so you don't know my password.
Speaker 1: I mean, one password does that.
Speaker 1: I mean, Apple did a few things that are basically competing with existing products.
Speaker 1: Like they have a new journaling app and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: But
Speaker 0: the password one's interesting because while I could see myself using that in a few limited circumstances, uh, mostly like I sell their separate accounts and separate logins for everything,
Speaker 1: but the handful
Speaker 0: of things that are shared for some reason, either because the service doesn't support it, you know, there's some reasons, uh, we don't access any of that stuff on Apple devices.
Speaker 1: So that's why I use one password.
Speaker 1: Uh, but yeah, the, um, I think that what's good, you know, people, some people like they jumped to conclusions, like panicking, like, Oh no, all the journaling apps are going to die because everyone will use the Apple journal app.
Speaker 1: Oh no.
Speaker 1: One password is under threat because Apple, everyone would just use Apple pass keys and key chain and this instead.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, but if you look in the app store notes was on the first iPhone.
Speaker 1: It's that that's how old the notes app is.
Speaker 1: Look how many note taking apps are in the app store and how well they do.
Speaker 1: Because no matter what Apple does, people are not completely satisfied with the Apple official app.
Speaker 1: They is, you know, so my PowerPoint is still alive and hasn't been defeated by, uh, whatever it's called.
Speaker 0: The keynote keynote.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Even though I would use keynote if I, if I had a Mac, right.
Speaker 0: You know, I wouldn't because honestly, Google is perfect for what we do and it's easy and keynotes real fancy though.
Speaker 1: Like you could, it's, you can make something more if you use keynote and go in on it, you can make something that's more impressive, right?
Speaker 1: Then you can with any of PowerPoint or Google, uh, slides.
Speaker 1: True.
Speaker 1: That's, that's the value of it really.
Speaker 1: I mean, they make the app.
Speaker 1: Well, they don't, I guess they don't do them that way anymore.
Speaker 1: Now they do videos, but when they did them in the theater, they used keynote for those, right?
Speaker 1: It's like they were dog food and that.
Speaker 1: So it's like, anyway, all right, let's talk about the Apple vision thing.
Speaker 1: So for many years, there were rumors and rumors and rumors.
Speaker 1: Apple was going to do some kind of goggles kind of AR something, something, right?
Speaker 1: No details, really.
Speaker 1: Just lots of rumors.
Speaker 1: They were going to do it right.
Speaker 1: Rumor, rumor, rumor.
Speaker 1: Then recently everyone's like, this is it.
Speaker 1: This is where they're actually gonna, it's coming out.
Speaker 1: And there were all sorts of whispers of like, you know, drama behind the scenes of like, people thought it wasn't going to go, but they pushed, you know, Tim Apple pushed it through and other people were like, I don't know about this, but turns out it was true.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: But the, I guess the most important thing is that there was a disconnect in my mind up until this was announced between my knowledge of what VR and AR is capable of at retail price points.
Speaker 0: And like what the state of the art is for consumer versus prosumer versus professional.
Speaker 0: And based on what people were claiming the Apple one could do, I could not see that fitting into those price points.
Speaker 1: I didn't see any claims.
Speaker 1: At least I didn't read any of the claims.
Speaker 0: Oh, speculation is all I saw.
Speaker 1: I mean, I didn't read literally anything.
Speaker 1: If there was people speculating or claims or rumors of what it actually did, I never read any of those.
Speaker 1: All I read in before today was Apple is going to make some kind of eyeball apple on your face.
Speaker 0: But I knew all I knew focused on AR and overlays, and that's not easy or cheap to do.
Speaker 0: And there's a lot of reasons why there hasn't been much like that before.
Speaker 0: And the answer was that it costs thirty five hundred dollars.
Speaker 0: That's how it has that level of technology.
Speaker 1: You're jumping right to the thirty five hundred dollars, the exact opposite of what they do in the keynote, which is save the thirty five hundred dollars.
Speaker 0: Let's bring that up front, because I want you to be disincentivized and know that you're not going to buy it before you hear about how cool it might be.
Speaker 1: So forget forget what it does.
Speaker 1: For anything to cost thirty five hundred dollars.
Speaker 0: That's a game.
Speaker 0: That is a top tier gaming workstation all in.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: The things that I have that cost that much money.
Speaker 1: Even the cameras like fancy cameras I have are not that much money.
Speaker 1: They're like half that at most.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Not even half that.
Speaker 1: So it's like my computer isn't even that much money.
Speaker 1: And maybe if you include all the monitors and all the other ancillary equipment, you know, it's like, no, I don't.
Speaker 1: What do I have that is on its own?
Speaker 1: My workstation thirty five hundred dollars.
Speaker 0: My workstation without monitors when I built it was about thirty five hundred dollars.
Speaker 1: But I never I've never bought a computer that expensive.
Speaker 1: You may recall it's like two K at most.
Speaker 0: I built that thing during the Intel sixth generation and it is still my primary workstation because I overbuilt it.
Speaker 1: Just a few months ago when I went on Newegg and I priced out a new computer, it wasn't thirty five hundred dollars.
Speaker 1: Well, nine hundred dollars.
Speaker 1: Newest Intel CPUs and Nvidia 40X something.
Speaker 0: Well, part of it was because nine hundred dollars of that was a relatively early, super fast M.2 PCIE anyway.
Speaker 0: That was a terrible.
Speaker 1: I don't think I own anything that's thirty five hundred dollars.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So therefore, maybe a piece of furniture like was the couch that I don't even think the couch was.
Speaker 0: I think our digital piano, the full like the couch.
Speaker 1: Might have been too fast.
Speaker 0: That digital piano cost around three thousand in the 90s when we got it.
Speaker 1: I still have a couch cost.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But let's say let's pretend that I did have a thirty five hundred dollar couch, even though I don't think it is.
Speaker 1: Is it this one?
Speaker 0: No, well, couches, a good couch has a lot of value in your day to day life and will last you basically forever.
Speaker 0: This is the first iteration, first gen of something from Apple.
Speaker 0: Think about the first gens of things and how much they advanced in later generations in the history of Apple.
Speaker 1: No, the couch was seventeen hundred, so not even half.
Speaker 1: So in order for me to buy anything, no matter what it does.
Speaker 1: It could be fucking unless it makes money like it's the hand of Midas that I would buy the right for.
Speaker 1: It has to be something that I use more than my couch, use more than my mattress, use more than my desktop, use more than the chair I'm sitting in right now that I cost me one thousand dollars and I bought it over a decade ago, more than my bicycle, which was less than three thousand dollars.
Speaker 1: I think, you know, it was less than thirty five hundred because it was on sale.
Speaker 1: I think the retail was thirty five.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, yeah, well, I don't have to use this thing.
Speaker 1: Constantly for it to be worth that much money.
Speaker 1: And no matter what it does, I am not going to be wearing something like that on my face like eight hours a day every day.
Speaker 0: A valve index all in assuming you have a workstation to plug it into is only a thousand dollars, including like the beacons and everything.
Speaker 1: So it's like there is my life.
Speaker 0: fully featured valve indexes or a valve index headset is like only five hundred bucks.
Speaker 1: So there is nothing in my life that I have currently valued at being worth paying that much money for.
Speaker 1: So there is no way I'm going to buy this, no matter how, even if it matches everything it's purported to do.
Speaker 1: It's not and I'm not rich, so it's not happening.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: OK, so let's talk about what the hell it does.
Speaker 1: I went before I knew anything about what it did, only that there were rumored AR goggles of some kind.
Speaker 0: And people seem to be really confusing if it was AR or VR.
Speaker 0: And it looks like it's trying to do a little bit of both.
Speaker 1: I think I think it's pretty much AR, but people are just saying VR because people don't care.
Speaker 0: Well, it is doing both in that it has two primary modes that are dynamic.
Speaker 0: If you're in an immersive app, then it fully immerses you in it like VR.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can block out the world with it because you're it's not.
Speaker 1: you're not seeing out into the world at all.
Speaker 1: It is completely blocking.
Speaker 1: There is no optical viewfinder, right?
Speaker 0: It's it.
Speaker 1: it's you're all you're only.
Speaker 1: your only vision of the outside world is through cameras.
Speaker 1: And then it's basically taking a recording of your face and has outward facing video screens so other people can see like a simulation of your eyes.
Speaker 1: They're not seeing your real eyes, but it looks like you got it.
Speaker 0: It's got a cool UX, actually, like I do like this one UX element in that it'll show your eyes to people if you can see the world through it because you're using overlays.
Speaker 0: But if you're in an app, it'll blank your eyes out.
Speaker 0: So anyone looking at you knows that you can't see them, that you're doing something else.
Speaker 1: But it's like going into it.
Speaker 1: I was like this if they actually come out with something like this, right?
Speaker 1: It's just going to be something that rich people buy to show off and don't actually use that much sharper image.
Speaker 1: type nerds by Apple fanboys who are loaded might buy it and companies might buy it for demonstrations and installations and showing off and demos and things like that.
Speaker 1: There might be some industrial applications or Apple partners that buy it so that they can then get their company highlighted on the Apple keynotes like, "Oh, check out what cool company X is doing with our
Speaker 1: product.".
Speaker 1: They always do that.
Speaker 1: But I don't think anyone else is going to be a customer of it.
Speaker 1: And I still think that that's the case.
Speaker 0: Well, I think where they've set the price point, they'll be the people who performatively have it to show it off.
Speaker 0: But I think they're really... My guess at their actual strategy is the only people they actually really want to buy this are either influencers who will just make it look cool to set the stage for people being excited about future versions of it.
Speaker 1: They want developers to buy it for sure because it's WWDC, right?
Speaker 1: Where they decided to show it off?
Speaker 1: because they want people to make software for it, to come up with ideas for it that Apple didn't have.
Speaker 0: Their actual target demographic for who would buy this headset is almost entirely industrial and operational companies.
Speaker 0: This is the kind of thing...
Speaker 1: There are already competitors in that space with products like the Microsoft Holo lens or whatever.
Speaker 0: And the only thing I can see different based on what we know about it so far, because I haven't released every detail about it.
Speaker 0: We're going based on what WWDC said.
Speaker 0: It seems like it is a material advancement in capabilities from all the existing AR headsets that are available to purchase.
Speaker 1: Based on what they said.
Speaker 1: Who knows what the reality is?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so my plan is I want to, when I can, without waiting in a line, I want to try it out at an Apple store.
Speaker 1: Yeah, everyone is.
Speaker 0: Because this is the kind of thing that I am very interested in.
Speaker 0: AR is such a killer app.
Speaker 0: But that said, I ain't dropping thirty five hundred bucks on something as excited as I am.
Speaker 1: I can afford to and I'm not going to.
Speaker 1: There's not a zero percent chance.
Speaker 1: If I'm going to drop thirty five hundred, I'll just buy MacBooks, right?
Speaker 1: It's like just get MacBooks.
Speaker 1: Because
Speaker 0: I've had the experience in VR, like regular old like consumer VR in an index of just using the desktop apps where I'm sitting at my desk, I put on the headset and I have several monitors and things all around me in free space that I can spin around and look at.
Speaker 0: And I've found that useful in some situations and interesting.
Speaker 0: But that is not.
Speaker 0: that was not materially better with that level of technology, especially that level of comfort than just having a smaller number of physical monitors in my real space.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So here's the thing, though, despite the insane price and despite going into it, thinking that's just some ridiculous product I'll never need.
Speaker 1: They did sell me right.
Speaker 1: They were showing the use cases for it.
Speaker 1: Like here's why you might want this.
Speaker 1: And I was actually sold on two use cases where I could see.
Speaker 1: those are viable use cases that show me why this product actually makes sense as a real thing that someone might need.
Speaker 1: So the first use case is, effectively speaking, this is like ten monitors and a home theater in a very small package.
Speaker 1: So if you are, say, somebody who at home does work with like several monitors, but you also travel a lot and when you travel, maybe you've got the biggest MacBook.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: That's still just one screen.
Speaker 1: Maybe you've got the iPad next to it to do the double screen thing that you can do.
Speaker 1: It's like that's still two screens.
Speaker 1: This is smaller than that kind of and is like enormous screen, effectively speaking.
Speaker 1: So if you're someone who does multi screen work and you travel, this lets you be very productive as you would be at home on the road.
Speaker 1: And that's that's a value proposition that makes sense.
Speaker 0: Similarly, we were talking about this before the show.
Speaker 0: You live in a tiny crappy place, a tiny space, tiny little closet.
Speaker 1: You're like a bender live in a closet or some shit.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You can't possibly fit.
Speaker 1: You got maybe got a tiny little TV.
Speaker 1: If you have anything at all, you can't fit a whole computer desk in.
Speaker 1: You're in there.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: But you want to have the experience of a home theater and a big this plus a lazy boy would not be the worst way to go if you're alone in a small space.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, if you think like if you're talking about the price, they actually say this in the keynote and it's not I don't I can't disagree.
Speaker 1: They're like, yeah, listen, this is thirty five hundred.
Speaker 1: But for the price of a home theater and a computer and a bunch of monitors and speakers, and et cetera, et cetera, this is actually less than the price of all those things combined.
Speaker 1: Now live in it.
Speaker 1: If you live in a tiny space and you want all those things and would use them frequently combined and you buy this and don't buy those other things at all, you're no worse off because you're basically spent the same close money and you saved a lot of space in your apartment and you can now save money on rent.
Speaker 1: You're living in a smaller place.
Speaker 0: On one hand, you could buy for the price of this thing seven index headsets, which are high resolution VR that can do a lot of what this does.
Speaker 0: You can watch a movie at pretty high resolution comfortably.
Speaker 0: It has similar specs, but I'm we're waiting to see the full specs on this thing in detail.
Speaker 0: But based on what they've said, it looks like because of the more limited scope of what this device is intending to do, mostly that it seems to be very good at overlaying a 2D plane or a curved effectively 2D plane with content on it, as opposed to doing a full 3D rendered world of like gaming VR.
Speaker 0: It would probably be orders of magnitude more quality for similar computing and battery and all and weight and waste than like a valve index,
Speaker 1: especially the feature that lets your MacBook, if you have one, if you somehow can afford this and a MacBook
Speaker 0: show up as a screen
Speaker 1: among your screens.
Speaker 1: And that's like you're really getting the productivity going on that way.
Speaker 0: But especially because this part of the price point seems to be that they can, because of what I described, have that high resolution experience in a headset that looks like it's not heavy
Speaker 1: and it is tiny because the battery is the end of a cable and only last two hours.
Speaker 1: So which you're going to be using this?
Speaker 1: plugged in at home or plugged in at work.
Speaker 1: You're not used.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: I mean, we'll see.
Speaker 1: But also notice that the battery you can detach the cable, which means you could buy a bunch of extra batteries for your long flight.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because that was a problem with Google Glass.
Speaker 0: Not that that's more like an auxiliary screen as opposed to AR.
Speaker 0: But, you know, we had Google Glass.
Speaker 0: we wore for a couple of years.
Speaker 0: I recently went through my archive of every photo I took with it, and it was a shockingly cool flashback of what my life was like back then.
Speaker 0: But I digress.
Speaker 0: Its main problem was that it only had a battery in it.
Speaker 0: So there wasn't a good way to plug a battery into it and put it like in your pocket to keep it going without a really ugly USB cable.
Speaker 0: And because of the way it was designed, it would overheat if you did that at all these problems.
Speaker 0: I think having the battery external on a wire is a really good idea.
Speaker 1: Well, I think it's just the best they could do.
Speaker 1: I think it's a problem.
Speaker 0: Well, it's better to it's kind of like you don't you want to wait.
Speaker 1: Obviously, you don't want it.
Speaker 1: Yes, you obviously don't want it on your head, right?
Speaker 1: It's the best they could do given the circumstances.
Speaker 1: But it's basically just like because of the circumstances, it's just not good enough, right?
Speaker 0: I think that's fine.
Speaker 0: That I have no complaint about that little cable.
Speaker 1: Well, at the back, I think it's not so much the cable.
Speaker 1: I think it's more that you got this whole fucking battery that's bigger than a phone.
Speaker 0: I can see a picture of it.
Speaker 0: It's smaller than my phone.
Speaker 1: Just stick it in your back pocket.
Speaker 1: You're good to go.
Speaker 1: Oh, and the video, it looked like it was like the size of like three phones, the battery.
Speaker 0: I think there's different versions because I'm looking at some photos and the photo I've got right now, it looks like my small anchor, not the tiny lipstick one, but like the old black anchor.
Speaker 1: We'll have to see how big that battery is.
Speaker 1: I thought it was a large.
Speaker 0: I imagine they might have multiple sizes.
Speaker 1: And the battery that I saw looked bigger than like the biggest iPhone.
Speaker 0: Now, the question really is going to be, is that just a battery or is that also the wireless?
Speaker 0: Did they confirm that?
Speaker 1: Yes, the thing that you attach is just a battery because the alternative is to plug into the wall.
Speaker 1: OK, everything is in the headset.
Speaker 1: All the chips, all the radios, all the cameras, they're all in your face, in the face part.
Speaker 1: So the other thing, the other use case they sold me on, right, was the when they showed a person on the airplane, like turning the knob to sort of turn off the air and go to just basically effectively VR, but basically block out the world and put in like a fake, you know, landscape around everything, basically the wallpaper, because I basically I saw that as like.
Speaker 1: that's like noise canceling headphones.
Speaker 1: And you don't want to hear anything else.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Other than what you want to be listening to, only this is like noise canceling for your eyes.
Speaker 1: I don't want to see any.
Speaker 1: I want to want to close my eyes and see nothing.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I don't want to go to sleep with a sleep mask, but I don't want to see anything at all.
Speaker 1: I don't want to see the people next to me.
Speaker 1: I don't want to see what's going on in this plane.
Speaker 1: I just but I want to see what I'm working on only noise canceling for the eyes, which we had a show on augmented reality in like twenty thirteen.
Speaker 1: We took it to the next level.
Speaker 1: Ed Block, IRL
Speaker 0: Ed Block, which I'm pretty sure we talked about in twenty thirteen on the show, because imagine if you could just replace every ad that ever appeared in your real life, walking down the street with
Speaker 1: all the billboards, all the flyers, all ads on TVs that are in a restaurant.
Speaker 1: There's a TV and your goggles like block the TV during the ad.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And then you're you're.
Speaker 1: the noise canceling blocks the audio from the ad, even though that everyone else who isn't wearing it still sees it because they're in the restaurant.
Speaker 0: That is a killer app that we're a ways from because this is not based on everything we know about it.
Speaker 0: The walk around with AR in your daily life.
Speaker 0: This is the task.
Speaker 0: oriented augmented reality.
Speaker 1: Now, the one that they sold on me a little bit right was when the guy was like watching sports on TV and they had all this extra stuff around the edge of the screen.
Speaker 1: Because like when I watch a hockey, I might have like a discord open or chatting with people about it and I might have some stats websites open.
Speaker 0: If I could pop discord, just be floating like above the TV.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: If I could just look at the TV the whole time and see all that stuff or better yet, go to a live sporting event and be able to keep my eyes on the action and see that stuff around without having to look at a phone, take my phone out and look away from the game.
Speaker 1: There's something there, but I don't think it's not as compelling as the other two things I mentioned.
Speaker 0: Or I would argue it's hyper compelling, but in a future state of AR hardware.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Now, the thing that I was absolutely the opposite of sold on was when like they showed the dude taking photos of like his kids with it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And it's like, and I was like, notice how every person he's taking a photo of all the memories, right?
Speaker 1: Are photos of people who are not wearing these stupid glasses, right?
Speaker 1: Only the person who's taking the photos is wearing these.
Speaker 1: Like he's in the kitchen and he takes photos of his kids over there.
Speaker 1: It's like, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: If you want to be honest, you got to have the kids wearing these and the whole family wearing these and then take the photos of your family and you have a memory of everyone wearing these stupid fucking apple goggles.
Speaker 1: And that obviously they didn't do that because that doesn't sell.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: That's a that's too obviously dystopian.
Speaker 0: Well, especially because what's funny is lesser tech like those snap glasses that kind of failed or Google Glass.
Speaker 0: If you want to just be able to take photos, that was a killer app.
Speaker 0: Like the photo taking of Google Glass was way more useful than most of what the rest of it did.
Speaker 1: But yeah, so I don't, you know, I don't think this is something that you're going to be wearing around the house just your whole daily life.
Speaker 1: You wear it when it's like time to sit in the home theater being productive or when there's a special circumstance like, you know, this is a time where this is going to enhance the activity I am about to participate in.
Speaker 1: Therefore, I will apply it.
Speaker 0: The phrase is task oriented, augmented reality that you're not going to be wearing this thing.
Speaker 1: They have not shown me any legitimate case where I think it's.
Speaker 1: I think it's actively bad to be wearing this when doing anything for which it is not very well.
Speaker 0: Say I had one.
Speaker 0: You know where I might wear it?
Speaker 0: Biking to like have nice direction.
Speaker 1: I would not wear it while biking.
Speaker 1: The battery dies in two hours.
Speaker 1: Once that battery dies, you see black and you die.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Hell no.
Speaker 0: I would plug that into a bigger battery.
Speaker 1: I guess if your bike ride is like 30 minutes.
Speaker 1: But I don't think this is.
Speaker 1: that's a terrible idea, especially since they said they were they bragged about reducing lag.
Speaker 1: The lag is still probably more than zero.
Speaker 0: I would wear it as the head of panels at a convention, sitting in panel ops doing my doing my thing.
Speaker 0: Maybe I could see myself doing that.
Speaker 0: I could see myself wearing it like watching a movie with friends remotely, especially if I could see if you're talking about jobs.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I could see, you know, somebody who's at an information booth.
Speaker 1: You could greet the customers, you could see them and talk to them and bring up information and answer their questions without looking away.
Speaker 0: You know, who'd be wearing this a plus at a five star hotel, the concierge.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: A teacher or a professor could wear this right while they're teaching a class.
Speaker 1: Because then they wouldn't have to like go in futz with their thing and change the slides or they wouldn't have to have a separate monitor to see the slides if they had any or things like that.
Speaker 0: Remember, the student, they can look up answers to things students are asking in real time.
Speaker 0: They don't admit that they don't know.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's there are cases like that where it becomes a value.
Speaker 1: But for a person, I guess I only see this first version of goodbye.
Speaker 1: Rich company has a use for it.
Speaker 1: Or you live in a really tiny space and somehow even those thirty five hundred dollars, it makes economic sense because it's still cheaper than a bigger space, a home theater and a computer and et cetera, et cetera, et cetera.
Speaker 0: And while, you know, I don't regret buying in and like using Google Glass for one thousand dollars, I'm saying I don't regret a half.
Speaker 1: This is Google Glass for you and all your friends.
Speaker 0: I don't regret that.
Speaker 0: But that price point ended up being like about how much value I got.
Speaker 0: Like I don't regret spending that much money.
Speaker 1: You used Google Glass a lot.
Speaker 0: I don't even know this is I'm not going to get seven valve index headsets worth of value out of this thing.
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 1: when I had the Google Glass, I wore I got I woke up, took a shower, I put it on.
Speaker 1: I didn't take it off till the end of the day.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: This is not that level of usage.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But, you know, what will this look till twenty twenty four?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: What will this look like?
Speaker 1: In twenty thirty.
Speaker 1: That's when.
Speaker 1: Is there going to be Apple Vision Mini?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: What is that going to look like?
Speaker 1: And I think that's when we might start considering, you know, maybe getting it if you have.
Speaker 0: You know, I'm going to link to the episode on augmented reality we did into the 2013 because what the hell we said then.
Speaker 0: Pretty sure the future state of augmented reality has always been the same idea and just the hardware cannot achieve that yet, nor can software in our current world.
Speaker 0: So it's kind of moot like.
Speaker 0: But when we get there, augmented reality is existentially and foundationally shattering to how humans interact.
Speaker 0: But that's a ways off because the hardware is not there.
Speaker 0: A.I.
Speaker 0: is going to mess this up way before we get to that.
Speaker 1: I think the most dystopian thing about this was not the eyeball thing.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Where, like, you're not seeing the person's real eyes when you look at them.
Speaker 0: I want to put like non-human eyes in there.
Speaker 0: Like a little robot eyes.
Speaker 1: The thing is that basically they said that when you set it up for the first time, you sort of aim it at your face so it can see your eyes and record them and whatnot.
Speaker 1: But also when you set it up for the first time, it captures your whole face.
Speaker 1: Because let's say you FaceTime someone while wearing this.
Speaker 1: Well, there isn't like a Web camera aimed at your face.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's basically going to make up sort of automatic right to.
Speaker 1: And even if there was a Web camera aimed at your face, what would it see?
Speaker 1: It would see a person wearing stupid fucking goggles.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So that's just not going to work for FaceTime.
Speaker 1: Instead, when you set it up and it captures your eyes, it captures your face and they create basically a virtual.
Speaker 0: you sort of like a live member is an automated Vtuber of your actual face.
Speaker 0: But it's also if someone somehow steals that data, that's everything you need to make deep fakes.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: But it basically it basically deep fakes you so that if you FaceTime with this, people can sort of see a virtual you instead of the real you while you're talking to them with FaceTime.
Speaker 1: But meanwhile, you see the real them because they're using normal Web camera.
Speaker 1: They didn't spend thirty five hundred dollars.
Speaker 1: So that was like, I think, a negative thing.
Speaker 1: It's like if you're going to FaceTime, you do not want to use this.
Speaker 1: Like even if you own one, it's like FaceTime.
Speaker 1: Take that thing off and get your iPhone out.
Speaker 0: It's like, yeah, they actually showed using it for completely separate corporate presentations, stuff like that completely separately.
Speaker 1: They showed they added FaceTime to Apple TV.
Speaker 1: That looked great, actually.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Just have to you just have to use your iPhone camera or something because the Apple TV doesn't have a camera.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But that actually looked terrific.
Speaker 1: Like it's like that kind of makes me think like, you know, you know, maybe Apple TV isn't the worst idea.
Speaker 1: Even, you know, HDPC is still way better.
Speaker 1: But it's like my HDPC isn't Apple, so I can't FaceTime that.
Speaker 1: But Apple, you know, Apple TV, I can't run ROMs or Steam with it.
Speaker 0: So one other news that we probably won't dwell on too long, because this is the tip of another long iceberg conversation I'm going to read.
Speaker 0: This is a post in the Apollo app.
Speaker 0: Reddit.
Speaker 0: It's very short.
Speaker 0: The top part had a call with Reddit to discuss pricing.
Speaker 0: Bad news for third party apps.
Speaker 0: They're announced pricing is close to Twitter's pricing, and Apollo would have to pay Reddit 20 million dollars a year to keep running.
Speaker 1: So if you don't know, Reddit is a popular website.
Speaker 1: That's, you know, a lot of people say a lot of different things about it, but it's basically, you know, forums.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: That are all separate, mostly.
Speaker 1: So each, you know, people say, oh, Reddit's full of shitty people.
Speaker 1: But actually, that's like saying, you know, PHP BB is full of shitty people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Counter Strike is full of shitty people like, yes, that's true.
Speaker 0: But also that's missing the point about public spaces and people.
Speaker 1: But Reddit, I think, is currently like in terms of the, you know, the platforms online.
Speaker 1: I think it's like, you know, in my opinion, at least it's like the best one right now.
Speaker 0: If I'm trying to learn to figure something out, I will go to a Reddit way before I'll go to a fandom wiki.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I use it more than a lot of the other ones because I have been very choosy.
Speaker 1: I unsubscribe from all subreddits except for a very, very few that are extremely relevant to my interests, like the one for the neighborhood I live in that is very active with cool people and has lots of good info.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: New York City biking like.
Speaker 1: that's the specificness.
Speaker 0: I'm in a micro group there that is just people who live in Queens who play Euchre.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So it's like that's.
Speaker 1: Reddit is valuable, but the user interface of Reddit, despite the fact that Reddit has like less ads and less it doesn't have no ads is less ads and less BS than a lot of the competitors.
Speaker 1: The UI basically they had an original UI.
Speaker 1: that is OK, but it's so old web and tiny text.
Speaker 1: It's not, you know, I know people like it because they're old school and used to it, but not a fan of that because it's so, you know, it's old and hard to use.
Speaker 1: And they got a new one, which is a little bit better, but also worse in a lot of ways.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Because it's slow and janky and but it's it just looks nicer.
Speaker 1: But it's more modern, I guess.
Speaker 1: So people love third party apps.
Speaker 1: Use the Reddit API, get a better UI because the official UI is a garbage and third party apps just broadly like forget Reddit are very much.
Speaker 0: They're not.
Speaker 0: they don't follow the World Wide Web ethos like there's a lot like this breaks down pretty quick.
Speaker 0: But the World Wide Web, one of its key components was that information is made available and you can render it however you want in the client and you shouldn't care how anyone renders your content.
Speaker 0: And there are.
Speaker 1: there are standards that browsers are supposed to follow.
Speaker 0: But if someone wants to change that, it's like if I want to always see thing in Comic Sans, like, sure, if I want to block ads from your website, sure.
Speaker 0: But third party apps serve the same purpose because somebody is going to want to use Reddit differently and it should be in that same ethos.
Speaker 0: Anyone should be able to interact with that public service where someone has an account and render the data they get out of it this any way they want.
Speaker 1: But when this topic comes up, accessibility also always comes up because a lot of websites are not and other Web services are not super accessible in their default forms.
Speaker 1: And a lot of third party apps either exist because they are better than the default in terms of accessibility or that's like a side effect, like they happen to be better UI.
Speaker 1: That's why they have customers.
Speaker 1: Therefore, they're also better UX and more accessible.
Speaker 1: And so now they become necessary for people who have accessibility issues in order to access the service in a good way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but this leads to because if an objective way to make any user experience both more accessible and a better user experience is to not have ads in it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So basically, Apollo is the best and I use it.
Speaker 1: I paid for it.
Speaker 1: Third party app for Reddit for your phone or your tablet or whatever you got.
Speaker 1: And it's.
Speaker 1: it's not perfect, but it's a lot better than any of the official Reddit app or Reddit website.
Speaker 1: And I like it a lot so much that I paid for it.
Speaker 1: But Reddit is decided, well, we're losing money.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: That guy is making money selling his app.
Speaker 1: We're losing money because everyone who uses that app to go to our service is using our bandwidth.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Getting our content costing us money, but they're not seeing our ads.
Speaker 1: So we're going to charge them money to hit our API and they're going to charge so much to that.
Speaker 1: Basically, their financial model no longer makes sense because nobody's going to pay that much to use Apollo.
Speaker 0: CNBC is reporting on this and they have.
Speaker 0: they have the money line.
Speaker 0: One sentence at the end of the article with the digital ad market facing a slowdown and Reddit now 18 months removed from the notification of its confidential IPO filing, the company may be facing pressure to bolster its revenue.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, Reddit, if you don't know, was originally like a standalone company.
Speaker 1: The guy who founded it, I met one time.
Speaker 1: He was a Silicon Valley dude.
Speaker 1: He was a weird dude, but somehow he ended up marrying Serena Williams and making babies.
Speaker 1: That was I thought that was the worst.
Speaker 1: But yeah, they seem to be happily married.
Speaker 1: So great, great for them.
Speaker 1: But so that dude isn't there anymore.
Speaker 1: Reddit got bought by Conde Nast, the magazine company.
Speaker 1: But then basically there's this other holding company that like owns Conde Nast and several other things.
Speaker 1: Reddit got broken off of Conde Nast and moved up.
Speaker 1: So now it's at basically the same level as Conde Nast owned by the same holding company.
Speaker 1: And so it's.
Speaker 1: I don't know how you can IPO when you're a wholly owned subsidiary.
Speaker 1: Does that mean you're no longer owned by the subsidiary?
Speaker 1: They're effectively selling the company to the public.
Speaker 1: Is that how that works?
Speaker 0: I'm not familiar with the details of how this one went down.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: But there's been rumors that they're going to IPO, but they haven't.
Speaker 1: So who knows yet, at least.
Speaker 1: But yeah, Reddit is, you know, doing very well in one sense and that it's sort of picking up a lot of steam from all these other Internet platforms doing poorly.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's how I came to it in the first place was when, like, Dig and a lot of other things failed, you know, and I sort of had to, you know, I gave up and went to Reddit instead.
Speaker 0: Well, the fundamental problem that we talk about a lot and always comes back to capitalism.
Speaker 0: None of these things make money.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: And actually, the CNBC reporting on Reddit specifically points out that Reddit makes the bulk of its money from advertising and it has never been able to significantly monetize its users.
Speaker 0: compared to even Facebook and Pinterest, which have done like they've captured a lot more money per user.
Speaker 0: Reddit cannot capture money from users, partly because I think a lot of people who use Reddit heavily are the kinds of people who are aggressively block ads.
Speaker 1: Well, I think also the people who are using Reddit are the people who are there for a like specific thing.
Speaker 1: They're not doom scrolling.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Like, you know, you can't just throw some other shit at them.
Speaker 1: That's not what they're looking like.
Speaker 0: I go to the Astoria even if it's not as I read every recent post, maybe like and that's it.
Speaker 0: Then I'm done for the day.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: Maybe the people go to Reddit and, you know, they search for a specific thing, find it, and that they're done.
Speaker 0: Notice how if you Google for stuff, a lot of times the Google auto suggestion will just add a Reddit to the end of a question because people are trying to find a Reddit that answers it compared to you
Speaker 1: don't know how to go to site colon Reddit dot com or they don't know how to go to Reddit first and then
Speaker 0: also some of the other searches in Google.
Speaker 0: Total aside that I discovered this on YouTube, Google and YouTube have quietly removed some of the operators that used to work.
Speaker 1: Interesting.
Speaker 0: Like Minus has stopped working in YouTube searches.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 0: But not in Google search.
Speaker 1: I'll have to test that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I never had that problem.
Speaker 0: I thought, well, I haven't used Minus on YouTube in a while.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess I don't.
Speaker 1: Minus is not something I use on YouTube generally.
Speaker 1: But yeah, Reddit is in trouble.
Speaker 1: And if they actually go through with this and ruin the third party apps, they might be in more trouble because the one thing that's actually keeping Reddit afloat is that they don't pay moderators anything.
Speaker 1: Every subreddit is something that someone makes for free and people, whoever starts the subreddit, has to moderate it themselves or get moderators.
Speaker 1: And those moderators are all working for free.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Unless somehow someone has a subreddit and they somehow make money and then they can pay their moderators.
Speaker 1: But Reddit isn't paying anybody.
Speaker 1: So even though they probably should, because moderators work harder than YouTube creators and YouTube pays YouTube creators somehow.
Speaker 0: So regardless, all those moderators, YouTube creators, somehow 99 percent of them make dozens of dollars a year.
Speaker 1: But Reddit moderators make zero dollars.
Speaker 1: But the Reddit moderators are like, they're the most ready.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: They're like, you already don't pay us.
Speaker 1: And now you're going to try to ruin Apollo and make Reddit even worse.
Speaker 1: Screw you.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You won't exist without us.
Speaker 1: And they are a bunch of major, major subreddits are going to just go dark.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: They're like, these subreddits are still ours.
Speaker 1: We we moderate them so we can turn them off.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: The tricky part is nobody has a place to go except rolling their own.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: But the point is, is that they can still put a lot of pressure on Reddit by making Reddit's website like.
Speaker 1: Reddit doesn't have enough control of its own website.
Speaker 1: Like it could be made useless by its users.
Speaker 0: Well, right.
Speaker 1: Turning off like Twitter.
Speaker 0: Twitter is getting like like getting worse and worse because people who make content are just leaving it slowly and steadily.
Speaker 1: So I guess there's a blackout on Reddit and we'll see if that pressures them to change the.
Speaker 0: here is my worry.
Speaker 0: If that pressure is successful, Reddit can't make money and will eventually go away anyway.
Speaker 0: If that pressure is not successful, Reddit will get worse and still won't make money and will still go away eventually because we're still skipping the fundamental point.
Speaker 0: None of these fucking websites make money.
Speaker 1: I think Reddit could be.
Speaker 1: I mean, well, it cannot be capitalist successful, right?
Speaker 0: If it's trying to IPO or I think Reddit could run at a break even.
Speaker 0: I think Twitter could have run at a break even.
Speaker 1: I think Reddit could be run profitably.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Not not vastly, but profit.
Speaker 0: When I say break even, I mean it can pay for its expenses and maybe it generates a little extra.
Speaker 1: If Wikipedia and archive.org can carry on, Reddit can carry on if its only goal is to carry on.
Speaker 0: Name a third one that carries on.
Speaker 0: Like that's the problem.
Speaker 0: Wikipedia, not many, not big ones.
Speaker 0: Wikipedia, partly because it's the only game in town for that.
Speaker 0: And also because it has a lot of institutional donation like.
Speaker 0: But Wikipedia somehow convinced all of society, except extreme right wing, not jobs, that it is a net good for the world.
Speaker 0: A lot of people earnestly believe in the mission of Wikipedia, probably orders of magnitude more than even know what Reddit is.
Speaker 1: I think the people who are the Reddit people, the people who use Apollo, right?
Speaker 1: If Reddit were somehow the ownership of Reddit was moved to either a non-profit or at least some group public benefit company, something like that.
Speaker 1: Anything that didn't care about making a lot of money, they just cared about maintaining Reddit.
Speaker 1: First of all, the first party apps and the website would stop sucking.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And so you wouldn't need the third party apps.
Speaker 1: And second of all, they would be able, if they managed to do that, then they would be able to garner the massive donations like Wikipedia does.
Speaker 1: I think you're right float.
Speaker 0: So that's they can even make the case of, look, if we can get enough donations to keep this human resource alive, then we will stop selling ads forever.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I think, you know, we just need the ownership of Reddit to change hands to the right party.
Speaker 1: But the problem, just like with sort of like how Flickr Flickr went to the, you know, Flickr is not doing well numbers wise.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But it was, you know, it's now owned by SmugMug, I think.
Speaker 1: And it is being well.
Speaker 0: Flickr now sells a product that its users pay for and I still pay for it.
Speaker 0: And it's a fine product.
Speaker 1: It's like people have forgotten Flickr, but Flickr is well taken care of.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's there.
Speaker 1: It's not going anywhere.
Speaker 1: So I think Reddit, if in the right hands, it could be well taken care of.
Speaker 0: Oh, absolutely.
Speaker 1: It's not its current hands.
Speaker 0: Reddit and Twitter and things like it, no social media network, no popular website could ever pay back the people who threw their money at it in the first place, expecting it to give them money back.
Speaker 1: Unless the amount of money they gave in the first place is very small.
Speaker 0: Which I don't think that's the case, considering things have never made fucking money at any point.
Speaker 1: What did Condé pay to buy Reddit?
Speaker 0: But anyway, we've gone on almost an hour.
Speaker 0: This is what happens when we don't do shows for a while.
Speaker 1: Get giant news.
Speaker 0: We also get pent up.
Speaker 0: You know, we have hung out a lot.
Speaker 0: Covid is still winding down.
Speaker 0: Things of the day.
Speaker 0: So this real short video, 54 seconds.
Speaker 0: This is a you know, there's.
Speaker 0: you're probably familiar with water, toilet and whole toilet, like the two primary kinds of toilets, either just a hole or a hole with some water in it.
Speaker 0: But did you know there's a third chemical toilet that's out there?
Speaker 0: There's the toilet with acid in it.
Speaker 0: There is another kind of toilet many of you might not be familiar with.
Speaker 0: This is the fire toilet.
Speaker 0: You poop in this toilet and it incinerates your poop into a fine white ash.
Speaker 0: No smell, no sound, just ash.
Speaker 0: And you dump the ash out every month or two.
Speaker 0: And this video in 54 seconds shows you how this thing works.
Speaker 0: And it is pretty cool.
Speaker 0: My solution is don't live in a place where you need to use the fire toilet.
Speaker 1: That's correct.
Speaker 1: And we don't need to have the fire.
Speaker 0: I mean, this is from Svalbard, Svalbard.
Speaker 0: So this is basically like North Hebra.
Speaker 0: If you're playing Tears of the Kingdom right now, don't live there.
Speaker 0: Like, yeah, live on like the edge of North Hebra hanging off that cliff.
Speaker 1: So when people talk about writing programs in assembly language, usually they're talking about writing programs for like an embedded device, a microcontroller, an old computer, you know, like an NES game or just, you know, if it's if it's for a modern computer, they're talking about writing something that like prints some text or does something really small.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: The idea of trying to write like a, you know, imagine trying to write like a modern application, like fucking Discord or YouTube or something in assembly.
Speaker 1: It's like that's not happening.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But here this is.
Speaker 1: I've never seen this before.
Speaker 1: Someone is this thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Someone has a whole tutorial right with all the code of how to write a GUI app in assembly.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: They're not writing the whole operating system from nothing.
Speaker 1: This doesn't run on bare metal.
Speaker 1: It's you already have a Linux computer with X 11 and you're going to write a program that actually opens a window and puts text in the window.
Speaker 1: But you're going to write that program in assembly.
Speaker 1: And that's pretty impressive.
Speaker 1: that they were able to do that, I think.
Speaker 1: And I think there's a lot to learn if you go through this exercise.
Speaker 1: So that's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: In the moment, the gig nights book club book was the satanic versus.
Speaker 0: We're done to the episode.
Speaker 0: Great book.
Speaker 0: You should read it.
Speaker 0: The new one is the book recommended by everyone's favorite person, Biggles Dickles Wolfwood that made the rounds.
Speaker 0: This is how you lose the time war.
Speaker 0: That's the title, I think.
Speaker 1: That's correct.
Speaker 1: The book is very short.
Speaker 1: It's like 200 pages and it has two authors, which is might break our website a bit.
Speaker 1: The two authors, I hope I can pronounce their names correctly.
Speaker 1: I think one of them is Max Gladstone.
Speaker 1: Easy name.
Speaker 1: The other person is Amal El Motar, I guess.
Speaker 1: Sorry.
Speaker 1: I should look up how to say your name.
Speaker 1: I will for the next episode.
Speaker 1: You'll probably never hear this anyway.
Speaker 1: I'm sorry.
Speaker 0: It's a short book, but just in fairness and because it's a book club to give you time to read it.
Speaker 0: We'll go a month instead of just doing it the next Thursday episode.
Speaker 0: So that would mean on Thursday the 29th, unless something comes up, we'll do the book club episode on this book because it's like 200 pages from what I can tell.
Speaker 1: And just so you know something about it.
Speaker 1: Hugo Award winner, best novella.
Speaker 1: Nebula and Locus Award winner, best novella.
Speaker 1: One of NPR's best books of 2019.
Speaker 1: And the summary is basically there are two secret agents, right?
Speaker 1: One of them is from the cyber world, right?
Speaker 1: Where there's like a singularity cyber brain, right?
Speaker 1: And the other one is from also sort of a world that's a singularity, but it's obviously.
Speaker 1: it's the garden, the tree world, you know, that the elf singularity with trees and plants and flowers, right?
Speaker 1: And they're against each other and they're both time-traveling rapidly and basically writing letters to one of them starts writing a letter to the other one.
Speaker 1: And then they don't stop writing letters back and forth.
Speaker 1: So I guess there's a, there's a word for it.
Speaker 1: What's it?
Speaker 1: Episto something, um, a story that's told through letters that are written.
Speaker 0: Story told through epistles.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: How you lose the time.
Speaker 1: It's a word.
Speaker 1: That's a new word.
Speaker 1: I just learned because of this book, uh, an epistolary novella.
Speaker 1: Epistolary means a story written as a series of letters.
Speaker 1: So, uh, that's, that's what you're getting to one.
Speaker 1: You're getting a bunch of letters written between these two time-traveling secret agents who are living in different societies that are fighting a war against each other.
Speaker 1: Through space and time.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So let's get into it.
Speaker 0: We kind of, because we went long, we don't have to go too long on this, but we did sort of already cover this.
Speaker 0: Like we got into this topic talking about that apple thing.
Speaker 1: So topics for a lot of Mondays these days, we look at the news.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: But it really kind of like, it's more a, how do we, and then how could, or maybe should you decide when to adopt a technology?
Speaker 0: Like where are the bright lines on?
Speaker 0: like, this is a technology I must adopt immediately at any cost versus this is a technology I not only will not adopt, but I will aggressively fight against other people adopting it.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's even further.
Speaker 1: Not just avoiding it, but preventing other people from using it.
Speaker 0: Well, like, you know, here's an example, uh, I'll give some examples of technology adoption.
Speaker 0: Cryptocurrency.
Speaker 0: I have spent my professional career since the dawn of it.
Speaker 0: I spent about two months on a committee to look at this new technology when blockchain appeared to determine if it had any value.
Speaker 0: And I determined with this working group that it had no value of any kind, that it was basically likely worthless.
Speaker 0: And now, uh, following that thread, I have continued to actively and aggressively try to prevent its adoption wherever I have the power to do so.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I see that's a technology that is actively harmful to the world at large.
Speaker 1: So for the world, it's.
Speaker 1: it's harmful to the world.
Speaker 1: Then it's also harmful to me because I live in the world and everyone I love and know and care about.
Speaker 1: So therefore, yes, try to destroy it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But then another completely different example, let's say VR technology, forget even the Apple thing, regular old VR, the kind we know about from oculus and rifts and gaming and all that, where it's progressing steadily and it almost hits these series of milestones.
Speaker 0: where every time it hits a milestone, a larger group of people decide that it is above their line and they adopt it.
Speaker 0: Scott's line is way higher than mine.
Speaker 0: My line is way higher than several other people we know.
Speaker 0: We know some people who adopted VR, like when the original rift was announced, like before there was even any hardware through Scott, where you're still waiting for.
Speaker 0: It's so tiny, you don't know you're wearing it and it's fully immersive in all possible ways.
Speaker 1: Maybe not even then.
Speaker 1: I still have to have a need for it.
Speaker 0: Well, there's a difference we need and want as well because those lines.
Speaker 1: I mean, yeah, want.
Speaker 1: But it's like.
Speaker 1: that's the no matter whether it's technology or not.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: The question I always ask myself is, am I going to use it?
Speaker 1: You know, and we talked about the bowling balls many times already.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like if I'm going to buy anything, it's am I going to use it?
Speaker 1: And I don't judge things by their price.
Speaker 1: I judge things by their price divided by their use.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: If I buy something for 10 bucks and I like I say by T-shirt for 10 bucks and I wear it once, like I actually feel kind of bad, even though it was just 10 bucks, because like that's 10 bucks to wear the shirt one time.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But if I buy a fancy T-shirt for 50 bucks, but I wear it like every week for years, it's like I don't feel bad about that at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So whenever I'm going to spend money on something, I don't look at the price as a raw number.
Speaker 1: I imagine, am I actually going to use it live?
Speaker 1: Am I going to get the value out of it, you know, compared to the price?
Speaker 1: And then that's how I judge whether it's going to happen.
Speaker 0: And that value can be different.
Speaker 0: things like, you know, forget VR.
Speaker 0: Talk about because the Nintendo Switch Breath of the Wild came out.
Speaker 0: We always used to talk about how don't buy a video game console just because of one exclusive game, because that implies that you're basically paying the price of the console plus the price of the game just to play the game.
Speaker 0: The console has to be judged for you by the collection of games you'll play on it relative to alternative ways to play that collection of games.
Speaker 0: And there are very few exclusive games in the modern world on consoles.
Speaker 0: But for Nintendo, like Tears of the Kingdom, I would say right now for me, the two Zelda games alone would have been worth the price of entry to buy a Nintendo Switch.
Speaker 0: It'd be close, but I would have bought a Nintendo Switch to play these two games, even if no other game existed for it.
Speaker 0: I think that would have happened.
Speaker 0: It would have been close on my line, but that would have been an OK line.
Speaker 0: So let's see, in terms of like cell phones, we kind of we wanted cell phones before cell phones existed like I wanted a cell phone when I was a little kid and wireless phones appeared like the wireless phones you could have in your house.
Speaker 0: But not have a cord.
Speaker 0: We wanted one.
Speaker 0: so bad, but they were so expensive.
Speaker 0: Our family couldn't afford one when they first came out.
Speaker 1: Other people had them.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And we just still didn't get one because like, you know, why it wasn't it wasn't super necessary.
Speaker 0: I mean, it would have been very useful to us, you know, with big house.
Speaker 1: I mean, yeah, it'd be nice, but it's like we just didn't get one for like.
Speaker 0: a way, you know, our sole reason was money, because that's sort of one of the big factors there of the value divided by money.
Speaker 0: But even if the value is high, let's say I would use, I don't know, a helicopter to go from here to skiing like I could just helicopter to ski.
Speaker 0: The value that would provide me personally, ignoring the externalities of the harm that causes to environment, because that's a different discussion, would be enormous.
Speaker 0: I would ski so much it would be ridiculous, but it doesn't matter how much value I get out of it, because the dollar amount it would cost to leverage that technology in my life would be so astronomical that there's no universe where I could reasonably afford that.
Speaker 0: So even even almost infinite value is destroyed if you do not have that capital to reasonably purchase and interact with said technology.
Speaker 0: Case in point, these apple glasses, they're so expensive that I can imagine if they were a thousand dollars.
Speaker 1: Thought they were going to be more expensive, but the price is still too high.
Speaker 0: Seven seven indexes worth of cost.
Speaker 0: You can buy seven valve indexes or one apple augmented reality.
Speaker 1: You could buy a MacBook and have lots of cash.
Speaker 0: It's like that old penny arcade.
Speaker 0: We're like, oh, I bought an iPod.
Speaker 0: It doesn't skip.
Speaker 0: And Tyco is like, yeah, I have a CD player and I cushion it with four hundred dollars of cash.
Speaker 1: Yep, you could buy.
Speaker 1: you could buy ten eleven Nintendo switches and have money left over.
Speaker 0: So VR is one of the few areas where Scott and I our lines are actually a little bit different because we generally kind of adopt things at about the same time.
Speaker 0: We have similar access to resources.
Speaker 0: like we tend to have similar opinions about those technology, but I adopted VR a couple of I'd say three generations before Scott will even consider adopting VR.
Speaker 1: I just I wouldn't use it.
Speaker 1: when would I use it?
Speaker 0: And I think there's a. there's a. that's a component of this that a lot of people overlook because a lot of people look at a piece of technology like these glasses and they think, what would I use it for from the context of a consumer, a gamer, et cetera.
Speaker 0: But let's say Scott and I, we're going to try to make apps like we're going to try to monetize in some fashion, then owning dev kits, owning the technology to make something even if we wouldn't use that thing all the time is suddenly a much better value proposition because it's almost like a tool of your trade.
Speaker 1: Well, that's that's not adopting a technology that's that's purchasing capital for your business.
Speaker 0: But for example, I was interested enough in VR to where I bought a relatively early VR equipment like.
Speaker 0: I bought the Oculus Rift and now I have a valve index specifically not so much because I wanted to play specific games because even now in the year twenty twenty three, there are less than ten a tier VR games like.
Speaker 0: there aren't that many series.
Speaker 1: I saw I saw a super hot VR speed run as GDQ.
Speaker 1: It took him like no time at all.
Speaker 1: And it was really fascinating because that's a game where you're like you stop to make the bad guys stop.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And you move to make the bad guys.
Speaker 0: You're good.
Speaker 0: You don't have to stop.
Speaker 1: But that's the point is that to do a speed run, you you have to.
Speaker 1: basically he's like constantly flailing his arms even when nothing's happening to make sure the game keeps going.
Speaker 1: It's like a big.
Speaker 1: it's like a workout.
Speaker 1: He's lucky.
Speaker 1: it was mercifully short.
Speaker 0: And that game is absolutely phenomenal.
Speaker 0: It is one of the best per minute of time I spent playing.
Speaker 0: It is one of the best video games I have ever played.
Speaker 1: But apparently you can do it in fifteen minutes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you're good at it.
Speaker 0: But play it play it from the beginning.
Speaker 0: Like you want to judge Breath of the Wild by the twenty three minute speed run link running naked and screaming straight at Gannon with a stick.
Speaker 0: But I guess while it is one of the best video game experiences I have ever had, if you're seeking VR to play that game and every other VR game that's at that level of quality, all of them combined are not even close to being worth the amount of dollars you would have to spend to have the VR to experience that in the first place.
Speaker 0: Yet you'd better have a lot more you want to do with VR.
Speaker 0: So I found that the line for me was one, interacting with people online in spaces like VRChat because they're so early.
Speaker 0: I almost want to personally do my own primary research about them.
Speaker 0: And two, in terms of experiences, I want to make VR experiences.
Speaker 0: So I wanted to interact with the technology as it evolved.
Speaker 0: And I'm willing to pay for that.
Speaker 0: But that is the value I'm getting out of VR.
Speaker 0: The games I play is maybe five percent of the actual value I've gotten out of VR.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, our friend Penny just entered VR a second ago, just popped up instead.
Speaker 1: But I mean, like, are you using?
Speaker 1: you paid all the money for the VR?
Speaker 1: Are you using it?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I actually am.
Speaker 0: I use it pretty regularly.
Speaker 1: How often do you use it?
Speaker 0: Until I got sick and it got warm out, like during covid, a couple of times a week.
Speaker 1: Like, all right, there you go.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: That's probably more than I used my switch.
Speaker 1: But again, it caught, you know, the valve in.
Speaker 0: But here's the problem.
Speaker 0: A couple of times a week when the weather's not nice, which is a problem, because now not only is the weather nice, but we're coming out, we're entering the long tail of covid winding down, meaning I'm doing a lot of stuff again and I'm doing stuff at the times I would normally be hanging out or playing with VR.
Speaker 0: So that's a different problem.
Speaker 0: But I've definitely gotten the value I wanted out of that index.
Speaker 0: But I'm not going to buy like an index to anytime soon.
Speaker 1: I think the the tough question is, if you ask yourself, are you going to use something?
Speaker 1: but something is, you know, new, it's a new technology.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And it's like you have to sort of you.
Speaker 1: can you know, when you watch an Apple keynote, you can imagine the scenarios they present to you.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But then you have to sort of figure out like, well, those aren't things that anyone can do in life right now.
Speaker 1: Because this technology is not available to the public right now.
Speaker 1: If I acquire that technology, will I change?
Speaker 1: Will my life change or will I intentionally change my life?
Speaker 1: So those scenarios they are presenting to me or some that I've imagined that they didn't imagine are actually now occurring in my life.
Speaker 0: And that requires a degree of self-awareness and introspection that many people cannot achieve or cannot achieve without great difficulty, because it is easy like that.
Speaker 0: The Apple thing could block ads in real life.
Speaker 0: Sign me up.
Speaker 0: But guess what?
Speaker 0: It doesn't do that yet.
Speaker 0: And it likely won't do that at any point or or something simpler.
Speaker 1: It's like they show a feature like, you know, FaceTime.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And it's like, OK, video chatting with people.
Speaker 1: It's like, all right, if I don't have an iPhone right now.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And I've never video chat, never.
Speaker 1: And I know video chat existed before FaceTime, but let's pretend that there's never been video chat before.
Speaker 1: And someone's trying to sell you a video chat machine.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And you're thinking like, will I use that?
Speaker 0: Young, naive rim would have said, fuck, yeah, video phone.
Speaker 0: It's the future.
Speaker 0: Old rim.
Speaker 0: I never want to be on video chat.
Speaker 0: Even when I'm talking to friends, I want it to be audio only because the video.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, well, will people I know also buy it?
Speaker 1: Will they video chat with me?
Speaker 1: How?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like right now, what do I do in my life right now in terms of chatting with people right now?
Speaker 1: I'm texting and phone calling.
Speaker 1: Am I going to do this?
Speaker 1: When am I going to do it?
Speaker 1: Who am I going to do it with?
Speaker 1: And you sort of have to imagine this different life, you know, a different you of the future and what your behaviors are going to be.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And it's like I've had Apple devices capable of FaceTime for a very long time.
Speaker 1: I've FaceTimed maybe a handful of times.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I'd say, you know, when I use video chat at work because we're required to.
Speaker 0: And when we do geek nights and rarely, mostly during covid, when a large event happened and we were also desperate that we all joined a big old discord call and half of us had our cameras on.
Speaker 0: And even then, the cameras were such a cacophony that they kind of weren't worthwhile.
Speaker 1: Now, maybe you look at your own life and you say, you know, I got these parents.
Speaker 1: They are family lives in another country.
Speaker 1: I emigrated somewhere.
Speaker 1: I only see them once a year.
Speaker 1: You know, we talk on the phone, but I only get to hear them.
Speaker 1: It would be nice to see them.
Speaker 1: I have, you know, I have like young relatives that are like probably grown up a whole bunch or probably wouldn't even recognize them.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But they still they sell iPhones in that country and they say iPhones in this country.
Speaker 1: And my relatives probably couldn't get Zoom or anything to work.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: This will work easily.
Speaker 1: This is worth investing in.
Speaker 1: It's going to get used.
Speaker 1: It'll actually change my.
Speaker 1: you can imagine the scenario because based on what your life circumstances are, how your life will be improved.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And so, yeah, that's actually probably worth a lot of money to you, even if you don't use it that often, even if you only video chat once a month or something like that, that probably becomes worth it to a person with that story versus a person who everyone they know lives in the same town and they hang out every night.
Speaker 1: And or they don't have any friends.
Speaker 1: They're antisocial.
Speaker 1: I live in a cave.
Speaker 0: So I guess much like the scout policy of don't buy a game on Steam unless you're going to play it immediately when it as soon as the transaction is complete.
Speaker 1: Love that great policy.
Speaker 1: It's still working.
Speaker 1: I highly recommend.
Speaker 0: I've been following it on Steam for a few years now and it has been shockingly effective at preventing me from buying games I'm not going to play.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I've saved quite a bit thanks to that policy.
Speaker 0: But I also when I have bought a game, even if I don't play it a lot, occasionally I've bought a game to play to see how it is partly to see if I should tell anyone else to use it, just like with VR.
Speaker 0: I didn't just go into VR like blindly after watching Oculus people talk about how great it is.
Speaker 0: I like went and got like demos from the company in that booth at PAX, like behind the scenes and like looked at it and tried it and read the specs and understand exactly what the limitations were and what I was getting into.
Speaker 0: So I didn't go in with unrealistic expectations.
Speaker 0: And I think a lot of people just generally in the world, but especially nerds, like you kind of alluded to earlier, they'll get excited about the possibilities of a technology or a thing, but they won't actually think about the reality of what that thing is.
Speaker 0: And they like to preorder before, like I don't preorder anything anymore except Zelda games.
Speaker 1: I preorder something.
Speaker 0: I just nothing I preorder anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: People imagine or they they're with what the ad has sold them.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Or, you know, the vision in their head does not match reality.
Speaker 1: And so they end up making purchases and then the things that they bought just end up sitting there.
Speaker 1: They were aspirational purchases.
Speaker 0: Last time I preordered a game that wasn't a Zelda game was, oh my God, it was Team Fortress.
Speaker 0: And the day it came out, I regretted that I had spent that money.
Speaker 0: And had I waited a day, I might have just not like bothered with it.
Speaker 1: I think this happens the most with exercise equipment.
Speaker 1: People buy exercise equipment and they don't actually use it.
Speaker 1: That's a very frequent occurrence, you know, for obvious reasons.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And the Geek Nights Patreon Patreon is above that $5 tier.
Speaker 0: So I say your name over and over again every episode.
Speaker 0: And I do stress, if you don't have those dollars, you can give as little as a dollar and you still get access to that RSS feed.
Speaker 0: And we are using the money on the website redesign, but we have plenty of it.
Speaker 0: So we don't need a lot more now.
Speaker 0: So what I'd say is Geek Nights is going to, for the foreseeable future, continue on its current thing.
Speaker 0: We're going to be doing more content again around panels and convention stuff.
Speaker 0: now that, you know, we're in a long tail of COVID.
Speaker 0: So expect us to get back to our sort of free 2020 levels of content creation, plus a few new things we are working on, like those are still coming along.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, don't feel like you have to give to the Patreon.
Speaker 0: I particularly expect that you'll want to do it if you want access to its feed and all that kind of stuff around there, or if you like me saying your name.
Speaker 0: But anyway, just wanted to get that out there.
Speaker 0: Patreon patrons for this episode of Geek Nights are Linky G Dread, Lily Tenebrae, Case Care, Makes Music, Chris Haddad, Clinton Walton, Dex, Finn, Joel Hayes, Penny Reimer, Rebecca Dunn, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Harl, and all the people who are giving like a dollar.
Speaker 0: I leave you tonight.
Speaker 0: Now that, you know, despite the fact that we said we were going to reimagine Wednesdays, we have a lot of Wednesday episodes queued up.
Speaker 0: We're talking about Spider-Man, Into the Spider-Verse 2 next time.
Speaker 0: So, that has nothing to do with what I leave you with, which is simply...