Speaker 1: It's Thursday, February 9th, 2023.
Speaker 1: I'm Rym.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is the Geek Nights Book Club!
Speaker 1: Tonight we are talking about Scott's most recent choice, Alif the Unseen.
Speaker 0: It was your choice.
Speaker 0: I gave you two options.
Speaker 1: Ah, it was your choice, and then I had the meta choice.
Speaker 1: It was you cut, and I chose.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So Alif the Unseen by G. Willow Wilson.
Speaker 0: It's my cut and your choice.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so why'd you pick it again?
Speaker 1: Because I remember we had a good conversation when we launched this one about like why we're picking this author in particular with Ms.
Speaker 1: Marvel.
Speaker 0: Right, so what happened, yeah, so what happened was I was like well I got to pick some book club books, right, and I got to pick two, and I will cut two, and Rym will choose one of the two.
Speaker 0: So I go to my Amazon wish list, which even if I don't buy the books on Amazon, I just use Amazon wish list.
Speaker 0: And whenever I see a book on the internet and I say I want to read that book, I don't buy it because that's a mistake.
Speaker 0: I'll add it to my wish list, and then if there comes a time where I'm actually going to read it immediately, then I'll buy it and start reading it right away.
Speaker 0: So I went to the wish list and said are there any books in here that are going to be good for the book club?
Speaker 0: And by complete coincidence, I noticed two of the books on.
Speaker 0: there were from the same author, an author I had never heard of.
Speaker 0: And I was like what are the odds that some author I've never heard of gets two books, two different books.
Speaker 0: In fact, I think they're only two books, at least they're only two like novels, onto my wish list separately.
Speaker 1: Right, that are not in a series.
Speaker 1: Like the Wheel of Time wouldn't have counted, like Prince of Nothing books don't count.
Speaker 0: I added them months or years apart, so it wasn't like I. at one point in time I like recognized the author and added all their books.
Speaker 0: It was like one book came up at some point and into my, you know, notice and was added to the wish list, and then sometime later the other book.
Speaker 0: So I'm like well that's a sign.
Speaker 0: So I look up information about the author G. Willow Wilson and I find out that they are a famous comic book writer, even though I haven't personally read many.
Speaker 0: any of their comic, you know, book works.
Speaker 0: They've, you know, they've done a lot of famous stuff.
Speaker 0: Like, you know, the newer Ms.
Speaker 0: Marvel, they basically invented that character, which is a big deal, right?
Speaker 0: It got really popular, even though I never read any of it.
Speaker 0: They've won, you know, they got some Eisner action going on, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, it's a big deal.
Speaker 0: comic book person and writer for many years and they had two novels and I'm like.
Speaker 0: well this seems like a significant person in the the nerd literature world, right?
Speaker 0: Fantasy sci-fi superhero biz.
Speaker 0: Let's check this out.
Speaker 0: and I was like and conveniently they've written two books for me to offer Rim to choose from, right?
Speaker 0: Oh well, you know, it's like it just lands in the lap.
Speaker 0: Such an easy go.
Speaker 0: So Rim chose the older of the two novels Leaf the Unseen, which is basically a middle eastern sort of, you know, magical realism, cyberpunk kind of deal, right?
Speaker 0: Which is like a great new combination.
Speaker 0: You can't find any fault in that combination whatsoever.
Speaker 0: That's a recipe, you know, the recipe was for greatness, right?
Speaker 0: But we hadn't yet tasted the the dish, right?
Speaker 0: We saw the ingredients and we said well that's going to be amazing, right?
Speaker 0: Just based on the ingredients alone and the name of the chef and other things the chef had done.
Speaker 0: We're like well that's going to be great and we ate the meal at this point finally.
Speaker 1: It was a pretty, it was a solid meal.
Speaker 1: I've enjoyed it, like I enjoyed it.
Speaker 1: I got a lot to say about it.
Speaker 0: And also this person is basically the exact same age as us, so we have a shared, you know, uh, you know.
Speaker 1: Their Wikipedia is great too because it's not long, but I'm gonna read a short quote from it.
Speaker 1: Wilson first encountered comics when she read an anti-smoking pamphlet featuring the x-men in fifth grade.
Speaker 1: I feel like I read that same pamphlet.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I read that one, but I've definitely seen.
Speaker 1: The characters fascinated her and she began watching the cartoon x-men every Saturday.
Speaker 1: The one we watched.
Speaker 0: I can say that the first time I ever saw the x-men was actually a coloring book.
Speaker 0: that wasn't even my, it was someone else's coloring book that they had already colored in that that they gave to me.
Speaker 0: They only, right?
Speaker 0: And it was like x-men.
Speaker 0: and I'm like who the, what the hell is x-men?
Speaker 0: I was like I don't know.
Speaker 1: I was aware of the x-men because my uncle and my mom were like into comics, but like as a kid I didn't really read them or think about them, but then when I was young we got an x-men board game.
Speaker 1: The one that came with all those miniatures and it came with a random issue of the x-men, but it was like a floppy that was between two story arcs and didn't make any sense because it had no context and nothing happened.
Speaker 1: It was just like Beast talking to somewhat to like Cyclops in an abandoned building the whole time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but basically the x-men in that comic book were like the the the x-factor style with like.
Speaker 0: it was that era, right?
Speaker 0: So it was kind of old and I was like it wasn't very appealing.
Speaker 0: But then, you know, once, you know, when I got into x-men was when everyone else got into x-men, right?
Speaker 0: When there was Jim Lee, Adjectiveless X-Men number one, the arcade game and the cartoon, right?
Speaker 1: That cartoon, that got me, that made me an x-men fan.
Speaker 1: That was very successful despite the fact that that cartoon, not that good.
Speaker 0: That cartoon is great.
Speaker 0: All right, let's talk about Alif the Unseen.
Speaker 1: All right, so it's the GeekNuts Book Club.
Speaker 1: So if you've never listened to the GeekNuts Book Club before, just to remind you or to share with you, one, it's a book club, meaning we all read the book.
Speaker 1: We're assuming you read the book.
Speaker 1: So if you did not read this book, you're going to have no fucking idea what we're talking about because we're not going to explain everything that happened in the book.
Speaker 0: We're going to talk about it assuming just to fully summarize the broad, the broad stroke.
Speaker 1: And two, obviously we're going to spoil stuff because we read the book and the whole point is talk about the book.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And if you, if you read the book, come to the places that we exist on the internet, which is our forum and our discord server and, you know, discuss, discuss the book with other people who also read the book.
Speaker 0: Hopefully we're the only ones reading it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Talk about the book with us.
Speaker 1: Cause there, there's some, it was a pretty good book overall.
Speaker 1: It wasn't the best written thing I've ever read.
Speaker 1: Uh, it's a little awkward in a few times.
Speaker 1: I'd say about a third of the computer scenes are plausible and two thirds of them are implausible.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I'm not, I'm not concerned about the plausible, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, I always complain when other nerds, I mean, I understand that feeling cause I've had it at times, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, they made us watch, I always say they made us watch the net in high school, like, Oh my God.
Speaker 0: Um, but it's like, you know, if you're going to sit there and complain, they're like, Oh, the computer part wasn't real.
Speaker 0: And therefore that ruined the whole thing for me.
Speaker 0: And it's like, I guess you're only gonna ever watch the hardest of sci-fis and don't watch any star wars.
Speaker 1: You're only going to watch things that you don't know shit about.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, if you w you can watch some movie about, uh, cooking and you don't know shit about cooking and then it's like, there'll be everything's wrong in it, but it doesn't bother you because you don't know anything about it.
Speaker 0: So it's like, so if I see bad computer stuff, it's like, I don't get hung up on it.
Speaker 0: I'm like, well, what I guess I would say is if I'm going to be hung up on that, how am I going to feel about the genies?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like, come on.
Speaker 1: But I said implausible and not bad because they fit into the implausible parts didn't get in the way at all because the story worked perfectly with the way they were portrayed.
Speaker 1: And obviously they were highly abstracted in the same way that like wizard magic is highly abstracted in most non prince of nothing books.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's even, it's even somewhat abstracted in those, but yeah, but it talks a lot more about that anyway.
Speaker 0: So, all right, so let us do that.
Speaker 0: The brief, very broad brush summary of what goes on in this book, right?
Speaker 0: Is this guy named Alif, right?
Speaker 1: Who I thought was a lot younger than I realized he was later in the book.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess he's, I always, he's like a college type person, I thought he was like 17, 18, but no, he was like 21, 22.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: He's not, he's not in college though.
Speaker 0: Uh, he's living with his, you know, family.
Speaker 0: Uh, I guess it's not his dad.
Speaker 0: His dad is some like deadbeat dad who's far away kinda.
Speaker 0: But anyway, he's living in sort of, uh, it doesn't actually like name a country.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's specifically left vague and unnamed on purpose, but other real countries are named like.
Speaker 1: Egypt is clearly nearby.
Speaker 1: Like the rest of the real world exists, but they do not tell you where this is specifically on purpose, probably to avoid difficulty in drama.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, a lot of it is based on like, you know, Arab spring, right?
Speaker 0: That happened was a great inspiration for this book.
Speaker 1: I mean, the book was published in 2012.
Speaker 0: That was a lot of that was in Egypt.
Speaker 0: It was like the center was in Egypt.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And, um, you know, but basically it's in a city in the middle of a desert, you know, I guess near some water, I think.
Speaker 0: But the, the city has like different districts sort of representing and, you know, all the different sort of aspects of, you know, you've got in one district, you've got like these really wealthy, you know, uh, people that sort of reminds you of like, you know, royalty from Saudi Arabia.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Big Saudi or UAE vibes in terms of how it was portrayed and like what kinds of places were shown.
Speaker 0: And then you've got, you know, another district that feels more like, you know, uh, you know, where the not so wealthy people live sort of like if you watch, you know, Disney's Aladdin, like, you know, the market area at the start, you know, and then you got sort of like a outskirts places, right.
Speaker 0: You know, um, there's like a prison off to the north area.
Speaker 0: It is a map in the book because it's a fantasy book and all good fantasy books have a map.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: But then you got a leaf who is living a lot of teenage nerd internet people's dream of.
Speaker 1: he's actually a pretty good like hacker type person.
Speaker 1: And then he's basically running null soft waste for anyone who has a beef with the government anywhere in the middle East.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So a leaf doesn't seem to have a strong, like he doesn't take sides in like the, the big cultural, you know, battles that are happening.
Speaker 0: His side is simply only like anti-authoritarian only.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So it's like, he's, you know, uh, providing service and his clients, like if his clients knew who each other were, like they might even hate each other.
Speaker 0: He's serving all the, doesn't skirt around.
Speaker 1: Like at the end, it kind of comes back together and reminds everyone like, yeah, a lot of the people leaf with helping are not great people.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Um, but you know, a leaf is what he's doing is basically helping people avoid like the big brother eye of the government on the internet kind of right.
Speaker 0: He's like providing the, you know, it's concealed internet services that the, you know, very much, uh, you know, surveillance society is, you know, normal people are being surveilled in an almost China like way in this society.
Speaker 1: You have to imagine that there's also some religious police and he's running a deniably encrypted like file transfer chat and voice network.
Speaker 1: Basically like people can communicate, coordinate think telegram plus null soft waste plus a couple other things kind of rolled in together.
Speaker 0: And he's also sort of, you know, he's, he's constantly protecting it from, you know, the event, the attacks from the outside.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like, it's not just like a, it's like, it's not a. set it and forget it deal.
Speaker 0: He's got to, you know, maintain this thing all the time.
Speaker 0: Um, and so he's doing that and he gets into, he's got this girlfriend also.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: And he gets into post college drama about their relationship.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, he's, he's a young individual, right.
Speaker 0: He's got, uh, he wants to get his, his business on.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: He fell in love with this girl.
Speaker 0: Um,
Speaker 1: it was mutual, at least for like, they were doing,
Speaker 0: it seems like a mutual situation, but she's like, look, you know, this is a mutual situation, but, uh, you know, I got to choose, you know, he's basically in a situation where he's in the lower part of society.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: He's a lower, you know, economic, uh, rung.
Speaker 0: So he doesn't have much to lose.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So he's like all in on the love action.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Just run away with me.
Speaker 1: And she's like, uh, my family's rich and my dad arranged a marriage.
Speaker 1: And are you serious?
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: She's like, she's like, you know, while I do, she's like, she likes him, but it's like, Hey, uh, I can't choose this over what I've got right now.
Speaker 1: Like any, and this is after about this book, like
Speaker 0: any
Speaker 1: like male gendered crypto online nerd, who's like the kind of character relief is his first solution is not to have a conversation or to do any normal adult reasonable thing, but to write an AI bot to hide her from him on the internet forever, because he's being a little baby about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: He's she's like, listen, all right, this is it.
Speaker 0: Don't contact me again.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Don't contact me.
Speaker 1: Well, I will contact you.
Speaker 1: I'm going to literally write a bot to erase you from the internet.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Well, it doesn't erase her from the internet.
Speaker 1: It's almost like an ad blocker that blocks him from ever seeing her again and prevents her from ever communicating with him again.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And it's not a simple one either.
Speaker 0: It's like that sort of.
Speaker 0: the plot is that he doesn't just block, like, you know, he doesn't do the simple thing of like, okay, this is her email address.
Speaker 0: I'm going to block that email address.
Speaker 0: This is her IP address.
Speaker 0: I'm going to block that.
Speaker 0: He makes like an intelligent, almost like a machine learning thing, like the chat GPT.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: That can read that looks at the text of incoming content.
Speaker 0: To his computer systems and tries to determine who wrote that content.
Speaker 0: So if she were to like get a new email address or a new text number or any kind of other communication service, let's say a new, a new communication service appears, right?
Speaker 0: A new, a new social network.
Speaker 0: And she makes an account and types messages.
Speaker 0: The AI can sort of detect that.
Speaker 0: that's her writing style.
Speaker 0: She wrote that and pre block so that there's absolutely no way that she will ever be able to digitally communicate with him and his computer systems.
Speaker 0: Period.
Speaker 0: End of story.
Speaker 1: I want to head off some nerds because right away, this is not one of the implausible things.
Speaker 1: It's not completely.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, this is real technology.
Speaker 1: It is doable.
Speaker 1: I've seen proofs of concept and demos of this kind of tech.
Speaker 1: A machine learning algorithms can indeed do this kind of thing.
Speaker 0: It's, it, it, it's not going to be, it's, I mean, in the book they portray it as being like a hundred percent, almost a hundred percent perfect, right?
Speaker 0: In the real world, it would be like some much lower percent perfect, but it would still be very impressive.
Speaker 1: It also wouldn't really work on like very small communications, right?
Speaker 0: But if we took, for example, every geek nights episode, it would, we could make something that separates the rim from the Scott.
Speaker 0: We could take all of rims, public postings and whatever other content rim has ever made, you know, and put it on, you know, that we could access and throw it all in there and make a thing that is very, a computer program that is very, very good at identifying whether something new, a new piece of text or a new audio is rim or not rim.
Speaker 1: It's basically like at work recently, I, you know, write evals and like review other people and write things that the person who's the recipient of it is going to get a summary, but they don't actually let them see the actual text.
Speaker 1: And I got a note back from HR that literally said like, yeah, we are really rewrote yours.
Speaker 1: Uh, you have a distinctive writing style.
Speaker 0: Uh, but I mean, you could do it for even people without it, right?
Speaker 0: Cause you're, I'm easy to detect on the internet, the kind of machine learning technology we have now that looks at a picture and is like, are there cats or no cats?
Speaker 0: Where are the cats?
Speaker 0: There's the cat.
Speaker 0: That's a tree.
Speaker 1: Now this is just shitty, but it's not over an ethical line yet, but then how does he train this machine learning model?
Speaker 1: He uses the same network that he built to protect all these dissidents and basically runs a botnet and non-consensual key loggers to gather the data necessary to train the model.
Speaker 1: And that of course, that's why the title is funny because Alif the Unseen is seen by the government and the main antagonist basically instantly in this book.
Speaker 1: Like he writes this thing and like the next day shit has hit the fan.
Speaker 1: And I appreciated that it moved fast.
Speaker 0: So the plot is that this AI becomes like too good.
Speaker 0: It's like, it's not just blocking this girl.
Speaker 0: It's like, it's, it's going out of control.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: And then the government, all his, all his contacts like, yo, what the fuck did you put on the botnet?
Speaker 1: It's using my CPU.
Speaker 1: And then the government's like, whoa, look at that.
Speaker 1: We've been trying to write something like that.
Speaker 1: Let's figure out who wrote that.
Speaker 0: Yep, exactly.
Speaker 0: So he's like, Oh shit.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: And he's, he's, so now he's on the run, right?
Speaker 0: Because what's, what's the name of the bad guy?
Speaker 1: Oh, well the hand, the hand.
Speaker 0: so that the hand is basically sort of this mysterious government individual.
Speaker 0: And you imagine that they're basically like, they're not the, the, the King or the Sultan or whatever the person.
Speaker 0: they're like the Jafar, they're the year.
Speaker 0: They're the, they're basically like, yeah, they're like this, the evil CTO of the government.
Speaker 0: Who's running the, the internet systems?
Speaker 1: because, yeah, but, uh, the IT department in wool, like the guy who ran that Bernard, I think was his name anyway.
Speaker 0: But yeah, so the hand, anyway, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't, but yeah, the hand is basically upon him, right?
Speaker 0: So he's like, Oh shit, I got to run and save my ass and also protect my clients.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, he shuts the thing down to protect the clients.
Speaker 0: He goes to his friend.
Speaker 1: He also cauterizes the wound and a whole bunch of them just get compromised straight up and they're just fucked.
Speaker 1: And there's, and to his credit, there's nothing like.
Speaker 1: he's really broken up about having to basically leave a whole bunch of people.
Speaker 1: He's helped to die, uh, literally die in many cases, but at the same time, there is literally nothing he could do.
Speaker 0: Cause I think a big theme is he could have not been a baby in the first place, but he could have too late.
Speaker 1: He could have not written tin.
Speaker 1: Sorry.
Speaker 1: And deployed it in the first place.
Speaker 1: That was his fucking.
Speaker 0: sorry is the name of the computer program.
Speaker 1: But at the same time of a really big theme in this book that I think is understated, but very important to it is the idea that people who are very online one, they will see very online solutions as the default solutions to problems.
Speaker 1: Like that's the hammer they use for any nail they see, even if it's a screw or a person, but also how internet power is real.
Speaker 1: Like the book doesn't say the internet doesn't do anything.
Speaker 1: That's, that is like the opposite of the limits.
Speaker 1: And a guy with a crowbar has a lot of power that an internet person cannot wield.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So once this happens, the game, the, the book sort of breaks out of the, the internet part, right?
Speaker 0: And now you have this real world situation where it's like, there's government agents coming to get him and he's just some kid.
Speaker 1: But what's fat, what I really like is he is at this point, he is portrayed despite his fuck up with tin.
Speaker 1: Sorry.
Speaker 1: He is a super skilled computer person.
Speaker 1: Like he's a good hacker.
Speaker 1: He's very good.
Speaker 1: He's got extreme OPSEC in his actual internet life.
Speaker 1: But as soon as he is walking around, looking around kid, doesn't know shit like uses a cell phone, like all the, he does all these fuck ups along the way and basically like makes it so easy for the police to find him.
Speaker 1: It's kind of funny, like how unworldly and naive he is once he's not online.
Speaker 0: So he gets, he's basically now just literally on the run, like running and hiding from, you know, people on the street trying to find him.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And he wrote, he gets assistance from local computer guy, which is, you know, clearly we're going to be one of those like awesome side characters.
Speaker 0: I imagine him a lot like, um, ghost in the shell.
Speaker 0: What's the, that's the guy's name.
Speaker 0: Uh, not narrow guy beard guy goes in the show.
Speaker 0: Who sits in the computer room all the time.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: I forget.
Speaker 1: I forget all their names.
Speaker 1: I haven't watched ghost in the shell in like a decade.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the one who's also addicted to pachinko, right?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I remember that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Uh, and also his neighbor, right?
Speaker 0: So his neighbor is the big deal, right?
Speaker 1: So his neighbor is like just this, you know, observant, you know, Muslim girls specifically, she converted against the wishes of her family to an extreme Wahhabist form of Islam.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: She wasn't that observant.
Speaker 0: And then she's like, no, what?
Speaker 0: I actually believe in this whole bunch.
Speaker 0: I'm going to observe more, you know, which is something I've seen in my life with a lot of Jews where they grew up in a house.
Speaker 0: And the house was this level of observant of Judaism.
Speaker 0: And some of the children in the house became less observant and some children in the house became more observant.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's a thing.
Speaker 0: It's a thing that happens.
Speaker 0: So yeah, that's, that's what happens to this neighbor.
Speaker 1: Obviously, like reading this book for the first time within two sentences of Dina being introduced, it is a hundred percent clear she's been the eponine to this other relationship the whole time.
Speaker 1: Like it is so obvious that she always had a thing.
Speaker 0: We've seen a lot of animes where, you know, the neighbor, the neighbor best friend your whole life wins out in the, in the dating sim.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: It's critically like, why are you reading?
Speaker 1: Why do you want to read all my fantasy books?
Speaker 1: Like, it's not like you can, like, you're still mad about it because of Islam or whatever.
Speaker 1: And he like does not get it that she just wants to hang out with him at any point.
Speaker 1: No, he doesn't figure it out until near the end of the book.
Speaker 0: That's, you know, he figures it out though to the credit of the author.
Speaker 1: I would say he kind of figures it out because multiple genies tell him like kind of directly.
Speaker 0: It is sort of a cliche though, right?
Speaker 0: Like, you know, the, the, the, the quote hot girl, right?
Speaker 0: And then the neighbor girl is the real one.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I mean, look at a fucking macross, right?
Speaker 0: You got, it's like the, the min may, but no, it was actually the Mesa the whole time.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: You've seen that play out a whole bunch.
Speaker 1: So anyway, but I like how he's playing.
Speaker 1: Eventually they, one of his computer friends is like, Oh, I know a guy who got beaten up real badly.
Speaker 1: You should go find out who beat him up and hire that guy.
Speaker 1: So anyway, he's like, yeah, that's a great idea.
Speaker 1: Let's go.
Speaker 0: He's on the run.
Speaker 0: And because he's desperate, he seeks help from Vikram, the vampire, who you imagine is just like some super dangerous underworld guy.
Speaker 1: My favorite character in the book instantly.
Speaker 1: The fact that their first meeting is Vikram basically just like punches him out.
Speaker 1: And then when he wakes up, all Vikram says like, Whoa, man.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Sorry.
Speaker 1: I, uh, didn't think you'd be that fragile buddy.
Speaker 1: Like the fuck are you even doing talking to me?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's like why?
Speaker 0: But anyway, Vikram is, literally, uh, a magical genie type being.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Uh, and now this is where you get into sort of the magical, right?
Speaker 0: But up until this point, the whole book was like, you know, cyber punk only, right?
Speaker 0: It's mostly realism.
Speaker 0: And then suddenly it's like the magic part starts to creep in.
Speaker 1: We've got a leaf living in a world that is unseen to most people, the internet, like he lives in the internet effectively.
Speaker 1: So he's living in this unseen world and then he is driven out of this unseen world into the real world where there's men with crowbars because he's in trouble.
Speaker 1: Uh, the scene world, which he doesn't understand that.
Speaker 1: Well, it's only a big parts of it are unseen to him effectively.
Speaker 1: Like he doesn't really think about it.
Speaker 1: And then he ends up in yet another unseen world.
Speaker 1: The world of the gin is definitely a parallel to the world of the internet in this book.
Speaker 1: Like that allegory is strong and pervasive and I think it's well executed.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like, how did the gin exist in this world?
Speaker 0: That's so modern.
Speaker 0: Well, it's like, well, there's a whole bunch of them.
Speaker 0: They're mostly, you know, on the edge of town, people who don't believe in them, look at them and just see normal people or see nothing or don't, you know, right.
Speaker 1: One of them is like, Oh yeah, a whole bunch of us are in Detroit.
Speaker 1: Like that's a pretty happening place for gin.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And it's like, but to actually get to like, you know, there's, there's places the gin live.
Speaker 0: Like there's a market and there's a city where they're at and you can't like get there.
Speaker 0: unless like, you know, you can see and understand and go the right way.
Speaker 0: That's like, you know, perpendicular to the modern world.
Speaker 1: Someone who's very online, like say me or Scott, there are parts of the internet and like places online that we just know how to get to.
Speaker 1: that a lot of people don't even know exist.
Speaker 1: And even if you told them they exist, good luck finding them.
Speaker 1: Explain to grandma, like great grandma, what a discord is, let alone get her to the point where she logs into one and a discourse, not even that hit, right.
Speaker 0: There's an IRCs and stuff.
Speaker 1: It's like, yeah, so Vikram explaining shit to the humans, uh, is very similar to Scott explaining shit to the non online people.
Speaker 1: we know.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But yeah, he's, you know, he's basically because he's got no other choice, right.
Speaker 1: And because they're willing to help him, uh, so generously, um, you get the impression Vikram and his sister are not necessarily good people, but they're not necessarily cruel people.
Speaker 1: They're just, they've lived so long.
Speaker 1: They've been on every side of everything and kind of done whatever for a long time.
Speaker 1: Like they are just inhuman, dangerous, but also interesting and kind of cool.
Speaker 1: Like I love how he hangs out with the convert and he's just always weird around her all the time.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So now why, why are these gin helping this, this guy, right?
Speaker 0: This, you know, they don't have to help them for any reason.
Speaker 0: They don't first.
Speaker 1: They're just like, kid, get the fuck out of here.
Speaker 1: You're in way over your head.
Speaker 1: But then they're like, oh wait, what, what's that book you got there?
Speaker 0: That's exactly the, the reason they help them is because of the, the McGuffin of the stit, the tail, the Alfio.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So basically, you know, humans have the book thousand and one night or, you know, nights, right.
Speaker 0: Famous book.
Speaker 0: I'm sure you know all about it.
Speaker 0: I hope you do anyway.
Speaker 1: Hey, what if that's the booklet book I'm taking?
Speaker 0: That's all right.
Speaker 0: But anyway, so, but you know, the Alfio is, I don't know if that's a thing.
Speaker 0: Does that a thing that exists or is just a tail or was it made up for this book specifically?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't know either.
Speaker 1: I'm going to look it up, but that brings to a side point that I just want to mention so we don't forget it.
Speaker 1: What I enjoyed about one thing I enjoyed about this book specifically was that a lot of the literature I read being a person living in America who's white, either like it comes from cultural traditions that I'm familiar with.
Speaker 1: And this is a Greek mythologies, Greek mythology, like European history, like that kind of.
Speaker 1: And the fact that people shit is a cyberpunk, magical realism, all of the stuff.
Speaker 1: But instead of like a reference to something that's described as an angel, it's all based in Middle Eastern related mythology and history and culture and religion.
Speaker 1: And it was refreshing just to see a book like this, like that, and from that perspective and having all the sort of references and ideas come from a very different frame from what I typically read.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, if you Google Alfio, it only comes up in relation to this book.
Speaker 1: It's not a thing.
Speaker 0: So at the very beginning of this book, so like the preamble, it is a scene of like this old scribe of some kind who has like, you know, captured some sort of jinn demon and forced him to talk, forced it to talk.
Speaker 1: And I love that jinn is like, you really want this story?
Speaker 1: Good fucking luck.
Speaker 1: I'll tell you.
Speaker 1: But it's going to be bad news, buddy.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And tell him the the jinn's tales and he transcribes them into a book.
Speaker 0: And that book is the Alfio.
Speaker 0: And Alif gets his hands on this book because the wealthy girlfriend, who is never going to see again, sends it to him.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And she trusted him and she was like, yeah, you're better off.
Speaker 1: Hey, whatever's going on with this book, you are the only person who's going to be able to get it out of here.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So he's got this book and the book is super.
Speaker 0: Why is the book super special?
Speaker 0: It's just a bunch of stories, right?
Speaker 1: Well, because this basically the book, I think, does not the greatest job of explaining this because they clearly a magical tome where literally, depending on who you are and what your frame of mind is, when you read it, like the text will be different potentially.
Speaker 1: And it is just allegory.
Speaker 1: And the implication I get, I read it as up to a point, the smarter or more worldly or more able to read or see the unseen you are, the deeper the allegory goes, like you'll get more out of the book.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, your own personal biases and your view of the world will almost poison what the book tells you.
Speaker 1: Like the book will tell you things from your own perspective, which leads me back to Tin Sari was a machine learning algorithm.
Speaker 1: I read the Altheom as being a jinn machine learning algorithm that will basically read the world and the human.
Speaker 1: And biases you bring it.
Speaker 1: the same way machine learning algorithms bring you the biases you handed them.
Speaker 0: I mean, even normal books present the biases you bring them.
Speaker 0: But so the idea, the reason the book is valuable that a leaf doesn't realize, but the hand does.
Speaker 0: And then a leaf eventually realizes is that the they're thinking that if you could understand this book, it could inspire you to understand a new way to program a computer, right?
Speaker 0: Metaphorically, right?
Speaker 0: If you could write a computer program, you know, the way that this book was written, then you could write a very powerful magical computer program.
Speaker 1: It's even hinted that it is a mystical form of machine learning or algorithmic like code in that you get the parable of the, you know, the acronym God, God over jinn and how that expands infinitely.
Speaker 1: And there's there's a lot of.
Speaker 1: some of the metaphors are a little clumsy, but they're all there and they all point to that same direction.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So in the interest of, you know, that's what get basically gets Vikram and everyone to help him out.
Speaker 0: is this book, right?
Speaker 0: It's like they need to, you know, understand what the book is.
Speaker 0: So they visit this translator woman.
Speaker 1: I love how later you find out, I don't even see her again.
Speaker 1: You just find out every, even the jinn are all like, oh yeah, she's way too powerful to fuck with.
Speaker 0: Oh, the translator.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, she comes up with later, like she's like, if they mention her and what, like what type of jinn she is toward the end.
Speaker 0: No, she's not a, she's not a jinn.
Speaker 0: She's just a person.
Speaker 1: Oh no, you're, you're talking about the convert.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The con.
Speaker 1: Oh, I was talking about the person who did some translation, who owns the shop that they went to first when they went into the immovable.
Speaker 0: Oh no, no, not that person.
Speaker 1: I forget any of their names.
Speaker 0: Unfortunately, the convert person, you get the feeling is sort of like a, an author stand in, in some ways, right?
Speaker 0: Because the author being a convert as well.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Cause she's definitely early on portrayed as like the white person who is converted, but doesn't fully get it.
Speaker 1: And like is, is too fervent in some ways and not fervent enough in other ways.
Speaker 1: And definitely has like very Western and very American and British influences, but also how she comes around and learns and grows as a character to the point that she has Vikram's baby and like becomes a bigger part of the world.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But the convert is basically like a, you know, a book, you know, archeology type expert person who's at the university and they get help from, from them.
Speaker 1: And then they get help from genies and it's a whole adventure kind of deal where they go to the university and Vikram just around and sneaks in on his own is being cagey.
Speaker 1: The whole time is one of my favorite scenes.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So, you know, a whole bunch of adventure biz happens and then, uh, I'll leave gets caught.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I'm you know, I think they get caught because they're at what ends up happening is like the, the, the climb, the climax of the adventure part at least is they're at like the big, uh, temple, right.
Speaker 0: Or mosque in the, in the city and the, you know, the guy who runs it, you know, the, the head religious guy is there and he's pretty pragmatic and chill.
Speaker 1: That guy's a fun character.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: He's also, but he's also old and like doesn't understand, you know, the computer biz, but like, you know, he's still, you know, understands like who's a good guy.
Speaker 1: He's very like, look, uh, clearly you are running away from what I assume are the police, but, uh, I'm just going to use the fact that you dirty the carpet in the mosque as an excuse to hide you here long enough to maybe help you out.
Speaker 1: Uh, or in the very least give you a respite.
Speaker 1: Like he's, you get the sense he has lived through multiple revolutions and societal upheavals over his long life.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, see the same thing happen.
Speaker 0: You know, I think happens a lot in, um, in older like gangster movies where like they go to the Catholic church, the Catholic priest and the Catholic priest will, you know, protect you.
Speaker 0: Cause it's like these is confessing.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But then, you know, the Catholic priest might tell someone to turn themselves in, but they won't turn someone in.
Speaker 1: So just like that scene where you've got the criminal in the church and the cops are like outside waiting for them to come out, you get the exact same situation here with the mosque.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But yeah, when he's in the church, a leaf sort of, you know, figures that out.
Speaker 0: He figures it out.
Speaker 0: He's got an old, the pre-sold shitty laptop or whatever.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: He's, he's got the book.
Speaker 0: He figures it out, but then he gets caught.
Speaker 0: Uh, and then he's got the prison action and the book.
Speaker 0: See, this is what the things I didn't like about the book, at least, you know, I guess it was positive in some ways and negative in some ways is that the, the amount of time spent on different things happening.
Speaker 0: It's like, sometimes the book felt like it was in fast forward and sometimes it felt like it was in slow motion.
Speaker 0: Now that it's a good thing.
Speaker 0: You're supposed to, you know, be changing the, the speed.
Speaker 1: You don't want to, I like to ma, but it is.
Speaker 1: every Duma book goes at the exact same pace of new information at events, no matter what.
Speaker 1: And I've never encountered an exception.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You know, that's not good, right?
Speaker 0: That's boring and tedious, but you also don't want is like, you know, this, these sort of wild swings that are, are sometimes appropriate and sometimes not appropriate.
Speaker 0: And I think the biggest wild swing was when he was in prison, the book slows down to like a crawl.
Speaker 1: Now I think I see now that's good because I feel like that, that was a good move there.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like to make you feel right.
Speaker 0: That like, you know, the part before it was, it was, should have been faster.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It was like a more adventure-y running away kind of situation.
Speaker 0: Move things along.
Speaker 0: You're in prison.
Speaker 0: You got to make, it wasn't in prison actually that long, but you had to make it actually was, but you had to make it feel like it's long to the reader.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: But I think what she did a
Speaker 0: very good job
Speaker 1: of that disorient the reader a little bit, just like a leaf is disoriented in the solitary confinement torture chamber, basically trying to get you to like, not be sure yourself and sort of have a like the, when he escapes, it's almost like the light coming back on and you as the reader are just as disoriented as he is.
Speaker 1: And that just wasn't, it could have been executed a little better.
Speaker 1: I agree because right after they get out of prison, it accelerates so fast and like half the things that happened, I would really have liked to have read a couple more sentences about that.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And so it's like when it was a good choice to go slow there, it's like at the different parts of the book, they were making mostly like the right choice of like, this should be fast.
Speaker 0: This should be slow.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And it's like, yes, correct.
Speaker 0: Those are the right choices, but the, the speed they set it to was wrong when they were going fast.
Speaker 0: Sometimes it was too fast when they were going slow.
Speaker 0: Sometimes it was too slow.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So it's like, yup.
Speaker 0: The prison being slow was good.
Speaker 0: The, the D actiony parts being fast was good, but too fast.
Speaker 0: It's like, chill out.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: We need, we need a few, especially the end of the book was, was way too fast.
Speaker 0: It's like the clot near the very end.
Speaker 0: Couldn't, I felt like it could, it could, didn't hit hard enough because it was going, it was breezing right past.
Speaker 1: It was going so fast that where in previous scenes I could picture in my head what was happening when the riot happens from that point on, I could not really piece together specifics of what happened.
Speaker 0: And I was, it was all, it might as well have written like, Oh, by the way, there's a riot going on.
Speaker 0: Like the whole city's in a riot.
Speaker 0: One sentence.
Speaker 1: You know what it, you know what it felt like?
Speaker 1: It felt like trying to read the Trigon manga.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You could
Speaker 1: have just been as simple as like
Speaker 0: one or two paragraphs to be like, you know, really paint the picture of what the, you know, the city in riot, you know, looking like, you know, they did it a little bit, but
Speaker 1: you know, what's interesting is because the book was
Speaker 0: more,
Speaker 1: so the novel was published just as the Arab spring failed, like it was finally done.
Speaker 1: It had been crushed.
Speaker 1: So at the very beginning, Alif is, you know, working for all dissidents.
Speaker 1: And at the end when the riot happens and like, no, it's right.
Speaker 1: It's not a hundred percent good.
Speaker 1: There's, it's not a, it's not a simple situation taking down the shot.
Speaker 1: Doesn't necessarily mean you have a progressive democracy the next day.
Speaker 1: And on one hand, you sort of see Alif being confronted with the fact that, Hey, you got what you wanted.
Speaker 1: All of this, this is exactly what you built.
Speaker 1: This is exactly what everything you have been doing online was leading to.
Speaker 1: We're not saying it's good.
Speaker 1: We're not saying it's bad, but that's it.
Speaker 1: You did it.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Is this really what you wanted?
Speaker 1: But two at that point when, uh, they almost, uh, kill new quarter.
Speaker 1: And I think it was kind of a cop out that they didn't kill new quarter because one thing that has happened consistently in this region, when there are revolutions like this, which happens in other parts of the world too, in other cultures, uh, the extremists will often ally with progressive students, all the other people who all agree the current regime is corrupt.
Speaker 1: But once the current regime is down, the extremist groups tend to immediately turn on their allies and consolidate power and make a worse regime.
Speaker 1: And you see that happening in the book a little bit when, you know, there are Islamists in the room along with the other revolutionaries and they're immediately executing people like as fast as possible.
Speaker 1: But I feel like it was a cop out to let new quarter one survive that because that really blunted the blow to Alif of.
Speaker 1: this isn't clean buddy.
Speaker 1: Like you have to accept the collateral damage of a revolution like this.
Speaker 1: And also at some point you have to have principles.
Speaker 1: You can't, you can't make waste and ignore the fact that Nazis are using it.
Speaker 1: You may not be able to prevent all Nazis from using it, but if you build null soft waste, you should at least think about how would you deal with the Nazis if they start using it too much.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And Alif did not.
Speaker 1: And I feel like new quarter surviving almost the lesson to Alif is yeah, that's all fine.
Speaker 1: It'll work itself out.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, but you know, new quarter is basically like, he's not, uh, like, you know, he's like, he's like some minor Prince guy.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And so he is the one who busts Alif out of prison.
Speaker 1: Now, on one hand, I like how it shows that he
Speaker 0: was, he was one of Alif's clients or friends originally,
Speaker 1: but there could be people who are in power and wealthy in a corrupt regime who want to be good people and do want to take the regime down, but don't see any way to do it.
Speaker 1: Like they don't actually have power to do anything substantial, but they want to.
Speaker 0: So imagine, imagine yourself in, you know, the French revolution and you are like a, in the court of the King.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And Marie Antoinette, but you're just a courtier.
Speaker 1: And you see that everyone in the government is super corrupt and fucked up and right.
Speaker 0: And it's like, she, she comes out, like, let them eat cake.
Speaker 0: And you're like, fuck this bitch.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like, but it's like, you're, what are you going to do?
Speaker 0: Go become a peasant?
Speaker 0: or it's like, you know, it's like, what can you try to say?
Speaker 1: Like, good luck.
Speaker 1: Have fun.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Go hang out at the tennis court with Rose.
Speaker 0: It's like, you can't, you know, there's only so much you can do in that position.
Speaker 0: And that's the position that the new quarter person is in.
Speaker 1: But I, I, his portrayal was pretty good.
Speaker 1: I still think he should have been killed.
Speaker 1: I think that would have made a much stronger statement, but I liked the fact that he is rewarded and thanked for the good he did, but also the book, the characters and the environment do not necessarily just forgive or forget the fact that he also didn't do as much as he could have and was living a life of abject luxury under this regime.
Speaker 0: And I mean, you know, he rescues him from prison and they get away and like what the bends or whatever, like some ridiculous car.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: But also he had his own unseen world.
Speaker 1: Like he knew the world of being a rich Prince.
Speaker 1: And then as soon as he steps out of that, he pulls the caper and then he's like, oh, fuck, I literally don't know what to do next.
Speaker 1: Where can I even go?
Speaker 1: My cell phone is probably too dangerous to use.
Speaker 1: Well, fuck, I guess I'll just die.
Speaker 1: Like being rich also means there is an unseen world to you, the world of what it's actually like for people who don't have money.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, I think, you know, the book, you know, there's a lot going on here.
Speaker 0: And I think, you know, in some senses it did a good job of like bringing all those different things together.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You know, the computer story, the magical genie story, the societal, you know, Arab Spring Revolution story.
Speaker 0: You know, the religious story, all those things combining here is what makes the book unique.
Speaker 0: But it was also a little bit too much.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: Just like and honestly, if the book had been like 50 more pages long and it just moved at a little slower pace and handled the end a little bit more tightly, I think that would have made it an objectively better book.
Speaker 1: So I enjoyed it.
Speaker 1: But it was.
Speaker 1: it's not like the best book I've ever written as a result of that little bit.
Speaker 1: Like pretty much everything after the prison was fun, but rushed.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I think I'd give it like, you know, the B plus tier, maybe seven out of ten, seven point five out of ten like that area.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I'm not I'm not upset to have read this at all.
Speaker 1: And I would like I'm glad I read it, but I'm not going to put it on like greatest hits list because there are some legitimately great moments, some legitimately heartfelt moments and also some laugh out loud moments like when they're in the actual unseen world.
Speaker 1: And New Quarter one is like kind of slowly going insane.
Speaker 1: And then Ali and the head of the mosque is there, too.
Speaker 1: And the gender like, hey, you want to drink this?
Speaker 1: It's not alcohol, but it'll still fuck you up.
Speaker 1: And New Quarters like, hell yeah, it ain't alcohol.
Speaker 1: It's legal.
Speaker 1: And the guy who runs the mosque is like, you don't need to take it that literally.
Speaker 1: It's still a drug that's probably going to fuck you up.
Speaker 1: You sure you want to drink that?
Speaker 1: And then a leaf has to pay.
Speaker 1: And he's like, he's talking to this ancient entity and he's like, how should I pay you?
Speaker 1: And the thing pauses.
Speaker 1: And it's like, so there's malware on my Dell laptop.
Speaker 1: Can you deal with that?
Speaker 0: It's like even the jinns have computers.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And cell phones and all that.
Speaker 0: Even though they're jinns, they still got all that same stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And I thought that was a fun moment.
Speaker 1: The moment when a leaf is still terrified of Vikram and is talking to Vikram and they don't even say it out loud right away.
Speaker 1: But there's the moment where a leaf realizes the cat monster girl that he had sex with was one, not a dream to literally real and was a jinn.
Speaker 1: Three is Vikram's sister.
Speaker 1: And there's this moment where you see like the gears turning as he figures this out and he gets terrified.
Speaker 1: And the fact that Vikram one already knew and two could not care less is really funny, especially at the end when she's still like, yo, that was fun.
Speaker 1: If you want to date like I'm down.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, kept visiting his room as a cat like, you know, like to men.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: A monster girlfriend who can turn into both a cat and a hawk and fly you around the city and knows a lot of interesting stuff.
Speaker 1: You could do worse.
Speaker 0: You could do a lot worse.
Speaker 0: But he you know, I guess he's very happy with his neighbor.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Which that was.
Speaker 1: that was definitely the intended outcome of, you know, him figuring out.
Speaker 1: I did appreciate all the bits around.
Speaker 1: Obviously, converting to a conservative edging into extremist religious organization of any kind is often portrayed as a negative.
Speaker 1: And there are negative aspects in this book, but there's a beautiful scene where he basically sees the inside, like what she sees inside of her niqab, because it's not even a hijab.
Speaker 1: She wears the extreme form.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And he's inside and he sees the unseen world of Deena, like he sees that she has decorated the inside of it, that like she is the mega nerd on the inside, even though she hides it.
Speaker 1: And that's yet another.
Speaker 1: That's like the fourth parallel thread of unseen worlds.
Speaker 1: Do you think, you know, somebody, do you really, you haven't seen the inside of their head, nor have you seen the inside of like their space, like seeing the inside of someone's room could be equally important.
Speaker 1: And that revelation to him seeing how she sees the world is a really important note in this book.
Speaker 1: You haven't played Disco Elysium, but there's a moment where you get into the hotel room of your partner, which this, your partner in this game is a very private person the whole game.
Speaker 1: And you build a big rapport, depending on how you play, but there's a moment and all you do is you get to see the inside of the room.
Speaker 1: he's been staying in for the last, for the previous few days or week.
Speaker 1: And it's one of the most intimate moments I've experienced in a video game, but it's as simple as you get inside his apartment or like his room and you see what's on his desk.
Speaker 1: Like that's all it is, but it's so profound in the context.
Speaker 0: You keep doing this thing where like, if you know, rim will, rim will like play a game or read a book and then abs like it'll take months for him to not use that one thing as like the reference for absolutely everything else.
Speaker 0: You play Disco Elysium and then like every single conversation for like six months, you find a way to make it relevant.
Speaker 0: Not that you're wrong, but it's just a thing you do.
Speaker 0: I think it's partly that you got to mix it up, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, it has unlike other media, like I couldn't tie this to Breath of the Wild or anything or like Advance Wars.
Speaker 1: More than it is.
Speaker 1: specifically, without spoiling anything, the direct themes of the seen and the unseen are extremely relevant and specifically one-to-one in some cases.
Speaker 0: So I don't know, anything else to say about this book?
Speaker 0: It wasn't actually that long.
Speaker 1: Oh, this is, this is like a couple of weekends read tops.
Speaker 1: Like once I started reading it, I was done almost instantly.
Speaker 1: It's only a couple hundred pages.
Speaker 0: It's a good, it's a good summer beach deal.
Speaker 0: So that'll be, you know, maybe if you haven't read it yet and some, why do you listen to all these spoilers?
Speaker 0: You wait.
Speaker 0: If I were you, I would absolutely read it.
Speaker 0: And I mean, I don't believe in spoilers, so I would also say someone who agrees with me might've listened to this episode and not care.
Speaker 1: You should probably read, and I'm going to read the Ms.
Speaker 1: Marvel book that G. Willow Wilson also wrote.
Speaker 0: And the, the other possible novel that was not selected was what, The Bird King?
Speaker 1: Which I, I'm going to read.
Speaker 1: I bought it.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I mean, I may read it.
Speaker 1: I can read it immediately, but I'm going to read it.
Speaker 1: It's a good, it might be my beach read this summer.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But yeah, The Bird King by G. Willow Wilson is the, is the book that Rym did not select, which was the second novel by Rym Willow Wilson.
Speaker 1: So it's time now.
Speaker 1: I get to do the, I cut and Scott chooses.
Speaker 1: I have picked two possible books and Scott did the thing where the two books were related and that they were by the same author among other things.
Speaker 1: So my two books were both published in the same year.
Speaker 1: Oh, 19 problems.
Speaker 0: So probably not the same author up.
Speaker 1: So 1988, both not that old, not that old.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Uh, they're both extremely famous books that have broad, widely discussed, uh, lit crit, uh, pull the sociopolitical implications.
Speaker 1: Like these are books that people should have read.
Speaker 0: And I consider it a book, a book I may have already read in high school if it's one or, or, or in college, if it's one of those, I'll just pick it and say, I read it already.
Speaker 1: So I'll say one more thing, uh, cause there's no way you'd guess, but, uh, by two famous authors, like very famous authors and I have only ever read excerpts from one of them and nothing from the other of them.
Speaker 1: So I feel like there
Speaker 0: are many, there are many, uh, books that fall into those kinds of categories for me where there's a famous author or there's something I've only seen an excerpt or, you know, I know it's a super famous book I've heard of and I just haven't read it yet.
Speaker 1: And so I'm choosing because whichever one's got picks, it will close what I think is a material gap in my literary education.
Speaker 0: So I, that's a good, that's a valid choice.
Speaker 0: So either, uh, if you want to get on with our buddy Umberto Eco, I actually, that's one of the, that's exact, that's one of the authors that I know is famous and have never read a book from, uh, Foucault's pendulum, which, okay, I've heard of that.
Speaker 1: Do you know what the, what it's actually about?
Speaker 0: No idea.
Speaker 0: I just know that that's my book.
Speaker 0: So I know that that is the name of a book by Umberto Eco and I haven't read it.
Speaker 1: So here's the, here's the broad deal with it.
Speaker 0: It is famous.
Speaker 1: You know that, you know, Dan Brown's the DaVinci code.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Imagine the DaVinci code is like the pop culture bullshit, not actually the same genre version of Foucault's pendulum.
Speaker 1: Foucault's pendulum is basically about a bunch of smart academics who think conspiracy theories are stupid and they start studying them for funsies.
Speaker 1: And the moral, the broad consensus is that the main themes of the book are that studying those things too seriously is caustic to your psyche and may make you go crazy or introduce you to dangerous people.
Speaker 1: And conspiratorial thinking is one of the primary dangers to humanity.
Speaker 0: Isn't that just Call of Cthulhu?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But for Foucault's pendulum, I think there's a lot more going on.
Speaker 0: And I think I'm sure it's a lot longer too.
Speaker 1: Also, I'm pretty sure Umberto Eco is a much better writer than.
Speaker 0: You don't say, I just say, but I think that the whole, the story of Call of Cthulhu is you learn too much and you saw things you shouldn't see.
Speaker 1: But I get the implication that you don't learn anything.
Speaker 1: that's true.
Speaker 1: just by hanging out with conspiracy nut jobs, you make yourself stupider.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: I didn't know anything.
Speaker 0: All I knew is the name and author of that book and that it was famous.
Speaker 0: And now I know a lot more.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Second option, which also 1988.
Speaker 1: I've never actually read Sam and Rushdie's The Satanic Verses, which is a magical realism story.
Speaker 0: Same exact category.
Speaker 0: Well, that's the one that all the, you know, the people, you know, that was banned everywhere, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And in fact, there was a very recent new assassination attempt that almost succeeded on Rushdie again over this book.
Speaker 0: He's alive.
Speaker 0: He made it.
Speaker 0: Good job.
Speaker 0: He made it with some permanent, he's not doing great.
Speaker 1: He's got some permanent disabilities because it was a very violent attack.
Speaker 1: The news really didn't explain exactly what happened right away.
Speaker 1: It was, he's lucky to be alive.
Speaker 1: There have been so many assassination attempts.
Speaker 0: Well, those books are basically in the exact same category.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: But the fact that they were famous.
Speaker 0: author, I've heard the book.
Speaker 0: I've never read it.
Speaker 0: I only know barely what it's about.
Speaker 0: I felt like I should have read it, but it didn't.
Speaker 1: I think they're both relevant to 1988.
Speaker 0: You could have told, you could have told me the plot of Satanic Verses when you talked about what goes back to that.
Speaker 0: I would have believed you.
Speaker 1: So,
Speaker 0: uh,
Speaker 1: but the fact that they were both written in 1988 by famous authors and I think they were very sociopolitically relevant in 1988 and I think they are equally, if not more relevant, based on what scant knowledge I have about them, having not read them in the year 2023.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm okay reading either or both of those books.
Speaker 0: So, and they're so equivalent.
Speaker 0: You wind it up.
Speaker 0: You got two apples that can barely tell them apart.
Speaker 1: And you do the thing of how many computers does Scott own?
Speaker 1: And the answers are seven or eight.
Speaker 1: Then I'm going to do, here are two books that are functionally equivalent.
Speaker 0: That's exactly what you did.
Speaker 0: That is, that is the greatest as a perfect, uh, and now, all right, so I have no choice, but, uh, to allow, I mean, it's, I guess it, you know, defeats the fun of it, but we got to go with the coin toss.
Speaker 1: It's too close.
Speaker 1: So we get the coin toss right now, live on the air.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I got random.org here.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And I wrote, I got the, what I do is the, and random.org, there's the list randomizer where you put items and it randomizes the order of the list.
Speaker 0: And so I just put rush D and echo and I put randomized and whoever is number one on the randomized list will be the book we read.
Speaker 0: And then if I'm, you know, smart, I would read the second book at some point because I'm going to, I will, it'll be a tragedy if I have not read both these books before I die.
Speaker 0: I guess so.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So let's see what random.org says.
Speaker 0: It says rush D wins.
Speaker 0: That's what it says.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 1: You'll be reading salmon rush.
Speaker 1: The satanic versus.
Speaker 1: this has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: For the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, gaming Tuesdays, anime comic Wednesdays, and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution.
Speaker 0: 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: And the patron patrons for this episode of the geek nights book club are Ellen Joyce, Lincoln, Gigi dread, Lily, Tenebrae case care makes music, Chris, the dog, Clinton, Walton, decks, Finn, Joel Hayes, penny rhymer, Rebecca Dunn, Sam Erickson, Shervin, Bono, and a ton of people who are giving us like a dollar because that is absolutely fine.
Speaker 1: You get the same stuff either way.
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah, we're, uh, looking at the new website and also looking at some new pipelines to maybe start providing transcripts of the episodes, uh, publishing in more places, maybe streaming live within discords to the stages.
Speaker 1: But, uh, that is all pending Adobe podcast going live because I don't want to make a new pipeline until I have tried out the new Adobe podcast thing because having, uh, had access to a preview.
Speaker 1: it is kind of phenomenal and I feel like it's going to save me a lot of hassle.
Speaker 1: But for now, at any rate, I leave you simply with... Happy things we should send into space.
Speaker 1: A jar of mayo.
Speaker 1: Magazine clippings of Scott Bayo.
Speaker 1: That song that starts with Dale.
Speaker 1: Little cat you're just like me.
Speaker 1: You go outside and squat to pee.
Speaker 1: Squat!
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, pretty paws off.
Speaker 1: They tend to go for the eyes.
Speaker 1: Just close your eyes and dive on them.
Speaker 1: Now that I made them all pretty, the pound will have to get me that fourth cat.