Speaker 0: It's Thursday, October 26th, 2023.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights Tonight.
Speaker 0: We are talking about scams.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So, uh, long day.
Speaker 0: I didn't notice, like, I was working from home and I was home all day working on stuff and I thought, oh, maybe I should go run and I step out on the balcony and it's like 70-something degrees.
Speaker 0: And it looks like it's going to be 80, uh, what, Saturday?
Speaker 0: It's going to be hot for a few days relative to what late October should be.
Speaker 1: Good.
Speaker 1: At least, you know, if you're going to destroy me and the world, at least I can enjoy it, right?
Speaker 0: Because we have very little control over that situation right now.
Speaker 0: What was that?
Speaker 0: When I see another Discord, I already vote.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess you don't have too many opening bits when, uh, you know, we're just sitting inside working all day.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: On weekdays, uh, and we do show, doing shows more often so there's no stockpiles.
Speaker 0: Yup, back to normal.
Speaker 0: I didn't bike to work, uh, yesterday so I didn't, uh, encounter any funny Manhattan situations.
Speaker 1: I haven't biked to work in, like, years because there's no work to bike to work.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't mind a bike to work, just, you know, the work part I would, I mind.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Um, yeah.
Speaker 1: So, uh, here's a really big news, uh, that I think basically the news is not reporting on because there are other, I guess, sexier news is to report on even though I think this one is, uh, a, a positive news.
Speaker 1: I guess positive news is don't get clicks, right?
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: And, uh, and also not going to impress or, you know, people won't understand how big a deal it is.
Speaker 1: But we all know that I have often and still do criticize the many rich people, Bill Gates foremost among them, right, who had billions of dollars and have chosen to make their primary charitable, I guess, endeavor, uh, trying to fight malaria.
Speaker 1: Now, obviously, malaria is bad.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying, like, don't fight it, right?
Speaker 1: But my personal opinion is that a, uh, cars kill more people than malaria, right?
Speaker 1: Cars, in terms of people just getting hit by cars, it's like one to two million people per year.
Speaker 1: And that doesn't include all the other ways cars kill people, right?
Speaker 0: Oh, it's actually, so for once, not only, this isn't even hyperbole, uh, because a couple of news organizations have covered this over the last few years.
Speaker 0: Cars, car crashes alone kill more people than malaria, HIV, and tuberculosis combined.
Speaker 1: Right, but there's no way Bill Gates is going to fight cars with his money because that dude has a giant garage full of porches, right?
Speaker 1: It's not going to happen, right?
Speaker 1: He's not even thinking of that on his hit list, right?
Speaker 1: And two, my other opinion, and this is just an opinion you may agree or not, right, is that in my view, if you're mad wealthy and you want to make positive change in the world, your best bet is to do what the evil Republican rich people do, and that's bribe the U.S.
Speaker 1: government.
Speaker 1: Because even if you're a billionaire, the U.S.
Speaker 1: government is a multi-trillionaire, right?
Speaker 0: Well, also, the U.S.
Speaker 0: government has two things that even the rich, all the richest people in the world combined do not have.
Speaker 0: Well, but the military, I guess I wanted to highlight a point.
Speaker 0: It's not just the military, because yes, as evil and dangerous as Megacorps are in the year 2023, Amazon does not have an aircraft carrier.
Speaker 1: Not yet.
Speaker 0: But I guess, yeah, sadly, but I guess the real power of something like the U.S.
Speaker 0: military is not that it can kill people.
Speaker 0: Like, that's like, what you need to really understand is that the United States military is the most advanced logistical system the world has ever seen.
Speaker 0: Like, if there is a disaster and you needed to get food aid or evacuate people or do the kinds of things you often need to do in the world, there is literally no organization on earth better equipped to do literally anything anywhere than the United States military.
Speaker 1: Right, but the point is, is that if you can influence the United States government to do positive things, that becomes a force multiplier, right?
Speaker 1: A trillion is a thousand billions, right?
Speaker 1: And the U.S.
Speaker 1: government is multi-trillion dollar, right?
Speaker 1: So, if you can use mere billions, mere billions, billions, right, with a B, mere, right?
Speaker 1: If you can use that to influence and get the U.S.
Speaker 1: government to change its policies in a positive way, you have basically can cause thousand times more your investment, right, in terms of what you want to happen in the world, right?
Speaker 1: So, that's my criticism, but those two uses aside of billions of dollars, right, fighting malaria is still way up on the list.
Speaker 1: We're talking top ten things to spend money on, right?
Speaker 1: The number of people killed by malaria each year in the world is like between half a million and a million, right?
Speaker 1: It kills a shit ton of people, and not only that, as the climate change is happening, the mosquitoes expand their territory, and the malaria is going to kill more people, right?
Speaker 1: So, fighting malaria, it's up there.
Speaker 1: It's not, he could do better, and that's why my criticism is there, in case anyone has heard me criticize on a previous podcast.
Speaker 0: More.
Speaker 1: You could, yeah, sure, but regardless, fighting malaria, really good, right, in terms of the overall picture.
Speaker 1: There's a lot worse things you could do, for sure.
Speaker 0: Like buy Twitter and destroy it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right, that's completely useless compared to fighting malaria, right?
Speaker 1: So, anyway, in the fight against malaria, there has been a revolutionary event, right?
Speaker 1: They have a vaccine, and I guess there have been vaccines before, and there will be different ones in the future.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of reasons why it's very hard to make a vaccine for malaria compared to a lot of other things.
Speaker 1: 'Cause malaria is a motherfucker, right, compared to those other viruses, right, you know?
Speaker 1: But they have a vaccine for malaria, and in the pilots and the tests that they have done, right, it has cut the deaths among children by 13% over four years.
Speaker 1: And you think, well, that's a small percentage.
Speaker 1: It's like 13% times, what, like 600,000, right?
Speaker 1: 600,000 times .13, that's saving 78,000 people a year, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, even if it was 10%, and there's 10 kids, it just saved a kid in a room of 10 kids.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: So, but the point is that that 13%, and that's deployed over a small group that they tested on, if you deployed this vaccine, even in its imperfect,
Speaker 0: flawed,
Speaker 1: not super effective, just somewhat good effective vaccine, widely, to the people of the world who are threatened by malaria, right, you will basically revolutionize those areas of the world, because so many less people will just die prematurely and unnecessarily, right?
Speaker 1: The economies, the cultures, just everything going on in those parts of the world will be dramatically changed if you can deploy this vaccine, which I think they're probably going to do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and this vaccine has a 36% efficacy rate in the current clinical trials, so there's more ground we can cover as well, but this leads into something we talk about a lot on Geek Nights around how it's not the bleeding edge of technology that is actually saving lives.
Speaker 0: It's taking technology we've got, however flawed, and deploying it at scale, and deploying logistics around it, using what we've already developed, and just giving it to people, or giving people access to it.
Speaker 0: Like, clean water will save a lot of people on Earth, and we have the science to clean water.
Speaker 0: We've had it for a very long time, we just don't use it everywhere.
Speaker 1: So yeah, this is, I hope this works, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I want to be really interested to see, like, what happens in the malaria-ed parts of the world, right?
Speaker 1: Over the course of the next decade or so.
Speaker 0: Well, I remember, so there was a thing on PBS a long time ago, 2016, I dug it up because I remember reading this, and it was talking about the American South, and how there was, like, let's ignore the current political realities of the American South, and just focus on this aspect of it.
Speaker 0: There was a long-standing cultural idea that people in the South were lazy, and lethargic, and would laze around a lot, the germ of laziness, like it was the thing that you'd see in a lot of writing.
Speaker 1: You mean it's hot out, and they didn't have air conditioning.
Speaker 0: Ah, so there was a bigger factor going on.
Speaker 0: A huge percentage of people who lived in the American South for a very long time were infected with hookworms.
Speaker 0: Which are also endemic in much of the world.
Speaker 0: And what ended that particular, basically, like, endemic disease was aggressive treatment, education, shoes, and a couple of, like, there's a bunch of stuff happening that you can read this article to see all the details about.
Speaker 0: I found it again.
Speaker 0: And basically, this disease was not talked about, and yet it was very likely the primary cause of all of these cultural associations, and a significant contributor to some of the economic challenges that the area faced for a long time.
Speaker 0: And people don't think about the extra externalities of endemic disease, especially people who have access to the internet and sit around in their houses working from home and making podcasts.
Speaker 0: Because if you live in the United States, you very likely do not encounter, even if you are relatively poor, the kinds of endemic diseases that are in much of the rest of the world.
Speaker 0: And the way we have made that happen could be deployed very widely, and it is not for political and economic reasons that are bullshit.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, it's the same old story where we've heard about, you know, crime and lead poisoning.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, how true, right?
Speaker 1: Seems to be somewhat true, right?
Speaker 1: Go, I guess, read about it if you care.
Speaker 1: But it's like, there are these other explanations for historical events and trends on a mass scale that are outside of anything that we could see or detect, especially in the past when we didn't have the technology that we do now.
Speaker 1: And it's like, we seem to just, you know, tell the history of human society as, you know, just humans, you know, being how they are.
Speaker 1: And it's like, actually, a lot of things could have been environmental things that caused it to happen.
Speaker 1: They were just invisible environmental things, not like volcanoes and hurricanes or, you know, they were visible at the time, but it's like we had no way to know that they happened unless there's some really good geology or, you know, who knows?
Speaker 0: Like the collapse of what the Mycenaean civilization where, yeah, all we know is around the same time, a bunch of these places all seem to have burned down and/or been abandoned, but we don't know what actually caused that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But, you know, even more recent things, it's like, we know about the Black Plague.
Speaker 1: It's like, but that was sort of a one that you could see even though it was a virus, but there are any, you know, diseases especially, right, that only have non-lethal, non-visible symptomatic, you know, non-visible symptoms, right?
Speaker 1: There could be some virus that just, you know, like you said, the hookworm that makes people tired.
Speaker 1: It's a parasite or, you know, lead poisoning.
Speaker 1: It makes people angry and stupid.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So does vitamin B deficiency.
Speaker 1: Things of that nature.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, there's no way, we had to do a lot of research in science to blame the correct thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Instead of, you know, people, certain people who always blame, you know, just individual responsibility on everything.
Speaker 0: It was a great, I just watched a lecture at the Royal Institute that was talking about obesity and food and the difference between processed food.
Speaker 1: That's another one, yeah.
Speaker 0: But he had a really good line, I'm paraphrasing, but he basically said in the context of physical fitness and health, that personal responsibility or willpower is usually just a proxy for poverty.
Speaker 0: That's correct.
Speaker 0: And he went into this for a while.
Speaker 0: And then he pulled up a really interesting statistic that showed that across, in America, across every demographic, every racial line, every cultural line, sex, gender, everything, obesity started rising at the same time for everyone, every age group, everything.
Speaker 0: There was a year where it basically started to rise from that point, which implies that nothing anyone human did had anything to do with this.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: In some other news, there's also very good news, but in a different way.
Speaker 0: You may remember that not that long ago, a bunch of open Nazis in something called "Unite the Right" had a torch-bearing Nazi rally.
Speaker 0: And a lot of people tried to act like they were not in fact Nazis, but were just concerned right-wing people who were expressing their rights or whatever.
Speaker 0: But the focal point of them and a movement around them has been around Confederate statues.
Speaker 0: Now, we already know, if you listen to Geek Nights, you know that Confederate statues are bullshit and they're not even historical.
Speaker 0: Most of them were built during the Civil Rights era, which tells you everything you need to know about them.
Speaker 0: It's not like they were built right after World War II, right after the Civil War.
Speaker 1: Even if they were, that would be weird.
Speaker 1: Imagine, like, you know, Genghis Khan and Alexander the Great have a fight and Alexander the Great loses.
Speaker 1: And then Genghis Khan has some Alexander the Great statues built, and they're not just like a memorial or some shit to my great opponent in an anime or something.
Speaker 1: They're like in all these random towns all over Asia, right?
Speaker 1: And they're built by, obviously, the people who were supporters of Alexander the Great after they got defeated.
Speaker 1: That would be, and, you know, it's like, hmm, that's a little weird.
Speaker 0: So there's a particularly important and famous statue of a traitor, Robert E. Lee, who, fun fact, a lot of people try to rehabilitate him by arguing that he fought for some noble reason or that he was a great general.
Speaker 0: And neither of those things is true.
Speaker 1: He was a stupid villain.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: He was also not even a particularly good general.
Speaker 0: The North basically didn't want to engage with the full might of its military right away for a bunch of complicated reasons.
Speaker 0: And his early quote victories were kind of just happenstance or the fact that the North wasn't really fighting that hard.
Speaker 0: But anyway, so this statue became the focal point of the neo-Confederate Nazis in Charlottesville, and the government decided to take it down.
Speaker 0: And there were a lot of threats of violence.
Speaker 0: It was very difficult to take it down safely.
Speaker 0: Nazis kept showing up anytime, like, people moved in to remove it.
Speaker 0: It was moved to a secret location at one point, and over time, the news kind of forgot about it.
Speaker 0: People stopped talking about this statue.
Speaker 0: Just now, we now know the final fate of the statue.
Speaker 0: Today at 3
Speaker 0: p.m.,
Speaker 0: the Washington Post has a bunch of video, and you can see exactly what they did to the statue.
Speaker 0: They took it to a secret foundry that was not named because they're afraid that Nazis will attack the people who work there.
Speaker 0: And they invited a small number of journalists and activists.
Speaker 0: A lot of non-white people were there for reasons you can imagine.
Speaker 0: And they videoed the extensive process of cutting this thing apart, melting it into slag, and then preparing to use it to make art in a museum for the future.
Speaker 1: They didn't make a "Lissey says Grant statue" outfit?
Speaker 0: That would be fantastic.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure exactly what they're going to make out of it, but this article has extensive video of them cutting this thing apart, and a lot of very cool people making very good and correct statements about what is going on and why.
Speaker 1: You know, that does remind me, I was thinking earlier this week, the same thing, is that in Manhattan, there is famous Grant's Tomb.
Speaker 1: Grant's Tomb is right there.
Speaker 1: Have I been there?
Speaker 1: Yes, many times, actually.
Speaker 0: Who's buried in Grant's Tomb?
Speaker 1: There's nobody.
Speaker 1: It's not a burial.
Speaker 1: It's a tomb.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, I typed "who's buried" because I was going to pull out the old reference to that, and Google recommended "in Grant's
Speaker 0: Tomb.".
Speaker 1: Noted New Yorker, Ulysses Grant.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's this little building, and it's like this park.
Speaker 1: There's even a little playground in that area, generally speaking, but you know, it's grass and a building, right?
Speaker 1: And I've been there many times.
Speaker 1: I've been passed there many times.
Speaker 1: I biked past it many times.
Speaker 1: I could tell you exactly where the fuck it is.
Speaker 1: I could walk there without a map, right?
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: I was thinking earlier this week, and also right now, I never went inside, not even one time.
Speaker 0: I've never been inside.
Speaker 0: I never thought about if you could go inside.
Speaker 1: I think it's open if you go during the day, right?
Speaker 0: I see a photo when I just went to a website, the National Park Service website, and it shows what looks like a bunch of people walking into it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a national park.
Speaker 1: You can go in there.
Speaker 1: I just have never gone in there, even though it's right there.
Speaker 0: We should go to Grant's Tomb.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Can you see Grant, or is it just like, no, you just see his name or something?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: There's no photo of the inside in this article that I just clicked on.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 1: I don't know, because I don't really want to see a skeleton.
Speaker 1: It's not, you know, it's Halloween, but seriously.
Speaker 0: Skeletons are neat.
Speaker 0: I could see Grant's skeleton.
Speaker 1: He was a big dude, right?
Speaker 0: I don't actually know how tall Grant was.
Speaker 1: I thought he was a big dude.
Speaker 1: Let me check.
Speaker 0: How tall was Grant?
Speaker 0: No, he was not a big dude.
Speaker 0: He was 5'8".
Speaker 0: He was taller than the average adult male in the year 1860.
Speaker 0: He was taller than me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he was shorter than me.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: I could have taken him.
Speaker 1: Probably not.
Speaker 1: I can't do one push-up.
Speaker 1: I think Grant could do push-ups.
Speaker 0: So, one last little news.
Speaker 0: Now, I guess this news would be better fitting on a Tuesday, because it's about a game.
Speaker 0: The game of ice hockey.
Speaker 0: A thing that happened in hockey recently is, for bigoted reasons, and the fact that no major capitalist organization wants to engage with what it perceives to be culture wars, because they don't want to deal with the assumed hassle, the NHL basically made this kind of bullshitty policy that effectively said players shouldn't put rainbow pride tape on their sticks during warm-ups.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, the whole policy was basically, it's like they just quietly, right, just sort of sent out a memo.
Speaker 1: And the thing is, it doesn't bother me.
Speaker 1: I mean, it does bother me that they have this wrong, stupid policy.
Speaker 1: But the thing that bothers me more is that you don't have the guts to explain yourself, right?
Speaker 1: It's like defend what your policy is.
Speaker 1: It's like if someone comes out and is like, "I want to kill all the poor people, and here's
Speaker 1: why.".
Speaker 1: And it's like, "Alright, you're a right-wing nutjob.
Speaker 1: I don't like you.
Speaker 1: You're bad.
Speaker 1: But at least I can't, you know, it's like you are who you are, right?
Speaker 1: You're being true to
Speaker 1: yourself.".
Speaker 1: If someone comes out and is like, "No players may do, wear, or display anything on the ice to support any cause, no individuality whatsoever, including specifically calling out the pride tape, which is the main
Speaker 1: one."
Speaker 1: And it's like, "Alright, do you have a reason?
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 1: We're not going to say.
Speaker 1: No
Speaker 1: comment."
Speaker 1: It's like, "Well...".
Speaker 0: We have a lot of additional information where it's pretty obvious what the reasons were in that it mostly seems like it came down to certain unnamed players on.
Speaker 0: certain teams are bigoted assholes and did not want to do it, but also didn't want...
Speaker 1: Well, that was the jerseys last year.
Speaker 1: But the tape, the new rule this year, there was no whys or wherefores.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure it has to do with these players who are assholes.
Speaker 0: One, don't want to let that...
Speaker 1: It came from the owners.
Speaker 1: It didn't come from the players.
Speaker 0: Well, I think the owners are probably worried about the sensibility of specific individual players.
Speaker 1: Well, the owners are just 32 different billionaire assholes, right?
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: But I guess if a whole team does it and one person on the team doesn't, well, we know who the asshole is.
Speaker 0: And I don't think... Yeah, good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the assholes don't want that.
Speaker 0: So a player on the Arizona Coyotes, Travis Dermott, just said fuck it.
Speaker 1: So people who aren't hockey people, you got to know Travis Dermott, right?
Speaker 1: This guy is an NHL player.
Speaker 1: He's in the NHL, right?
Speaker 1: But he is not like an always NHL player.
Speaker 1: This is one of those guys who's like spending AHL time.
Speaker 1: He's a borderline guy, right?
Speaker 1: So he actually has, on the one hand, he's got more to lose, right?
Speaker 1: Because if you're sent down to the AHL, the money you make significantly decreases, right?
Speaker 1: A fine, if he's fined, he doesn't make a zillion dollars, right?
Speaker 1: Like the top players.
Speaker 1: He gets paid way less.
Speaker 1: Let's go to Cap Friendly and see how much money Travis Dermott gets.
Speaker 0: And even though it's going to sound like a lot because it's professional sports, you have to understand that you can't keep playing that sport past like 30.
Speaker 1: Travis Dermott has basically the league minimum $800,000 contract and he's a UFA at the end of this season.
Speaker 1: So basically, you know, it's like he's in the weakest position and basically an NHL player can be in, right?
Speaker 1: And other players, to their credit, right?
Speaker 1: Including like the top player, like, you know, Connor McDavid did say things about this policy, you know, saying it's stupid, whatever.
Speaker 1: But only Travis Dermott, who had everything to lose.
Speaker 1: And, you know, this cause of, you know, of LGBT issues was important to him, right?
Speaker 1: And has been for some time.
Speaker 1: He was the only one to actually have the guts to put a little piece of tape with some colors on it on his stick during a real hockey game.
Speaker 0: He didn't do the trolly type thing you could have done of, it's just, it's a rainbow.
Speaker 0: What are you going to find me over it?
Speaker 0: No, he was very vocal about why he did it.
Speaker 0: He just did it.
Speaker 0: He basically said, bring it.
Speaker 0: What are you going to do?
Speaker 0: Because now this was brave and powerful.
Speaker 0: This forced the NHL to, and all these billionaires.
Speaker 1: Look at this, one little guy, like this no name guy, right?
Speaker 1: Puts a little piece of tape on the stick, right?
Speaker 1: And they asked the NHL, right?
Speaker 1: The reporters who are basically all, every NHL reporter that I've heard, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, there must not be any right wing NHL reporters, or at least not any open their mouth.
Speaker 1: Because literally every single NHL writer from teams all over, right?
Speaker 1: Even teams that are in like, you know, places you would think are not left wing.
Speaker 1: Were like, they were against, they wanted the tape.
Speaker 1: They were called, they were bashing the NHL big time, right?
Speaker 1: But one dude puts a little piece of tape on his stick, who's a nobody in the league basically, and the NHL immediately folds.
Speaker 1: They're like, all right, you can do it.
Speaker 0: They folded so fast and you can see why.
Speaker 0: Because think about it, you put them in a position now, if instead of their cowardly nonstatement originally, like this cowardly policy that's obscuring all the reasons and everything.
Speaker 1: But again, they folded, which is the right call, again with no explanation.
Speaker 1: No guts to say why you're doing what you're doing or defend what you're doing.
Speaker 1: You just say, this is what I'm doing.
Speaker 1: This is what our policy is.
Speaker 1: No, not even one shred of courage to be willing to say why you made those decisions that you did.
Speaker 0: And think about how it worked.
Speaker 0: The NHL now to respond to him, what could they have done?
Speaker 0: They could have won, fucked over the little guy, and then they'd have to say why.
Speaker 0: And if they didn't, it would still be obvious why.
Speaker 0: And if the story is, player fined by NHL for expressing pro-LGBT.
Speaker 1: Other people were going to pay his fine if he got fined.
Speaker 1: That's besides the point.
Speaker 0: But the media circus and the scrutiny the NHL would have been under if they got after him.
Speaker 0: Any institution like this will always take the coward's path.
Speaker 0: So the coward's path in this situation is to say almost nothing and just stop enforcing the thing you didn't say anything about the first time.
Speaker 0: So if you're ever in a situation where you have an enemy who is a coward and you think the coward's path will get what you wanted anyway, try to force them into the coward's path.
Speaker 0: And two, never lose sight of the fact that one person taking a stand often can have a huge impact in situations.
Speaker 0: Partly because almost no one is ever willing to take that stand.
Speaker 0: You need at least one person to take a stand openly and risk those consequences and actually just go for it.
Speaker 1: And also, if you had any suspicions that all of the corporate entities who were, I guess we can call it rainbow washing, who are doing pride events or any other cause when any corporation acts like they're supporting some cause.
Speaker 1: And you think it might not be genuine, but at least it helps.
Speaker 1: It's like here's the confirmation you needed.
Speaker 1: It's not genuine.
Speaker 1: You know that it's not.
Speaker 1: It's like if they're supporting, there's a capitalist motivation behind it unless proven otherwise with some actual meaningful gutsy actions.
Speaker 1: When they say hockey is for everyone, what they're really saying is please don't hate hockey.
Speaker 1: We need the biggest audience we can and we don't want to shun any, we don't want to make any possible customers feel unwelcome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, translate that hockey is for everyone, mostly means to the NHL.
Speaker 0: We want to make sure the right wing nut jobs keep watching.
Speaker 1: Right, but do we actually support you?
Speaker 1: Will we actually stand up for you and lay down, you know, make a sacrifice to support your cause or lay ourselves down on the line for you?
Speaker 1: No, because we don't actually care.
Speaker 1: We just want to make sure that we keep as the maximum number of customers as possible.
Speaker 0: Well, this is too why I treat rainbow washing as something different.
Speaker 0: What I use it as primarily, it's almost like a bellwether or a windsock about the actual sentiment of what's going on in regard to capital and LGBT rights in that if society is opening, then the companies will do whatever they think is on the side of the money.
Speaker 0: So it's a good sign.
Speaker 0: when more companies are willing to take that extreme, even if it's a purely selfish "stand" and they're just doing it for promotional purposes, it means that the bean counters and lawyers have decided.
Speaker 0: the money in society is on this side of that issue, which means that we're slowly winning the fight in society.
Speaker 0: And it's worrying that a number of major companies, including Disney just recently, have started to back off because they're afraid of backlash from the right wing because that backlash has been growing rapidly just over the last year.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I think the other problem is that while on the one hand you can see the capitalist companies, in the United States at least, go against or for the way the government goes because it's like the money, despite capitalism being bullshit, is still somewhat democratic in terms of the number of people.
Speaker 1: If the majority of the people in the United States support a thing and the dollar votes go to that thing, it's like, yeah, so companies will go in that direction, but yet the federal government especially is undemocratic.
Speaker 1: It doesn't reflect the popular vote and therefore you can see the mismatch.
Speaker 1: But if you see the companies more fearful of actions the government will take, then how people will vote with their dollars, you could see the companies go away from what's popular among the people because the government harm might hurt their bottom line with policies more than the loss of customers.
Speaker 0: So anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: So this is actually an extremely well done video and it's called Nothing's Working Out, Waluigi.
Speaker 0: It's a full length song and a very well animated, extremely stylish, professional looking music video and the song seems to be about someone whose life just isn't working out and it's all about Waluigi and his life just not working out.
Speaker 0: It's super well done.
Speaker 0: So I dug a little deeper to see what the deal was and it seems like it's just original fan animation straight up.
Speaker 0: It's not even one of those.
Speaker 0: take an anime opener or something else and just sort of reanimate it.
Speaker 0: It seems like it's completely original.
Speaker 0: The song that is used is from a band in Japan, Meiyo, and they have an animated music video, but the music video they have is not the same as the Waluigi one.
Speaker 0: The Waluigi one is basically completely original animation that has only a few aesthetic references to the original video.
Speaker 0: The original video is also great and the song is great, but this Waluigi video just stands out to me.
Speaker 1: Oh, getting complicated.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 0: Oh, there's a further rabbit hole.
Speaker 0: There's a women's version of the song as well from the same band that has its own animated music video.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: But yeah, you want to see sexy Waluigi?
Speaker 0: Here we go.
Speaker 1: So, lately I've been rearranging my internet reading situation, especially with the death of all social things basically.
Speaker 1: And I was thinking about old newspapers and there's been this conglomeration of things that have happened.
Speaker 1: One thing that happened is the New Yorker wrote a review and I was reminded that the Bill Watterson book that we talked about a hundred years ago, the little story book called The Mysteries that he did with John Cash, it finally came out like sixteen days ago.
Speaker 1: Oh.
Speaker 1: I've been reading so many web comics.
Speaker 1: It's like the newspaper, I'm trying to basically reorganize all my reading biz.
Speaker 1: It's like newspapers always used to have funny bits and it's like now.
Speaker 1: people are reading news and there's no funny bits mixed in unless it's the New Yorker.
Speaker 1: So it has comics on everything, right?
Speaker 1: And it's like, hey, I should try to basically incorporate into my internet reading.
Speaker 1: I should try to bring back the comics going on.
Speaker 1: And another thing the newspapers had, right along with the comics, is the puzzle action.
Speaker 1: So I've actually been using the New York Puzzly app, which basically the crossword, I'm not huge on crossword.
Speaker 1: I'm really bad at them.
Speaker 1: I can't even do them past like Wednesday.
Speaker 1: Sometimes not even Wednesday.
Speaker 1: But regardless, it's like they have added all these other puzzles to the New York Times puzzle app, including, you know, the wordle obviously, but they got this connections one that's really hot and the spelling bee one.
Speaker 1: I like the spelling bee one a lot.
Speaker 1: That's like my top one.
Speaker 1: So what's happened is Zach Gage.
Speaker 1: You may know Zach Gage because I think he worked at like for some other people making other games.
Speaker 1: You might know, like I think he had a hand in the ridiculous fishing, even though that wasn't his main.
Speaker 1: He wasn't the main guy on it.
Speaker 1: But Spell Tower, you may have heard of the really bad chess.
Speaker 1: You may have heard of.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So Zach Gage is.
Speaker 1: latest thing is this thing called Puzmo and it's you can go to Puzmo dot com.
Speaker 1: And what they're trying to do is they're trying to basically recreate, you know, basically it's going to be a competitor for that New York Times puzzle game app.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like daily puzzle action going on.
Speaker 1: And so what they've done is every day they're going to mail out five hundred keys to people to get into Puzmo.
Speaker 1: It's not open to the world yet.
Speaker 1: So how do you get one of the five hundred keys?
Speaker 1: Well, if you sign up to the mailing list, they email you the moment the daily puzzle goes live.
Speaker 1: They got one puzzle that you don't have to log in to play.
Speaker 1: And if you're one of the first five hundred people to solve that puzzle, then you can mail you a key in the snail mail to get into Puzmo.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So the first day that I noticed this Puzmo, there was a chess puzzle and five hundred people already solved it.
Speaker 1: And I suck at chess puzzles anyway.
Speaker 0: I just did today's puzzle while you were talking because it was not I did yesterday.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But that was an easy one.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But I did yesterday's puzzle.
Speaker 1: And I was one of the first five hundred to do it.
Speaker 1: So I'm going to get in the mail a key to get into Puzmo.
Speaker 1: And I guess, Rim, you can.
Speaker 1: if you put your email address in and you're fast tomorrow, you might be able to get a key.
Speaker 0: I should try to be fast tomorrow.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But yeah, Puzmo I think is going to be hopefully a good addition to the daily, you know, daily biz.
Speaker 1: So check out.
Speaker 1: And if you if you if you're not fast, at least you're still getting one puzzle every day.
Speaker 1: So, you know.
Speaker 0: In the meta moment, the Geek Nights Book Club book, The Murderbot Diaries.
Speaker 0: I am like 80 percent through the last of the currently published Murderbot diaries that I have access to.
Speaker 0: And when the new one comes out, as we've said, we're going to do the show.
Speaker 0: We'll give you a couple of few weeks to read more Murderbot.
Speaker 0: But we're going to talk about the whole Murderbot series when we do.
Speaker 1: the next Murderbot book is one of the small ones.
Speaker 1: I'm going to read it in like a sitting.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the Murderbot books are real fast reads.
Speaker 0: And I guess the only thing I'll say now, because it couldn't be further from from Taylor Genji, the Murderbot.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: It's a they were refreshing science fiction to read in that they take a straight line toward the interesting aspects of the science fiction concepts they are dealing with.
Speaker 0: And they just kind of shine on them directly.
Speaker 0: But also the characters are kind of delightful.
Speaker 0: And I have the exact opposite opinion of the listener who said that as soon as the books got long, they got tedious and there's just one long book.
Speaker 1: Just one of them is long.
Speaker 0: But I love the human characters.
Speaker 0: They're all great.
Speaker 0: I love how Murderbot has these weird opinions of all the different human characters and like secretly kind of idolizes one of them is annoyed by one of them.
Speaker 0: And the whole thing with the kid and the fourth book, fifth book, fifth book, the teenager.
Speaker 1: Our new Web site is up.
Speaker 1: It is live.
Speaker 1: It is functioning.
Speaker 1: But it is still in the process of continuous and forever improvement for as long as Geek Nights exists.
Speaker 1: So, you know, check it out.
Speaker 1: Use it for what you need to use it for or don't use it because something else satisfies you.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Give us your comments.
Speaker 0: Tell us what you think.
Speaker 0: Report bugs.
Speaker 1: We need to know about features.
Speaker 1: We need to know about bugs, changes, anything like that.
Speaker 0: I mean, the listener pointed out it was hard to get the thing of the day links in various forms and Scott fixed that basically right away.
Speaker 1: Well, that took me like that was actually somewhat annoying defense.
Speaker 1: But yeah, that felt like an important one that the, you know, the posts were basically incomplete.
Speaker 1: You know, I'm working on improving where I can.
Speaker 1: We got to get the automatic forum post working.
Speaker 1: That's the next.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll get there.
Speaker 0: Bit by bit.
Speaker 0: I got to make some pipelines.
Speaker 0: There's a few things I got to do still in my task list.
Speaker 0: We will be live at PAX Unplugged on Friday.
Speaker 0: Learn and play Wist, Hearts and Wizard.
Speaker 0: We're not just going to tell you how to play these games.
Speaker 0: We're going to teach you basically R trick taking.
Speaker 0: And then we're going to teach you how to be not the best in the world, but pretty dangerous and good, especially at Hearts and Wizard because we are both pretty good at Hearts and Wizard.
Speaker 0: I think if Scott and I played in a long form Hearts tournament, it'd be a pretty close fight.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I played some Oh Hell, which is like 90 percent the same as Wizard yesterday.
Speaker 1: And it's not as good as at least whatever rules they were using, especially there's.
Speaker 1: it was not as good, especially with seven people.
Speaker 1: It was not.
Speaker 1: it was not good.
Speaker 1: I'd much rather play Wizard.
Speaker 0: And then on Saturday, mastering game mechanics, worker placement.
Speaker 0: Fifty nine minutes of us talking about worker placement, the mechanic.
Speaker 0: I got to start working on those slides a little more deeply.
Speaker 0: We got about a month.
Speaker 0: Luckily, I think we have more than an hour's worth of content.
Speaker 0: So this is going to be mostly an editing and whittling down exercise rather than a writing an entire panel exercise.
Speaker 1: I think the biggest problem is that, you know, while we've played many worker placement games and have many skills at those games, there's so many worker placement games we haven't played and things we don't know.
Speaker 1: And, you know, there's always going to be that nerd who's like, oh, what about this one that does it differently?
Speaker 1: And what about that one that doesn't differently?
Speaker 1: And it's like, look, you know, I've played a thousand games, but I haven't played ten thousand games.
Speaker 0: But I feel like we're going to we're going to teach enough rules from a few specific several specific examples.
Speaker 0: I feel like example driven conversations in this will be more useful than purely abstract, because if we just want to define what a worker placement game is in a reasonably objective way, that would take more than an hour by itself.
Speaker 0: So there's a story here and there's a lot to unpack about it and not necessarily what you, the listener, might think we would say we should unpack about it.
Speaker 0: But the cause scam, like the concept of a scam, like in general, has been around as long as there have been humans who can communicate with each other and have needs and wants and desires and difficulty achieving those things.
Speaker 1: Scams are I mean, I mean, the core of a scam is that one human basically deceives another human and convinces that human to act in the interest of the deceiver at great misfortune of the person being deceived.
Speaker 0: If we have to define it.
Speaker 0: So the story here is fascinating because basically two people got scammed by actually a very common form of scam now where basically someone will message someone who's not super technologically proficient online and make a long term fake friendship with them, mostly via text messages and Facebook posts and that kind of thing.
Speaker 0: And then well into that relationship, make stuff up and then kick off the scam and start collecting money from them from there.
Speaker 0: Like it's a very long form close up magic style of scam, but it's so common and it almost always involves certain kinds of financial transactions, usually to buy dubious cryptocurrency.
Speaker 0: So all the banks and all the places you can interact with even cryptocurrency or transfer money or anything basically know about these things.
Speaker 0: And the problem they're having is that there are a lot of situations like this one where someone is obviously being scammed, like anyone who knows this person and finds out about the transaction they're trying to accomplish would say, yo, you're being scammed.
Speaker 0: But the people are being scammed will absolutely not listen to them.
Speaker 0: But the banks know and the banks will tell people directly, look, the transaction you just tried to put in is definitely a scam.
Speaker 0: If you proceed with this transaction, which we have currently blocked, you're almost definitely going to lose your money.
Speaker 0: We cannot help you get it back.
Speaker 0: Even if you call the police, there'll be nothing we can do.
Speaker 0: And often what the people who are being scammed will do is threaten to sue their own bank if they don't make the transaction go through.
Speaker 0: So the bank eventually, in this case, they made the person who was being scammed write a handwritten note explaining, quote, Revolut has warned me that this is likely a scam and that I am unlikely to recover my funds, et cetera, et cetera.
Speaker 0: They made her write this out on a piece of paper, take a selfie of herself holding up the piece of paper with the date and send it to them.
Speaker 0: And then when they couldn't convince her, they eventually let the transaction go through.
Speaker 0: And the news article is about, oh, no, it was a scam and she gave up her life savings.
Speaker 0: It's common, this kind of thing.
Speaker 0: And it is easy to try to blame the victim.
Speaker 0: And there are a lot of very credulous people out there who are easily scammed.
Speaker 0: But there is also a bigger story around why and how people fall for scams in general, because it's kind of sad how often people fall for what appear to the kind of person who listens to Geek Nights as obviously a scam, like zero doubt instantly.
Speaker 0: Have you ever been scammed?
Speaker 1: Have I been scammed?
Speaker 0: I have been scammed once when I was young in a late middle school by a carny out of like 20 bucks.
Speaker 0: And I was scammed, but I knew it was a scam.
Speaker 0: And I went along with it because it was funny and fun.
Speaker 0: I was in India once and I bought some worthless art for basically five or six US dollars, which was clearly part of a scam to sell me something worthless.
Speaker 1: I don't know if that's so much a scam, but there have been times where people awkwardly pressure you.
Speaker 1: I think that's a good example in a market.
Speaker 1: Especially the kind of market that doesn't exist in the US so much.
Speaker 1: I guess it does flee markets, but street markets.
Speaker 0: I've had people pull the aggressive to the point of I am uncomfortable hard sell on me and artist alleys at anime conventions before.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's true.
Speaker 1: That's another good example.
Speaker 0: I can definitely feel someone who was less willful or more worried about social consequences of falling for it and buying a print they didn't want.
Speaker 1: Actually, I can tell you a time where I was pressured and it didn't work because I was in Israel in the year 2000.
Speaker 1: And this dude, we're going through a place that's a street market with various crafts and touristy tchotchkes and all that kind of stuff that you would expect.
Speaker 1: And this dude comes up behind me because I'm some 18 year old white kid.
Speaker 1: Clearly, I'm speaking English.
Speaker 1: He can see that I'm not.
Speaker 1: He puts his arm around me.
Speaker 1: He's like, hello, my friend.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It was so.
Speaker 1: it was like from a movie.
Speaker 1: I think he was talking that way, like almost on purpose already.
Speaker 0: My pickpocket flag is that full alert just from what you said.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: But it wasn't a pickpocket issue.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But he's that he's like, hey, come here, check out my friends, you know, merge, you know, original handmade.
Speaker 1: So great.
Speaker 1: Oh, this is the best.
Speaker 1: Isn't it beautiful?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And it's like, you know, he's basically they create.
Speaker 1: it's not a scam so much as where you're being deceived.
Speaker 1: I mean, there might have been some deception.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, was it all handmade Armenian high quality, rare shit?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But it's like, you know, that was the price too high, probably.
Speaker 1: I didn't buy any of it because even then I knew better.
Speaker 1: But it's like people in those situations, the things that like in New York City, people do the CD selling.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like or the or the petty cab guys.
Speaker 1: It's like they don't.
Speaker 1: they're not lying to you so much as they are putting you in a situation where it's they're making it.
Speaker 1: if you aren't don't have courage.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You're afraid for to say no and you end up just losing money that you didn't lose.
Speaker 1: Some of those attacks on people who don't have courage.
Speaker 0: And some of those get dicey because they edge into an unspoken threat and they effectively become a mugging in some cases.
Speaker 0: Some of those CD sell cases.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: If they're actually going to follow through.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, even if they were, it's not just a dangerous situation.
Speaker 0: They will imply that they're angry.
Speaker 0: They might not actually throw a punch.
Speaker 0: But they will talk like they will without actually making an explicit threat.
Speaker 0: I've watched them shake down tourists in Bryant Park before.
Speaker 0: Like they edge into straight up mugging someone under threat of violence.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But the scams.
Speaker 1: Differ from those in two ways.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Well, there's two kinds of scams.
Speaker 1: And there's that.
Speaker 1: one kind of scam is where you're sort of making it instead of threatening a person.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You're appealing to their sympathies like, you know, I'm so poor.
Speaker 1: Please give me money.
Speaker 1: Appealing to their their kind heart to get them to cave.
Speaker 1: Whereas actually you're not poor at all.
Speaker 1: You're you're right.
Speaker 1: As soon as the day's over, you're going to get in your car and drive back.
Speaker 0: Of course, even then, you know, we're talking about this.
Speaker 0: I feel like that's not necessarily a scam either.
Speaker 0: That's social pressure because there's no transaction.
Speaker 0: It's not like like if you get tricked by someone like that who did not need that help.
Speaker 0: Well, you still got whatever.
Speaker 1: And I'm not.
Speaker 1: I don't want people to get confused and think the people pretend to be poor to, you know, panhandle our extreme minority.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But there there are more than zero of those people that they do exist.
Speaker 0: I guess I'm saying even a situation like that isn't necessarily really a scam because the person who gets a scam because they're lying.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: But they're not lying about the transaction as it is conducted with the scammy in that the person who got scammed feels like they did a good thing.
Speaker 0: So they got what they wanted out of the transaction.
Speaker 0: They couldn't be different for them.
Speaker 0: Doesn't matter what is for them.
Speaker 1: I guess so.
Speaker 1: But yeah, but I guess real scams like the one in your original story, that's a scam where the person was led to believe that they were investing and that their investment had big returns.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: When actually they were giving and not getting any investment.
Speaker 1: And these scans because someone made a fake website.
Speaker 1: I can make a website that has the number of billion dollars written on it.
Speaker 1: And if you believe that that's representing your investment.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, that's kind of.
Speaker 0: that's kind of what most Ponzi scams have been for all of time.
Speaker 0: That's what most pyramid scams are.
Speaker 0: They're all like that.
Speaker 0: But I guess that's the line.
Speaker 0: A scam unlike all these other forms of trickery and shenanigans and all this nonsense out there.
Speaker 0: Scams, I feel like are related to first degree fraudulent transactions like a Fyre Festival was a scam.
Speaker 0: There was no Fyre Festival.
Speaker 0: There never was a Fyre Festival.
Speaker 0: They were selling a fake thing from day one.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Or like, you know, what about.
Speaker 1: Well, then what do you say about like a fake medicine?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Someone takes the fake medicine.
Speaker 1: They're paying for basically nothing.
Speaker 1: They take it and then maybe they think it worked on them.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: I would argue selling someone a homeopathic remedy that makes a claim is a direct scam.
Speaker 1: But but according to your argument about the you gave money to the fake poor person, you know, where you felt good while they take the homeopathy and they feel good.
Speaker 0: I guess if you want to make a distinction there, a distinction could be that the advertisement of the effect is itself a scam because it cannot even be possible.
Speaker 0: It is absolutely fake.
Speaker 1: But the person experiences the effect.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Just like the person experienced the feeling of goodness of donating to a poor person, even though they donated to a not poor person.
Speaker 0: True.
Speaker 0: But the donating to the donation situation, at least that is a social effect as opposed to a medical effect that could be measured.
Speaker 1: I still say like if somebody is deceived into doing something that is detrimental to them.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Whether they know it or not.
Speaker 1: And beneficial to the deceiver.
Speaker 1: That's enough.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But I guess like I differentiate scams more on the method.
Speaker 1: If somehow my scam is so strong that you don't know you've been scammed even after you've been scammed and you never believe that you've been scammed for the rest of your life, even though you were, that's still a scam.
Speaker 0: Was it really, though?
Speaker 0: What if someone, Fyre Festival was exactly what they thought it was going to be and they had a grand old time.
Speaker 1: Then they still got scammed.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: I like to differentiate them more along the lines of what is the fundamental trigger or goad of the scam?
Speaker 0: Because there's scams that play on sympathy, like you've mentioned.
Speaker 0: Pretty sure one of our old forumites got scammed by someone who claimed to have a disease who didn't.
Speaker 0: And there was a whole thing long ago.
Speaker 0: One of those old divorced dad types.
Speaker 0: But then there is the scam that plays on greed.
Speaker 0: The scam of the too good to be true deal.
Speaker 1: That is the other kind that I was going to talk about, which is the kind in your story.
Speaker 0: Because those are the kind that I find the most interesting.
Speaker 0: because when you, if you, if you find, especially the ones that imply that what's going on is shady, like in the one Hemingway book, I think it was in the Sun Also Rises where they go to the horse track.
Speaker 0: Uh, might've been farewell to arms.
Speaker 0: I think it was Sun Also Rises.
Speaker 0: They go to the horse track.
Speaker 1: I've read both of those, but I don't remember.
Speaker 0: They go to a horse track and they see that one of the horses has been, has clearly been dyed black.
Speaker 0: Like it's not actually black.
Speaker 0: Like someone has died this horse.
Speaker 0: So they assume shenanigans are afoot.
Speaker 0: This must be a horse that's been like banned or something.
Speaker 0: There's a mob thing going on.
Speaker 0: So, and it's got really bad odds.
Speaker 0: So we're going to bet on this horse, assuming that there is someone else conducting a mob style betting scam related to that horse.
Speaker 0: And then the horse doesn't win.
Speaker 0: And then they're mad that they got scammed when really, no, you tried to scam.
Speaker 0: You tried to join the scam.
Speaker 0: You thought it was a scam and you joined it.
Speaker 0: Did you get, even if you got scammed, you're not a good person because you also tried to scam.
Speaker 0: So the kind of scam that plays on like, Hey, you want to do some insider trading and trick someone to buy a penny stock.
Speaker 0: that is a scam and it's immoral.
Speaker 0: But I also don't have sympathy for the victim because in that case, the victim basically said, yes, I want to commit a crime for money.
Speaker 1: It depends on the, the, you got to get into the details, right?
Speaker 1: Because the greed based scams can fall into a few categories, right?
Speaker 1: In your, in the story that started this whole episode, right?
Speaker 1: That person, was their motivation greed?
Speaker 0: Well, but it was great combined with concern for the family and also a phrase that gets misused where this is probably actually true here.
Speaker 1: Economic anxiety because everybody's poor also, but also just, you know, a lack of education, you know, incompetence, ignorance, whatever you want to call it, but which is not that person's fault, right?
Speaker 1: We're not going to blame a person themselves for not being smart enough, right?
Speaker 1: That person might be super smart about something else.
Speaker 1: That's not financial scams, right?
Speaker 1: Um, they're just not smart about financial scams.
Speaker 1: And therefore this, this, you know, it's like, I, I, you know, I, for all I know, I could have been scammed in some kind of scam.
Speaker 1: that I'm just not, I don't know about that kind of right.
Speaker 1: And it's like a whole world of scammery.
Speaker 1: I that's, I've, I've been completely clueless to this whole time current definitions.
Speaker 0: I think I've never been scams.
Speaker 1: I don't think you don't think so.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But that brings you to the next kind of scam, which is when there is an actual con.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Whereas the scam is so complex and so elaborate that even the intelligent, smart, you know, can see a scam coming person is still fooled by it.
Speaker 0: And the scammer gets access to your computer and then gaslights you and does things to set up the scam over the course of years for the big payout.
Speaker 0: Like that level of attention from, imagine if an entire global crime network has picked you to scam personally, or like the CIA is trying to rip you off.
Speaker 0: Like what are you going to be fucked no matter what in the end?
Speaker 1: They're going to get you some, you know, something so elaborate, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, usually you see this in movies, right?
Speaker 1: But it's like, there have been some rare instances in real life of like, you know, someone, you know, a lot of times it's a sexually related or romantically related where somebody will, you know, get themselves involved with someone else, uh, in a, uh, insincere manner.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: In order to get their monies, right.
Speaker 1: Or getting their will or whatever, things of that nature.
Speaker 1: Um, sometimes, you know, it's that it happens more than zero times and it's, it's, it's, it's a scam when it happens, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's tough because the, a lot of scare, there's a lot of scams out there.
Speaker 0: And I feel like one thing I read doing some research around this, like after reading this article this morning is there's some evidence that people who'd fall for one scam tend to fall for a lot of scams.
Speaker 0: Like there's a big divide between people who tend to fall for scams broadly and people who rarely or never fall for scams.
Speaker 1: The people who are vulnerable to scams gets like, you know, it's like, that's a hot, there's like a list.
Speaker 1: It's like, once you've fallen for one, then it's like, you'll never hear the end of it.
Speaker 1: It's the same thing.
Speaker 1: It's not only scams, but like the debt collectors.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, let's say you got some debts you can't pay and those, the original person you owed money to right.
Speaker 1: Sells your debt to a debt collector.
Speaker 1: They've rid themselves of that.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And now the debt collector is like, they have all these debts they've bought for pennies on the dollar.
Speaker 1: And if they can actually get any money at all for, you know, they're, they're making bank.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So they're basically like, they're ready for not basically none of those debts to actually collect on.
Speaker 1: Cause a lot of them are uncollectable.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But they think they can collect on enough of them to make, to get their money back from buying those heavily discounted debts.
Speaker 1: So if they find you, like you actually in your, in the United States, at least your best interest is to not answer and not pay.
Speaker 1: Because as soon as you pay one, they're like, ah, we got someone who actually pays off, tries to pay off their debts.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And then every debt collector will look for every debt that belongs to that person and start hounding them big time.
Speaker 1: Because that's a person who will actually try to get money, can get money and we'll try to pay debts.
Speaker 1: So let's get them to pay as many of the debts as we can.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's a person who can be scammed every scammer in the universe.
Speaker 1: They got a list of the people who are vulnerable to scams.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And they start hammering on those people.
Speaker 0: The worst one I read was about those multi-level marketing.
Speaker 1: Like in a gold rush.
Speaker 1: And everyone goes to the one place that has a, where they heard there was gold.
Speaker 0: Cause the multi-level marketing scams are extra insidious here because the kinds of people who fall for them, they will realize at the end of one that it was a scam and they were fucked and like admit to it.
Speaker 1: And then do another one.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: They'll go immediately to another one.
Speaker 0: Like every few months they move on to another scam.
Speaker 0: And it's, and the worst part is like reading the testimonials from like family and friends of these people, they are a hundred percent sure the next one's good and nothing anyone they know says will dissuade them from this course.
Speaker 0: And the scams are not only obvious to the rest of the family, they're the exact same scam every time.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, if I go to a video game and the boss has a weak spot and his eyeball, it's like the next time, do you see him?
Speaker 1: Does he have eyeball armor?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: Doesn't.
Speaker 1: So I guess eyeball is still the weak spot next time too.
Speaker 0: And I don't know what to do about that because you've, we got to protect people from scams.
Speaker 0: And I feel like the right way to go, education only seems to work up to a point.
Speaker 0: Like it feels, cause it's a case of what the MLM people, no amount of education stops them from falling for those scams.
Speaker 0: They'll keep falling for them.
Speaker 1: There are some people though who like can be educated and like might've fallen for an MLM or they will stop after one or once they realize, but then there's another class that will like, you know, fall for it repeatedly.
Speaker 0: And I feel like you have to be in all societal problems, like.
Speaker 0: this is a microcosm of bigger picture things.
Speaker 0: There's no panacea to any problem.
Speaker 0: You have to treat those differently.
Speaker 0: Like education campaigns are important because let's say you woke up from a coma today and you get back to your life.
Speaker 0: And you've never heard of cryptocurrency.
Speaker 0: And the first instance of Bitcoin you encounter is a Bitcoin person who's going to lie to you about it.
Speaker 0: And if you try to do research, a lot of people lie about Bitcoin being worth more than $0.
Speaker 0: So unless you were educated by society that Bitcoin is a scam, you could very easily fall for it, but the knowledge inoculates you.
Speaker 0: That is a separate concern from the people who will just fall for scams forever.
Speaker 0: And that's where we need to like criminalize multi-level marketing.
Speaker 0: Like that should not be allowed to exist as a form of business.
Speaker 0: We should not allow, well, you have to, even if we couldn't necessarily ban people practicing homeopathy like on themselves, we could definitely ban people selling it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Let me, you know, it depends if you're going to talk about, you know, what the law is in any particular country, but I think it's just the core thing that allows scams to proliferate, proliferate, whatever, proliferate.
Speaker 1: is this, you know, the philosophy of freedom, right?
Speaker 1: People want freedom.
Speaker 1: They don't want to be told what to do.
Speaker 1: They don't want, you know, a nanny state.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And what, you know, you hear those sorts of ideas around and to a certain extent, it's like, you know, you agree with them.
Speaker 1: It's like, hey, do you want them to force every single person who, you know, I don't know, go skiing?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, no more, no more dangerous hills skiing because people get hurt on them.
Speaker 0: Or case in point, nobody, almost no resort requires helmets, but most people wear them most of the time because they're a good idea.
Speaker 0: But sometimes I want to ski without a helmet because I'm doing something really easy or like biking to work on a city bike.
Speaker 0: I don't wear a helmet when I do that, but biking 50 miles, I wear a helmet.
Speaker 0: Is there risk there?
Speaker 0: Absolutely.
Speaker 0: But that's a risk.
Speaker 0: That's a risk I think an adult human can choose to take on.
Speaker 0: And I think where society needs to intervene and there's nanny state nonsense is usually just right wing people being mad about basic regulations that are good.
Speaker 0: We need societal intervention when dangers are not obvious to the average person.
Speaker 1: I think the difference is that the, not only are the danger is not obvious, right?
Speaker 1: These dangers are created by people, right?
Speaker 1: So I think what we need to do is you need to say, sure, you know, if you want to fall for a scam, that's legal.
Speaker 1: It's legal to fall for a scam.
Speaker 1: You're already victimizing yourself.
Speaker 1: There's no point in having society victimize you further, right?
Speaker 1: But if you are creating hazards, right?
Speaker 1: If you are creating a danger that will harm people, right?
Speaker 1: If I'm going to the ski mountain and I'm installing some extra hidden rocks and I'm putting some spikes on the trees and I'm putting a hidden, I don't know, pop up chainsaw under the snow.
Speaker 0: Libertarians will tell you that should be fine.
Speaker 0: And the market will decide because they're morons.
Speaker 1: Ah, no one's coming to Scott's chainsaw.
Speaker 1: Everybody goes, except super meat boy.
Speaker 1: He's the only one who wants to ski there.
Speaker 1: He skied down that mountain so many times.
Speaker 1: Hasn't hit the bottom yet though.
Speaker 1: Um, but yeah, it doesn't use the low either.
Speaker 0: I actually have a good example.
Speaker 0: So case in point, I don't know what they're called.
Speaker 0: So there's a stupid thing that dangerous people are doing on ski mountains and they're all mad because ski mountains have figured this out and are banning them and they're making a big crusade.
Speaker 0: There's all these, there's Reddit and nonsense about these things that people like, it's my right.
Speaker 0: And the ski mountains should not be able to stop me from doing this, what they're doing.
Speaker 0: So skis are long, right?
Speaker 0: Like you've seen skis.
Speaker 0: They're like, they're about as long as a person is tall in the modern era.
Speaker 0: They need to be long for a reason.
Speaker 0: Short skis are actually really dangerous to the people who use them.
Speaker 0: They're not dangerous to other people, but they're dangerous to you.
Speaker 0: Like you might think if you're bad at skiing, if you get those little short skis that are like a foot long, that you'll be able to turn easier.
Speaker 0: It'll be more fun.
Speaker 0: The reality is those things are just going to give you a spiral fracture.
Speaker 0: Like skis are long for a reason.
Speaker 0: Those things are dangerous and maybe they should be banned.
Speaker 1: I mean, I see people in the Olympics and they don't use short skis.
Speaker 0: Well, you can't go fast.
Speaker 1: They think that the short ones are not the right ones.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, most people who try those short skis don't realize how dangerous they are because they don't actually know how to ski that well.
Speaker 0: Or because they don't know how to ski that well, they feel like when skiing, they have trouble turning quickly and they feel like their long skis are awkward.
Speaker 0: Kind of like how if you've never driven a car before, a car feels really big and awkward until you internalize like how big it really is when you drive it.
Speaker 0: So they think they'll be easier to ski, but anyway, they're dangerous, but they're only dangerous to the person who uses them.
Speaker 0: So ski resorts generally allow them, but they are responsible for most of the injuries at ski resorts.
Speaker 0: But there's another kind of ski and these things are dangerous bullshit.
Speaker 0: They're basically ski boots that themselves are just skis.
Speaker 0: Like they just have a flat bottom and they're like as long as the boot.
Speaker 0: Like they're just a boot basically.
Speaker 0: And there's a very small but dedicated community of people who are obsessed with these things, but ski resorts have said that is too far.
Speaker 0: Those are likely to cause uncontrolled falling situations, which are some of the most dangerous possible things in the ski resort.
Speaker 0: And unlike the little short skis where you're really only a danger to yourself, these little ski boot things, you're a danger to everyone else on the mountain that you're going to hit when you slide down the entire mountain because those things don't work.
Speaker 0: So the ski resorts have banned those because they're a danger to you and other people.
Speaker 0: They haven't banned the short skis because they're really only a danger to you.
Speaker 0: I thought that was an interesting line and I hate the people who are using these boot skis because there is nothing good about them and I found a whole bunch of YouTube shorts of people basically trying to do a gotcha on the cops who are kicking them off of ski resorts after they got trespassed when the ski resort said you can't ride our ski lift with those things, they're dangerous.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess the analogy I would make for a scammer is imagine someone has a big long stick and they're holding it over their shoulders horizontally and they walk down the road.
Speaker 1: It's like most people will see that stick and duck under the stick and not get hit as this person walks down the sidewalk.
Speaker 1: But someone might not be paying attention, someone might not be able to see, somebody might just be a doofus, I don't know.
Speaker 1: But some people are going to get hit in the head by this big wide stick.
Speaker 1: Someone's walking down the road carrying it head level.
Speaker 1: And it's like, hey, it's not the fault of any of the people who got hit in the head.
Speaker 1: Even if someone gets hit the next time and the next time, every single time a stick person comes walking down the street, the same person keeps getting hit by it.
Speaker 1: They haven't learned their lesson.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: The stick person who's carrying the stick that way shouldn't be doing that.
Speaker 1: They're creating a dangerous situation.
Speaker 1: Even if I duck under it every single time and it never hits me even once, that's besides the point.
Speaker 1: When you're trying to scam people, you're creating a danger.
Speaker 1: You're attempting to harm others, so go fuck yourself.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So, I don't know how to prevent people who fall for scams from falling for scams, but the best I can do is give you, the listener, advice and maybe you won't fall for a scam, but it really comes down to, if something seems too good to be true, it definitely is.
Speaker 0: That is how almost all scams are.
Speaker 0: If it is hard to make money and it's hard to find a job that pays a lot and you see a job posting that seems like it pays a lot lot and doesn't require any particular skills, that's a scam.
Speaker 0: 100% that's a scam.
Speaker 0: If there were jobs that paid you $4,000 a week and they don't have any requirements, guess what I'd be doing?
Speaker 1: I think that if someone's a Geek Nights listener, I'm going to trust you're smart.
Speaker 1: You're probably not falling for scams on your own.
Speaker 1: You're probably hip to the internet and you know how to avoid scams on your own.
Speaker 1: But the things that I think are relevant to a Geek Nights listener are A, you're going to get old and there may reach a point in your life where no matter how smart you are now, you are no longer capable of avoiding scams in your old age.
Speaker 1: Because the world would be even more different than it is now and your mental faculties may or may not fade depending on your circumstances.
Speaker 1: And what do you do now to prevent yourself from getting scammed in the future?
Speaker 1: is you just have to put in financial planning in place so that no one can loot you no matter how foolish you become.
Speaker 1: And the second thing you have to do is that even if you are wise and avoid scams, there are people in your life that you care about who may not be so wise and you need to protect them from scams.
Speaker 1: And if all your efforts cannot protect them from scams, what you need to do is you simply basically need to, as much as it may discomfort you, you need to basically make sure that somebody close to you falling for scams doesn't hurt you.
Speaker 0: Put your own mask on first before you put someone else's mask on in a plane that is depressurized.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So like let's say your parent is aging and they reach the point where they're, you know, you see them going to fall for scams, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, well, A, try to educate them obviously, right?
Speaker 1: If they can't, right, you're going to need to resort to like, you know, measures like, hey, maybe they shouldn't be allowed to control their own monies anymore if they're so vulnerable to scam.
Speaker 1: And if you somehow can't do that, right, you need to just, you've done all that you can do to protect them from themselves and getting scammed.
Speaker 1: And there's no more that you can do.
Speaker 0: Two of the listener in the stream talked about how they got scammed in various ways.
Speaker 0: And a third listener's parents are currently in the process of being scammed and they don't know what to do.
Speaker 0: It's a widespread problem.
Speaker 1: That's a shame.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: I think if you can't educate them and they can't learn their lesson and you can't protect them from themselves using any available legal means.
Speaker 0: I mean, I had a friend in high school who fell for the Amway scam and I hate to say it, I had to befriend them.
Speaker 0: Like I could not interact with them anymore.
Speaker 0: They were gone and there was nothing I could do about it.
Speaker 1: It's like, it sucks big time, especially if it's like, you know, like the listener, right, where your parents are being scammed.
Speaker 1: They're like, it sucks big time.
Speaker 1: But once you've done all you can do, you just have to protect yourself, right?
Speaker 1: If the person being scammed comes and asks you for money, it's like, no, absolutely.
Speaker 1: You bought a bunch of MLM stuff and you're trying to sell it to me.
Speaker 1: No, right.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to be a part of it.
Speaker 1: And if you keep coming after me for it, it's like, I have no choice but to stop being in contact with you.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like if it gets that bad and no amount of education, if all the other measures do not work, then that's like, you know, it's really sad.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: That basically some strange scammer person could like effectively steal away like people that you cared about from your life.
Speaker 1: But there's no there's no other option.
Speaker 1: that I'm aware of.
Speaker 0: Because there's still that there's still the bad guy, like they are the one, the scammer who is causing the moral hazard in this case.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know,
Speaker 0: in terms of not getting
Speaker 1: not a lot you can do once, you know, especially if you don't, it's like you could try to spend money to go and like, you know, what, find the scammer and, you know, hire what, investigators or who knows what to try and go fight the scammer or something.
Speaker 1: But it's like, now you're losing money.
Speaker 0: Oh, no.
Speaker 0: One of the listeners even someone they know someone who fell for the Amway scam.
Speaker 0: And it got to the point in high school where even the teachers were like, kid, it's a scam.
Speaker 0: It's not a job.
Speaker 0: You got to guess it didn't work.
Speaker 0: That's the.
Speaker 0: that's the thing that I have no idea how to help with is, is there anything you can do to protect someone else who is scam vulnerable just broadly, like the kind of person who moves from scam to scam to scam?
Speaker 0: I feel like there's literally nothing you can do.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, if we knew if we knew something you could do right, there would be a lot less scammers out there already because people would be doing that thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like if there was an answer, the problem would would be gone.
Speaker 0: If there was a it's like if there were jobs that paid four thousand dollars a week to do nothing from home with a high school diploma, everyone would have that job.
Speaker 1: I think that's actually a good way to think about.
Speaker 1: it is like if you how do you know something is too good to be true?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like be like, you know, say, you know how the world is as long as you're I guess if you're your image of how the world is, is wrong, then you're already in a bad place.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But you're already you know, you're going to be in a weird church chugging homeopathy from your Amway stock if you're like that.
Speaker 1: But as long as your impression of how the world is is close to correct and you look at something and you say, would the world be different than it is if that were true?
Speaker 0: Why hasn't anyone else invested in this weird penny stock?
Speaker 0: How come how come my new friend on the Internet has told me and no one else about this opportunity?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like that sort of thing is like, would the world make it?
Speaker 1: Does this make sense within the greater context of reality?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: And that's how.
Speaker 0: how are there people if there are jobs that pay four thousand dollars a week for no skills?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 1: If this is just a matter of me being lucky, why is it me that's lucky?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It could have been anybody.
Speaker 1: Why is it me?
Speaker 0: And I guess if you treat the world that way and have a relatively accurate view of the world, then the odds of you missing out on a good opportunity are still basically zero because there aren't really opportunities like that.
Speaker 0: It's in general.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowclue.com for show notes, discussion, links and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 0: Tuesdays, gaming and games.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are animation and comics.
Speaker 0: Thursdays are arbitrary and indiscriminate.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 international license.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of Geek Nights are Alan Joyce, Link Eiji, Jarett, Lily Tenebrae, Case Care, Makes the Music, Chris, Dodd, Christopher Orr, Clinton Walton, M, Def, Mac, Finn, Joel Hayes, Penny Reimer, Rebecca Dunn, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Harl, a ton of people who give like a dollar and a ton of people who give nothing at all just to get access to that sweet RSS feed.
Speaker 0: Yeah?
Speaker 0: Keep opening requests, comments, thoughts about the website.
Speaker 0: We plan to continue to invest into it heavily now that we've gotten the baseline live and we're going to start working on additional syndication from there.
Speaker 0: So otherwise, tonight there's late hockey and I leave you simply with... Tonight on Unsolved Mysteries.
Speaker 0: Two families move into an idyllic suburb only to discover that their homes lie on top of an abandoned graveyard.
Speaker 0: Soon they are tormented by strange phenomena and threatening apparitions and are driven into a state of complete terror.
Speaker 0: Are the spirits of the dead seeking vengeance on the living for the desecration of their graves?