Rym: Hey, it's Tuesday, November 10th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott over Skype, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We actually played some amorphic us.
Rym: We talked about the dungeons and dragons online.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Left 4 Dead's coming.
Scott: oh Yeah, you know what actually.
Scott: I had played the demo on the piece.
Rym: I'm avoiding playing the demo I pre-loaded, but I'm not playing the demo.
Rym: There's no reason not to play you know.
Rym: I'm not playing the demo I don't have time.
Rym: I'm doing other stuff.
Rym: I'm just gonna have this like glorious day when the game actually comes out.
Scott: It's like a 30-second demo And it doesn't actually have like.
Scott: remember how the first the original like.
Scott: usually when you play Left 4 Dead campaign There's like that.
Scott: You know you it builds up to like a climax.
Scott: Yeah, this is like.
Scott: it builds up to like a sort of okay.
Scott: You pulled the switch moment, and that's it.
Rym: well cuz they don't even need it.
Rym: This is not a demo that's going to sell the game.
Rym: No one's going to buy the game.
Rym: who wasn't going to otherwise?
Rym: with the demo the demo is just.
Rym: Yeah, good job captain captain sky.
Rym: I'm not cutting this out so go on.
Scott: So I'm playing.
Scott: I played the demo on the PC But I downloading the demo on the 360 just because you know it's surprising like I don't realize it But like how many you know you see people making like cake is a lie jokes.
Scott: a lot of those people played that Wrong machine.
Scott: good.
Rym: God.
Rym: so one of my co-workers today, right he comes into our little office because I have like a corner office now like actually a nice corner office with windows and Of course they look out at like 41st Street.
Rym: It's like second place But he comes in.
Rym: he's like man.
Rym: I was playing this game.
Rym: You got it.
Rym: You guys got to try it.
Rym: It's called Portal and so It's like so it's about this this person right and you're like wake up in a lab And you have this gun that shoots two portals and you got to bust your way out.
Rym: And there's this funny computer voice, and there's all this stuff written on the walls.
Rym: You're supposed to get cake at the end, but the cake is a lie And I just looked at him the whole time.
Rym: all you remind me of that penny arcade where Gabe's like man.
Rym: I just found this game counter-strike.
Rym: There's some kind of map.
Rym: What is it?
Rym: dust?
Rym: Dusker.
Rym: But I was and he's like yeah, I'm playing on my xbox right now.
Rym: It's totally awesome.
Rym: and even the smart co-workers who play video games they are.
Rym: They all play Left 4 Dead on the stupid Xbox, they're like you want to play it.
Rym: I'm like on the Xbox.
Rym: is that even that even really a game?
Scott: Yeah, I'm gonna try the demo on the Xbox.
Scott: of course I've already got it on the PC to preload it But I'll try to Xbox one and see how it goes.
Scott: you know just to see what the experience is of these that these other people are having.
Scott: But yeah, if something's on Steam.
Scott: Why would you ever I mean the only games?
Scott: I would get on the Xbox are either a games not available on Steam or B Games that are optimally played with game pads on a large screen like a castle crashers that you might as well.
Scott: You know what I wish.
Scott: that shrine game was on the Xbox instead of on the PC.
Scott: glad I'm glad I didn't buy it on the PC yet cuz I'm still holding out Hope that it shows up on something else.
Rym: Yeah, like bionic commando would have been good on the Xbox had I had an Xbox.
Scott: actually this X this new excite game just came out for the Wii and But I'm not buying it yet cuz I'm not buying anything cuz I have no monies.
Rym: ah No monies.
Rym: I have plenty of monies.
Scott: You want to buy me some excite bike?
Rym: not particularly.
Rym: I'm trying to figure out what to do with my monies other than do everything I want to do because I Don't want to know by the apartment directly under my apartment on this show.
Rym: lately We've been talking a lot about all this meta stuff before the show.
Rym: I'm trying to at least hold off a little bit because like Scott's got his apartment all worked out.
Rym: It's nice, but Dude, I'm trying to buy a house from seems to have skipped town and things are getting crazy And I think I'm gonna have to pay.
Rym: No, I'm not.
Rym: the bank doesn't own it yet.
Rym: I it's so complicated.
Rym: What's going on?
Rym: Apparently the bank wants to sell it to me desperately,
Scott: but they
Rym: they
Scott: can't
Rym: until they Foreclose on the dude who disappeared but for closing cost so much money And is such a pain in the ass and it's gonna take so long That the banks like yeah, I don't know what to do and my lawyers like I don't know what to do And I'm like damn
Scott: it after the guy.
Rym: so get this.
Rym: I started looking at other houses And you just take the house like yoink guys not here abandonment yoink No, it takes a while.
Rym: foreclosure takes a long time.
Rym: remember our friends landlords and everyone talking about a heart.
Rym: It is to actually evict someone.
Rym: So even worse I find like five other houses that are even nicer than this one and a few from McMansions And they're all you know pretty reasonably priced like under 500 K. So I go to the realtor, and I'm like yeah, can I see these four houses, and she's like.
Rym: One of those is an abandoned foreclosure.
Rym: the other three are short sales that are pretty much in the same boat that the house you're trying to buy now is.
Rym: I'm like are there any non foreclosure short sale houses in Beacon, and she's like Not really Except this one everyone who can afford their houses just living in it going.
Rym: ah Pretty much yeah because the markets so bad that no one said
Scott: about those houses that we looked at before like the one around the Corner or the one that just like the one around the corner Oh, yeah,
Rym: all the all the crazy man like the big McMansions are still for sale.
Rym: But while as much as I'd like to live in one of those things.
Scott: I can't really justify Just two people living in like a 6,000 square foot house And while I can you see someone posted in the forum of someone that Hampton's mansion The most that's like the most like expansive residential property in the country.
Scott: I think or perhaps the world I forget.
Rym: yeah I don't know what to do at this time.
Rym: you owns it Because I'll hold on to my bonuses are but yeah, so I'm still in this house right now.
Scott: So so back in the day there was this Warcraft 3 mod.
Scott: you know my brother actually played a lot of Warcraft 3.
Scott: I didn't but I watched him a bit You know and never good at Warcraft 3.
Scott: I was never good at any.
Scott: RTS is beyond Warcraft 1.
Rym: yeah You saying never good is kind of a misnomer because that's like saying I was never good at the bagpipes.
Rym: You you were terrible at RTS is I've seen you play.
Scott: RTS is Yeah, I suck so.
Scott: But Warcraft 3 had an expansive mod community and one of the most popular mods was what people called dota Which is defense of the ancients.
Rym: it was basically a tower defense game.
Scott: Well, it was somewhat of a tower defense game But not really because you didn't actually like build the towers or control the towers.
Scott: what you did is you controlled one guy.
Scott: It was like you're playing an RTS, but you're one guy, but that one guy has a lot of different stuff You can do.
Scott: you know.
Scott: it's like imagine.
Scott: You know it's it's sort of like member in command and conquer.
Scott: It was the Tanya unit that could like you know is that's the super commando chick that was I believe red alert.
Scott: Yeah, she was totally awesome right.
Rym: Yeah, that was.
Rym: I remember when rental her came out.
Rym: I was like man.
Rym: this game was kind of new school or in Starcraft.
Scott: There was the ghost unit right so You could.
Scott: it was basically Defense of the ancients is basically there's a tower defense game going on right But you are just one guy and the tower defense game is automatic And you got to level up this guy and also attack the other.
Scott: you know properly And this one guy can do like ten times as more things and is like way more powerful than that Tanya unit.
Scott: You know you're controlling it in an RTS fashion It's you know.
Scott: you attack retreat attack the left attack on the right.
Scott: use this ability use that ability You know buy this item you know that sort of thing.
Scott: so That game was pretty popular back in the day and the guys who made it have a new game come in called towers of Neuwirth.
Scott: Neuwirth, I don't know how it's supposed to be pronounced, but it's People in the forum giving out the demo keys or the beta keys their beta keys.
Scott: yeah I got one I played it last night, and I'm sort of unsure about this game.
Scott: It's like okay It is a game of leveling up And I can see with my eyeballs some rock-paper-scissors elements to it And it's it's incredibly suspicious like ah you could well remember all games have those elements.
Scott: I mean you look at this game on the surface from our perspective, and you're like This is not looking like a good game to me.
Scott: This is look at every hallmark of a bad game, right?
Scott: But I actually played it and I played it a couple times and learned how to play and learned how it works And it was actually like an incredibly at least that instance of playing was incredibly good.
Scott: like at first We were getting crushed it was two versus two We were getting crushed and then somehow we like pulled it out in the end in dramatic fashion.
Scott: It was incredibly close to me had a big comeback, and it was like whoa Something going on in this game even though it has all these hallmarks of bad games.
Scott: Well, remember good game happened.
Rym: I don't know where I can remember.
Rym: also even Ostensibly bad games can be good in the sense that they're made in such a way that they're fun regardless of how bad they actually Are.
Scott: I mean no so I'm gonna.
Scott: I'm gonna play it a few more times to be sure probably beginning after when we're done with this show.
Scott: but if you if you are interested in this kind of game you should come to the forum dot front recruiter calm or Elsewhere and you should get beta keys for heroes of net worth.
Scott: and then if you pay $30 only $30 They you can basically get the full game.
Rym: You know with a pre-order God, so if you pre-purchase Left 4 Dead 2, you know you get.
Rym: You get the hat that the military guy wore in the original Left 4 Dead Mm-hmm.
Scott: well you were the one who pre-purchases you get the hat or do I?
Rym: I was.
Rym: I did not yet finish that sentence.
Rym: you get the hat for your Team Fortress 2 guy.
Rym: Get a special hat in Team Fortress 2 So they're not mailing you a hat.
Rym: so if I go play Team Fortress 2 right now I can put on that hat and wear it around the game while I'm playing.
Scott: Who gives a shit that that?
Rym: I have a feeling that I don't know.
Rym: I'm worried because they've already gotten so much leveling and so much achievement like game affecting stuff in Team Fortress 2 and I'm worried that in the long run Any like valve games are gonna start having this stuff all over the place.
Scott: I think that the world has realized something right.
Scott: you know how we look at things like fake medicine.
Scott: We're like ah these assholes.
Scott: They're making all this money off fake medicine those bastards.
Scott: They can go to hell and die right, but look at what's going on like like Zynga and valve and World of Warcraft And all these other companies out there.
Scott: There are a lot of them.
Scott: Those aren't even the worst offenders right and You know a guy online right.
Scott: they're basically taking people's money in exchange for nothing Just like a hat a virtual hat on the Xbox.
Scott: right there was a thing I could have gotten like a Giants New York Giants You know Jersey for my avatar, but they wanted to charge me real American dollars for that.
Scott: so I'm like fuck.
Scott: no Why would I spend money on that if it was free sure but at the same time it were like even one penny is not worth It.
Scott: yet all these people are making money by selling nothing.
Scott: I think Either a we have to decide that that's morally offensive Almost as morally offensive as fake medicine and that we shouldn't do it.
Rym: I don't think that's because it's definitely be be.
Scott: we should start selling fake shit So we can get some fucking money now.
Rym: the problem with that is that we're getting very close I think to a gluts and then there's going to be a decline.
Scott: you think there's gonna be a decline.
Scott: You don't think that using basic psychology to just get people to fork over real money for virtual goods will always work Not always in a vacuum because it's not just usually most of the people who buy this stuff.
Rym: They get it work better in the foreseeable future.
Rym: They get it within The context of some other thing that they're paying for that they actually for whatever reason enjoy.
Rym: now That might be a thing.
Scott: you have to make the thing that they enjoy and then sell them the virtual goods in it.
Scott: That's that's how it works.
Rym: But not only that.
Rym: some people only Actually, I mean some people do it for the prestige like the people had those badges in NS back in the day.
Rym: the people who?
Rym: Get this tf2 hat or whatever.
Scott: You can use the black armor in all the time.
Rym: Thing is I would have paid the $40 anyway because that is basically.
Rym: I remember when I donated money to Obama's primary.
Scott: Can you want to hear a surprise a somewhat surprising but also not surprising thing?
Scott: Something like 95% old news and it's two pre-orders are 40 or the $40 one and almost nobody bought the $20 one.
Rym: But kind of like how I've donated money to Obama's primary just because it was like alright I'm basically putting my money in the lottery that maybe something cool will happen.
Rym: It was the same thing with NS - it's like alright my extra $20.
Scott: Yeah, how did that work out for you?
Scott: Yeah, yeah, but but Anything cool happen.
Rym: Oh, yes, it's happening.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Anyway, I don't want to get into politics.
Rym: Mr.
Rym: Doesn't pay attention doesn't know anything about what's going on in the world at all.
Rym: But that aside aren't exactly paying my extra $20 to NS is basically me saying look If there's even a tiny chance of NS to happening I have to give the money to make sure that that chance goes up by a tiny percent.
Scott: Yeah, but I'm you know, the black armor part is yeah.
Rym: Well, the black armor was just a nice thing.
Rym: If it had been say, I don't know the
Scott: black armor is nice But the at the team fortress hat is not nice
Rym: because the team I don't care about Team Fortress 2 is not going to be made better or worse by that and left 4 dead is coming out Regardless of whether or not I get that hat.
Scott: So, you know what they should have done is they should have let you use Team Fortress 2 guys in left 4 dead.
Scott: So it's like I'll pick Engineer and play left 4 dead and set up a turn.
Scott: Oh my god, I might say funny things that they always do.
Rym: I might pay a small amount of money.
Rym: We just make that a mod dude, yeah.
Scott: But the Team Fortress Pick four of them and put them in left 4 dead and don't change anything left 4 dead except for that.
Rym: But I want to even have their powers and just have heavy weapons guys standing there.
Scott: I'm saying it'll be exactly the same as you'll be.
Scott: it'll feel like you're playing Team Fortress 2 only the map and the Objectives and the bad guys will be.
Scott: you know, left 4 dead.
Scott: So it'd be like, you know, oh it's a witch Thing is you need some voice acting cuz you need like the heavy to be like Oh which do not go scare her That's the best you could do.
Scott: So maybe she's news.
Rym: so Super Mario Brothers we it's coming out, you know, I know it's coming out because Out for a while and like all the news is talking about how it's gonna know.
Scott: But I mean I walked past the Nintendo store the other day.
Scott: It was just all the windows had a gigantic Mario in them like it was just the craziest Mario setup ever.
Rym: It was just well It's gonna have the.
Rym: it's in that red case and they make it.
Rym: a lot of people are making a big deal about the red Case and Reggie was going on and on about it.
Rym: This game is gonna sell more than modern warfare.
Scott: It's gonna be a tough.
Scott: It's gonna be a close race.
Scott: I think yeah How about that modern warfare game?
Scott: Like I never I barely even heard of that game and then suddenly I just keep seeing people talk about it a little bit.
Scott: Well, why is exploded suddenly?
Scott: It's like it's fucking like taking over the world.
Rym: I've I knew I saw it on the horizon for a long time because there was all this weird meta news about it And I thought people to go in mw2 and I was like is mech warrior to make it a comeback?
Rym: Yeah, but that kind of culminated in the fact that if you buy the bonus box, it comes with a bust of some dudes face and an actual night-vision goggles set like for real.
Rym: like actually how much is that set there?
Rym: Uh, Over a hundred and fifty dollars.
Scott: How much is night vision goggle?
Rym: I have no idea but it's only ninety dollars more than buying the game by itself.
Rym: and it comes with this guy's face and Night vision goggles.
Rym: and I watched a video.
Rym: They are well I watched.
Rym: the thing is they're kind of ungainly but I watched bleep-bloop of all people they had.
Rym: They didn't review the game.
Rym: They're like whatever on the game, but they reviewed the night vision goggles And he like goes into the closet and he's like I see a broom and stuff.
Rym: they work.
Rym: Yeah, so night vision goggles?
Scott: I don't.
Rym: even the bust of the guy's head is like.
Rym: I think it's to hold the night vision goggles when you're not wearing them.
Rym: Oh That makes sense, but it's kind of a silly mw2.
Scott: This is a Call of Duty game, right?
Rym: Yeah It's like the sequel to mw1, which was Call of Duty 4.
Rym: Anyway, those games were so under my radar that I basically I know it's so weird.
Scott: It's like everyone was playing quake Counter-Strike, you know tribes all those unreal tournament right all these.
Scott: the real FPS is Yeah, I said it and then it's sort of like they started coming out with these.
Scott: war FPS is for like the PlayStation 1 era You know, they came up with a Call of Duty or what were some of the other ones like men at war I don't even know.
Scott: just make it up name man.
Scott: It was like it seemed.
Scott: Yeah It seemed like there were a whole bunch of like just generic war FPS's that were coming out of the PlayStation.
Scott: the PlayStation 2.
Rym: does a Wolfenstein count Castle Einstein?
Scott: No, it's a war.
Scott: Yeah, I guess you know the Xbox 360 This is.
Scott: they kept coming out with a whole bunch of these generic war FPS's one after the other and he just kept coming out with them and coming out with them and I don't recall them really ever being that Popular like you didn't see you know, I didn't see a lot of people playing them or talking about him.
Scott: but it's like just more recently like they've just like the popularity of these things is going like Like like exponentially up and it's like where the hell did these things come from?
Scott: It's like, you know, it's at all like the halo people switch over to them or something.
Scott: It's like, I don't know.
Rym: But the thing about this is one I wonder what's gonna happen to release dates in the future because Apparently GameStop just started selling the game early.
Scott: I think they just said that they said that it was on purpose.
Rym: They know they admitted straight up.
Rym: They said it was on purpose and they talked to Activision about it.
Rym: and they were doing it because other Retailers in the same areas had already started selling it earlier.
Scott: Yeah, well, I think that's because if you're a tiny retailer, right?
Scott: Like let's say your dragon's dead, you know You could order like five copies of it.
Scott: sell them early.
Scott: Get some business, you know, not only that if I were them I would not have otherwise got.
Rym: I would sell them early For more money.
Rym: Oh, of course, I'd be like extra 50 bucks.
Rym: get it today.
Scott: Yeah, of course, they would totally do that.
Rym: But the thing is so.
Rym: I think these things only matter now for physical media distribution.
Rym: any I mean in Steam left for dead just activates at the same time for everyone in the world at the same time and that's it.
Rym: There's none of this BS.
Scott: No, but I think what it is is that with physical media distribution Basically, you just have to accept the fact that if you send product to a retailer They can sell it immediately and it's only like the very large and punishable Retailers like Best Buy that you're actually going to be able to like put a leash on them and force them to do what you
Rym: know.
Rym: No, no, no.
Rym: I think there's another problem there.
Rym: the bigger a retailer is for your business the more clout they have to say Yeah, we sold it early.
Rym: What you're not gonna ship us your next game Right.
Scott: No.
Scott: Well, yeah, it depends on what you're selling right.
Scott: cuz look with Apple It's the exact opposite.
Scott: Apple basically says if you sell iPods, you will not discount them one penny.
Scott: In fact, you will not discount any Apple product even one penny ever under any circumstances even when they're doing like clearance.
Scott: You know, we're going out of business at Circuit City.
Scott: The iPods are the same price because if you you know Apple has everyone by the goddamn balls.
Scott: So, you know, it just depends on who you are how much you can push them around or not.
Rym: but look we're getting into the point to where until the collapse of physical media is complete and At that point Walmart's gonna be pretty much the sole retailer of anything like that.
Scott: GameStop I think still has enough cloud to say fuck you Yeah, but I think also in a way it's sort of like You know GameStop does have the clout because you know GameStop makes a lot of money for now game.
Scott: But at the same time right GameStop also really needed it cuz it's like they're losing to.
Scott: you know Amazon and there's a lot of pressure coming down on them.
Rym: Well at this by the say at the same time give them a slight advantage.
Rym: at the same time yet again GameStop because they're basically pawn shops.
Rym: at this point They don't even need the first runs anymore.
Rym: people will buy stuff on Amazon Anyway, and they should just if they ever get new stuff sell it early because that's the only way they'll sell it and just give the big flying finger to everyone.
Rym: and When people buy stuff on Amazon, they'll sell it back to GameStop.
Rym: But then they can sell it in the cycle because Amazon's doing sellbacks now.
Scott: So it's like we'll see.
Rym: the thing is it's game design for that?
Scott: No Amazon sellback best buy was starting to do.
Scott: use games in some places to Amazon.
Rym: sellback only works for the people with credit cards.
Rym: the Primary demographic of sellbacks is punk kids with no credit card.
Rym: Once we get to the point of punk kids having a credit card equivalent Entire spheres of the economy will disappear overnight.
Scott: Yeah, I remember one gigantic.
Scott: You know kids are.
Scott: the major limitation of kids buying things is not that they are completely broke because they got money.
Scott: They don't have a lot but they got money.
Scott: They got enough to buy a video game in once in a while, right?
Scott: The thing is is a they don't have a credit card and B They don't have a car.
Scott: So even they can't buy anything unless it's in a physical store or their parents buy it for them Which is ha ha ha right not gonna happen.
Scott: And B even if they got the money and they want to spend it They have to wait for their parents to take them to the store.
Scott: Even today in this modern world unless your parents are totally awesome, you know, so Even if you give your kid one of those kids credit cards that I discovered You know, it's like It's not enough.
Scott: You know, they got it.
Scott: They got to be able to get there to get the stuff or whatever.
Rym: Okay update here the.
Rym: I did some investigation I found another link a better link that I'll use for my news link.
Rym: the night-vision goggles that come with the game are made by and suspiciously similar to The same company that makes some crappy like I clops toy.
Rym: That's 50 bucks at Toys R Us And that I clops toy is a night-vision goggle thing Yep, and I was looking online for like 200 bucks.
Rym: You can get actual like Soviet military grade.
Scott: I like night-vision But I don't want shitty Soviet ones.
Rym: I want yeah Us ones or something for under five hundred for under five hundred dollars.
Rym: You can get badass night vision.
Scott: I want the cut.
Scott: I want the counter-strike kind of one.
Scott: So everything's green.
Rym: They're all like that because green is the color that's the most sensitive to our eyes.
Scott: Basically very good.
Rym: Yes Yes, you can also detect if someone's using night vision pretty easily because they just at least this kind of night vision is a use a flashbang and they go.
Rym: No Because this is the kind that illuminates the area with IR then has a camera.
Rym: So if you just if you just look for IR, you'll see like this basically a flashlight coming out of the dude's face.
Rym: You basically have to.
Rym: there's either active night vision or there's passive night vision a passive night vision as far as I know is not That great because you basically have to rely on the extent light In some form Doesn't matter because the most militaries in the world people don't even have the Toys R Us night vision.
Rym: Sadly that's very true.
Scott: Yeah, very sad.
Rym: Okay, but this modern warfare thing really look what's happening here.
Rym: I've realized it.
Rym: all These kids who grew up playing the console FPS is are going through the same evolution that the computer FPS is went through.
Rym: we started with you know after doom and Crappy Wolfenstein 3d after he got past the initial steps.
Rym: What was popular at first?
Rym: It was the FPS is that were like quake deathmatch II kind of stuff like the original halo like that's our like golden eye that kind of stuff that they were playing.
Rym: and Then as it moved on they started getting more and more about the series business war realistic kind of things.
Rym: You know the all these World War two, whatever.
Rym: that's basically when we found out about action quake and counter-strike.
Rym: and I guess the next step is they're gonna move into the Tribe Z area.
Scott: Yeah, I don't see that happening because the tribe Z area games are far too complex to even do with the expo.
Rym: I'll have to because while the games are pretty bad all things considered still just because of the you know, the sheer limitation of the controllers Eventually, these kids are gonna realize the limitations and get sick of playing on the console.
Rym: One would hope I got a lot of confidence.
Rym: That's the only hope I've got left because NS two And a little bit of leopard ed 2 are some of the last games on the horizon that I care about at all.
Scott: I Think we'll be alright Enough games for us to play and enough people playing them that we will be safe.
Rym: It's a poor simulacrum, but there's really.
Rym: there's nothing that can replace tribes - No, not really.
Rym: Nothing not even tribes - it's too much of a pain in the ass to play it anywhere.
Scott: Yeah, there is a. there's a remake of mech warrior 2 out there that I'm gonna The real mw2.
Rym: Yeah But anyway things of the day.
Rym: so Emily and Alex work from use games and we had the trailer for their new game guns vicarous and It's finally actually out.
Rym: So it's my thing of the day for one.
Rym: You can just buy it and play the demo but - I bitched to Alex because there was a Feature that was sorely lacking.
Rym: that only as far as I can tell me and Scott Johnson care about.
Scott: A lot of people care about the inverted mouse.
Rym: So I went I got I played the demo and I was like Alex.
Rym: There's no inverted mouse.
Rym: I can't buy this game.
Rym: and Alex was like damn it.
Rym: And then two days later He's like I coded you stupid inverted mouse and Scott Johnson You know if checkbox negative one.
Rym: Yeah, you had to do a little bit.
Rym: It was more than it wasn't trivial.
Scott: It's it's not hard.
Rym: No, it's not hard and non-trivial or two entirely different things.
Rym: Anyway, but he did it the games like eight bucks and I bought it because it was fun and It's really hard.
Rym: Yeah, well then you got to play it with actual other people.
Scott: If you try to play it alone, you're only gonna beat one level.
Rym: Yeah, if you need other people to get more than one level but playing it with other people like with some voice chat I'm feeling this Confluence like it's a proof of concept for a kind of game.
Rym: Like if you go to the next step with this game It's like you've got almost a tower.
Scott: If I was them what I would do is I would work on a new game But I would keep polishing this one because with enough polish it could it could be something good.
Scott: It's so close to like you as polish also gives you know more incentive for people to pay for it as well.
Rym: Cuz yeah knowing that they're gonna get more polish in the future You know, it's just I'll admit like honestly and this isn't just me saying it because you know We know the people who made the game.
Rym: It's different from a lot of games out there and anything That's different makes me very happy unless it's different in a bad way Mm-hmm.
Scott: Yeah, it definitely is unique.
Scott: All right, so there's a Sun micro systems, you know, they do a lot of open source stuff actually a ton of it.
Scott: Yeah one one thing that they did Ways back that I forgot the name of then remember the name of that forgot the name of then remember the name of then lost Then found again is the thing called project dark star.
Scott: and basically Sun made this Server, you know, it's it's.
Scott: it's just sort of a server that you can use as a server for any multiplayer online game.
Scott: So if you want to make a multiplayer online game and need a server you can use project dark star and it's like, you know Making an MMO use this, you know making a counter-strike.
Scott: use this and it's you know.
Scott: I never actually used it.
Scott: But what I have found here is a Lab 55 62 project snowman developing a 3d multiplayer game using project dark star and this is a 7-step tutorial that from start to finish you will make a multiplayer online game in Pro in project dark star.
Scott: so and it's all free stuff here.
Scott: so, you know and this tells you everything and gives you absolutely everything you need and You don't need any.
Scott: You know, you don't need any spend any money.
Scott: You don't need to.
Scott: you know know anything about.
Scott: you know programming But some Java would help you out quite a bit, you know, and you can follow these instructions.
Scott: It takes about.
Scott: let's see It tells you that it takes about two hours But who knows how long?
Scott: you know that may vary and you can make a multiplayer 3d online game.
Scott: So that's that's pretty cool.
Scott: I'm gonna try it out so I can learn and see if this engine is any good or not.
Scott: It's the competition.
Rym: So very briefly the meta minutes just to point out Scott's coming.
Scott: I met a minute Scott's coming in over Skype.
Rym: We're totally fast and loose.
Rym: We're not editing like we normally do at all.
Rym: GeekNights is almost fast karate.
Rym: at this point We'll be back to normal.
Scott: We'll be back to normal.
Scott: it's it's slow I do.
Rym: it's space karate.
Rym: It's like regular karate, but it's half as powerful.
Rym: Yeah, need like a thousand regular karate is to get one space karate or no the opposite of that.
Rym: In fact, yeah.
Rym: Anyway, the only thing I want to point out is that one Connecticut next summer where the heads of panels panel registration is open.
Rym: if you have a panel and you want to submit it for consideration Send us your panel.
Rym: We're looking for Panels other than anime panels particularly gaming and other cool stuff.
Scott: Anime is also good though.
Scott: We do need some animes and mangas.
Scott: Mangas are better.
Scott: You know.
Scott: if you got some mangas bring that on.
Scott: Yeah But yet we also do you want to announce the other thing about Connecticut?
Scott: You would hold back.
Rym: we got a hold back because I got to show you all the details We had to give it.
Rym: we had to give it a. it's not actually a silly name But it looks like a silly name if you don't know the history of Connecticut.
Scott: Yeah, anyway The previous Weekend, we were at Zenkai con.
Scott: a good time was had if you discovered us at Zenkai con.
Rym: Hello Yep I'd recommend listening to other episodes from I don't know a month ago or earlier because we're in this weird transitional state right now.
Rym: We move all our stuff around so GeekNights is almost on hiatus.
Scott: Yes, the current book club selection is the hitchhiker's guide to the galaxy by Douglas Adams.
Scott: only the original none of the you know Prequels or sequels or any other books other than the original book.
Scott: you're probably if you buy it You're probably gonna end up buying like, you know, five or six volumes in one but only the first one will be discussed on the book club episode.
Scott: and Is there anything else we have to discuss in the minute here, I think that's enough.
Rym: that's enough for now back to the the actual show.
Rym: You know, we always diss on the memorpica as being shit and people always used to say I remember Scott You don't even give these games a chance You haven't played World of Warcraft and we've been semi secretly for a while now playing a whole bunch of MMOs.
Scott: Well, I mean the thing is we had played, you know, our defense was that we had played.
Scott: Oh, yeah I played World of Warcraft once for a little bit and I we had always played, you know muds.
Rym: Yep I had played for many years the first MMO Which is still to this day and I now that I've played a whole bunch of other my MMOs.
Rym: There's no Significant difference.
Rym: In fact, there are some ways that modern MMOs are worse than the right.
Scott: Let's wait on that.
Scott: Yeah, so we You know, but people are like, hey you haven't actually Seriously played like all these games, you know, and there are actually surprisingly a lot of MMOs out there a ton of them.
Scott: It's like you think they cost so much money to run.
Scott: you got to keep the servers up and the whole thing, right?
Scott: It's like you think there wouldn't be that many that are active at once but you know in that World of Warcraft would Obviously that's gonna stick around forever or for incredibly incredibly long time.
Scott: But you think the other ones, you know And the thing is actually a lot of them have bled like.
Scott: there are a lot of MMOs that have just they you know a professionally produced published game.
Scott: Not enough people play it and it shuts down.
Rym: or even then some of the ones I tried to play like I'd get a demo Just didn't work.
Rym: Yeah, we couldn't even get it to go.
Scott: There was one that I played.
Scott: I forget which one it was but it was free.
Scott: But basically the interface on it was so bad that after like 10 seconds It was just on.
Scott: oh there were two that were like that dungeon runners and something else.
Scott: something realms I forget but basically they were just within 30 seconds.
Scott: They were unplayable.
Scott: You see the thing that's really freaked me out Right.
Scott: It's like in a way people were right.
Scott: It's like who are you to talk about MMOs?
Scott: You didn't play it You're not playing them.
Scott: and the thing is I wasn't playing them and I was complaining that oh, they're all these grindy games.
Scott: All you do is click click click click click level up level up level up get to the max level And then there's not.
Scott: what do you do?
Scott: Right and it's there's not.
Scott: the actual combat is just rock-paper-scissors BS.
Scott: It's not actually very good and you know, it's just the psychological trap and that whole thing I'm not even gonna get into right.
Scott: and that's our complaint with MMOs.
Scott: the thing is That may or may not be true.
Scott: I didn't get far enough in any MMO to find out because They were just so bad in these other ways that I did not Except I didn't even get to the point of grinding except surprisingly, you know, we'll talk about this more.
Rym: we're gonna do a separate show on like all these MMOs, but People are right World of Warcraft is the best one.
Rym: I mean I got to the grind pretty quick and I was able to grind efficiently.
Rym: It's like I. we both thought the grind would be the rising Lee.
Scott: I mean I predict I knew that I'm you know that World of Warcraft.
Scott: I Had always said that it's the same as the other ones only it's polished and actually, you know, it's polished well beyond.
Rym: so I guess my point is that we both Expected like the grind to be the bad part and the fact that the games are too shitty to even get to the grind.
Rym: And then Wow selling point is that it gets you right to the grinding.
Rym: It was kind of amazing.
Scott: I mean like every other game that I played so far and I've still got a few more on the list.
Scott: I stopped playing because of some other reason but Wow, I stopped playing because well, I had to pay money to continue and More prominently because it was basically kill 10 skeletons.
Scott: now kill 15 skeletons.
Scott: I was like game over But is I could actually kill the 15 skeletons?
Scott: it was doable the controls worked which is you know I mean like that is why Wow is the king, you know, I still gonna make fun of Wow.
Scott: I still don't think it's a good game but It's better than all the other ones.
Scott: and if you're gonna play one, you know Despite any problems that may have if you're not playing Wow Why not?
Scott: because the other ones are just horrendous.
Rym: though I did discover something kind of interesting.
Rym: You know I was playing Eve online for a while trying to get into that and then people used to make a joke that like Eve online It's just Excel.
Scott: Yeah, I was gonna make that joke.
Rym: I was about to be like, yeah It's it's more Excel than I thought it was scary.
Rym: What I was about to say I have.
Rym: I'll pretend you didn't ruin my joke Yeah, but then I was.
Rym: you know I was at work and someone had installed it on my PC and then I looked around and actually someone went around my company installing Eve online on every computer in my office.
Rym: They called it Excel for some reason, but it's the same game.
Rym: That's what I was about to say, but you totally ruined it.
Scott: That's fine It's so true though Like I didn't realize how true it was until I really spent like a good 20 minutes.
Rym: I blame the escapist.
Rym: when we used to read the escapist every other story was like the drama of Eve and reading those I was like wow, that must be the best game ever.
Rym: And then I'd play it and I see that that it's literally just a spreadsheet.
Rym: It's so Nothing.
Scott: Yeah, it's like they would always have these stories about like to be corporations and intrigue.
Scott: and you know, like traitorous ness See any avatars.
Scott: I see spaceships.
Scott: How can you have traitorous ness if I don't even see the?
Rym: here's how I would explain it with Eve.
Scott: It's like like someone would see some numbers go down in this spreadsheet and they'd be like, oh my god traitorous ness.
Scott: It's like imagine at least chose you the dwarves.
Rym: imagine if you're playing monopoly or no.
Rym: No, let's get even worse.
Rym: You're playing Uno online, right?
Rym: But you're playing Uno with like 10,000 people, but it's just Uno.
Rym: It's just Uno and You're all in the same chat room Yelling at each other and you have all this drama that's completely unrelated to the actual game you're playing.
Rym: That's where all that drama comes from an Eve.
Rym: It's all this meta clan drama.
Rym: the game itself has about all the drama of me Summing a hundred columns and then dividing them by the number of columns.
Scott: Anyway, so the game that you know Mostly in this episode because we're gonna have to do more episodes about all these MMOs are playing right but mostly I want to talk About the turbine engine.
Scott: apparently there's an MMO engine out there called the turbine engine and apparently a lot of different MMOs use the same exact engine.
Scott: and Two games that I played on this engine were Lord of the Rings online which came in our packs goodie bag for free.
Rym: Yeah That game wasn't worth playing tell you a lot.
Scott: and the recently Free to play Dungeons & Dragons online Eberron, whatever right.
Scott: so the Dungeons & Dragons one is free The Lord of the Rings one is not free.
Scott: You have to you get a trial and then you have to pay money.
Scott: and but they're on the same engine.
Scott: But I think the Lord of the Rings one is on a newer version of the engine or at least you know.
Scott: It seemed like it was a newer version of the engine.
Scott: Anyway, I couldn't really you know, it was it felt more polished.
Scott: So I assumed it was newer, you know, but it could you know.
Scott: But I mean, it's just basically the two games are basically mods on the same engine the same way counter-strike and NS Are on the same engine.
Scott: So Anyway, this engine is turbine engine ought to talk about it.
Scott: Generally.
Scott: first the user interfaces It has like all the menus and stuff are horrendously and needlessly complicated Like you push like F something to bring up a menu and it has like a million widgets and buttons and things and they're not Actually wanted to do what.
Scott: I had to be hidden or I couldn't find it or like I need to manage my inventory.
Scott: I basically had to stand still pull up a whole bunch of screens Drag-and-drop and fiddle and click and fiddle and push buttons the only reasons you get them all off the screen again so I can actually see what was going on.
Rym: none of this got in My way because once I equipped some stuff and it was so tedious to do it all I never bothered again, even with all the items and stuff I was getting because you won every raid no matter what.
Rym: so I didn't even bother equipping the new stuff I was getting.
Scott: so the other major problem I have in this engine, right?
Scott: I mean, I guess, you know, the graphics are fine.
Scott: I mean things look like they look, you know, however, the people who made the game made it look It's that the controls are like not Good, because I played Wow first for a while and it was like, alright it controlled the way I expected.
Rym: I'm walking around I can zoom the camera in and out.
Rym: Everything's fine.
Rym: I Played D&D online and like I could not walk like I just I could not move around.
Rym: It was so difficult.
Rym: The camera is like the worst camera in the world.
Scott: The worst thing isn't even that because those are bad.
Scott: But the worst thing is like trying to pick something up for example in D&D online.
Scott: I hit a bad guy.
Scott: He dies.
Scott: He dropped some gold on the ground.
Rym: No, he drops.
Rym: No, no, no.
Rym: No, he drops some fucking copper.
Rym: You don't get gold Right.
Scott: So I have to move the camera so that I can see the copper.
Scott: then I have to click.
Scott: I have to move the mouse like I'm just this tiny spot and click to pick up the copper and it's barely any copper at All.
Scott: it's not enough to do anything You know and I have to keep doing this.
Scott: every time I freakin get a pile of copper.
Rym: See at least in Lego games.
Rym: you just walk over it and you get it.
Scott: Yeah So the Lord of the Rings Online game was a little bit better in that I was a dwarf and it gave me a quest like pig berries from eight Bushes, so the bushes were glowing which helped a lot.
Scott: It was like, oh, there's a bush.
Scott: So I walk over to the bush and then I click on it and I was actually able to click on the bush because it was kind of big a lot bigger than a pile of copper pieces on The ground and it was like you're not close enough to the bush.
Scott: So I have to move my guy like into the bush and then it's like now It's hard to click on the bush because my guys in the way it's
Rym: feeling like that in general like in combat I'd lose I'd attack and it just wouldn't hit the guy because I wasn't facing him perfectly.
Rym: I'd like back up and like swivel the camera like swivel into him and then hit my attack again.
Scott: Yeah, it's like dude.
Scott: They should just have freaking you know Like the turn-based combat because this you know, if you're gonna have real-time combat, you know Cuz the combat is real time in these games, you know If you're gonna have real-time combat, you need to make it like an action RPG.
Scott: make it freakin.
Scott: You know River City Ransom.
Scott: make it.
Scott: you know Kingdom Hearts where I push the button and I swing and I can use a gamepad and it's just I beat them up.
Scott: You know that?
Scott: give me that kind of real-time combat if that's what you want.
Scott: If you're not gonna do that Don't make like this crappy pain-in-the-ass real-time combat with shitty controls.
Scott: Just go turn base.
Scott: Well, the worst thing is make it Baldur's Gate where you pause the game.
Rym: It's so obvious what they're doing.
Rym: you look at the interface.
Rym: It looks exactly like a shitty version of World of Warcraft interface.
Rym: The combat is basically identical to Wow except harder to control more pain in the ass and what you do matters less.
Scott: Yep, every single one of these games, you know a lot a surprising number of games Were just straight-up Unabashed World of Warcraft clones and I was like, okay, you know, I guess you know If you're if you're out to make money, you know, you see the World of Warcraft works, you know You're gonna just you know steal from the non-forgotten masters, you know, that's not a bad move But you have to do better than them.
Scott: It's the same thing that we see in like the cell phone industry.
Scott: people look at the iPhone and they go.
Scott: Ah That iPhones doing real low.
Scott: We should copy that.
Scott: So what do they do?
Scott: They make a touchscreen phone with square icons on the front that Misses out on all the actually important things that the iPhone does better.
Scott: It's like no you have to actually be better.
Scott: You can't just sort of make a shitty copy.
Scott: That's nowhere near as good.
Scott: You actually need to be better than that.
Scott: people can tell they're not stupid and they're doing the same exact thing.
Scott: And it's like really?
Scott: Yes, really?
Scott: That's how the world is.
Scott: I guess people just copy the thing that's great and don't do a good job.
Rym: So the worst thing is, you know, we get into the game.
Rym: It's free.
Rym: I make my character and the first thing I notice is that half the classes and Races and stuff aren't available to me.
Rym: and it's like for four bucks.
Rym: You can be a monk For another dollar you can be a warforged monk whoo-dee-doo-dee-doo and Like.
Rym: it's one thing that they went to the model of make the game free and charge people for in-game stuff.
Rym: But it's way out of hand like it's worse than gun bound.
Rym: Yeah, but I mean it's just the point to where I went to the website Where and to see what I could buy.
Rym: and it's like you want to want a magic missiles.
Rym: You want a wand of healing.
Rym: you want a bauble that gives you plus 50% XP for four hours after you break it.
Rym: Any item in the game anything in the world you could possibly want you can just buy with money.
Rym: you can buy extra levels.
Scott: It's ridiculous.
Rym: I didn't even look.
Rym: everything was like five to fifteen dollars as far as I could tell.
Scott: Wow, wait five dollars for just like a wand of magic missiles.
Rym: one class.
Rym: I wanted to buy was eight bucks.
Rym: You wanted to buy a class as in I would have played it if it was free.
Rym: I would have played that class.
Rym: But the worst thing is like.
Rym: I saw people in the game talking about it and they're like man.
Rym: don't buy that class.
Rym: yet I got it.
Rym: It's not that powerful.
Scott: It's not worth the eight bucks Which is interesting because as far as I can tell The stats of the classes made at least public knowledge before you spend your money on them.
Rym: I guess I don't even know.
Rym: it's just stupid.
Rym: and the thing is it more powerful doesn't matter because every raid I played you're just one kind of automatically even on the hard mode.
Scott: It's not the hard mode.
Scott: I know that was surprising.
Scott: Like I thought the hard mode is gonna be grueling But we basically walked in and it was basically shitty gauntlet shitty 3d god.
Rym: Yep I mean I play a fight like a paladin straight up.
Rym: I'm an elven paladin Literally, I stand there the enemies all come at me and I'm just like sword other sword sword other sword sword other sword sword Other sword and they all just die in one hit.
Scott: I was actually a wizard.
Scott: I wanted to actually try to do something tricky, you know Cuz if you're a fighter all you do is stand there hold down the attack button and don't do anything.
Scott: And I was like why even bother?
Scott: so I was a wizard.
Scott: So, you know what I did.
Scott: I stood far away.
Scott: I kind of moved the camera to keep the bad guys on screen and I Kept pushing the magic missile button over and over again and the magic missiles hit the bad guys.
Rym: It's so bad.
Rym: Like it drops you in the bad guys got close to me.
Scott: What did I do?
Rym: even though I'm a wizard I held down the regular melee attack button and it killed him Just the same as my sword as far as I could tell.
Rym: Yeah, but it's like it drops you into whatever quest and it's like the evil lord of the Forgotten Land.
Rym: The plot plot plot plot plot.
Rym: you hear the creaking of dange and bones in the distance and Then it drops you into the thing and it's literally like walk by.
Rym: there are a thousand identical sarcophagi if you smile.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: If you're gonna make like a scary, you know dungeon instance kind of thing Why don't you actually like sort of you know design some interesting levels?
Scott: These are like it looked like someone was using the.
Scott: you know, like the mage master whatever they're called D&D thingies like you walk around together the same map with the same different maps with the same pieces.
Rym: It's like a thousand barrels in the storehouse.
Rym: Everyone you smash has like two copper pieces that come out that you have to click on to pick up.
Rym: Yeah So we won't.
Rym: we play a bunch and we find even a tedious grind.
Scott: It's like a tedious clean up the level.
Scott: I mean Lego Star Wars is better than this because at least Lego Star Wars is Sort of you know easier and you could just walk over the golds to pick them up, you know.
Rym: So the worst thing is Scott, you know We both play it on our own for a while and I keep saying the worst thing because they keep getting worse And it played like it has this kind of initial, you know Here's how the game starts introduce some characters get you to a town and at the end of the quest It drops you in the world and you get the choice of like a fire sword like basically get a weapon on fire.
Rym: So then you go into the town where everybody starts the beginner town and everyone has a sword on fire.
Rym: Literally, there are just like hundreds of people wearing various amounts of like newbie rags Carrying flaming swords running around not interacting in any way clipping through each other.
Scott: Yeah, so this is one thing that I didn't quite grasp until I started playing a bunch of these is that the MMOs are Not massive at all.
Scott: Like they are in no way massive.
Scott: all they are even World of Warcraft even though slightly less so than the others.
Scott: What they do is It's actually just no different than say Counter-strike, right you have a game lobby where people sort of you know Chat while they're waiting to get into a game and when you get into a game, it's just a game.
Scott: That's not massive.
Scott: You know, you go to an instance and even you might go to an instance with 30 guys.
Scott: You know if it's a if it's a big, you know I know World of Warcraft has big instances where you bring in a lot of people but it's not massive.
Scott: You know, I mean you could play a game of tribes - with that's 40 on 40 or 50 on 50 And that's more massive than that and tribes - doesn't claim to be a massive game.
Scott: So the only massive parts are the lobbies and you know what in a any other game online?
Rym: Sure the chat lobby probably has like thousands of people the thing is in D&D online at least the the ways to Interact with people you run into are so minimal and unusable and chat with them.
Scott: You can trade with them The chat and even trade with them because half your items all your good ones Anyway are stuck to you and you can't possibly give them to anyone else because they're bound to only your character and no other character.
Rym: Well even worse I keep saying worse.
Rym: You try to like interact with people and you get this tiny little chat box and you can't read anything That's going on in it.
Rym: And even if you talk to people no one ever responds.
Scott: It's basically only people you can really talk to.
Scott: are the people that you friend or in your clan Which is like why does it even matter if these other people are here or not?
Rym: Yeah, it doesn't at all.
Rym: You don't interact with these people in any way.
Rym: you go into like the inn expecting some flavor.
Scott: There's just decorations in the town.
Rym: I went into the inn to seek you don't mind the thing I used to do a lot and old MMOs was like hang out In places with cool people.
Scott: I would do that all the time even in tiny muds.
Scott: You could go to like a tavern sit down, you know, have a drink, you know.
Scott: sit in a chair talk to the bartender.
Scott: He would say funny things.
Scott: I walk into the inn.
Scott: people would come in sit down have a drink and talk to you.
Scott: You could play like cards while you talked about, you know in character kind of stuff.
Rym: I go into the inn in D&D online and there are literally like a hundred newbies in newbie rags with flaming swords Jumping up and down on the tables and behind the bar.
Rym: You can't sit down.
Rym: You can't do anything special.
Rym: It's just a room with idiot shit cocking newbies jumping up and down with flaming swords.
Scott: 90% of the people are just basically crowding around the bartender who gives you quests and he's saying the same exact thing.
Scott: He's not moving.
Scott: He's saying the same exact thing to everyone.
Scott: He's not even really an NPC.
Scott: He's basically just a button you click on to get a quest.
Rym: He's like those dispensers in Bioshock.
Scott: Yeah, basically he's.
Scott: he's.
Scott: uh, you know, he's a circus of value.
Rym: It's so ludicrous and laughable that the situations I ran into playing this game were on the level of what I would say about like if I was making fun of an MMO that didn't exist like if I was parodying how bad an MMO could be.
Scott: but so it's like all I have to do to make what game caught an MMO and get people to pay a monthly fee for it and pay real money for it.
Scott: instead of just making my game a one-time fee game is Instead of the chat team, you know matchup Lobby being a chat room I make it like a place to 3d avatar chat room and suddenly I can charge money for it.
Scott: Holy crap, you know What is Yahoo doing with their backgammon?
Scott: There's like a thousands of people playing Yahoo backgammon in any one moment if they just made the matchup chat Lobby Have avatars.
Rym: I have to do one thing further.
Rym: You have to level up.
Rym: Yeah, I'm level eight.
Rym: I get to roll three Leveling in backgammon on Yahoo.
Scott: You basically you start off with like some number of points and when you lose you lose points and when you win you get points.
Rym: No, no, I'm talking about leveling in the bunging style of I'm level 80.
Rym: I roll 3d6.
Scott: Ahh, 3d6 in backgammon.
Rym: I get flaming sword In backgammon?
Scott: Yeah, in backgammon You're playing hearts.
Scott: You're just like yeah, I can throw out any heart I want.
Rym: No playing hearts.
Rym: I'm like Siobhan dragon.
Rym: Yeah, follow that suit bitches.
Rym: That's basically what's going on though.
Scott: So the worst part like at least I was you know, I was bashing the MMOs for the grindy parts.
Scott: I didn't realize there were all these other horrible parts to them, you know.
Scott: And the thing is World of Warcraft to its credit does not have half of these horrible other things But it does have the other.
Rym: In D&D Online We both leveled up a bit and tried to like play on our own and after I failed to have like No one I talked to in that game who was a real PC passed the Turing test Like they did.
Rym: I'm not kid.
Rym: they did not pass the Turing test.
Rym: I was not convinced they were real people.
Rym: So finally Scott and I were like, all right Let's play on the same round.
Rym: and we made sure we're in the same round.
Rym: and I'm like, I'm hanging out by the docks Come find me.
Rym: We'll join up a former party and it will go kick some ass multiplayer.
Rym: So I'm standing on the docks and Scott has to make an all-new character because it won't let him like join my realm.
Rym: He can't transfer his character.
Rym: So he makes a character And goes through the bullshit starter quest again that you can't die in.
Rym: Literally, but the priest is like I cast a spell on you that makes you immune to death until you leave this dungeon.
Rym: It's like great.
Scott: Why did you cast that on everyone?
Scott: and then let's just you know, sort of walk through here lazily.
Rym: Why don't I just learn that spell?
Rym: Yeah, right Anyway, so I'm by the docks and Scott's like.
Rym: I'm here.
Rym: Where are you?
Rym: and I'm like, I'm here.
Rym: I'm the elf in the chain mail with the flaming sword jumping up and down on the barrel next to the other elf with the Flaming sword.
Scott: I'm next to NPC so-and-so jumping up and down.
Rym: I'm next to NPC so-and-so I'm jumping up and down.
Rym: You sure we're at the same dock.
Rym: So I don't see you fast forward 20 fucking minutes later Cuz I like logged out and logged back in and make sure we were in the same realm.
Scott: Definitely in the same realm.
Rym: I went around looking for like another doc cuz I thought you were stupid.
Rym: I thought you were like at some other doc that I didn't know about like way off somewhere.
Rym: So I was like, this is bullshit Scott's an idiot.
Rym: Finally in the upper left hand corner, if you click on something, it's like which instance of This town are you in?
Rym: and there are three.
Rym: and it's not only.
Scott: not only is the game not actually Massive and the only massive part is a chat lobby that happens to be 3d with avatars, right?
Scott: But that chat lobby isn't even that massive because there's multiples of the same exact town and you know There's basically ten copies of the same town and you pick which of the ten copies of the town that you're in.
Rym: Seriously Never mind you have to pay for.
Rym: D&D online is Unplayable at least the reason it's free.
Rym: All right, at least gun bound was fun as a game That's true.
Rym: That's true.
Rym: I mean I could punish people.
Rym: that's that's more than I can save.
Rym: and the clipping like the game you like it lets you jump But it doesn't let you jump on anything.
Rym: because if you jump on something either it has no effect on the game or They don't actually jump on it because it would break the game.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: why even give the ability to jump if there is no platforming aspect to this game whatsoever?
Rym: I mean I would jump and I'd see like a low fence and I couldn't jump over it.
Scott: Yeah, also if the game, you know, it's like you look at the way the game mechanics are right in the way You know, it's sort of like this sort of real-time but poor kind of you know thing.
Scott: It's sort of like.
Scott: well, why do you why are you limiting me in these ways for no reason?
Scott: Like for example, like, you know, you know when you play hero quest, right?
Scott: You know, we sort of realized like why bother rolling the dice to walk around?
Rym: That was the day when we're playing hero quest and Alex was the game master and he was you know He was beating us a little bit partly because the first time we played Scott ran around opening all the doors.
Rym: So the cast nights came out in mass.
Scott: It's more fun.
Rym: So then we're like, let's play again and Alex is like, alright and we get it.
Rym: We're like, we're gonna open a door and then I turn to Alex and I'm like we stand here and take no action Until all of us roll six for our movement in the same round Mm-hmm, and he's like Fuck.
Scott: His choices were either a force us to go with our first roll Right be force us to actually keep rolling until we got what we wanted
Rym: which I was I was totally willing to do
Scott: yeah, which is technically I think what is required by the rules or be given and Allow us to proceed which of course also ruined the game but in a different way.
Rym: But D&D online comes pre ruined That's true.
Rym: There's.
Rym: there was no at any point an element of gameplay.
Rym: You couldn't even say like Wow, you can at least explore the landscape because there's stuff out there and while you can't Wow to its credit, you know The number one thing of all the comparisons to make between Wow and the other MMOs.
Scott: Wow had colors.
Scott: Wow was really colorful and had way better art than any of these.
Scott: I mean the Lord of the Rings.
Scott: one was basically had some colors, but it wasn't great.
Scott: and D&D online is just Bright a brown and gray screen and that's it except for the flaming swords and The high-level characters had colors like the ones that you know The NPCs in the noob quest that you know, the base of the tutorial quest.
Scott: they had colors But there were no other colors in the game whatsoever.
Scott: It was just brown and gray and it's like wow You know World of Warcraft has lots of colors.
Scott: It's at least fun to look at.
Rym: But D&D online is so shit.
Rym: But there's so many people playing it and I think it just proves that punk kids if something's free will do it.
Scott: Well, no, it's not just that it's free that they'll do it.
Scott: It's free and it has this psychological thing where they're leveling up in the whole business Right and they have plenty of free time on their hands and nothing to do and they are bored out of there.
Rym: Yeah, some guy came up to me.
Rym: He was like level 18 And he was like, I want to grind the blah blah blah quest on expert mode a bunch of times today.
Rym: Who's with me?
Rym: And I was like, I'm level 7 and he's like, that's fine.
Rym: I'll power level you you blah blah blah and As far as I can tell that dude was sitting there all day Playing the same quest over and over again the quest by the way consisted of Holding down a button and walking.
Rym: Oh, this was the one quest We did.
Rym: we're literally.
Rym: you walk into one room and then these specters just keep coming out of the walls until you kill them all.
Scott: Oh that one.
Rym: Yeah that one.
Scott: Yeah, I guess if you're gonna do some power leveling That's a good one to do because I could have beaten that one with the drinking bird.
Scott: That's like the can of coke the place you give.
Rym: oh Mike no to be fair that kind of coke.
Rym: Yeah, while it won the tournament it was vanilla coke.
Rym: I mean I couldn't even beat that.
Scott: I don't think.
Scott: did it actually win the tournament.
Rym: It came in second place.
Rym: I recall or something like that.
Rym: So people know
Scott: right to prove Yu-Gi-Oh the card game right to prove that this game Like, you know in Magic the Gathering if I just take some Magic the Gathering cards and I get the best cards in the world Right the most expensive best cards and I play but I have no clue what I'm doing
Rym: I could lose, you
Scott: know, I might not play any land at all.
Scott: I might just go doo doo doo doo doo, you know and lose in Yu-Gi-Oh, right?
Scott: They basically proved that it only matters what cards you have.
Scott: the decisions you make in the game don't mean anything.
Rym: Yep, there's our friend Luke and they were a millennium for a tournament.
Rym: So they got the store to provide basically all the absolute best most expensive cards.
Rym: They made the best egg you can make and they gave the cat the 20 ounce or 20 Yeah, 20 ounce bottle of vanilla coke the rule that every round it would draw card and play the card and drew.
Rym: and that was it.
Scott: Yep, so I mean they had the best Yu-Gi-Oh cards in the world because the store it's a game store.
Scott: They have every Yu-Gi-Oh card, right?
Scott: So every turn it drew a card and played it and it had the best cards in the world.
Scott: It just won and it was a can of coke Vanilla coke.
Scott: vanilla coke beat a whole bunch of people at Yu-Gi-Oh.
Scott: I don't know if it won but it beat a whole bunch of people at you.
Scott: I have to imagine D&D online is the same thing.
Scott: You have a drinking bird that just pecks at your attack button and if you're on that quest with the ghosts, you're gonna win.
Rym: I don't even know like I want to make fun of the game, but it's so literally What game?
Scott: What game are you making fun of?
Rym: A bunch of identical gray characters with flaming swords jumping up and down in the inn yelling at each other about.
Rym: I don't even know what they're yelling.
Rym: They're just typing Gibberish.
Rym: the talking in that game is on the level of a YouTube comment.
Rym: There's nothing there.
Scott: I have a prediction though.
Scott: I have a prediction here and I want to.
Scott: I want to sort of you know.
Scott: Get people off our backs preemptively right.
Scott: people are gonna say You were just playing the beginning part of the game where the nubs are.
Scott: if you go to and they're gonna say this for all The MMO is not just D&D online, right?
Scott: If you level up and you go to the later parts of the game where the better content is, right?
Scott: It's not like that.
Scott: this good stuff elsewhere in the game.
Scott: You just didn't get there yet, you know.
Scott: So the game isn't crap.
Scott: this good stuff is just not where you were.
Scott: you didn't go to the good stuff.
Rym: Well, there's one way around that in D&D online.
Rym: You can just buy your way to the quote-unquote good part.
Scott: Yes, sorry.
Rym: No, but it cuts it with real money.
Rym: You can just buy all the levels you want by the class you want and you're good to go.
Scott: If I could just pick my level for free, that would be okay.
Scott: But paying real money not okay.
Rym: But everything is work aft right.
Scott: people make the same argument.
Scott: They're like someone told me like yeah, they haven't.
Scott: you know that that content You know.
Scott: at the at the you know, the noob content basically hasn't changed ever.
Scott: That's at least if they're like.
Rym: all the new content is like, you know in the end of the there is a valid argument for Wow that at least there is evidence that The content in the later game is probably objectively better because it's much newer and they haven't revamped the beginning of the game.
Rym: But that is possible.
Rym: However, well, let's just talk about D&D online D&D online.
Rym: there The beginning content is not that much older than whatever new content they have.
Rym: if there even is new content There is no indication at all that the game is in any way different at any point in the game ever.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: The thing is regardless of whether the content that is later in the game is good or not You know if they get content at the beginning of the game is bad, right?
Scott: Then the game is bad.
Scott: I mean if you're playing Mario 1, right and Basically, the only good levels in Mario 1 is world 8 and worlds 1 through 7 or shit.
Scott: or even if worlds 1 through 4 Are bad and worlds 5 through 8 are good Is it worth suffering worlds 1 through 4 just to play worlds 5 through 8?
Scott: When there are other games that exist where worlds 1 through 8 are all good Why would I ever play the game that is half bad or has a bad part in the beginning or has any badness?
Scott: that?
Scott: Requires me to suffer through it whatsoever.
Scott: Even if it was just world 1 - 1 was bad.
Scott: See at least at least with why would I suffer when I can just play?
Scott: I don't know new Super Mario Brothers We that's coming out this week where the whole thing is probably gonna be kind of fun at least with Wow.
Rym: in the early content There's a lot more to be said.
Rym: like there.
Rym: there is a I. we can actually review it because there is a game that happens.
Scott: But yes, it's.
Rym: it is far better than the other.
Rym: but D&D online No, I'm saying D&D online There's like nothing.
Rym: It's kind of like when they were trying and penny arcade to make fun of doom 3 and doom 3 had like the art Like the upside down flaming skull And it's like.
Rym: what do you say about that?
Scott: Yeah, it's like it's like if I was gonna score these games on a score of 0 to 10, right?
Scott: It's like the D&D online.
Scott: we get a 0 because it's just poop all the way through and the World of Warcraft would get like A3 or three and a half, you know, it's like it's still not good But you know, there's far.
Scott: it's pretty much the best of all the MMOs.
Scott: Yeah, and if you were putting it if you're in ranking only MMOs so the best MMO in the world was 10 and the worst MMO in the world was 0.
Scott: World of Warcraft would be 10 and All these other things would be 0.
Scott: Well, I guess even then D&D online wouldn't be 0 because I was actually able to complete some quests.
Scott: Yes Runners would be 0 because it was absolutely unplayable.
Rym: You know, it can't be 0 because I was able to log into it And that's already more than many of the games.
Rym: I tried to play.
Rym: That's true.
Rym: The thing is it's all okay because there'll be a constant stream of MMOs.
Rym: I mean actually there's a sequel to Eve online coming.
Rym: that might be good.
Scott: Are they gonna get rid of Eve online and go with the sequel only know Microsoft's making and it's called office 2010.
Rym: Oh It's all moot.
Rym: one of my co-workers totally I'm not even kidding took the day after left 4 dead comes out off work to play it all day with his friend.
Scott: thought About doing that for Team Fortress 2. good thing We did.
Rym: Oh my if I had done that for Team Fortress 2 I would have been the saddest panda that had ever especially since you didn't come out like most of the day.
Rym: I know you have to take the next day off.
Rym: Left 4 Dead 2 might have been worth it.
Rym: NS is definitely gonna be worth it the day that game comes out.
Rym: I'm not going to work Really?
Rym: Wow.
Rym: Yeah, cuz this is my last hope.
Rym: I waited like a decade for Team Fortress 2 and it fucked me.
Rym: NS is the last thing I got Mmm, and if it fails come out on a weekend We won't have to take.
Rym: if NS 2 fails like basically will make the NS 1 mod and if that fails We'll just play NS 1.
Rym: Forever Will be the mode will be the worst gaming podcast ever like the year 2040 look.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I was playing some NS 1 today.
Rym: Yep, maybe we'll start even going more retro.
Rym: We'll be playing like NS 1 version 1 point whatever with babblers instead of 3.2.
Scott: You know, well, you like the babblers.
Scott: It's not actually good.
Rym: They weren't good.
Rym: Hey more than once I killed myself or my own hive with those things.
Scott: More than once most of the time I used a babbler.
Rym: if you drop the babbler I suppose to an enemy.
Rym: if you were like running forward too quickly and you throw a babbler it just sat in you and ate you Yep.
Rym: Oh, those were good times.
Scott: We should make.
Scott: put the babblers in the MMOs And I don't mean like you're in the MMO.
Scott: You're playing the game and you click a button and babblers come out.
Scott: I mean like, you know, we take babblers and we put them in the offices of all the people who make the MMOs.
Rym: I Think we're done here.
Rym: Yes This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.