Rym: Hey, it's Thursday October 29th, and this is GeekNights tonight a show We recorded a while ago about stolen bicycles.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Oh Snap it's Thursday.
Scott: No, it's not.
Scott: It's Sunday.
Rym: You got to break the illusion.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: You know I'm always the illusion breaker.
Scott: That is my job.
Scott: Whatever rims whenever Rym says oh my god.
Scott: It was so amazing I say it was all right.
Scott: and when Rym says oh my god.
Scott: I totally kicked this guy's ass.
Scott: I'm like you pushed him over, and then he ran away, and you know that's how it.
Scott: That's how it goes in this world.
Scott: Rym is the hyperbole in the line and Scott is always your source of truth boring reality which is far more upsetting That you never seem to enjoy anything.
Rym: and your response to pretty much any media.
Scott: We consume is hey Yeah, all the all the non is are from the past long ago.
Scott: Uh-huh trying to talk about Star Wars.
Scott: I will not go a. Really Star Wars is like 30 years old.
Scott: It's older than me.
Scott: That's more like 40 years old.
Scott: good.
Scott: Yeah, all right.
Scott: Wow that that's really sad.
Scott: Star Wars is 40 years old.
Scott: It's like an old man.
Rym: So we're gonna do Thursday show I guess but the illusions broken.
Rym: I don't know if I can do it now.
Rym: Oh plus Scott doesn't the closer very specifically say GeekNights is actually recorded at night.
Scott: You know we would update the closer if someone wasn't so lazy.
Rym: I've been willing to do it a couple times But why don't we do it right now then?
Rym: because we have to write the script again.
Scott: Okay, cuz I remember the last time you should remove that part cuz the Sun is shining on my face.
Rym: I remember the last time when we tried to rerecord it and you were like yeah We don't need to rewrite a script, and then it was just ah I don't remember.
Rym: This was many many months ago.
Scott: This was I don't think this happened.
Rym: This is when we first got the nice microphone because remember that was recorded with the old microphone.
Scott: No, I think we record re-recorded it afterwards.
Rym: Yes, but if we took a couple of recordings Yeah, we did didn't.
Scott: and then we haven't tried again since we've just kept saying we should we anyway.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Scott: so We're gonna do news whatever.
Scott: I guess not a thing a day.
Rym: We'd said ahead of time.
Rym: We weren't gonna do that.
Scott: all right.
Scott: So thing of the day.
Scott: well at the beginning.
Rym: I was you have an opening bit.
Scott: Oh an opening bit shit I'm moving.
Scott: yeah now.
Scott: Oh look grab Basically I don't have any show ideas.
Rym: all this means for me is that Scott has not been around.
Rym: he's been moving his stuff around and He dirtied up a bunch of my dishes and left him filthy in the kitchen rotting.
Scott: I did not use any of your dishes.
Scott: I've been using exclusively paper dishes Scott.
Rym: I will point out wait Here's what I found in the kitchen.
Rym: one the toast of the tray to the toaster with like week and a half old Rotten Chinese food leavings on it.
Rym: I clean that.
Rym: That was not you a man.
Rym: it had one of your forks stuck in it.
Rym: No, you're a fork.
Rym: I cleaned it.
Rym: It's sitting there.
Rym: also my a glass baking pan.
Rym: You know the dish that we cook chicken in.
Rym: remember when you cooked those?
Rym: uh that chicken the chicken legs I was a long time ago.
Rym: Yeah, and you never washed that thing.
Scott: I did.
Rym: no it still got the chicken goop in it.
Scott: I remember cleaning it.
Rym: well going to get out of the kitchen and look all right had things there.
Scott: I remember cleaning that.
Scott: I remember specifically I cleaned all dishes.
Scott: Oh, you know what actually you're right.
Scott: You know what I did.
Rym: What did you do?
Scott: I was being evil.
Scott: You know what I did.
Rym: What did you do?
Scott: well when I packed all my dishes to take them away, right?
Scott: I said haha I will clean everything that belongs to me and if it belongs to Rym even if I dirtied it well Fuck it because I'm just leaving it here great.
Scott: So yeah, I did.
Rym: that's nice.
Rym: I Love the fact Scott used one of my you.
Rym: I had a box from UPS.
Rym: I got a package from Michigan a while ago.
Rym: So Scott packs a bunch of his glasses into this box and then seals it up And then just leaves it out like I left it next to all this other stuff that was backed up Scott.
Rym: He was sitting on the table with all the mail.
Scott: It's pretty sure that I put it on the ground.
Rym: It was sitting on the table next to all the mail.
Rym: So I'm gonna mail.
Rym: I see this box and I'm like a box for me from Michigan from Chesterfield What the fuck.
Rym: and I'm trying to get my old band videos, so I'm thinking did they just mail them to me?
Rym: I didn't pay or anything yet.
Rym: What's going on here?
Rym: So I open it and I find all these bags packed in.
Rym: I open up the bags and I find all the Scott's teacups.
Scott: Yeah, I don't drink tea even.
Rym: why do you even have those teacups?
Scott: They came with a set of plates and you know bowls and things.
Rym: but why do you keep an unnecessary thing?
Rym: Are you ever gonna use them?
Scott: Well, you know people come over and use them.
Rym: What are they?
Rym: Do you don't even have any way to make tea?
Scott: I'll probably get a teapot just cuz I need to make hot water occasionally.
Rym: Oh, do you use the hot water for you know for like.
Scott: you know, sometimes you need it for like a hot chocolate.
Scott: sometimes or You know, sometimes you just need to pour hot water on something Some ants.
Scott: if not, I don't think there's any ants on the third floor.
Rym: I don't think pouring hot water is gonna solve your end problem But yeah.
Scott: So I attempted to you know.
Scott: Normally you move in the one big go you put everything you own in a truck you drive it and you unpack it and it's I remember me and Pete had to drive that like 30 foot monster truck did not want to do that with its three speeds.
Rym: Oh my god, that was a nightmare 401k.
Scott: I thought I would be clever and I just I've been just driving my car back and forth you know with my stuff in it, you know and do a little bit at a time and it's taken me about a month and It's also sucks.
Scott: I mean it really.
Scott: it doesn't suck in terms of like the hard work because in all honesty It's really not that hard in terms, you know, it's like I just unpacked a bunch of stuff.
Scott: yesterday I was surprised at how you know little more there is to do.
Scott: it sucks in sort of like the logistics way.
Scott: It's like okay You sort of the even though it's difficult to put your furniture in a truck then take it out of a truck and then put it in a building, you know, and it sucks.
Scott: cuz the thing is That is difficult And You can make it less difficult by paying movers a lot of money.
Rym: But that's my plan going forward.
Rym: if I weren't moving like around the corner Yeah, I would have just paid large men to do everything for me.
Scott: But it is logistically simple right you put your stuff you move your stuff.
Scott: You can understand what to do.
Scott: You just got to do it.
Scott: I Thought I'd be clever.
Scott: I was like, aha I'll buy all new furniture a new mattress new fucking everything almost all new everything I get in my chair down there somehow But almost all take it on the train Right.
Rym: Okay, so just put tie it up for the bikes go.
Scott: So I'm trying to do everything all You know like that.
Scott: the thing is logistics of it are far more difficult.
Scott: it's like, okay, so I gotta get this Delivered but I have to be there.
Scott: But it's a it's.
Scott: it's much more difficult in terms of what the hell should I do?
Rym: Gassy hiccups coming out.
Scott: I just I just ate lunch and whatnot.
Rym: So that's not a normal reaction to eating lunch.
Scott: regardless I'm gonna put my clothes in the car today and then I'm gonna come back here go to sleep go to work tomorrow And then I should be all set.
Scott: The only things that are left here are things which don't belong to me Things which I don't want anymore or things that we haven't determined what to do with you things You don't know what to do with or things that I don't really need.
Rym: Down in Queens luckily because we're being nice to our land the landlords people were living The place.
Rym: the people who own the place we're living in now, it's a pretty big house.
Rym: We've pretty much got this house until the end of the year.
Rym: It's gonna be empty soon?
Rym: Yeah So we're just gonna if we have it till the end of the year if we if we have it one more day like if we Have the week of awesome party or whatever over New Year's.
Rym: I don't know what we're doing over New Year's at all Like I haven't planned.
Scott: I want to go the retro arcade museum.
Rym: Yeah, we'll do that.
Rym: But you know, you know like people come for like a week or two around New Year's every year We'll have an empty house.
Scott: What are you gonna do with an empty house?
Rym: put all the all the visigoths will sleep here.
Scott: an empty room?
Rym: Yeah empty rooms.
Scott: We'll have to Get some Board games in this empty house, or maybe we can play an empty house kind of game, huh?
Rym: Maybe in December once the house is empty.
Rym: We kept saying we wanted to have a little like gaming convention.
Rym: We'll just have it in the house.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, I think we'll get in trouble.
Rym: How would we get in trouble?
Rym: I don't know if we're still paying rent.
Rym: It's our house.
Rym: We can do whatever we want.
Scott: I wonder if we're allowed to have a tag sale.
Scott: We should have a free sale.
Scott: We just put out stuff out in the long.
Scott: be like free.
Scott: come get this.
Rym: I think all we have to do is go to the beacon whatever and be like we want to have a garage sale Yeah, but I don't.
Scott: we should ask Mary.
Rym: I realize they don't seem to call them garage sales out here.
Scott: I think that's a more Midwestern thing where they call garage sale tag sale yard sale You know, they call them all sorts of things.
Rym: what I what's really weird what I never see around here are the basement sales.
Scott: No, they have a state sales.
Scott: Yeah, I never seen a basement sale ever.
Rym: Not only did I we do a basement sale a couple times Because it was people came into our house went into the basement and in the basement.
Rym: We set up a garage sale.
Scott: I've never seen a basement sale.
Rym: I was always weird going to basement sales though because you basically go into someone's house and it's their normal living house.
Rym: And one thing I can say.
Rym: People may or may not comment on how messy or neat, you know me and Scott or other people who live are From my experiences going to other people's houses as a child.
Rym: in the suburbs.
Rym: The vast majority of people fall into two camps.
Rym: They either have the fake living room that no one actually uses full of knickknacks And then they like the hidden family room.
Rym: That's just a disaster where they actually do stuff.
Scott: Yeah well I mean like a lot of the people I knew like in Connecticut the style was you'd have a house with a bunch of rooms and a lot of the rooms would be.
Scott: some rooms would be clean and some rooms wouldn't like.
Scott: the basement would just be like this disaster or their their minivan would be Disaster and like, you know some of the you know bedroom like the kids bedroom would be disaster.
Scott: The parents bedroom be clean and then like one living.
Scott: the kitchen like one half the kitchen and the dining room Would be clean and the other half of the kitchen be a disaster.
Rym: and it's like they never clean the disaster parts But they kept the clean parts always clean But a lot of times the one the clean parts were the rooms that just never got used at all or the showrooms.
Rym: like when I first moved into you know, we got a big house in sterling heights as a kid So we had a. finally we had what all our relatives had a living room and a family room.
Rym: and What ended up happening was the family room was our normal living room and the living room was just this other living room with couches And a TV and everything that no one ever sat in.
Rym: it was just empty and full of knickknacks.
Rym: So then we turned that into a computer room and we moved everything around.
Scott: Yeah, also a common pattern I saw was they would have like in the basement There'd be a TV and a couch and all that's where kids would go To go watch TV or play video games and then there'd be a real living room Which would be clean where you you know, they would all you know, the adults would sit and watch TV.
Rym: Yeah, but the other camp of people as far as I could tell they just lived in filth.
Rym: just the level of mess not even just mess like there's stuff laying around but like Stacks of pizza boxes.
Scott: Yeah, I think that the thing is is that You know, it's like there's a certain level, you know, there are people that are super clean.
Scott: There's.
Scott: you know, there's a whole range of people and how clean they are.
Scott: But I think that the people who are super clean, I think there's an event horizon They don't really.
Scott: they never you know, they'll find someone who's sort of middling clean and they'll be like, oh my god is terrible.
Scott: It's like they haven't seen the really terrible because that's the kind of person that they're never gonna interact with ever and then they're never Gonna go to that person's house and they're never gonna see how bad it really can be and then won't Understand how the medium clean person is actually really clean.
Scott: It's like unless you go to a lot a lot of people's houses You're not really gonna sort of you know figure out like, you know who you know How many people are and that'd be actually a good really good scientific study.
Scott: if you would census Ask you if the census would just like sort of evaluate how clean people's houses are and they could be like 10% of how Houses we would classify as uber clean and uber.
Scott: Eh, yeah, like, you know uber clean is like, you know Old lady with plastic on the couch, you know in China in a cabinet.
Rym: Can you imagine the shitstorm the Republicans would raise if the census workers came in to look around your house?
Rym: Just asking you questions.
Scott: Yeah They would just peak, you know They would be the judgment from looking in the windows in the front door that could be.
Rym: because what if?
Rym: what if it's like the serial?
Rym: Killer with the nice exterior and the nice like anteroom or the nice soft foyer and then inside bodies everywhere.
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: You know that at least you're doing some cleaning.
Scott: It's like, you know, they think you could tell from I think, you know the front few rooms.
Rym: how what amazes me is the surprising number of people who Kind of passed that event horizon of cleanliness to where they just stop like using the toilet or they just stop.
Scott: You can see those on the Internet's blot of them, you know, like the guy poops and jars or the guy He just never throws anything out.
Scott: So the house is just a pile of trash.
Rym: It's such a common thing like there was one recently on Farg.
Rym: I found where a dude literally like his neighbors called the police cuz they thought he died Really?
Scott: He just smelled so bad.
Rym: He just smelled so bad because the apartment was just full of garbage.
Rym: and the thing is is for everyone who talked to him He was basically Completely sane and there was nothing you could really like.
Rym: you couldn't arrest him for being insane except that his apartment was disgusting.
Scott: Well, you could say it's an environmental hazard.
Rym: I think they evicted him.
Rym: Yeah All right, yeah, so it's Thursday.
Rym: Okay, we got a. really I feel now like there's a big change.
Rym: we're moving around in our lives and everything and sometime next week We'll have the you know state of the podcast.
Rym: cuz all you punk kids are like panicking about geek dies going away even though it's not uh-huh, but I Feel like we said way back We're gonna make Thursday different and we really we'd always like pointedly try to make Thursday different and more loose didn't fail.
Rym: And then we'd always like like we do one like yeah, we didn't do news.
Rym: We just talked about fun stuff.
Rym: It was Thursday.
Rym: Yeah, then the next Thursday We'd be sitting here with show like there's fucking no news and we just like pick news and talk about stuff.
Rym: We didn't care about.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: Maybe we should you know, if we're gonna maybe not record at night or maybe we'll probably still record at night Cuz that's when we're home from work, but I mean, you know, maybe we should change our format something I don't know not just Thursday.
Rym: All we have to do is go back to what we kept saying.
Rym: We're gonna make Thursday.
Rym: It's Thursday was the free format.
Rym: Thursday was the the lounge.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, we'll see.
Scott: Anyway, so do we want to things of the day, right?
Rym: Yeah, we got some things of the day.
Rym: Okay So things of the day.
Rym: I hate to go to just a college humor But more and more I realize you guys the only website you look at with funny stuff Not only that you guys as far as I can tell don't go to college humor.
Scott: It's not weird that it's like college humor is a filter of internet videos.
Scott: It's pretty good.
Scott: But now we're like a filter of a filter.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know where you people find funny things on the internet.
Scott: You know, actually I think that it's sort of you know, if you look at a lot of filter sites, right?
Scott: It's basically the way they work.
Scott: is They just anything they see?
Scott: that's sort of.
Scott: you know Whoever the filter is likes.
Scott: they put it up and some days there might be a lot and sometimes they might be a little.
Scott: I Think a better way to make a filter Would be that at the end of the day you have to put up X thing.
Scott: No, you can you limit it to X things?
Scott: So it's like even if there were ten great things you only can put up three and that way I Think there's at least three good enough things on the internet every day, right?
Scott: So if you limit yourself to just like three a day.
Scott: Then this thing your filter is gonna be really good and you might miss something, but you know what?
Scott: It's like come on There's enough I don't need.
Rym: I'm gonna have a big problem come November.
Rym: I'm too used to having my daily Cinemassacre.
Scott: Oh, I know right.
Rym: It's like the only thing I can rely on in my life right now Is that every day I get a cinemasker and I could see some horribly violent old bloody movie.
Scott: add some and some more webcomics.
Rym: It's hard to find new good webcomics.
Scott: You know the thing is every time I find a good new webcomic I forget to add it to my webcomic bookmark folder.
Scott: But now I just installed a clean OS.
Scott: I'll be redoing my webcomic book more than once.
Rym: I'll find a new webcomic and I like oh, this is great.
Rym: And then I'd like go through the archives and I get up to the recent one and I realize it's the same one I looked at when I first found the webcomic and I find out it's not updating anymore.
Scott: Yeah, I mean likely this every day.
Scott: I basically go to you know, my comics folder.
Scott: I open it in tabs and then I'll manually go to like xkcd later.
Scott: It's like just when I remember to.
Scott: it's like Why don't I add it to the thing?
Rym: You know, I'm even worse.
Rym: I've gotten to the point.
Rym: I really only read penny arcade vg cats xkcd and oots.
Scott: You're not reading.
Scott: Dr.
Scott: McNinja.
Rym: Dr.
Rym: McNinja.
Rym: I don't even have to say that's just a given.
Rym: I dr McNinja is not.
Rym: very few things on this earth have ever so Coincided with my humorous aesthetic as dr.
Rym: McNinja.
Rym: Pulp fiction with a laugh track.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: I saw this.
Rym: It's good.
Rym: The reason I use this is that we're trying to watch Seinfeld again.
Rym: and really didn't people in the forum keep trying to get us to watch these TV shows?
Rym: and I just Cannot watch a show with a laugh track anymore.
Rym: It is it is unwatchable laugh.
Scott: Yeah, it's weird.
Scott: It's like I used to watch TV like up until I was like 18 years old I watched a lot of TV as much as a couch potato, but you know a few hours a day I would watch TV a lot of cartoons Seinfeld.
Rym: so so I realized in America if you sit around and watch too much TV, you're a couch potato.
Rym: Yeah, if you wander around space with a gun, you're a space potato.
Scott: Why are you space potato lazy?
Rym: Matsumoto?
Scott: Oh Okay, so Yeah, the thing is I didn't really notice laugh tracks then after like years of not watching TV really much at all.
Scott: and Then the only times I really watch TV is like live sports Which don't have laugh tracks like I went batch to watch back to watch Seinfeld again more recently, you know.
Scott: And the laugh track it's like really stands out like a sore thumb.
Rym: It is incredibly painful Like ads and everything.
Rym: like when I stopped watching TV and then you know I came back to home in Michigan for like a week after I'd been at college for like months and months with no TV and TV was on and I was kind of doing something kind of an edge to it.
Rym: Then the ads happened and I just couldn't deal with it.
Scott: Well, I was waiting for the cable guy.
Scott: yesterday I watched the Simpsons treehouse of horror on Hulu right with the stolen wireless.
Rym: not as good as it used to be it was.
Scott: it was you know average ish, but the It was definitely not as good as you know, some of the the best of them But I have the shit in there was like there was like a commercial.
Scott: It was only one commercial but like in the middle of the episode, it's just a gut commercial.
Scott: I'm like what the fuck it's like.
Scott: it totally threw me off.
Rym: Anyway, so Pulp Fiction with a laugh track This is how one is.
Scott: look how the laugh track changes.
Scott: Pulp Fiction now, you know and for you know humorous But also negative effect depending on your point of view.
Rym: But I guess the way you might feel watching this is how I feel like watching any show with a laugh track.
Rym: It's just like what's going on?
Rym: Of course independently that show that people kept.
Rym: what was the show?
Rym: they kept trying to get us to watch about the geeks?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I just know that there was some TV show That was just a crappy sitcom where all the proper nouns were nerd proper nouns.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah It's like come on if you actually you know At least like the arrested development was actually somewhat of an original show and wasn't following the standard sitcom formula.
Rym: Yep, and it was actually pretty funny steeple steeple.
Scott: Okay touching.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: Okay My thing of the day, right?
Rym: Yeah fast and loose here.
Rym: It's like fast karate for the GeekNights.
Scott: It's what happens when we're going during the day and we're not freaking tired as all hell.
Rym: Yeah, plus we haven't you know, Scott's been doing moving and stuff and I was working in the night shift.
Rym: all last week We actually haven't talked.
Rym: We're at length for like a week.
Scott: We're refreshed now.
Rym: Scott would come home from work and I'd be like getting ready to go to work and then he'd like go to Queens.
Scott: and uh anyway, the There's always all sorts of awesome stuff made out of Lego.
Scott: big things nerdy.
Rym: I believe you mean Lego bricks.
Scott: No, Lego is plural.
Rym: No, it's Lego bricks.
Scott: anyway Lego is the polar of Lego regardless.
Scott: This dude made a pop-up book out of Lego.
Scott: Now.
Scott: It's not a whole pop-up book.
Scott: It only has one quote page but basically it's a. it's a rectangular box of Lego, but you can open it up and when you do a Castle comes out.
Scott: It's kind of crazy and awesome.
Scott: you can't really understand how it works until you see the video of it and then you'd be like, oh I get it.
Scott: and Just like thinking about how the dude made this thing.
Scott: It's like I can't even like begin to even a man like where would you start like?
Scott: I haven't oh my god.
Scott: So it's.
Scott: it's pretty amazing one of the best Lego things I've seen probably like top five at least of Lego things ever.
Scott: so You should probably see it.
Scott: It's a video on the internet and it's nice.
Scott: the video actually, you know Replays the transformation sequence over and over slowly from all kinds of angles so you can really see what's going on here.
Scott: Yeah, as opposed to being like, huh?
Scott: What the fuck?
Rym: Okay, so We kind of delayed purposefully now building up to this because people have been bugging me for this story Since I tweeted about.
Scott: I don't think I've even heard the whole whole story with details.
Scott: Of course, I will be challenged as we discussed the meaning of the show.
Scott: I will be challenging your hyperbole Although the problem is I was not there so I do not.
Scott: I do not know the truth So I cannot protect people from.
Rym: I have the pictures of Everything I could take pictures of and the evidence and the chain and everything of all the.
Rym: I've all this physical evidence to back It up.
Rym: that's pretty good including the fact that I got my bike back.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Where is it?
Scott: I haven't seen it.
Rym: It's an Emily's place cuz I can't ride it.
Rym: the jackass like cut up the seat.
Rym: I don't know how you could sit on it.
Rym: It was like if anyway Up the seat.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, I mean the reason Scott didn't hear the story was that everyone came over because we were going to The awesome the geeky wedding of cat and Steve.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So everyone was like meeting at our house and then all going to the wedding but everyone came at different times.
Rym: So people came and they're like, oh my god the bike.
Rym: So I told the story of the bike and then more people came and then someone would be like, yeah I remember telling the story about the bike.
Rym: I tell the story again and then more people came and more people came and then finally like I think Nuri and Pete and Scott Are back.
Rym: So I go.
Rym: I start to tell the story and then like we got distracted by something that we all went to the wedding.
Rym: Yep, so I didn't actually tell the story to the rest of those people.
Rym: Uh-huh, though to my credit.
Rym: I had to tell the story so many times.
Rym: The fact that it was consistent among all those tellings is a tiny bit of evidence for the fact that it is in fact true.
Scott: I'm not denying the truth of the story by I'm shy but I I know and I will assume that various details that sound Hyperbolic, you know, there will be much exaggeration of small things even though the story as a whole will probably be very accurate.
Scott: It will not be precise.
Rym: I can be perfect.
Rym: I will be 100% precise.
Rym: In fact, I'll make an effort to not in any way exaggerate a moment of it.
Rym: Uh-huh So to begin the party failed right there to begin that.
Rym: that's that.
Rym: that's fine.
Rym: To begin the fable of how Rym God's it really a fable.
Scott: Is there a moral?
Rym: I think there is a moral.
Scott: It can't be a fable that immoral.
Rym: There's a moral.
Rym: This is a GeekNights fable.
Rym: We haven't done one of these in like two years.
Scott: lion in the in the mouse You know leave the thumbtack in the line Got his motherfucking bike back.
Rym: So I was.
Rym: I was walking home from the train station and Thor appeared and Thor was like Rym.
Rym: I just wanted to tell you you're like the coolest dude ever All right, so I'd stayed in the city late.
Rym: We're out to hang out with like you going enough and everybody, you know All our friends that we don't get to see a lot even though they live in Brooklyn now like right there.
Rym: but that's just cuz.
Rym: they're busy and we're busy and Emily had to stay in the city to use a work computer to do some Japanese lesson thing.
Rym: So I took like two trains earlier home than she did.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So I get home at like 10 o'clock.
Rym: It's super late.
Rym: my car is still busted.
Rym: It was cold.
Rym: I didn't bring my rollerblades the train station or anything.
Scott: You just walk to Emily's house and sleep.
Rym: So I was gonna walk to Emily's house and basically just fall asleep and wait for her to get home and then I don't know Eat some food or something because I was hungry.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: But and I'm walking up from the train station.
Rym: and you know behind the train station There's like that like there's the sidewalk up and then over the bridge.
Rym: Yep So I'm walking back over there and that's where my bike was originally stolen from the bike lock area over there Mm-hmm.
Rym: So every time I would walk past that I would always kind of look at the bike lock area like Just in case my bike was there.
Rym: Obviously, it was never there.
Rym: I mean what kind of thief is stupid enough to put the bike where he stole it from?
Scott: Usually a bike thief just sort of sells it or gets rid of it or takes it far away.
Scott: I mean you would have to be a real moronic bike thief to like park it where you stole it from.
Rym: Well, well, we'll sell.
Rym: well, we'll see where this goes.
Rym: So I'm tired and as I'm walking up the sidewalk I see a bike chained like crazy chain like two Lengths of thick chain to a tree like two and a half football fields up from where the bikes are normally locked up by Itself.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And as I walk by I've already done the So, I don't think to do that again, I just keep walking.
Rym: I'm like hey bike hey kind of looks like my bike.
Scott: hey Was my bike Great, someone stole a bike and then crazy chained it to a tree.
Rym: Well, obviously they're afraid it was gonna get stolen.
Scott: I can see how you would be afraid is gonna get stolen if you know how easy it is to sell.
Rym: done cuz there's bike thieves about.
Rym: but no For a second.
Rym: I'm looking at it and I'm like, is this my bike?
Rym: I can't really tell because it's got electrical tape all over it and it's got a different seat on it.
Rym: So I'm standing here like looking at it.
Rym: But the serial number on the front is the same serial number like.
Rym: it's the same.
Scott: You had a serial number.
Rym: Yeah, all right I'm not gonna say it on the air but it has a four-digit serial number stamped onto a badge on it.
Rym: This is back.
Rym: Remember this bike is so old.
Rym: This is when Schwinn had the lifetime warranty.
Rym: to this day I can take that bike to any Schwinn dealer.
Scott: I know there's a lot less Schwinn now, you know it's like now.
Scott: it's all like Trek and Cannondale and oh Specialized I feel like the Kings.
Scott: now Schwinn is sort of disappeared.
Rym: Ah, they're still around.
Scott: Obviously, they're still around but I'm saying that the other brands of biker now in the front.
Rym: So I could do a whole show on what happened with Schwinn.
Rym: the short story I could tell you is that Schwinn started making bikes for People like Walmart and they started making lower quality like lower end bikes in addition to their high-end bikes.
Scott: I just read this great article talking about the croc shoes and it basically was the same thing.
Scott: is that croc shoes?
Scott: You know they were around and they were sort of like, you know, it's this indestructible foam.
Scott: personally I think the shoes look stupid, but you know people were interested in them.
Scott: The thing that the mistake they made was that they expanded so quickly.
Scott: It was like this thing that you could only buy in certain places and was sort of special and they made it completely Non-special by producing a bajillion of them and selling them in every fuck store.
Rym: But that was brilliant.
Rym: because look what happened.
Rym: They did that now.
Rym: Oh because they screwed it up.
Rym: What you're supposed to do is once you have that fad boom like as soon as the fad boom starts Stop production because it's going to stop within three months and you'll be done.
Scott: See but what you could know see the better idea that is that is a good idea is to just ride the fad and then Stop as soon as the fad is over.
Rym: That's all I want because I want to have money.
Scott: I don't want to be making money to have money But the correct business strategy is to you keep it so that you can only buy them in a few select places And you don't flood the market with supplies.
Scott: so they remain sort of this hot item and that's what determines the difference between a fad and You know like like an icon I'd rather rather have the fad because then the fad I just basically I say you're only.
Scott: are you looking for money?
Scott: Are you looking for King?
Rym: I'm looking for money so I can become King in a different arena.
Rym: Do you want to be the croc King?
Scott: Those guys did and they fail.
Rym: Yeah, cuz you don't want to be the croc King.
Scott: Yeah Anyway, maybe the crocodile now neither the croc pop.
Rym: So it's clearly my bike.
Rym: but here here's what the dude has done.
Rym: one He is wrapped black electrical tape around different parts of the frame in some like sad attempt to disguise the bike.
Scott: I like the electrical tape look but I mean, you know not for disguising.
Rym: He's covered up part of the Schwinn thing and you know I have those like mountain bike handlebar things on the top like stick out the front.
Rym: Yep, he put duct tape on those two and then electrical tape till I cover it all up to make the bike look different Mm-hmm.
Rym: He also the seat.
Rym: I had that seat on it.
Rym: yep, he cut all this like fabric of the seat off cuz it was a very distinctive like orthopedic kind of seat and Cut it down to like the bare structure to make it look different.
Rym: Basically, it was expensive.
Rym: It was like an $80 seat.
Rym: Yeah, so he basically ruined the thing and did all this other like dumb stuff to the bike to disguise it.
Rym: But he was unable to fully disguise it.
Rym: He did not cover the entire frame in electrical tape.
Rym: He put like one two foot length of tape wrapped around like one part of the frame and then another like foot and a half length of Electrical tape supposed to do the whole thing.
Scott: That's what makes it look cool with the.
Rym: I don't know If he just couldn't afford enough electrical tape or what guys.
Scott: he couldn't afford a bike but even better.
Rym: He like wrapped around like the front before and after where my water bottle thing is.
Rym: Yeah, but he didn't wrap around the water bottle thing, but that's where the big Schwinn logo was.
Rym: And he cut the water bottle thing like he was trying to remove it from the bike but it failed.
Rym: Like he literally like I can see he must have hacksawed through it a couple times, but he couldn't quite get it off.
Rym: So he gave up.
Rym: I guess he didn't have an allen wrench.
Scott: Yeah, right I was he not a bike person?
Scott: if he doesn't have an allen wrench, so he's also not an IKEA person.
Rym: So I'm standing here looking at my bike double chain with the super thick chain and two locks.
Rym: Two locks that had a key lock and a combination lock.
Rym: good ones like high-quality ones.
Scott: Well, you can afford good locks, but he can't afford electrical tape.
Rym: So I'm standing here looking at my bike thinking what the fuck?
Rym: So I lives no way to get the bike off the tree like this.
Rym: There's no way I'm cut the tree down.
Rym: I don't have any.
Scott: just call Called the policeman like.
Scott: this is my bike.
Rym: I never actually told the police like the bike was stolen cuz I never expected to get it back.
Scott: Oh, that was.
Scott: I would have report it anyway just for the sake of it.
Scott: Yeah, it's in on the file.
Rym: Yeah, I might report it later just to get it, but I don't care.
Rym: so I'm standing there.
Rym: It's like what the fuck am I gonna do?
Rym: and even if I call the police It's like 11 o'clock at night in Beacon unless I call 9-1-1.
Rym: There's gonna be no police coming Mmm, and are they gonna come with like a side cutter or something?
Scott: You can just get a bolt cutter, you know clink plus.
Rym: while I knew the serial number of the bike We could have gone to Home Depot and gotten one I no longer had like the Documentation like I could not have easily proven that it was actually my bike.
Scott: Do we have photos of you with the bike somewhere?
Rym: Yeah, we could dig those up But it would have.
Rym: it would have been time consuming and I would have had to convince the police right then to cut the bike Down and give it to me.
Rym: Mmm With or without a police report.
Rym: It might not have been that easy Mmm, so also my phone because I hadn't charged it in two days not a battery.
Scott: Yeah, good job.
Scott: Mr Never charges the phone never even picks up the phone even if it is charged.
Scott: So what's the point of having it?
Rym: Cuz I I don't use the phone.
Rym: I use it as it's a portable internet device that happens To be able to call people.
Rym: Yeah So I'm standing there thinking all right, I cannot leave this spot lest the jackass come and take the bike Mm-hmm, but I haven't figured out what to do yet.
Rym: So I'm looking around.
Rym: I don't see anyone like around.
Rym: I'm debating like should I just wait for Emily to come home?
Rym: But what if she walks out the other way from the train station?
Rym: Yeah, as I'm standing there this large african-american gentleman comes up behind me and says can I help you?
Rym: And he's about.
Rym: he's not quite a foot taller than me But he's a full head taller than he.
Scott: just wait this guy just walks up to you and as if he can help you Just when you're just standing there.
Rym: Yeah, I'm standing in front of this bike like looking at the bike.
Rym: I'm like examining the bike because I'm still also thinking I'm sure this is my bike, right?
Rym: I'm sure cuz I because I remembered that four-digit number But I wasn't a hundred percent sure cuz it's been so long since I've looked at that number.
Rym: So I'm like, there's no way this isn't my bike who has an orange Schwinn from 15 years ago and bacon?
Scott: nobody.
Rym: So.
Rym: and then I back up and I'm like looking at the bike like alright, what do I do?
Rym: and the guy comes up?
Rym: He's like, can I help you?
Rym: So I look at him and he is he is has the look of someone who's gonna give me some trouble and I am sure This is the guy who stole my bike.
Rym: He has not figured out yet that I that this is my bike and I have full knowledge.
Scott: Mmm,
Rym: I have my cell phone still in my hand because the battery was dead and I determined this fact when I went to turn It on to call someone And as I know, you know why it was dead because I used it the entire way home on the train looking at the internet With the pilot one bar of evdo.
Scott: Yeah, you should not do that.
Rym: So I look at him and you know, he has asked this question and before you give me any trouble I just say this is my fucking bike.
Rym: It was stolen from the train station like a month ago.
Rym: I can't believe.
Rym: I found it here and I kind of turned my back to him for a second Like I you know, like I don't know it's him.
Rym: And then I turned back and like and I had my phone in my hand.
Rym: I'm like, yeah, I called the police.
Rym: I'm just waiting for them to come and cut it down for me.
Rym: And he looks at me for a second and he like goes like he's about to argue or something and then he fucking runs.
Rym: Yeah, he just turns around and runs.
Scott: I want to run after him and beat him up.
Rym: He was a head taller than me.
Scott: basically what happened to mr.
Scott: Kung Fu?
Rym: Come foot.
Rym: it doesn't matter how good you are at a martial art.
Rym: anytime you get into an altercation with the person There's a chance you're gonna get hurt.
Scott: Yeah But is it where you know, you're not gonna.
Scott: it's not gonna kill you So you'll just get hurt in exchange for awesome up now because getting my bike back was my only concern now.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So now so wait the thing is right.
Scott: You got to get the keys from the dude to get the bike off now.
Scott: That's the reason to chase him now.
Rym: now also I did not want to interact with him too much.
Rym: And that's part of the moral because this is something my dad taught me as a kid and it is rung true to this day.
Rym: It is the the one of the entire morals of this whole Event the fabled moral.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: It's the fabled moral.
Rym: So now I'm standing there and the guys run off.
Rym: I still can't get the bike off So I wait until he's run out of sight and then I follow him Surreptitious like and after he's gotten around the corner, he's just walking kind of hunched over obviously pissed off.
Rym: He never once turns around looks behind him and I was.
Rym: I kind of like Slicked along and followed him from a distance just to see where he went.
Rym: He lives in those crappy shady like low-rent apartments next to rambling Alex live.
Rym: Uh-huh So I know exactly where he lives.
Rym: I've seen the dude like hanging out around town since then.
Rym: Mm-hmm so All right, I determined that he's gone back to his house and because I bluffed him with the phone thing about the police He's obviously not going to go back to where the bike is anytime soon.
Rym: Let's the police get him.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So now I go into Emily's apartments like what do I do?
Rym: So I scavenge around and it just so happens that Emily has a hacksaw.
Scott: Aren't these big?
Scott: are these?
Scott: what kind of chains are on there?
Scott: They're like New York City kind of change Yes, so how's the hacksaw gonna get through that?
Rym: It's got a hex.
Rym: I was cut through those things like butter.
Rym: Have you ever used a hacksaw?
Scott: Yeah, but I mean through that kind of chain really?
Scott: Yeah butter Uh-huh.
Scott: What's it been some hacks?
Rym: Uh, yeah Well, the the main part of the chain was about the thickness of this allen rash a little thicker than this.
Scott: Okay, no so that wasn't the big New York City chain got.
Rym: the big New York City chain is not that much thicker than this and would Take maybe two more minutes of hacksawing to get through.
Scott: I must have been a good hacksaw.
Rym: Hacksaws or hacksaws?
Rym: You've obviously never used.
Scott: the head views the hacksaw but I take it.
Scott: Oh, it took me a lot of time to get through metal Maybe you're not?
Scott: that's like I'm had some pipes and it would take me like, you know, 15 minutes.
Scott: really.
Rym: Yeah, it took me 10 minutes to hacksaw through this entire chain.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So anyway, I grabbed like this hacksaw and a bunch of wrenches Oh not wrenches, but a bunch of like pliers and things and I walked back down there.
Rym: And of course now if the dude like comes back you can attack him with a hacksaw.
Rym: Yes, I can hack.
Rym: saw him Because remember part of my you know bluff with the phone, you know saying I called the police was that in case I didn't really want to have to fight the guy but I was prepared to fight the guy and mean being machine.
Rym: basically, my plan was to Bluff with the phone.
Rym: if he calls my bluff at all or looks like he's about to call my bluff.
Rym: I was gonna be a kick in the nuts.
Rym: pretty much unprovoked and immediate Yep, but now he ran and nothing could have been more of telling of his guilt than the fact that he ran.
Rym: Ran.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Also proved that he's a coward.
Rym: Yep So I go back and the bikes there and this is what I learned.
Rym: This is a secondary moral a secondary fable part of this.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I Stole my bike back and Many many people observed me doing this.
Rym: No one so much as looked at me twice.
Rym: No one called the police No one even asked me what I was doing.
Rym: I'm sitting there in a trench coat hunched over some dudes bike hack sawing the chain off loudly and Obviously.
Rym: people walked by as a train had let out and did not eat like.
Rym: they just walked right by.
Rym: they didn't even look at me.
Rym: No one slowed down their car no one.
Scott: well, you know what it is, right?
Scott: Is this like if you're doing something like that and you're actually guilty, right?
Scott: Why would you do it?
Scott: in plain sight?
Scott: you would do it all Shady like if it was dark and like you were trying to hide from people.
Scott: then they'd be like a whole bike thief.
Scott: But the fact that you're doing it wide open Suggested that you would like lost your bike keys or something.
Scott: That's the assumption that good people make.
Rym: the answer to that clearly is I should steal every bike and beacon duh With a hacksaw loudly, this is the difference.
Scott: This is why right like a cowardly thief like that fails.
Scott: But the brave thief does not.
Scott: the brave thief will just go and act like he's supposed to be there and he can just commit Crimes in plain sight and no one will even realize it.
Scott: even cowardly thief tries to do things the TV way.
Scott: You know, it's the same thing with like the terrorists, right?
Scott: The the terrorists that succeed are the you know The very few that are like engineers with the smart thing, of course Those people are good and would never do such a thing.
Rym: even better though at one point You know after I've cut the bike off and remember one I kind of skipped this part.
Rym: But well after the guy ran away and I followed him to see where he lived.
Rym: I went back to the bike.
Rym: first I took my front seat at my seat and the front tire off So that if he happened to go back like if I was unable to cut the bike off till the next day At least he couldn't ride it away To slow him down.
Rym: Hmm So I carried that back up and you know I had cut the bike off again and I was walking back up toward Emily's house carrying a bike that was missing its front tire and carrying a hacksaw and Carrying the chain I had just cut.
Rym: yeah a cop drove by slowly and did not even like.
Rym: he saw me and did not even care.
Rym: Yeah, didn't even ask like is that your bike?
Rym: I Expected the cop to at least be like is that your bike?
Rym: and if he saw I said yes.
Rym: Maybe he just would have not cared the fact that he said nothing What's hilarious?
Scott: He didn't even look at you.
Rym: He looked at me like the way cops look at everybody when they drive by like with that You know non seeing like I look.
Rym: but I do not mean that's even it.
Scott: You know, usually we're all like a police can't be searching my shit.
Scott: You're telling me that's not like probable cause to at least talk to someone.
Rym: Yes, like if you tried to arrest me over the hacksaw and a bike with missing pieces, but at least the hey How's it going there mister?
Rym: You need some help with that bike.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Can I help you?
Scott: At least you know what that.
Scott: that makes me feel good about those police those.
Scott: that's a good policeman You just you know, let's it go.
Scott: cuz he does.
Scott: now he doesn't know the story.
Scott: It could be anything.
Rym: What's cool in general is it is a reasonable doubt?
Rym: Beacon police have been generally cooler to me than any police I've ever engaged with in my entire life.
Scott: I know right the beacon police are so much better like the fish kill police.
Rym: Oh my god, the Newburgh police coolest thing beacon police There are no speed traps when they do a quote-unquote speed trap There's only one place they go and it's this road where people shouldn't fucking be speeding.
Scott: Also, they like to put their speeding machines out, you know Which?
Scott: actually if you investigate like the statistics of those things they actually work really well.
Rym: I accept increasing safety for a low price except against what you know.
Rym: when I was young and I had my race car as a Kid those were basically high score meters.
Scott: You know statistically those things work really well and they're well worth, you know, putting them in strategic places.
Rym: They should put the train station because people go like 50 miles an hour through that like pie.
Scott: All right Well, they have one there all the time, but they never actually sit near them and pulling it over.
Scott: They just leave them out there, which is what you're supposed to do with.
Rym: but when they do, you know traps.
Rym: They don't do speed trap.
Rym: They do fucking four-way stop Jesus Christ traps.
Rym: Yeah and I love it when they do that because literally I'll see them pull over and many people as could possibly Pulled over and I was a cop.
Scott: I would do the only kind of pull.
Scott: I could totally Fulfill all quotas just by pulling people over for not putting their goddamn lights on.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: Yeah, so is that the whole story of the bike returning?
Rym: well, there's all the little follow-up stuff.
Rym: But basically, yeah, I got you know, I go back I carry the bike back and the chain and you know this guy.
Rym: he's such a genius.
Rym: I'll get to that part.
Rym: I can explain all the reasons why he's a genius.
Rym: It's better there's so it's.
Rym: there's so much to why this guy is so great.
Rym: I carried the bike back to Emily's house.
Rym: I'm victorious.
Rym: I have my bike.
Rym: I feel like a man.
Rym: I confronted the guy.
Rym: I bluffed I was willing to fight but I did not actually have to fight Because of my clever bluff of having called the police with my dead cell phone.
Rym: Mm-hmm and Emily comes home and I tell the story and everyone's happy and The stories don't.
Rym: I've got my bike.
Rym: I have to get it fixed.
Rym: There was damage done.
Rym: I'm gonna have to spend about a hundred bikes bucks fixing this bike.
Rym: Let's just get new bike because this bike is a great bike.
Rym: I'm gonna get a new bike, but I'm gonna keep this bike.
Rym: Yeah Actually, my plan is to buy a new bike but I'm going to buy a street bike.
Rym: as much as I like mountain biking.
Rym: I Don't mountain bike enough to justify a $2,000 mountain bike.
Scott: I'm gonna get a bike that is comfortable for just going around the streets like ah So I'm going to keep this, you know, the most kind of comfortable bike would actually be the recumbent bike But that's that's not gonna happen.
Scott: Why not?
Scott: It's like you get fucking killed.
Rym: So I'm gonna keep this bike as my mountain bike and I'm gonna basically now I'm gonna renovate the thing I'm gonna have to replace like all the stuff the jackass broke on it.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I've had Two bikes stolen one the fart.
Scott: the second bike I had stolen was the far less exciting story.
Scott: I was in summer camp actually and my bike was just sort of tied up on the side of the house.
Scott: and Then I was at Action Park.
Scott: Oh, is it Dorney Park?
Scott: I forget doesn't matter.
Scott: I was a summer camp.
Scott: I was on a summer camp trip to an amusement park.
Scott: I was in an arcade.
Scott: I used the pay, you know when you're out at summer camp You always use the payphone to call your parents whenever you're out and about.
Scott: so I did and my mom was like Yeah, your bike got stolen.
Scott: I was like fun the fucking side of the house.
Scott: What the fuck.
Scott: and that was it.
Scott: and then since then I didn't have a bike again until the one that I have now Which is broken.
Scott: but the bike I had before that one right was stolen.
Scott: basically, I was stupid and we were you know, basically I used my bike to go between all different friends houses who lived on the Same street and you know, we'd all ride bikes around and whatnot, you know to play wiffle ball Whatever and I had left it, you know lying on the lawn.
Rym: I always did that.
Rym: There's never any trouble, right?
Scott: So, you know, I was upstairs playing some video games.
Scott: It was you know, nice bright, you know, sunny day.
Scott: I was you know, and You know, I hear like some, you know kids laughing outside but the only kids on our block are the ones that I know the ones I go to ride bikes with and I look out the window and I see some like, you know three kids I don't know on bikes riding down the hill and I'm like, oh new kids, huh?
Scott: Oh, whatever I'm playing some video games playing some video games Go outside.
Scott: eventually, you know after like an hour or so Bikes gone.
Scott: My friend's bike is gone My friend's friend's bike is gone.
Scott: Everyone's bikes are gone because everyone had left them lying on their lawns respectively.
Scott: It's apparently some new kids came along and stole all our bikes at once the whole blocks worth of bikes.
Scott: Apparently stealing one bike is really not enough to get the police to show up but back in that day and time in the summer In a town where there's not that much crime really when a whole blocks worth of bikes got stolen all at once You know, the police decide to actually come and do something.
Scott: So, but you know, they're actually like three police cars on our street.
Scott: Everyone was talking to him.
Scott: They were taking statements and asking questions and you know, they had little notebooks writing everything down.
Scott: You know, my dad gets in his car and starts driving around looking.
Scott: the police are driving around looking, you know I'm just sitting at home going dum-dee-dum.
Scott: I guess I'll just play more video games.
Scott: Eventually, my dad comes back with my bike and I'm like, whoa, what the fuck.
Scott: Apparently as he told it as I remember this is like a long time ago like Almost 20 years ago.
Scott: The way he told it was that he was just.
Scott: he found the kids.
Scott: He was driving after him.
Scott: He got to like an intersection and cops are coming at him from the other end of the intersection And the kids like bail off into the woods.
Scott: My dad gets the bike back and I guess the police got the kid And my bike.
Scott: I got it back, but they bent the handle handlebars.
Rym: How do you bend the handlebars?
Scott: I don't understand.
Scott: apparently this thing a lot of people do and did is done when they get a bike like bend the handlebars.
Scott: They'll just like go and bend them.
Scott: It's like ah So like.
Scott: I sat on the bike and I was like, oh and I put my hands on the handlebars.
Scott: It's like what the fuck like you could tell immediately they were wrong.
Scott: So my dad sort of bent him back to where they were but it was like it was not New handlebars.
Scott: Yeah, it was a Huffy.
Scott: So whatever It was like who gave a shit.
Scott: All right, it was like a $50 bike.
Scott: But the point is, you know, they stole it and I used that bike a lot in those days to go around you know to people's houses and It was actually you know what that would.
Scott: that is something that will not happen ever again, you know.
Scott: Police actually like chasing down bike thieves.
Scott: Yeah, all of our bikes were returned and all those kids.
Scott: I saw them sitting in the back of the police cars going Ah shit, nah Juvy to them.
Scott: I don't know if they'll go to juvie But they'll probably just get you know a scolding and get sent back to their parents.
Scott: Whatever those kids are now Probably I imagine they are not presidents of large corporations.
Scott: I Would bet on that.
Rym: so an assessment of my bike.
Rym: as I get it back.
Rym: the dude had one Poorly tried to disguise it Very poorly like it's like.
Rym: so he won.
Scott: Why is it the bike?
Scott: thieves always vandalize the bike.
Scott: if I'm gonna steal a bike Number one, I'll probably do a Rym did I'll just hack saw it in plain sight.
Scott: number two, I'll take it far far away and never go back to where it came from with it.
Scott: and Three I won't do anything to it because it's probably in really good condition.
Scott: Why would I ruin it?
Scott: If anything I'll make it better.
Rym: Well, because I have an assessment of the person who stole my bike and I think it's pretty accurate I feel that he because he was he looked like he was about 27 28 like about our age.
Rym: Okay, and I'm pretty sure he's a habitual thief of opportunity.
Rym: I have a feeling that this guy will pretty much steal anything that is easily stolen without a lot of risk.
Scott: Why doesn't he robbed like all the stores in town that have no security whatsoever?
Rym: Because that's that's upping the ante.
Rym: There's a lot more risk there, but see like someone leaves a bike out.
Rym: someone leaves like a car running whatever.
Rym: I don't know if he'd even steal a car and he's on that level.
Rym: someone leaves something out.
Rym: Just take it you can use it.
Rym: and the reason I think this is that it wasn't just a punk kid like I expected stealing it for a jar ride because a punk Kid would have left it in the woods somewhere.
Rym: Yeah, or would like I don't sell it.
Rym: They would have done something with it.
Rym: They wouldn't have continued to use it as their mode of transportation.
Rym: mmm, and - he knew that you know, there was a danger of being caught.
Rym: he Obviously has done this before or at least put enough thought enough pre meditation into his actions after stealing it as a theft of opportunity and To disguise it poorly in order to prevent it from being discovered that he is in fact stolen it.
Rym: So he thought that through to some degree.
Scott: Well, I mean, you know, it's like they know they had to do something, but he thought you didn't do enough.
Rym: Now also to disguise that he cut up the seat as much as he could.
Rym: I don't know how he could ride it though Cuz.
Rym: basically it would shove a spike up your ass if you sat on it.
Scott: He probably didn't sit.
Scott: he price stood.
Rym: Yeah, push pushing push pushing along.
Scott: Yeah, obviously not a bite expert.
Scott: Now please if you're a bike expert you have your own bike.
Scott: I don't think you become a bike.
Rym: I don't think he knew how to shift the gears.
Rym: Yeah, because one the gear was in the gear I'd left it in which is a gear you can't really use to ride it.
Rym: It's like the going up a steep hill gear the granny gear.
Rym: Yes Well or the mountain biker gear.
Rym: and two.
Rym: I don't think he knew how to shift the front gears because he cut off the front shifter wire completely.
Rym: He removed it.
Scott: what?
Rym: Because I think the way the way it was left He probably wasn't strong enough to ride it and he couldn't figure out how to shift it to an easier gear.
Rym: So we cut the wire which caused it to default to the easiest gear.
Rym: Yeah So I have to replace like the shifter wire and everything.
Scott: Yeah, I just buy a new one.
Rym: Why this bike is still like the frame.
Rym: It'd be like 400 bucks to buy another frame like that.
Rym: Whatever plus.
Rym: I mean like I said, I'm gonna keep this as my mountain bike.
Rym: I'm gonna fully refurbish it cuz that's still a lot cheaper than buying a new mountain bike.
Rym: and I prefer I've ridden like the 11,000 $12,000 mountain bikes and I still to this day prefer a hardtail over a full suspension mostly because I don't do the crazy hardcore mountain biking I do like I'm a mid-core.
Scott: I don't think I'll ever need a bike with the rear suspension.
Scott: Maybe if I had a motorcycle I would need what?
Rym: Something.
Rym: and I'm gonna buy a street bike like new like a three or four thousand dollar nice street bike and I'll use that as My street biking around.
Scott: but yeah, I'll get a new one in the spring that is appropriate for city bikings.
Rym: But dude, the dude probably maybe even left.
Rym: he had a bike originally that he left behind somewhere because he stole it from the train Station, you know, I left it unlocked with all the other bikes like not obviously Not locked up.
Rym: you would have had to go over and like check and be like hey This bike isn't locked and take it so definitely habitual thief of opportunity Coward because he ran away from me when he could have easily at least from perception You're just looking at me He possibly could have from his perception overpowered being just taking the bike away and then been safe.
Rym: But no he ran as soon as there was any thought of the police possibly finding him.
Scott: I mean what you know, it probably you know, either a It was like, you know a repeat offenders.
Scott: So, you know the police it was not gonna be too good.
Scott: because I mean really if that's all he'd ever done was stolen that Bike really?
Scott: What's the penalty?
Scott: It's not that bad, you know, what are they gonna put you?
Scott: I mean they go to jail really probably for that, you know, and if you do it'll be like for days not for you Know months and months and months like if you would.
Rym: but I just think the psychology I were the reason.
Rym: I think he's a repeat Offender and habitual and all this is just the manner in which he disguised the bike was so premeditated and yet so poor.
Scott: No, that's the thing is like anyone who's actually good at crime Doesn't get caught and is not really considered to be a criminal.
Scott: This is what organized crime is all about Even worse.
Rym: anyone who's smart enough to pull off like the crazy crime could probably make more money with a job Exactly.
Scott: That's that's another problem Yep.
Rym: So I gotta like repair all this.
Scott: anyone who's smart enough to do Terrorism is smart enough to make a lot of money with being an engineer.
Scott: Anyone who's smart, you know, this is the same problem The whole world has all not.
Scott: the vast majority of people with evil intent are also incredibly stupid because anyone who's incredibly Smart can actually get what they want without being you know evil.
Scott: It's like if you're really smart, you can get rich just by working.
Scott: The only people who are gonna resort to crime to get bunch of money People were not smart enough to get a good job.
Rym: I mean look despite the fact that he disguised the bike as best as his brain could manage He parked it where he stole it.
Rym: But again, look he recognized that I'm the whoever he stole it from might see it If he left it with all the bikes like chained up to the bike thing.
Rym: So he parked it like 200 yards up the way like the person wouldn't see it.
Rym: But that's on the path.
Scott: You'd have to walk if you went that way anyway.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: It's probably been parked there every day.
Rym: I just never walked that way until that one night.
Scott: It's quite possible.
Rym: So that and three he had this crazy chain, right and two locks and the chain was like rafting rafting rafting rafting around the bike and around the tree.
Rym: Upon investigation after I came back with a hacksaw the entire thing the entire chaining effort Rested upon one link.
Rym: Yeah, so I cut that one link off and the bike was free.
Scott: Yep So, you know chains weakest link and such and such.
Rym: yes But you'd think if you had two locks He would have thought that he has to have at least more than one link holding the whole thing together.
Scott: Yep The of course there is an exception to what I was saying before about smartness and criminals is that they're obviously Smart criminals like, you know, say Enron guys are made off guys.
Scott: But the thing is you can see that they actually they were very smart.
Scott: Look how long it took to get made off, you know, he was really smart about not getting caught.
Scott: It's just you know, when people when the scrutiny increases, you know, it's you know, it is very difficult to find them.
Scott: It was not very difficult to get someone who's dumb thing is people like that.
Rym: It would be easy to get them except that the people they sucker Profit in the short term and thus probably know there's something shady going on But have the cognitive dissonance and decide not to act on that because they're getting too much of a return.
Rym: Yep That's the real problem.
Scott: It's one of the problems.
Rym: Yeah, so back to the device that my dad gave me as a kid.
Rym: and this was all.
Rym: this is also independently advice that was given to me by an unrelated police officer at one point in my childhood and the advice was such if you ever Come into conflict some sort of direct altercation with someone who is not intelligent and of a very low Socio-economic class and I very much I want to stress it has to be both, you know You can't just rag on someone who's poor might not be their fault and being poor sucks.
Rym: But if they're poor and Independently of being poor are stupid You do not want to entangle your affairs with them in any capacity and any.
Rym: any time you need Justice or you need some recompense from someone like that Get it as anonymously and as I guess surreptitiously as possible and never in any way officially engage with them.
Rym: if Possible do not ever let them know who you are or where you actually live.
Rym: Mmm because my experience from living in Suburbs next to suburbs that had very different socio-economic classes.
Rym: any time There was a conflict between people in the two different neighborhoods The people from the bad neighborhood would basically just come in the night and vandalize and there was no way to prove They did it or get them back.
Rym: Mmm people with nothing to lose who are also stupid and or also vindictive can do a lot of economic harm to people who have assets and have something to lose and There's really no way to stop them.
Rym: She had no way to get them back.
Scott: Shoot them.
Rym: That's not an answer.
Rym: Well, of course that happened.
Rym: I mean when I was a kid one of those stupid people His day, you know what the statute of limitations all that his name was Nick.
Rym: Oh the kid who's his mom his mom different shot him and his dad.
Rym: After the kid came with the dad after they divorced and tried to set the car on fire Came back to the house set the car on fire Menace the wife.
Rym: So the wife shot the dad and the kid dead.
Rym: yeah, and those those sorts of people the feet not the people who would basically come back and Vandalize or you know do the sort of nothing to lose surreptitious economic harm.
Rym: you basically don't want to have any interaction with those people because no legal system justice is going to prevent them from coming back and Putting on to you their socio-economic harm Mmm, so the best really
Scott: is strange in a way that like the person who's got like, you know If you you know, like you see your Bill Gates against homeless bum, right?
Scott: Homeless bum can fucking do all this shit to Bill Gates.
Scott: He's got nothing to lose.
Scott: and what can Bill Gates do to homeless bum?
Scott: Nothing.
Scott: I mean what if he shoots homeless bum then Bill Gates?
Scott: that hurts Bill Gates more than hurts almost bum.
Rym: Yeah, well, I would argue Morris the idea that As you have to always bear in mind in general that you shouldn't seek revenge you should really only seek justice in that try to make the world go back to the status quo.
Scott: or What I'm saying is that you know, basically this homeless bum, right?
Scott: He's gonna keep your Bill Gates It's almost bum keeps vandalizing your house keeps terrorizing you right?
Scott: There's nothing you can do to him.
Scott: You can you're never gonna he's never gonna do something so serious to go to jail for a long time.
Scott: He'll go to jail for a short time and then he'll come and harass you and the amount of time he's away Does not really help you out much at all.
Scott: It just gives you like a short respite.
Rym: So look at the harm.
Rym: I mean.
Rym: if I have a nice car and someone like this decides that they want to get me they just key up my you know $40,000 car.
Scott: throw some eggs.
Scott: eggs are real cheap.
Scott: The car is expensive.
Scott: He doesn't have a car for you to egg.
Scott: He's almost bum.
Scott: So what what is Bill Gates supposed to do in that situation?
Scott: You know, it's like, okay He's never gonna go to jail forever.
Scott: He's never gonna move away.
Scott: He's never gonna stop harassing me.
Scott: He has no money for us to take away, right?
Scott: There's a restraining order.
Scott: doesn't help because then he just goes to jail for a short time and gets out again to harass me.
Scott: Again, I have all sorts of things that harass.
Rym: They gonna say you engage with one of these people anonymously and they are out of kidding with you.
Rym: If you follow up with legal action now, there's a record and he can find out your name and your address and all that stuff.
Scott: Yeah, so what can Bill Gates really do if a homeless bum wants to bother him?
Scott: You can hire, you know, Bill Gates is so rich that he can have a private security force like bodyguards and stuff And thus he specifically when you're on that level of richness.
Scott: He doesn't have to worry.
Scott: But what if you're like say a lawyer just a normal kind of lawyer in a town you make half a million dollars a year.
Scott: You're wealthy, but you're not Bill Gates rich.
Scott: You don't have bodyguards or a private security force.
Scott: You just drive a Porsche and you have a five-bedroom house of the big lawn, man I'm gonna have a five-bedroom house real soon.
Scott: and you got a harsh and you got a homeless bum Fothering you and you have this problem.
Scott: I just described with Bill Gates Really?
Scott: It's like, you know, you can shoot the bum, you know, obviously that's revenge.
Scott: But at the same time that will and is one of the few courses of action you can take that will stop the problem.
Scott: However, it's like what else can you possibly do?
Scott: You can't afford private security.
Scott: the legal system will not keep the homeless bum away from you long enough.
Scott: You could I guess move which is like why should you move?
Scott: just gives a homeless bum and this sort of Same problem.
Scott: We're like some like illegal immigrant drives a car with no insurance and crashes into you.
Scott: You know, it's the same problem.
Scott: It's like what the fuck can you do?
Rym: Well, the sad the really sad thing is that I wish I wasn't just speaking from experience But having you know, I was born in downtown Detroit.
Rym: Like I lived in downtown Detroit for a long time which it's always funny like People who don't know me like strangers I bring that up and they always suddenly get this perception that I'm hard somehow.
Rym: Yeah, born in downtown Detroit.
Rym: I'm just I'm just some IT guys, right?
Scott: I actually have a solution for this problem.
Rym: because but at the same I just want to point out that you know Having lived there and then having moved to very wealthy suburbs next to very poor suburbs and you know But there are cool people in the nice areas and cool people like.
Rym: there were cool people in both classes.
Rym: Yeah but the people who were not cool who were in the lower class were the ones who and they would often come into the Neighborhoods and just wreak havoc and there was nothing that could be done.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So what's your solution?
Rym: sky solution?
Scott: So when I went to Israel back in oh, oh, so I depart them to Israel.
Scott: No, but you know, they basically told us, you know Don't smoke weed.
Scott: Don't do nothing.
Scott: Good God.
Scott: and we're like, you know, why?
Scott: what are they?
Scott: You know, of course, no one did right even though one Israeli guy tried to get us to They.
Scott: basically they were like look if you do it You'll get exiled and you know be allowed back here again and you'll be exiled immediately.
Rym: So where do we exile American citizens to let alone all of the constitutional ramifications of this?
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Scott: We just exiled them.
Scott: You don't have to exile them to anywhere.
Rym: What do you mean?
Rym: So what do you send them into the ocean?
Rym: It's like you got that's.
Rym: you might as well just hang him.
Rym: It's the same thing.
Scott: Well, no, it's the same as like when you're at a bar late at night.
Scott: It's like you don't gotta go home, but you can't stay here.
Rym: So yeah Scott your example of homeless bum He can't afford to go anywhere.
Scott: That's why exiling is the best cuz he can't afford to come back.
Rym: So where do you take him?
Rym: I mean how many like there were a lot of places in Detroit were in the Detroit suburbs where there'd be homeless people who'd like Get themselves out to the fancy suburbs and it basically what the police would do is pick them up Drive them to downtown Detroit and just leave them there.
Scott: That's not far enough But you know what?
Scott: Actually, that's not a bad idea.
Scott: Come to think of it.
Scott: There's no one nice left in Detroit.
Scott: Let's just send everyone to do.
Rym: No, I have this crazy.
Rym: I think what we should do.
Rym: I want to do a show on this because I want to talk.
Rym: I want to present my full Idea.
Rym: take the homeless bums.
Rym: No, no.
Rym: No, it's actually a real.
Rym: I think it's a good idea.
Rym: I want to present this idea to you and to the listeners and I want I Want people to argue against this idea because I think it's something we could debate.
Rym: Imagine if the federal government took over the city of Detroit kind of like Robocop style like Detroit is done.
Scott: Well, you need a Robocop.
Scott: First of all, well Spitzer listen, I nominate myself.
Rym: You want to be Robocop?
Scott: Hells.
Scott: Yeah, I got a gun in my leg.
Rym: It's pretty easy.
Rym: step one run afoul of like 40 guys with guns.
Rym: step two get shot for like 10 minutes straight.
Rym: step three Robocop.
Scott: See, I don't think the step three exists yet.
Scott: Otherwise, I would do the step one And I need a guarantee of the step three.
Rym: little-known fact.
Rym: That was the first rated X movie.
Scott: I don't think it was rated X.
Rym: It was originally.
Rym: they had to tone it down.
Rym: That shooting scene in the beginning was too hardcore for Robocop was hardcore.
Scott: I mean that gun just like a blue people's brains.
Rym: Anyway, but the thing is I watched that like oh, no gun.
Rym: I watched that scene again recently on YouTube.
Rym: It's pretty tame by nowadays standards.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Oh, yeah I mean, well you seen each of the killer.
Rym: I mean, yeah thing is it's not that far off from each of the killer.
Rym: I know right Jesus, but say we took Detroit and it became a federal city.
Rym: It is no longer under the jurisdiction of the state of Michigan.
Rym: It is a separate.
Scott: I don't think that's gonna work constitutionally.
Rym: Why not?
Scott: It's you can't do that.
Rym: Do you convince Michigan to seed it?
Rym: seed the land to the federal government?
Scott: I don't know that's gonna work.
Rym: Why that would work?
Rym: You'd have to bribe the state.
Rym: just remember back in the day like Michigan Kind of went to war with Ohio and the feds were like you get this land.
Rym: Ohio gets this land.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean that would be like if they just I don't think that can happen.
Rym: Basically, I think we could do it.
Rym: one we could do some sort of martial law thing to do it.
Scott: I don't think they can do.
Rym: or some sort of eminent domains do it.
Rym: or You just convinced the state of Michigan to sell it to the federal government because the state of Michigan has no money.
Rym: They need money desperately and much of the rest of Michigan does not like Detroit.
Rym: So it would be win-win for everyone.
Rym: Yeah, we make it a communist city Communist city.
Rym: the feds take it over and you put out the call.
Rym: anyone in America No matter what.
Rym: if you move to Detroit We will give you a place to live and a living wage.
Scott: and who's gonna pay for that?
Rym: Taxpayers.
Scott: and we already don't have any money as it is.
Rym: We have plenty of taxpayer money Uh-huh.
Rym: We replace most social most.
Rym: Well, not most social programs, but any social programs we can with the federal city.
Rym: Oh So you saying we should cancel other federal we say no matter how bad your lot is.
Rym: So you're saying like no more food stamps.
Scott: If you don't even have enough money for food go to Detroit and there you can.
Scott: then you can have food.
Rym: There should still be food stamps.
Rym: There should be a level between I need some help to get back on my feet and I have to go to Detroit.
Scott: I mean no more welfare.
Rym: the welfare is now go to Detroit but more like welfare Helps you out in that like welfare is the alright.
Rym: I live somewhere.
Rym: I need a little help to get back on my feet.
Rym: If after an amount of time you can't you still have not gotten back on your feet.
Rym: Alright, no more welfare.
Rym: You've got to go to Detroit and then we guarantee your job.
Scott: Detroit would just become like even like the worst place in the universe.
Scott: Maybe not.
Scott: Well, so what are we gonna have those people do?
Rym: Public infrastructure works to start and then from there they live in Detroit and we ship them off with the survey crew.
Scott: Public infrastructure is not an export.
Scott: So basically it's a whole bunch of money.
Scott: So you have a huge debt.
Rym: So then data entry for the government recodifying the C We.
Rym: this is one of those grand plans.
Rym: stage one is set this up.
Rym: Stage two is use this massive pool of cheap labor to do the data entry and the license plate making for my massive Rewriting and codification of US law.
Scott: I'm sure yeah thing is that requires smart people or well-directed people.
Scott: Also, you know people move there with their families and then you ship the the people who are who's gonna who's gonna go become like You need thing is you need also smart jobs there too to run things.
Scott: Who's smart is gonna want to go live there?
Rym: So here's what'll happen, right?
Rym: So you've got this big city in Detroit and you've got people with guaranteed income Guaranteed jobs.
Scott: Oh, sorry.
Scott: So it's really communism those people.
Scott: Why would they even work?
Scott: I would just sit home and to get the guaranteed income you have to work.
Rym: You don't get the income.
Rym: Yeah, you have to have a job, but I'll just do a bad job.
Rym: Well, maybe then you make less income.
Rym: Maybe we have communism.
Rym: You could still reward people a little bit more.
Scott: Maybe you remember these people are not these people.
Scott: the reason that you know At least some of them the reason that they're poor is because they're just not good at things.
Rym: And the people are good go there get a job and also you offer free education and training in any life's gonna be the educators.
Rym: Well, here's the thing.
Rym: at first we offer large subsidies to convince people to move there.
Scott: Yeah This is sounds like you're just a big money hole.
Rym: No Cuz here's the thing you realize.
Rym: surrounding Detroit are some of the richest most prosperous suburbs in the country.
Scott: Aren't they empty now?
Rym: No, the suburbs are crazy for those people work in Detroit.
Rym: They just don't live in Detroit.
Scott: Isn't Detroit crumbling?
Rym: yes, yeah, but there are still offices down there and public infrastructure and things and also more and more There are businesses around the suburbs.
Scott: All right,
Rym: but yeah, those are some crazily economically prosperous places around there Mm-hmm,
Scott: but
Rym: you basically no one no one from there would want to live in Detroit But they would live next to it and sell services to it
Scott: Mmm,
Rym: and you basically be pumping money through Detroit and then back into the economy.
Rym: Cuz think about it right but then you had to get money back the other direction From a really sick cat because then it goes back into the economy and people pay taxes on it.
Rym: No Yeah, and think about this way.
Rym: Here's a really cynical thing.
Rym: I'm about to say these kinds of people are gonna end up in Detroit or not?
Rym: The kinds of people are gonna save that money.
Rym: But anyway, I actually have a much more detailed and less crazy planned.
Scott: I think a much less crazy plan would be this if you were to Legalize drugs then you could just say yes drugs are legal, but all drug factories must be in Detroit.
Rym: Ah Detroit's the special economic zone for hemp production.
Scott: So they grow all the weed wherever then grow it anywhere growing's, you know Fine, let it let them grow wherever they want.
Scott: But the all the packaging and manual labor must be in Detroit and Detroit will become like the weed capital.
Rym: Ah Detroit weed City.
Scott: Yep, and then that's actually, you know much better than Manual labor of.
Scott: you know law writing, you know.
Scott: We could just have people Sticking weed in boxes and then those same people would buy and smoke the weed that they package and they would be fine.
Rym: that raises ethical questions of getting people addicted to a drug and then making them work to create that drug at a profit for You and then they spend all the money you pay them on the drug.
Scott: if the person just gonna be a homeless bum forever I think that's better to just live in weed City.
Scott: Anyway package weed Anyway, so no actually they probably know a lot about it.
Rym: Moral.
Scott: the third they know about computers.
Rym: aside from you know, not entangling your affairs with people like this Steal bikes.
Rym: It's trivial to steal bikes.
Rym: No one will stop you.
Scott: Yeah, why should I even buy a bike in the spring?
Scott: I'm just gonna like find like a really nice one and steal it.
Rym: I guess you can't.
Rym: you got to steal it from like Cold Spring You know, that's the sure.
Scott: I can't steal one from the city.
Scott: I'll have to go like off into the middle of nowhere and steal one of the city.
Rym: There's so many identical bikes.
Scott: Well, the thing is you get you might get caught there.
Scott: there's a lot more eyeballs, you know, I gotta find out now.
Rym: No Emily was telling me that recent an experiment dude would chain a bike up in like Populated crowded parts of the city like Astor place and then come back like a few days later and hacks all the thing off.
Rym: I just take it.
Rym: No, no one cared.
Rym: No one even looked at him.
Scott: Yeah The thing the thing you got to worry about though is like I'm gonna be looking if I'm gonna steal a bike.
Scott: I'm gonna steal a nice bike.
Scott: I'm not gonna bother going to the effort of stealing for some cheapo crap bike.
Scott: I'm gonna go for like the fancy bike.
Scott: So if I'm gonna do that The guy who rides it might come back.
Scott: So I gotta do it.
Scott: You know one where I know the guy isn't coming in the time.
Scott: It takes a hexa further moral.
Rym: if you're gonna chain up a bike that you stole at least To have it not all rely on one link, dude Could we maybe like make like a like a bike chain that actually fucking works and can't be hexa?
Rym: Anything can be hacksaw.
Rym: No.
Scott: No, I mean like.
Scott: What if you made it out of the same stuff you make a hacksaw out of can you hacksaw?
Rym: Hey, yes, you can act saw hacksaw.
Scott: What if we made it?
Rym: you Scott?
Rym: What I will hacksaw through a hacksaw blade if you want, why don't we?
Scott: Make an electrified Bike chain.
Scott: So if you try to hack saw it, it shocks you Just have a taser bike.
Scott: Exactly it like right in the middle of the chain is an electric wire as a battery and if you'd hacksaw through the middle It'll just freakin knock you out.
Rym: So I cut the battery off.
Scott: first the batteries in the chain.
Rym: So then I wear gloves.
Scott: Yeah An exploding bike chain if you cut through it is actually just an exploding bike.
Rym: Steal the bike it blows up.
Scott: How do we put a GPS in the frame?
Rym: You're gonna spend that much money on a bike if it's a fancy bike.
Scott: It'll be worth it.
Scott: if you buy like a $1,000 is not a fancy bike.
Scott: It would be worth it if I had $1,000 bike even though it's not that fancy.
Rym: that bike is $1,000 bike.
Scott: They'll be worth it to have a GPS in there.
Rym: Yeah, you should come to the bike store.
Rym: If you want to buy a new bike they have those $2,000.
Scott: I've seen Scott.
Rym: No, I test rode a $18,000.
Scott: What the hell could it possibly be made of?
Scott: made of gold penises?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: It was made of titanium.
Rym: It weighed nothing.
Rym: I could pick this whole bike up with like one finger upside down Uh-huh.
Rym: It was a full-on even with the tires.
Rym: Yeah with a full suspension Mm-hmm.
Rym: This was the bike like ride down a ski slope mountain like rocky craziness.
Scott: You see a lot of the bikes have gimmicks that are just like for yuppies and don't aren't really helpful.
Rym: No This was a real mountain bike like.
Rym: it had this system where because you have this problem of loss when you ride a bike with A full suspension where the suspension moves and it takes energy away from your riding.
Rym: That's why I like to ride a hardtail bike.
Rym: There's no rear suspension So I have more power to put into my riding.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and I like the feel of it and all that it kind of bounces.
Rym: So if you have a really fancy bike you can have these incredibly complex Systems that will only allow the suspension to engage when there is a movement from the bottom and first on the bottom But not from the top.
Scott: Mmm, that's real fancy.
Rym: Yes, and it's like this crazy pneumatic system and that system was like five grand by itself.
Scott: Whoa Well, I can do mad.
Rym: Oh, it worked though.
Rym: I rode the bike.
Rym: I like rode over like these crazy rocks and didn't even feel him like it was an amazing bike.
Scott: Yeah, you know that like that pride.
Scott: beyond that where is $18,000?
Scott: obviously not gonna buy it But just imagine like riding around the city and it's like just.
Scott: it's like you're riding a bike But it's smooth like riding in like a Lincoln town car or a Cadillac.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Anyway, we've gone on way too long.
Scott: We needed to go along.
Scott: We haven't done an episode of forever.
Rym: So let's end this now.
Scott: It's 2000 forever.
Rym: So with the moral of this don't lock it.
Rym: Don't leave your bike on lock as a visual thief up.
Scott: Don't steal bikes.
Scott: Don't get your bike stolen.
Scott: Don't actually shoot homeless people.
Rym: Yes, don't entangle your affairs with people who are poor and indigent.
Rym: Yep Poor and no stupid and indigent.
Rym: Yeah, not poor and indigent because they're cool people who are poor and indigent.
Rym: So stupid and indigent do not entangle your affairs, right?
Rym: And if you are if you confront someone who stole your bike Bluff that you called the police.
Rym: if you have not already called the police, but be ready for dick punching.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Scott: Don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.