Rym: Hey, it's Wednesday, November 4th.
Rym: I'm Rym Scott over Skype and this is GeekNights tonight a rambling review of giant robo the animation.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: Well, it's Wednesday.
Scott: Oh Man I just I need it to be Friday.
Scott: Oh, no, I don't we're going to a convention.
Rym: Are we?
Rym: that's gonna be fun, though?
Scott: Yeah, but it's like I. really it's a bad timing.
Rym: What do you possibly have to do that needs that weekend?
Scott: I still don't even have any freaking curtains or rugs or couch or I got so much shit going on.
Rym: I thought you ordered a couch.
Scott: Yeah, it's not waiting for it to show up.
Scott: I got you know, maybe it could have been delivered on Saturday, but no now it can't be delivered Saturday.
Rym: Are you least gonna be free by the time anime Boston comes around and PAX East?
Scott: Yeah, I think I'll be okay by that.
Scott: I just need you know, like a couple months to you know get sorted in.
Scott: such I still have boxes on the floor, but only a few of actually Surprisingly unpacked a great deal of things because I'm working on all our anime Boston stuff.
Rym: That's the one kind we haven't planned a lot yet because it kind of just works out.
Rym: Yeah That's.
Scott: uh, I don't even I haven't been thinking about conventions at all.
Rym: This is why I'm here to handle all this.
Rym: I'm already putting in all our stuff for every con that'll take stuff.
Scott: I have been working on the website though.
Scott: I made a big progress.
Scott: So it like I think what I my strategy now is pretty much, you know, I've been I've been so perfectionist, I mean, you know not absolute perfectionist, but it's like I Twiddle and twiddle and tool till it's just right and I put it out there.
Scott: for now I think what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna make a few improvements and as soon as I get you know I basically need like one or two more.
Scott: then I'm gonna put it out there and then I'm gonna make you know I'm gonna follow the release.
Scott: early release often cult of done.
Rym: Well, I was about to say at work right one of my guys who developed stuff like he's.
Rym: he was complaining about not getting stuff done.
Scott: I'm not because releasing is a feature, you know.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: That's exactly what I said.
Rym: He's like he's having all these problems.
Rym: I looked at him.
Rym: I was like, you know Getting the product out is in and of itself a feature and he looks at me and he's like that's really wise.
Rym: And then he was like all inspired.
Scott: Yes, we stole all our wisdom from the Internet.
Rym: I see a lot of my wisdom from the Greeks to Greeks and the Internet.
Scott: You know what that where I live is a very Greek neighborhood and actually if you get off my subway station There's one of those parks there, you know, it's typical New York Park with the playground and you know Wall ball and some benches and that's all man.
Rym: I want to play some wall ball.
Scott: Yeah, but you know what it is.
Scott: it's actually it's Athens Park and there's a zoo statue and there's an Aristotle statue and there's some pillars.
Rym: and What kinds of pillars, you know, like Parthenon kinds?
Scott: and then there's a. there's a. this is like a plaque on the zoo statue.
Scott: that's sort of like, you know, Donated by like, you know president of Greece or whatever or something like that.
Scott: So it's like oh it is very cool to go hang out in the Athens Park.
Rym: you know what you should do because it's the kind of prank I like is Make a little tiny fake plaque.
Rym: You just kind of sit on top of it.
Rym: That just says look you mighty.
Scott: The thing is it's everything's in good condition there so it doesn't.
Rym: so let's look you might lose.
Scott: The pillars are actually in perfect condition.
Scott: But the thing is there.
Scott: it's sort of like these three pillars of the thing on top and that's it.
Scott: It's sort of it's sort of made to look like a ruin, you know, so I guess you could put look you mighty on that.
Scott: Yeah, that's pretty cool.
Scott: It's cool park.
Rym: Anyway, I talked about anime news, you know, we try to do that but The anime news now we're like nothing happens anymore at all.
Scott: Well, cuz there's no the only news you can really get right.
Scott: you realize most news sites even like Kotaku or a joystick or or?
Scott: Anything all they really do is regurgitate press releases.
Scott: Yeah And they're not doing business or a lot of business.
Scott: there aren't a lot of press releases.
Rym: The secondary news about conventions and things like that, but even the conventions, you know We're kind of we're a convention season has been done for a while And now that I'm working we're working more with like Otakon and all these other cons and staff.
Rym: I'm learning that more and more these cons don't do anything until not that long before the cons happen.
Rym: So we're like between.
Rym: the only time where there's news is when all the secondary like meta news about anime cons and stuff happens.
Scott: Network is like now.
Scott: it's not really the anime news network anymore.
Scott: Instead.
Scott: It's really like.
Scott: it's the you know news about.
Scott: you know, it's just generic stuff that happens to people who may be associated with anime.
Scott: It is like someone who wrote a manga got sick to me.
Rym: It's the anime news Nina site that happens to have news on it and a nice encyclopedia.
Scott: You know this.
Scott: yeah I think definitely they need to.
Scott: They need to start pushing their like columns out into the front more because that's really most of their content now.
Scott: and you know I guess we could talk about anime news network for a whole bunch.
Scott: But yeah, it's Anime news anymore.
Scott: So you got to do something else.
Rym: Yep, but there is a tiny bit of news, but I actually didn't find it on the anime news network.
Rym: I found it on the Scott news network.
Rym: You know, we join the Otakon staff.
Rym: we would join the panels department and they have as far as I can tell they haven't really Done anything yet.
Rym: like Otakon is not gearing up to do anything yet until the new year starts.
Rym: Meanwhile the comic-con the San Diego comic-con.
Rym: that happens like comic-con Maybe a month before Otakon actually less than a month before Otakon.
Rym: this time I think their preview night badges are already sold out.
Rym: the four days plus the special day and The regular four day membership badge is almost sold out already.
Rym: The con isn't until the end of July and it's basically sold out.
Scott: They're already on the move.
Scott: meanwhile This one convention is one four and a half four day one night X, you know four day five night event.
Scott: It's basically a year-round job.
Rym: Meanwhile, I email, you know, our staff contacts know to count.
Rym: I'm like we want to get these people to do a cool like lecture at Otakon and they're like email us back in January.
Scott: Yeah, good job.
Rym: I'm like great.
Scott: Thanks Like Otakon is always talking, you know, we were volunteer run.
Scott: we work so hard we don't get paid.
Scott: Well, look, you're not really, you know, you know say all you want, you know I I put up so I can I don't have to shut up and you know what you guys do not work hard enough Not as hard as people work at other conventions.
Scott: paid or unpaid Enforcers work harder and better than the Otakon staffers.
Scott: a step the fuck up.
Rym: I hate to.
Rym: you know Do that?
Rym: I hate to wrang on Otakon because I do like Otakon and I do enjoy it.
Rym: Oh, it's great.
Scott: But I'm just saying it's like you need to step up the game.
Scott: That's you know the game.
Scott: They've been playing the same game They've been playing for years and everyone else is getting ahead of them and you know doing a better job then and they're doing the same Job, they did five years ago, which is still a damn good job.
Scott: It's just the competition is getting fierce.
Scott: It's what I used to go to Otakon and you go to some other con and it was clear Otakon was just a million times better.
Scott: but now other cons are getting better than Otakon and Otakon is staying at the same level of quality and Relatively speaking.
Scott: It doesn't you know measure up someone like case in point.
Rym: Look at anime Boston.
Rym: anime, Boston Like it.
Rym: just it grew so suddenly that I had all these problems.
Scott: But they keep stepping up their game.
Rym: the last anime Boston I'd say was equivalent to Otakon and everything but scale.
Rym: Yep, in fact as a from the meta perspective it was better because anime Boston It's a lot of stuff for us.
Scott: Yeah, they paid us money.
Rym: Yeah, they covered our expenses.
Rym: Otakon's like yeah, there's a badge.
Rym: Yeah, all right, but We've gone on that rant like yes, but there is one convention beyond the San Diego comic-con.
Rym: That's already got us act together.
Rym: So I got I got a point out.
Rym: Connecticut is already accepting panel submissions because we're the heads of panels and look at us.
Rym: We've already gotten some panel submissions a decent number in fact, and we're already working on stuff.
Rym: so if you want to present at Connecticut follow the link and send us a panel submission and you'll get an email back and we'll probably be able to give you a scheduled time a lot sooner than you'd expect.
Scott: So I don't really have a news because you know There isn't one but I will continue my sort of tradition of doing like geek bites on Wednesday.
Scott: as long as you know There's no anime manga news.
Scott: So I actually I don't have a new thing to talk about though I could probably think of one if I had to but I want to walk in Tetsuwan birdie.
Scott: Yeah, I do want to talk about though.
Scott: 20th century boys volume 5, right?
Scott: So I'm reading 20th century boys, of course and volume 5.
Scott: I got it yesterday, right and I read it last night and you know, I never thought that I would like have a negative thing to say about a Salva book but really like just like it's such a fucking tease.
Scott: It's like dude you cannot just keep dragging it out like this.
Scott: you have to.
Scott: you know Spill the beans at some point, you know, it just doesn't work, you know, and I mean there's a. you know You talk to these, you know, if you're gonna talk about suspense, it's like sure you got to lead people along but you can't like just never have The moment and just keep skipping over it forever.
Scott: there has to be a point at which you let it go.
Scott: and if you're it's like you know in comedy even if your joke is perfect if the timing is off it doesn't work.
Scott: and In 20th century boys volume 5 he messes up the timing of the suspense release.
Scott: He should have released and he just didn't.
Scott: he just keeps holding on to it.
Scott: You know, it's like it just sort of falls on the floor, but it rather than being released.
Scott: So you still don't know what it is, but now you're just like I'll fuck it.
Scott: I don't give a shit anymore.
Scott: I mean imagine this.
Scott: imagine.
Scott: here's the perfect example right here.
Scott: This is the best analogy I can think of.
Scott: Okay, so you're watching You're watching The Empire Strikes Back.
Rym: All right.
Scott: Okay, and you're watching it and you're watching it and You know Luke is talking to Yoda and he's like I gotta go help them, you know, and Yoda is like you shouldn't go help them right.
Scott: and then it stops and It cuts to the beginning of the return of the Jedi and he's like, you know Luke is like knocking on Jabba the Hutt's door.
Scott: That is what this is.
Scott: And then they start teasing you like, you know, oh You know, they don't actually tell you what happened at the end of Empire Strikes Back But they sorta.
Scott: you could you start to infer it.
Scott: but he purposefully keeps hints very very small.
Scott: So it's like, you know, so it like you see.
Rym: so you see Luke and he's got like a black arm and you don't know why exactly.
Scott: that is right and They're gonna.
Scott: basically it's like this multi imagine like a whole series of movies, right?
Scott: But they take the climaxes off the end of them the the revealing awesome epic climax moments chop them all off and stick them all at the very very ends you have to watch like 10 movies and Then you get like a climb.
Scott: However, I don't even know if there's a climax at the end because I haven't gotten to the end.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: This is possibly do when you read the last volume.
Rym: It's basically going to be 200 pages of orgasm.
Scott: It's no good.
Scott: You've got to give it to me You that point in the middle right the scene with the with the speech and the gun and the whole thing, right?
Scott: yeah, 20th century boys needs that.
Scott: it needs that scene in the middle of the series and It didn't.
Scott: I didn't get the scene in the middle of the series.
Scott: He's just like fuck you.
Scott: This is where you should have put that scene right here and he didn't do it.
Rym: You know, it's very interesting cuz it's kind of Wagnerian because if you watch like got her dammer on or any of those Wagner operas the kind of music he uses like it it grows and builds intention like the chords like But they'll never like resolve into the chord that finalizes it.
Rym: The cadence just kind of keeps building and building and building and building and building and building and building and building and building forever And you don't get any release for like four hours.
Scott: then you fall asleep You know, you're sitting there.
Scott: You're like build build build Where's the release?
Scott: and then eventually you're not getting a release long enough and you're just like, huh?
Scott: Whatever and I'm all whatever now with 20th century boys.
Scott: So volume six is not have That scene that I need then.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I'll probably still buy the whole damn thing.
Scott: You Know I definitely already that that fact It's like Pluto is just like, you know I I was like having a hard time determining like Pluto or 20th century boys.
Scott: But now it's Pluto by like a landslide.
Rym: see it's way it's hard for me to say because Pluto is satisfying My deep-rooted desire for more ghost in the shell a little bit which kind of gives it this Artificial boost in my liking of it.
Rym: That's true.
Rym: And it's it's.
Rym: it's not good in a way.
Rym: It's kind of like that penny arcade where he's like, well, there's no substitute for the original tribes, too.
Rym: But I can prescribe some of this and some of this Like onslaught or whatever.
Rym: that was.
Scott: What is that thing?
Rym: that the instant action doesn't matter was a poor simulacrum?
Rym: Yeah, it's like methadone to my heroin addiction.
Rym: But It is interesting you bring that up because giant robo which we're gonna talk about the other half of the show Kinda, it does that same thing.
Rym: It'll keep like leading you on to something like blah blah blah blah blah the trash Eventually, but they keep.
Scott: I've watched two The first disc of giant robo, which is the first two, I guess I'll call them movies because they're pretty long.
Scott: Yeah, the first episodes.
Rym: and they tell you shit But at the same time they keep hint it like there's a lot that's left unsaid.
Scott: oh But I mean 20th century boys basically says nothing Nothing At least giant robo will.
Rym: it doesn't actually say as much as you think but every time you think wait What about suddenly there's a giant robot and you forget about all that?
Rym: Yeah, like you get all these you get all these like other kinds of releases then you forget that wait a minute.
Rym: What the fuck is Vogler up to anyway?
Scott: I'll save my giant robo talk for the other part of the show.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah So things of the day.
Rym: I bring to you something very very sad.
Rym: There's no video or anything But it's an end of an era and this reminded me of so much of my childhood.
Rym: you kids today You have like Red Bull and amp and rock star and balls And Bronco and power thirst and like you have energy drinks and you don't even think about it.
Rym: They're just there.
Rym: When we were kids in the 80s and 90s there weren't energy drinks.
Rym: There was.
Scott: yeah, I mean it was like this coveted thing Like we knew that out there somewhere like I didn't drink them, of course, but other kids, you know There was like this these mythical like drinks like Joel Joel and kicks.
Rym: They're the only two.
Rym: surge wasn't an energy drink.
Rym: surge was just a like Mountain Dew.
Rym: that kind of tasted weird.
Scott: Yeah, anyway, there was like these mythical drinks that like you couldn't just get at any grocery store.
Scott: You could only get them in certain special.
Rym: Yeah, you know where I get.
Rym: they had like they had like 2x caffeine.
Rym: There was the Michigan equivalent of a bodega and there's one bodega head kick and we used to buy it like Secretly.
Rym: our parents wouldn't let us drink it.
Rym: I mean kids weren't allowed to drink coffee back then and most of us didn't even like coffee and there was nothing else.
Rym: So we'd all drink Mountain Dew and like it hopped up on caffeine from Mountain Dew and the piddly amount of caffeine in it.
Scott: And isn't it weird?
Scott: like kids back then you weren't allowed to drink an energy drink.
Scott: now kids could drink over energy drinks They want but they can't walk down the street at night.
Rym: Yeah but Jolt Cola was like this big deal whenever anyone got some like if someone got a case of jolt We'd have a party with it.
Rym: We'd stay up all night playing video games drinking jolt.
Scott: Yeah, it was like holy if someone had like a bottle of jolt in school.
Scott: It was like, holy shit They might even get in trouble even at RIT when we were there like Red Bull's like 10 jolts Red Bull back.
Rym: That was still not that commonly available and like Red Bull didn't even exist.
Rym: the closest thing to an energy energy drink We had was like that dragon berry like sobe stuff with the taurine in it.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't drink that.
Rym: I drank that but this is an end of an era.
Rym: and I didn't realize that Jolt Cola was based out of Pittsburgh by RIT.
Rym: Interesting, they filed chapter 11 bankruptcy.
Rym: They're like five million dollars and dead.
Scott: It's all over, you know, there's no reason that had to happen.
Scott: They could have easily Remarketed themselves with all the energy drinks and you know the fact that people remembered the name Jolt.
Scott: What are they?
Rym: could you know, they would have been very very careful.
Rym: They would have had to market it basically to people born between 1981 and 1989.
Scott: I think also that you know if they I don't know what it tastes like But I'm sure that if they could have worked on the flavor a lot and they could have you know Yeah, Joel tasted like fucking ass.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: To make an energy drink that tasted good and that I think really because the energy drinks they don't taste good.
Rym: I mean, yeah, the Red Bull is great and balls is awesome.
Scott: I'm sure they can.
Rym: power service has all new flavors like chocolate and gun.
Rym: But I just I want to point out it's just the disparity of the ages.
Rym: Jolt's catchphrase was quote twice the caffeine.
Scott: Yeah, nowadays it's like caffeine free lots of other shit though.
Rym: Well, I mean kind of like.
Rym: there was this peak and then it kind of leveled out.
Rym: I mean there's like Red Bull.
Rym: and then it all ramped up to calf or cocaine and then everyone tried cocaine and was like wow This is just poison.
Rym: and then they ramped it back down to Red Bull and nothing really went beyond Red Bull All right.
Scott: So You know how if you read like the old comic books from like the 50s and the 60s I hit you.
Scott: you little guy Know a little bit before that era, right?
Scott: There were always those ones that like, you know, like tales to astonish or strange tales or tales of suspense or stuff like that You know
Rym: and they usually
Scott: they a lot of them would involve like some monster, you know They'd always make up a monster and the monster would be in that one comic book.
Scott: and that was it Right, and so here's a blog the monster blog, right?
Scott: Which is a tribute to the monster comics of Jack Kirby.
Scott: and Basically, this tells you about all the different monsters of that category.
Scott: So there's the imaginary monsters alien conquerors Aliens disguised as humans atomic freaks.
Scott: atomic freaks slash possible deviant mutates Mutate yeah benevolent aliens dragon creatures freaks of nature freaks of nature that are possible deviant mutates Hoaxes humans that are you know in disguise or something like that?
Scott: human mutants lab experiment gone wild miscellaneous mythological creatures sea monsters sentient plant life strange places subterranean creatures supernatural beings technology gone wild transformed humans and unusual objects, so Just to give you you know examples of what we're talking about here.
Scott: We're talking about monsters like Dragoon the flaming invader.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Okay, goo.
Scott: Damn.
Scott: like father like son Mumba the wicked wooden statue or Rambu his very name made mankind tremble, you know, I think we need an anime that is like that Sprag the living hill.
Rym: What's it do?
Rym: feed people who walk on it?
Rym: It's not so much a hill can do Sprag conquer of the human race.
Scott: Here's the planet.
Scott: Let's see original appearance.
Scott: journey into mystery number 68.
Scott: Wow, he's actually also appeared in sensational she-hulk 31.
Rym: Yeah, it's a giant hill that is alive with the sound of murder, I don't know.
Scott: Let's see in Something fear the villagers watched is from the great yawning chasm there emerged the most fantastic Most incredible sight ever seen by mortal man.
Scott: Look for the love of heaven.
Scott: That thing is is alive.
Scott: it's Throbbing breathing.
Scott: keep back don't go near it.
Rym: I somehow imagine all of these monsters looking vaguely like the claw.
Rym: No, they actually as big as a flying battleship.
Rym: it's a flying battleship.
Rym: Jack Kirby monsters lying battleship.
Scott: You know, the thing is like, you know, I'm not the biggest Jack Kirby fan in the universe But I mean this style of monster is totally freakin sweet.
Rym: Yeah It's the kind of thing that you either have to do so unironically That you just have to go with it kind of like giant robo or a read or die Or you have to just completely make fun of it.
Rym: if you fall anywhere between those two extremes you're done.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, here's a blog about all about those monsters and not much else.
Scott: So check it out.
Rym: Sounds like a pretty good blog.
Rym: It's a good blood.
Rym: So the meta Musil minute here.
Scott: Ah Very good.
Scott: We remembered.
Rym: Okay, I can't panel submit them.
Rym: Zen kai khan this weekend.
Scott: King of Prussia, Pennsylvania.
Rym: Yep, November 6th, or is it?
Rym: does it start on Friday or just Saturday Saturday and Sunday?
Rym: Yes, so November 7th and 8th, not 6th.
Rym: There's nothing going on on Friday.
Rym: We're not even getting into town until late.
Scott: Yes Also the book club Selection is the hitchhiker's guide to the galaxy by Douglas Adam Douglas Only the first one not any of the restaurants or salmon or anything.
Rym: I got to think about what to pick for my book.
Scott: Yeah, are you gonna use the same criteria?
Rym: I did or I'm thinking the monster at the end of the book We got to get these kids to read.
Scott: I mean maybe if we did like a whole collection of kids books, you know Maybe hop on pop like the hats.
Scott: Yeah, we did like 10 or 20 of them.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know Any other.
Rym: Yes, we're still using Skype and GeekNights is all kind of fast and loose.
Rym: And so we situate all our.
Scott: It's a little bit better.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It's a little bit better.
Rym: eventually, we'll do the dual recording and record ahead and all that and I got to figure out what I'm doing with buying a House or whatever because the dude I was gonna buy this house from apparently skip town and didn't pay the property Taxes and the bank like doesn't know what to do and the house is abandoned.
Rym: They cut off the gas.
Scott: I went over to the house and it's like Maybe they could demolish the house and you could just buy the land.
Rym: No, dude.
Rym: So here's the thing.
Rym: land, right?
Rym: You know mountain beacon.
Rym: and out to the left of it There's this gigantic two-acre lot with like a driveway going through it and nothing in it.
Rym: Yep That's for sale for like a hundred and forty thousand dollars.
Scott: Just buy it.
Rym: I'm thinking about just buying it and just like put a shack on it.
Rym: No I'll just buy it and then like live with Emily and pay rent there or something for like a year until I pay off the You know measly hundred and forty thousand dollar mortgage.
Rym: and then I own two acres of like prime land next to the mountain with light.
Scott: You know what you could do is right you get you buy it Right, and then what you do is you build like a little house like, you know, just you know something That's not very big buying a building.
Rym: A little house is not substantially cheaper than building a big house Really?
Scott: I mean not even like a house almost like like an in-law thing like a garage a kitchen a living room.
Rym: No, I was looking you realize for for like 300 grand I can build like a five-bedroom three-bathroom like Monster house with a gallery and a balcony.
Scott: Yeah, I'm talking about like $50,000.
Rym: build like a little time Scotty would cost me more than $50,000 to get the architect and the contractor and the sewer connections.
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: I was like if you could just get like, you know, basically an apartment there Right, then you basically just live in it and then eventually build a big old house like it like a half a million dollar house And then
Rym: you have this little apartment Basically cost the same no matter how big the house I build is within a certain scale.
Rym: and as my grandpa said because my grandpa built his own party house a long time Little old for that.
Rym: now He turned 80 recently Yeah, but yeah You know, he could at least talk and tell you what what he basically told me a long time ago was.
Rym: if you're building your Own house build a mansion.
Rym: There's no reason not to and all I can picture now is courage wolf saying that to me There's no reason not to.
Rym: So we'll see.
Rym: I'm sorting all that shit out.
Rym: however If I don't do that I'm thinking about renting space either in the city or in Beacon like commercial space just to have a studio.
Rym: I got all this money to like.
Rym: if I don't buy this house right now I've got money to do something with like a lot of those I know some places in the city that would be good for that.
Rym: I'm also seriously trying to find out what it would cost to license the translation and distribution and whatever rights to sanctuary.
Scott: Oh Really you want to get the public really seriously.
Rym: if I fits like if I can get it for like under 80 grand or so I'm just doing it.
Rym: Jesus Really.
Rym: Wow think about think about sanctuary.
Rym: right?
Rym: If you took that did a treatment of it to get like a screenplay and tried to sell that as like a 24 style TV show In America, I don't know if we get.
Scott: I don't know how much rights we get.
Scott: you'd have to get you know.
Rym: Well, yeah, that's why I'm sorting all that out and that's taking a lot of my time.
Scott: Like even if we bought the rights would be allowed to just put it out online for free like we'd want to.
Scott: you know.
Scott: Would we be?
Scott: you know, how much you'd be allowed to do would be able to just?
Rym: That's exactly what I have to figure out.
Rym: I have to find the rights and figure it all out And that's that's what I'm spending my time on right now.
Rym: I'll be sweet.
Rym: Oh my god If nothing else I could just be like yeah sanctuary by Rym.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think you can do that.
Rym: It depends on what rights I get.
Scott: The rights to that sort of thing never leave the creator, you know only the only the copy rights.
Rym: We can see what I can do.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway anyway, so giant robo Giant robo watch the whole thing.
Scott: I've only watched it's weird cuz it's all it's like.
Scott: it's.
Scott: it's an OAV, right?
Scott: It's only a few episodes.
Scott: How many episodes is it?
Scott: Ah eight, I believe Alright, so I've watched disc one which had two episodes, but they were long.
Scott: I think it's like.
Scott: it's like movies almost, you know TV miniseries, it's.
Scott: it feels like it's a TV miniseries where each episode is like one of those one-hour deals.
Rym: Well, it's got.
Scott: it was a high production value OAV with like seven episodes Yeah, and the other thing is the thing is that second episode though?
Scott: Like the first half of it was like recap of the first episode, you know, yeah, which is like really it's an OAV.
Scott: Why are you recapping?
Rym: Well, there's a part of.
Rym: there's a reason for that.
Rym: Let me tell you all the story of giant robo before we talk about what it's about.
Rym: Giant robo was originally a manga and a terrible live-action TV show from the late 60s Called giant robo.
Rym: that has almost nothing to do with giant robo.
Rym: the animation.
Rym: Ah It's weird.
Rym: I can't even there's so much to say about that.
Rym: I was watching clips of it on YouTube and good God Suffice the generic old crappy robot show that happens to have this robot in it Kinda but it was by a guy named Mitsuteru Yokoyama and this is from like late 60s early 70s, so The anime giant robo.
Rym: the animation was directed by Yoshihiro Imagawa.
Rym: You know G Gundam Imagawa.
Scott: I think it's isn't it?
Scott: Yasuhiro Imagawa.
Rym: Yasuhiro Imagawa.
Rym: What did I say?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I gotta look it up But he is the G Gundam guy.
Scott: Oh The G Gundam guy really that explains, you know, it's not really like G Gundam that much at all.
Rym: So, yeah But he's the G Gundam guy and I think he wrote like the script for berserk And a couple other weird random shows.
Scott: hmm Anyway, yeah, so yeah, he's Yasuhiro Imagawa.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So basically what happened was the producer of such great works as Urochika Doji and ninja resurrection Went to Imagawa and was like I want you to make an anime based on giant robo.
Rym: And Imagawa was like I'm totally a fan of Yokoyama because you know Tetsujin 28 was awesome.
Rym: So I'm gonna make it.
Rym: I'm gonna go all for it.
Rym: But as they got all the deal together They basically discovered that they only had the rights to giant robo and not to any other character from the giant robo manga or TV show Really?
Rym: So what they did?
Scott: so they were originally.
Scott: we're going.
Scott: we're going to just do a remake of the original giant robo.
Rym: I'm not a hundred percent sure on that.
Rym: All I know is that because they did not have the rights to any character, but giant robo They basically took all these random characters from all of Yokoyama's other works and use them as characters in giant robo.
Rym: Okay, so also notice how the opener to giant robo has all those robots that are not in the show.
Rym: and I'm gonna tell you They're not in the show.
Rym: There are.
Scott: it's a Nintendo horse situation.
Rym: There aren't even that many giant robots in the show.
Scott: Yeah, I've only seen like two so far besides giant robo himself.
Rym: Yeah, there are also very few actual giant robot fights.
Rym: And in fact, I'd say there are more people versus.
Rym: they're incorrect.
Scott: They're really reminiscent of big O fights.
Scott: Well or big O is reminiscent of giant robo.
Rym: Yeah Well, there's more to the story.
Rym: so giant robo was begun and first released in 1992.
Rym: The last episode was not released until 1998.
Scott: Oh It's one of those big long OAVs where they take forever to come out with the next.
Rym: Yeah, and they made a bunch of episodes.
Rym: then there was a long delay.
Rym: then they made the gin race special and then they came back and made the end.
Rym: and apparently in the interim between like the last and the second last episode and all during that period a Bunch of the staff who were working on giant robo Worked on other stuff and a lot of the same people did big O. that did giant robo.
Scott: Wasn't big O made later?
Rym: Yeah, but like the people went on to work on big O And they worked out a bunch of other weird projects like in the interim when giant robo was working on and not working on.
Scott: Very interesting, so there's always there is a gigantic list of like animators on the anime news network.
Rym: Yes, there's this.
Rym: so there's this gigantic crazy story of how giant robo happened.
Rym: and there's a manga that was made in like 2007 and there was like a remake TV anime that I don't know anyone who's seen from the same time.
Rym: and There's all this stuff around giant robo.
Scott: and yeah, there's something on here about giant robo 40th anniversary here on the anime news network.
Scott: So it says it came out in 2007 13 episodes.
Scott: Oh, yeah, so here's the thing.
Rym: So people worked on giant robo also worked on get a robo Armageddon.
Rym: All right, so Basically, I'm gonna have to skip all that.
Rym: We're just talking about giant robo the animation the 90s Oav7 episodes.
Rym: we're not talking about any other part of it because other than a couple of YouTube clips.
Rym: I know nothing about it.
Scott: Yeah, and we're really only talking about the first two episodes because that's all I've seen so far and we'll talk about it again After I've seen.
Rym: this is not a final thoughts.
Rym: This is a review.
Rym: We were reviewing giant robo because I think you should all watch giant robo and I'm trying to convince you to watch Giant robo.
Rym: if you want the history of it or you know, attention 28 and how that led to this.
Rym: I'll bow up.
Rym: I guess you should go to anime world order because as Daryl Surratt points out commonly We are nothing but rank amateurs in the face of his majesty.
Scott: Perhaps, you know, the thing is is like we watched giant robo for the first time.
Scott: We watched the first episode of it anyway, and the RIT anime closed way back.
Rym: And we walked out before it even ended.
Scott: Yeah, well, no, I think we finished that first episode.
Rym: No, we walked out and played some games.
Scott: I'm pretty sure I Remember watching the whole first episode.
Rym: I think I walked out and played Carcassonne or something.
Rym: You stayed till the end.
Rym: then you met with us later.
Scott: Anyway, you know and back then, you know, we weren't particularly thrilled with it.
Scott: We didn't feel a strong need to see any more of it and we didn't see any more.
Rym: It was so weird how I Watch it now and I'm really surprised I didn't catch on to or like the show as much as I didn't back then.
Rym: back then I was like, yeah Whatever some stupid robot show.
Rym: Why does everyone have superpowers?
Rym: This is dumb.
Scott: Well, you know, I don't think it's dumb now Like I guess I did then but I don't.
Scott: I'm not it's still not as like thrilled with it as you are.
Rym: I love this show.
Rym: This is this is becoming like every time I watch parts of it again It becomes one of my favorite anime like it's rising in the list.
Rym: It's in like my top 25 favorite anime.
Scott: now Yeah, this is not my.
Scott: what am I top 25 favorite anime?
Scott: I mean, it's alright, but it's not like.
Scott: oh, yeah It's just it's okay.
Scott: It's you know, it's it's got some parts to it that I can appreciate but it's not like.
Scott: Incredibly thrilling and amazing and epic and whatever.
Rym: It's difficult to describe the plot of giant Robo because it it's a show that begins in media res and ends in media res.
Rym: it was actually described by a lot of the people working on it as it was intended to be the penultimate battle between the good and evil in this world Not the ultimate battle.
Rym: It is basically the penultimate that battle.
Rym: It starts at the beginning of like the conflict before the final conflict But they never intended to show you the final conflict.
Rym: They did.
Rym: actually there's all this stuff where they release like the names of the follow-on series.
Rym: There's supposed to be like a prequel and then like a three-day like the end and end that were never made And I don't know if they were even actually intended to be made.
Rym: it was kind of like Star Wars where Star Wars starts in the middle of this gigantic Galactic Civil War and Ends kind of after one like big climax, but doesn't resolve the overarching story.
Rym: It's like one tiny piece of this ongoing intergalactic story.
Rym: Giant Robo is kind of the exact same thing.
Rym: It starts with this crazy
Scott: retrain
Rym: like battle where there's a guy with a briefcase and he's on a train and he's trying to get away from this other guy with a giant robot and then bad guys appear and good guys appear and they're all superheroes and it's just this beautifully animated gigantic running fight scene through this new futurist world.
Scott: Yeah, the animation is pretty good.
Scott: You know the music I mean, I guess the sound is good, but I mean the music.
Scott: I couldn't even like recognize the song from it.
Rym: It's not like memorable music Straight up like classical style custom soundtrack.
Scott: I don't even like notice it at all Are you kidding?
Rym: The music is like the best part of giant Robo other than the cell animation.
Scott: No, it's it.
Scott: good music is like the kind of music like you.
Scott: remember it and you recognize it.
Scott: I couldn't you know, it's just it's.
Scott: it's serviceable.
Scott: It's you know, I don't notice it.
Scott: You know, I'm sure it, you know works at the mood, but it's not music.
Scott: I could if you played for me a song from the giant Robo soundtrack I couldn't tell you that it was some giant robo really like.
Rym: really that's very surprising to me because to me the soundtrack is Amazing.
Rym: It's very I don't want to necessarily say operatic.
Rym: But have you ever actually seen an opera?
Rym: Yeah, what opera?
Scott: I saw?
Scott: Romeo and Juliet at the Met and I saw Something else.
Scott: I forget
Rym: because one common thing in a lot of opera especially later opera is the like the leitmotif There's like the theme or the melody of a different character and giant Robo has his own very specific leitmotif
Scott: And the
Rym: music is very like almost Too big for the show.
Rym: like the show can barely contain the music and it really to me sets up this Almost too epic to be believed premise.
Rym: it's it's kind of Gurren Lagann esque in that the music is bigger than the show could possibly be and you're forced to either think the show is stupid or Ignore the soundtrack or just take it at face value.
Rym: and this is the most epic thing ever.
Scott: hmm, I Don't know.
Scott: It's to me.
Scott: You know, I mean it's like I don't.
Scott: there's no like, you know, like memorable Melodies or anything like that.
Scott: It doesn't stand out.
Scott: It's just.
Rym: you know, there's Not that that giant robo theme that they play every time giant robo is about to do something.
Scott: No, like I couldn't if you played it for me.
Scott: I like, you know, if you played three things for me I couldn't tell you which one it was.
Scott: Wow.
Rym: I That really amazes me like it really does surprise me.
Scott: Yeah, and they you know, what else is going on in the show?
Scott: I mean the characters.
Scott: it seems like, you know Like.
Scott: the characters don't really have like, you know, they're not very complex, you know, it's pretty much like he's the fat guy.
Scott: He she's the hot girl who has awesome powers, but won't use them because of some reason, you know He's the kid with a bunch of responsibility on his shoulders, you know, I mean, I've only watched two episodes.
Scott: But you know the characters.
Scott: it's sort of like.
Scott: they're just these.
Scott: like, you know archetypes.
Rym: That's exactly what they are.
Rym: They're larger than life.
Rym: the music the style everything in the show is so larger than life both directly and I guess on the meta perspective that the characters are all like the embodiment of some idea or something.
Rym: and they're.
Rym: They're bigger than a real character could possibly be but they're more complex than you'll give them credit for.
Rym: you see the rest of the Show, they're not as simple as they appear right away except for Tetsukyo a big stupid axe guy.
Scott: He is exactly what he appears to be, you know I mean like some of them, you know I mean they're cool in their style and such like the guy with the inner pole guy with the red coat.
Scott: He's got a good style.
Rym: Oh, you don't even have any idea his character.
Rym: There's stuff about him.
Scott: yeah, I'm sure there is you know, and it's like the.
Scott: You know sort of like this.
Scott: there's always those.
Scott: there's a lot of those characters who sort of like they don't do too much.
Scott: You know, they've always got that.
Scott: that's like it's the old Simpsons guy in the white suit just standing there.
Rym: Exactly There's a whole lot of that going on.
Rym: The way I will put it is that every character is kind of set up to be too big like the show can't contain them.
Rym: every single one of them is going to have their Final Fantasy 4 moments the moment where they just like bust out in the most of like crazy possible way and fulfill everything they could possibly be.
Rym: and Like it's like every character has a scene like in Read or Die when they take that paper airplane and jump off the roof.
Scott: Yeah, I guess kind of.
Scott: but you know, it's like it's all.
Scott: that's all like action kind of stuff.
Rym: Yeah, it is actually it's action and just I don't know.
Rym: I don't know why this isn't resonating with you so much.
Rym: the show is just Everything is larger than life and over the top but it's balanced by this kind of very serious treatment and very Serious and poignant use of music and theme at the same time.
Scott: The other thing that gets me is like you've got this sort of you know mystery going on right about.
Scott: you know Oh, what was best darl and then you find that out, but then there's still other mysteries, you know Like the guy's like I'll tell you the truth and then he doesn't because he dies.
Scott: and you know It's like all this kind of stuff.
Scott: and you want to know like what is really going on.
Scott: What is you know, how does this thing really work?
Scott: Why is it this way?
Scott: This is a point of what happened in the past and the thing, you know, I mean, it's it's you know, it's a mystery.
Scott: I want to know what happens, you know I'm intrigued to discover the secrets.
Scott: The thing is it seems like they just sort of like repeat a lot of things over and over again Like they show like I've watched two so far Vogler and they're like, oh don't turn on the thing.
Rym: He's like fuck you.
Rym: Haha, and he turns down the thing.
Scott: I've seen that flashback like ten times.
Scott: All right.
Rym: All right, I'm playing I'm not there is no spoiler here But that is very very intentional and done to great effect in this show.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it's you know, sometimes they you know, they flashback they show a little more a little less than you know.
Rym: No, no, really pretty much show you don't be the same thing.
Scott: I've seen this before.
Scott: show me something new.
Rym: They do it on purpose because it's a show that kind of presents to you a reality of the world.
Rym: These are the good guys.
Rym: These are the bad guys.
Rym: This guy is doing evil this dies doing good.
Rym: These people want this.
Rym: these people want this.
Rym: This is what happened in the past.
Rym: we don't know what's gonna happen in the future and they They kind of the show like a big climax of the show near the end is they show you you know The.
Rym: the flashbacks are always very consistent.
Rym: It's like nothing changes them.
Rym: It's not like you Tana where like you see things differently as people learn different things and this it's exactly In this.
Rym: what'll happen is at some point near the end of the show You see a flashback to like two minutes before the flashback you kept seeing and It changes everything but not in like a dumb dares ex mocking away, but in a oh shit.
Scott: Really kind of way Yeah, but it's I can already sort of figure out.
Rym: Can you what do you think the deal is?
Rym: I'm curious because this can't be a spoiler.
Rym: You're guessing you don't know.
Scott: What do I think the deal is?
Rym: Yes What do you think the deal is?
Scott: Well, first of all, right they make vulgar to be out like this like this.
Scott: bad, dude, right.
Scott: Yeah, you know there was an experiment and he purposefully, you know did the experiment got real wrong and he knew it You know, there was a big risk and of course the big badness happened.
Scott: right and all the other scientists try to stop him, but the Shizuma, right?
Scott: He's basically the whole time.
Scott: He's like, oh forgive me.
Scott: Oh, I have penance, right?
Scott: So it is obvious that he actually did something horrible, right if there's no question about that whatsoever Right.
Scott: So what horrible thing did he do?
Scott: and it's probably something along the lines of you know When they were working on that technology, you know, maybe it's actually Babies or you know, it's something like that.
Scott: is you know like he's the one who actually did something that was wrong and there was a reason that Vogler did what he did.
Scott: that makes sense in the context of you know, some evil thing that Shizuma perpetrated and you know They betrayed Vogler.
Scott: That's why they were all famous and he was like presumed dead and you know forgotten intentionally and something like that.
Rym: what I will say is that you know you pointed out that you didn't think the characters were terribly complex and There's definitely the implication that the plot is not terribly complex other than the I guess artificial complexity of the Baphomet ads.
Rym: I'm gonna call him the Technology the.
Rym: oh, she's gonna drive something something I a Vogler something something but That I oh my god.
Rym: There's a scene near the end where a character says to another character words to the effect of what did you expect me to do?
Rym: And that is possibly the saddest moment in it like of all anime I've ever seen.
Rym: That ranks in the top 10 of the saddest Moments ever just when the characters like what did you expect me to do?
Rym: But is it?
Rym: I guess the show like there's the tragedy of our star and all these mysteries and they kind of reveal them all And you start to like there's like 20th century.
Rym: They're trying to figure out too Like what is the deal with the special samples?
Rym: and they got the bad guys have two and the good guys have one and oh Shit, the baby all three to really make shit.
Rym: Oh shit if the bad guys get all three.
Rym: But they actually you know The characters kind of smartly are experimenting and they try to figure it out and stuff happens and I guess Everything is completely self referentially consistent In a seven episode OAV.
Scott: if you're not self, you know consistent That's a big.
Rym: but it's also consistent in a. it's not just a technobabble answer at the end Like it's not just a oh the blah blah blah and we save the day.
Rym: It's a lot more complex than that.
Rym: mm-hmm really sad - Lot of people guys.
Rym: Yeah This is a show for you guys out there where the tragedy of the past that no one will talk about Killed like two-thirds the world's population.
Rym: Yeah, and what they're fighting now is far worse than that.
Scott: The one thing that like it's weird because there are other there, you know that main mystery They pay a lot of attention to you know.
Scott: Which is weird because usually what other shows do is they'll have like this core mystery But they'll spend a lot of attention to other things and they'll only get back to the core at the very end right, whereas giant robo is basically constantly focusing on this core mystery and They're pretty much ignoring like all these other things that are out there Like for example giant robo himself, right the kids dad made giant robo,
Rym: right?
Scott: And you know that you know is whatever.
Scott: but like they don't like who is the kids dad?
Scott: They don't even talk about that at all.
Scott: Like, you know, the it barely gets any screen time, you know that question.
Rym: Well, I mean part of that.
Rym: look it throws you in in media res.
Rym: So you have no idea who the experts of justice are or who big fire is.
Rym: We'll talk about big fire in a minute.
Rym: We got a. we have to talk about that.
Rym: Especially What do they want?
Scott: big if I out how many?
Rym: ah Basically I love big fire.
Rym: They're possibly my there's something about a name like big fire.
Rym: It's a good name And the way they drive the fact that you know, they're like yes big fire But in the context of the anime, they're like the BF a group.
Rym: So did you get to the point not really spoiler where the the eye of frankenpfon fogler Activates and like everything starts shutting down and it cuts to all the big fire bases all around the world having trouble?
Scott: No, it's just so.
Scott: I mean it's floating around.
Rym: so there's there's the scene where you kind of learn It didn't activate that much only activate a little bit.
Rym: Well, you kind of learned I guess the the extent of big fires evil network where like stuff starts shutting down all over the place It's even hurting big fire.
Rym: So suddenly in the main big fire headquarters, you see like big fire Antarctica calling in.
Rym: They're like everyone's freezing to death.
Rym: What do we do?
Rym: and then like big fire the moon calls in?
Rym: Everything's fine here.
Rym: Fuck you all.
Rym: But then you see like this hint there's a big fire base that is under the White House just waiting to invade.
Rym: it Like that like big fire has bases in like everybody's closet.
Scott: as far as I can tell How many people if two-thirds of the world population died.
Scott: how many people can?
Scott: it's like half the world must be in big fire.
Rym: That's that's what's great about this show.
Rym: Like you've only seen the beginning it just gets more and more over the top like It's as though big O in the first episode punch someone with that punch and in the next episode Like grew another piston on that punch and by the end of the episode like use the entire earth as the piston to punch another evil earth.
Rym: That's kind of what happens in John and Gurren Lagann.
Rym: Giant Robo doesn't quite go that far But I guess ideologically it does because really notice how like even in the first couple episodes like giant Robo Doesn't really do too much.
Rym: The giant robot fights are basically big O punch and it's done.
Scott: But the characters fight like giant robots Like the characters are like they fight like street fighter people with more superpowers.
Rym: yeah, let it go a little bit further where a guy gets shot the way a giant robot would get shot and basically his whole torso is missing the same as if a giant Robo had been shot and he's basically standing there and he's like Well, you may have destroyed me but blah blah blah
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So at least you got to see my favorite villain in all anime ever.
Rym: now Albert to the impact.
Scott: Did I see I guess?
Rym: The steampunk kind of thing on his eye?
Rym: Yeah so that guy that guy gets more and more and more awesome as the show goes on and he's Seems like the people he's with.
Rym: they're sort of incompetent though Yeah, but at the same time you haven't met all of the magnificent ten because there's kind of there's no right there like magnificent ten.
Scott: It's like I've only seen two or three of them And when you meet the rest of them you've only got seven episodes.
Rym: like the experts of justice are all great and later in the show you meet like Ten more experts of justice basically.
Rym: But then there's magnificent ten and there's so much cooler and more badass than the experts of justice.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, there's that one Magnificent ten guy with the.
Scott: he's not like the oni mask and he just doesn't say cool.
Rym: What's his name?
Rym: That guy's scary.
Rym: He's like he's the scariest dude.
Rym: You see you feel like.
Scott: I always like that kind of character that guy who doesn't say anything.
Scott: He's obviously mysteriously.
Scott: You don't know what his powers are.
Scott: He's just quiet and off to the side.
Rym: Yeah when Albert the impacts flunky is like you fucker when they have that evil meeting and then co just kind of Shows up behind him.
Rym: He's like, I'll kill you.
Rym: I don't even blink Like I can kill you without expanding any effort.
Scott: and Albert's like, all right, so then guys I Was like that kind of guy, you know, I basically if I was Mama, Roshi, I wouldn't have a dog.
Scott: I would have a you know, a quiet guy who's mysteriously and incredibly powerful.
Scott: Or you know It seems like he's incredibly powerful.
Scott: He just doesn't do anything.
Rym: So I got to talk a little bit too about the head of you know, the guy who's obviously the chief the boss He he's been gatekeepers basically had the same guy in charge.
Rym: as far as I can say.
Scott: Yeah, I mean well big fire the generic big fire guys are very similar to the geeky.
Rym: You know, there's a lot of gatekeepers parallels just in general I guess I kind of realize I guess I like the gatekeepers when I first saw the same sort of thing.
Scott: There's a team, you know of good guys, you know, they're all different archetype characters, right?
Scott: and there's a. there's a bad organization that has a bunch of identical henchmen and You know, it's they have this really sort of dramatic like go get him.
Scott: Yes, beat the bad guy kind of.
Scott: you know mood about them, you know, it there's a lot of it's sort of.
Scott: You know, it's it's common in a lot of Japanese things, you know, like the giant robot shows the old, you know They have the same.
Rym: I guess I guess what I was saying is the gatekeepers.
Rym: I liked it when I first saw it and now I saw it long after I gave up on giant robo.
Rym: Now that I see giant robo and I'm older I realize Everything I liked about gatekeepers was something that was basically either homage or parody or stolen from giant robo like that.
Rym: I don't know if it came from giant robo Or at least from that kind of show.
Rym: These are long, these are old tropes At least from that kind of show, but you've got to admit the commander is they're basically the same guy.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, of course, you know every the commanders are.
Scott: there's pretty much three kind.
Scott: two kind Most commanders in anime like ship captains, right?
Rym: They're You know, there's always exceptions, but a lot of them are acting global.
Scott: Yeah, the captain global kind where they sit there quietly and they're real smart.
Scott: Yeah, and then there's and then there's the Kind which is like attack.
Rym: This kind is not just attack.
Rym: This kind is the attack.
Rym: I have a full power that I am NOT using.
Rym: I will only intervene if all else is lost.
Rym: It's like he's just waiting there with his fists.
Rym: Like eventually I'm gonna punch someone.
Scott: Yeah, there's a whole lot of that, you know, don't use yours, you know full power.
Scott: You know only use the amount of power you have to like in ray.
Scott: It's like you don't don't use your power again ray ever, you know, you shouldn't have.
Rym: you know in Japan It's an insult to use your full power at any course.
Scott: You know you.
Scott: only you have to slowly amplify your power and use stronger and stronger attacks.
Rym: Like I'm gonna spoil you never have to.
Rym: I'm gonna spoil one small thing the chief because you know everyone's a superpower.
Rym: notice
Scott: how I don't
Rym: know if you saw when the Greta Garbo best name for a ship ever gets attacked and Albert is like busting in and you see like all the normal dudes Attacking like they're superheroes basically like minor superheroes Like everybody has powers in this show at one point a bunch of normal.
Scott: That's part of the plot, too.
Scott: You know, maybe that's you know, something about the Shizuma Drive something something has to do with the fact that everyone has freakin superpowers.
Rym: But there's a point at which a bunch of normal dudes form up like they're forming a combining robot Just like gatekeepers.
Rym: Yeah, they all like form together just like that It's it's.
Rym: it's only for a second like you might even miss it cuz it's so quick, but it's totally there.
Rym: but the chief his power cuz everyone has a power is Basically that he can charge up this punch like he can just be like I'm gonna punch you now You little guy and if he punches something whatever it is, he could punch the earth.
Rym: earth is dead earth is gone.
Rym: He has the biggest punch and that's all he's got.
Rym: He can do it once.
Scott: Wow, okay, so on amazon.com.
Scott: Yeah, you can get all of giant Robo the complete thin with or without.
Rym: so without the eye of Vogler that I have.
Scott: That's right, the eye of Vogler is actually $70.
Rym: Wow, I'm glad I bought that thing for like 30 bucks at Otakon.
Scott: Yeah, so you can get the complete thin pack of giant Robo for $15 dude for that even if you don't like giant Robo for the price of one DVD Basically, you can get an entire series you.
Scott: it might as well buy it guys because you know, we've been really I mean, I'm not even like I'm not even super excited about it like other people are but You know, I mean for $15, it's totally worth it.
Rym: Jesus I mean it.
Scott: oh wait, actually the $15 one.
Scott: right it says pre-order on that, right?
Scott: but there's a Economy pack which looks like it's the same exact thing and that's $20, but that you can buy right now.
Rym: Yeah, you probably don't need the eye of Vogler.
Scott: The eye of Vogler is pretty giant Robo.
Scott: the complete edition.
Scott: premium eyeball Parentheses premium eyeball parent close parenthesis $72.
Scott: but there's someone selling a used one a used eye a premium I've.
Rym: What did he use it for?
Rym: No But I don't know this show especially.
Rym: I'm curious to hear what you have to say when you've seen the whole show because they kind of reveal Everything and the I guess, you know, depending what the reveals are Determines a lot about what I'm gonna think about.
Scott: It's revealed and it's like oh, yeah, whatever.
Scott: I saw that coming.
Scott: then it's like, okay.
Rym: This is the show.
Scott: I never would have thought of that and what I didn't think of is awesome.
Rym: Remember way way back We saw this try gun AMV and in the beginning of the AMV It shows a scene from giant Robo where a dude is like talking to the main character and then he just shoots himself in the head.
Rym: No, you don't remember that.
Rym: I'll show it to you after the show.
Rym: This is basically it's the scene where a Character it from giant Robo who you will recognize is talking to the kid who pilots giant Robo and he stands there And he says a bunch of stuff on top of a like mountain of discarded shoes image drives and then while smiling He just shoots himself in the head.
Rym: All right, that's that's from giant Robo.
Rym: That's that's kind of to give you an idea where the show goes.
Scott: Someone's gonna all right.
Scott: That's interesting.
Rym: Yeah All right, I Don't know.
Rym: we just we talked about this off the show.
Rym: I think is great and Scott doesn't think it's that great.
Rym: But I'll say this if you consider yourself an anime fan at all You should watch at least one episode of giant Robo because one I think a lot of people who think they won't like a show Like this will probably really really like it
Scott: Say well, I don't think it's you know, so amazing.
Rym: I can definitely tell that I a lot of people most people looking at this will think it's totally awesome But also anime fan type people even if you don't like it You have to have seen it so you can at least talk about it or shows like it.
Rym: I mean if you've never seen a show like this How do you know you don't like them?
Rym: and how do you know they're bad?
Rym: and how can you even say they're bad?
Rym: How can you say anything about anime?
Rym: The show is great.
Rym: I want to watch it again.
Rym: I'm watching it with Emily actually right now.
Scott: Uh-huh How can you watch it?
Scott: You gave me the discs?
Rym: Yeah Well, we temporarily stopped watching it so you can watch it and then we're gonna continue watching it.
Rym: All right, plus I still have the third disc and the Gin Ray special which you should not watch.
Rym: It's just kind of funny and dumb but it It's kind of a travesty if you already know how giant Robo ends to watch the Gin Ray special.
Rym: Imagine if cowboy bebop had be like spike and vicious and Julia go to the beach episode like after the show.
Rym: That's what that's like to watch.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback Via audio.
Scott: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Scott: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.