Rym: Hey, it's Monday, May 4th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is geek nides tonight's typing.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So I realized the other day kind of shockingly that 90s nostalgia is soon going to be the thing.
Rym: and I realized this when I saw Fern Gully.
Rym: Suddenly everyone on the internet was talking about Fern Gully I think because it was on the Netflix on demand.
Rym: all of a sudden and we all remember Fern Gully is 90s.
Rym: I thought I'm pretty sure that was a 90s movie.
Rym: Scott I'm just gonna check.
Rym: it had a surfer guy named Zach and it was about the rainforests.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: There is no way that movie wasn't made in the 90s.
Rym: Wow.
Scott: I can't find it on IMDb.
Scott: What the fuck?
Rym: There's no way it's not an IMDb.
Rym: Not that it was a good movie.
Scott: Oh, there it is.
Scott: It's always was one word.
Scott: That's why I couldn't get it.
Scott: Okay, Fern Gully 1 92 Gully 2 The magical rescue.
Scott: Wow, oh there's a trailer.
Rym: we don't need to watch the trailer.
Rym: I mean, I saw the land before time seven.
Scott: I don't you saw the land before time seven.
Scott: I'm gonna find out how many land before times there are here.
Rym: I go to Wikipedia, but it just I Wasn't that long ago.
Rym: someone was someone in the crew brought up something about the nostalgia culture.
Rym: How come how come it was all 80s nostalgia or is the next generation not gonna be full of nostalgia?
Rym: And then we all kind of pointed out that we're right about that time.
Rym: We're just gonna turn into 90s nostalgia because our generation, you know The late 80s early 90s are getting to the age where the 80s nostalgia came out when those people hit our age.
Scott: Okay, according to Wikipedia on the land before time series page because if you just go to land before time It talks about the first movie, but there's a land before time series page on Wikipedia.
Rym: What's it say about Petrie?
Rym: Here's the man.
Scott: it doesn't say anything.
Scott: it says says it says that there were ahem done done done done.
Scott: in current existence There are 13 lands before time Jesus and next year.
Scott: Well in 2009 land before time 14 will exist.
Rym: It's not like they could avert the apocalypse.
Scott: I Think it might be something that's like someone is paying to keep going in order to like, you know Train animators or something like, you know, I just I don't know.
Scott: I mean, it's like you can break.
Scott: I think that's my guess is you can break into the animation industry.
Scott: It's like you get on the land before time and then you can work on something else.
Rym: as you know Maybe the land before time is like hentai in Japan because half the great voice actors We know started out in hentai.
Scott: Oh, it could be something in.
Rym: ever since I found out who the rape man really was I've just been disillusioned Mm-hmm.
Scott: Anyway, so I started a new work today.
Rym: Yeah, Scott's gainfully employed.
Scott: It's a I was Just a month ago.
Scott: This isn't in fact, it's more rare for me to not be gainfully.
Rym: Yes, but you it has been a change of state.
Rym: I mean, it's kind of like Manchester differential where we only update when there is a change.
Scott: You mean like it anyway, it only writes down the changes It doesn't make copies of the whole.
Rym: well actually Manchester differential also has an automatic mid-bit transition.
Rym: Technically you have a fake update every second, but then right anyway.
Scott: So, you know, there are things to say about the new work, but you know pertaining to the work itself.
Scott: I can't really say anything.
Scott: But pertaining to the meta of the work You know, they didn't give me too much choice in Machinery, so my choices are pretty much Desktop Dell which was you know, which I would have gone with because I had an Optiplex in my last job and it was fantastic Except for the fact that there might be some working from home action going on.
Scott: So it has to be some sort of laptop action right with some sort of docking situation like there was at my two jobs ago You know, so I wanted a Lenovo x300 but that probably wasn't gonna happen.
Scott: So my choices are pretty much like Dell laptop or MacBook, right?
Scott: So I'm like, well, you know, whatever It's for work only.
Scott: I'm not using it for my shit.
Scott: So as long as it, you know is good for the work It doesn't bother me, you know.
Scott: So the other guy was using the MacBook and apparently the MacBook Pro doesn't come in 13-inch It only comes in 15 or 17.
Scott: Yeah, so I was like well fuck that.
Scott: so I got the 13 You know and I could probably do a whole show.
Scott: I just talking about it cuz I've never really used a ma an OS X as a desktop for an extended usage.
Rym: I mean I can say way way back, you know in the kind of early days of GeekNights Remember when I still work to that hospital and I bought that Mac mini and I was like, yeah fuck Linux fuck windows.
Rym: I'm going Mac and Wallet could not podcast and it could not play games.
Rym: It was really pretty and slick for everything else.
Scott: I was yeah, I mean it seems like you know for everything that there is.
Scott: That's bad about it.
Scott: There's something else good like for example, right?
Scott: They have done the new ones.
Scott: They got this giant touchpad.
Scott: That is a button, right?
Scott: And there are some things I don't like about it.
Scott: Like pushing it in is a little harder than pushing in like a separate button, you know, like on my other my laptop You know, so that's annoying and it doesn't have two buttons, but it does have ways that you can you know Like I set it up.
Scott: So if you push the bottom right corner of it, it is a right button.
Scott: Click you see stuff like that, but for every bad thing like that There's a good thing.
Scott: for example, if you put two fingers on it and slide around you can scroll up and down.
Scott: And if you put four fingers on it, you can do the expose by going up or down, you know I'm gonna follow Luke here.
Rym: There is a sexual joke that could be made.
Rym: Yeah, I'm not going to make.
Scott: there is a lot this you know, so that's pretty cool.
Rym: Yeah, what happens if you do the shocker to it?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: But there are actually little videos in the preferences in the control panel showing you like the control panel for configuring.
Scott: It has video showing you how to use it.
Scott: Anyway, the one there is one the one annoyance that is like the annoyance I cannot beat and it is like this incredible Constant annoyance and I want to.
Scott: I want to call out and see if anyone can help me with this because it's not the kind Of thing that's easy to search for.
Rym: I swear to God if you say it's a Mac.
Rym: How do I change that?
Scott: No Okay.
Scott: So here's the problem, right?
Scott: All right.
Scott: Okay caps lock key is useless.
Scott: Everyone knows this right.
Scott: if you use caps lock key You're stupid Except for very very rare circumstances.
Rym: simple data entry, right?
Scott: So because it's you know Even though you should you know, you might have an occasional legitimate use for it There's no reason for it to be right there in an incredibly easy to hit position.
Scott: You want the keys you use the most often to be in the incredibly easy to hit positions, you know Right next to your home row, you know, you want the rarely placed keys to be far away.
Scott: So I always and you should do convert caps lock into control.
Rym: I found four programs you can pay for to do that.
Scott: No, no, no, no, no what that's just.
Rym: I'm just.
Rym: I just did.
Scott: Uh, anyway, you can turn caps lock into control in the Mac OS X control panel, there's an option.
Scott: I did it.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: All right, obviously, there's something wrong.
Scott: Obviously.
Scott: Yes I'm just explaining the situation.
Scott: is it sticky?
Scott: No Get me it's a complicated situation.
Scott: It's not something stupid.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Okay, so In Firefox right on Windows and Linux all the keyboard Shortcuts are like ctrl T for a new tab or ctrl N for a new window or ctrl tab to change tabs, right?
Scott: That's awesome.
Scott: Right in Mac all the keyboard shortcuts in Firefox are command T command tab command N Right.
Scott: replace control with the command key, right?
Scott: Not a big deal.
Scott: So I changed the caps the can caps lock into command instead of changing it into control, right?
Scott: That's cool.
Scott: the problem is on the Mac and say the terminal application or Vim or just about anywhere else.
Scott: It's still control.
Scott: It's not command.
Scott: So I have to constantly freaking go into the menu like for Firefox.
Scott: I need it to the caps lock key to be command but everywhere else I need the caps lock key to be control and There's no way to do that.
Scott: So either I have to use like this command key.
Scott: That's in a weird position for all the Firefox shortcuts or I have to use like the control key.
Scott: That's in a weird position from the everything else shortcut.
Rym: Okay, so I found this farm post or someone has the same quick problem.
Rym: They ask it in a very different way, uh-huh.
Rym: I installed Firefox on my Mac my new Mac, by the way It's awesome.
Rym: I really like it.
Rym: But for some reason all the control shortcuts don't work Hmm.
Rym: Why can't I hit?
Rym: why don't my control something shortcuts work?
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: I don't think he realizes Right.
Scott: I knew that they were command.
Rym: I don't think he realizes the first response works.
Rym: fine for me.
Rym: Yes Reply, what are you using?
Rym: reply windows?
Rym: I Don't know.
Scott: did see this wasn't a problem in the living room where we have a Mac already because I only ever used Firefox in the living room.
Scott: I don't use anything else down there.
Scott: So turning the caps lock in living room into the command key is great because I never need the control key.
Scott: I don't use anything but Firefox in the living room.
Scott: I don't use the terminal I don't and the worst right is that I've got parallels with Ubuntu and Windows running in it.
Scott: Right, so what I'm what I'm focused on?
Scott: like this virtual machine running Ubuntu and I've got a terminal and I want to push ctrl L to clear the terminal right or ctrl T to open a tab in the Firefox in the virtual machine.
Scott: I got this command key there.
Scott: So I think the optimal solution would be to set the key to be control because in everything but Firefox I want it to be control, right?
Scott: So then wouldn't just I need to find I need to find some way to Screw with a Mac Firefox so that control works instead of command for all the shortcuts.
Scott: So if anyone knows how to do that, or if anyone knows of any other solution to this problem I need this.
Scott: this is like a serious problem here.
Rym: Yeah, you're right.
Rym: That's kind of hard to Google for.
Scott: yeah How do I change?
Rym: Control?
Scott: Yeah, how to modify Mac Firefox keyboard shortcuts from command to control?
Scott: I don't think that's gonna come up with the right answer.
Rym: I'm kind of curious too because that would I would run into this problem if I tried.
Scott: it's it's incredibly frustrating You know, especially since right?
Scott: I mean while this is gonna be my work computer and Hours wise I will spend more time using it than other computers.
Scott: I still use Windows and Linux just about everywhere and I've got this virtual machine and you know.
Scott: So I'm not really, you know while I'm using a Mac hardware machine like, you know, eight hours a day at least probably You know for the you know foreseeable future.
Scott: I You know, I'm not really using Mac OS, you know that many hours and So I getting used to like using the command key instead of the control key is probably just gonna be incredibly frustrating Because I'd have to keep switching back and forth, you know I've sort of unified the keyboard shortcuts across everything because I'm using you know Vim and the terminal and Firefox everywhere and they're all the same shortcuts except on the stupid Mac where it's a different shortcut.
Scott: It's like die.
Scott: So that's help me out.
Scott: Yeah, so my pinky doesn't break off.
Rym: We won't give you anything other than fame and Internet glory, but that's it.
Rym: So you got any I don't know.
Rym: tech news a tech news Well speaking of I got a bunch of little stuff.
Scott: well speaking of the the apples, right?
Scott: There are some stories going around relatively recently less than a week ago that Well, actually it's sort of like there were murmurs way back like months ago.
Scott: And now there's more murmurs, right?
Scott: The murmur way back was that Apple bought like these chip making chip designing companies like companies that design microchips Right and more recently they've started to hire, you know microchip designer people.
Scott: So everyone's like Apple's gonna make their own chips, you know.
Scott: And the murmurs that are going around are ludicrous.
Scott: I say cuz what people are saying is like Apple's gonna make you know their own CPUs instead of using Intel that way, you know You can't install OS X on fucking anything But Apple hardware because Apple hard will be the only way to get Apple chips and that's gonna be it.
Rym: No, they don't even need that.
Scott: while Apple would probably like the DRM aspect of that There is no way that any chip Apple can design is ever ever ever going to Match with Intel or Nvidia in the performance power usage efficiency departments.
Scott: It would cost so much money and require so much talent.
Scott: There is absolutely no way they can ever catch up to that right, you know, it's kind of sad.
Rym: I used to work in a place where I could find out more about this But yeah, I don't.
Scott: but what Apple is doing I can almost guarantee is they're looking for ways To develop more specialized chips for the smaller devices, you know, that's actually what I was just about to suggest.
Rym: It's also a way to really really reduce the cost of production for things like iPod.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it's not necessarily the CPUs either right?
Scott: I mean look at an iPod.
Scott: right in an iPod You have all different functionality, right?
Scott: You need a display chip for the screen You need audio processing for the output, you know hole to your headphones You need input processing because they all iPods all have.
Scott: you know audio input.
Scott: you need, you know I guess some sort of I/O chip for you know, the buttons I guess and stuff like that, right and you know You only need certain functions, right?
Scott: So you can you know put a CPU in the iPod, right.
Scott: and then you know Put some software and some firmware on there and you're good to go.
Scott: But if you can somehow manage to make a chip You know that in hardware does the things the iPod does and doesn't do anything else and is incredibly Specialized to those functions, you know mp3 decoding video decoding, etc.
Scott: Etc.
Scott: You can make the iPod a fuck lot smaller.
Rym: I don't think miniaturization itself is gonna be the concern because if you I mean if you actually touched the newest shuffle.
Scott: Well, they're not snow not just smaller But also more efficient in the electricity and battery life and I think we're pretty much every department.
Rym: I think we're gonna see a lot more battery life if they make their own gym.
Rym: Yes, the iPhone battery life, you know, it's the other thing, you know I did see a lot of rumors about.
Rym: you know, where is Apple gonna build their fab?
Rym: They're very clearly going to whatever and I don't know what company they'll go with but they might design a chip But then they'll send it to someone like Charlie.
Scott: Yeah, almost nobody owns fabs.
Scott: almost everyone who designs chips sends them to a fab Puts an order in and gets the chips back in the mail.
Scott: That's that's how it works.
Scott: I mean, I mean all the iPods are what they're built by like Foxconn or some, you know, Chinese place, right?
Scott: But if you buy an Apple product, it says designed by Apple in California made in China.
Rym: Well, like as I recall remember the the cell processor the ps3 the IBM baby.
Rym: Yeah, that was made by IBM, but it was also made by chartered and all these other people.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know this fabs all over Taiwan Southeast Asia in the u.s.
Scott: This fab some of them not that The biggest fabs in the country is right down the road from us used to work at it But there's you know, there's lots of fabs around and very few company.
Scott: There's a lot more companies designing chips than you know, actually making them.
Scott: I mean, it's the same thing with electronics in general, right?
Scott: I mean a lot of people design gadgets, but they don't own a gadget factory, right?
Scott: I mean just because you design gadgets and sell gadgets with your brand name on them doesn't mean you own a gadget factory.
Scott: You probably just pay someone else to use their gadget factory Usually China.
Rym: more to the point if they actually are going to be designing chips and you know those these rumors are going around We're not going to see any products using these chips for years at least because the does the process of making a chip.
Scott: Well, they did.
Scott: they bought a company that already had a bunch of work done and now they hired people.
Scott: So they're probably well on their way.
Scott: I think within a year or two You'll see the problem.
Rym: maybe because the once the chip is designed like you've got a solid design down.
Rym: That's when all the problems actually begin because that's when you do like the test runs you have.
Rym: you know The really poor yields you have to go through this specialized kind of.
Scott: yeah But they're not doing.
Scott: yeah, but the chips that they're probably making right are.
Scott: they're not making like these high-performance CPUs.
Scott: They're making like, you know chips that are much simpler.
Rym: No But if they're making simpler chips or they're using commodity Manufacturing methods then they're not gonna get that much benefit because they probably can't get much more.
Scott: I mean, they're gonna use modern manufacturing methods, but they're gonna make like, you know an mp3 decoder chip.
Scott: You know that has some other stuff on it.
Scott: It's not, you know, too complicated.
Scott: So it's you know, it's it's gonna be a lot less difficult than if you were gonna make, you know From actual manufacturing.
Rym: it's an incredibly complicated process and the real issue is that if you make anything new it Takes ages to figure out how to make it efficiently enough for it not to just lose money.
Scott: Yeah, but you're not making it, you know, calm.
Scott: It's not like, you know a core to do.
Scott: All right, it's it's you know It's an iPod chip.
Rym: What I'm saying is that if they use kind of the tried-and-true Manufacturing methods such that they could start rolling this out more quickly.
Rym: Then there are.
Rym: they very likely can't do anything Particularly advanced and as in I don't see them doing anything.
Rym: That would be a noticeable improvement.
Scott: Well, it's a noticeable improvement because what they'll be doing is what Apple has always done right ever since the Apple - which was come.
Scott: Right now, you know, the iPod will have three chips in it.
Scott: In the next iPod will have one that does the work of all those three, you know That's that's really all Steve Wozniak did on the original Apple was.
Scott: he just looked at existing computers And he said and there are all these new chips coming out all the time that you can get in Radio Shack or wherever.
Scott: And he's like, hey this new chip that just came out does the work of those three chips.
Scott: And he just kept doing that over and over again and the result was the first Apple computer.
Scott: So I think that you know, there aren't these new chips coming out.
Scott: that does the work of you know The three anymore at least not as rapidly because people have sort of settled into just getting a CPU and doing everything in software With very few specialized hardware chips.
Scott: So what they're gonna do is they're gonna do it Steve Wozniak did way back in the early 80s is You know make a chip that does the work of three or four chips that are already in the iPod.
Rym: I guess if they're gonna if they do something like that I don't think we're actually gonna see any major improvements in their technology.
Rym: All we're gonna see is they charge the same amount of money for the iPod But it cost them a lot less to make it.
Scott: they could be that too.
Scott: I'm pretty sure that they're pretty much by making their own chips They're pretty much getting all of the benefits that we have described.
Scott: at the only cost to them is the cost of designing the chips.
Rym: Well, you know, this is kind of the common thing for any time the economy is slow Especially now where Apple, you know their sales in a recession and this sort of thing people won't buy.
Scott: the $400 I think is Apple's doing better than they are.
Rym: but but now is the time to invest in R&D Especially when it's cheaper to get our and absolutely is.
Scott: this is the R&D time.
Scott: Yes,
Rym: so Apple's looking forward and I'll bet they're just trying to lower their costs and I don't think Anything of note is going to come of this Except for the fact that Apple profits will increase in the long run at least for two years and maybe after that time They might have some sort of advanced chip that does something cool.
Scott: Hmm Plus, you know any?
Scott: you know when they do make the like these chips, you know, they don't really advertise like.
Scott: hey This is what chips are in the iPod, right?
Scott: You're only gonna find out like if they've done something like after in gadget busts an iPod open and says hey There's only like one chip in this thing.
Scott: What the fuck?
Rym: Well, see that's the initial stage.
Rym: my bet stage one is just you know Have a cheaper manufacturing process sell the $400 iPods, but make a lot more money off of them.
Scott: Which is that'd be funny.
Scott: open up an iPod and it's literally a headphone jack a screen a chip a battery and a flash Thing and that's it.
Rym: But then maybe if I were Apple my long-term strategy would be that two three years from now I Suddenly have you know, the Intel brand a little logo the AMD little logo.
Rym: I would have the Apple chip logo.
Rym: I'd call it something cool.
Rym: I would put that sticker on all the stuff that used it and just charge twice as much for those things.
Rym: Not bad regardless of whether or not the chip was actually different.
Scott: Mmm.
Rym: I can't rely on Apple too much though.
Scott: Someone else also said that you know make is like.
Scott: right now a lot of the chips in the Apple Products are made by you know competitors.
Scott: Like I think like Samsung makes them like flash that they use It's like.
Scott: but Samsung also makes mp3 players.
Scott: So by making their own chips, maybe even making their own flash and you know and such they can avoid some of that.
Scott: you know conflict of interest in that department and also, you know, sometimes Apple like wants to order stuff and You know, they're sort of held back and their supplies are limited or whatever because you know, people can't keep up.
Rym: Well, it's not just maybe but it did the.
Rym: there are two basic paradigms of manufacturing for chips And this applies generally to industrial stuff not just chips thing, you know flash and other parts Like I just said.
Rym: this also applies broadly to general industrial manufacturing.
Rym: but there's either the kind of Commodity you create a whole bunch stored in warehouses and ship it out or the so-called Just-in-time manufacturing where you are manufacturing things to be shipped directly to the people who use them and you never carry an inventory which of Course is much higher risk for the people downstream much lower risk for the people upstream.
Scott: Mm-hmm Yeah, I think you know Apple might be doing something there to you know help its flow.
Rym: but speaking of a conflict of interest remember way back we I forget what show it was but we talked a lot about how Cabled providers are in this conundrum where on one hand they provide TV and on the other hand they provide internet.
Rym: So they have this automatic conflict of interest between two competing media that they have an interest in both of them.
Rym: You know, what do they do?
Rym: They're kind of screwing water screwing the other and they're working to the contrary aims of all the consumers.
Scott: Yeah, it's like if you were simultaneously I don't know an ISP and a newspaper at the same time.
Scott: It's like, you know, how well by letting people go to news.google.com We're also making our newspaper business go down.
Rym: Well, there's an article on slash shot talking about just that before so we broke the news first.
Rym: I think everyone smart already realized that.
Rym: but it is an interesting article because they the.
Rym: The supposition here is that cable networks that are also is PS most of their infrastructure costs and most of the money and Expenses that are that are happening now that are causing them to say oh we need to raise prices are from HD TV Content and have nothing to do with their ISP internet side.
Scott: Well, but I thought that you know TV like cable TV, you know doesn't use the same.
Scott: I mean it uses bandwidth.
Scott: obviously That's you know technological reality, but it's not IP bandwidth.
Scott: It's you know broadcast it out.
Scott: It's not packet So it's got.
Rym: but so I said infrastructures the infrastructure and cost on the back end of distributing this high-definition signal all this Data everywhere storing it relaying it Uh-huh, keeping up with it Don't forget all the licensing fees and the the complicated relationship of how our cable network gets television and then gives it to you
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Well, then again, not all is PS are also cable companies.
Scott: You know, some of the ones are you know that are you know, sort of hurting net neutrality are not all you know cable They're you know, giving you, you know t1s and DSLs and phone companies and shit like that.
Rym: Well, they're talking just about cable.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: All right.
Rym: It's an interesting article.
Rym: I recommend everyone read it.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it is.
Scott: it is sort of true that you know you look and you know cable channels do use bandwidth And if they remove say a cable channel, they could fill that space Theoretically, you know with packets instead, you know, they could do that.
Rym: Well, I think it's more that there's gonna be a lot of pressure and a lot of people are supposing this.
Rym: at least You don't remember the whole a la carte cable pricing thing the thing that the that FCC supposedly demanded but never happened.
Rym: if that actually happens that might just be the absolute end of TV.
Rym: because think about this that Like the domino effect would be massive because you've got a lot of TV channels like sippy That no one would actually pay for in enough quantity.
Scott: Yeah if you get if I gave you a list of every cable channel there that exists in the entire world and You would circle the ones you're willing to pay for and the more you circle the more you pay How many are you gonna circle?
Scott: I would circle.
Rym: imagine cable TV would become ESPN TV.
Scott: Yeah, I would circle pretty much any live sports network that carries a New York team that I care about right?
Scott: I would circle one of the mate one of each of the major networks just because You know Cartoon Network ain't what it used to be.
Scott: So fuck them, right?
Scott: I don't know what.
Scott: I circle anything else.
Rym: What about sippy?
Scott: No, no, no.
Rym: What about the anime network?
Rym: does that even still?
Scott: that's an on-demand thing and it sucks.
Rym: Yeah, it does suck I just point out.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: What else would I circle?
Scott: I Don't know.
Rym: What would you circle thing is if if the internet provided live sports for free?
Scott: I don't even need all live sports.
Scott: I just need you know, the incredibly major live sports that I just need hockey.
Rym: All I need is I'm willing to pay a lot of money to just get hockey on my computer.
Scott: You can you can pay you can but it's they black out New York, which you don't care about.
Rym: So I kind of care.
Scott: well Because that's the thing.
Scott: It's like the baseball.
Scott: look at this, right?
Scott: You can go to MLB TV baseball, right?
Scott: You can pay like a lot of money to get the audio of all baseball games live, right?
Scott: But they black out your local teams.
Scott: But with an iPhone you can pay ten bucks a year and get the audio live of all games including your local teams.
Scott: So what the fuck?
Scott: it's from the same company Major League Baseball.
Scott: It's not like a different company.
Scott: It's the same people.
Rym: See, I don't know what sports is thinking because they haven't embraced the internet yet.
Rym: But at the same time I feel like they could make a lot more.
Scott: It's like they've been there have done internet stuff.
Scott: I mean they put Sunday Night Football live streaming on NBC sports.com last year, but they haven't gone all the way.
Scott: They haven't gone all the way.
Scott: I mean like the Masters golf tournament was partially on Streaming live.
Rym: it's like you could watch like oh my god the stupid masters killed because you know We only we have like these three t1s for like useless internet.
Rym: So everyone was watching the master route anything that doesn't matter.
Rym: over these three t1s and during the stupid masters They were completely utilized for the entirety.
Scott: Everyone wants to tie.
Scott: watch Tiger Woods.
Scott: I mean even me.
Scott: I don't care about golf, but it's like you see Tiger Woods.
Rym: But plus look if I can watch that different sports have embraced it to different degrees, too.
Rym: And it's it's this complicated give-and-take, but and see double-a basketball.
Scott: They put the whole tournament live streaming.
Rym: I think the bellwether is going to if we start seeing a shift toward Ubiquitous sports coverage that is easy for people to get to and not too expensive on the internet.
Scott: It makes sports a lot more popular.
Rym: more to the point I think a lot of sub popular sports know them the less, you know, like hockey and f1 and all those things.
Scott: Oh f1 f1 is streaming on the internets.
Scott: Oh my gosh.
Rym: Not only would they get a big boost, but I think that is the canary for the absolute end of broadcast television.
Scott: Oh, definitely Absolutely, like.
Rym: I think that would just destroy it because everyone wants a CSPN.
Scott: the thing is the one thing about sports though, right?
Scott: Is that?
Scott: simultaneously with what we just said Sports are like the only thing that really needs to be in HD Like the difference between HD hockey and non HD hockey.
Scott: if you if you look I mean Normally like people look at like an HD movie in a non HD movie and they're like think sometimes they can't even tell the difference.
Scott: But in HD hockey, you can see more of the ice You can eat it's easier to see the puck.
Scott: There is a dramatic difference like ludicrously dramatic.
Scott: So if you want to put it over the Internet's, you know with a packet switched You know type of situation rather than a cables kind of situation.
Scott: You're using even more bandwidth.
Scott: So You know for the HD.
Rym: so see.
Rym: at the same time if There were some sort of course cable TV could benefit from this if they use IP v6 into the multicast Even with if we just used a multicast type of infrastructure To stream live media.
Rym: Because the live stream, you know The everyone watching it at once is the only real bandwidth problem We have left.
Rym: if it's not a live stream if it's just you know, after the fact time shifted anything like that Peer-to-peer torrent style media distribution works beautifully.
Rym: Yep The only thing that doesn't handle is a live stream and multicast handles that perfectly.
Rym: Mm-hmm You can just assume that everyone no one uses multicast.
Rym: Well multicast is very difficult to use.
Scott: Yes We should do a show on multicast technology, that's good because I don't only know, you know, the surface level things I've learned.
Rym: we use it extensively at work and I I thought I knew a lot about it and I did.
Rym: but I've learned a Lot more.
Rym: that's good.
Scott: Yeah Postgres is hard by the way.
Rym: Yeah hard, but awesome.
Scott: Well, it's also very hard.
Rym: But speaking of hard things of the day Oh Thing of the day you got a thing of the day.
Scott: Well, do you remember a while ago?
Scott: There was this manga guide to databases.
Rym: I do in fact, it was on slash dot or recently again real again There was something to it.
Scott: I saw it just a little while ago to remind It's been around for a few months now But it's um, basically someone made a little manga book and it was a guide to databases.
Scott: so as an educational manga about Databases and it was cute.
Scott: I discovered something called Ubuntu.
Scott: it is a manga guide to Ubuntu Ubuntu.
Scott: So, how can that not be?
Scott: how can that not be the thing of the day?
Scott: Wow, there's an inside joke that disappeared I know right and the thing is I'm looking at like the arts.
Scott: Pretty good for something that it's like educational whatever and it was, you know Originally done in Japanese for Japanese people and is now translated to English and it's like totally awesome.
Rym: I think there's a big market for this.
Scott: I hope there's a lot of Japanese people use Ubuntu.
Rym: I hope artists get together with their tech friends and make more stuff like this.
Scott: It's funny because I'm looking at this drawing of like some girls sitting at a desk with the computer and she sort of got this like Look and like.
Scott: if you look at the her speech, it's all like, you know Japanese characters, but there's words like gooey Unixer Windows OS Slackware.
Scott: open Solaris question mark.
Scott: It's kind of funny By the way.
Scott: open Solaris while I don't really.
Scott: I mean Solaris is good for stuff But the main thing going on right now with open Solaris is they have.
Scott: ZFS is by default and ZFS is like the best file System to ever exist in the history of the universe.
Scott: and if you're running like a NAS or something Open Solaris is the win for the file servers right now.
Rym: So I'm not.
Rym: this isn't my thing of the day, but I just have to point it out on CollegeHumor.
Rym: right now There's a CollegeHumor tribute to Guy Ritchie and if you don't know who that is just go to CollegeHumor and find the video.
Rym: But no my thing of the day is that there was a man in Texas Bill Waters who for whatever reason he bought this old ledger book and he's flipping through it and it was from some pharmacy somewhere and Inside of it.
Rym: It happened to have these interesting old formulas for a whole bunch of weird stuff.
Rym: One of them was entitled Dr.
Rym: Pepper's peps and bitters Mm-hmm.
Rym: He may or may not have found one of the original formulas for either.
Rym: Dr.
Rym: Pepper or a Dr.
Rym: Pepper derived Digestive.
Scott: Well, you don't want the second one.
Rym: You might you might.
Scott: I think we have better digestives nowadays than they did in the olden days But I recommend.
Rym: this is an interesting article because a lot of people don't realize that like the formula for coca-cola Dr.
Rym: Pepper or any of these kind of old soft drinks and even a lot of new food are not patented.
Rym: and The reason they're not patented because it's when you apply for a patent You have to say what you're doing and give it to the world and then when the patent expires, it's free reign.
Scott: Yeah, so that's the thing the difference between a patent and a copyright.
Scott: at least practically speaking.
Scott: right you copyright something.
Scott: Well, there's also trade seeker right?
Scott: So trade secret is where you don't tell anybody anything.
Scott: You don't copyright it You don't patent it.
Scott: You don't do shit.
Scott: You just keep it a secret.
Scott: and if anyone steals the secret you can be like, hey, they stole our secret, right?
Scott: Patent.
Scott: when you patent something you say I invented this.
Scott: here are diagrams of it.
Scott: Here's descriptions of it.
Scott: Here's the whole thing.
Scott: Here's my invention.
Scott: You show it to the government and the government shows it to the whole world and everyone can look it up in the patent database.
Scott: But everyone can see it, but no one's allowed to copy it.
Scott: for what?
Scott: 14 years.
Scott: I think some number of years.
Scott: No one can copy it, but everyone can see it.
Scott: But when the years run out Everyone can copy it.
Scott: That's what a patent does and a copyright while we all know what a copyright does.
Scott: So, you know, they patented a lot of these things back in the day.
Scott: so any old inventions you can copy but usually you don't want to copy an old invention unless you're steampunk in it because You got something better.
Scott: nowadays, you know who wants to copy, you know an apple - unless you you know Really want to make one?
Rym: Well plus I mean think I'm back then.
Rym: This was the you know, the early days of soda.
Rym: when suddenly people are making soda There's soda fountains and soda juice, but those were good days.
Scott: food never goes out of style.
Rym: So When was the last time anyone drank moxie?
Scott: Most food never goes out of style.
Scott: So old food is totally awesome.
Rym: Actually, you know, you know, as long as it's not the coca-cola with actual cocaine in it, you know It's big in Costa Rica.
Rym: What tab really?
Scott: Yeah Until you got to try that Pepsi throwback and tell me what the deal is.
Rym: I'll try it.
Rym: We got to do a double-blind though.
Scott: Oh, you want me to do it that way?
Scott: Yeah, we should All right, so go buy some cans or whatever.
Scott: I'll get some throwback and then get some and then get some Pepsi also and I could regular old Pepsi.
Rym: I could tell the difference between the dr.
Rym: Peppers, but I the dr.
Scott: Pepper and then we should also.
Scott: they think it Mountain Dew throwback.
Scott: So we'll do both.
Rym: but there was I don't know because Mountain Dew I don't think was ever made with sugar.
Scott: Yeah, so they're throwing back to nothing.
Scott: They're throwing back to what Mountain Dew would have been like.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It's a. that's all you.
Scott: I don't.
Scott: I don't drink the soda But I do enjoy the idea of the sugar soda.
Rym: Mountain Dew was this weird thing because I can't stand it now It's not a good drink.
Rym: But when I was young I drank it all the time, but I didn't even really like it.
Rym: then I drank it because it was the most caffeinated soda I knew about Not more than you didn't know about Joel.
Scott: Well back then I know about Joel.
Rym: Joel was hard to get only the bodega was hard to get and even then my parents wouldn't let me go to the bodega.
Scott: I was like middle school and it say it was great cuz it said like 2x on it like they were bragging.
Scott: Yeah, now where's Joel Red Bolt own them, but it was weird.
Rym: I remember there was this culture in middle school of those kids what were hopped up on caffeine all the time and Mountain Dew was the drink of choice never would carry around like their 2-liter.
Rym: and like.
Rym: we made a big deal about caffeine and altoids Mmm, I guess that's what we were into.
Rym: I don't know altoids are a big deal in high school But then we discovered kick and we thought that it had more caffeine in it.
Rym: It tasted like ass.
Scott: Why don't you do penguin mints?
Rym: There weren't penguin mints back then.
Rym: Yeah, there were when we were in middle school.
Scott: Oh in high school.
Scott: We had penguin mints.
Rym: Yeah, I'm talking middle school.
Rym: Okay high school.
Rym: I learned about coffee.
Scott: Uh-huh Anyway, anyway, so we're gonna do show about typing as promised.
Rym: Yes, I sing.
Scott: All right, so the dead?
Rym: So if zombies attack?
Rym: First thing you got to do
Scott: I want to talk about learning to type first because you know Like a lot of people have a hard time learning to type and I had you know It was hard for me to learn to type, you know, I used a computer since kindergarten.
Scott: I used a computer, right?
Rym: How did you learn how to type.
Rym: wait what first when did you transition from you know, trying to type to?
Rym: Actually typing correctly.
Scott: Well, I mean, you know, I was hunted and pecking since kindergarten, right?
Scott: But I got kind of fast ish because I did it so much But it wasn't.
Scott: I wasn't typing properly and I knew I should type properly But I just didn't and I tried to use a couple typing programs, but I never stuck to it really, you know.
Scott: And then in high school, there was a typing class and I eventually got around to taking it I don't know if I've told the story in the show before and the teacher was this old lady.
Scott: She was so old and she was sort of crazy Right, but and it was this computer lab full of IBM xt's like the oldest possible IBM's in the universe and they're these giant clickety clickety keyboards.
Scott: and like I was I Took the last time that class was ever given.
Scott: the lady retired and they got rid of the computer lab.
Scott: right after I took that Class I was like, whoo?
Scott: But I took that class and we went in and they had you know a silly little typing program, you know Where you would you know, it's like there'd be like a little race car, you know on some five and a quarter inch floppy disk And you'd type in the race car would go and we had like it is incredibly incredibly old Microsoft Word.
Scott: we would type in you know in this incredibly blocky font and you know stuff like that.
Scott: and just Doing it going to that class every day, you know five days a week and sticking to it Like suddenly I didn't even realize you know that I was like, oh shit.
Scott: I'm typing.
Scott: Oh shit Yes, I got it.
Scott: You know, it's like I was thinking hard about it, you know for a while like, okay that letters over here That letter this finger in that direction and I still don't type a hundred percent properly.
Scott: I mean, I never used the right shift ever.
Scott: I know I'm supposed to.
Scott: I just don't really.
Scott: I never use right shift.
Scott: I always use left shift for everything.
Scott: So if I'm like gonna type an uppercase a I'll move my ring finger all the way over to the a. you know Also like up in the middle area up in the top in the middle where the index fingers go like in the TU area.
Scott: You know, I always like sometimes my fingers will cross over to the other side.
Scott: It's like I'll use the left index and I should use the right index and vice versa sometimes and also the numbers above.
Scott: You know the the numpad numbers I can type, you know, I take my hand to put on the numpad.
Scott: I can type like crazy.
Scott: but the numbers above the letters I have to look sometimes or feel around or I'll hit the wrong one sometimes.
Scott: but other than that I type, you know.
Rym: See I never really took typing classes like they had it in my school and when I was in like fifth grade We had to do these kind of exercises.
Rym: They they had this thing called computer class and I think that was when I realized that pretty much no one Anywhere near me in the world at that time knew anything about computers.
Scott: I learned that in kindergarten when you know, I could play word but the teacher didn't know how to play word much.
Rym: I never owned a computer of my own and I found the word much is debug menu until my 486 SX to 486 DX.
Rym: for but well, I guess it felt my Atari.
Scott: But anyway, but I remember tired 7800 is not a computer.
Rym: They would take technically it is I guess Yeah, they would take me my time.
Rym: X was a computer.
Rym: I'll go into this room and it had all these old computers on the wall.
Rym: I never would set a computer and log in by typing your name But if my name was screwed up because there's a space in my name so I would only type the first two letters.
Rym: if I typed anything else it would crash and Then it would ask us questions.
Rym: Like what's four plus five?
Rym: What color is this?
Rym: What color is that?
Rym: and every now and then it'd be this typing exercise Which was just type the sentence you're looking at and if you don't type the right letter nothing happens.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and it was awful.
Rym: I don't learn how to type.
Scott: that's not gonna help you learn to type not at all.
Rym: When I really learned how to type was when I finally got my computer.
Rym: I got online and I was hanging out in prodigy chat room No shit.
Rym: And I wanted to say stuff to people and I had to say stuff quickly or I'd be get left behind.
Rym: I learned how to type very very rapidly just by actually having to type to do other things.
Rym: It's the I find my whole life and I think this applies to all technology.
Rym: if you want to learn a technology Don't try to learn that technology.
Rym: try to do something with that technology and you'll learn it as a course.
Rym: I'm just doing it.
Scott: But the other thing is, you know, if you you know, a lot of people like, you know They'll say I want to learn Python or something, right?
Scott: So they'll be like, okay, and they'll go about learning it.
Scott: It's like no, no, no, that doesn't that doesn't work.
Scott: You need to have a need for it to learn, you know.
Scott: It's like I want to learn how to swing a hammer.
Scott: Well, I hope you have something you're gonna make that needs hammering and it has to be something you actually want to make and not Just you know some board with a bunch of nails in it for the purpose of hammering, you know It has to be a real thing that you want.
Scott: So that requires you to learn the skill.
Scott: if you're not required to learn the skill It's gonna be very difficult to learn the skill for reals.
Scott: And now the other thing something I've realized right is That you know, it's funny that you talk about how you learn to type from a chat room, right?
Scott: But if you look around the world today majority people don't.
Scott: well, I think what it is is that You know, we talk about like AOL speaks, you know, like lol, you know They're tech speak or whatever the fuck you want to call it.
Scott: Basically, you know not typing properly not spelling things using like the letter U instead of you
Rym: I always felt even when I was a young kid I always felt like people who typed like that were just solving a problem in the wrong way like the price of the problem.
Rym: I cannot type fast enough to say what I want to say quickly solution type shittier.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I sort of realized like, you know people sort of get this idea that that text speak AOL speak kind of typing.
Scott: You know where you leave out all these vowels and use the letter R instead of ARE is because of bad grammar or lack of Intelligence?
Scott: it's not.
Scott: it's simply because of bad typing skills.
Scott: All right, and it has nothing to do with age either.
Scott: I mean my grandma right?
Scott: She doesn't know how to type.
Scott: She can't type for hilla beans.
Scott: And the only thing she really knows how to use is, you know GM or pigeon to.
Scott: I am people.
Scott: that's all she knows how to do right and she refuses to learn anything else.
Scott: so we just sort of given up on her and she's stubborn and impatient.
Scott: but When she types she'll type like the letter U and it's not because she's some 13 year old kid it's because she wants to send you the message quickly and she can't type.
Scott: and You know, even an old person will naturally arrive at that solution without, you know hearing of that solution from anyone else.
Scott: She wasn't influenced by anyone else typing like that to her or seeing anyone else talk like that.
Scott: She arrived there on her own, you know, and you're typing on like a cell phone, you know.
Scott: And it doesn't have a full keyboard like a blackberry or even if it does it's hard to type.
Scott: and that's why people you know When they're texting not just because of the character limit, but also because of that but because About that about why it's the number of characters that it is.
Rym: It's fascinating.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, it's because texts go on like this sideband.
Scott: It's like it's it's in the routing protocol.
Rym: No, it talks about the magic number of you know, how many characters you need on average to form complete sentences?
Rym: Oh Yeah, there's.
Scott: there's an interesting article You see because the other thing the other interesting technological thing is that text messages aren't actually sent on their own.
Rym: Yes That's why that's why the article is so fascinating because it talks about how they it would have just been 128 characters because that was perfect for the sideband they had.
Rym: yeah But it turned out that the magic number for typing sentences.
Rym: a guy just sat down and wrote all these random Sentences whatever he was thinking of and he counted the characters and he decided that 128 characters Prevents you from saying anything meaningful, but a hundred and sixty was this magic number.
Rym: Uh-huh Yeah, but yet the I didn't read the whole article.
Rym: So I'm going based on slash.
Scott: We'll talk about text messages themselves.
Scott: We should do a show.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: effort show Yeah, whatever.
Rym: But one thing I really find interesting is that when I first got online like really not prodigy, you know and all those chat rooms the BBS is.
Rym: but when I got ICQ back in the day when While they're probably were shit cockers there weren't nearly as many because there was a barrier to entry and I'm not saying the barrier to Entries you'd come back.
Rym: It's just you know, it was different time.
Rym: you understand 1987 88 like 1997 98 that's more likely but nobody typed like that.
Rym: the only people who typed in that kind of halting lead speak any of that stuff were the idiots and Everyone like when I was online, you know talking to people in ICQ just going into random chat rooms.
Rym: It was, you know begin sentences with uppercase letters end them with punctuation semicolons.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it's simply a matter of typing skill, you know It's like.
Scott: I knew plenty of people that are actually like.
Scott: you'll see executives type, you know Like emailing really stupidly and it's not because they're stupid It's because they can't type for shit and they can't be bothered to sit there.
Scott: You know doing the one finger jabs to write this gigantic essay, you know There for days kind of randomly faster than to write with a pen.
Rym: I was I was writing documentation for our internal wiki and I use the acronym WYSIWYG a bunch of times and I realized that I can type.
Rym: what you see is what you get faster than I can type WYSIWYG.
Scott: It's about the same.
Rym: I cuz I have to stop and think about what letters are in WYSIWYG because it's not.
Rym: Yeah, it's not an acronym WYSIWYG It's not an acronym that works for the letters in my brain.
Rym: It works as like this one phenom like this word WYSIWYG.
Rym: So when I have to type it, it's a lot easier to type.
Rym: what you see is what you get.
Rym: Yep, exactly, and it bothered me.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: now something else about typing, right?
Scott: I mean we've done shows on keyboards before.
Scott: but like I said I learned on the IBM XT and I actually think that if you're going to learn to type You should try to find an IBM XT keyboard Which it is possible to make an IBM XT keyboard work With a modern computer.
Rym: I mean, I have the DOS keyboard.
Scott: That's pretty close.
Rym: I love this thing so much.
Scott: Then the main thing about the reasons the XT or a similar keyboard are good for learning to type on is number one.
Scott: The buttons are hard to push down.
Scott: Relatively speaking they have a lot of tactile feedback.
Scott: They click they snap, you know There's a lot of space between.
Rym: the tactile feedback is key If you want to be a touch typist, right?
Rym: I mean, have you ever tried to type on a non feedback keyboard at all?
Rym: Like one of those solid surfaces with capacitance.
Scott: Yeah, like you type, you know, like on a table.
Scott: you ever seen that like keyboard?
Scott: That's like a laser thing that you know draws a keyboard on the table.
Scott: with a laser.
Rym: I mean the thing where for like 10 years every on the internet you kept seeing pictures of a company saying Yeah, we know you can buy it But it's now you can but for a long time you couldn't.
Rym: but even like these pictures of it and people saying yes We made it it's coming out next week and then it never.
Scott: yeah But I try to learn like, you know how to type on a laptop keyboard, right?
Scott: It's hard to feel your way around.
Scott: the whole thing is flat.
Scott: It's not at an angle, right?
Scott: I mean if you learn how to type already you can type on a laptop keyboard.
Scott: But learning to type on a laptop keyboard is asking for trouble because you're not getting all this help.
Scott: You know in in, you know that teaches your fingers, you know an initial D. They talk about the hachi roku is the car that teaches you how to race because the car gives you all this feedback.
Scott: It's an old piece of junk.
Scott: All right, but the old piece of junk, you know by just by driving it You can sort of feel things out and learn things where if you started by driving a Ferrari You wouldn't be able to learn those things.
Scott: you would just die, right?
Scott: So if you're learning to type you should type on like a really really standard keyboard with you know big You know keys that are far apart standard size, you know Hopefully very springy and clicky if possible, you know, not mushy and comfortable.
Rym: But then again, I learned how to type without any of that.
Scott: Yeah, and that's why you don't but you don't type properly according to the correct typing way.
Rym: actually type with perfect home row now.
Scott: Oh really?
Scott: Cuz you used to you know, give you some bullshit like oh I typed with some made-up met that I made up.
Rym: now I didn't make up a method.
Rym: I noticed that when I used to type partly because the way I would always sit because you know, no lessons I learned to type just because I was in chat room.
Scott: Yeah, you didn't you didn't learn, you know, according to the you know The rules of typing you just learned a natural method of your hand.
Rym: but my natural method was fast.
Rym: and the real point I want to make is that if you want to learn how to type the Most foolproof way is to never take shortcuts
Scott: Mm-hmm
Rym: because I always typed in complete sentences and I typed with perfect grammar and I thought a lot about what I was saying.
Rym: So as a result, I was forced to either type very very slowly and be frustrated all the time or get faster very quickly.
Scott: Yep, you know, I mean if you type in complete sentences the correct grammar, right and all these things.
Scott: You're actually gonna force yourselves to use all the keys on the keyboard.
Scott: Not just a few of them.
Scott: more often You know, so you're gonna be forced to use, you know, the shift key to capitalize.
Scott: You're gonna be forced to use like the periods and the commas down low and the question marks and you know if you code that's even better.
Scott: because you're gonna be forced to use the curly braces and the back slashes and the Asterisks and the who knows what right.
Scott: and by forcing yourself to use more of the keys You'll be better at typing if you only if the less keys you use the less typing skill you'll have.
Rym: But what I used to do, you know, you you said I had a method.
Rym: I didn't.
Rym: it was just that I Tended to always be at this angle from the keyboard just because I sat like I Just kind of as slouched as possible like sideways in the chair.
Rym: So the keyboard was at an angle to my hands.
Rym: So my hands kind of just read an angle to the keyboard.
Rym: I always typed with the keyboard at like a 30-degree angle counterclockwise Mm-hmm.
Rym: So as a result my hands like floated.
Rym: But I realized later that this is why I respect home row printing or piping so much And why I think you should learn home row if you can.
Rym: Naturally while my hands kind of floated and I was at this angle my two index fingers Naturally always ended up hovering over where they should have been in the home row.
Rym: It's just that my whole hand pivoted left and right with the pinky finger on the other end Mm-hmm, but it's still like.
Rym: completely naturally and without instruction I gravitated toward the home row because it is the most efficient way to type.
Scott: Yeah, and the other thing is you know the home row, right?
Scott: You know this little nubs on the F and the J usually some keyboards like maybe the D and the K But mostly the F and the J for you to you know.
Scott: So that way without looking you can feel where to put your hands.
Scott: You know because you feel these little nubs on two of the keys.
Scott: That's where you put your index fingers And I think that's a big thing is not looking and if you have to get a keyboard that doesn't have any letters on it So you can't look and I think that will really help you.
Scott: if you have a you know I mean it takes some willpower if you're especially if you're used to looking to not look You know and it took me like a couple weeks to like you know stop looking you know.
Scott: So if you're having trouble learning you know because you keep looking Get a blank keyboard and that goes and force yourself to use it and throw and block up all your other Keyboards in a closet or something or very easily.
Rym: if you can't get a blank keyboard just get a Dvorak keyboard.
Scott: Oh, yeah, yeah Get a Dvorak keyboard.
Scott: or like pluck the keys off your keyboard and move them all around Because you can take keys off most keyboards
Rym: on most keyboards not for a long time the old IBM ones you could
Scott: yeah But I don't know Normal the kind of keyboard that I suggested you should be learning on.
Rym: you can take the keys off But those keyboards aren't that common.
Scott: yeah But take the key.
Scott: if you can take the keys off and shuffle them around.
Scott: That way you can't look because looking won't
Rym: help you see but at the same time Looking works just fine for me early on learning because I kind of I was trying to type quickly so I'd stare at the T keyboard and I kind of watch what my hands were doing and think about what they were doing.
Scott: see something else that actually helps is If you keep looking down right because the idea is you don't just get efficiency from being able to type quickly.
Scott: you get Efficiency from being able to look at the screen while typing right.
Scott: let's say you know how to type real fast But you have to look right so you'll look down at your hands.
Scott: You know type a whole sentence.
Scott: Then you'll look up and then see the typo.
Scott: then you have to go back and edit the typo.
Scott: But if you're looking while typing you'll see the typo when it appears and you'll Backspace it real quick with your typing skills and the sentence will be correct in a much faster amount of time.
Scott: So what you can do if you're having trouble looking and you can't shuffle the keys or get a blank keyboard?
Scott: Get an on-screen just like a graphic of the keyboard on the screen.
Scott: that way your eyes will at least be on the screen.
Scott: You won't have to look down at the keyboard because you have a reminder on the screen of where the keys are.
Rym: That is an absolutely fantastic way to learn how to type.
Scott: It's very good.
Scott: That's most typing programs.
Scott: have a picture of the keyboard on the screen in the early phases You know.
Rym: for that very reason actually I have one other really important hint.
Rym: Don't you at least when you're trying to learn how to type for computer stuff as much as possible early on Don't use the numbers at the top use your right hand only on the numpad and learn ten key typing?
Scott: Yes, you should be.
Rym: typing will save your ass.
Scott: You definitely want to learn how to type on the numpad to do like a whole bunch of numbers Like I use it all the time for example like I use list all right and I buy get a bunch of books in the mail and then I want to enter them all in With the ISBN numbers.
Scott: if I wasn't using the numpad, you know, how long that would take like forever.
Scott: So but I use the numpad.
Scott: He says like did it?
Rym: That's the one thing.
Rym: I was actually trained in ten key because my first job was for the US Census doing payroll.
Scott: So I would type in everyone's time sheets, yeah, I mean a lot of keyboards today don't have the numpad.
Scott: I mean, I don't have a numpad on my keyboard, but I have a separate numpad because Sometimes you just have to enter in a bunch of numbers, you know And if you're gonna enter in a bunch of numbers a spreadsheet or something.
Scott: the numpad is just so much faster like times a bajillion and It's something you know, you might not use it often, but when you're using it, it's so helpful.
Scott: You really numpad typing is almost as important as the regular keyboard typing and you should learn that too.
Scott: Don't neglect it.
Rym: I Really don't recommend typing games.
Rym: They diving typing in the dead is fun But at the same time you're gonna be.
Rym: you know, I've seen there seems well, they're good.
Scott: They're not good for learning to type.
Scott: they're good for you know, maintaining your typing skills.
Rym: But at the same time I feel like I see two different kinds of good typists and they're the people who type like 110 words a minute, but they make a mistake every other word.
Rym: They're just so fast that they make up for all the mistakes constantly by backspacing.
Rym: And then there are people who type like 70 words a minute, but they never make mistakes ever.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I'm in the former category.
Rym: I'll type like 120 words a minute But you'll see me like backspacing like at least once in every word.
Scott: mine sort of you know My with me.
Scott: it varies like if I'm typing something that's not too long like, you know Maybe I am or a tweet or a forum post.
Scott: 99% of the time.
Scott: it'll be a hundred percent correct and it won't be so fast But it'll be you know fast real fast.
Scott: But I go on typing something big like a blog post or an essay or something Like.
Scott: I'll type as fast or even faster than the ideas come into my brain.
Scott: But when I go back over it, they'll be miss, you know, four or five mistakes, you know every.
Scott: you know.
Scott: Mistake per paragraph you wanted.
Rym: as long as you can type faster than you can think of what you want to type You're good to go.
Scott: Yeah Then you're not limited in any way, you know, you know 120 words a minute.
Rym: I'm not going to be thinking of a hundred and twenty useful words to type in a minute.
Rym: That's only useful if you're doing something like transcribing.
Scott: Yeah transcribing and that's the reason a lot of people have Transcribers still like lawyers and like old lawyers and people like.
Scott: that is because you know, they're from the olden days.
Scott: They never typed they need to get lots of words onto paper, but they don't have any typing skills and they have.
Rym: You know that dr.
Rym: Pepper thing I was talking about.
Rym: Yeah, the biggest trouble they're having is that no one can read the handwriting in the ledger.
Rym: It's all in cursive and no one can read it.
Scott: Damn, we can read ancient tablets of stone with Sanskrit on them, but we can't read the dr Pepper, you know the way you said that I expected you to say ancient spirits of evil Transform this decade form into legible handwriting.
Rym: Okay, I don't know what else we can say about typing.
Rym: learn to type.
Scott: yeah everyone, you know You should really learn to type.
Scott: and you know, I think actually here Here's an incentive to learn to type right if you think about it in our forum.
Scott: We demand you know Excellent grammar and spelling, you know, we're not super perfect demanding, but it's got to be good.
Scott: You know, none of this, you know normal internet crap, right?
Scott: The thing is the reason that we demand that is not because we you know want excellent grammar and spelling but because if you're forced to have excellent grammar and spelling you'll be forced to think about what you're typing and thus you'll make better posts.
Scott: and if a post is Poopy and crappy you won't even bother and thus the overall, you know signal-to-noise ratio of quality on the forum will be up.
Scott: But if you learn to type right you won't have to think so much about typing a whole bunch of stuff in the forum.
Scott: so If you learn to type you can post a bunch of crap and probably get away with it Because you're gonna have great grammar and spelling and a big long post and type a bunch of bullshit.
Scott: But if you're typing in space for typing is bad.
Scott: You're gonna and it's gonna take you forever to type a bunch of bullshit.
Scott: So it's getting much more difficult for you to make low quality posts Especially fanboy pose.
Scott: Yeah, so being a fanboy with typing skills you have you have this Incredible dangerous power to spread stupidity at greater speeds.
Rym: actually some of the greatest fun I had was that back in the day with ICQ you could you can either type and people would see what you were typing in real time, which was the default or You could have it to where you could type your message and then hit enter and then it would go or alt enter in my case.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So Everyone I knew had it set to where I could see what they were typing, but they didn't realize that was what was going on.
Rym: so both a lot of people typed so slowly that they would start to like say something like ask a question and I would Answer the question before they sent it.
Rym: Mm-hmm You would not believe the amount of mayhem I could cause.
Rym: I convinced a large number of people that I had psychic powers.
Scott: Wow a large number is four or five but still Yeah You know, I think the other thing to say is that you know keyboards, right?
Scott: I mean computers have been around for a while and just about every aspect of them is improved.
Scott: We invented the mouse.
Scott: we upgraded to the optical mouse the laser mouse.
Scott: We put more buttons on the mouse.
Scott: the mouse is evolving.
Scott: The keyboard is evolving a little bit, you know They're moving the keys around.
Scott: some of the keyboards are getting stupid, you know, but really the keyboard is not going anywhere.
Scott: and You know, it's.
Scott: it's like the mouse doesn't take much learning to.
Scott: you know master, you know It's sort of intuitive in a way.
Scott: The keyboard needs mastery and it's not going anywhere.
Scott: The keyboard is gonna be around for a long.
Rym: Longevity is evidence of its efficiency.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: The keyboard is not going anywhere.
Scott: It's been around since the typewriter.
Scott: It's gonna be around for at least another decade or two though I do have to say all the it's not more almost every improvement.
Rym: I've said.
Rym: well quote unquote improvement.
Rym: I've seen two keyboards.
Rym: It's not actually improvement in my opinion.
Rym: like those split keyboards I feel like no good.
Rym: All they do is slow you down and hurt your wrist.
Scott: You know I have the happy hacking keyboard and the improvements it makes are the escape key is closer because I hit it very often because I Use vim which is not useful for most people who barely ever hit escape escape colon right percent sign.
Scott: There's a control instead of a caps lock, which is nice.
Rym: Yeah Of course, do we really need pause anymore?
Scott: No, but we don't.
Rym: and who in the world types in insert mode?
Rym: Well, the insert key is useful for other things Yes, but in many things that I do like if I'm in Word, I accidentally hit that key.
Rym: I'm fucked.
Rym: Yeah, that has never been useful to me No, but like shift insert like is paste in something and whatever the other thing I really need to get out here.
Rym: I had arguments at work about this and one because I'm on the right side.
Rym: Scott agrees with me.
Rym: Don't learn anything but QWERTY unless you speak a foreign language and have to use a foreign keyboard.
Rym: QWERTY is the only worthwhile keyboard.
Rym: Dvorak is absolute gibberish.
Rym: It's useless.
Rym: It's not better.
Rym: Anyone says it's better ask them for evidence.
Rym: There's no evidence.
Rym: It's this minority thing the only people who use two people who think it's cool or rationalize some bullshit reason for using it.
Scott: They just want to be different and they think it's better because they're like, oh look They took the most frequently used things and put them right near the index finger To be different, but they don't want to admit that.
Rym: so they rationalize why they're different.
Scott: that's correct.
Scott: But the rationalization has no basis in science or ergonomics or anything.
Rym: learning Dvorak is just gonna slow you down in QWERTY and make you generally incompatible with almost the entire world.
Scott: And there are people who say that they can just switch back and forth.
Scott: But they say I've seen people who have said they can switch back and forth sit at a QWERTY and go And mess up right and go oops just like I sit at a Dvorak and go oops.
Rym: Well, if I sit at a Dvorak I go.
Rym: what the fuck is this?
Scott: That's right.
Scott: So don't learn any other layout besides QWERTY.
Scott: It's not worth it.
Scott: It's just stupid.
Rym: Maybe a zerty but only if that's you know, the style of your area.
Scott: Yeah, you know learn your local keyboard and you know because I mean most people listening to this podcast know English because we're speaking in English and English is sort of becoming the language up to internets, you know, I mean most programming languages are in English.
Scott: You know, it's just the sad reality that you know, the not so great language I mean, it's not the worst language, but there are better languages.
Scott: But this is the one that won because the United States has the most money and the most guns.
Rym: I am curious.
Rym: What is a better language than English?
Scott: Yeah Loge bond Loge bond Esperanto not Esperanto.
Scott: Russians fun Russians fun Languages out there.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our crapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row.
Scott: crew calm or you can send audio feedback via Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website if you like what you hear.
Rym: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.