Rym: It's Thursday March 5th.
Scott: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: the laser tag the airsoft the paintball.
Scott: Let's do this Stupid economy.
Rym: I got this letter, you know, I don't really check my mail but I got this letter from Geico cuz.
Rym: I have a Geico credit card because they give me like a ton off my car insurance and Back when I used to drive a lot.
Rym: I got three percent off gas.
Scott: I mean, you know all credit cards that don't have some sort of annual fee, you know are relatively equal.
Scott: You know because we're not stupid where we're carrying a balance and you're only gonna carry a balance of in an emergency.
Scott: And in that case, do you really care what the interest rate is?
Scott: I mean, no one's gonna give you a 99% industry.
Scott: It's always gonna be some reasonable or relatively reasonable number.
Rym: Well, yeah, unless you get a quote unquote credit card from well Joe Joe down on the car, of course.
Scott: But the vast majority of credit cards are relatively equal.
Scott: So in most sit in the vast majority of situations.
Scott: this thing that separates them from one another is first of all Is it visa American Express or MasterCard?
Scott: or discover because that determines where it will be accepted.
Rym: I'm gonna lecture on credit cards there.
Scott: Well, no, I don't know but the other thing is the rewards.
Scott: So you chose the Geico credit card because they gave you huge rewards because auto insurance is a pretty big expense.
Scott: Well using that card except that saves you a lot of money.
Rym: My auto insurance has been for a while like $20 a month because I drive What what is apparently junk barely classified as a car?
Rym: what what I would have called in my younger days in Michigan a beater?
Scott: Yeah, I'm about to pay off my car.
Scott: So then I will own it fully and then I will decrease the insurance and get a higher Deductible.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Yep, and it will be much better.
Rym: I have like a $5,000 deductible on a car that's worth about five hundred dollars.
Scott: I've got a $500 deductible, which sucks.
Scott: I'd much rather have a one or two thousand dollar deductible But the owner of the car or part owner of the car will not let me.
Scott: Wow I need to buy the car from them into to to change the deductible.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway, you know I use this credit card, even though like I don't drive that much anymore.
Rym: So the benefits weren't so great, but whatever it had a high limit and they reduced my limit by an order of magnitude.
Rym: Huh.
Rym: and they sent this email basically saying hey We're lowering every single Geico credit card person's limit down to some piddly amount.
Rym: It's like $1,400.
Scott: Whoa, even if you had a big limit before they said that they're doing it across the board.
Rym: They have they're not.
Rym: they didn't even check anyone's credit.
Rym: They just dropped everyone across the board and I gotta get a new credit card now because I spend more than that every month.
Rym: So, you know, I can't I mean use my credit card I've got.
Scott: I've got a visa which is the Sony card from.
Scott: you know Which is the first credit card ever got.
Scott: and I recently got an American Express.
Scott: That's a cash back thingy and that's you know, pretty much, you know, it's the you can't get.
Scott: I mean I could get a gold or platinum or whatever American Express, but they all have annual fees big ones.
Scott: It's a big scam.
Scott: so I stick with the one that just gives me cash back right and I basically use the American Express for everything except for places that don't accept it.
Scott: and then I have visa which everyone fucking accepts and that you know, They both have limits of like three to four thousand or even more.
Scott: So it's like whatever I spend like I charge like $1,000 a month So it's no big deal.
Rym: Yeah, but I charge a little more than that.
Scott: So you're buying too much.
Rym: Buy a lot of stuff.
Rym: What do you want?
Rym: Plus it.
Rym: I've been.
Rym: it's weird now The economy's gone down, but I haven't really changed my spending habits.
Scott: Well, I haven't either because I was frugal before.
Scott: so I can't really get more frugal without starting to actually make sacrifices.
Scott: But I don't need to because I've been frugal and my bank account even I'm still employed.
Scott: I still make the same money.
Scott: Yeah, so I still am getting a profit.
Scott: The only reason I'm not actually seeing the actual number go way up is so that I keep Shoving thousands of dollars to pay off the car sooner than I'm supposed to.
Rym: it was just weird to have something like that happen.
Rym: It was one of those kind of secondary effects of a shrinking economy.
Scott: Can you just cancel the card?
Scott: Yeah, see the thing is you have to go around to all the automatic places.
Scott: You're automatically paying stuff with the card and switch it up.
Rym: I know and that totally sucks.
Rym: I mean, I'm having enough trouble switching banks.
Scott: I know it's like if you switch banks I've got like five or six places that automatically take money out of my bank account automatically put money in plus.
Scott: I gotta go and refill out all these forms to just to switch a bank if I want bank.
Rym: I was thinking of switching to.
Rym: isn't doing so well now, so I don't know what to do.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know and even the Swiss banks are having trouble now.
Scott: They're getting forced to cough up their info as you can.
Scott: you can't.
Scott: even you're not even safe in a Swiss bank anymore.
Scott: I mean, what what's the world coming to?
Rym: Well, that's where you keep all your legal money, obviously.
Scott: Well, yeah, duh.
Scott: That's what they're for.
Scott: I mean, I guess you know, there's still I mean my bank is you know a savings and loan from Connecticut and it's FDIC insured for you know what that's worth these things.
Rym: My bank was a bank in Michigan a tiny little bank that got bought out By a bigger bank and bought out by a bigger bank and bought out by a bigger bank and bought out by a bigger bank.
Rym: My routing number means nothing to anyone at this point.
Scott: I mean, it's weird.
Scott: It's like I was in Connecticut right and when I was a kid There were basically two banks still two banks that sort of had a lot of branches and you know There were always.
Scott: you know, there would be a Chase Bank like one branch of it.
Scott: You know, there'd be one HSBC branch, right?
Scott: But there was.
Scott: you know There are a whole bunch of people's bank branches and a whole bunch of these like it was like Connecticut something Bank right and the Connecticut something Brank one day got bought by this other bank Shawmut and it was a big deal.
Scott: and Then with like in no time at all Shawmut got bought by something else and got bought by something else.
Scott: And now it's like a Wachovia owns whatever that used to be right?
Scott: It's like the fifth time has been bought out.
Scott: Yep, but people's bank is still there.
Scott: It's still people's bank.
Scott: and Back when you know things are starting to get bad I went to their website because that's where all my money is and they say it was like right on the front page.
Scott: People's Bank largely untouched by you know lack of money in bad mortgages not too bad.
Scott: Oh, it's like they're just carry, you know, it's a savings alone Bank.
Scott: It's perfectly normal and mundane in every way.
Scott: It's it's pretty much only in Connecticut and I think Massachusetts and it's.
Scott: it's just fine.
Rym: the real trouble I had those that I never really wrote checks.
Rym: So I got a book of checks when I opened this account.
Rym: So my book of checks not only says the name of a bank that doesn't exist anymore.
Rym: That is four generations removed from the bank.
Rym: I use now.
Rym: Yeah, but it has my mom's name.
Rym: My checks have my mom's name and they have an address that no one in my family has lived at.
Scott: That's a problem a decade.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I mean I got an account at.
Scott: you know that whatever other bank, right?
Scott: But then when I left to go to college I had it, you know, I'm checking account and like, you know way early.
Scott: but then when I left to go to college, I switched to the People's Bank because The People's Bank had a special college deal that let me get you know.
Scott: All the no ATM fees and all that other business I got going on.
Scott: That's you know, so I switched the account over and I had basically when I was in high school I had these Dilbert checks and then I had like a whole box of checks, right?
Scott: and then I barely used any of them and I switched accounts and then I got the superhero checks and I still have The superhero checks.
Scott: That's how few I use.
Rym: I ran into.
Scott: these checks are literally like I've had them for over a debt for a decade or more.
Rym: My well, I have this box of HSBC checks because I opened an account there when I was at RIT But then I didn't use it because almost right away like my bank got bought out again and then a local bank in Rochester Turned into my bank.
Rym: No, so I just gave up on HSBC.
Rym: I was like pull all my money out and left it.
Scott: So no, maybe maybe you could go to HSBC.
Scott: I mean, they're not, you know, no one's doing well, but they're an okay International Bank.
Rym: We're up relatively solid yeah, but my real trouble is when I got.
Rym: part of the reason I want to shift banks is because my routing number and everything is so old that Getting new checks because I actually use my last personal check the only because I only ever got one.
Scott: when you get a new bank Account usually they give you one book of checks.
Rym: Yes for free But I can't get checks with my current account because the routing numbers and all this stuff Associated with it is so old.
Rym: and it's been I'm sure if you went to the bag I did and they like couldn't figure it Out and they wanted to charge me all this money.
Scott: Well, yeah, that's the thing is when you get checks from some online check printing place They're wicked cheap, but when you buy them at the bank They always charge you an arm and a leg, but you know, what sucked when I got the superhero checks?
Scott: You know why I got the superhero checks.
Scott: Why'd you get the super super cheap, right?
Scott: Yeah, the the actual bank the old they.
Scott: they had a partnership with this company called like deluxe Right that printed checks and they charge like ten times the amount that everyone else charged for printing check.
Rym: Actually what I learned because you know, I reprint stuff for GeekNights Like we got our new business cards and all that stuff we do and I print it.
Rym: I do a lot of printing Mm-hmm, but I've discovered that now a lot of places and many of them didn't do it until recently.
Rym: But you can just make whatever kind of check you want.
Scott: Yeah, you can make whatever you want.
Scott: It's no big deal.
Rym: and But thinking about making some kind of awesome checks, right?
Scott: But this this place that partnered with the bank You know that you know is the official check provider for the bank that you know charged arm and a leg more than anyone else.
Scott: They offered Star Wars checks that no one else offered.
Scott: It was like, ah, I Could get and they were way more awesome than any of the checks you could.
Scott: I mean there's literally.
Scott: I looked around.
Scott: there was nowhere To get Star Wars checks.
Scott: They added the like the exclusive license.
Rym: Maybe we should make the GeekNights checkbook and then you know, you would get GeekNights checks besides us.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I mean if if one of the checks already home today, I mean the thing is right.
Scott: I had one box of checks for a decade and I haven't even used up half of it.
Scott: Yeah that and checks are going.
Scott: the way of the dodo bird Going there's.
Rym: I basically only write checks to interface with people who don't use modern.
Scott: I only write checks and I want to buy dodo birds.
Scott: They're kind of hard to come by yeah But Odio, alright, so we did book club last Thursday, right?
Scott: But One thing that people mentioned that is was absolutely right is that we didn't do Well, not not only did we not do a good job of selling the next book We didn't do any job of selling the next book.
Scott: I pretty much said the next book is gonna be this the end?
Rym: Well, I guess I assumed that people knew who Ernest Hemingway was and that I wouldn't need to sell Ernest Hemingway to people.
Scott: Well, no, we're talking about the book that I was selling after we were done with the Ernest Hemingway.
Rym: Oh, yeah, well considering how few people listen to the Hemingway episode.
Rym: It's true I think many people even know what book we're doing next.
Scott: Yeah, it's also true.
Scott: But anyway, so I think I don't know.
Scott: maybe you know Mix up the book club a little bit more.
Scott: Like should we do the selling of the next book and the reviewing of the previous book?
Scott: Like, you know, some people suggested we do the half-and-half.
Scott: I think that's not a bad idea.
Scott: Yeah And actually maybe if we do the selling of the next book in the first half That might actually work better for people who didn't read, you know, if they listen to the episode right away They get them.
Scott: they get the selling because that's what they need.
Scott: if you haven't read the book You know you you want the selling right away rather than you know the review of the book.
Rym: You didn't read right away, but I think for now we're just gonna kind of play it by ear and just kind of.
Rym: we're just gonna do the book club stuff as it comes up and as it makes sense because Overthinking it is just gonna cause trouble exactly.
Scott: So Anyway, I want to spend you know a few minutes here to sell you on the next book.
Scott: Right, because if you haven't read this book the Sun, you know you you.
Scott: this is sort of one of those books.
Scott: It's a little bit more the of the then some of the other books we've done in the book club.
Scott: In fact, this is probably like my new favorite book since I read it.
Scott: But anyway, that's a heady claim.
Scott: The book is the amazing adventures of cavalier and clay Written by Michael Chabon.
Scott: it won the Pulitzer Prize.
Scott: You cannot win a better prize than that for writing things.
Scott: It's not possible.
Rym: What if you win the Nobel Peace Prize because you wrote a book that fostered?
Scott: It's not a book for we discussed this already.
Scott: That's not a book for writing.
Scott: You could win the Nobel Prize for literature.
Scott: You could win the Nobel Prize for literature But that is not as good as the Pulitzer Prize.
Scott: It is one step below and in the book of Scott Alright, so when a book wins the Pulitzer Prize, that's serious business.
Scott: I mean we've done some books that are like, you know, pretty great I mean Scott Hemingway and such not Pulitzer Prize winner.
Rym: What won the last Pulitzer Prize?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Can you name any other books that won Pulitzer Prizes?
Scott: I could I. Actually, I saw someone who had the newest Pulitzer Prize winning thing on the train the other day and I forgot what it was But I meant to go and add it to my Amazon.
Rym: whatever.
Rym: I can point out that this book.
Rym: I have not read it.
Rym: I'm the only person in the world who hasn't read it.
Scott: I don't know I don't.
Scott: I don't know how much of the crew has read it.
Scott: I think I don't know if Alex I mean, I know me and Emily have read it.
Scott: I don't know anyone else though.
Rym: now the thing is because Emily knows that we're doing this as the next book.
Rym: She's reading it again and I get to read it again.
Rym: Yeah, but you know this crew I've only read it once.
Rym: this crew is not a crew that will often Reconsume media unless that media is of the highest quality.
Scott: Yeah, so let me let me just tell you what this book is about a little bit, right?
Scott: So it's a novel it's a. it's a fictional story of These two cousins, right?
Scott: Cavalier and Clay I forget what their.
Scott: I think it was a Joe Cavalier and what's Forget the first name of the other guy, but it doesn't really matter so much.
Scott: Anyway, you know, they're like Jewish cousins and one guy is you know a Jew living in I think Brooklyn right and the other guy Cavalier.
Scott: so clay lives in Brooklyn right and Cavalier was in Europe during you know The Holocaust and such and his family sent him away to go live with the cousins in America, right?
Scott: So you have that sort of Holocaust story, right?
Scott: You've also got this, you know sort of Retelling mishmash of the history of comic books in America right as he basically tells all these stories that are obviously just Riffs on the true stories of Eisner and Eiger and Simon and Schuster and all these famous American comic artists, right?
Scott: He retells their stories with Cavalier and clay as you know, the artist and writer of the comics, right?
Scott: You've also got adventure stories going on, right?
Scott: You've also got escapist like, you know, Houdini kind of action going on.
Scott: You've also got The golem, you know going on the whole story of the golem of Prague.
Scott: I like golems great and that ties in with the Houdini parts, right?
Scott: You've also Got, you know sort of like, you know, this love story and dealing, you know with like, you know art and a lot.
Scott: It there's a lot of New York in this book.
Scott: a whole bunch of New York.
Scott: Empire State Building plays a huge part in this book And they turned the Empire State Building into a golem.
Scott: No, okay, not it's not ridiculous.
Scott: It's it's there's nothing in here.
Scott: That is Magical or unbelievable.
Scott: you got war story in here.
Scott: There's a whole, you know war action going on.
Scott: That's part of the adventure, you know, and you've also got You know lots of you know, it's it's just all these things right that seem like they would be separate books.
Scott: yet somehow They're all in this one story with these, you know, two characters sort of at the center of.
Scott: you know the vast majority of it and It's really pretty thrilling and pretty much It doesn't hurt that all of those things like right down the alley of Scott Rubin.
Scott: It's like comic books Jews You know Houdini Adventure, you know all the all in one in one book and it's you know It's one of the best books I've ever read and I could.
Scott: I could probably read it like ten more times.
Scott: I mean, it's like it's Watchmen.
Scott: good.
Scott: That's how good this book is.
Scott: So If you're gonna read one book club, I'm not.
Scott: I promise I won't say this ever again.
Scott: If you catch me saying this about any other book club book ever again Call me out.
Scott: Right, if you read if you're ever gonna do the book club even once and you're if you're only gonna do the book club once This should be the one time that you do it for this book and it's not an expensive book Let's see.
Scott: The cover price is $15 for the softcover.
Scott: So on Amazon, it's probably less than that.
Scott: It's got to be less than that.
Scott: It's got to be like eight or something like that.
Scott: I'm just guessing I don't have a computer in front of me.
Scott: So the amazing adventures of cavalier and clay.
Scott: cavalier is spelt with a K clay is spelt with the C Willing to it.
Scott: Yeah by Michael Chavon.
Scott: read this book.
Scott: Oh Thing is this is not you know, the book is six hundred and thirty.
Scott: No, it's not six.
Scott: Is it?
Scott: how many pay?
Scott: Yeah, I think it's six hundred and thirty nine pages.
Scott: This isn't?
Scott: this isn't like a sissy book Away, I think it's so.
Rym: things of the day booty Booty my poots my butt Pooted cat jazz Cat jazz nutters.
Rym: I like nutters a lot.
Rym: All right, there's something about nutters.
Scott: What's cat jazz?
Rym: How about fup?
Scott: What's fup?
Scott: I'm juicy Are you maybe?
Rym: Oh Titli ist is in here.
Scott: what?
Rym: or titleist?
Rym: but it looks like they interpreted as titli.
Scott: is Oh titleist Like the golf ball?
Scott: or titli is as in the most hits Bungle hater.
Rym: Oh geeked up Okay, so I found this list of all the license plates that were rejected by the state of Ohio.
Scott: See, I mean New York, right?
Scott: I got fear and Rym got Oh Tory and they didn't reject right?
Scott: They were cool.
Scott: They were told.
Scott: and I see you know what.
Scott: I drive around New York and I see license plates And I see a lot of cool ones out there.
Scott: So I know that someone whoever is approving and disapproving the vanity plates in New York I mean, they're obviously not gonna let like fuck you through but they're letting cool stuff through and they gotta let the ass man through.
Scott: I know right ass man.
Scott: I'm pretty sure that's real ass, man Right.
Scott: So Ohio must just be fucking sticklers.
Rym: No fact Penina, okay.
Rym: All right con man con man one con man to con man three.
Scott: I think someone was trying to get Right, but it's like, you know, I could understand, you know I mean first of all, right if I was in charge pretty much anything would be approved except for like 001 I 1 I 0.
Rym: That was always my plan though because the cops wouldn't know what to do and I couldn't get my ticket.
Scott: Yeah the cops would have to look real close to get your correct license plate and if they they typed it in wrong they get.
Scott: so that is obviously a license plate.
Scott: that's not okay, but It's some.
Scott: you know, I would be fine with fuck you but okay even if poop on you po up Oh and you yeah things even if you wanted to weed out profane license plates, okay Even by a pretty strict judgment.
Scott: What's wrong with geeked up?
Scott: I mean, how is that profane in any way?
Rym: Well biting the heads off chickens.
Rym: It's it's horrible.
Scott: I know right I mean what?
Scott: what are the?
Scott: there's a whole bunch of them on there?
Scott: Like.
Scott: I can understand rejecting some of these, you know Like maybe you maybe even the poop and the ass ones and the bitch wall Even though I feel like they should allow.
Rym: they should allow.
Scott: I think they don't.
Scott: you know I would like them to allow it but I can understand at least if they don't allow like dumb bitch, right?
Rym: Well, I can understand that Rinzel, I can't think of anything bad exactly.
Scott: What's wrong with Rinzel?
Rym: Someone tried to get you think?
Scott: See, I guess they knew what you think was.
Scott: Maybe they just go to Urban Dictionary Maybe they search for every single thing on Google and find and that's why some of the ones are rejected because maybe just bad Search results come up.
Rym: Related I hate Ohio.
Scott: Oh, yeah, they got anything.
Scott: This is sucks.
Scott: They don't allow which it's pretty consistent.
Rym: Yeah, but fuck I can't figure out what wife up.
Scott: I guess it's just you know, fuck you people.
Rym: I don't know I don't know but fuck it's kind of too classy.
Rym: I like fuck.
Scott: Yeah, what's I can fuck?
Scott: I don't see anything wrong with that.
Scott: But I don't know.
Scott: a lot of these seem like they were rejected even though they weren't profane and I think there might be room.
Scott: I'm not a lawyer, but here's what.
Rym: here's what bothers me.
Rym: one Profane is very different from obscene.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: And Here are the guidelines that Ohio uses from the article.
Rym: All right, they will block any license plate.
Rym: that quote advocates lawlessness.
Rym: Okay quote could reasonably be expected to provoke a violent response without additional comments Mm-hmm.
Rym: So apparently geeked up either promotes lawlessness or will provoke a violent response.
Scott: Oh those the only two.
Rym: or our quote profane obscene sexually explicit or Scatological.
Scott: No, that's explains the poop ones Logical but P is okay Apparently unless it's obscene or profane.
Rym: now here's what bothers me.
Rym: obscene means one thing but profane There shouldn't.
Rym: you shouldn't be able to restrict profanity because profanity has religious connotations.
Rym: You shouldn't I don't.
Rym: I think that someone in Ohio could sue on the grounds that the state cannot restrict profane license plates.
Rym: They can restrict obscene ones and all these other things, but I don't think I think you'd have a good case against profane.
Scott: it is a question for Thades.
Rym: friend ray the First Amendment lawyer from Ohio Of course I also feel like could reasonably be expected to provoke a violent response doesn't fit with pretty much any of these unless yeah It's like.
Scott: what license plate could you make that would elicit?
Rym: or what kind of people are living in, Ohio?
Scott: Examine like me, you know what I you know, it could evoke a violent response.
Scott: Fuck the cops.
Scott: that would have listed a violent response from the cops, right or like kill police or kill cops.
Scott: That would.
Scott: that would be you know, not work out, but I mean geeked up.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Okay kill yourself I don't know.
Rym: I can find that kind of funny and naked Dave and beetle bomb.
Scott: Yeah, what's wrong with those?
Scott: I don't know ultra pimp.
Scott: I think even by those rules a lot of a lot of these license plates are not obscene profane They don't have vocal violent response.
Scott: They're not scat illogical.
Scott: You know some of them are but a lot of them aren't and it's sort of fucked up.
Rym: But I feel like scat illogical should be a requirement.
Scott: Yeah just Ohio the poop state I Mean we already know that it is.
Scott: we might as well, you know, just say okay proud.
Rym: Okay eat poo.
Scott: It is scat illogical though, so it is against law, but it's kind of funny.
Rym: I don't know if I saw if I was driving and I saw a license plate that said eat poo.
Rym: I Would not be driven to this mad enraged act of violence.
Scott: I would drive next to the person to give him a high-five.
Rym: Oh Well, I've had vanity place my whole life.
Rym: I will have vanity place for the rest of my life because the the minor cost involved is worth it for the fact that a Lot of people see that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, so a long time ago on the show I did a thing of the day about a patent that is owned by?
Scott: well I don't know if you own a patent but a patent that was issued to mr Penn Gillette of Penn & Teller and his patent was for the Jill jet, which is a a device that you have in a hot tub that shoots a jet of water for pleasuring women and You know, he uses it quite often.
Scott: I can I can tell you that But I discovered more recently another patent owned by a mr.
Scott: Michael Jackson.
Scott: Yes, the white scary guy of thrillers isn't like Michael Jackson like a micro and his micro of software.
Scott: No This is actually a patent that was issued to a US patent issued to be Michael Jackson who by the way is a Selling a bunch of his stuff on auction including.
Scott: He has really good taste in arcade games.
Scott: So If you want some of his really good and pristine arcade machines, they are up for auction.
Scott: Some of them are really really hot too.
Scott: Secondly he's I just read in the news today that like he's going to do live concerts and that's sort of fucked up.
Scott: How's he?
Scott: can he still do a live concert?
Rym: I saw some article though.
Rym: He went to the doctor to find out if he can still do concerts.
Scott: really Yeah, he said he's gonna do ten shows.
Rym: So it's like, huh, you know If he he'll probably do one in New York, I would consider I think he was doing it.
Rym: I just it was like an England didn't say about the u.s Cuz I I would probably go see him just so I could say in my life that I saw Michael Jackson.
Scott: Well, I mean, that's the thing right even if he's a scary dude Even if he's like yeah It's like there's like one of the greatest albums ever made.
Scott: if he can still perform the music in the same way It's like it's I was.
Scott: go see a Mike Tyson fight, you know cherries a piece of shit.
Scott: But you go on YouTube and watch him beat the shit out of someone.
Scott: It's so fucking amazing.
Rym: I don't make a license plate about it.
Scott: Oh, yeah, that's right.
Scott: Um, but anyway, so this is a patent owned by Michael Jackson.
Scott: what the patent is for If you know, Michael Jackson is is sort of like oh That's all right.
Scott: So do you remember?
Scott: When Michael Jackson would dance and he would lean over and he would lean so far over yet Somehow he would not fall down even though he was leaning Impossibly far and possibly beyond the point where his center of gravity would tip now.
Rym: I just always assumed he was awesome.
Rym: I would try to do that.
Scott: as a kid I thought that he just really strong leg muscles or that there was.
Scott: you know I never even thought about like, you know what the trick was or what but he always did that dance where he leaned really far.
Scott: So this patent is for the thing that lets him lean really far and I'll let you Look at the patent yourself and go oh and feel stupid like the rest of us.
Rym: Yeah, so where my lasers at?
Scott: So we we took us a while to come up with what to do the show on but we finally settled.
Scott: we're gonna talk about laser crabs laser crab paint balls and airsofts.
Rym: all the sort of real-world FPS is Cuz I'll admit, you know when I was a kid we're thinking about it.
Rym: I was a kid.
Rym: you're all kids.
Rym: at some point a lot of you still are kids and You had guns like fake guns water guns super soakers.
Rym: The lowest level is.
Rym: the lowest level is like the P the object that is shaped like a gun.
Rym: That does not work in any way.
Rym: Like.
Scott: I used it as a trigger and it goes click.
Rym: No.
Rym: No, that's the step up I'm talking about like.
Rym: I took some waffle blocks and made a gun Oh carried it around.
Scott: then you just took some Legos and you made a right angle where one side was longer than the other side Or like I'm.
Rym: when I was a kid I remember I knew a lot of friends whose parents like wouldn't let their kids play with guns.
Scott: Those kids As a tangent I want to say right I found it so strange that Kids who were like, you know, hick, you know Hicks or maybe you know actually had real guns.
Scott: You know like you would go to summer camp right and they have Riflery and people would actually fire real guns in the rifle range and you would have like eight-year-old kids on the rifle range of 22s and They were very you know, I mean these weren't mature kids They were eight years old but on the rifle range they handled themselves very maturely.
Scott: They would never point the gun at anyone else.
Scott: They would never do anything stupid.
Scott: You know everyone was there and taking things very seriously and and such and such.
Scott: and you know No one had sort of like this unsafe fascination with guns or anything like that.
Scott: but when you're you know, when you I would go to like a kid's house, right or A kid would come over and it was some kid who wasn't allowed to have any toy guns by his parents.
Scott: Those kids who weren't allowed any, you know exposure to guns at all.
Scott: We're just sort of Dangerously fascinated with toy guns.
Scott: and if you took them like I would go to a birthday party and you like at someone's house you had a toy gun or two and you could tell that like Some of the kids at the party would just be like so fascinated with the toy guns They would just play with them and ignore everything else and the rest of us would be like what the fuck's wrong with you guys.
Scott: Why are you playing with the toy guns?
Scott: We got like freaking, you know, gigantic transformer here who makes noise And lights up and is like, you know two feet long.
Scott: What are you guys doing?
Scott: You know, and they were just you know in credit and I Think that you know We.
Scott: a better way or something that we could do to have better gun safety is to have you know Proper, you know 22 rifle marksmanship as you know in school.
Rym: Of course the the beg to question if you want.
Rym: we're not gonna debate gun ownership right now.
Rym: Is that?
Rym: Why do we live in a society where we have to make sure everyone is super cool with guns?
Scott: Exactly, but that's that's neither here.
Rym: But
Scott: anyway, the point is is that I think it's related to laser tag, you know paintball airsoft because These are sort of ways in which you can sort of you know Learn about guns and weapons and sort of aiming and using them and and such in a very safe and risk-free Environment.
Scott: and also, you know, they're it's sort of weird.
Scott: It's like you can play an FPS but an FPS is not.
Scott: this is like, you know a totally other level We're talking about here, you know, even laser tag is like a way way more than an FPS is Yep, and I just I love it and I want to do more of it.
Rym: cuz I remember when I was a kid.
Rym: You know first it was just we had to play with like whatever we had.
Rym: But then the nerf revolution happened and so therefore for Kevin suddenly you could prove there's no more.
Rym: I shot you.
Rym: No, you didn't it was hit you in the face.
Rym: I gotcha you're done.
Scott: Then you put thumb tacks on the end of him and you know, and you hit somebody.
Rym: No, I went.
Rym: I really I went on a different tack.
Rym: I modified my nerf guns.
Rym: I remember one time Greg an old FRC person we haven't talked to in a while.
Rym: They kind of went off on their own way, but we Even.
Rym: he came out with me to Michigan to go to Cedar Point and we were hanging out in my parents house.
Scott: It was like after freshman year of uni and you had your modified bow and arrow is there.
Rym: I had my modified nerf gun That I'd modified when I was a kid.
Rym: So we walked down and in the basement and I turn around he's coming down the stairs and I say check out my nerf gun.
Rym: And he goes, yeah, what of it?
Rym: and I shot it at him and he goes holy shit followed by fuck.
Rym: It was most excellent.
Scott: that's good stuff.
Rym: that thing hurt you.
Scott: just what had you do?
Scott: rubber bands now?
Rym: Well, all I did.
Rym: I took the that six shot that shot regular nerf arrows.
Rym: Yeah from a six shooter.
Rym: Yeah, I put a Arrow storm.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Yes, I put a Gigantic spring in it and instead of shooting the big arrows I shot the little orange suction darts from the nerf like Razorback.
Scott: So you put the arrows inside the holes instead of around.
Rym: yep shit be crazy.
Scott: Yeah, that then there's no friction of its sliding off the plastic shaft or any.
Scott: yeah
Rym: But I mean that still it wasn't really fun enough because while you can play the awesome nerf bow and arrow and everything Well, I need to go pick up all those arrows afterward and the neighbor kid would always like lose all your arrows and
Scott: tell me About it.
Rym: You could always dodge those things.
Scott: Oh even for you know, if you were anywhere with any sort of range and you saw it coming it wasn't gonna hit you.
Rym: I mean, they're not like night arrows, right?
Scott: So, you know really it's like you want to have.
Scott: you know, sort of the thrill and fun of having some sort of you know gun combat simulation, but you don't actually want anyone to get hurt right and You know, you just you just sort of want to and but you actually want to use you know Your physical abilities as opposed to say just your hands with an FPS.
Scott: you actually want to walk around Actually duck actually crawl actually climb things.
Rym: I still actually hide I feel like competition and fighting and things are still.
Rym: you know humans are animals and I think There are a lot of things in humanity that harken back to our older days our more primitive days And I feel like there is this drive to fight and nothing is better than taking that drive and making an awesome game about it.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you're what are they?
Scott: What else can you really do in terms of like, you know, satisfying this urge to fight But also doing it, you know for real soccer Lee right soccer that that work for Europe.
Scott: Yeah, doing it physically and not simulating it right but also not getting hurt I mean even if you do martial arts or boxing or something along those lines I mean, you're not gonna get killed but you're it.
Scott: you hurt sometimes, you know You get whacked with a stick or you get punched in the face and you go shit, you know.
Scott: Plus there's something about boxing, you know, I mean you're gonna get brain damage.
Rym: It's it's gonna have the same reason why like boffin weapons are so much fun but I think there's it's different with gun because it's a lot more tactical and strategic and Reflexes and a lot less of all the other factors.
Scott: Yeah, definitely.
Scott: Well, I mean, you know, you could do like, you know act like some of the real quote real sword fighting stuff.
Scott: You can sort of get that.
Rym: Yeah, I've done fencing and I was hurt once by katsu doing kendo.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean the thing with sword fighting is I think it's more, you know, like Maneuvers and things like that.
Scott: You're very close with the other person but with guns, you know, you're sort of you're.
Scott: it's more about the environment.
Scott: Right, you know you're jumping on things running away from things, you know dodging.
Scott: It's more of an extended thing as opposed to a quick reflexes thing like aha.
Scott: Okay, it's over.
Scott: You know guns is more like it's an extended engagement.
Scott: I think that's the best way of putting it.
Scott: But anyway, you know, I've done paintball a few times.
Scott: How many times you done paintball paintball?
Rym: I don't like three or four times.
Rym: I think max not that many.
Rym: Yeah, two of those times were at RIT and two were in high school.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I only did it once at RIT.
Scott: I think I did it two or three times before then.
Rym: I think we did it didn't we go with like?
Scott: yeah, we went.
Scott: No in freshman year.
Scott: We went with your floor.
Scott: Yeah, we went laser tag with hello.
Rym: Yes, we did.
Scott: Yeah when we went to laser tag, I complete it's like Scott dominated everyone like to a degree that was frightening.
Scott: I say we went into this laser tag and it was a pretty good laser tag, basically You know, they had all these guns.
Rym: Well, it was laser quest.
Rym: That's like the standard generic.
Scott: Yeah for all laser Yeah, all the guns work right.
Scott: you can shoot someone in the front or the back or the gun.
Scott: I think You can shoot as many times as you want right and every time you hit someone They're sort of they can't fight, you know They're sort of dead for a few seconds like what like five to ten seconds something like that And then when they come back to life then they can shoot again.
Scott: So it's basically when you shoot someone their gun gets turned off for a short time and then they're back in the game.
Scott: So you want to get hit as little times as possible because that also enables you to hit others as many times as possible.
Scott: And the rules I think were no running All right.
Scott: I think that was it, you know, no running and no hitting people.
Rym: and see now that's that's why I mean I love laser tag, but the way.
Rym: well one laser tag is dead.
Rym: Laser tag is like the deadest freaking.
Scott: well outdoor laser tag still has something because they know but it's not where it doesn't.
Rym: there are Two.
Scott: there are a couple places.
Scott: They're like two places to do it.
Rym: It's got the nearest laser tag place to us is like 40 miles away.
Scott: Oh, yeah, there's so few of them but you know, they're about as common as you know.
Scott: Go-kart tracks, you know, there are a lot more go-karts.
Scott: You think so?
Scott: Yeah, I'm talking about real go-karts though Not the fake ones.
Rym: plus remember laser tag like has had this long decline and a lot of the companies that make the equipment have Gone out of business.
Scott: It's true.
Rym: It's true and there's not that much demand for it.
Scott: I mean paintball and airsoft pushed him out.
Rym: Well, the real problem was that all the ways to play laser tag that were fun for people like us We're not fun for the primary demographic which was nine-year-old birthday parties.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: so laser take like laser quest was always super lame like laser quest was the weakest laser tag for me because it's always like Every man for himself free-for-all and there's actually every man for himself free-for-all is better than some of the other ones I've done.
Scott: I did a laser tag once that basically was like there's two bases on each side quote bases and you had to basically Get across the map without dying Right and if you know well map right room without dying and if you did die you had to go all the way back to your side to this one spot.
Scott: that would bring you back to life right.
Scott: and Once you got to the other side You got into one of these two corners and in the corners these tiny bases and you would sit in the tiny base shooting the little like target a tiny target constantly as much as you could to rack up as many points as you could for your Team until someone eventually came into your little, you know enemy base and shot you and he had to run all the way back here.
Scott: So it was pretty much a whole lot of running back and forth and not a whole lot of shooting.
Rym: people see But I like it.
Rym: like cues are I like the fact that you had lives and the fact that the game cues?
Scott: I was more like an actual multiplayer.
Rym: Yes yes, but that's what I'm talking about.
Rym: the good the really good laser tag was few and far between because usually it was laser tag where It's a bunch of people kind of playing half-assed Lee.
Rym: You're not allowed to run You're not allowed to climb.
Rym: There's like people everywhere making sure you don't break the rules and you've got the six-year-old kid like holding his hand over his sensor Just like walking behind you shooting you in the back.
Scott: Yeah, well, I mean, you know, that's the thing is whenever you.
Scott: I think that's part of the problem.
Scott: Is that that the?
Scott: I don't want a tangent here, right because we're go.
Scott: but the part of the reason why the arcade failed in the US is because The people who would really keep an arcade going are serious gamers.
Scott: but most of the people who went to the arcade were non serious gamers, you know, like just kids having a birthday party or whatever and They did not mix.
Scott: well it's like the serious gamer isn't gonna play laser tag when it's full of kids who aren't taking it seriously and are just Ruining it and sort of making it stupid
Rym: plus the fact that they dumb the game down to accommodate the fact that you know every 20 Minutes, they run a 15-minute game.
Rym: Yeah, so it's always like the 15-minute.
Rym: You can never die free-for-all as opposed to like the awesome cues are.
Rym: All right, let's go.
Rym: two teams You know green and orange Bases six lives.
Rym: if you run out of lives, you're fucking done.
Scott: Go home.
Scott: Yeah, I mean when you can when you do that, right you're gonna get you know The birthday party crowd.
Scott: but the birthday party crowd is gonna get bored of that eventually, you know They'll do laser tag for one birthday and that's it.
Scott: They're never gonna do it again Not even that they won't even want to keep.
Scott: you want to make a lot of money.
Scott: You need to make it serious so that you have acts like a league and you have people coming constantly.
Scott: This is the bowling alleys, right bowling alleys are the only people that have sort of figured out this Physical space entertainment thing.
Scott: right you have the sit, you know the boat.
Scott: Yeah, the birthday party situation covered but you also have the league situation.
Scott: serious people covered.
Scott: You've got to cover both and laser tag covered.
Rym: neither There are laser tag places that do and those are the ones that have like these awesome thriving communities.
Rym: They're just aren't any anywhere near us or we would totally be a part of that.
Scott: I mean there are definitely some but they are very few and far between.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: They're not near us, right?
Scott: Yeah, so that's that's the deal with.
Scott: laser tag got ruined by the birthday party crowd.
Scott: Yeah, ball paintball never got really ruined by the birthday party crowd because it's sort of a thing that you wouldn't do unless you were Serious, you know, you're sort of afraid it's gonna hurt.
Scott: or you know, it's not something kids do It's something that people who are sorta at least semi serious go and do you know?
Scott: I guess there might be some sort of corporate paintball outings going on, you know stuff like that.
Scott: But you know people don't generally do paintball unless they actually want to do sort of a gun Combat kind of thing.
Rym: but even then I mean every time I've done paintball like it's really fun.
Rym: But I don't like the rules of paintball as most people play it.
Rym: Yeah, most of the games of paintball I've seen or played they play like the very like all the very specific kinds of games that are in no way Reminiscent of combat or a simulation of combat or any.
Rym: they're just basically this completely separate Specific game that happens to use paintball equipment.
Scott: Mm-hmm Yeah, it's like they'll do say capture the flag, but you shoot people to get them out or speedball and all that.
Scott: Yeah, you know, they'll come up with some sort of rules or you know something along and then they're just using paintball gun.
Rym: I remember specifically when I played paintball at RIT and I tried to use some tactics.
Rym: I go to that guy next to me.
Rym: I'm like, alright you rush forward to that fortification.
Rym: I will cover you.
Rym: So he's like I'm like ready and I stick my gun over the barrier without looking and start just peppering the field.
Rym: You know, that's what military cover fire is in some cases.
Scott: Your balls are just landing in the grass not doing anything.
Rym: Well, no I because it forces feet basically cover fire Forces the whatever is trying to shoot you to back down long enough for the person you were covering to get to the next place to hide Mm-hmm.
Rym: and immediately the giraffe blows the whistle and stops the game and comes over and sights me for the fact that you're not allowed To shoot around a barrier without seeing around the barrier while you're shooting because you might hurt someone.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, that's that's the problem.
Rym: And then what that that would like?
Rym: that was the beginning of it and the more I played like there were so many fiddly rules That it wasn't that fun.
Scott: Yeah I mean the other thing is that you know If you're not serious about paintball if you just go to a paintball place and just you know Start playing rent some equipment go with all your friends or whatever.
Scott: They don't crank the guns up all the way.
Scott: You know, they're they're pretty.
Scott: they power them down, you know And that sort of makes it so.
Scott: they won't hurt people or get your eye out or any, you know.
Scott: But and they won't you know leave big welts on you or anything.
Scott: But the fact is then you power it down the balls don't go very far and they're very inaccurate So you can't really aim very well over any sort of distance.
Scott: So It's sort of like it's like what the fuck, you know I only have a limited number of balls here and I basically just wasted them all shooting at you even all the way over there Where it was impossible for me to hit you.
Rym: but it just seems like if there's a lot of spray and pray going on and the good guns just fire a lot faster and A lot better and I don't know.
Rym: paintballs cool.
Rym: Don't get us wrong.
Rym: I'm not like Disparaging your sport.
Rym: I know we have paintball people who are like about to kill us.
Rym: Yeah, but I don't know.
Rym: I feel like more and more.
Rym: what I want is just counter-strike in the real world.
Scott: Well, I mean that's really what the thing is right.
Scott: It's like FPS is you know have real guns and things right?
Scott: Well simulations of real guns and Thus, they actually do a pretty good job of simulating, you know, the sort of combat situations that you you know What a what they're like fantasies that you want to fulfill right and that that satisfies, you know The the urge to have a combat situation, you know without actual risk, right?
Scott: Cuz no one actually wants real combat.
Scott: That's terrible.
Scott: So If you want that sort of scenario Without the risk but by doing it with paintball you're sort of you're failing to fulfill the scenario.
Rym: plus I've seen some paintball places that do objective based stuff like that But it there aren't that many of them as far as I can tell.
Rym: Yeah, if you people know about more let me know but my ideal I feel like more and more.
Rym: I've just got to get into airsoft because I feel like that's the only place where I can get exactly what I want.
Scott: Yeah, so basically it people don't know right cuz not it's surprising how many people don't know airsoft.
Scott: Airsoft is basically It's sort of like paintball and that you have guns and you shoot each other right and you you know Generate some sort of sport around that that idea.
Scott: And of course, it's not real weapons.
Scott: They won't kill you or anything and you know, there's no bull It's not even it's less than BBs, right?
Scott: But basically what it is is plastic BBs.
Scott: They're about the size of a BB But they're made of plastic and they shoot pretty fast Like you could shoot through like a cardboard box of these things, but you can't shoot through someone's skin with them, right?
Scott: If I shot you and it hit your skin, you would just go out fuck.
Rym: Well, it depends.
Rym: I mean you can.
Rym: you can make an airsoft gun that will will hurt people about as much as Almost as much as a 22.
Scott: you you could crank up the power.
Scott: Well, no a 22 can kill someone.
Rym: This is not gonna make an airsoft gun that would kill some if you hit someone in the unprotected Eyeball or if you if you shot straight up the nose Going like 800 FPS or something, I guess.
Scott: but no it really.
Scott: but you know, they're not gonna hurt.
Scott: You know, they will hurt but they it's very very difficult.
Scott: If you are following basic and very simple you basically have to go out of your way to permanently injure someone You know in normal play with even, you know, read any sort of basic safety.
Scott: No one's gonna get actually hurt they'll just they might feel pain when they get hit but they won't get hurt right.
Scott: and The things you know, they're little plastic BBs.
Scott: they shoot straight sort of like the way real, you know, almost like the way real bullets shoot.
Scott: and all the guns or most of the guns are actually modeled after real-world guns.
Scott: so you can go and get like an airsoft mp5 and Except for the orange tip on the front, you know, which identifies it as not a real weapon It looks like an mp5 and fires about the same rate as an mp5.
Scott: and they have the same thing.
Scott: You can get an ak-47 or an m4, you know deagle or you know, whatever you want and you know.
Scott: Thus it is, you know, very good at fulfilling the simulation of combat cuz like you could go in with like You know a pistol at the hip and a shotgun on the back and a rifle in the hands and the ammo is small You know, it's like paintball.
Scott: or you get this big bucket of balls that you know can you know get jammed all the time?
Scott: And so, you know, it's just little plastic pellets.
Scott: You can just you know have a whole bunch of them.
Scott: It's no problem.
Rym: It just generally looks like a lot of fun and we always that we haven't done it But we always have this idea of buying a bunch of cheap airsoft gun.
Scott: I mean, it's really not as expensive as you would think.
Rym: like what we can we're thinking We'll just buy like the cheapest crap like a bunch of pistols all around low velocity.
Rym: So we don't have to get like armor or anything and just get basic safety equipment.
Scott: Yeah, you need you basically need a face mask, you know.
Scott: So you don't get your eyes or your face or anything, right?
Scott: And you just need to have some amount of clothing covering your body Maybe some gloves.
Scott: that way, you know, if you get hit in the leg instead of hitting your bare leg It hits some jeans and then you know, you're alright.
Rym: Yeah, but I figure we can just get these.
Rym: There's a million like abandoned factories around.
Scott: Well, you really want to go to an actual airsoft place because I find any really near us.
Rym: There's that one lame paintball place near us.
Scott: Yeah Well, I mean the thing is, you know, you don't have to go there all the time But you want to go there at least once because you'll learn a lot about.
Scott: if you don't know about the airsoft or the paintball Or whatever you will learn a lot of the things you need to know from the people there who basically do it for a living.
Scott: And once you learn it Then you can sort of go and find Abandoned factory, whatever and do it with your friends as long as there's no one there, you know
Rym: I can just imagine the police like coming into this warehouse and finding like 18 members of the front row crew having a shootout.
Scott: Yeah with like mp5s and m4s and AKs We would be spending at least a night in jail.
Rym: That might be worth it.
Scott: Maybe you know, the thing is if you find it truly out of the way abandoned place They're never gonna.
Scott: you know, one's gonna know it's not a problem, you know, your worst worry is like some, you know Stranger will come along and be like what the fuck.
Scott: or maybe they'll you know, they'll get hit and you'll be like, oh shit.
Scott: Oh, yeah, that's something to worry about.
Rym: Well, then you just got to make sure there are no witnesses.
Scott: Yeah, well, it's hard to get rid of witnesses and all you've got is guns the shoot plastic.
Scott: You pew-pew-pew-pew-pew-pew.
Rym: Ah, stop it.
Scott: You'll never tell the coppers pew-pew It hurts my ass He's broke the butt, all right, I
Rym: don't know I'm I'm feeling this more and more But maybe it's partly because right now I'm really stir-crazy because it's near the end of winter and
Scott: I want
Rym: to get outside and move Around again.
Scott: I'll tell you what, let's this is summer.
Scott: Let's do it.
Rym: No matter what let's do it We'll find a place and all right The front row crew is getting into airsoft that it is hereby declared.
Rym: there can be no shit talking.
Rym: All right, all right we committed.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is right that the one thing about airsoft right is.
Scott: I know I don't know enough about it But I do know that they have electric guns that you know going battery power.
Scott: Everyone says you want like the gas blowback gun yeah, and they also have ones that you know have like gas cartridges and it's like Which way should you go?
Scott: Really?
Rym: It's like everyone's told me just go with gas blowback.
Scott: Yeah, but I've also heard that like, you know, the gas is better, but I've also heard you know, the electric freaking works.
Scott: It's not you know, it's not like total crap.
Scott: Well you so and it's way cheap.
Scott: So if you're just you know, testing it out having a good, you know, get the electric you'll save a ton of money.
Rym: Well to start I imagine we're gonna buy like the cheapest craft.
Scott: I think we should rent then buy.
Scott: then, you know, it's like we should step it up.
Scott: You know go to the place and rent.
Scott: go to the place with our bought stuff.
Scott: then You know keep using the shitty bought stuff until where we know better.
Scott: then buy good stuff.
Scott: Then keep using the good stuff and then you know, see if we get serious and such, you know Yeah, I'm standard progression.
Rym: I'm feeling this.
Rym: I think we could have some fun in an abandoned factory with some pistols.
Scott: Yeah Sure.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.