Rym: Hey, it's Tuesday July 7th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We talk a bit about cheating and all of its stripes and flavors.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So I have actually believe it or not been playing some video games lately.
Rym: wait wait wait a new Video game because you could say that and just be playing punch-out the old punch-out as was often the case.
Scott: No, no, I'm playing well depending on your point of view.
Scott: well one of them.
Scott: well first of all I've played this.
Scott: There's a game called trine TR I any and the demo is on steam and also the full versions on steam for $30 And I think it might be on ps3.
Scott: I don't know, but it is a side scrolling Puzzly platforming game.
Scott: basically you have a wizard a knight and a thief and they each do different things And you have to you know get to the end of the level.
Rym: well we were trying To play it over the weekend.
Scott: actually I did play it and the thing about this game is it's co-op.
Scott: You can play one two or three players on the same machine.
Scott: Well this makes for a really really interesting time really fun.
Rym: The problem was we had four people who wanted to play it.
Rym: only three people can play it.
Rym: No one wanted to pay $30 for it.
Scott: When this game goes on if you got tons of money sure go $30 go nuts.
Scott: right the thing is there's no network Multiplayer, so it's sort of like ah you got to play locally got it.
Rym: at the same time It's.
Rym: while I can't excuse the lack of the online multiplayer I will at least say that local multiplayer for a game like that.
Rym: It's pretty great is much more satisfying than playing online.
Scott: I think it's.
Scott: it's basically if you liked you know the bionic commando rearmed.
Scott: You know play this thing.
Scott: Get three friends together.
Scott: play this co-op locally on your PC.
Scott: get you know three Xbox 360 game pads You know so that you can actually play it because to play with the keyboard of them.
Scott: It was just terrible forget it.
Rym: So speaking of every game if you never played bionic commando rearmed buy it and play it.
Scott: no Yeah, it was great.
Rym: Yeah, like we got it We should beat the co-op sometimes.
Scott: so but no, but there's a free demo of Trine.
Scott: so play the demo which is all I've played and You'll probably like it immediately.
Scott: And I guess what.
Scott: maybe we'll talk more about that game if and when?
Scott: We play by the full version and play co-op through the whole thing.
Scott: who knows I've also been playing Blood Bowl.
Rym: what the old board game?
Scott: no well Yeah, I'll tell you a little.
Scott: you know I'm probably gonna repeat what I'm about to say.
Scott: if you know cuz we're definitely gonna do A whole show about blood Bowl the video game.
Scott: Oh, yeah a new one, but I'll repeat I'll say stuff now and repeat it later.
Scott: anyway Blood Bowl was an old board game a miniatures board game made by Games Workshop.
Scott: the same people make Warhammer and such and basically What it is is it's fantasy football But it's not fantasy.
Scott: but it's not fantasy football in terms of like yahoo sports fantasy football It's get the ball in the end zone with orcs dwarves and elves.
Scott: That's what is that kind of fantasy football.
Rym: very much in the Warhammer universe.
Scott: very much The game itself the board game.
Scott: you can still buy it.
Scott: I think it shouldn't be too hard to find.
Scott: I'm not sure how imprinted is.
Rym: Millennium Games always has at least like one copy.
Scott: I could definitely I if I wanted to I could get a new copy, but they're like $75.
Scott: There was a board.
Scott: there was a video game version of it for DOS back in the day Right.
Scott: then there was as company sort of made a game called Chaos League and Games Workshop was like hey What the fuck is this Chaos League?
Scott: shit Blood Bowl thieves?
Scott: You know what the fuck.
Scott: but instead of getting all stupid They just got those guys And they had to make Blood Bowl the video game and you can get it right now for $50, which is a lot You know, but and the game has many problems many problems, however Deep inside the game.
Scott: Well, not too deep inside.
Scott: you can play Blood Bowl the original board game as per the Living Blood Bowl 5.0 rule set exactly According to those rules and you don't have to deal with setting up the pieces or rolling the dice or any of that annoying Shit, you'll never have like rules arguments.
Scott: You never had to get your measuring stick or deal with any of that bullshit.
Scott: You can play a game of Blood Bowl in a short amount of time Even though the user interface is bleh.
Scott: You can play it online against people.
Scott: So if you like Blood Bowl It's a game for you and it's probably worth $50.
Scott: I've been playing it quite a bit.
Rym: It's tricky watching Scott play because he'll play it and he'll come downstairs or something to say man that game is awesome.
Rym: But then an hour later, he'll be playing.
Rym: it was like man.
Scott: that game sucks Usually depends on if I roll the dice.
Scott: Well, if I virtually roll the dice well or not.
Rym: It got to the point to where I'd come home from work and I just ask him so is Blood Bowl good or bad?
Scott: It's it's one of those games where you know, some games have a lot of randomness, right?
Scott: Let's say monopoly where your whole game rests on the rolls of the dice.
Scott: Or you have a game with no randomness or almost no randomness like say go right?
Scott: Yeah, but Blood Bowl It's like it has this randomness, but the randomness is you know You can mitigate for it.
Scott: You know you could you know gate.
Scott: for yes You act you act in such a way and take moves in such a way that you know Even if you roll poorly and you get the worst possible result You'll still be alright and you're not gonna just lose because of it.
Rym: I would say more to for a game like Blood Bowl specifically Blood Bowl a game where tackling may or may not involve death.
Rym: It's you know steam rollers on the field, but you know, maybe at halftime the ref will say hey, that's an illegal weapon Stop using it.
Rym: but the randomness is such that a game like this will have those that tension of a real sports game where One team might be better than the other team and the game might be going pretty solidly But someone could hit a grand slam at any time.
Scott: Well, the base has to be loaded first.
Scott: But yeah, it's like they could load the base.
Scott: You know the randomness you mitigate for it you handle it and if you're a smart player You're not gonna lose just because you rolled poorly and the mitigate for that's not how you use that word.
Rym: No, you just you say you mitigate it anyway.
Scott: But I don't understand what you're saying before anyway.
Scott: But there's occasions where one role is like a huge deal and it actually ends up being like a real sport.
Scott: You know occasionally someone catches that long bomb and it's just crazy awesome.
Scott: And you know, it's it's.
Scott: you know, if that the other team gets that crazy awesome long bomb then you hate the game.
Scott: Yeah If you get it's the best game ever.
Scott: look at that dramatic, you know.
Scott: last play the game touchdown.
Rym: We have to play the game a lot more before we talk about it.
Scott: That is correct.
Rym: stand chill details.
Scott: Let us move to news.
Rym: So what do you have?
Scott: What do I have?
Scott: Well There is a company that in the past Well, there are actually many game companies that in the past made great games and really nowadays either don't make such good games Or don't make games at all.
Scott: and one such company is Lucas Arts, which you know is definitely if you don't know It is tied to Lucasfilm.
Scott: But they made Star Wars some of the better and some of the worst games to come out for that era thing is back In the day, they didn't just make Star Wars games.
Scott: Well, they did although they did make Star Wars games.
Scott: They made other games like well, Indiana Jones adventure games, which was also a Lucas property.
Scott: I made things like the dig and loom and And full throttle and a lot of point-and-click adventure games, which you can play in the ever-famous scum VM.
Scott: But they made some other games too.
Scott: And actually they've got lots of recent games like, you know, Lego, Indiana Jones Lego Star Wars The defunct Star Wars galaxy, I think was actually Sony or those Lego games.
Rym: I always I really like the style of them But you can't play those games for more than 15 minutes with a thinking adult brain and not Continue to keep that thinking adult brain active.
Rym: Yeah, that game is just oh my god The cutscenes are really funny.
Rym: they are Not games.
Scott: Well, it's a walk around and hit things.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: That's gauntlet.
Scott: That's what it is gone.
Rym: I think we spent more time killing each other in the ready room than we ever did playing the game.
Scott: Yeah, all those Lego games like Lego Star Wars is gauntlet.
Scott: Anyway, so the thing is a lot of these games have been unavailable for a very long time Which is why scum VM exists because people wanted to play old Lucas arts adventure games.
Scott: They loved on modern computers and so they made scum VM.
Scott: now the thing is Just now for the first time in a long time.
Scott: Some of these games are actually going to return.
Scott: First of all, they're making a new monkey island game.
Scott: It's not a remake of an old monkey island game.
Scott: It's actually a brand new monkey island game.
Scott: It's all 3d and shit and it's coming out soon.
Scott: ish I don't know exactly when they're also Releasing the original monkey island But it's gonna be all new just like the new monkey on with 3d and the whole thing as far as I know.
Scott: so if you never played the monkey island and You want to play it legitimately and not just go download and use scum VM.
Scott: You can buy that and you'll also if you're a fan of the old monkey island You're the kind of person who played them all ten times.
Scott: like I know many people are.
Scott: you can go and get this new monkey on game and continue in your 3-point action.
Rym: monkey island.
Rym: They're very important to play at least once because you'd be surprised how many of the kind of offhand references and gaming culture Came from those games that people don't even recognize anymore.
Rym: Like they'll make a joke but not realize that monkey island is where that joke came from.
Scott: I remember I got a CD from a PC gamer magazine.
Rym: Oh my god coconut monkey coconut.
Scott: Hello I'm coconut monkey.
Rym: How do you keep beating me?
Rym: Even you have neither arms nor legs.
Rym: It in fact was a coconut monkey CD, oh my god, I should make coconut monkey my thing of the day.
Rym: forget Star Wars.
Scott: Oh, is he on YouTube?
Rym: I'll find him.
Rym: you keep talking.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Hello I'm coconut monkey and on my PC gamer CD that Scott got in his magazine There was a. There was a the full version of monkey island and if you paid $20 you could get a code that would unlock it.
Scott: so you didn't need to go and buy a CD.
Scott: I never paid that $20.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: There's a whole ton of coconut monkey in here.
Rym: Oh shit I think I got anything in the day.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Anyway the So yeah, they're also the bigger.
Scott: the main news here is not what I just said about monkey island or PC gamer CDs.
Scott: It's that Lucas arts is putting a bunch of games on Steam tomorrow, of course, you're probably listening to this tomorrow.
Scott: So today July what 8th?
Rym: Let's see it.
Rym: July 8th bla bla bla bla.
Rym: Indiana Jones and the fate of Atlantis.
Scott: That's an adventure.
Rym: Jones in the last crusade.
Scott: adventure game the graphic adventure.
Rym: There was a colon there.
Rym: You interrupted me.
Scott: Yep loom loom for people who don't know is a point-and-click adventure game.
Scott: if As far as I know it was the first ever game released on CD-ROM It's also kind of a special game.
Scott: It's very special.
Scott: It's probably not like any other game Any other game you've played.
Scott: yeah It's not doom.
Scott: It's loom.
Scott: Yes a loom you use to weave things.
Rym: I I witnessed not that long ago the saddest conversation I've ever seen online That basically went along the lines of man.
Rym: I just got a copy of loom.
Rym: That game was awesome.
Rym: Oh you mean doom?
Rym: Yeah, that was pretty awesome.
Rym: No loom.
Rym: There was a game called loom.
Scott: Yes, there was a game called loom is pretty significant.
Rym: yep the dig Dangerous Lego Indiana Jones Star Wars Battlefront 2 Star Wars Republic commandos Star Wars Starfighter Thrillville off the rails.
Rym: I don't know what that is.
Scott: that is either.
Scott: people like those Battlefront games But you know.
Scott: obviously you know none of these.
Scott: some of these games might be exciting to you especially probably the loom and the dig and fate of Atlantis.
Scott: right those are.
Scott: those are good point-and-click adventures, but Nothing else really that exciting as far as I'm concerned.
Scott: however What is exciting is that look LucasArts is putting games on Steam?
Scott: This is just the beginning.
Scott: if this is the beginning that's a pretty damn good beginning.
Scott: look There's.
Rym: they started with what ten games, and they're all just straight up.
Rym: you know pixel for pixel ports and the question the obvious thing to say is is TIE fighter coming question mark question mark question mark exclamation point and aside TIE fighter and TIE fighter CD which was just TIE fighter remade a year later But well not even remade.
Rym: just the graphics are made better Have been rated pretty consistently among some the greatest game ever made.
Scott: Yeah I mean this.
Scott: there's all sorts of old games that we rave about that are hard or Impossible to play in current days.
Scott: right we talk about games like you know or they are.
Scott: you can play them in current days But it's a little tricky right we talk about like I mega TF ain't around tribes - right TIE fighter is probably like the one old Game it was so great yet like this.
Scott: I don't even know how to play it today.
Scott: I couldn't even I still do even if I pirate it.
Scott: How would I get it to run?
Rym: I guess box its backspace for full throttle and then on my hat up down left and right would redirect all the shields.
Scott: no No, I mean how to get it to run.
Rym: Oh, I was playing it like a year and a half ago in DOS box.
Rym: Just fine really.
Scott: yeah might be worth pirating Pirating.
Rym: I own it.
Rym: I still have the CD.
Rym: It's under my bed in fact.
Rym: I can kick the box.
Rym: It's in with my foot right now.
Scott: Why don't we get that shit going you want to?
Rym: Tie fighter as I recall I believe was given the highest rating a game had ever been given by PC gamer when it came out and It was only beaten the following year by itself re-released.
Rym: oh shit tie fighter is just.
Rym: it was a. Actually a game came before it called x-wing and that game was okay, it was the same thing.
Scott: yeah It was a game where you fly an x-wing.
Rym: that was it and tie fighter was just x-wing kind of redone.
Rym: My graphics are better controls are better Gameplay was better, but more importantly You play as just some guy a low-level grunt high fighter pilot working for the Empire Which is a force of peace and prosperity fighting against these anarchist rebel scum of course and?
Rym: You're going around doing all the stuff that the Empire was doing.
Rym: that wasn't all necessarily that evil force.
Rym: You're also doing all the evil, but it's always portrayed in this very good way, and you know what?
Rym: Having played all of x-wing and having played all of tie fighter fuck the rebels That it is so much more fun and more rewarding to be a member of the nation of the Empire.
Rym: As uniforms nice Equipment everybody's real professional.
Scott: Yeah, who wants to fly like some piece of shit x-wing?
Scott: that's like falling apart.
Scott: Yeah, you can fly nice clean tie defender.
Rym: You don't get a tie defender.
Rym: only.
Rym: like the best of the best you're gonna be flying some tie fighter with no shields.
Scott: I'm the best of the best though.
Scott: Yeah, well you'll die like the rest You know loaded with like eight torpedoes.
Scott: Good times Ship actually works.
Scott: The thing is you look we're gonna link to some YouTube videos because barely anyone's actually played tie fighter this game.
Scott: This game is from what you're like 94.
Rym: I think it was released in 94 and then teen years old re-released in 95.
Scott: So it's 15 years old.
Scott: you needed a maybe for the 15th anniversary.
Scott: Maybe that maybe they are gonna.
Rym: basically needed your full keyboard ready to go and you had to memorize all the buttons.
Scott: look how Complicated this game is but yet look how many features it has that are just.
Scott: you know This is old DOS game and this game did shit that it is not present in modern games at all.
Scott: It's like games got worse and you look at this game.
Scott: It's like wow really that's 94 shit.
Scott: That's better than like any game out today.
Rym: I mean no game has come close to it.
Scott: There were like the voice acting is actually good like well.
Rym: Well now it is video game good.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: it's movie good.
Rym: It gets a little awkward.
Rym: star wars good.
Rym: some of the other cuts cut scenes quite.
Scott: star wars good.
Rym: Signal advice.
Rym: Admiral throng to have his tie squadrons launched immediately.
Scott: Yeah, these cutscenes are like amazing.
Rym: You just want to see more Admiral throng.
Scott: What's wrong with that?
Scott: Well thrown You know that this you actually have all these ships, you know like they actually.
Scott: you know like the configurations and you can have so many ships out in space all fighting at the same time and give guys orders.
Scott: and Like the game actually has a very high attention to detail Like let's say you got in a mission and Darth Vader's out with you on the mission.
Scott: if you accidentally give him orders You're in trouble.
Scott: Yeah, you don't tell him what to do.
Rym: Also, don't let him die.
Rym: He might do something stupid He might mess up.
Scott: Yeah, you can.
Scott: you can do pretty much anything.
Scott: I mean you could turn around and try to blow up the Star Destroyer if you want.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, good luck with that.
Rym: So I got good enough at the game where I would get bored and I would just get in like a tie advanced and just Try to destroy all of the capital ships in a mission and then hyperspace out.
Rym: Mm-hmm I did it once nice like I destroyed two Star Destroyers and my entire fleet.
Rym: It was awesome.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know what would be really cool is if you did that then it would just load up x-wing.
Rym: There were games that came after that were updates.
Scott: Well x-wing vs tie fighter fuck that game.
Rym: that game was so unplayable and broken.
Scott: and then x-wing Alliance.
Rym: x-wing Alliance was actually really playable But it was too little too late.
Rym: It kind of came out at the end of the joystick era.
Rym: There are no longer joysticks.
Rym: We just now recently had that one Logitech flight stick.
Scott: I don't know what game they made that for.
Rym: I don't know why they made it.
Scott: Yeah I mean it looks pretty good from what I had to use it to find out.
Rym: I hope that it can be the chicken or the egg in the chicken egg conundrum of.
Rym: there are no free space shooters because there Aren't joysticks.
Rym: There are no joysticks because there aren't free space shooters, but no one's gonna pay that much.
Rym: But then again people bought that stupid console to play the met game on the Xbox.
Scott: not too many people though enough people.
Rym: Yeah, the steel battalion, especially considering that Gigantic monolithic console did almost nothing for the game.
Rym: You hit most of those buttons once.
Scott: Yeah I almost feel like maybe the time to come back with the free space shooter might have been like some years ago and people are really willing to buy plastic instruments.
Rym: tie fighter was just so great and They if they remade it if this game ever came out as an updated multiplayer game Oh my god I would.
Rym: I look forward to this and More so than I could have possibly looked forward to Team Fortress 2 or even NS2.
Scott: You heard it here.
Scott: first prediction 15th anniversary of tie fighter re-release.
Rym: I hope that by saying it we've made it so make it so.
Rym: You know what make it so is from right?
Rym: No, okay.
Rym: Anyway so I don't want to talk about this a lot, but there was a Dot a while ago and What I found more interesting as usual than the article were the comments about the article.
Rym: But the article was talking about it raised the question Why don't MMOs allow easier transportation?
Rym: and it talks a lot about how.
Rym: in MMOs You pretty much have to point your guy in a direction and he walks and walks and walks and walks and walks And then you get somewhere.
Rym: and the arguments on one side were that if you let people teleport everywhere Then the world feels too small.
Rym: but then people counter-argued by saying that no the world feels small because you have to walk through these desolate wastelands where there's nothing interactive anywhere along the way and It's a complex issue and I'm not sure I don't think there's a good answer yet, but MMOs suck
Scott: Well said.
Scott: But
Rym: now in the comments what I found interesting was that most of the people who were Arguing against the question of why don't we who were saying we shouldn't make it easier We're making these really kind of weird like reflective Like there were arguments that only made sense Inside of the context of the MMOs that they played like they would argue that like something in the game like, you know Well, we don't need to make transportation faster because the game already did it.
Rym: if you get this trinket in this trinket and this mount The mount flies 50% faster than normal.
Rym: You can get there in like four minutes instead of eight.
Rym: Therefore we don't need to make it any faster.
Rym: and it's like what kind of person makes an argument like that Person is only thinking inside the box.
Scott: I mean quote.
Rym: then they added the Burning Crusade expansion with flying mounts.
Rym: the level 40 mounts dropped to 60 gold Level 60 mounts dropped to blah blah blah blah blah blah trying to skip ahead to the part that matters For a 60% flying speed mount.
Rym: Wow, never mind I picked the wrong wall of text to read and it ends with.
Rym: you could boost these numbers by a further 10% if you get the right trinkets and equip them.
Scott: Uh-huh, and that is the argument against making travel faster in MMOs.
Scott: I Think the thing is I think you know fallout actually did a pretty good job of.
Scott: you know.
Scott: You walk somewhere the first time you want to go there and that forces you to you know Explore the map and think the thing.
Scott: the map and fallout, you know while it wasn't as extensive as an MMO map It was pretty big and there was actually stuff all over the place Even if a lot of it was sort of repetitive stuff.
Scott: there was stuff everywhere to explore, you know.
Scott: I think actually half-life 2 had a better mat Transportation in terms of exploring, you know Even though it was linear because like you're driving down the road in your little dune buggy and you see a house off to the side You can go and fully explore that house or you can keep going, you know, and I think you know the
Rym: the feel
Scott: of exploring a big world and finding actual stuff in it is in itself fun,
Rym: but
Scott: Once you get somewhere once I've already made a trip, right?
Scott: That why should I make the same trip again?
Scott: If nothing along that road has changed?
Scott: Well one argument might be an alternative road.
Rym: one argument is that there are you there's some Game-breaking mechanics that could come into play.
Rym: where say you can teleport anywhere You've already been.
Rym: then maybe you can use that to get away from someone who hasn't been somewhere yet immediately Instead of them having to chase you stuff like that.
Scott: Well, I mean obviously you I mean think about this right like in fallout 3 If there are bad guys about you can't quick walk you have to get rid of them first.
Scott: So if someone's after me and there's like a bad guy chasing me I can't teleport while the bad guys chasing me either got I got to fight it or get away from it So that it's no longer chasing me and then I can teleport, you know It's a simple fix.
Scott: It's already been implemented.
Rym: Remember look at a non MMO like Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles and just remember that the thing where you just had a map you picked where you wanted to go and it would kind of interrupt your automatic travel periodically and show you a little cutscene a little random interaction and What I think should make an MMO awesome.
Rym: why MMOs could be so awesome would be those weird interactions where you're traveling somewhere and you meet someone on the road or you find something along the way.
Rym: that's interesting but I think the problem is that the MMO is just.
Scott: you're holding down one arrow and just walking.
Rym: the MMO that everyone plays World of Warcraft Doesn't have that.
Rym: you're not going to run into anything you want to run into on your way somewhere.
Rym: You might just have to fight some annoying bad guys or you're on your way to a raid You don't want to be late or you're just bored.
Rym: and everyone I know who plays World of Warcraft always They'll like I see them they'll set their character to auto run somewhere and they're like watching a movie in a window or playing But Joel or something.
Scott: they got Twitter and Wow.
Rym: now I hear That that's not worse than bejeweled so I can't talk about it.
Rym: No whenever something like that happens I can't talk about it unless it's worse than the last thing that happened.
Rym: I haven't talked about Jack Thompson in a long long time.
Scott: There's nothing to say about Jack Thompson a long long time.
Rym: Yes, and with Wow bejeweled isn't Wow.
Rym: Nothing that gay could add to Wow would make me talk about that.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah I think the thing is there's other good things to consider right?
Scott: For example, let's say you could teleport everywhere, right?
Scott: Well, if you could teleport everywhere you'd save a lot of time.
Scott: I mean how many hours does someone spend typing but then so early?
Scott: some said walking.
Scott: therefore They're gonna complete quests faster and complete levels faster and they're gonna get ahead in the game faster Which means they're gonna reach the maximum in the game faster They're gonna get bored with the game faster and they're gonna close their account sooner.
Scott: Yep, and so when there's an MMO at any game that charges you monthly They want you to spend a lot of time playing.
Scott: they want to make it you know take as long as possible to get ahead in the game because Then you will you know think they got it.
Scott: They have this careful psychological balance of make it so that it takes you a long time to play so that you'll stay subscribed for many months, but also Constantly reward you so that you're constantly enjoying yourself so that you will never get bored and want to stop playing.
Rym: I feel like the way the problem kind of everyone who addresses this problem in the questions Even in the article kind of looks at it from the wrong perspective that it wouldn't be an issue if the game were truly Truly massive as opposed to just a giant ready room where people move between these kind of instantiated encounters.
Scott: Yep
Rym: Because if it were truly massive You would be interacting with interesting things all the time and you'd be going places and the world would just be this organic evolving place Instead of this Static place that was just a kind of scenery between the two places you want it to be to do your next raid
Scott: that happens To have auction houses and shops and things of that nature.
Rym: Yeah, it is.
Rym: I guess this article just Not like you could in a lot of other MMOs.
Rym: no, I mean in the realm.
Rym: I had my house and we had our guild houses.
Rym: I had my bedroom.
Rym: I had that sword I've got I put on my wall.
Scott: I know you could get land in Ultima online.
Rym: Yeah, I had a garden So my own private garden.
Scott: Yeah, see like if someone if people could yes That's what I if I made an MMO the what I would do is I wouldn't you know I have like land for sale or anything stupid like that right is?
Scott: I would let people build, you know Like you go out you go into the you know There'd be a giant map you got.
Scott: you chop down some trees and you can build a log cabin just out and you know Wherever you want.
Scott: and then you know people who are Traveling around might come across your log cabin and knock on the door.
Scott: Maybe they steal all your shit and that'd be perfectly legitimate, you know, you know That's how it would be and it would be.
Scott: it would be very cool.
Scott: Maybe you could like, you know, you could build weird things just leave them out in in the world like you set up You know Maybe like skulls on sticks and you set up like a whole row of them in the woods somewhere.
Scott: if I can try to scare The shit out of people I point out you could.
Rym: you can have your little place in a kingdom of loathing Your little campsite, all right.
Rym: Yeah Anyway, I don't know why I was diverged from its roots in some ways like it's diverged from a lot of the things that made Mucks and muds and mushes and moves interesting But it's basically stuck to the one thing that was bad about mine.
Scott: Well, it's not just wow I mean, there's a lot of games.
Scott: Well, I say well, you gotta walk to get some.
Rym: it's just like how you know In the beyond Dungeons and Dragons panel, we talk a lot about Dungeons and Dragons.
Rym: The everything we say applies to almost every role-playing game.
Rym: But everyone knows D&D everyone plays D&D everyone plays Wow, and now they're the same game.
Scott: So well thing is I've noticed that people, you know Whenever there's a talk about MMOs people always bring up like Eve online doesn't do.
Scott: that even lives the good one, you know.
Scott: Yeah, Eve online doesn't have all these problems.
Scott: Like Eve online is some great amazing game.
Scott: I see people playing Eve online, you know what they're doing.
Scott: instead of going and killing rats to level up They're going in mining asteroids to level up and get you know resources, right?
Scott: It's the same shit.
Rym: I was not the one who said it.
Rym: It was said long before me.
Rym: I'm not being original anyway, but Eve online is the greatest spreadsheet simulator.
Rym: The world has ever created.
Scott: So, you know all these people they're like, oh Eve online doesn't have these problems.
Scott: listen I saw a guy playing it.
Scott: He freaking had a ship.
Scott: He had to fly it all the way out somewhere which is the same thing as walking to get somewhere, right?
Scott: He had to mine asteroids and fly him back all slow like it's the same thing.
Rym: So things of the day I'm saving coconut monkey.
Rym: I'll wait till you all forget and I'll bring him up again.
Rym: I'm coconut out of nowhere But suffice it to say coconut monkey has neither arms nor legs, but my thing of the day is some footage from TIE fighter.
Rym: This is one of the cutscenes from the game and it's a spoiler.
Rym: I'm gonna tell you right now Admiral Harkov Betrays your Imperial ass and you catch him and you give him to Darth Vader and Darth Vader interrogates him in the episode 5 manner.
Rym: The fact that he basically like he.
Scott: Clearly just go on Star Wars.
Rym: He clearly does not need the answer to the question.
Rym: He has asked this man.
Scott: Yeah, he could reread his mind.
Rym: He knows In Star Wars when he kills the Admiral he's like no.
Scott: but really go on YouTube and watch Videos of TIE fighter gameplay.
Scott: seriously, just go do it.
Scott: So search for TIE fighter.
Scott: You'll find it.
Rym: We'll link to something.
Scott: We'll link to some.
Scott: All right, my thing of the day.
Scott: So the day apparently at It might have been e3.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I didn't.
Scott: I watched this video the other day, but it's some gay.
Scott: There were some Italian guys and they were actually protesting because Mario was such a bad Italian stereotype.
Scott: You know, it's sort of like when those people were complaining that Resident Evil 5 was racist.
Scott: You know same kind of thing and you know, they're kind of right.
Scott: It's kind of surprising that you know, nobody's really complained about you know, the racistness of Mario.
Scott: I mean, I mean, come on, he's like It's all Come on.
Scott: I mean and no one seems to care about this, you know, it's like if Mickey Mouse was like, you know Like I am the French Mickey Mouse.
Scott: Oh, I can't even do French and Mickey Mouse at the same time.
Scott: Yeah, how do you do?
Scott: How do you do that?
Scott: And also be home?
Rym: I don't think it's possible.
Scott: Anyway, you know people would be like what the fuck is this shit?
Rym: You know, there'd be a big complaints but no part of it is that Mario has been such an institution for so long.
Rym: and if anyone had made a Complaints in the early days when it was 8-bit.
Rym: Could they have been taken seriously?
Scott: No, I guess the answer is no.
Rym: And then as graphics got better, it was far too late to make a complaint.
Scott: But anyway, the thing about this video is not just that some guys were complaining about the racistness of Mario.
Scott: It's that It's.
Scott: it's pretty unbelievable.
Scott: It's like two internet videos joined into one because I mean that alone would be internet video right.
Scott: but an escaped gorilla Kidnaps their girlfriend while this video is being.
Scott: it's unbelievable.
Scott: And then they go and they rescue the girlfriend.
Scott: It's Unbelievable, you have to see this shit the hat and the mustache.
Rym: Oh my god the mushrooms.
Rym: - So anyway We came up with this show kind of out of nowhere because there was an article Somewhat recently that we both read independently.
Rym: We didn't talk about it and Scott brought it up and I remembered it and we realized this pretty much Makes for a very interesting Tuesday show and I can't believe we never talked about this before.
Rym: Yep, and maybe we did but I'm not gonna go through the archive.
Scott: Well, I think there was.
Scott: we did a show on griefing where we discussed many of the things that we will probably repeat ourselves In this show, but there is a very big difference between griefing and cheating and I think cheating does demand its own episode.
Scott: But let before we just dive into cheating.
Scott: Let's talk about this article here.
Rym: so a Loyola professor made a character in City of Heroes City of villains called Twixt
Scott: Twixt and
Rym: He basically he seemed to play this game for fun, but also for academia And he in the course of play decided to engage in a number of so-called Breaching experiments where he would breach social mores that were not enforced by game logic.
Rym: It's basically the equivalent of doing a study where in the real world you get into an elevator the door closes and you face all The other people instead of facing the door.
Scott: Think about whenever an elevator right everyone in the elevator puts their faces towards the elevator door.
Scott: Right, if you get an elevator and you put your back to the door and look at all the people in the elevator They'll freak out do it.
Scott: It's fun.
Rym: Yep,
Scott: but
Rym: it's the idea that if there is some sort of Unenforceable or unenforced social moray or some sort of thing that is legal to do Possible to do easy to do and even beneficial to do that due to some societal unwritten restriction is never done you can cause all sorts of havoc by breaking it.
Rym: and he uses these video games that have basically a Completely 100% fabricated made-up internet culture in them to see how Universal these concepts are.
Rym: and he basically and all I could think of reading this article was way back when we used to play What Jedi Knight Jedi Knight - yeah, which was on the quake 3 engine?
Rym: It was basically an FPS lightsaber game where he was an FPS But you also had lightsabers but Scott and I played it with each other a whole bunch and then we started playing online.
Rym: I remember every time we play it online I would run into a server and there'd be like 20 people all fighting with lightsabers.
Scott: It was only.
Scott: it was only on the dual servers because there were servers where you could play the actual FPS But they're also servers where you would just have lightsabers duels and it was sort of like ricochet where two people would fight at A time and everyone else would just sort of be waiting.
Scott: Yeah, or maybe it would do like, you know round-robin tournament.
Scott: This
Rym: happened to me a few times even in these the kind of freewheeling servers where it'd be a melee but you know, everyone's ever is like ten people fighting all over the place and Someone would come in front of me and he'd stop and look at me and he'd do his little bow Like do you want to duel and I just kill him?
Rym: Yep, but in the duels it was even worse Like the game would start and both players like walking right up next to each other Lightsabers out and they'd both like duck in the counter-strike teabagging motion back away And I think some people would like look at.
Scott: they wouldn't duck.
Scott: They would look at the ground and then look back up again to make their character lean over.
Rym: Everyone would basically bow and there was all this sort of formalized unwritten Unenforced by the game logic culture in the game.
Scott: Yeah, I would just kill anyone who bowed immediately.
Rym: I think I win if someone bowed.
Rym: their head came off in a second.
Rym: I was banned from servers for that bike.
Scott: And the thing is if they you know when the next person, you know thing is if you did if you didn't bow People got pissed and they tried they'd really freak out on you.
Scott: I was all dark side.
Scott: I get him with my lightning.
Scott: Yeah, every like.
Scott: yes, right?
Rym: It was kind of broken that as long as you had good FPS and skills You could just run away from someone lightning them until they die.
Rym: Oh, yeah, there's basically nothing.
Scott: The game we're talking about the game had sort of an unwritten Rule and people got really pissed if you broke this unwritten and this wasn't even like a glitch or anything.
Rym: This was just this rule that came out of nowhere that players Enforced on their own as best they could.
Rym: it didn't come from the game designers didn't come from the game world.
Rym: It came from nothing but the players and yet people would lose their shit If you didn't follow the arbitrary rules that weren't written down anywhere.
Scott: Now the thing is right as we're going to discuss this is we don't?
Scott: I do not consider this and I would argue that It is not cheating right.
Scott: killing someone while they're bowing isn't cheating.
Rym: It's no different than killing someone while they're typing.
Rym: and you know what?
Rym: if I see that flag in quake 3 that means you're typing.
Rym: that is a beacon for a railgun to the head and Basically the argument here right is what is cheating right?
Rym: Oh, I didn't we?
Rym: I want to at least mention the rest of this article.
Scott: Oh, there's more to the article.
Rym: well very interesting because the the guy who did this.
Rym: he did this in this MMO And he basically did what we did but he did it methodically and Such a way as to kind of catalog how people respond and reacted and all he would do was go into these PvP areas where?
Rym: Traditionally players wouldn't actually do the PvP like many versus many fights Which was to capture all these pillboxes.
Rym: the players would all kind of ignore each other even though they were enemies and farm XP uh-huh, or They would like fight.
Rym: these little duels like two of them would fight in like one corner of the map and all these people would Stand around and watch and he would join these matches and just proceed to win trivially so and he would use just intelligent basic strategy and Nothing against the rules.
Rym: No glitches.
Rym: He didn't even come close to using a glitch.
Rym: He did everything that was perfectly just within the scope of the game.
Scott: Well, that's it.
Scott: that's a case of.
Scott: you know basically by the definitions that I hold right those people right who everyone else But him was actually a griefer.
Scott: It's just they were all griefers.
Rym: Well the thing is what he discovered was that as he played this way people Like they went crazy to a degree that is laughable.
Rym: like he started he got death threats.
Rym: toward the end of this people Constantly made big petitions to get a band from the game.
Rym: They had got to the point where entire groups of people would just make alternate characters level them up all the way Attack him constantly and mass to try to force him off.
Rym: But because he used these basic strategies that they never apparently thought of he would beat them anyway Really?
Scott: Wow, it's that kind of game.
Rym: He basically just he by playing smartly could beat people Consistently and they could really do nothing about it because they refused to do what he did which was just basic strategy.
Rym: They thought that whatever that strategy was which had to do with teleporting people around the map Was unfair and against their social mores.
Rym: they refused to do it And they got mad when he did it and even the game designers basically sided with him saying look this part of the game deal With it.
Scott: Oh nice good game designers.
Rym: But the fact that like you should read the article to see all the details.
Rym: But basically he determined that humans will almost Immediately resort to the most brutal things they can possibly resort to to enforce their own personal arbitrary Social mores.
Rym: and if those mores are unenforceable by their own laws or by the laws of their society They will pretty much immediately do anything they can to circumvent those laws in order to enforce their own fake laws.
Rym: Yeah, and he makes some interesting conclusions and it's an interesting read.
Scott: Mm-hmm But how this relates to cheating right.
Scott: is that you know the discussion of?
Scott: is this guy cheating where the other people cheating?
Scott: You know what is cheating right and you know of course these these other guys right the guys who are getting killed there.
Scott: They would definitely argue that this guy was cheating.
Scott: no question.
Scott: They would argue that and there's a reason they are wrong and the reason is this right.
Scott: we did a show about griefing and Griefing was defined as you have someone playing a game right and they're not.
Scott: they're not breaking the rules of the game But what they're doing is they have a different goal, right?
Scott: So let's say we're playing Monopoly.
Rym: the game theory term is utility right different utility.
Scott: So we're playing Monopoly right and we're both mean remember both obeying the rules of Monopoly.
Scott: Rym wants to win at Monopoly So he wants to get the most money and he wants me to go bankrupt, right?
Scott: I don't want to win I don't care if I go bankrupt or not.
Scott: I just want to piss Rym off.
Scott: No, I just want to get as many houses as I can.
Scott: That's my goal.
Scott: You get a lot of houses, you know.
Scott: So I just buy as many houses I can and everybody hotels I get is you know?
Scott: And I just get as many properties I can but I don't really care about trying to get a lot of money You know and I just you know I'll be willing to spend like all this extra money to buy properties from you and get houses or whatever.
Rym: now We're basically playing two different games in the same space But my utility of the game as was laid forth and as people, you know Like the actual game as per the rules going toward the victory condition Is ruined by the fact that the people I'm playing with aren't going toward the written victory condition.
Scott: Yeah, so in the situation in the city of heroes villains, whatever, right?
Scott: There's a game of the you know Heroes versus villains.
Scott: kill all the heroes kill all the villains and this guy is playing that game and that's the utility He has.
Scott: apparently the game intends you to have but apparently no one else wants to play.
Scott: Other players have an alternate utility of get tons of XP or do whatever.
Scott: they'll tell they're doing So, you know, it's actually.
Scott: even though it would seem as if he was the griefer He's the one who's actually has the intended utility.
Scott: Therefore all the other players are griefers.
Rym: Well, of course the other interesting thing here is in the whole game theory, you know game theory.
Rym: nominally You can use it to determine what the best possible course of action is for a rational actor in a situation.
Rym: So the idea that you know I act in my own Best self-interest and I assume that everyone else is acting in their own best self-interest.
Rym: So I play games and I try to win said games and I don't cheat But I use whatever tools the game gives me to the best of my ability.
Rym: But a lot of people in a lot of competitive games if someone uses a strategy that is perfectly legitimate But that they perceive somehow is unfair.
Rym: They will basically accuse you of cheating.
Rym: Mm-hmm, even though you're following the rules completely and My entire life I have been one of those people to where if something works I will do it constantly and repeatedly until it is no longer work.
Scott: Yes, take for example the snaking in Mario Kart DS, right?
Rym: It makes it a worse game, but it's in there.
Rym: I cannot I cannot not do it.
Rym: Yes can a fire butt burn if there is brush before it?
Scott: So here's the thing with cheating.
Scott: right a game is Defined by its rules.
Scott: the rules of monopoly are Monopoly.
Scott: if you have if you change even one rule, that's not monopoly.
Scott: That's some other game, right?
Scott: I mean you look and that's not to say that, you know, there.
Scott: there's lots of complexity to that.
Scott: You know and look at something like baseball right the rules of baseball change a lot over time how they change Stadium to stadium right and you just you call it Major League Baseball.
Scott: But really every different stadium American League National League every different year where the rules change Those are all actually different games.
Scott: a game is its rules.
Scott: So a cheater or cheating is when you you you declare yes I am playing this game, but you actually Break the rules in some way.
Scott: that's sort of obvious, right?
Scott: But if you accept the fact that a game is defined by its rules a cheater is actually someone Who they're not just breaking the rules, right?
Scott: They declare that they're playing one game, but they're actually playing a different game.
Scott: See a griefer is someone with a different utility.
Scott: a cheater is someone who's actually not playing.
Scott: they're doing something else But they're in your game.
Scott: So what this something else they're doing is Interacting with the game that you are playing in some way now, there's also the huge I've.
Rym: what amazes me is that I see people complaining that other people are cheating at Single-player games and I don't think there's even like.
Rym: I don't think there is even any Discussion there if you own a game you should be able to you do whatever you want with it.
Rym: Okay?
Scott: Well, well the question of are they cheating yes or no, right?
Rym: Well, I don't think it even matters at that.
Scott: Well, I don't think it matters either.
Scott: But there is a question of are they cheating or not?
Scott: and I would say in a video game, right?
Scott: You look at a board game, right?
Scott: The rules are.
Scott: you know the game and cheating is breaking the rules or not playing a different game.
Scott: So if you do something that is contrary to what the rule book says then that is cheating, right?
Scott: But in a video game there isn't necessarily a comprehensive rule book.
Scott: I mean something like civilization 2 back in the day came with a big old rule book with all the rules in it.
Scott: But you know a modern video games don't come with dick for dick.
Scott: Maybe they'll come with a PDF manual if you're lucky, right?
Scott: so the rules of a video game are the source code of the video game and Therefore if you do not modify the source code of the video game It is impossible.
Scott: and the game, you know, this obviously cheat modes that are in the game, you know They're either labeled cheating.
Scott: So those are obviously a separate thing You know.
Rym: are they though because they're straight-up part of the game.
Rym: I can do it.
Scott: They are part of the game.
Rym: those got if you're going by that logic.
Rym: All right I don't have to modify the source code of counter-strike to use an aimbot.
Rym: In fact, I could use an aimbot that just watches what comes out of the game and then directs inputs into the game.
Scott: That is true.
Rym: Is that cheating then by your definition?
Scott: I would actually say it is not cheating But what it is is you are not actually playing.
Scott: some computer program is playing in your stead.
Scott: All right It's a completely different thing.
Scott: You're not cheating at the game.
Scott: You're not breaking the rules of the game.
Scott: What you're doing is you're not playing.
Scott: someone else is playing for you.
Scott: Some computer program is playing the game.
Scott: I would make the argument that at least if you make the argument that that no I mean bot is cheating then you have to also beat.
Scott: make the argument that just a bot is cheating if you play against bots.
Rym: No, what I would argue is that colloquially I think it is more useful to apply the broad term cheating to that situation.
Rym: Perhaps because if someone if I'm playing quake 3 and I just have an aimbot or whatever I hit middle mouse it just puts the pointer on the head of the nearest person.
Rym: in my sights That's cheating.
Scott: Oh Hey, if it's not modifying the source code of the game, you're not breaking the rules.
Rym: I Disagree with that.
Scott: You're just not playing.
Scott: some very good computer is playing instead of you.
Rym: But Scott, I think it's a pointless distinction.
Scott: Yeah, I think it's a useful distinction now because part of it is that.
Rym: how is it actually useful though?
Scott: Well, because you're still playing quake 3 you're not you're not, you know doing anything.
Scott: That's like otherwise, you know If some guys rocketing around without taking damage when he should be that's cheating.
Rym: By the same token One of the implied ideas of playing a game like this, especially, you know A multiplayer online game is that you are the person you say you are that I am playing.
Rym: I am Rym Rym is playing.
Rym: if I'm using an aimbot I am cheating and that I am saying that I am Rym But I'm not Rym.
Scott: Well, you might be lying right and you know, you could not you know Legally attribute the victories and losses.
Rym: There's basically practically zero cheating in any multiplayer game in the world.
Scott: No, most cheating is modification of source code.
Scott: No, it really isn't.
Scott: Yeah, it is.
Rym: So what names and cheating then like all the counter-strike aimbots?
Scott: They you know, they they they they don't.
Scott: they don't work the way you you know.
Scott: They don't look at the screen and then move the mouse.
Rym: But how is that a useful distinction?
Scott: Because you're you're either breaking the rules of the game or you're not.
Scott: it's you know It's something that looks at the screen and then moves the mouse.
Scott: It's not breaking the rules of the game It's not doing anything that is outside the bounds of what is allowed by the rule book.
Rym: Alright, so name a non FPS example of cheating.
Scott: then a non FPS example of cheating.
Rym: Yes Because I think your definition is so narrow as to be useless.
Scott: you play Yahtzee You roll the dice and then you just turn them all to six and you say look at video game.
Scott: Oh in a video game because this is where your definition I think breaks down a video game example of cheating.
Scott: That's not an FPS.
Scott: You just give you you hack the game to give yourself like a million gold.
Scott: and who does that of a star?
Rym: competitive multiplayer games?
Rym: And a competitive multiplayer game because that's the only place for cheating matters.
Rym: you're cheating in a single-player game.
Rym: great.
Scott: Yeah Does it really happen?
Rym: and colloquially who is going to argue that an aimbot is not cheating?
Scott: Yeah, well, it depends on the most aim.
Scott: bots are cheating.
Scott: They're not using the non cheating method that you just describe.
Rym: It wouldn't be that hard to make an aimbot that just.
Rym: basically I have to change some arbitrary parameters.
Rym: It does the exact same thing and suddenly it's not cheating because of some semantic BS.
Scott: No a name by the didn't cheat.
Scott: you need like a camera looking at your monitor.
Rym: No, not even that.
Rym: I could just and I could have a program that sits in like in line Analyzes what the video card is doing and then makes decisions.
Rym: I'm not modifying the game I'm just reading the information the game has and they so it.
Scott: basically you're.
Scott: yeah, you're just connecting the video output to the best input.
Rym: I'm not modifying the source code.
Rym: What if I have something that just reads all of the games RAM in real time and Then just gives me all this extra information from the RAM?
Rym: I'm not modifying anything.
Rym: The information is clearly available technologically.
Rym: the source code.
Rym: lets me read it.
Rym: Yeah So so there's basically nothing is cheating.
Rym: Yeah, so the definition is basically useless.
Scott: It's not useless.
Rym: I think it's useless.
Scott: No anyway Anyway, so the thing is right we talked about.
Scott: you know, cheating is breaking the rules of a game.
Scott: and you see this guy He's playing a city of heroes.
Scott: He's not breaking the rules of the game in any way whatsoever.
Scott: Everything he does is perfectly in line with the rules of the game, you know, everything that he does is pretty.
Scott: no It's the game.
Scott: lets him do it.
Rym: Yeah, I just think I think your extreme example is useless.
Rym: I mean a good example of this I think would be I used to play weapons factory.
Rym: You know, there was the successor to Team Fortress.
Rym: It was the quake 2 mod versus capture.
Rym: the flag classes recalls all that stuff.
Rym: and there used to be flash grenades And they were great.
Rym: They were too great.
Rym: They blinded you for like 20 seconds.
Rym: That's way too long and I care you could carry like 15 of them at a time.
Rym: That's just the problem with game being bad and the recon could fly but people didn't really use them that much.
Rym: So one day I'm bass ackwards one of my favorite maps me and my friend Ken.
Rym: we decided hey, let's win the game Let's just win this game for the clan.
Rym: So what we did is we were both recon's.
Rym: we flew to the enemy base and in the enemy base was the flag thing.
Rym: But we didn't even bother capping.
Rym: There was also a button hidden in the wall.
Rym: That was known.
Rym: It was part of the map.
Rym: You could hit this button and is the equivalent of a field goal.
Rym: So you'd get you know, like a hundred two hundred points for capturing the flag.
Rym: You'd get like three points if you hit this button and you could hit it every like 30 seconds In the enemy base, it was basically the tiebreaker, you know, I can't catch the flag, but I run in here and hit this button.
Scott: Oh, that's pretty good.
Rym: We went in there and we had an engineer outside who basically provided us with ammo forever.
Rym: He was hiding and I flew around the top dropping a flash bomb every 20 seconds.
Rym: very meanwhile Ken would swoop down hit the button and Then every minute or so we'd switch it up and then we'd periodically swap out and one of us go get ammo and come back And we basically kept the entire enemy team blind and stupid for the entire map and we won on nothing but field goals.
Scott: There you go.
Rym: I was Banned from a couple servers for it.
Rym: I was hated forever and not that long after they ended up removing flash from the game.
Scott: There you go See, I mean, you know, there are many games that have problems.
Scott: I mean that's directly in line with you know, the the snaking in Mario Kart DS, right?
Scott: It's something that you know, you know, even if you might call it a glitch right the minus world in Mario one or something Something that was not intended.
Scott: right it, you know, there are plenty of games out there that have bad rules.
Scott: I mean look at you know stuff in like D&D third edition, you know, they wrote it right into the rule book.
Scott: You got the 10-foot reach and the whole thing.
Scott: You could hit him and take a step back and hit him and take a step back and they can't hit you.
Rym: Well, this is the real situation.
Rym: they could the conflation between cheating and just being good at a game.
Rym: Yeah, because I've been kicked from servers in the past and so is Scott and I'm sure a lot of you have Before being accused of cheating when in fact, no, I was just really good.
Rym: I mean, I've gotten headshots that were improbable, but they were legitimate headshots.
Rym: I was kicked for being in anybody even though I wasn't but Especially with games that involve that are complex or games that involve there when there were many different strategies You can employ a lot of times, you know A smart player will identify the most effective strategies and if there is a strategy that is greatly more effective than any other strategy You're a fool to not use it in my opinion because now you're basically violating your own utility.
Rym: You're breaking your cognitive dissonance of.
Rym: you could win.
Rym: It's like playing poker and you have a royal flush, but you decide it's unfair that you have a royal flush So you decide to fold anyway, yeah, or you don't go all-in.
Rym: you say you know what?
Rym: I'm not gonna go all-in cuz that's mean.
Scott: Well, it's it's you know, it's that's not cheating.
Scott: It's what's called cheap, right?
Scott: People think it's cheap.
Scott: Well,
Rym: no, that's what I'm saying that that's the much more interesting argument that people perceive things as being unfair in games But oftentimes what they perceive as being unfair is just a strategy They're unwilling or unable to employ that is far more effective than the one that they themselves employ.
Scott: Yeah, I think the thing is if a game has a cheap strategy available And the reason a strategy is cheap right is not just because it's extremely effective and you win It's also because it's relatively trivial to employ.
Scott: I mean really people don't have a problem if there's a game that has a very powerful strategy that is difficult to employ.
Rym: Look at snaking.
Scott: snaking on it's not that difficult.
Rym: It was difficult on any but there were a few maps It was easy on.
Scott: but it's much more difficult to say Hit all of the shortcuts with precise timing.
Scott: that it is to snake down the straightaways You know.
Scott: yet going down all the shortcuts with the precise timing is much more difficult than staking down the straightaways You know, so it's a matter of.
Rym: but if if a strategy is so trivial then everyone could do it So that means that someone is choosing not to use an optimal obvious strategy, of course I mean look at an example of having no cheapness right.
Scott: look at what do we play?
Scott: We just played power grid.
Scott: right.
Scott: and power grid, you know, some power plants are better than others.
Scott: But the better power plants are more expensive.
Scott: that the awesome fusion power plant is minimum $50 50 electro.
Scott: Sorry, right if the 50, you know if the fusion power plant was one electro It would be cheap.
Scott: It wouldn't be cheating.
Scott: It would just be a bad game that had these cheap and effect, you know effective things in it.
Scott: So if a game has something that could be considered cheating, you know some strategy that just dominates that's trivial to employ.
Scott: Yeah, and people consider it cheating, but it's not.
Scott: it's perfectly in line with the rules.
Scott: It's just a bad game that has cheap things in it.
Scott: well
Rym: one thing I do I do find interesting is that the thing that people that Cheating is pretty much come down to online as far as I can see what people complain about the most and say is cheating the most Are people who buy gold or gold farm or use bots to get experience in MMOs?
Rym: It seems like that is the the quote unquote Cheating that most of the internet is most in an uproar about even though I don't consider it cheating.
Scott: Yeah well that is one problem I have with MMOs and some other games online.
Scott: a lot is They like to enforce a lot of rules outside of the source code, right?
Scott: Like, you know, for example I remember reading something way back in the early days of Wow about some people who were like able to get up on the roofs Of some buildings and then shoot people from above and they couldn't.
Scott: no one could shoot back and they killed a bunch of people from Above right and and then they got banned or something It's like your code.
Scott: let them get up on the roof and let them do that.
Scott: They weren't?
Scott: you know?
Rym: They didn't hack the game plus stuff like that brings forth some of the coolest and most fun things in MMOs.
Rym: The best memories I have are when someone figured out something crazy you could do and then the game world went crazy for a few Days until the admins like wait a minute.
Rym: Okay, something's going on here But rather than banning all the people involved the best way to handle it was to do something clever Or equally clever to fix it, you know.
Rym: say people are getting on the roofs and doing something like that.
Scott: Introduce some monsters that fly around and eat people on the roofs or maybe Let them fix it So that people on the ground can shoot back or fix this and no one get on the roofs anymore.
Scott: or you know Don't go doing you know, just bullshit just smacking people down for being awesome.
Rym: or look at the the ever famous the the murder of Lord British Exactly.
Rym: That was one of the most epic moments in MMOs ever.
Rym: I mean, I still know people who to this day are like I was there.
Rym: I was there when Lord British died and it was crazy and the internet went nuts about it and it was super awesome and They basically reacted to it in the absolute worst possible way.
Rym: if they'd been cool They would have just made the game world be like, all right, Lord British is dead.
Rym: You assholes brought this on yourselves.
Rym: Yeah made bad shit happen and then they could have had some sort of cool story arc.
Scott: and then Lord British is keeping out the bad guys.
Rym: Have Lord British come back or have some like gigantic final quest in the game to bring him back from the dead?
Rym: You know some be British.
Rym: you can sum it up pretty simply solve in-game problems in-game.
Rym: Don't solve them out of game because all you do is make your game crap.
Scott: Yep, and likewise it goes in the reverse direction right looking like some house rules like Monopoly.
Scott: We always talk about the free parking and the money in the middle, right?
Scott: If you even know everyone agrees to do that, don't do that.
Scott: You're all cheating all of you.
Scott: everyone in the game is cheating.
Rym: Can you call it cheating if all the players in a game agree to a set of rules and a set of utility?
Scott: Well, yes You.
Scott: if you don't want to call it cheating you at least have to agree that you're not playing Monopoly you're playing something.
Rym: I think it's just a semantic point at that.
Scott: I think it's important.
Scott: I don't think it matters because you get young because you get someone will come up and be like, oh, I'm so great at Monopoly.
Scott: It's like yeah, let's put some money in the middle way.
Scott: You're not playing monopolies here.
Scott: You're great at something else You know, you're great at being lucky at landing.
Scott: every parking is what you're great at, you know.
Rym: But that somehow without that monopoly is still a skill based game.
Scott: I didn't say monopoly is skill based game.
Scott: Monopoly is just a real example because a good example for this kind of stuff because people know the rules of it and how it Works generally.
Rym: I mean the only problem I see there and it's always solved socially.
Rym: if you play with people and some people Don't know the rules because they've been playing the game wrong and you either don't play with those people Force them to play the right rules agree to a house rule.
Rym: That's not really a concern.
Scott: Well, it's not.
Scott: I mean cheating.
Scott: the thing is, you know people tend to think of cheating is something that just you know Makes the ruins the game.
Scott: I think there's a lot of cheating that isn't a concern, but it's still cheating, you know, semantically speaking You know like take for example this right you look we were talking the other day about jigaboo Jones.
Scott: Right, you know the guy who can pretty much.
Scott: if you give him two casino dice He can roll whatever the hell he wants Right, and we talked about well if you're playing burning wheel right nowhere in the burning wheel rule book Does it really explicitly say that?
Scott: You know, I mean look at craps as very specific rules about rolling the dice has to bounce so many times It has to hit the opposite wall right.
Scott: burning wheel doesn't really specify how the dice had to be rolled.
Scott: It just says roll dice.
Scott: So jigaboo Jones playing burning wheel could make just sixes show up.
Scott: you could roll one dice get a six to show up every time Use a fate point and basically roll in a million successes and He would win whatever he wanted to.
Scott: and you know This question of is it cheating came up for him to do that and there's a couple of valid arguments.
Scott: one Is that there's sort of this implication that when you roll the dice?
Scott: You're supposed to roll them and it should be random and that jigaboo Jones is clearly not random.
Scott: He's just.
Scott: you know, he can fix dice because he has skills.
Scott: The.
Scott: the other argument was you know burning wheel?
Scott: really it's like sure get all successes.
Scott: occasionally You're gonna want some failures.
Scott: You're actually you know, in some ways you're making the game worse for yourself.
Scott: You're not really, you know, you can't make the game better by fixing the results of the dice You're just making the game well different.
Rym: What came out of that conversation to me was this whole you could make an interesting game.
Rym: I like the idea now of some sort of Role-playing game where the system for resolving conflicts is some sort of game of strength and or dexterity Mmm, some sort of like maybe a Mario Party minigame.
Scott: you play pick-up sticks to determine who wins a duel of it Something like that something you could practice outside again.
Rym: I just have this vague concept of you could.
Rym: I think you could make something strange and unique and interesting.
Scott: What's the game from?
Scott: Prince of Nothing Bajunka.
Scott: you could play some bajunka Or you could like how about?
Scott: you know, you could like lay a ghost stone and you know as part of the game something like that.
Rym: Well in that case it really just comes down to Blue crane in writing burning wheel did not even consider the possibility of someone learning how to toss dice.
Rym: Nope, so if you asked him you would probably say yeah, that's pretty stupid.
Rym: if you do that and that you know you enforce that Socially, which is just what they did against the guy.
Scott: but right but isn't enforcing that socially Basically the same as getting the guys off the roof?
Scott: and Wow You're socially enforcing a rule rather than you know, putting it in the code or in the rule book?
Rym: Yep it is and that's why you house rules come down to.
Rym: everyone agrees to the rules and you don't play with people who don't agree with the rules.
Rym: if you're playing D&D and you have all these beer and pretzels house rules as long as everyone in the game is aware of and agrees to them, that's great.
Rym: and The problem with an MMO is that the only rules everyone agreed to when they played are the rules that are the source code and the rules in the TOS.
Rym: so as a result You you can't unless you're violating one of those two things directly.
Rym: You're not really violating the social contract as far as I see because in MMO The coolest thing about MMOs is that they're a microcosm of the real world and in the real world Say I'm country a and I want to do something and country B wants to stop me.
Rym: if I have a bigger army than country A there's no game master to say hey, you can't invade country B. I just do it.
Rym: Yep, and I like the idea that If you want to enforce non written rules in an MMO or a game like that You have to enforce them in the game within the context of the game.
Rym: So the whole let's all get together and beat him, you know gang up on him South Park style is a fantastic response.
Rym: The fact that they couldn't beat him was just hilarious.
Rym: Yeah, yeah And burning wheel.
Rym: it just comes down to the fact that everyone in the group agrees.
Rym: if if you learned how to toss sixes And you can reliably toss sixes and you didn't agree to using a dice cup.
Rym: We just kick you out of our burning wheel game.
Scott: Yeah, there's other things, you know, there's nothing you know.
Scott: dice cup isn't you know?
Scott: Not allowed by the rules you could definitely force people to use cheating.
Rym: It's all.
Rym: I would say that realistically something is only cheating if it is a is either.
Rym: again It's against the stated accepted rules of the game that have been agreed to by all players in the game Mm-hmm.
Scott: Yeah, there's also something to think about.
Scott: right as you look at something like say D&D right where it is There's nominally this game master who decides the rules.
Rym: the best game masters Just make shit up all the time in D&D because you have to so right.
Scott: So but they make all this shit up or they maybe they enforce rules that aren't even in the book and all this stuff.
Scott: Are they game masters in a way cheating you see?
Rym: Well in a game like that it again comes down to What's the most enjoyable experience for the players?
Rym: Mm-hmm as a whole.
Rym: there's also to consider, you know any consent of everyone playing under a game master Implicitly agrees to the.
Rym: you know, however that they got game master style of play Whatever he does.
Rym: That's why I'm playing in his game and not Joey Jojo's game.
Scott: There's also stuff to think about like referees right like look at basketball or or soccer.
Scott: There's a you know, certain sports or hockey.
Scott: There's a lot of subjective rules, you know, maybe the ref didn't see the hook.
Scott: Maybe you know the ref thinks that's a foul.
Scott: It wasn't a friend then.
Rym: that's a metagame and that is part of the game.
Rym: I mean a valid strategy in hockey is hit him when the refs not looking.
Scott: It's a very good strategy.
Scott: hit him when the refs not looking.
Rym: and again things like that.
Rym: Or were some of the greatest most amazing moments in gaming and sports.
Rym: and everything come from where someone pulls the crazy trick play.
Rym: That was technically correct.
Rym: Technically.
Rym: Okay the best kind of okay Mmm, and in video games the same thing, you know when someone pulls off some crazy stunt that no one thought was possible and kills Lord British how awesome is that?
Rym: and then just respond to it in an intelligent and equally clever way and everything works out in the Well, how about like, you know, do you actually cheat and anything ever?
Rym: I've the only game I cheat at and I still cheat at it to this day.
Scott: is you correct?
Rym: It's Euchre because Euchre is a stupid get.
Rym: Euchre is a memorized game.
Rym: I'm a perfect Euchre player.
Rym: It's not hard to be a perfect Euchre player.
Rym: So the real game is how much table talk and you get away with before you're called on it.
Rym: How much can you stack the deck?
Rym: and in high school?
Rym: We played Euchre very pointedly.
Rym: Everyone was constantly trying to cheat.
Rym: Oh Directly they were trying to stack the deck.
Rym: They're trying to slip cards around and that in itself was the game.
Rym: We we were playing a game where we agreed that everyone was going to try to cheat to the best of their ability Mm-hmm, and it was super awesome as a result.
Scott: Well, how about like when I was playing citadels that one time and Basically, I took the cards.
Scott: I would pick a roll.
Scott: I would hand them to you Unshuffled.
Scott: you would fan them out and select one and I all had to do is look at them while you fanned them and select.
Scott: Now I remembered what order they were in when I handed them to you.
Rym: I do not consider that cheating because again extent meta information.
Rym: It's one thing.
Rym: if I look over your screen and teeny and see your time that is clearly cheating.
Rym: But if I have not moved myself in any way I'm Sitting unmoving with blinders on and you happen to get up and knock your screen over and I see that you have no red tiles.
Rym: I'm pretty much obligated to use that information against you.
Scott: Yeah, but doesn't it in also some way?
Scott: it's not necessarily cheating because it wasn't your intent action to break the rules But the rules are sort of broken by accident in the same time.
Scott: It's almost like a game glitch.
Scott: So even though if you have cannot be blamed for the cheating and you of course would have to be expected to act on this information you could in a Justifiably asterisk the game.
Rym: but the real answer is if anything happens at all you have to ask her as the game You could keep playing or not, but the game is immediately asterisk.
Rym: But at the same time the asterisk comes automatically because I can't unsee what has been seen.
Rym: Of course you cannot unsee and I cannot act as though I have not seen because I have seen.
Rym: I cannot discount the Information because the information is there.
Rym: and even if I tried to discount it Like maybe I would have attacked even though I didn't know what your cards were.
Rym: Maybe I had a 60% chance now.
Rym: I have a hundred percent chance, you know that sort of thing.
Rym: And also the situation where I used to do this a lot to you where if you would always stack your tiles up in T&E Behind your screen.
Rym: I couldn't see the tiles But I noticed that you've ever had a stack of three or more.
Rym: When you were going for cut tiles of that color you would reach at it from the top with your fingers But if it was a small stack of like one you would come at it from the side.
Rym: It was the subconscious thing and it was reliable and I used it to great effect because it was always right and I would always Know if you had three or less of a tile.
Rym: Yeah And eventually you stop doing that because I pointed it out.
Rym: But I don't think that was cheating any more than reading someone's poker tell is cheating.
Scott: Mm-hmm Yeah, but it's straight, you know It's like all these sort of meta game.
Scott: things right can help you do things in the game that you're not breaking any rules Of the game, but in a way you are breaking the intent of the game, you know It's like the game intends for that information to be secret.
Scott: yet You are discovering that information by accident or by on purpose
Rym: at the same time through means
Scott: that are not breaking anything
Rym: much more real-world scenario because in the real world there is all this extent information and an intelligent person cannot ignore extent information and Succeed reliably over time.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and you're doing yourself a disservice to ignore extent information.
Rym: I use that word a lot when we play board games.
Rym: Scott has a terrible difficulty in keeping all of it together in some games.
Scott: Well, let's talk about right.
Scott: What do you do if you're playing a game right and I say a board game just because it's more of a social
Rym: And I fuck up on my own and no one knows
Scott: No, and there's someone who's actually like a cheater like you go to a convention and there's someone who's like, you know They're trying to cheat to win.
Rym: it's very very simple and I use this policy universally.
Scott: if I'm playing a board game and Someone cheats like actually cheating like there is monopoly and they're just taking money out of the bank And I catch them cheating.
Rym: I call them on it immediately with proof And if they don't admit to it, I end the game and died.
Rym: they're done.
Rym: I don't want to play with them again.
Rym: That's it.
Scott: What if you do that?
Scott: You're wrong.
Rym: Well one I wouldn't do that.
Rym: Unless I had proof.
Rym: Of course not Suspect somebody kind of awkward if I said but then again the way I play board games It's very obvious if someone is cheating and if I know someone is cheating.
Rym: based on that All I have to do is wait for the the point at which there is a reliable audit trail because most board games Have a pretty good audit trail to where you can count back turns and determine, you know He couldn't have moved more than X spaces and still have more than Y resources left.
Rym: Hey, he has Z resources.
Rym: That's impossible.
Rym: He cheated Mmm, he might have made a mistake and that's the point.
Rym: you call him on it and then you know you go from there.
Rym: But yeah I basically I will end a game immediately if someone has cheated and I will refuse to continue to play a game if someone cheated Mm-hmm.
Scott: Is there you know, is there any real like excuse for someone is cheating?
Rym: Never.
Scott: No?
Scott: No.
Scott: You don't think so?
Rym: I don't think so.
Scott: There's no good reason to like go and break the rules.
Rym: Well, suppose your daughter was kidnapped Okay, and you're playing and the guy says beat me in Puerto Rico and I won't murder her.
Scott: Well, cuz I mean, you know you talk about stuff, you know You look at like some of those mahjong shows and gambling and manga.
Rym: Well, see that's the situation.
Rym: There are games like that where there are real-world situations independent of games where
Scott: Cheating
Rym: as in going against the rules of something the implied rules the written rules Whatever is in your personal best interest and that brings up the the same thing of enforcing game stuff in game in the real world.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: The rules are physics.
Rym: Yep And if I do if you violate physics you are cheating.
Rym: that is the only way to cheat in the real world.
Rym: Really?
Rym: Mmm, so if I can get away with it It wasn't cheating and Society may impose based on the power they have over me some punishment for the fact.
Rym: some slight You know I've broken a rule that society agreed upon.
Scott: Society can punish me if that's just something that they're choosing to do also within the laws of physics.
Rym: That is just.
Rym: it's Hannibal Lecter situation where if someone Cannot be punished by society because society has no power over them Then they can get away with a lot and basically do whatever they want and they have transcended humanity.
Rym: They're a transhuman and they probably need people.
Rym: and I'm not advocating that people should do these sorts of things because I like all good People have an ethical and moral code but at the same time cheating is in the real world.
Rym: is this really strange?
Rym: long sliding subjective scale and cheating in what there's no such thing as absolute cheating because breaking the rules of a game is only Cheating if it can be enforced by the rules of the world.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it's your.
Scott: it's like, you know, we in the in the real world, right?
Scott: It's like no matter what anyone thinks you can't you know Scott?
Scott: look make something for nothing.
Scott: It's the laws of physics.
Rym: in a way the speed limit on the road outside our house is 15 miles an hour according to that Sign.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Have you ever Seen anyone drive 15 miles an hour.
Scott: They did it a few times for lulls.
Rym: I actually I do it every day because it's hilarious.
Scott: Yeah, no, but you know the laws of physics.
Scott: You just can't break them.
Scott: You know, we can't do anything that breaks the laws of physics.
Scott: But in a board game the rules are just on paper.
Scott: They're not actually physically enforced unless you know, you have some perfectly coded video game that you know You didn't modify in any way in which case the rules are physically enforced.
Rym: Now the real.
Rym: the other issue too is some game like I see some people discussing some games.
Rym: they they'll rate a game not just based on skill or lock or theme or any of those things but based on the Ability of players to cheat without being caught and how enforceable the rules are in a game.
Rym: because some games have very Unenforceable rules.
Scott: that's true some games and it's like you look at something like say You know T&E I could just draw a tiles and always have two extra tiles in the crib.
Scott: Yep And nobody would really know unless they counted like the tiles in the bag or something Which is against the rules to count the tiles in the bag.
Rym: Well, what you could do is have a in a tournament situation.
Rym: what I would do?
Scott: have someone looking over everyone.
Rym: You know every round at the beginning and end of a round players would have to flip all their tiles over Hide their score and turn over their screen.
Rym: That's not bad and show all of their face.
Scott: Oh, what if I just kept the tile up my sleeve?
Rym: Well, yeah, but that everyone else wear short sleeves.
Scott: I kept it in my pants.
Rym: No pants.
Scott: I have slayed a hand.
Rym: no hands.
Rym: You stand behind lose sight and you direct other people with notes that you press up to the glass.
Rym: But I Got my take on that is that if that's even a concern for you your friends are all douchebags.
Rym: You shouldn't be playing games with them.
Rym: Yeah, it is never in my life than a concern that any of my friends would ever cheat at a board game.
Scott: I mean, it's actually sort of fun because always like if someone's doing well be like you cheater you're cheating Like.
Scott: we accuse people of cheating sort of sarcastically all the time, but no one ever actually intentionally cheats now Occasionally sometimes, you know, there's of course asterisk, but there are also situations in which you know, someone will maybe forget to do something or They'll do something incorrectly Accidentally, right like.
Rym: maybe it's rare that it goes unnoticed just because bored German style board games tend to be so just number heavy And we're all Concentrating and analyzing so much that everyone's counting everything all the time like three people out of five.
Rym: Well, pretty much immediately notice any discrepancy on the board at any given time.
Rym: Yep Like hey, there's only two rocks on the rock thing.
Rym: There should be three because the rock thing came out two turns ago.
Rym: Someone forgot to take a rock lava block.
Scott: I think it's actually really cool.
Scott: when you have some of the cool video games.
Scott: I actually keep a log of the whole game like Wesnoth you can play back the whole game.
Scott: Yeah stuff like that is really cool.
Scott: Because if there's any discrepancy, you know, you can see it somewhere in the game law.
Rym: or like Dracula It has that great mechanic of the whole game is enforced by the cards.
Rym: You're putting down Dracula.
Scott: Here's that son to talk about right?
Scott: Let's talk about Dracula and Illuminati because those are interesting games.
Scott: when it comes to cheating Dracula had the.
Scott: What's the game actually called furry of Dracula?
Rym: Fury of Dracula.
Scott: actually, you know, the game has as a cheating rule.
Rym: Well, here's the thing.
Rym: games It's the same as Java.
Rym: you had.
Rym: you have the exception.
Rym: the game will throw an exception if something outside the rules happens.
Rym: If you don't handle that exception the game crashes right like Tigris in Euphrates.
Scott: someone cheats, right?
Rym: There's no way to recover.
Scott: There's no way to like fix the game.
Scott: The game's just screwed up.
Scott: It's over right.
Scott: but in Furry of Dracula if someone cheats the instruction book says, you know If Dracula cheats then this happens and it's very because Dracula is all alone.
Scott: No one's allowed to look at what he's doing.
Scott: so it's very possible for Dracula To do things in his hidden movement that are not legitimate.
Scott: He can just move all the way across the board and try to cheat.
Scott: Right, but he can also be caught.
Scott: and if he's caught cheating then certain things happen that are very bad for drag.
Scott: Well part of the reason.
Scott: at the same time That's sort of right.
Scott: having that rule on the one hand makes it so that the game is not gonna get screwed up.
Scott: Right if Dracula accidentally or intentionally cheats right the game can continue and it'll be okay.
Scott: But in a way that sort of encourages Dracula to try to cheat and get away with it.
Rym: Well, it luckily it's difficult for him to do so.
Scott: it is very difficult to do So.
Rym: I think that's just a situation of you.
Rym: I think my Java exception analogy is probably the best one.
Rym: Good games.
Rym: I've noticed have started to include Ways to handle anomalous situations such that you can continue to play the game Like we've seen other games where they have a rule.
Rym: for what if some player just up and quits near the end of the game?
Rym: Well, this is that and then continue.
Rym: Mm-hmm And that also prevents the game from crashing.
Rym: and like Euchre we did the same thing.
Rym: You know when I said our friends all cheated the.
Rym: in the way most people play Euchre There's the the renege and all the sorts of things that if you screw this up and you're caught The other team gets two points.
Rym: you all this sort of stuff to just make the game continue to play Because in the Wild West rules, there's no rule for it.
Rym: If someone cheats the cards, what do you do?
Rym: You either say damn it you cheated or you shoot him in the face.
Scott: Yeah, no, but Illuminati actually has the cheating rule is try to cheat and don't get gone.
Rym: I know Illuminati has two modes of play don't cheat try to cheat.
Rym: And the cheating game has rules for cheating and basically it specifies you are allowed to cheat in these areas.
Rym: You're not allowed to cheat in these areas.
Rym: Here's what it happens if someone catches you cheating.
Scott: Yeah, what it really does see they call it cheating.
Scott: But what it really is?
Scott: it says, okay You are allowed to break these rules right and in a time as long as you aren't caught.
Scott: So really all it's doing is just adding Extra things to the game in terms of you know Making sleight of hand skills and distractive skills sort of count that otherwise don't count and it allows you to use You know different abilities in different ways.
Scott: It's kind of.
Scott: it's kind of interesting, you know, it's like normally, you know You just you wouldn't do those things at all or if you did them your game would be fucked up.
Scott: But Illuminati, you know, they explicitly tell you to try to do those things and as long as you don't get caught That's that's kind of interesting.
Scott: it's like hey play Illuminati, but also play they don't get caught game.
Rym: Yep, now along those lines you ever heard of the situation where you accidentally cheated at a game?
Scott: Sometimes?
Scott: well, I never actually cheated.
Rym: but where it looks you look down and you're like, alright I took one too many tiles.
Rym: I have seven tiles.
Rym: It's teeny.
Rym: Oh shit.
Scott: Yeah, or oops I made the change and properly have to give some back or you know, oops Sure that I have supposed to have that many.
Rym: the way I handle it is if it's something that can't affect another player and Can't like it's not something that can affect the game directly.
Rym: I will always go with the root of do whatever Resolution is the most harmful to me.
Rym: Yeah, like if I'm not like if I accidentally like if I'm not sure whether or not I took my victory points for the bath My dad in the previous turn.
Rym: I just don't take it's like.
Rym: well, I don't know if I took it or not So I can't take it.
Rym: Yep a best case.
Rym: I'm I'm fine worst case.
Rym: I'm down.
Scott: one point like oh Did I did I collect my money for the that income there?
Scott: Oh, I forget if I collected it or not.
Scott: Uh, I just won't collect it, you know, if you collect it well, then maybe you collect too much.
Scott: But if you don't collect it Well, then you know, maybe you don't maybe you didn't collect enough and maybe that would have helped you win.
Scott: But at least this way, you know, you're sort of cheating to harm yourself in a way rather than cheating to help yourself.
Scott: Yep, I mean, you know, it's like I guess in some games, you know taking less money might be an advantage.
Scott: Do you get this game has some sort of tax mechanic or something?
Scott: But you know in most games, you know No one's gonna complain if you cheat to bring yourself down And farther away from winning.
Rym: but the most even then in that situation anytime I've screwed up a rule.
Rym: I think anyone who plays games should do this.
Rym: You just you kind of say hey everybody I screwed this up.
Rym: Here's what I did.
Rym: How do we resolve this?
Rym: to continue playing the game?
Rym: Yeah, I accidentally have seven tiles.
Rym: How about I flip them all over and someone randomly take one out right now and throw it away, you know, something like that?
Rym: Yep,
Scott: it's not a bad idea
Rym: Yeah, but I I also I want to get back to burning wheel because we talked earlier about well
Scott: burning wheel I also I was the one other I think I had to say about it was that it actually says in the rule book like Hey, don't worry.
Scott: If you screw up some rules sometimes, you know, there's so many rules here.
Scott: No one's perfect.
Scott: Just you know, if you screw something up, maybe you won't notice it.
Scott: But if you do notice it don't try to fix it just make a note of it.
Scott: So you don't screw it up next time and continue, you know, and that's sort of like hey, you know that the strict rules Lawyeriness is not the biggest deal in burning wheel.
Scott: having a good time is the biggest deal and you know That's appropriate as burning wheel as a role-playing storytelling game and not a winning losing game.
Scott: But in a winning losing game, you couldn't have that kind of rule.
Scott: It wouldn't work out at all.
Rym: But I mean look at this is why burning wheel is so special.
Rym: because in games a lot of role-playing style games There's the whole meta game where you know my character doesn't know something but I know it and DMS always have to deal with the problem of a player will have their character act in a certain way that they wouldn't have normally done because The person playing the character knows something they saw on the other person's character sheet that sort of thing.
Rym: and The reason I love burning real so much is that the game is designed to encourage you to do that and that by doing That the game will be better.
Scott: Mmm that doing the meta stuff by very things I would like some be considered cheating actually make the game better.
Scott: Yes, so doing everything you possibly can to get your way can only improve the game and cannot worsen it.
Rym: Do we have anything else to say?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: We had a lot of stuff.
Rym: Cheated games.
Rym: gold farming isn't cheating because it doesn't hurt anyone but no one.
Scott: Yeah, cheating pretty much, you know Depending on your definition of cheating if you agree with me or Rym I think we both agree that you know cheating is you know, whether it's cheating or not It's only wrong if you're you know, breaking the rules to get an unfair advantage and you ruin the game for other people.
Scott: That's that's the big deal.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front road crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.