Rym: It's Tuesday, June 23rd.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is Geek Nodz.
Rym: Tonight...
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So this weekend was a burning weekend.
Rym: We got the crew together, played our burning wheel.
Rym: We finally dropped that long-running Epic Roman politics campaign to play something more birthed in burning wheel as opposed to originally birthed in D&D.
Rym: I think it worked really well.
Scott: Yeah, it was a pretty good game going on.
Scott: I just I wish I wasn't so humid and I didn't get a headache and sort of pass out.
Rym: I felt so bad for Scott.
Rym: The game was going strong and he was being all spidery and then about halfway through he kind of laid down and never got that guy.
Scott: It's like I was like I was.
Scott: I was like I don't want to lay down.
Scott: I shouldn't lay down.
Scott: I know laying down is like you know the bad move.
Scott: But it was just so bleh and Alex.
Scott: I know he has that really powerful air conditioner.
Scott: That would have worked.
Scott: He just didn't want to put it in.
Rym: You know he never uses that thing.
Rym: I'm surprised.
Scott: The thing is so so Ridiculously powerful and has so many BTUs.
Scott: It would have been fun, but he didn't use it.
Scott: And so you know not even just because of the heat I was feeling bleh earlier, and it was just compounding my bleh, but I had probably the best duel of wits I've ever had.
Rym: I used ugly truth.
Rym: I'm proud of that.
Scott: Oh you duel of wits Jess, right?
Scott: Yeah Yeah, I remember that.
Rym: That was pretty epic.
Scott: That was alright.
Rym: But you know after the game the next day we're hanging out with the crew like we always do and you know people leave at different times and half the crew had left and half the crew was still around.
Rym: and Kate and Adam, well Adam, takes the dogs outside for a walk.
Rym: Yeah, you forgot about what happened over the weekend because I was like I got something to talk about and you were like alright I got nothing.
Scott: Yeah, I knew there was something.
Scott: I just couldn't forget what it was.
Rym: So Adam's out there And he yells from the outside downstairs down from the deck.
Rym: Hey, Rym Somebody left an alligator skull down here.
Rym: No, I think it's an entire alligator head.
Scott: What?
Rym: You gotta come see this.
Scott: First of all, we're not in Florida.
Scott: So this makes no sense.
Rym: Second I'm expecting to see like a deer skull or a stick shaped vaguely like an alligator head or I don't know Just a piece of garbage, but I walk out there and I see this thing.
Rym: So I what we go up to it and he's like that's an alligator skull.
Rym: I'm like, I don't know I don't know.
Rym: So he grabs a stick.
Rym: He flips it over.
Rym: It's a fucking alligator head.
Scott: It's not even just the skull It's like the full head.
Scott: It's got an eyeball.
Scott: It's got teeth It's got skin.
Scott: It's got all sorts of business going on.
Scott: It's a full on Alligators head like cut off right behind the eyes.
Rym: It was definitely real too.
Rym: Absolutely It was taxidermy because it had a glass eye, but that was definitely a real alligator.
Scott: Yeah, it was clearly.
Scott: yeah It's like it was so weird.
Scott: It was like, okay.
Scott: There's no way that this is actually a Alligator that died back here because it's not Florida But it was taxidermy.
Scott: alligator head made its way into our backyard And it wasn't like we couldn't find the rest of the alligator.
Rym: Yeah The thing is the head was cut off like sawed off cleanly and the spine and everything was still in there like the spa.
Rym: Oh my god, it was pretty nasty, but it was sawed clean off and the head was facing forward from this old wooden fence.
Rym: So we all kind of climb up onto the fence and look over not really expecting an alligator body But kind of expecting one.
Scott: but there was not an alligator body over there.
Rym: We looked around.
Rym: I went back there later and there's no alligator body.
Scott: It's like how did it get back there?
Scott: It's like our backyard is basically not existed and no one goes back.
Rym: No one goes there had to have been there for the entirety of the years that we've been living here.
Scott: There is no way it was there for the entirety of the year.
Rym: But then how would have gotten there?
Rym: who would have put it there?
Scott: There's no knowing how it got there.
Scott: But regardless there is an alligator head that was in the backyard and we throw it out and I have a pictures of it.
Rym: The neighbor lady comes out and she's like, what are you guys all looking at?
Rym: And we're like, there's an alligator head behind the house and she's like, I don't know anything about that.
Scott: I Think she put it there.
Scott: She's covered it up.
Rym: The fact that it was cut off so cleanly.
Scott: It was very strange Of course.
Rym: the my second thought after that's an alligator head.
Rym: Well, I guess my third thought because my second thought was it has a glass eye.
Rym: the third thought was Draco Litch.
Scott: What?
Rym: Maybe arch Litch?
Scott: my.
Scott: my thought was how the fuck did it get there?
Scott: And I still don't know and I probably never will.
Rym: So that was our weekend burning wheel and an alligator head.
Rym: We took some pictures of it.
Rym: we'll put them online at some point just to prove it.
Rym: No one would believe us unless we had pictures.
Scott: picture didn't happen.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Well, we've got pics.
Rym: it happened.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: So what do you got?
Scott: Alright video games, let's see Hmm.
Scott: Oh, right.
Scott: Well, first of all, I want to say that I thought it was that a real pause.
Rym: or did you actually forget what you were?
Rym: Going to say I didn't forget anything.
Rym: Okay?
Scott: Okay So I system shock 2 is an old game that I know that I never played until now.
Rym: you and our waters boys And I think are playing it up.
Scott: Yeah, cuz it's got co-op, right?
Scott: it's like whoa, this old FPS is co-op and that's kind of.
Scott: what I'm dying for is some cop FPS and the thing is it's mostly a RPG FPS more than a cop FPS.
Scott: but playing it.
Scott: It's like I played Bioshock first.
Scott: So now playing System Shock 2 it's like oh wow Bioshock was a lot more like System Shock 2 than I realized Which you know makes sense, but you know, I didn't under.
Scott: I didn't know the connections because I hadn't played both of them.
Scott: But if you haven't played the System Shock 2 it'll run on pretty much almost any computer that's modern.
Scott: So and you're not gonna be able to buy it legitimately.
Scott: just get it off the Internet's for free.
Scott: it's not difficult.
Scott: and if you can play it co-op.
Scott: and the interesting thing about playing a co-op right is that The game doesn't give you any more stuff.
Scott: So it's like you have to divide the ammo between you know All the people playing evenly which kind of or you can hoard it all if you're a asshole.
Scott: So it kind of sucks in that regard.
Scott: but in terms of you get these upgrade modules as you complete quests and such.
Scott: So you everyone upgrades a whole shit ton.
Scott: So you it's like you're wicked powerful because normally it's like if you're playing the one-player game.
Scott: You'd have to concentrate on say psychic powers or hacking or military skills.
Scott: We're playing.
Scott: I got all the military skills He's got all the hacking skills.
Scott: So it's like hey we We're maxing it out here and it's it's pretty good.
Scott: Yeah, we're almost done, you know, whatever.
Scott: Also this Friday I think if not late Thursday Blood Bowl is coming out for the PC.
Scott: Now here's the story behind this blood bowl.
Scott: way back in the day games workshop the makers of Warhammer made a game called blood bowl.
Scott: And blood bowl, it's football.
Scott: It's a football game, but you kill people.
Scott: so it's sort of like football Warhammer.
Scott: But it was cool because it was like you get all the good of a miniatures Warhammer type game without the collecting miss.
Scott: You just buy this one box.
Scott: it has blood bowl in it and that's it.
Scott: and it was you know But you get it's it's Warhammer like gaming.
Scott: So This they made a warhead a blood bowl video game back in the 90s.
Scott: That was all DOS styling, but then another company Unofficially and illegitimately made a game called chaos league right and they got in trouble.
Scott: They were I got they.
Scott: you can't don't do that.
Scott: But then Unlike every other stupid company in the world They made nice.
Scott: and now the people who made chaos league or obviously blood bowl fans are making the official blood bowl game and it's coming out for the PC on Friday and Not it's all.
Scott: in addition to being you know, having the turn-based blood bowl gameplay It also has a real-time blood bowl gameplay that I assume is more like Madden ish kind of game.
Scott: I don't know The trailer is not really.
Scott: the video trailer is not really helping me out here.
Scott: They're also coming out with DS and PSP blood bowls that are a lot like the original board game.
Scott: So You know the game is kind of expensive to buy the board version.
Scott: It's like $75.
Rym: It's kind of hard to find.
Scott: Oh, no, you can just buy it online easily.
Rym: I don't know at least in person because I remember at RIT You just go to the games workshop store in the city.
Rym: They got true remember at RIT They had like three sets of it at our wag.
Scott: Well millennium had like three sets and they were always just sitting there.
Scott: No one bought it.
Scott: Yeah anyway You got to go to a gaming store to get.
Scott: you're not gonna find it anywhere else.
Rym: It's not gonna be a Toys R Us.
Scott: Yeah, that's for sure.
Scott: But the video game is $50.
Scott: So if you think of it, that's sort of a steal Especially since you're getting the you know The board game and another game and all these graphics and on such and such.
Scott: I don't think it's gonna be on steam though Just sort of like bleh, but it is gonna be you know, downloadable Somehow through whatever frickin service they're using.
Scott: I think my strategy is I'm gonna wait like a few days You know wait probably till the next week.
Scott: see how people receive the game See if they like it or not And you know if there's enough people playing it so that I can actually you know Get the game on against people often enough.
Scott: then I'll buy it.
Scott: Otherwise, I'll wait until it's much less expensive or I'll just get the DS one, you know and just play that with the local Multiplayer against people.
Rym: we'll see.
Rym: I mean the DS more and more.
Rym: the DS just can't have the complex kind of games I want.
Scott: well, it's it's basically.
Scott: I looked at the screenshots.
Scott: The DS one's not gonna be out for a lot longer.
Scott: It's not coming out on Friday But the DS one it looks like it's just blood Bowl just like the board game only on the DS.
Scott: So yeah, can't really go wrong.
Rym: I've only actually played blood Bowl the board game once and I didn't even play it all the way through.
Scott: Yeah, it's basically the way it works.
Scott: is you have?
Scott: the basic rules are like this right you have so many players right, but only 11 can be on the field at once because football and Every turn each guy can perform an action and the actions are like move block kill.
Scott: You know block is is fight, you know pass chart, right?
Scott: But then there are certain special actions right and on your turn You can only do one special action with one dude, you know, so, you know It's like everyone on your whole team does one of the normal actions and one guy can do a special action.
Scott: It could be any guy.
Scott: so you can have like this guy do the special action or that guy It's not like only the quarterback can do the special action.
Scott: But and you basically you just do this every turn, you know, and then there's some dice and some other charts and things You know like if you and like, you know, if you move and if you move near enemies They can try to trip you and all this sort of stuff, you know, but that's that's how the game is played.
Scott: so it's you know, it's pretty good.
Scott: as far as a Miniature turn-based strategy games go plus football.
Rym: but speaking of games that are coming out We didn't talk about this as much as I would have expected because it kind of it got Announced when we weren't really doing video game shows.
Rym: We were kind of in this in-between period for various reasons, but NS2 is actually coming for real.
Rym: pre-orders were announced a while ago.
Rym: You can go right now spend money pre-order and All I know is that I look to see if we had talked about this as a noobs.
Rym: I didn't remember and I saw that the last time we noted that we talked about natural selection Was in 2006 when NS2 announced that they might have dynamic infestation.
Scott: So we're gonna have to go over this whole thing again, basically natural selection.
Scott: one is an awesome half-life mod.
Scott: That's an RTS and an FPS at the same time and we don't need to explain that we did.
Rym: I just finished the explanation.
Rym: We did all show on it.
Rym: NS2 is Pretty much the only game I've been looking forward to since Team Fortress 2.
Scott: Yeah, and especially since Team Fortress 2 was up, right?
Rym: Team Fortress 2 was awesome up until the moment I took my first step as a player in the game.
Rym: Yeah at that moment I was vaguely disappointed and I became extremely disappointed.
Scott: Team Fortress 2 is like wow.
Scott: to me It's like the game itself.
Scott: the gameplay poop complete poop, but many humorous things result, you know Like Leroy Jenkins and you know meet the whoever.
Rym: Well, the thing is oh my god meet the spy was pretty damn good It was better than the everything since meet the heavy.
Scott: Oh, I like the engineer one.
Rym: It was okay.
Rym: Anyway, but NS2 is Probably going to be the most important FPS to come out since the re-release of Quake 3.
Scott: Yes, not only is NS2 first of all outside its own engine, right?
Scott: It's not using the half-life engine or the source entry or anything.
Scott: Secondly, the system requirements are really low.
Rym: So everyone can play Number three, I mean seriously 1.2 gigahertz processor 200.
Scott: you might be able to play it in a netbook if you got a GPU 256 megabytes of RAM DirectX 9 a mouse a keyboard Okay, internet access.
Scott: Yeah, it's gonna be super moddable with Lua.
Scott: if you don't know what Lua is It's basically a scripting language.
Scott: That's mad easy.
Scott: So you people get me modding the fuck out of this game.
Rym: Well more importantly the team behind it these people.
Rym: we're not gonna not the whole not to tell the whole story here But NS1 was a game that had a niche.
Rym: It wasn't super popular outside of people who got it.
Rym: it has a very small community that is extremely dedicated much like Not quake arena.
Rym: quicker in is basically dead like mega TF or weapons factory or tribes to now There's these little groups of people that play it and no one else does.
Rym: But the people who made NS get it.
Rym: They understand what it is to make a unique and different and amazing game more so than other people I have seen.
Rym: Natural selection is one of the greatest games ever made and NS2 Even if it is even if they deliver on less than half of what they claim to deliver on It's still gonna be the best FPS ever.
Rym: probably looks like it at least the best AC.
Rym: well, not even asymmetric because I think it'll be the best versus FPS ever made quite possibly.
Scott: I mean I can't counter-strike and tribes two are up there But I can't put it in the same categories like half-life.
Rym: single-player is a totally different thing.
Scott: Yeah, no, but I mean some of the changes that I heard about are you know, they're doing?
Scott: look You know, first of all, all the graphics are updated right?
Rym: They look real good If the teaser trailer is to be believed.
Scott: Yeah, but you know, they're doing a lot.
Scott: First of all, the alien is gonna have a commander which is good and bad sort of I kind of see.
Rym: at one hand I think that's crap.
Rym: I liked the hive mine, you know asymmetric whatever but at the same time I've really trust these guys judgment?
Scott: Yeah, also like the ono stomp is gonna disable structures and such temporarily.
Scott: So we could like stomp on the IP and the IP will stop spinning.
Scott: apparently the new IP spins.
Rym: Basically, what I think they're doing is they?
Rym: they they were really ambitious with ns1 and they basically pushed half-life 1 as far as they Could.
Rym: yeah and all the stuff they didn't do they wanted to do they just do that the game they'd already reached the limit.
Rym: I mean babblers never worked.
Scott: Yeah I mean basically like you know These guys are great at taking a small amount of resources and pushing them to the max.
Scott: I mean their half-life 1 mod looks as good as a lot of hat better than half-life 2 mods that are out there.
Scott: it's so good, but so the You know, they're.
Scott: that's why that has such low system requirements because they have the skills to be able to push You know really hard and make it really awesome.
Scott: But also they're not eating lots of you know, fancy shit.
Rym: They're not like taking the original game and just like going crazy.
Rym: now that they have resources and they're doing it on their own And all this stuff there.
Rym: as far as I can tell they're basically doing all the things That they wanted to do originally but couldn't just due to limitations of technology.
Scott: Yeah, they're also the.
Scott: The infestation is going to spread.
Scott: I don't know how it will spread but it's gonna spread in some way.
Scott: and then you can use flamethrowers You know to push it back well, or you can close bulkheads to sort of just seal it back.
Rym: Well, one thing about NS that made it great was that it was primarily an area control game.
Rym: But area control was either siege points choke points or resource towers.
Rym: But now with this infestation area control takes on a much more visceral feeling.
Scott: It's a lot more zerg ish on the bad guys on the alien side Not bad guys.
Scott: You could be the aliens then it'd be the good guys.
Rym: They Know the natural selection team unknown worlds.
Rym: They they breached this balance between atmosphere aka realism and gameplay That I've never seen anyone ever come close to.
Rym: games usually decide between being atmospheric and immersive or being a good Straight up, you know competitive game.
Scott: Yeah, like very quick is really good game It's it's you know game play is all about.
Scott: there's no atmosphere atmosphere in quake.
Scott: It barely feels like you know, but say half-life.
Scott: well half-life has good gameplay, but not multiplayer.
Scott: Why?
Rym: yes counter-strike did a pretty good job of giving up some of the realism to make the game playable and fun.
Rym: Action quake was not in any way realistic and had very little atmosphere, but it was real fun.
Rym: Yep, but NS2 they never sacrificed gameplay for style or vice-versa, but they max both of them out.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty crazy.
Scott: Anyway, I'm really gonna make a concerted effort to make mods of NS2.
Scott: I've never really done the mods big time but NS2 we're gonna mod that shit.
Scott: first mod Babblers.
Scott: first mod bat.
Scott: we're gonna do all the obvious.
Scott: mods gorge no animation jump.
Scott: You know classic mode gorge race combat gorge race Babblers.
Rym: Oh I can love babblers.
Rym: But anyway, just you know, be aware We don't advertise or anything on GeekNights.
Rym: But you can pre-order NS2 and you can either spend $20 or twice as much as that.
Rym: and you don't get anything different.
Rym: if you spend more other than that You held these people out and you get black armor.
Rym: It's actually beta and the alpha.
Scott: Yeah, it's actually sort of quite needed to pay the $40.
Scott: if we're gonna mod it We're gonna need to get in as early as possible.
Scott: But also it's interesting to see that the vast majority of the pre-orders got that they didn't say how.
Scott: I didn't see how many there Were but they said the vast majority percentage wise of pre-orders were the $40.
Rym: think about it.
Rym: who is pre-ordering this game?
Rym: But the existing NS community is in my opinion the closest knit online gaming community left.
Scott: Really the survival of the game though depends on the long tail of people buying the $20 version You know after its release.
Rym: but even if only all the current NS2 play NS1 players buy it and then unknown worlds goes out Of business the game exists and these people will play NS for the rest of their lives Probably like it and you might scoff at that, but I really yeah.
Rym: But I got one more announcement because it is a Tuesday and unlike other conventions we do that every day.
Rym: Thank God This convention is a lot more gamey.
Rym: We are going to be at Connecticut at the Hartford Convention Center in Hartford, Connecticut July the weekend of July.
Rym: Also August July 31st, August 1st, August 2nd, Friday Saturday Sunday Kaleida Sunday Sunday Sunday.
Scott: Oh shit.
Scott: Can you can't say that?
Rym: We're gonna be doing a couple of panels there.
Rym: Let's see We're doing.
Rym: good morning Connecticut.
Rym: bite-sized anime illusions would be fun beyond hundreds of don't do.
Scott: this conceptual game design.
Rym: Action cast will survive in the mecha attack.
Rym: We have a room.
Scott: that is just our room And no one else is in this room But us for the entire convention, so there is a GeekNights' panel room now.
Rym: We have gotten ourselves.
Rym: We are doing like 11 panels.
Rym: Just me and Scott.
Rym: Also, we have the front row crew doing a whole bunch of panels like a burning wheel character burning workshop Geekology geek research independent game development all this sort of stuff.
Rym: We have also got Luke Crane the guy who did burning wheel and all that and Jared Sorensen The guy who did action castle and all that Inspectors.
Rym: Yeah and lacuna and project doughnut They're going to be doing a couple of panels and they're gonna be running demos of games all weekend.
Rym: ConnectiCon is gonna be.
Rym: if nothing else You can come to ConnectiCon come to our panel room and get awesome GeekNights front row crew Luke Crane Jared Sorenson stuff For the entire convention with.
Scott: So even if ConnectiCon is no good, right and I don't know how it's gonna be I have no you know, cuz ConnectiCon has been sort of iffy.
Scott: the thing is a. even though ConnectiCon is iffy I'm not gonna lie.
Scott: the board game area.
Scott: There is always 100% awesome.
Rym: They should just make that a convention in and of itself that accounts tabletop gaming is better than most tabletop gaming conventions I've been to.
Scott: and two there's a whole panel room.
Scott: That is we it's just us.
Scott: So if you're a fan of us, you're listening to us Obviously.
Scott: you can be safe in that room and the tabletop gaming area for the whole convention all three days And it'll be worth your while to go to ConnectiCon and it'll also make us look really good.
Scott: Yeah, you come just for us and no other reason.
Rym: plus I will say this We have gone to ConnectiCon for several years and we have never failed to have a very good time.
Rym: We're always a little bit leery ahead of time because the con always kind of Puts it real close to the wire in terms of being ready to run.
Rym: Yeah, but it's always fun when we're there.
Rym: and this year The you can think of this basically as the test run of what we're going to be doing in all the bigger Conventions in years to come.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Also, you might see us pass out from doing 11 panels.
Rym: So things of the day I have something very little here very very minor.
Rym: It's not terribly important.
Rym: But remember Mortal Kombat.
Rym: It was a. it wasn't a good game.
Rym: No one can claim it was actually a good game with a straight face.
Rym: It was not.
Scott: a Mortal Kombat 2 was not well terrible fighting.
Rym: It was a good, you know It was not an objectively good game.
Rym: It was an okay fighting game, but I had Street Fighter 2.
Scott: Well, it was a different kind of fighting game from Street Fighter 2.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: It was a memorize the combos game.
Scott: What game isn't?
Rym: it was memorize the arbitrary annoying counterintuitive.
Rym: not that fun combos game It was.
Rym: it was also the jump up and backwards while kicking most of the time game.
Scott: Yeah that was a very important maneuver.
Scott: the cross up kick but jump over a guy and then kick him in the back of the head to Start your combo.
Rym: Yep or jump backwards while kicking hopefully disrupting their attempt to jump forward around you and kick Yep, and also you can beat the single-player by just using the trip.
Scott: move over and over and over again except you can like two Characters you can beat the majority of people in arcades.
Rym: Do you hear that arcades?
Rym: I played these games in an arc.
Scott: This is pretty much the last triumph of the arcade was Street Fighter 2 turbo and Mortal Kombat 2.
Scott: People were lining up in arcades to play these games and then the home versions came out and then the arcade died.
Rym: Mortal Kombat 3 was like the last Arcade game.
Rym: it went up like that was.
Rym: I went to an arcade There was Mortal Kombat 3 then all the arcades shut down like within a month and that was it.
Rym: Yep But Mortal Kombat was important primarily because it was bloody and gory for the time and it set a lot of precedents.
Rym: It was the first time video games Really really really shook up pop culture and there was a lot of reaction.
Scott: a video game should got pop culture But they didn't shake it up because of violence.
Rym: Yeah, well they'd shaken it up for other reasons but finally they shook it up because of violence in a way that even the Like the slowest reporters figured out.
Rym: Yep, but other than that.
Rym: No, it wasn't a great game But they used models to make the game.
Rym: the game, you know was motion capture and model.
Scott: Yeah, I mean Street Fighter has always been you know hand-drawn art to make all the characters and such.
Scott: but in Mortal Kombat 2 They used motion capture and photography and stop-motion, you know Even though it was low resolution It looked really good sort of the same way that Donkey Kong Country looked really good because the you know the way they generated all the sprites for all the characters and animations and such.
Rym: but I have a picture for you of How they did that and it is both interesting and a little bit disappointing To see this totally ghetto but totally the same kind of way.
Rym: I would do that sort of thing.
Rym: set up Yeah bonus points for the desk lamp taped to the candy tin that is self held up by two books And it's Goro.
Rym: you get to see Goro.
Scott: he has four arms.
Rym: I hated him so I also have four arms do you?
Rym: yeah All right.
Rym: What do you have for me?
Scott: So this is a video game.
Scott: I can't if you can read this page.
Scott: It's a Japanese language page.
Scott: I sort of hovered over all the links looking for a download.
Scott: I couldn't find one.
Scott: I don't know if it's downloadable.
Scott: I don't know what the deal.
Scott: is it even real?
Scott: I think it's real But I don't know how to play it or get it or what it runs on.
Scott: but the game is called Symphony of the blood and I don't know why it's called Symphony of the blood as I would say aka blood symphony.
Scott: what the game is right is a doujin game.
Scott: it is a Tezuka doujin game a Tezuka doujin fighting game in which there is a slew of Tezuka characters Which you can select and then play a sort of guilty gears looking kind of fighting game with so blackjack versus princess knight versus daddy First Unico.
Scott: I don't see Astro boy in there.
Rym: You gotta be in there yet.
Scott: verse You know Jackie Maru.
Scott: verse who knows who?
Scott: right?
Scott: all sorts of you know Tezuka character.
Scott: It's pretty hardcore you can all.
Scott: all you need.
Scott: the thing of the day is just all these images in this website.
Scott: it's this is a game that I want to play just because of the awesome novelty of it.
Scott: and Yeah, that's that's about it.
Rym: so Remember that sound I?
Scott: Not until we just I just reminded me myself of it like a few minutes ago.
Rym: that brought back a flood of memories.
Rym: Green wizard needs food badly, but red warrior shot the food.
Scott: you asshole.
Rym: I remember playing gauntlet a lot.
Scott: You couldn't play to win could you?
Scott: you always said you just play to be an asshole.
Rym: we we played it on the emulator At RIT or actually I think we played it on a real NES a bunch of times, too.
Rym: Yeah, because we had that NES that I won that gamecube version also.
Rym: Yeah, we did, but I also had that NES that I won at Ohio con all right.
Scott: That's why we had extra NES.
Rym: Yeah, we had two NES as a result, but gauntlet was not a good game.
Scott: Well let's talk about what gauntlet is before we talk about why it's.
Rym: does anyone not know what gauntlet is?
Rym: Do we really need to start every video game show about a game?
Rym: That's more than like two years old.
Rym: being like.
Rym: this was a game Where you like you know Mario Brothers you walk from left to right to left.
Scott: well I mean all.
Scott: it was really something different.
Scott: I mean back in the day you'd go to the arcade Just rogue.
Rym: only it was like it was real time.
Scott: rogue was real time.
Rym: It was more real time I Guess.
Scott: I think the only difference between gauntlet and rogue really is that it was less.
Scott: it was less complex than rogue you had.
Scott: you could have multiplayer and You everyone shot things you know in sort of in an action RPG Zelda kind of way Whereas in rogue you went up to next to a bad guy and pushed fight fight fight.
Rym: Well, you can do that too.
Rym: You can walk up to enemies.
Rym: Just push on them to kill him.
Scott: Yeah, but it wasn't.
Scott: it wasn't you know cycle.
Scott: You know like rogue wasn't exactly turn-based, but it was sort of cycles.
Scott: It's like you know to be fight fight fight whereas in discrete units whereas in gauntlet It would be basically the cycles were constantly rolling around.
Scott: you know even if you're just standing still you would just take all shit ton Of damage, I just I remember renting gauntlet.
Rym: Fairly, I never bought gauntlet one But I'd rent it every now and then.
Rym: you know every weekend my parents be like you can run one video game And I would sometimes rent the same game more than once because if you rented the wrong game you were fucked for the weekend.
Rym: Yep, I rented some bad games in my time.
Rym: Oh, it sucks, but gauntlet was gauntlet one at least.
Rym: I remember renting it and Being fascinated with it, but at the same time Hating it say I only ever played gauntlet really in the arcades right.
Scott: so gauntlet one in the arcade was something special back in its day because first of all Four people could play it at once and this was before Ninja Turtles or x-men or the Simpsons right.
Scott: so that was a big deal.
Scott: Second of all it had actual voice coming out of the machine.
Scott: it would say things which is a big deal.
Scott: right I mean Sinistar said things, but you know it's like very few machines had that ability to talk to.
Rym: you see I never.
Rym: gauntlet was always in the arcade.
Rym: I never played it because all I could always think was I got gauntlet at home.
Rym: It's the same stupid game.
Scott: see I was I had was had gauntlet in the arcade before gauntlet at home.
Scott: So gauntlet was at home also at home.
Scott: You didn't have a four score.
Scott: Yeah, I did Shit and remember that was gauntlet - I didn't know I didn't know anyone with the four score.
Rym: one gauntlet one did not have the Four player at home.
Rym: see there you go and - it was much shittier gauntlet - was the best that game got on the NES.
Rym: But gauntlet - I had the four score.
Rym: I would often play it with four people.
Scott: the thing I liked about gauntlet one You know.
Scott: I think the reason I played it all the arcade was sort of like the the dungeon Explory aspect of it.
Scott: you know it's like that the sort of maze action And I always I always seem to like maze action for some reason.
Rym: you know it was weird As a kid when I didn't really understand how this stuff worked.
Rym: I remember playing gauntlet and thinking that The maps were so poorly put together and so glitchy and so crappy That I didn't feel like I was exploring anything.
Rym: I felt like it was a race against the game glitching me to death.
Scott: That's sort of true.
Rym: the arcade was a little less glitch than the NES Especially gauntlet 2 where as far as I could tell you get five or six levels in and then it would just be random.
Scott: Bullshit it was random.
Scott: We just looked that up.
Rym: Yeah, but eventually you hit a level where there's just like you just couldn't win.
Rym: I just beat like I'd start and there's walls around me and no secrets And then I would die.
Scott: well the thing the thing about gauntlet.
Scott: right the reason it was primarily an arcade game is because Basically you had health and as you played even if you didn't fight any bad guys You just stood still.
Scott: your health was constantly going down, and you could put in quarters to make your health go up.
Scott: It was the ultimate quarter munching designed game.
Scott: It's like if you're playing Zelda and your hearts always went down And you can make him go up by putting in a quarter.
Scott: the only other way to make him go up was by touching food But there was always a risk.
Scott: the food would get shot.
Rym: of course that Aspect of it was what made it great at home and in the arcade because you'd play for a while And you know you'd be trying to succeed, but eventually you'd get to that point where Even
Scott: if you're playing perfectly and killing all the bad guys and getting all the treasures There's not enough food to just as to keep you alive And it takes time to play it and your health goes down.
Scott: But eventually you're gonna die.
Rym: eventually warrior takes the food that wizard needed to survive.
Rym: So wizard doesn't save warrior from death and then warrior pushes wizard into the next three deaths.
Rym: Then wizard dies.
Rym: then warrior dies.
Scott: Yeah, it's like Rym.
Scott: It's if you don't try to win.
Scott: That's what happens.
Rym: Well the thing is Scott always wanted to play the wizard the wussy-ass wizard
Scott: because the wizard had could shoot And if the wizard used the magic he cleared out a lot more bad guys, but
Rym: the warrior was so strong and while he was slower Warrior could always push the wizard.
Rym: so we'd play for like a half hour at RIT.
Scott: That's another thing.
Scott: that was bullshit, right?
Scott: It's like okay.
Scott: The warrior is strong.
Scott: He's always strong.
Scott: right?
Scott: you have the Wizards net the Warriors never in a bad situation.
Rym: The the wizard can be in a bad situation.
Scott: Yeah, but the wizard has this magic that's wicked powerful and is the only way to get rid of death if he shows up.
Scott: but if The Grim Reaper, I'm sorry, but if the you only can cast a magic spell if you have a potion wasn't it?
Rym: I thought it was just called death.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: It doesn't matter I'm pretty sure it was called but if you get the potion well it was called it and death was called death.
Scott: Yes, if you use up all your potions the wizard is completely useless because he's now just sort of.
Scott: you know Does that magic?
Scott: so if death shows up and you don't have any potions you did it to run away?
Rym: I just remember this one time Scott and I were playing.
Rym: no one else wanted to play because I had a four score.
Rym: I haven't brought it to RIT.
Rym: We just didn't really use it.
Scott: I don't remember seeing it.
Rym: It was there.
Rym: I've got it around the house somewhere.
Scott: I've never seen it.
Rym: I owned every four score game.
Scott: I've never seen this four score.
Rym: Anyway, they were almost all terrible except for the racing game.
Rym: Yep, but you know we were playing for like a half hour 20.
Rym: I forget exactly how.
Scott: the four score for the original Gameboy.
Rym: No, I remember I never knew anyone when I was young who was cool who owned a Gameboy other than me one time.
Rym: Everyone owned.
Scott: one time when I was on a field trip in elementary school Someone had the Gameboy four player and they're playing that f1 game.
Rym: See I was desperate.
Rym: I was desperate for most of my childhood to find anyone cool.
Rym: and by cool I define that as anyone who owned either a combination of a Gameboy and hunt for the red October and the link cable or Crystal warriors a game gear and the link cable because those games both had awesome Multiplayer that I never in my life was able to play.
Scott: not once not eat Your brother get another one.
Rym: and then we had one Gameboy and one game gear.
Scott: in my household get another Gameboy.
Rym: We didn't have money.
Rym: I was I was in like middle school.
Scott: You could have gotten two game boys instead of the game gear.
Rym: now We wanted the game gear more.
Rym: we got the game boy later two game gears then now because we couldn't afford two game gears.
Rym: Anyway, plus we had all right.
Rym: I did not realize that hunt for the red October would exist.
Rym: Anyway, yeah, but at one point we're walking and Scott's behind me and this death is chasing us.
Rym: we don't have any potions and I'm like he.
Rym: Scott's like go go go, but I'm slower than him and He starts to go around me to leave me to my fate with death.
Rym: and I realized wait a minute.
Rym: Wait a minute I'm a warrior.
Rym: so I stood in the middle wouldn't let him get past me and Waited for death sweet death to eat itself on Scott.
Scott: and then we continued and there was nowhere to run.
Rym: And then for the next five minutes I proceeded to push Scott into every death we came across.
Scott: Yeah, for some reason the warrior can push the wizard and the wizard can't push back.
Scott: So if there wasn't like a place to run away to I really had no choice.
Scott: and where I went and if I didn't have Any magic death would always come and get me.
Rym: the game was basically green wizard needs food badly.
Rym: Red warrior shot the food.
Rym: red warrior shot the food.
Rym: green wizard is about to die.
Rym: Red warrior shot the food.
Scott: You Couldn't play to win could you?
Rym: ah, there's no way to win.
Rym: that game goes on forever.
Rym: It goes on forever.
Scott: Yes, the other gauntlets are beautiful.
Rym: call it one.
Rym: You can actually beat go online.
Rym: Look on YouTube You'll see what it ends with and let me tell you that is not worth it.
Rym: Good God.
Scott: No, but actually in the arcade When you know later on think there was a gauntlet legends in the arcade was actually a 3d gauntlet game.
Scott: The game was itself wasn't 3d.
Scott: It's still played 2d But 3d graphics.
Rym: that game had all the character model all the lack of fun of the original gauntlet But without any of the charm and with added complexity.
Scott: Well, it was weird cuz like I played in the arcade and for some reason it was fun.
Scott: then, you know.
Scott: And the thing was in the arcade you could save your game.
Scott: So I saved my game on the local arcade machine and I would go back and I would play it every once in a while.
Scott: There would up my guy.
Scott: I remember this was level up and stuff.
Rym: That was before.
Rym: games like initial D were really available where you had like cards or something you could save.
Scott: Yeah, this you just put in your initials and it loaded up a game.
Rym: a bunch of game.
Rym: police 9-1-1 had that dude, isn't it?
Scott: I don't remember.
Rym: maybe that was later though.
Rym: But anyway, I Forgot where I was going with now.
Scott: So then we got this gauntlet legends the same game for the n64 and that had four controllers.
Scott: so me and my brother and two friends.
Scott: we'd always play that and it was like wicked fun.
Scott: and Then so when I got the GameCube at RIT, I bought gauntlet, you know The next gauntlet for the GameCube and for some reason it wasn't fun anymore.
Scott: No one wanted to play it.
Scott: I don't know what it was.
Scott: You wanted to play it with people cuz I remembered having such good times with it in high school on the on the n64.
Scott: So I figured well, I'll have the same good times in the GameCube.
Rym: Well, I remember you were like.
Rym: I got it.
Rym: I was like, okay and we sat down to play it and five minutes later I realized that all I was doing was holding right and a at the same time and occasionally I would hold up an Robotron controls.
Scott: so you're shooting with one stick and moving with the other.
Rym: didn't matter at all.
Rym: You basically just walked in shot.
Rym: There was no puzzle.
Rym: There was nothing.
Scott: Oh, there were.
Scott: there were puzzles.
Scott: at least.
Rym: the original gauntlet was so crappy just due to the limitations of the technology that you forgave It for the fact that it was basically not a game.
Scott: Yeah But yeah now I sort of realized, you know the badness of gauntlet and it's hard to play it now.
Rym: I was into the arcade game though for a little while at RIT because when we first got to RIT I remember they they had a night.
Rym: the arcade was free.
Rym: You could go in swipe your card and get infinite tokens Mmm, so I got infinite tokens and I. we kept playing gauntlet and I saved my game and I was leveling up and doing all that stuff.
Rym: and one day like a week later I went into the arcade and I swept my card and I saw that it had debited money from my flex account And I was like what?
Rym: and I went up to the guy and he's like, why did this take money from me?
Rym: He was like you thought free play would last forever.
Rym: Yeah, and I never played gauntlet again.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, it was basically worth zero to me Words, but if it's zero you'll play.
Scott: of course.
Rym: that was that not anymore.
Rym: back then I would remember RIT was the time in our lives when we had infinite free time, but no money.
Rym: Yeah now I have infinite money, but no free time.
Scott: It's strange now that I'm beginning to see like the connection between games like rogue net hack Right gauntlet and Diablo and they're all sort of like these similar games.
Scott: It's all about there's a dungeon you're exploring the dungeon right and you're simultaneously fighting the bad guys and that's real and getting treasure and that's and the sort of amazed to it.
Scott: and It's weird because it's like, you know, you think the D&D based game is more like the MMO style, right?
Scott: But it's strange how the D&D the fundamentals of D&D sort of diverged into like these sort of different Gameplay types in the video game area.
Rym: Well, I mean remember the Dungeons & Dragons arcade game.
Scott: Well, that was just a side scroll and beat him up.
Scott: Yeah, I had some elements of D&D.
Rym: that game was actually for its time kind of awesome.
Scott: Yes, it was an alright game.
Scott: You had some decisions to make of where to go.
Scott: Yeah you had lots of items you could use.
Scott: you could turn on dead infinity times and it was awesome.
Scott: and you could Get secret doors if you have opened them up and it required some modicum of teamwork Some You had to set the troll on fire.
Rym: Yeah, it wasn't a great game, but it was better than gauntlet.
Scott: Yeah, it was at least really entertaining.
Scott: I remember playing that one at the movie theater a lot.
Rym: Yep I remember oh my god.
Rym: after a science Olympiad competition Yeah I was in like seventh grade and we stopped at this pizza joint on the way home the whole team and they had the D&D Machine the it was the cocktail cabinet version.
Scott: Oh, wow I've never seen such a thing.
Rym: so us kids stayed there for two hours to the chagrin of our parents who wouldn't you know?
Rym: We could they couldn't make us leave and we took turns and we were almost at the end of the game and Someone I ran out of money.
Rym: I won't say who?
Rym: Someone it was me bumped into the power cable That was actually barely plugged in but none of us noticed the whole time.
Rym: It's how I was playing and I kind of bumped into with my foot and it fell out and the game stopped.
Rym: and there was this silence followed by a cry that I've never heard since.
Scott: That's a good start.
Rym: No one knew it was me.
Scott: I never fessed up, you know, that would be a lot worse if it was a gauntlet game.
Scott: We're like level 200 something.
Rym: Oh my god Man, there's that YouTube video of a perfect score run of gauntlet 2.
Rym: Wow I watched the end of part 23 of Mmm, I also found a question someone asked online of does gauntlet 2 end?
Rym: and no one answered it.
Scott: Wow Yeah, I don't know gauntlet is strange and that it has some things that like were invented in gauntlet that were really good.
Scott: I mean like the bad guys spigot.
Scott: they sort of invented that in gauntlet.
Rym: Yep, and the game just for you know for a young kid in that era of game It was.
Rym: it was a game that could only exist in the form it did in the era that it did.
Rym: but at the same time games that are Fundamentally the same but just have basically they add a bunch of fluff on top of what is basically just gauntlet.
Scott: Can't tell you how many times a new game comes out and I'm like, oh that's just gauntlet You know, it is like.
Rym: it's not even like.
Rym: oh you're just saying that it's just like.
Scott: the only difference I mean Diablo and gauntlet.
Scott: is that Diablo?
Scott: Doesn't have the robotron control style.
Scott: It has the click on the bad guy a whole bunch of times control style.
Scott: That's really the only difference.
Rym: gauntlet 4 even had going to town and buy shit.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, but gauntlet also had a little bit of that four swords element Especially gauntlet 2 because every now and then a level would start and it would say things like your shots hurt the other players Wink wink.
Rym: Yeah, and like if a power-up was there only one person could get it plus the brilliance of it.
Scott: Yeah, it was sort of like this really unpolished, you know, I mean Basically, you know, there's the new Mario game coming out for the the Wii that they're all pushing now, right?
Scott: That's gonna that they promoted big at e3 for Mario's.
Scott: They're talking all about you know, the competitive cooperative where you're cooperating to beat the game But you're also competing.
Scott: now see which of you is better than the other never mind the fact that Nintendo.
Scott: They're acting like they just invented it But even though they invented it with four swords and crystal chronicles and crystal chronicles, right?
Scott: And well crystal chronicles didn't really have the competitive part.
Rym: Yes Cooperative it had the competitive part in that everyone had their goal their secret goal.
Scott: All right.
Scott: You're right.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, and you got items based on that at the end of every mission.
Scott: Yeah, but you know gauntlet sort of had that only unpolished, you know.
Scott: in that, you know You were cooperating to beat the game but you're competing, you know yet score first of all who got the high score and You wanted to get more food.
Scott: You wanted to take food away from other people's that you know You would live longer and have to pay less quarters and death would come.
Rym: Yeah, you did.
Rym: if you didn't have potions Someone was getting it.
Scott: Someone was taking one for you want that to be someone else and not you And if someone else is gonna grab the food shoot that food.
Scott: You don't want them to eat the food because then they're basically getting free money in terms of quarters.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: and that's you know, what gauntlet was about Wasn't I?
Rym: just I don't know.
Rym: the game is really at the core of a lot of popular games today and I That you know, it's not like.
Rym: I've realized this now.
Rym: I've always realized this but the reason I'm so disillusioned with a lot of gaming today And the reason I look at a lot of new games and like I play five minutes I'm immediately done with them.
Rym: Just can't enjoy them at all Is that almost every game that comes out is at its core identical to a game?
Rym: I already played the fullness of when I was like 11.
Scott: Yep, and gauntlet is off in that game.
Scott: Yep, I mean just try to name some of the games that are basically gauntlet World of Warcraft.
Rym: Oh No World of Warcraft is beyond that World of Warcraft.
Scott: Yeah, it's definitely mud, you know, it's sort of like, you know They're all these sort of things that evolved from the D&D based video.
Rym: Look muds were stateful gauntlet was stateless.
Scott: Yeah, the muds.
Scott: Yeah, the mud.
Scott: you had the mud Jenner you had the mud Genre, you had the gauntlet genre.
Scott: you had the sort of Dungeon master gold box kind of genre in another direction, you know.
Scott: They're all these sort of different kinds of play styles that came out of the D&D Idea and gauntlet is just one of those.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I think we're done.
Rym: I don't know what else I can say about gauntlet other than green wizard shot the food.
Rym: Yeah, that voice was so awesome when I was a kid coming out of my NES.
Scott: I mean, it's like even though the game is bad that voice is still famous.
Scott: I mean, you know, it's like you think about it.
Scott: back in the day so few games had digitized voice and those that did Anything that the digitized voice said became famous.
Scott: I mean everything sinistar said is fun run run run Castle to stay alive.
Scott: Yeah, I mean job red commander any video game from that era that talked because so few of them talked.
Scott: Everything it said became like a famous quote.
Rym: I remember when I buy now video games like full voice acting and I Remember when I bought tie fighter.
Rym: I didn't even have x-wing but it was the first like big iron Computer game that I bought as opposed to pirated Yeah, and I also didn't have a working sound card for a long time up until that point.
Rym: So I got tie fighter and that MIDI of star wars starts playing.
Rym: I'm thinking like yeah, this is awesome This is awesome.
Rym: This is awesome.
Rym: And then Darth Vader looks at me and says signal vice admiral thon thron to have his tie squadron sent immediately And I was like, oh my god, it talked.
Rym: That game talking was like the biggest thing ever.
Rym: and now You know one thing I can say to the voice acting and a lot of early games was a lot better than the voice acting now Tie fighter sounded exactly like people in Star Wars.
Scott: Yeah, but I'm saying I'm talking about things like wing commander Which is bad acting period yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, maybe it's just tie fighter had good voice acting and nothing else.
Scott: Oh, you know what?
Scott: They added on good old games.com.
Scott: What dad all of the Pandora directed.
Scott: What's his text?
Scott: Murphy Murphy?
Rym: Those games thought but they were also awesome.
Scott: He added all of them everything.
Rym: Wait.
Rym: Wait the original original ones Yeah, all of them.
Rym: What about the multimedia remakes under a killing moon?
Rym: Yeah, that's all of them.
Rym: Oh my god under a killing moon.
Rym: I played that with my 2x CD-ROM on my multimedia PC.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: All right I don't think we got much more to say and I want to eat dinner.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Scott: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.