Scott: It's Thursday, October 8th, I'm Scott, I'm Rip, and this is GeekNights, tonight with the book club Der Steppenwolf.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: I've been rollerblading to the train station every day because my car, like the brakes are busted and I just haven't had a chance to take it to a mechanic.
Scott: You haven't had the experience of driving on the brand new road.
Scott: Ah, it's so smooth.
Rym: I had the experience of rollerblading on that road and let me tell you.
Scott: They paved our road, by the way.
Rym: It's a pleasant experience.
Scott: Our road that was desperately in need of paving was paved and it did an excellent job.
Scott: They did it very quickly and it's great.
Rym: In general, it makes me very happy that I live in this little city of Beacon because- The thing is I paid for this road with taxes and now I'm leaving.
Rym: Well thanks for the road.
Scott: Yeah, great.
Rym: But the cool thing is, my only complaint about Beacon, other than the key food, is that all the infrastructure is shitty and old.
Rym: Like the power outages happen kind of often because like every pole is on the verge of death at any moment.
Rym: Like at any second they're all just gonna fall over.
Scott: But I don't even have poles to be underground.
Rym: Yeah, all the modern suburbs are underground for the most part, at least the internal distribution in like a subdivision, not so much the like main carrier lines.
Scott: There's this city, everything's underground.
Rym: Yeah, including scary old steam pipes and electricity.
Rym: No one knows where it's coming from or going.
Rym: But you know, Beacon, like my big complaint was all the old infrastructure, the busted roads, the busted sidewalks, and the elections are coming up.
Rym: And for a second I was thinking, "Huh, maybe I should figure out who's gonna raise taxes and fix this
Rym: stuff.".
Scott: I tried to figure out who to vote for, right?
Scott: What?
Rym: Doesn't matter because in the last month it looks like they got all this government subsidy money from the bailout and the stimulus package and suddenly they're fixing everything.
Rym: Like they're replacing power poles and paving roads and fixing sidewalks.
Scott: So I was trying to see who to vote for and I think I'm just gonna have to skip this vote because I happen to be moving very close to voting time.
Scott: It's the local election, so it's the least important vote.
Rym: Well it's also the most important.
Scott: And I don't think I'll be registered in time to vote for like New York mayor, which could matter, but whatever.
Rym: Well think of it this way, it's the most important vote for you directly, but only if the candidates are reasonably different.
Scott: But anyway, so I looked at like the cards.
Scott: Apparently all the candidates go house to house.
Scott: But when they came to our house, of course we were not home because we commute.
Scott: Yeah, great.
Scott: Good job, guys.
Scott: And they all left little cards.
Scott: So I read little cards that they left.
Rym: I remember last time there was an election here, both parties basically said they would do the exact same thing.
Scott: And one of the cards though, I remember one of the cards and it said one item on one of the cards really stood out to me.
Scott: It said, took money back from the MTA, so money doesn't leave our county.
Scott: And I was like, I was like, fuck you.
Rym: You bastard.
Scott: The only reason my money came into your county is because the train is there.
Scott: Without that train, you wouldn't have nothing.
Rym: I like beacon.
Rym: If there was no train, I would be living in Manhattan.
Rym: Cause what else am I going to do?
Scott: So it's like, uh, I, I didn't know who to vote for, but I knew not that guy anyway.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But you know, rollerblading.
Rym: So I have my rollerblades in the city and one thing I've never really done in my life is rollerbladed in a dense urban environment, but muse games, you know, Emily and Alex, the game company, they made their game guns of Icarus and we had a game party last night.
Rym: So I was going to go.
Rym: It's downtown and I decided to rollerblade from midtown to Chinatown during the like rush hour commute.
Scott: Good job.
Rym: That was one of the more exhilarating and death defying things I've ever done in my life.
Scott: You need a helmet for that shit.
Rym: Actually, a helmet probably wouldn't have done me any good.
Rym: I had my, our risk guards.
Rym: That's really all you need.
Scott: A helmet would have done you some good if a car hit you, a car wasn't going to hit me.
Scott: It could have.
Rym: I wasn't too worried.
Rym: I got to say the most dangerous place to be.
Rym: If you're on the street, it's one of those fucking bike lanes.
Rym: You're better off just in traffic dodging buses than in those bike lanes.
Scott: Well, it depends on which bike lane, you know, it's like, um, you know, the bike lane, like on Broadway is actually really wide and has a barrier next to it and like cars can't get into it.
Scott: You know?
Rym: So it's like stretch.
Rym: You realize you get past that stretch and there's people just like parked blocking it.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Rym: It's like, wow, great.
Rym: Thanks dude.
Scott: Bike people just sort of get used to it.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: Rollerbladers too.
Rym: But I got to say it was kind of awesome just dodging buses and going all over the street and cutting across and trying to figure out how to get to, I don't know if I'll do it again anytime soon because I afterward I thought maybe I might've died, but, uh, it was fun at least once.
Rym: I feel like everyone should do that at least once in their life.
Scott: You know, there's like, you know, the thing is, you know, if you've never done it before, I could understand why you think, oh man, is death defying whatever, right?
Scott: It's like little old ladies riding their bicycles around New York city.
Scott: It is not nearly a dangerous death, defying kind of thing.
Scott: It just feels like it.
Scott: If you're not used to it as soon as you're used to it, it's just like, oh, whatever.
Rym: Cause I've ridden bikes in that sort of traffic and in fact I've ridden bikes in the city before and it's a completely different experience from rollerblading one.
Rym: rollerblades are not like you can maneuver very well, but what you cannot do quickly in the street without a bunch of space around you is stop.
Rym: And also cars apparently just can't see a rollerblader like they did like bikes at least like they, they see bikes and they know I'm there.
Rym: And while they might be mad at me and they might cut it close, I don't worry that the cars are just going to hit me out.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Cars almost just hit me out.
Rym: Just like I was completely invisible.
Rym: I hit a guy's car with the shoes I was carrying after he almost hit me.
Scott: If I do think about it, most of the time I've ever seen any sort of non bikes in the city, like skateboard guys and a blade.
Rym: It's always like in the, they're always on the sidewalk.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: They don't really go down the street.
Rym: So I tried to go down the sidewalk.
Rym: that was even more dangerous.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, so I'm still moving.
Scott: I'm getting, making a good progress.
Scott: I have the keys.
Scott: I've got stuff.
Scott: I'm going to get deliveries and whatnot.
Scott: I went today to get a mattress.
Scott: So I may say I went to the sleepies nearest my work because they have sleepies, not mattress King.
Scott: Where is there a mattress King?
Rym: I don't even know if that's a real place.
Scott: I know.
Scott: Right.
Rym: The thing is, right.
Rym: It sounds like it should be a real place.
Scott: I usually, I would shop around for something like this and usually I would shop online also, but a mattress, you got to lay in it, you know, before you buy it.
Scott: And a mattress is something you're going to have for a long time.
Scott: Like the matches I have now I've had for eight years, you know?
Rym: Wow.
Rym: The mattress I've had, I have now I've had for nine years.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, and you know, the dude at the mattress place was like, look, you know, he was, he was a real friendly guy, but he obviously was a skilled mattress salesman.
Scott: There was no question about that.
Scott: Cause he's like, look, a mattress is something you got.
Rym: He go up to you and he's like, the more expensive ones are clearly superior.
Scott: No.
Scott: What he actually said was, look, a mattress is something you're going to have, you know, for like 10 years, if not more right.
Scott: It's you're going to spend how much time on it, half your day, every day, or at least like a 30 year day, every day.
Scott: You know, you, you should get a good one, even if it costs more, you know, which is kind of true.
Rym: Well, considering I'm sitting in an Aeron chair and you have a human freedom chair.
Rym: I think that is exactly the argument to use on someone like.
Scott: that is exactly the argument that I used on myself.
Rym: I was like, well, you know, what matches did you get?
Scott: I got, Oh, what the, I forget what the hell it was.
Rym: It was, I forget to compare features because I, my mattress is a very expensive mattress.
Scott: And I think the mattress is like $1,200, but that's about what mine was.
Scott: So I, uh, you know, I basically, I knew, right.
Scott: The thing is we had that thread in the forum.
Scott: Like you can't avoid these psychological tricks, even though you know, they're there.
Scott: The thing was what I did is I said, okay, psychological trick number one, the expensive wine tastes better, right?
Scott: I knew that.
Scott: So you know what I did?
Scott: I laid on the mattresses and didn't look at any price tags, but until I had already determined which ones I liked better.
Rym: Ah, good idea.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So what's the plan?
Rym: unless like something ludicrous, like you ask and it's a thousand, a hundred thousand dollars just to pick what everyone felt the best, no matter what kind of.
Scott: And then trick number two, right.
Scott: Was I knew that you'd sort of remember which ones you slept in based on the order you like laid on them in.
Scott: So I laid out, I kept switching between them in different patterns.
Scott: You know, I kept going back and forth across the store and you know, to try, you know, to compare better.
Scott: And a lot of this was really helpful because there were a lot of sort of like these test mattresses where it'd be like, you know, half the mattress is one way and half was the other way.
Scott: So you can just sort of roll over to sort of get a different feel.
Rym: And some people buy actual mattresses like that.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I also tested out these pillows and I found like the best pillow.
Scott: So I carry that same pillow to all the mattresses to get to get, you know, the correct comparison.
Scott: You know, I'd always be using the same pillow.
Scott: And then I picked a mattress and I'm like, yeah, just fucking give me this mattress.
Scott: God damn it.
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: But they have a policy.
Scott: If I think I can find the mattress cheaper, like elsewhere, I can get my money.
Scott: I can get the difference plus 10 percent.
Scott: So I'm going to go and shop around, see if I can find that mattress online for less money and get some money back.
Scott: But yeah, the one thing that I learned going there because I went there during lunch, I'm trying to move without missing any work.
Scott: So like every lunch, I'm doing something.
Scott: If you have lunch in New York City or just pretty much anywhere, spend your lunch at the mattress store.
Scott: It's like free naps.
Scott: I mean, come on.
Rym: How long will they let me sleep before they come in a cost me?
Scott: This guy was like, like totally, you know, of course I was buying a mattress, but he was like, he was like encouraging me to just like lay around his store and, you know, not leave until I, you know, bought something.
Scott: But, you know, you know, he might catch on after three years, be like, you know, I was already like.
Scott: he was like super friendly, you know, I totally love to be friends with that guy.
Rym: Are you sure it wasn't professionally friendly, like the people in the fancy hotels?
Scott: He seemed genuinely friendly.
Rym: It's hard to say.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, he was trying to get you to buy a mattress more than a thousand dollars.
Scott: I know it's like it was weird because it was like the perfect salesman, like I was.
Scott: his sales skills were either so good either.
Scott: A, he was just genuinely super awesome or B, his sales skills were so awesome that, you know, whatever he can take my money because like, you know, some guys, their salesman, they come off with the hard sell.
Scott: This guy just came off as like this guy I want to hang out with because he's so great.
Scott: And he knew a lot about mattresses.
Scott: I might have to go meet this guy, go to the sleepies on 57th Avenue, New York, Manhattan.
Rym: So what do you pay you for an ad?
Rym: Is that just going out here?
Scott: No, he was just real friendly and his psychological tricks worked on me despite me trying.
Scott: I avoided the trick of judging the mattress by the price, but I couldn't avoid the trick of good salesmen.
Rym: So I had to go there at some point.
Rym: My mattress is getting old.
Scott: Oh, apparently the mattress I have.
Scott: I don't have to turn it over every six months.
Scott: I asked him, like, you know, so when, you know, should I turn my mattress over?
Scott: He's like, no, new mattresses don't have to turn them over.
Scott: Wow.
Rym: I got to turn mine over every six months.
Scott: He did have one trick that I didn't fall for, though.
Rym: I tried to sell you something.
Scott: Apparently the mattress has like a huge warranty, right?
Scott: Like if a spring pops out like in an old cartoon, I get, you know, they'll replace the whole thing.
Rym: So he tried to sell you some sort of special warranty.
Scott: Apparently, mattress companies, all the mattress manufacturers have a trick in their warranties.
Scott: If there's any stain whatsoever on the mattress, your warranty is just gone.
Scott: That's the trick.
Scott: So why is this a trick?
Scott: Because they want to sell you a mattress cover.
Rym: Wait, wait.
Rym: One of those plastic things.
Scott: No, no, no.
Scott: A mattress pad like I have already.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The thing is, so you had these fancy mattress pads and he was like, oh, this one is hypoallergenic and this one keeps the dust mites out and this one's waterproof.
Scott: And they're right.
Scott: And I was like, whoa, I don't need waterproof.
Scott: Well, he's like, imagine if you spill a glass of wine, you know, on your bed.
Scott: I'm like, well, you know, I'll lose my problem with that.
Rym: Is that if you want if you have a cheap mattress, then, yeah, like that artificial mattress pad, like pillow top cover, you need that.
Rym: But if you have a mattress that already has the pillow top on it and you don't care that it's eventually going to have the vague color of body oil in the part you sleep on, I think is I have a mattress pad.
Scott: He was trying to sell me a mattress pad for like 70 bucks.
Scott: That was all fancy.
Scott: And the thing was that mattress pad, a lot of the features of it that he claimed were duplicated in my already, you know, existing mattress.
Rym: I got a waterproof mattress.
Scott: No, not the waterproof part, but like, you know, the anti allergen dust mite parts, whatever.
Scott: I just ignored that anyway, but because I don't need that.
Rym: But regardless, I like you had to throw that in there just in case, like, oh, but I don't need that.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So I think is I'll just buy the same kind of mattress pad that I already have for a lot less than seventy dollars.
Scott: So I was like, no, no mattress pad.
Scott: Just deliver this to my apartment.
Scott: So thank you.
Rym: Fascinating.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But yeah, free naps.
Rym: Oh, yeah, until they realize you're not actually buying a mattress, then they don't let you back into the store, different disguise every day.
Rym: I don't have that many disguises.
Scott: Oh, go to different mattress stores like consecutive days with a disguise and rotate it around.
Rym: So anyway, you know, it's Thursday.
Rym: We always try to make Thursday just fun and mixed up.
Rym: And we don't have to.
Rym: it's not like we have to follow the format and do the news and all the stuff we normally do.
Rym: And it's time to do the book club, which we should have done last Thursday's show.
Rym: But I know I called Scott's bluff because he was like, well, I think the book will be done.
Rym: I'll finish it and we'll do the book club the next gig nights Thursday.
Rym: And I was like, OK.
Rym: And I didn't even bother finishing the book because I assume Scott wouldn't.
Rym: And then Scott finished the book and I didn't.
Scott: So that's right.
Rym: I had to.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So I made you look like a fool.
Rym: Yeah, but I finished the book anyway.
Scott: The long delayed book club.
Scott: I feel like we haven't done any Thursday episodes other than book clubs.
Scott: Like we just keep skipping Thursdays.
Rym: I said we haven't done the book club in forever.
Rym: And I how many of you actually read Stephen Wolf?
Scott: I think the thing is, from now on, starting today during the meta moment, I met a minute, whatever you want to call it.
Scott: Metamucil.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I'm going to keep saying that during the meta segment of our show, I'm going to announce the book club book every single show speaking.
Rym: I think that will help of which it's your turn to pick.
Rym: What is the next book club?
Scott: Well, we'll talk about that later.
Rym: Oh, we're going to the second half now.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So anyway, we read Steppenwolf now by what I want to say.
Scott: OK, I hope that's all you with that pronunciation.
Rym: Somebody emailed us and said Ehrman essay.
Scott: But yes, no, but someone emailed us who was like a scholar in this sort of, you know, in this German literature.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I am not, you know, putting them down in any way.
Scott: In fact, I think that's totally awesome.
Scott: And I totally respect everything that they have to say about this book.
Rym: You know, that is pretty much the standard boilerplate for dudes about to get punched intellectually.
Scott: No, not at all.
Scott: The thing is, right.
Scott: He was like basically in his email was like, you have to let me come on the episode where you talk about the show so I can talk about all these intellectual bits that you won't understand.
Scott: Just reading it once without, you know, the meta context of, you know, the scholarly knowledges and all that.
Scott: And you know what?
Scott: He's probably exactly right.
Scott: There's probably a whole bunch of shit we don't know.
Scott: We're going to sound like complete morons if like a literature scholar listens to this episode.
Scott: That's all correct.
Scott: The thing is, uh, the GeekNights Book Club, the goal is get people to read because people don't read books anymore as much read a book.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: So and I think that talking about a book in the scholarly way that we would appreciate as smart peoples that we are, would not really do such a good job of getting illiterates.
Rym: Scott, I will say this, you know what you've actually just said, what I am here by covering my ass to make sure that no one realizes that I did not analyze this book in any depth.
Scott: I analyze it in depth.
Scott: What I'm saying is that I want to get the guy to do to talk about all the scholarliness on another episode and not this episode.
Rym: I do agree with that.
Rym: I want to split up because it's kind of like I read Steppenwolf, not necessarily from the academic perspective.
Rym: Like if I was reading a book to analyze, like I used to do in high school and college or with certain books that I reread, like The Prince of Nothing, I'll sit there and like I'll analyze.
Rym: I'll take notes.
Rym: I'll think I'll try to like, oh, well, he quoted this.
Rym: I wonder if it was referencing this earlier and all that sort of stuff.
Rym: But I read this the way I would approach reading like any fiction novel.
Rym: I just read it straight up, just go, let's go.
Rym: I didn't go back.
Rym: I didn't find quotes again or anything.
Rym: And I just have my straight up unadulterated opinion.
Rym: I never read this book in school.
Rym: I never had anyone like analyze it for me or explain anything for me.
Rym: I even avoided looking at the Wikipedia page.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't look at the Wikipedia page at all.
Scott: I know nothing about this book other than what was in the book.
Rym: So I want to point out before we continue, if you have not already read Steppenwolf, stop listening, because we're about to talk about Steppenwolf as though you've already read it.
Scott: Can we really spoil Steppenwolf?
Rym: I mean, I kind of even then if someone listens, I'm not going to be like, so the plot was that there was this man named Herman Allen stabs a bitch.
Rym: The end.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, but just warning, we're going to spoil this book and it's not that spoilable, but I'd recommend you read it before you listen to what we're about to say.
Scott: Right.
Rym: So the first thing I want to jump right into the pretty much the biggest part.
Rym: I don't think Hermione was real.
Rym: I think that was just all in his head the whole time.
Scott: You don't think what was real?
Rym: The girl, the main character girl.
Rym: I don't think there was any from the very beginning when he first met her.
Scott: I was the way you said her name.
Scott: I guess I was mispronouncing your name where you are on her mind.
Rym: What are you going to call her?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Herman.
Rym: Her many.
Scott: I have no idea.
Rym: I go with Hermione.
Scott: OK, whatever.
Rym: That's probably just like hung himself.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But that's actually that gives us a good tangent.
Scott: This book is really written in German.
Scott: Right.
Scott: We're reading a translation.
Scott: Is that correct?
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So, I mean, I wonder what was lost in translation here.
Scott: Obviously something.
Scott: I mean, there's parts in this book where there are like poems and rhymes and various things of that nature.
Scott: You know, how well were those translated from, you know, the original?
Scott: I mean, you know, I was like every time something like that came up, a poem or a rhyme or something or some song lyrics or anything along those lines, like I always just thought like, huh, I wonder what I'm missing here, that it not being in German.
Rym: Well, here's a note from the translation.
Rym: This is the first revised edition of Basil Creighton's translation of 1929.
Rym: Whoa.
Rym: That's good in a way, because it was contemporary English.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Rym: In the revision, we were intent on a more exact.
Rym: So they revised it in 1963.
Rym: But the base is the 1929 one.
Rym: We exact and more readily understood rendition.
Rym: British spellings and idioms have been Americanized.
Rym: Germanisms removed, awkward sentences improved and misleading translations corrected.
Scott: I want the Germanisms, though.
Scott: Oh, well, yeah.
Rym: But how are you going to go down the road of the fan subs?
Scott: No, but I just wonder what I'm missing.
Rym: Yeah, well, I feel in any translated work, if you really if you go beyond, I mean, let's be perfectly honest here, right?
Scott: What's lost in translation matters a lot more in a great literary work than it does in an anime, even if it's a great anime.
Scott: I mean, come on.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Seriously.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So well, what I would just say is that if you're going to take any work seriously, like if you really like if Steppenwolf meant something to you beyond just being a novel, you got to learn German and read in German.
Rym: Well, what I would recommend is in the very least read of any work like this, a literal kind of translation and independently of that, a kind of like modernly rendered, you know, proper translation.
Scott: Not a bad idea either.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Usually reading multiple translations, you can sort of add them together and sort of sort of infer what the original route was that someone could translate in those two different ways.
Rym: But pretty much from the beginning, I just I figured that she was completely in his head and that was all just either in his head or in the very least he was you know, the character was taking his experience and writing about it as though the experience, everything was this girl, you know, because this is all read by the other main character nominally.
Scott: Well, yes, that's the thing, right?
Scott: You look at this book as a whole, right?
Scott: And what really drew me into the book was that first part where you have the guy talking about the Steppenwolf who lived in his same apartment building as he was.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And that part was pretty awesome.
Scott: And then the rest of the book is not the Steppenwolf talking directly.
Scott: But this dude read, you know, reading the memoirs that the Steppenwolf left behind.
Scott: And he even says straight up like, yeah, I think a lot of the stuff in here is obviously not real.
Scott: And I basically assumed like, OK, not all this anything in it that happens here that is fantastic in any sort of way is obviously not real.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: But I'll go one step further and say that even the non fantastic meeting with this girl was completely.
Scott: Well, I mean, as soon as he pretty much from the point in the.
Scott: Memoirs where he like started seeing like the words appear like, you know, not for everyone.
Scott: I was like, yeah, it's not from here on out.
Scott: Everything's fake.
Rym: We'll see
Scott: hints of truth here and there, like
Rym: having read other works by the author, I just I kind of got this impression that the intent there was to kind of express the this meta intent, the intent of the Steppenwolf, the guy writing this memoir, was that he had a profound revelation.
Rym: and the profound revelation, if he had just explained the revelation, would not have felt so profound to someone analyzing it or reading about it, who didn't actually experience it.
Rym: So he translated his, you know, internal experience into this fantastical experience in order to express upon other people just the gravity of the feeling that he felt and the gravity of what happened to his life in his mind.
Rym: So, you know, he didn't literally find a magic theater.
Rym: He had some revelation that would have felt like finding a magical theater that opens your mind.
Scott: And I think I think the part where he went to the to the professor's house, that was probably that was one of my favorite scenes.
Scott: That was pretty good.
Scott: That was probably actually a mostly.
Scott: I mean, like we talk about this, like, oh, that part was real.
Scott: That part wasn't.
Scott: the whole book is a work of fiction, right?
Scott: It's one of those books in a book.
Scott: And the thing is, the book in a book always feel you think that would be sort of cliche.
Scott: But every time I see the book in a book or even the book in a book in a book, which I have seen, it's out there, it works like really well.
Scott: I guess it's because nobody dares to do it unless they they're going to do it.
Scott: well, you know.
Rym: But that's that whole scene where he sees that painting of Goeth and he's just like, fuck you painting.
Rym: But actually, the reason I like that scene, too, is the thing is, I can really identify with that.
Scott: You like how many times I see a painting of like some old historic character or a fictional character.
Scott: And I'm like, that's not what the fuck that dude looks like.
Scott: But that wasn't his feeling.
Rym: It was more it was such a complex feeling that at first he appreciates the painting and then he goes through these different like he and like he sees the painting and all these different layers.
Rym: And every time he peels away a layer, he gets more and more pissed off about the painting.
Rym: But that scene, too, is up until that point, the book pulls a couple of switcheroos on the Steppenwolf, because first, from the perspective of the dude just reading the memoir, you know, that bourgeois guy reading the memoir, the Steppenwolf is this fascinating and alluring character.
Rym: And he seems cool.
Rym: He seems powerful.
Rym: You think that is a man.
Rym: Look at that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, like, look at what the dude says about the Steppenwolf in the scene where they're like both in the music house and this or no, when they both go to see the lecturer and Steppenwolf gives them a look and he's like, oh, that look is incredibly powerful.
Scott: Look, that's, you know, said so much.
Scott: Oh, my God.
Rym: And then you get you get inside the Steppenwolf's head with his memoir.
Rym: And again, like, oh, it's a man of two natures.
Rym: You feel like you're going along a certain way.
Rym: And then you find the Steppenwolf treatise and it's basically like, yeah, stupid old Steppenwolf making bullshit up in your head.
Rym: That's all just crap.
Rym: And you know it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I liked how, you know, it was totally right.
Scott: It was like, you know, you sort of prevent for they present you with this analogy of, you know, that the the duality of the wolf and the man and whatever.
Scott: And then.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And then the Steppenwolf book, the Steppenwolf treatise shows up and is like, look, is actually like a thousand bajillion components to the man.
Scott: that are all, you know, blah, blah, blah.
Scott: It's like you can't possibly even understand.
Scott: It's so complex.
Scott: It's like, oh, yeah, that's right.
Scott: It's like someone gives you an analogy.
Scott: And then, you know, at least in the book, they can just make this fictional world match that analogy.
Scott: So you totally buy into it.
Scott: And then they sort of just like hit you over the head to remind you.
Scott: It's like, no, shit ain't that simple.
Scott: Stupid.
Scott: It's like but then it was very refreshing.
Rym: Even then, you still you know, the way he reacts to the treatise and all that, you still feel like they're all these scenes where you feel like he's a a powerful and enigmatic and cool figure in general.
Rym: But the scene where he just kind of loses his cool and yells at the professor and like all of that together.
Rym: And as the book goes on, you start to realize that, no, he's kind of just a jerk and a loner and he did it all to himself and he works himself up into these just fevers of just I don't know, he gets mad about stupid things for no good reason.
Rym: He blames it on himself and he's Steppenwolf and he's not a very likable fellow, both within and without.
Scott: Well, I mean, the thing that I thought is like, you know, they build him up sort of early on, you know, they show him like saying really wise things like what was that really wise thing?
Rym: He said, oh, God, as the beginning, never, never have I read a book more quotable than this book.
Rym: But there are quotes that you have to memorize.
Scott: They're like paragraph long quotation, just like my favorite one was still that one that was in the introductory part, like talking about men who live in their time and before their time and after their time.
Scott: No, but about, you know, men were made for land, you know, and that was the analogy at the end of that.
Rym: But the whole thing before that was that, you know, the men who suffer, those who were born before the time where they would, you know, that's right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: That one, too.
Scott: Both of those pretty much.
Scott: I sort of feel like that.
Scott: both of those are what the books about, but regardless, the I forget what I was saying.
Scott: Right.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Like men were made for, you know, the land.
Scott: And if you go into the sea and the sea, if you go in the sea, then you'll you know, you'll eventually drown.
Scott: And how I forget how much I had the exact quote.
Scott: and on the book in front of me, I thought about getting all the.
Rym: early on when I was reading, I was thinking, oh, that's a good quote.
Rym: I was noting them.
Scott: all like these are things I want to bring up, but not things that you can say quickly, like I Caramba.
Rym: Well, not only that, I realized that this book is one of those quotation per page books where it's just insight upon insight upon insight and quotation upon quotation upon quotation.
Rym: And there are so many just half paragraph long aphorisms that I don't know what to say.
Rym: They're brilliant.
Rym: I just have to memorize them all because there is a quote for every occasion in Steppenwolf.
Scott: If you need to put someone down, it's like Queen, they got a song for every possible scenario.
Rym: It's exactly that.
Rym: If you need to be able to just trump anyone in any kind of philosophical argument, there is a Steppenwolf quote for you that will be relevant to whatever it is that you're talking about.
Scott: There's a lot of things like that.
Scott: I mean, you could probably do the same with like a playdoh, you know, you just any situation.
Scott: I got a playdoh for that.
Scott: Watch out.
Rym: Yeah, but the Steppenwolf ones are more pragmatically relevant to the real world.
Scott: Yeah, I think it's weird.
Scott: It feels like the book is set up in a way at least that like I feel like, you know, it's like you read it and there are certain parts that you can like strongly relate to and there are certain parts that you don't.
Scott: But I sort of feel like the book was constructed so that no matter who you are, if you read it, you're going to strongly relate to some portion of it.
Rym: Well, I think that's why on purpose people seem to really have very mixed feelings about this book.
Rym: And a lot of people identify with it in basically completely opposite ways for the completely opposite reasons.
Rym: I think it's because the idea of the Steppenwolf, like the idea of what he is, feels very alluring because it's almost this cop out, this answer like, ah, that explains me.
Rym: I feel like the Steppenwolf.
Rym: sometimes I feel like the outsider.
Scott: That's the thing is they show you the Steppenwolf feeling so many different ways that you felt some of those ways before, no matter who you are, if you're a human being.
Scott: And you sort of identify with those commonalities you have with the Steppenwolf and then those, you know, the things that you have in common with the Steppenwolf, you know, sort of grow larger in your view of him and the things you don't have in common with him sort of grow smaller.
Scott: So then he just looks like you no matter who you are.
Scott: But he looks different to every person because every person is a different person.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And you could go one step further and say that the book means whatever you really wanted it to mean.
Rym: But it does.
Rym: it does it kind of cleverly where I could see people seeing the end of this book as a tragedy and as a victory, like I could see both interpretations.
Rym: And I think it's really just a reflection of what kind of person you are as to how you take it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The thing is, I took it sort of like in this weird, completely neutral way.
Scott: You know, it's like I just didn't like.
Rym: I took it that I took it.
Rym: I felt a lot at the end of the book, probably the same way Mozart felt about the Steppenwolf at the end of the book, just shaking your head like, dude, you just didn't get it.
Scott: That was so weird when the Mozart showed up.
Scott: That was great because because it was kind of like I just I just like imagined it like this crazy movie, like like suddenly Mozart appears and like I imagine I got my imagination of it was like completely unlike what was actually written.
Scott: Like I saw them like sitting like in chairs somewhere with like stars everywhere, like they were in outer space or something.
Rym: I got that exact same vibe.
Rym: Really?
Rym: And I think why?
Rym: Because he hinted this all the time and it was when he looked at that painting of Goeth and then later when he, you know, he talks about the celestial immortality and all those things.
Rym: There is that feeling and I know you've experienced it.
Rym: I know I've experienced.
Rym: I think a lot of people have experienced it where you.
Rym: it's easy to forget that the immortals of the world and when I say immortals, I mean, you know, really.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: People who effectively became immortal through their works, though not obviously living forever somewhere in a bunker.
Scott: Elvis.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Not like Elvis.
Rym: But the whole the idea that is very easy to forget that they were people and to something to esteem upon their works, almost undo praise, maybe not undo is not the word, but it's almost easy to feel that they were transcendent geniuses.
Rym: They perceive the world beyond what anyone today could or beyond what I could, that they're beyond me.
Rym: And to strive for genius is to strive for this unattainable, peaceful, the celestial laughter of the sky and all those sorts of things.
Rym: And you see the step of doing that, like he envisions these people, like he hates that painting of Goeth, but that's exactly how he sees Mozart.
Rym: His mental picture of Mozart is the same as that painting.
Rym: And he didn't realize it.
Rym: And then he meets Mozart and Mozart.
Scott: Mozart is just totally normal, like a jerk like everybody.
Scott: Yeah, Mozart was a jerk like everyone.
Scott: I mean, you know, whenever I start to like, you know, like praise famous people in that sort of way, which I do on occasion, you know, like raise, you know, these these sort of figures up to like a above human level, you can always think about Van Gogh is just completely nuts.
Scott: But and that brings me back down.
Rym: I think that's why we both pictured the same idea of like Mozart and all these people kind of sitting serenely among the stars, laughing the laughter of the immortals and this sort of.
Rym: and that's what the Steppenwolf felt.
Rym: And he felt like that's what he was striving for.
Rym: And that's what he had to do.
Scott: They were laughing at him, not with him.
Rym: Except that's literally because that is kind of the point of the book.
Rym: I think that, you know, Mozart was a normal person and he got the world.
Rym: He got it.
Rym: He laughed at it.
Rym: At least Mozart of this book.
Rym: Maybe not the real Mozart.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, it depends on what version of Mozart you're looking at.
Scott: Oh, I could Salieri genius.
Rym: These are originals.
Scott: OK.
Scott: Oh, man.
Rym: But that whole scene at the end, it actually reminded me I don't actually I got to.
Rym: I need some help.
Rym: Listeners, I saw something when I was a kid.
Rym: I don't know if it was a film, a short film.
Rym: I have no idea what it was.
Rym: But it kept cutting between this old man talking about how he realized that he can sharpen pencils with a knife rather than using a pencil sharpener by just going around the edge with the knife.
Rym: And these clowns in like this World War One prison and they kept making jokes and it ended with the clown giving the greatest joke of all.
Rym: And he says he's going to do a magic trick for everyone.
Rym: And then they put him up against the wall and they shoot him and he just dies.
Rym: And that was the trick.
Rym: And I have no idea what this was.
Rym: And like I have these student film.
Rym: No, it was on TV, whatever.
Rym: But I was the whole end of Steppenwolf from the murder cars all the way to the end.
Rym: I couldn't think of anything but this film and I have no idea what it is.
Rym: And I wish I had more to explain, but I don't.
Rym: There's a tank in it at one point, like World War One kind of tank.
Scott: I think one thing that was weird for me was that like murder cars.
Scott: No, no, no.
Scott: Like earlier in the book, I sort of you know, I sort of was imagining like an older time, like, you know, obviously, I mean, what's the time period for this is like earlier 1900s, I'm guessing.
Rym: The book was written, you know, between World War One and World War Two.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But I was sort of like imagining it in like an almost like almost a Victorian world.
Scott: Like I was imagining shit being old, like way, you know, much older.
Scott: And then like as the book got later on, you know, it's like the time, at least in the imagining in my head, like pushed it way up, like I was almost imagining like, you know, the 20s, you know, which I guess is what it's supposed to be.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So it's like the way there was something about, you know, it you know, it started when like you met the girl and that sort of thing.
Scott: You know, the book like the time just fast forward in my head, sort of imagining like a different time period.
Rym: Well, I feel the book was very timeless.
Rym: And I think ahead of its time in its perception of technology and the future.
Rym: I mean, murder car aside, that whole part near the end where there was the talk of like modern world and the changing world and the whole idea that every generation feels like this is the end and everything's coming to chaos.
Rym: That was true.
Rym: But, you know, it's one thing we know that it's one of those things where, you know, that I know that the world's not falling apart anymore now than it was during the Greek Dark Ages.
Rym: Well, I guess it really was falling apart during the Greek Dark Ages, but it was a renaissance.
Rym: But that aside, like the whole every generation, like everything's falling apart.
Rym: And yet to read the feeling of that in a book from the 30s to so literally see someone describing the decay of society exactly the way someone like me would feel it and describe it today in almost the exact same words, more
Scott: shit changes, more shit stays the same.
Rym: That whole murder car segment and the whole thing where Mozart pulls out the crappy gramophone.
Rym: He's like, listen to that.
Rym: You can still hear the music even through the static.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: That was that part with the gramophone.
Scott: That was fucking sweet.
Scott: That was brilliant because I was like, hells yeah.
Scott: You know, there's the obvious surface level shit of shut the fuck up audio files.
Scott: But, you know, it's like it's so true.
Scott: It's not the the actual, you know, the the the like the the details of the sensory input that really matter.
Scott: You know, it's like you can dance to it just as well.
Scott: If it's, you know, full of static as if it's not as long as it's dance, as long as the signal is coming through, it's all good.
Rym: You know, you can leave your friends behind.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And that, you know, that analogy is good for, you know, so many different kinds of messages.
Rym: I think it was a broader metaphor, though, for it was.
Rym: it was back to the whole Mozart thing of.
Rym: he imagines this perfect clarity of, you know, the immortals of Mozart, of these people, of these achievements of genius.
Rym: And he doesn't realize that the real world is full of static and noise and that nothing's ever as clear cut and perfect as he wants it to be in his head.
Rym: And in the real world, you have to just accept the static and listen for the music behind the static.
Rym: But if you look for just the music and you issue the static, you'll never find anything.
Rym: And you'll die and boring old lonely man who may or may not have had gay orgy sex while taking cocaine.
Scott: May or may not.
Rym: Actually, a funny moment when he when when he was talking to Hermione about Maria, who I want to talk about her separately, and he there's the point at which he's asking her like Maria tells him about something or Hermione tells him about some like technique of kissing that Maria
Scott: had
Rym: and they talk about it and they're like, oh, no, we can't.
Rym: we can't talk about that yet.
Rym: We're not lovers yet.
Rym: And then he thinks about it for a second and he wonders how the two girls would be so acquainted with each other's ways of loving.
Rym: And there's a sentence somewhere near the end of that chapter where he's basically like.
Rym: and then the Stephen Wolf considered these brave new ramifications of the world or something like that, which is this kind of thinly veiled lesbian joke that was I found.
Rym: I laughed out loud.
Scott: One thing that I've noticed and I sort of have a theory about this, right.
Scott: All the literature is that I read, you know, when I was you know, when I was in school, most of the books that I read that were highbrow or because school told me to and, you know, sexy parts were there, but not often for, you know, school politically correct bullshit reasons.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And I've sort of noticed that, like almost all of the highbrow books I've read in college and then since usually have some strong sexual elements to them.
Scott: And I think pretty much like I'm getting the feeling is my theory that all the highbrow literature has strong sexual elements and that schools are basically like desperate.
Scott: They pretty much give you all the ones that don't, which is pretty much all they got.
Scott: That's why everyone reads all the same books in high school because the only ones that are not offensive.
Rym: Sadly, I'm very surprised that more high school.
Rym: I mean, this would be Stephen Wolf is like the perfect book to give to like a senior high school class.
Scott: I read Siddhartha as a senior in high school, same dude, but that didn't have nearly as much sexiness in it.
Rym: I got to read that again.
Rym: That was a good book.
Scott: Yeah, it was good.
Scott: I like that one.
Scott: I like it better than this one.
Rym: Oh, really?
Rym: See, I got to read Demian again.
Rym: I don't know Demian more or not.
Scott: So I mean, as as something to read, to enjoy.
Scott: I mean, like I didn't really enjoy Stephen Wolf that much.
Scott: Like, it's not something I would read because I want to, you know, it wasn't like fun or pleasant, but I thought it both fun and pleasant.
Scott: It was it was intellectually stimulating and it wasn't intellectually draining, which is which a lot of things are.
Scott: It was a book that that's a point in its favor, but it wasn't like a pleasure.
Rym: It was a book that really forced me to analyze a lot of things about myself, to be honest.
Rym: And while I didn't necessarily change any of my opinions, I analyzed them and I thought about a lot of kind of very personal, internal things.
Scott: I also do that with any book that doesn't suck.
Rym: I also I didn't analyze anything in myself when I read Hyperion.
Rym: It was a good book, but it was.
Rym: it was not an introspective book.
Rym: It was an extrospective book.
Scott: I did a little bit when I was thinking about the the console guy.
Rym: Yeah, anyway, no, the only inward looking thing I thought at the end of that, not to not to spoil, but when you find out who the traitor is, the first thing I thought was the fuck is wrong with me that I didn't see this guy.
Rym: Like I just I draw.
Rym: I sat the book down.
Rym: I'm like, am I that stupid?
Rym: Am I really that stupid?
Scott: Yes.
Rym: And yes, we all are.
Scott: All right.
Rym: But I feel like if I had read Steppenwolf when I was younger, I might have turned out slightly differently because I was closer to being the Steppenwolf when I was younger than I am now.
Rym: Perhaps I'm talking like if I had read this in like middle school, I would have been a slightly different person or in the very least, I think I would have become the person I am now more rapidly than I did.
Scott: Maybe the thing is, it's weird.
Scott: It's like, you know, I've obviously consumed a great deal of media in all mediums, right, that are available to us as, you know, human beings.
Scott: And while there is no doubt that many of them have probably changed who I am or contributed to me being the way I am today, I can't actually make a lot of like direct connections like because I read that book at that time.
Scott: That's why I do this.
Scott: I can't really do any of it's weird.
Rym: I can, but only in retrospect, like, you know, I watched Captain Tyler a long time ago and I missed a bunch of episodes and all that.
Rym: But I watching it again now.
Rym: It's almost frightening to see how influential it probably was on me.
Scott: I think that is maybe if I did like reread something that I read way back and then remembered when I read it originally.
Rym: I think that's what you have to do.
Scott: Yeah, I don't do a lot of that, though.
Scott: I try to always get something new because, you know, I try not to do repeats, especially on something as, you know, time consuming as a book.
Rym: It's so difficult, though.
Scott: I mean, my coworker, this book is time consuming.
Scott: I read it in a few days.
Rym: My coworker watched some Cowboy Bebop and he was like, man, that scene.
Rym: And he started talking about a scene.
Rym: And all I could think was I got to watch Cowboy Bebop again.
Rym: Jesus Christ.
Scott: I started rewatching it again like some months ago, but then I stopped before I finished it.
Rym: I think I'm going to rewatch it again.
Scott: I already did that recently.
Scott: I watched the whole thing on the train some months ago.
Scott: Anything else you got to say about Der Steppenwolf?
Rym: Murder car.
Scott: Murder car.
Scott: That was that was I think, you know, I said the book was unpleasant, you know, well, not.
Scott: but, you know, wasn't really fun.
Scott: The part at the end with all the doors and the murder cars and all that, that was probably the most enjoyable part, other than the very, very introductory part where it wasn't the step before you actually read the Steppenwolf's memoirs themselves.
Rym: Each of the doors, I was fat.
Rym: I felt like I identified with him one last time where I I desperately wanted to enter several of the doors that he did not enter.
Rym: And I was kind of pissed off that he entered murder car, of all things, because there were better doors than murder car.
Scott: Well, you could tell that like he was, you know, sort of still resisting, you know, you know, look at the whole metaphor, the the room with the chess pieces.
Rym: And he got them out and he kept wanting to use the chess pieces and make worlds and make lives and rearrange everything.
Rym: But he kept getting distracted by all the other doors.
Rym: And then eventually it was too late.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: That was a important part.
Rym: Also, the have every girl door.
Scott: I would have just stayed in that one forever.
Rym: But that was that was I think that was one of the most powerful parts of the book.
Scott: Just that, you know, as I wondered, I mean, which dude does not have pretty much all that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like there is not a guy, a human, a man on earth who cannot identify with that door and what happens beyond it.
Scott: Not one.
Rym: But think about the moral of that door.
Rym: The moral of that is basically Courage Wolf.
Rym: The moral of that door is literally Luke Morgan's ask every girl out.
Rym: Don't be a pussy.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: That's kind of the moral of the book.
Rym: I mean, really, if you break it down, I mean, there are a lot of higher morals and there's a complex.
Scott: And I'm sure, you know, according to the dude who is all scholarly, he's like, yeah, nobody really understands this book on their first go.
Scott: So we're probably totally wrong.
Rym: It's a complicated book and it says a lot.
Rym: But I think complicated man, the core understands the core moral of the book.
Rym: to break it down into a very, very simple and possibly vulgar vernacular is do drugs at least once in your life.
Rym: Don't be a pussy.
Rym: Live a little.
Rym: Have an orgy at least once.
Rym: I'm not kidding.
Rym: Like it's basically a just live your life.
Rym: Listen to the music through the static.
Rym: Don't worry about the static.
Rym: Do the best you can.
Rym: Don't be a pussy.
Rym: Seriously, don't be a pussy.
Rym: Good God.
Rym: Just don't be a pussy.
Rym: Don't strive for things that don't exist.
Scott: Dance.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Learning to dance is like a large, large portion of the book.
Rym: It was a good metaphor to notice how it culminated in a dance.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Incredibly long and multi-dance.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: I like that one part of the dance where like, you know, the one girl's like, oh, you're you suck.
Scott: And then later she's like, whoa, you don't suck anymore because he transformed just by getting in.
Rym: Well, actually, that's my going into hell because, you know, I'm back.
Scott: I'm sure you've had again.
Rym: And I know a lot of people experience this and part of that's why I think people identify with the Steppenwolf.
Rym: He's at like the concert when he sees all the people around him, like enraptured by the concert or like he sees that he has this impression of other people, that they are fully engaged by the concert, by the music.
Rym: They're dancing.
Rym: They're enjoying themselves.
Rym: They're doing whatever.
Rym: But he is distracted in his own mind and he can't lose himself in the music.
Rym: He's thinking about all these other things.
Rym: And as a result, he feels a part.
Rym: All those other people are drawn into this thing.
Rym: And I am not.
Rym: I'm the Steppenwolf.
Rym: I am.
Rym: He's thinking about all these other things.
Rym: He can't be drawn in and he feels like he's missing out and he doesn't know why.
Rym: And it bothers him.
Scott: And he just and he starts thinking about it.
Scott: Why am I missing out?
Scott: And that doesn't help you.
Scott: That's basically just going the opposite direction.
Rym: I'm sure you felt that you're at a concert.
Rym: But you get the the matter where you start thinking after the concert, what do I do where I should move my arms in the air?
Scott: Well, I mean, a lot of people have problems like that, like they can't go to sleep because they just keep thinking about shit or like lately.
Scott: I just been thinking about all this shit I got to do for moving and I can't like do other stuff.
Rym: But look, the the only time in this whole book, well, one of the only times.
Rym: Well, no, the only
Scott: time you're drowning in your thinking
Rym: when he's happy, really, are when he just gives in and actually is able to enjoy what he is doing for what he is doing without worrying about the details of what he is doing and without trying to ascribe whatever he's doing to some higher purpose when he loses himself and making love to Maria, when he loses himself at the ball at the end.
Rym: Those are the only times he loses himself.
Rym: And he's not like he becomes stupid or like literally loses his mind.
Rym: He just gives in and doesn't.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Also, I just sort of say, you know, he gets those, you know, there's that theater and it's like not for everyone for Mad Men only.
Scott: Oh, shit.
Scott: You know, and that's sort of like mysterious kind of shit like that.
Scott: Like, I love that kind of action.
Scott: Like what was that Schwarzenegger movie?
Scott: Last Action Hero.
Scott: Ah, where they go like that mysterious movie theater.
Scott: You know, you know all that.
Scott: I love that kind of shit.
Rym: I'll say straight up.
Rym: That was a pretty good movie for what it was.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I just I just, you know, whatever.
Scott: There's that sort of like mysterious crap like that.
Scott: Like, I like that.
Rym: Oh, we didn't even get to talk about it.
Rym: I don't want to get into it.
Rym: We've already gone on a while, but the whole thing about the bourgeois and just the whole, you know, the comfortable people never accomplish anything.
Rym: They're always torn between two worlds, the the very poor and the very rich and the adventure and all the all the ways that you can be forced to live life.
Rym: And then like the the middle class of mind, life is the worst one because you can't you're not ever shaken up and you basically live this comfortable, precarious existence forever.
Rym: The clean doorstep and all that.
Rym: And there's a lot to say about that, but we've gone on long enough.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: All righty.
Rym: So what's the next book?
Scott: We can do things of the day.
Rym: There's Scott.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So no things the day to day.
Scott: This is going to be weird.
Scott: The next book.
Scott: Well, OK, so the goal of the book club is to get people to fucking read.
Scott: Right.
Rym: I suggested The Little Prince.
Scott: That's a good one.
Scott: We'll do that next.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I'm trying to think what book is going to get people to read.
Scott: So I'm like, aha, I know what we'll get people to read.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You can't come out with like some book they never heard of because then they might not want to read it.
Rym: You might have to come up with a book that everyone's heard of, but no one's read.
Scott: Well, the thing is, it's not a but I didn't come up with one that everyone's heard of, but no one's read.
Scott: I came up with one that everyone's heard of, but probably not everyone's read.
Scott: Right.
Scott: At least I haven't read it in like a bajillion years.
Scott: And once, like, you know, like they hear it and we give them an excuse.
Scott: There's like they're going to be like, oh, you can't I got to read it.
Scott: How could I not?
Scott: Right.
Scott: So the book.
Scott: And I also I wanted to pick one that would be, you know, sort of fun and entertaining and not so heavy and intellectual and brainy.
Scott: You know, that way, you know, everyone could sort of get into it and, you know, not like shy away from something that might be all schoolish.
Scott: And also I wanted to get something that be relatively short and easy to read.
Scott: I went, you know, I'm like, what?
Scott: There couldn't possibly be a better book, at least not within like.
Scott: after I thought of it like a couple of weeks ago, I could not think of any possible better book club.
Scott: pick for a show called GeekNights.
Scott: All right.
Scott: And you still have no idea what it is, dude.
Rym: Maybe one of those chocolate war kind of books.
Scott: No, not even close.
Scott: OK, the book we are going to read is you're in the right.
Scott: No, OK.
Scott: Not that one either.
Scott: It is the Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy.
Scott: Now, they they have a like a huge mega deluxe editions that have like all the books in it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I am only assigning you kiddies the very first original Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy book.
Rym: All right.
Rym: A little hint.
Rym: A lot of people probably have not actually read these this book or any of them.
Rym: What I will recommend is that, like Scott said, you're brilliant.
Rym: This is your excuse to read them and never let anyone know your dark secret.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I haven't read it since like forever.
Scott: I barely remember half of it.
Rym: So I remember listening to radio dramas of it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I remember there's the radio drama and there's the more recent movie that I never saw, but I saw the trailer radio drama, which is brilliantly.
Rym: voice acted good.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, quick.
Rym: They're coming.
Rym: Nobody.
Scott: So everyone go on Amazon buy a link.
Scott: I'm going to link to like the the mega deluxe edition that includes like all this stuff and also link to just, you know, the original book by itself with nothing extra added.
Scott: And that's all we're going to talk about.
Scott: We're only going to talk about the very first book.
Scott: We're not going to talk about, you know, like freaking Sammons of Doubt or any shit like that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So keep that to yourself.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays we have video games, board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights and Thursdays are the catch alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives, visit the website, which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Scott: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.