Rym: It's Thursday, April 30th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: Chrysler's bankrupt and this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we talk about how to not suck at eating out.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: We're back.
Scott: Oh no.
Scott: Evan, I sort of, you know, this isn't like big news or anything, but I sort of gave up on, suffice to say, not because there's anything wrong with it on the, from the user perspective, but because I'm certain administrating the behind the scenes of it, it's basically poop right now.
Scott: It's super poop.
Scott: It's terrible.
Scott: Laconica is not so good.
Rym: It has a very high total cost of ownership, I would say that.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Because I mean, I kind of poked at it every now and then and I can see
Scott: like they have, they have an admirable goal of making it as easy to use and set up as WordPress, which is, you know, they, they're on the right track, you know, they want it to be that they know what's right, but it's not going, it's not actually going in that direction right now.
Scott: It's a huge pain in the ass.
Scott: It sucks.
Rym: See, now here's the thing.
Rym: It would have been okay if it had at least properly integrated with all the Twitter stuff, but it did kind of, kind of, but a lot of the applications didn't work with it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: A lot of embedded.
Scott: I think that's actually, that's actually more a problem of the Twitter clients, not, you know, because, uh, Laconic has the same exact API as Twitter.
Scott: It's like any Twitter app should actually be able to work with Laconic.
Scott: All you have to do is be able to change the URL, but what I was saying is that the change, the URL feature, that's what I was saying, that almost every app just hard codes, Twitter, and you're fucked.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: They hard like tweet deck could work perfectly with Laconica, except you can't change the URL from twitter.com to like, you know, whatever your Laconica is.
Scott: So anyway, it was, well, I guess a lot of it's open source, so you could, you could, but anyway, it's a huge pain in the ass, right?
Scott: To run this thing.
Rym: We should have just taken every open source Twitter app and just forked it to Laconica.
Scott: Anyway, uh, the thing is you need to change the URL to the specific Laconica server.
Rym: I fork it to where there's a text box.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: Um, but anyway, it's a huge pain in the ass, but people like it.
Scott: People were using it and I sort of feel bad shutting them off.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I'm just gonna let it sit there.
Scott: I'm not touching it ever unless, you know, if it breaks, it's going to stay broken.
Scott: I'm not going to fix it.
Scott: If it continues to work, I'm going to let it continue to work.
Rym: A spam farm.
Rym: It'll disappear.
Scott: Well, that's true.
Scott: Um, uh, but you know, maybe someday, you know, like maybe Laconica 1.0 will be very nice.
Scott: And in that case I will upgrade to.
Rym: at this point, I really predict that Twitter just one and Twitter is going to be there until something else completely takes it over.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Uh, so I just sort of stopped using it really.
Scott: And I'm just using Twitter and it's, it's way better because everyone else is actually using it.
Rym: Yeah, I'm, I'm switching.
Rym: I have a Twitter account that the only thing in there was stuff automatically sent from Laconica and that stopped working at some point.
Scott: I started, you know, and the thing is, you know, I read an article today that was totally true.
Scott: It's one of those things like, duh.
Scott: You know, I remember the article that said, uh, every people, everyone installs iPhone apps, doesn't use them.
Scott: Right.
Scott: This article was like, most people who joined Twitter stop using it after like 30 days or bear or just they join, but they don't actually use it.
Rym: Well, think about it.
Rym: I mean, you hear about it in the news, especially now where all the mainstream media, like in Costa Rica, right?
Rym: We sat down and tried to watch some Spanish news and then we'd watched some CNN and all this stuff one night, you know, just to see what was going on in the world.
Rym: And every news was talking about Twitter.
Scott: Every news is talking about Twitter, all the newscaster sharing their Twitters.
Scott: You know, I even saw when I was in Florida on the TV, uh, I think CNN was using Skype to bring someone in for a video interview and there was a Skype logo on the screen.
Scott: So it's like, really?
Scott: It's like, Whoa, the TV news is doing the same shit.
Scott: I do.
Scott: Why?
Scott: Why are they on TV?
Scott: I should be on TV.
Scott: I'm doing the same exact thing as they are.
Rym: Um, no, but you know, and then just, well, plus, I mean, Twitter is not that useful unless you're one of the people who is either going to use it for what it's good at or come up with a new way to use it.
Rym: Most people will use it for the novelty and they'll basically just be doing what that video did.
Scott: It's sort of the same problem that I had when I would, you know, with Facebook and things is that if you just log into it, right, if you make an account, if you don't actually use it, like you have to actually put in some effort, you have to go out and follow some people or friends, some people, and you have to, you know, type in some stuff.
Scott: You actually have to put some work into it to sort of, you know, crank them, you know, the flywheel and get it going.
Scott: And if you don't do that, you're just like, and you just look at it and try to figure it out, but you don't actually put in the work, you know, to get it going.
Scott: You're just going to go, what the fuck is this and stop and not even and just ignore it.
Rym: Well, I think a lot of people just don't have, you know, someone who's not super into the Internet and technology doesn't give you instant gratification is going to hear about it, think it's cool, think it's like Facebook.
Rym: They'll get on it and they'll start typing into it and I'll just type stuff for a while.
Rym: But they probably won't figure out to follow anyone or even have anyone to follow.
Rym: And then they'll give up.
Scott: I mean, Twitter sort of is helping itself now.
Scott: It's like when you when you make an account, it's sort of like tells you some interesting people to follow and sort of helps you automatically follow some famous people and stuff like that, you know, but whatever.
Scott: So.
Scott: But yeah.
Scott: Anyway, I was on the tweets and somebody I've messaged, you know, what, you know, show schedules you return to will probably do a Thursday tomorrow.
Scott: And people are real excited about a Thursday tomorrow.
Scott: So here it is.
Rym: So tomorrow became today and exactly didn't know what to do the show on until five minutes ago.
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: In fact, until about five minutes and twenty six seconds ago.
Scott: That's all right.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But we're not talking about Twitter.
Rym: Don't worry.
Scott: And, you know, we've been away from the show for a while, so we've built up quite a queue of things to discuss.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: And we want hope that we'll refrain from draining the queue in one episode.
Rym: I will point out for the uninitiated that Scott was in Florida for much of last week.
Scott: Well, we've got.
Scott: we got me in Florida.
Rym: Emily and I were in Costa Rica spending a couple of days in the Ocata resort.
Rym: And also the rest of our time in the cloud forest at the Continental Divide.
Scott: And also I was a job getting.
Scott: So there is a lot going on.
Scott: Anyway, you want to you want to go on to like news thing today?
Scott: What I guess.
Rym: But at least I can for a lot of people who I know are waiting for the show on Costa Rica.
Rym: Emily and I are going to record that probably this weekend, maybe Monday.
Rym: You'll get it at some point.
Rym: I also have I took like five hundred pictures, maybe a quarter of them are worth looking at.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, just dump them on the flicker and then delete the ones that I learned.
Rym: I can say one thing.
Rym: I learned a lot about S.L.R.
Rym: cameras.
Rym: Uh huh.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I kind of like S.L.R.
Rym: cameras.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I'd like it, too.
Scott: But it's sort of like Twitter.
Scott: You got to put some effort into it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anything else?
Rym: Thing is, you'd be amazed how quickly like how much you can learn from reading five minutes of a fact that says this is what this does and this is what I mean.
Scott: You know, my I'm still like trying to get more out of my digital camera because I've seen some my regular non S.L.R.
Scott: digital camera because I see other people like take amazing pictures of these freaking cameras.
Scott: You know, it's like the point and shoot things.
Scott: It's like I have one of those.
Scott: I have a pretty good one of those.
Scott: Why doesn't my picture look like that?
Scott: So I've been playing around with it a lot more.
Scott: And I think I've been taking better pictures with it.
Rym: Well, you know, I was looking at the kinds of pictures people take with my camera and I'm pretty much doing the best I can do.
Scott: Yeah, that's good.
Rym: With my two megapixels.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Time to move up to make.
Scott: I mean, the iPhone, I think it almost has two megapixels.
Scott: I don't even know.
Rym: Remember, we're at the point where megapixels matter a lot less than what kind of stuff is on the back end and the lenses.
Scott: The iPhones.
Scott: major problem is it doesn't have autofocus.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, it also doesn't really have lenses.
Scott: You can go and get lenses for it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I've seen pictures of those and those.
Rym: just that that's a side talking right.
Scott: there is a side talking.
Rym: So news that isn't the bird flu.
Rym: We're going to talk about that on Monday, probably.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Well, this is a this is sort of a Monday news.
Scott: So it but it's not bird flu or swine flu or so.
Scott: We have.
Scott: we have our Internet service from Cablevision.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they give you optimum voice, optimum TV and optimum.
Rym: You got to pay for it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But, you know, it's the way.
Scott: their plan is a pretty simple plan.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Is that if you get all three services, the triple play, they're 30 bucks each for a total of ninety dollars.
Scott: If you get just one service, it's fifty dollars.
Scott: So the Internet is fifty dollars.
Scott: The voice is fifty dollars.
Scott: The TV is fifty dollars.
Scott: But then, you know, you got HBO's and all sorts of packages going on there.
Scott: But that's typical.
Scott: They're coming out.
Scott: They're rolling it out real soon, like next month ish in certain places.
Scott: Optimum ultra, you know, an awesome ultra is.
Rym: Well, I do because you already told me I already read about it, but you can.
Scott: you can break the for ninety nine ninety nine, which is one hundred dollars.
Rym: Ninety nine.
Scott: They will give you also online Internet connection.
Rym: What is this, an ad?
Scott: Right.
Scott: I don't know what the upload speed is.
Scott: The download speed is one hundred and one megabits per second.
Rym: Now, there are many questions about this, as in what what can we expect from the upstream providers?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But I'm sure I mean, our upstream is like two.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So and our downstream is over 10.
Scott: It's like 14.
Scott: So I mean, the upstream of about 10 will keep it to the same.
Rym: Here's the question.
Rym: Is this always going to be unmetered?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I mean, you know, Cable Vision is actually one of the better Internet providers.
Scott: You know, they don't.
Scott: I've never gotten a complaint about bit torrenting or Pirate Bay or or anything like that.
Scott: They're just totally cool.
Rym: The thing that it's so totally.
Scott: they're not so good with the cable and some other things, but we don't care about that.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But here's the problem.
Scott: As an Internet service provider, Cable Vision is pretty awesome with our current with our current service.
Rym: It's already faster than we need.
Rym: I know because they won't let us host on that ultra whatever.
Rym: There's no way you can get the business class, but that's too expensive and not fast enough.
Scott: Well, you can get the business class with the ultra.
Rym: Even so, it's not going to be enough.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The thing is, I mean, one hundred and one is so fast.
Scott: First of all, you pretty much need gigabit.
Scott: If you actually are getting one hundred from the outside for the outside, you need a gigabit inside or else it's just not going to happen.
Rym: Well, now, because if you're fully switched, it won't really matter.
Rym: Well, remember, there's no collisions on a fully switched FTX.
Scott: No, no, but one hundred and one megabits per second is greater than so one hundred network.
Rym: You're going to lose that one megabit per second.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Oh, no.
Scott: I'm paying ninety nine dollars a month.
Scott: That's twelve hundred a year.
Scott: I want that one megabit.
Rym: You're not going to be able to use it.
Rym: And if you have a good switch and you have two computers connecting and you set it up right, you can still use that hundred and one with a hundred based network.
Scott: Oh, man.
Scott: But yet it's still that stupid fast.
Scott: Think about how fast you could download like a movie, like a full HD movie, like.
Scott: Pretty well, I mean, seriously, it's ludicrous speed.
Rym: All right, so but what about all these articles about how the Internet's going to slow down and stop and we're running out of bandwidth and everyone's going to have to meet her and it's too expensive.
Scott: Cablevision apparently disagrees with, you know, Comcast and Time Warner and everyone else.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I'm leery.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And Fios also seems to disagree.
Scott: It's like Verizon and Cablevision are like on one side.
Rym: like Fios, though, has a lot of problems.
Scott: It does.
Scott: But its problems are not bandwidth and speed.
Scott: Its problems are else.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But see the else.
Rym: when it comes to the fact that my co-workers come in every day and they're like, yeah, my files was down for like four hours last night.
Scott: Well, you know, you got to pay for business if you want reliability.
Scott: No.
Scott: But, you know, the problems are not bandwidth.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So on the bandwidth issue alone, you have Fios and Cablevision and then everyone else.
Scott: So I think that's interesting.
Rym: I think there's much more important news than the fact that you can get more Internet than you need.
Scott: One hundred and one megabits per second.
Scott: I need that for what I would pay for.
Rym: What would you use it for?
Scott: Oh, that would have been toward going all day getting what I would go buy like a NAS and load it up.
Rym: What would you get?
Rym: You know, there's a lot of stuff out there.
Scott: Every thing ever.
Rym: You don't like things.
Scott: Just because I can.
Rym: Scott, you used to hate the fanboys who did that.
Rym: Remember the guys at RIT who would go on the direct connect and download like four terabytes.
Scott: They were on a meager O.C.
Scott: three.
Scott: This is a is one hundred and one megabit.
Rym: They were on two O.C.
Rym: threes and a T3.
Scott: How is an O.C.
Scott: three?
Scott: One hundred and one megabits per second.
Rym: An O.C.
Rym: three is a lot.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But I don't know how much.
Scott: I don't think I don't know.
Rym: Remember, it was Internet, too, which actually means a lot more.
Scott: That does mean I would pay one hundred dollars a month to get an Internet to even without Internet one.
Rym: I can't express to you how much I would pay to have the legal right to use Internet to from my home.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Without having to go back to school.
Scott: I mean, and then have to pay.
Scott: You know, I had to buy like a Cisco router that would, you know, automatically route the Internet, two packets over one wire and the Internet one packets of the.
Rym: You know what?
Scott: If I ever get rich and then IPv6, I would pay so much.
Rym: If I ever get rich enough, I'll just pay to be a student again, be a student forever and just have my my connection to Internet, too, from my apartment on campus somewhere.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I would pay to be.
Scott: I know if I was rich enough, I would make a school.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Well, it's got school for the four gifted students.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: So Chrysler actually filed for bankruptcy.
Scott: Oh, no.
Rym: And I guess everyone saw this coming.
Rym: But I think I don't think I need to say they're going to be a lot of ramifications to this, not just in the business world, but mostly just any kind of public perception ripple.
Scott: Well, I think it's sort of a good thing, actually, in that if you look at history, right, at least the history of the United States, there have been a lot of brands.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And there are a lot of brands that were old and don't exist anymore.
Scott: I mean, you know, there was like they used to be cars from brands like Tucker or Studebaker.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And, you know, we used to have like, you know, I don't know, lots of stuff doesn't exist.
Scott: I don't.
Scott: Does RCA still exist?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Really?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: But there's lots of.
Scott: there's lots of brands that don't exist anymore.
Scott: But for a while now, in recent history.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Very few brands have died.
Scott: I think the last brand I can remember dying, at least major one, was like MCI.
Scott: You know, can you remember one more reason than that?
Scott: You know what?
Rym: Actually, I still call MCI all the time.
Rym: We have a lot of MCI circuits.
Scott: Really?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I thought they were dead.
Rym: They are dead.
Scott: OK.
Scott: But yeah, it's like.
Scott: I think that we do need to have sort of a, you know, a reminder, you know, I think it would have a good psychological helping to society if we realize that, you know, these brands aren't like, you know, permanent.
Rym: But the brands basically are permanent because bankruptcy doesn't mean Chrysler disappears.
Rym: Bankruptcy means Chrysler doesn't have to pay a lot of its debts and will reappear.
Scott: I know.
Scott: But it's still.
Scott: it's just to show that these things are vulnerable.
Scott: People think of these things as like, you know, like, like, like, like unmoving rocks, like, you know, things that are always there.
Scott: You know, they don't even think about the moving to know that these things can move and change and aren't like, you know, 100 percent stable, I think is how we'll see.
Rym: No, I think we need a much more fundamental change.
Rym: And my fear is that if only Chrysler goes down like this and Ford is probably going to pull through and, you know, all this stuff's going on, I feel like we're not going to change.
Rym: the fundamental problem that why do we make an incrementally better car every year and then have this whole like there's such a drive to get people to constantly buy new cars when now my 98 Sunfire is going pretty strong?
Scott: You know, I mean, people are talking a lot about this is that there is sort of like these rules of society that and we sort of treat them like their laws of physics.
Scott: We don't even think about changing them because they've become so ingrained.
Scott: But really, we can you know, there are things like you don't even question, like, why do you have, you know, like one model of every type of class of car for every brand?
Scott: Why do you make a new model every single year?
Scott: Why, you know, why do you do it this way?
Scott: You can do it differently.
Scott: There's no law saying you have to do it that way.
Rym: You can do whatever the hell you want.
Rym: I mean, we see this in everything.
Rym: You're all geeks.
Rym: Look at anime cons.
Rym: People start a new anime convention and they look at all the other conventions, say, well, I got to have a cosplay and I got to have some video rooms and I got to have the fan parodies and I got to have the cosplay ball and I got to have this and that.
Rym: And people just it's very rare to see anything kind of break away from the mold if there is an established mold already in place.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, why can't you have, say, an anime convention that's outside and is just one big thing and there's only one event and there's one schedule and everyone does all these things together and that's it.
Scott: And this food, you know, it could be like that's like nothing like anime conventions are now.
Scott: But if it's about anime, why is it still an anime convention?
Scott: It's a gathering of anime folks.
Rym: But everything in the car thing really bothers me just because a lot of cars like.
Rym: I look at them and I wonder who the hell's buying these cars.
Rym: I guess the answer was no one.
Rym: And that's why Chrysler is going out.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And the other thing is you look around.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And there are certain car models that are bought in crazy numbers like Honda Civic Toyota, Corolla Mazda three.
Scott: Mazda three is not bought in that crazy.
Rym: It's still bought a lot.
Scott: It's a very popular car.
Scott: Not as popular as the other two.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And there are other cars that are hardly bought.
Scott: You know, like you hardly ever see like, I don't know, Pontiac Solstice.
Scott: Right.
Scott: When do you see one of those?
Rym: You know what those guys like once a month, you got part of.
Rym: that is where we live.
Rym: Look at where we live.
Rym: We live in New York.
Rym: I know.
Rym: Go to the Midwest and you see a total like when I was in high school.
Rym: Right.
Rym: I drove a laser and the popular car in the area was a duster, a duster.
Rym: Everyone had a duster.
Scott: What's a duster?
Rym: Pretty crappy car.
Scott: I never even heard of one.
Rym: Anyway, I had my laser and a lot of people had lasers.
Rym: And when I left Michigan, I've seen like two lasers ever since I left Michigan.
Scott: It's like, you look at Ford, right?
Scott: Ford makes, let's see if I can name all their cars, but it's like, they've got, you know, a Mustang, they've got the focus, they've got, uh, the tourist equivalent.
Scott: I think they changed the name of it.
Scott: They got like three or four different trucks.
Scott: They got vans, they got right.
Scott: Why do you, you know, I mean, sure.
Scott: Every one of those types of vehicles is needed by someone, but why does every single car brand have to have one car in every class?
Scott: I mean, is it really necessary?
Rym: Well, even more, I noticed something.
Scott: I guess Mazda sort of breaks the mold.
Scott: They don't have any vans.
Scott: that, you know, I think they have like a, an SUV, a convertible, a normal car and a race car.
Rym: Well, one thing I noticed come kind of to the side, but it struck me suddenly that I was kind of thinking about buying a new car and I'm poking around.
Rym: And when I was a kid, I knew every make and model of car and I knew who made what, like.
Rym: I knew it all, like every single car that was a production.
Rym: I know a bunch, but I don't know all, but I used to know all.
Rym: And I realized the reason I did is I watched TV and you know, I listened to the radio and everything and there's a lot of car advertising seems to be the primary advertising.
Rym: There are more car ads than everything else.
Scott: Absolutely.
Rym: And you'd always, you know, the Ford, like a rock, cars, soft drinks, banks.
Scott: That's like the big ads.
Rym: They just like Ford focus just sounded right.
Rym: But it only sounded right because I heard Ford focus in the background from these commercials forever.
Rym: So now, you know, I haven't watched TV in like seven years really.
Rym: And I don't use, yeah, yeah.
Rym: From, from 2000, it has been nine years since I had cable TV or watched any appreciable amount of TV radio block ads on the internet.
Rym: So I like the solstice.
Rym: I didn't know it existed.
Scott: I knew it existed only because I saw one on the street.
Rym: Well, I didn't really, I'd see cars.
Rym: I didn't exist anymore.
Rym: Pontiac's gone, but I didn't know the Pontiac's gone, gone, or I'd see it.
Rym: Saturn's probably, maybe I'd see something like a solstice, but unless I looked for the logo, I wouldn't know who made it.
Rym: I didn't have that.
Scott: Whenever I see a car I've never seen before.
Scott: I always try to, I try to see what it is.
Rym: See, the other thing that helped was when I stopped driving and just started taking the train.
Rym: every day, I stopped seeing cars.
Scott: That's true too.
Rym: But I wonder if, you know, we're, you know, the affluent 20 something demographic, the demographic that is the most sought after in the world.
Rym: And yet at the same time, the most difficult to advertise to, I think our demographic more and more is disconnected from advertising and isn't affected by car advertising as much.
Rym: And as a result, probably at least in theory, spend a little bit more time researching because we don't know when we buy cars and we'll probably gravitate toward cars that our friends have bought or that I don't know, we found online on some blog or something.
Scott: Maybe like two of our friends bought Honda fits.
Rym: You know, I didn't know the Honda fit existed.
Scott: I knew it existed and I probably would have bought it if it was available.
Rym: You know, when I bought my car, which it wasn't, it wasn't out until he drove up with this car.
Rym: And I'm like, what kind of car is this?
Rym: He's like a Honda fit.
Rym: And I look online and it's a pretty damn good car.
Scott: It's pretty good.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It's very nice.
Rym: And Honda's doing okay.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But yeah, I think that, you know, why do we need, you know, I mean, I'm all for, you know, individuality, customization, right?
Scott: Personalization all.
Scott: I mean, I bought custom sunglasses, a custom messenger bag, you know, custom everything, right?
Scott: But is it really necessary with something as big and as expensive as cars to have so many different ones, especially when many of them are so unpopular or so rarely used?
Rym: Well, it doesn't help that cars themselves are not terribly customizable.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Partly due to manufacturing.
Rym: They are.
Rym: If you're a ricer, I don't think that's not custom.
Rym: That's something special.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I mean, Sion tried to do that, you know, the shtick where they were trying to market their cars as being customizable to racers.
Rym: But how did that go?
Scott: Some people are buying them.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I just, I, I kind of wonder what's going to happen to my home state of Michigan because things are not going well in Michigan.
Scott: It's going to be an awesome airsoft paintball arena.
Rym: No, because if you're in the dot and you're in downtown Detroit in like some factory, abandoned factory playing airsoft, God's hour, someone with a real gun is going to want to join in on the fun.
Scott: It's all right.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day, let's get this going.
Rym: So I have a dream that the MLK estate is going to stop trying to sue people who do things with Martin Luther King's speeches and images.
Rym: And I'm pretty sure that this is fair use.
Rym: And if it isn't, it should be.
Rym: But I like this.
Rym: So it's my thing of the day.
Rym: It's a, there was this thing on college humor of charge Hill giving his speeches run through the Britney Spears filter, which is basically you can, it's pretty easy to take a mediocre singer and run pitch shift shifting to make them sound like a really good.
Scott: Well, don't you have to tell the shifter like what the song is to a degree?
Rym: I mean, there's different ways to do it.
Scott: It doesn't just work for any singing.
Scott: You have to like, tell it like, you know, what the notes are.
Rym: Not necessarily.
Rym: I mean, it depends on what you're trying to do.
Rym: One way to do it is to give it a key and all the key changes.
Rym: So what key it's in at a given time, and then you just sing as close as you can and it'll match you to what note you probably should be singing.
Rym: And then there are all different ways to do it.
Rym: It's really complex, interesting, cool software.
Rym: And you can do it live.
Rym: You can do it after the fact, but someone did a mediocre job with Churchill and it was pretty good.
Rym: Someone then did a pretty awesome job with Martin Luther King Jr's.
Rym: I have a dream speech.
Rym: They kind of made this techno E remix music video thing that honestly is kind of inspiring and is kind of touching to watch.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty good.
Rym: I highly recommend you watch it and maybe someday we'll talk more about that sort of software because I think it's neat.
Scott: Or the Martin Luther King estate.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I've talked about them before, so I don't want to belabor the point, but when was the last time we had someone in the US who was as memorable and important as Martin Luther King
Rym: Jr.?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, I started discussing this like a few minutes ago.
Scott: It sort of came to me, right?
Scott: Like who today?
Scott: Can you think of a single person alive today who you could conceive of ever having a federal holiday for them?
Rym: Wait, having or should have?
Scott: You know, should have.
Rym: Uh, Dallaire.
Scott: Well, I mean, a United States federal holiday.
Rym: Uh, it still should be Dallaire.
Scott: You know what I'm saying?
Scott: Like who alive?
Scott: I mean, like even Obama, who is historically significant.
Scott: Should there really be a Barack Obama day?
Rym: We have to wait.
Rym: He needs more time.
Rym: He hasn't, he's only, he's only been president like a hundred days.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But I mean, not really, probably not.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, you know what, who, who alive then should ever have a federal holiday for them?
Scott: There's no one like that.
Scott: People like that I think are, don't exist anymore.
Scott: And I think that's part of the, the reason why we can't, you know, make changes happen because you know, there's, we don't have those kinds of people around.
Rym: See, is it really a matter of not having these people or is it just a matter of expectations and perceptions changing coupled with the fact that media is more diffuse?
Scott: Well, I think that, you know, it could be that those things are the cause of not having the people.
Scott: And it's sort of a reciprocal situation, sort of catch 22, perhaps.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Something like that.
Scott: You know, it's like, I blame partly on the fact that if there was a big, united, strong movement of ideas and enough people agreeing on something awesome, then you know that that person just emerges.
Scott: or, you know, is it that you need that person to make it emerge when it's, you know, where the, the movement is there, but hidden?
Rym: I think part of it honestly, is that a lot of these old historical figures, we have the long great speech that they gave, especially in this era where there was video of this speech, but before we got into the TV, Twitter soundbite era.
Rym: So you've got eloquent speakers writing literary, intelligent, engaging speeches.
Rym: We had orators and there aren't that many orders anymore.
Rym: And well, no, no, I take that back.
Rym: There are orders, but people don't give a shit anymore.
Scott: Well, if you, you go to Ted, that's, that's where I get my oration.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But how popular is Ted?
Scott: popular among smart people?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Watch that videos.
Scott: I've been watched.
Scott: I subscribe to.
Scott: Ted is a video podcast now.
Scott: So I'm just watching all of them on the iPhone or whatever.
Scott: That's the way to go.
Rym: I'm seriously considering just paying and joining and going.
Scott: It's like a bajillion dollars.
Scott: I'm thinking about it's like a quarter of your monies a year.
Rym: There are different levels.
Scott: You realize really isn't, but I've seen tickets go on eBay for like $25,000.
Rym: Well, there are different levels of sponsorship.
Rym: Some of those levels do not involve going, at least not right away.
Scott: Well then why would I pay if I'm not going to get other stuff?
Scott: I can see it all for free.
Scott: I'm not going to pay unless I get to go.
Rym: You don't want to support the Ted organization.
Scott: I would like to support them.
Scott: I support them by watching.
Scott: And by watching, I increase their numbers because they have ads.
Rym: I did learn how to nominate people to get a Ted talk.
Scott: Don't you have to be a Ted person already?
Scott: No.
Scott: Then you can nominate someone else.
Scott: Well, you can know, it's sort of a, you know, invite only inside out thing.
Rym: No, you can just dominate people.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: And there's all this stuff you have to fill out.
Rym: It's a pretty intense form.
Rym: And the thing is, I can't think of anyone worthy who hasn't already given one that I know of.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: We tend to not know those kinds of people.
Rym: And I thought for a second, Oh, I'll nominate myself.
Rym: And that, that felt so sleazy.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The thing is you compare yourself to like even the lowliest person at Ted.
Scott: It's like not even close.
Rym: I'm just like a lowly worm.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's anyway, my thing of the day, some guy made this cool website.
Scott: He's got penguin books, science fiction covers, uh, through the years.
Scott: So you can go year by year and look at like all the book covers and see the art of them and how it changed.
Scott: And it's a, it's a very good, a lesson in design.
Scott: And there's a lot of cool book covers going on.
Scott: It's very, very nice.
Scott: I like this kind of action.
Rym: So I can't believe, Oh, you have more to say?
Scott: No, I just like, I like book covers a lot.
Rym: Gabe would like.
Scott: it has a lot of, uh, spaceships, you know, with a planet and a rocket kind of like how.
Rym: I really like old video game box cover art.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Right.
Rym: And I don't like new video game box cover art because all looks the same.
Rym: Hmm.
Rym: I mean, remember like mega man too.
Rym: Like there was a, uh, anyway, so people have been asking us to do how to not suck episodes again.
Rym: And independently of that, people have suggested that we do food episodes again.
Scott: I don't know what you people, what it is with eating, chew your food, swallow, use the utensils properly.
Rym: Don't eat too much.
Scott: Don't eat too much.
Rym: Eat mostly plants and grain, which are plants.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: A little bit of meat.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Not so much trans fat, zero trans fat, but specifically you can eat sugar though.
Rym: Someone suggested to do a show on how to not suck at eating out.
Rym: And I was intrigued by this because I didn't think people had trouble, but no, the thing is you didn't think people had trouble, but then I think no, I have proof that people have trouble.
Scott: I actually think about my experiences.
Scott: And I realize a lot of people who aren't me have trouble.
Rym: You want to, uh, you want absolute proof that people have difficulty eating out properly drive by a cracker barrel.
Rym: There are people in that parking lot.
Rym: There are cars parked there.
Rym: A lot of them.
Rym: Well, I'll qualify that there are cars parked there after 1130 AM.
Rym: All right.
Scott: So rule number one, don't go to fast food unless you have no choice.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, a lot of people out there, you might love you some McDonald's, but you're basically just poisoning yourself to death.
Scott: I mean, it's as bad as, you know, smoking.
Scott: So just don't, don't eat there ever unless you, you know, you're hungry and there's absolutely nothing else you can do.
Rym: I won't quite take that tack because as a kid, I had a lot of fast food.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You know how many times I ate at Arby's and got like some chicken strips and every day in the summer when I was like a sophomore or junior in high school, I would get in my car.
Rym: I drive to Arby's.
Rym: I get like curly fries and like the biggest sandwich, the big Montana and a Jamoca shake.
Scott: One, one, uh, I remember my dad picked me up from summer camp once and we went to Arby's on the way home and he had the big Montana.
Scott: And then he got sick where I always had, you know, every time I went there, I always got, you know, the chicken, whatever the curly fries and a shake, but the key, I am too smart.
Scott: I do not go there anymore.
Rym: The key was the Jamoca shake.
Rym: I got a shake and I would eat a Taco Bell pretty often.
Rym: I'll still occasionally eat a Taco Bell if I'm desperate.
Rym: I guess I've got a hierarchy now where there's this waiting of how desperate am I?
Rym: What's nearby?
Rym: And the more desperate I am, the further I'll go or the lower I'll go.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: But the thing is it, I have to be quite desperate to go to like a subway.
Rym: I had to be even more desperate to go someplace like, you know, a burger, you know, I think my order is pretty much at the top of the fast food chain is the like, well, White Castle because White Castle is awesome.
Scott: The top are the places that are sort of like not quite fast food, right?
Scott: Like a quiz nose or like a five guys or, you know, those, those sorts of things.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then you got subways sort of like the barrier, right?
Scott: Cause it's sort of like, it's actually a sandwich.
Scott: You go there, right?
Scott: I like, they got that nice, the chicken teriyaki sandwich where like they microwave a little bit of chicken.
Rym: It's not really bad for you.
Rym: Cause it's just bread and lettuce.
Scott: You know, then they got like a chocolate chip cookie, which is just a chocolate, you know, then at least their food isn't like full of trans fat and nasty, horrible chemicals, you know, it's just normal, cheap sandwich.
Rym: But I think going down the line, it's a Arby's, but only the chicken.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Arby's I, you know, I just, not that Arby's is any healthier than the others.
Scott: I just sort of like it more.
Scott: So I'm more willing to eat there.
Scott: Cause you know, it's like, well, it's just as poisonous as McDonald's, but I like it more.
Scott: So it goes, and then you got like a Wendy's a little bit better.
Rym: Wendy's really only for the dollar menu and those, uh, uh, frosty.
Scott: You get the chicken nuggets are okay.
Scott: There you go.
Rym: They have vanilla Frosty's now.
Scott: Yeah, I know.
Rym: That's crazy.
Scott: It is.
Rym: I had one really at the airport.
Rym: Wow.
Rym: And you know what, you know, it was in it Oreos.
Scott: Damn.
Scott: And then, you know, you start going down a little bit and you, I think the bottom is Jack in the box.
Scott: I think the bottom is like those really nasty places like Burger King and Burger King KFC, right?
Scott: Those sorts of really, really nasty shit.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: McDonald's is even above Burger King.
Scott: McDonald's is sort of like the barrier between like fast food and the terrible fast food.
Rym: It's weird though, because McDonald's and I'm not the only one, a lot of people agree with me, the breakfast, not that bad.
Scott: Well, the thing is I won't eat the breakfast like on purpose, you know, but I mean, it's, it's edible, but it's weird how McDonald's breakfast rates a lot higher than most other fast food places, but McDonald's anything else now?
Scott: I think that I just have an advantage of being in New York city.
Scott: You can just go to any deli and get a breakfast sandwich.
Scott: So why would you go to McDonald's to get a breakfast?
Rym: Oh no, I only get breakfast sandwiches if I'm in like some other heathen city and it doesn't have like a deli and ask for a breakfast sandwich.
Scott: You know what they do?
Scott: They take two eggs.
Scott: They break them on the griddle.
Scott: They take some bacon.
Scott: They put it on the griddle.
Scott: They take a Thomas English muffin, just like from the grocery store.
Scott: They take a piece of cheese, just like from the grocery store.
Scott: They put it together and then you eat it.
Scott: And it's like $2.
Scott: And it's like, um, why would I go to McDonald's and get there?
Scott: Like manufactured process stuff when I can go and get basically exactly like what I would make in my house for $2.
Rym: But I've been in cities where there's just, there's nothing around and you're stuck.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: That's it's basically middle of nowhere.
Rym: that like when I was in a Columbia in Columbia, where, uh, it's near DC.
Rym: I don't know if it was actually in Maryland or what, or how about when we were at Silicon, right?
Scott: They had one fancy restaurant, that Italian place, right?
Scott: And then there was a Wendy's and a Denny's.
Scott: It's like, well, we don't have much choice.
Rym: We ate at that Denny's with, uh, entertainment system.
Rym: We did.
Rym: And that was when we learned that they're all kind of jerks and they all smoke.
Scott: Well, one guy, the guy who played Pokemon was okay.
Rym: He was cool, but everyone else was just kind of, kind of, kind of bitches.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I just, it was weird.
Rym: I remember that very in stark detail.
Scott: It was kind of weird.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, but we don't want to just talk about fast food, but talk about actual sitting down food.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Uh, don't go to stuff on the walls, restaurants either.
Rym: They're, they're all the same and they're not good.
Scott: Friday's Ruby Tuesday, et cetera, et cetera.
Scott: Right.
Scott: All of those plays.
Scott: I mean, there are restaurants that have stuff on the walls that are okay.
Scott: Like, uh, fun rockers.
Rym: It's a sliding scale.
Rym: Like I think the top, top, top of the equivalent of a stuff on the walls is the Outback because that's equivalent to a stuff on the walls.
Rym: I say, yeah, it is the kind of food you get.
Rym: I mean, Outback is definitely a stuff on the walls, but I feel like it is the pinnacle of stuff on the walls.
Rym: beyond that you're in a real restaurant and below that you're at Ruby Tuesday getting the runs.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, the main problem with the stuff on the walls restaurants is that almost everything on the menu, not everything, you know, but almost everything is the quadra effect of it's either.
Scott: it's either cool range, right?
Scott: It's like bacon, cheese, cool ranch, et cetera.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And, or mayonnaise.
Scott: And it's like every meal is either the same as the other ones, uh, not good fried or that's it, you know?
Scott: So it's, it's not good to eat there, especially considering, you know, those places aren't too cheap for the same price.
Scott: You can go to like a diner and get something better or, you know, good.
Scott: Like, you know, any number of you can go to like an actual Italian restaurant for the same price as the stuff on the walls, what people often overlook.
Rym: And here's, this is aimed primarily at college kids.
Rym: If you want to eat and you don't have money and you got a bunch of friends, go to a stuff on the walls place and order nothing but appetizers.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Cause they always have mad appetizer deals at those kinds of places.
Rym: Get yourself like four orders of fried mozzarella sticks.
Rym: You're good to go.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, it's like we would, uh, way back, we'd go to Applebee's, which is like a place you should never go.
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: After all the R wag meetings.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Because they gave you a half off on all the appetite when they gave us half off on the appetizers.
Scott: Cause he went on Tuesday.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And we were in a large group.
Scott: So everyone would buy a ton of advertising, but then they realized what was going on.
Rym: Cause we'd always show up.
Rym: Right.
Rym: So it'd be like 20 to 30 people take over this Applebee's and everyone will order the nachos for like four bucks.
Rym: And the nachos cost them probably more than four bucks to make, because I remember after a couple of months of this, there was a little thing on the menu saying, does not apply to nachos.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But even so you like cheese steaks and all sorts of, you know, fried, like a fried platter, all kinds of stuff.
Rym: Anyway, remember the Applebee's because we'll have to come back to the Applebee's because the Applebee's taught me a very important lesson.
Scott: Oh yes.
Scott: That is the most important lesson.
Scott: I think it's the most important thing we have to teach tonight, but we'll come back to that at the end.
Rym: Just remember Applebee's.
Rym: we will return, but no, we're talking now about real fucking restaurants as in a restaurant that has a name and that name is not anywhere else yet.
Scott: Oh, you know what I found out recently?
Scott: Olive garden, Capitol grill, same company.
Rym: Really?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: That's interesting to know.
Rym: Well, I should qualify that there are restaurants that are changed, right?
Scott: There are restaurants, you know, chain, you know, it's like a stuff on the walls is a chain, right?
Scott: But there are chains that are not stuff on the wall.
Rym: Case in point, the Capitol grill, right?
Scott: The Capitol grill is an actual, very fancy high class steakhouse, but it's also a chain there in many cities.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Capitol grill is basically a New York city style steakhouse, but they're in other cities.
Rym: So if you don't live in New York city, you can go to a Capitol grill and you'll find out what a New York city steakhouse is like.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, there's one in New York, but there's one in Baltimore.
Scott: I'm sure there's one in California somewhere.
Scott: I got to go to the website.
Scott: They list all of them.
Rym: I got to tell you, I, we, we tricked a vendor into buying us lunch there one day.
Scott: Did you, did you buy his stuff?
Scott: No, he bought you steaks and you didn't buy anything from him.
Rym: He didn't buy me just any steak.
Rym: He bought me an inch and a half thick, like almost completely raw steak that was seared black on the outside.
Rym: You know, it was seasoned with sugar, sugar, just sugar.
Scott: That's a good way to go.
Rym: That was the second best steak I've ever had in my life.
Rym: All right.
Scott: So step one, when going to a real restaurant, deciding which real restaurant to go to, this is impossible in the front row crew.
Scott: Well, you know, the problem is, is whatever kind of restaurant you pick, which is usually associated with some nationality.
Scott: If your group is too big, someone is going to veto, right?
Scott: So what you really basically have to do is if you're someone else is vetoing, you're basically going to have to sort of screw someone, you know, and if they can't deal with that, then, you know, just get rid of them.
Scott: Tell them to save the drama for someone else.
Rym: Really the simplest way about this is you should be able to eat.
Rym: And you know what?
Scott: That's what I was just about to say.
Rym: No, no, no.
Rym: Wait, wait, wait.
Rym: I'm going to go one step further.
Rym: You can eat at any kind of restaurant because like we have friends who say like, oh, they don't want to eat at Indian places.
Rym: But if you look at the menu, there is stuff that anyone will eat on every menu of just about every restaurant in the world.
Scott: Well, I mean, there are some people who are like crazy picky, like, you know, I mean, this picky, like, oh, I don't want that.
Scott: I don't want that.
Scott: But there's crazy picky.
Scott: Like I know people who literally they eat like chicken and French fries and that is it.
Rym: Well, I remember for the longest time, your brother was like that where I go visit you at your house and your parents would make like awesome steaks and they'd make your brother a chicken filet because that's all he would eat.
Scott: He's better than that now.
Scott: But I mean, there are people I know who exist that are like like that and are older than us, like 30 or 40 something.
Rym: Not in the front row crew, though.
Scott: No, not the front row crew.
Scott: But, you know, so you think about yourself.
Scott: You should be able to eat at any restaurant, no matter what restaurant is picked.
Scott: You might not be in the mood.
Scott: It might not be the best, but there should.
Scott: if you're hungry, there will be something there for you to eat.
Scott: You have to be, you know, you have to be able to accept that and be willing to go anywhere.
Scott: You know, you can have a preference, but you should never sort of had to, you know, completely object.
Scott: You know, I mean, like I always I never want to go to the Indian restaurant.
Scott: But when we go, I go and I eat something, you know, it doesn't kill me.
Scott: I think the mango is the reason you go.
Scott: Well, the mango is excellent.
Scott: But, you know, there are places I would rather go, but I go anyway.
Scott: You know, Scott Johnson doesn't like the cafe, Maya, because he doesn't like peppers and onions.
Scott: But he goes anyway because he's not, you know, well, he is.
Scott: But he goes anyway.
Rym: The real key is and this is always like the critical balance, not just in food, but in life.
Rym: The careful choosing between the two opposite ends of this one spectrum.
Rym: on the far left is adventure.
Rym: On the far right is known goodness.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: I like you're obviously never going to go to a restaurant that you know is bad, right?
Scott: We're assuming that right off the bat.
Scott: So there's restaurants you're familiar with that are good, which means you'll go to them or restaurants that are unknown.
Scott: No one has been there.
Scott: And the strategy is if you've never been to a restaurant, go with only a few people like maybe one or two because you want to go with more than once.
Scott: You can try multiple dishes, but you don't want to go too many because if it sucks, you're wasting a lot of money.
Rym: This really only applies if you've got a crew.
Rym: I mean, if the front row crew is together and we're going to a restaurant that is between 10 and 25 people at any given time.
Scott: That's a lot of people.
Rym: So if we take 20 people to a restaurant that no one's been to before and it sucks, 20 people got screwed.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: So we'll send scouts ahead like Emily and I will go try a restaurant and we'll come back and be like, that place sucked.
Rym: We're not going there ever again.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So you got to test with a few people, but if it's known goodness, it's known goodness.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Now, if you've got, you got to kind of in your local area, build up the list of standbys.
Rym: You've got to have like five or six restaurants that are the standbys that you can always go to no matter what.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And then you have the few special place, keep the hours of the restaurants in mind quite often.
Scott: You know, if you don't know what the hours are, it might be like nine o'clock and you like, Hey, let's go to the something, something you forget that it's lunch only.
Scott: You're like, Oh crap.
Rym: And then it's diner time.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: It's no good.
Scott: Um, secondly, you know what?
Rym: This applies to dishes too, because the cafe Maya has some of the best Mexican food ever.
Rym: Like that's, Oh my God.
Rym: It's pretty.
Scott: I really, I haven't even found a place in the city.
Scott: That's as good as that.
Rym: The cafe Maya in fish kill New York, but there's a couple of, there's one in Waffensters falls all expansions of it, but the central one in fish kill, like it is famous in the mid Hudson Valley as like this awesome place.
Scott: It's fucking amazing.
Rym: You want to eat there for dinner and like Saturday night, there's like an hour or two hour wait.
Scott: I was just about to talk about weights, right?
Rym: All right.
Rym: You've got to be willing to fucking bail immediately, right?
Scott: When you show up at a restaurant, right?
Scott: You have to already know before you even get there, how long you're willing to wait, right?
Scott: And if the wait time is longer than that, just get in your car and go, don't like stand around and do the hokey pokey.
Scott: Cause you're basically just, you know, you're basically screwing yourself by going to walk up and be like, how long's the wait?
Rym: And if they say half hour and you're not willing to wait, you say, Oh, nevermind.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: And when they say half hour, pretend they said 45 minutes, you know, if they say 45 minutes, pretend they said an hour, unless it's the sick of tie.
Rym: Fuck you sick of tie, right?
Scott: You know, if the restaurant won't tell you what the weight is, just leave.
Scott: You're wasting your time there.
Rym: You know, now you might say Rym and Scott, you're smart.
Rym: Why don't you just get reservations up this?
Rym: If you can get reservations, get them.
Rym: But I will warn you, if you live in an area where there are a lot of popular restaurants and a lot of people, pretty much no good restaurant is going to take reservations.
Scott: Or if they do take reservations, you're not gonna be able to get one unless you call way ahead.
Scott: And if you're, you know, it's hard to decide where to eat that far in advance.
Scott: Cause what kind of mood will you get?
Rym: Seriously, like pretty much every good restaurant in New York and in this area, except for the ultra fancy ones, like they won't, they don't take reservations because they're going to be full no matter what, for all the hours they're open.
Scott: reservations are for when you're going to have like a party with a schedule, you know, like, Hey, such and such day as someone's anniversary, let's get a reservation for 25 people at the fancy house.
Scott: You know, that's what a reservation is for.
Scott: Reservations are not for really anything else.
Rym: What you can do is try the call ahead.
Rym: The call ahead is a special thing.
Rym: And that is the way I have gotten reservations from places that don't do reservations.
Scott: You say, Hey, you guys full, what's your weight before you go there?
Rym: Or you call him and remember you, you can't just call him and ask because then they're either going to lie or they're going to say, yeah, we don't know.
Scott: Just show up or they won't even pick up the phone and don't say the word reservation.
Rym: You call and you just ask like, Hey, listen, I got like 30 people.
Rym: And in an hour or so, we're going to come by your place.
Rym: You think you can handle that?
Rym: And now, instead of just, you're not asking them for something anymore, you are offering them 30 people worth of food and big groups tend to tip extravagantly and order more food than they otherwise would.
Rym: If the individuals came by themselves, you can also put them all around one table, one waiter handles it all, all the orders come in at once.
Rym: Restaurants love you.
Rym: If you bring a giant group, unless you're a diner in a college town, in which case they able to shut the door in your face or unless you're jerks.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But we had a lot to talk about.
Rym: We could do like a week on restaurants.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But anyway, so you got to deal with the weight intelligently.
Scott: Don't you basically want to avoid spending a lot of time waiting?
Scott: Cause that sucks ass, you know, be willing to just, you know, have backup places to go.
Rym: If the weights are too long at the other places, if you got the long wait, confirm the way like multiple times.
Rym: And then everybody go to like the bookstore next door or outside and hang out for an hour and then come back.
Rym: And if that restaurant doesn't have your table for you when you get back or they say, Hey, you weren't here.
Rym: We gave it up.
Rym: Never eat there again.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Ever.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Um, so when ordering, just order food order order and don't, don't be afraid.
Scott: Like my mom doesn't talk to waiters, you know, don't be my mom.
Scott: You have to talk to the waiter.
Scott: order, you know, speak up, say something.
Rym: If you didn't hear what the special was, just ask again, because every time the waiter comes, they say the four specials, they leave a few minutes later, someone in our group will be like, Hey, what was in that fish special?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: No one remembers as the waiter.
Rym: Don't just order it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, go, you know, if you need some water, if you know, I mean, you know, people like sort of are afraid to like harass waiters a little bit because they're afraid of like spitting in the food number one.
Rym: If you're getting the waiter's attention, there are ways to do it in ways not to do it.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Don't come over here.
Rym: Don't do the two finger in the mouth of whistle.
Rym: Don't snap your fingers and say Garcon Garcon unless you're in the kind of restaurant where you're paying enough money to where they expect that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But you know, if you just, you know, if you just talk to them like normal people, they're not going to think you're an ass just because you, you know, talk to them a bunch, you know, like if you need a napkin, if you need new silverware, you know, just, just freaking ask for it.
Scott: Don't and don't hesitate either.
Scott: You know, because if you hesitate, you're just going to be sitting there like waiting for another four because you dropped yours on the floor.
Scott: You need that for quickly.
Rym: Now to who's getting cold if you need the waiter, but most people do.
Rym: And everyone does this.
Rym: Like I watch people at other tables doing it.
Rym: And it aggravates me to the point that I almost want to intervene on their behalf.
Rym: If you want a waiter, just we'll look around.
Rym: And as soon as you see anyone who works in the restaurant, just watch their face and make eye contact with them.
Rym: Everyone seems to like, kind of look in the direction of a waiter kind of, but then if the waiter turns to them, they like avoid eye contact and kind of just like, look like they're waiting for someone, but they don't actually engage.
Scott: And a lot of people, a lot of people like only want to talk to the waiter for their table.
Scott: Just talk to the first one who comes by.
Scott: Cause if like you're going to, sometimes depending on the restaurant, it might be a while before the one for your table comes back, you know, they might be hanging out.
Scott: They might be doing other tables.
Rym: This does not apply to fancy restaurants.
Rym: I mean, if you're at like sparks in New York city, like the steakhouse, there are waiters watching your table for any discomfort and they appear and fix it.
Rym: Like I dropped my fork, a waiter, just put another one on the table before I could reach down and get it.
Scott: Wow.
Scott: That's good stuff.
Rym: It was amazing.
Scott: I like, yeah, some restaurants like they'll refill the water as soon as it's empty and others, you gotta be like, Hey, can I get some water over here?
Rym: Some places will just bring another bottle of the wine you uncork it and just start pouring glasses.
Scott: That's cause they want it.
Rym: They want you to start paying, but at the same time they're basically pouring money, but these are the kind of places where you're going to order it anyway.
Rym: They just know.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Uh, seriously make eye contact.
Rym: And then as soon as they make eye contact with you, don't break it.
Scott: Look right at them and nod like, come here or give, you know, some sort of, you know, signal that is visual and perhaps audible to let them know that you want them to don't do the Lewis black, where the fuck is my food?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And the thing is, you know, if your food is like, you know, not coming, you know, you know, usually what I've never had some, you know, like sometimes you might get worried.
Scott: Like everyone else's food comes and your food doesn't come.
Scott: You might be worried, like, Oh, do they fuck up my order?
Scott: What's going on?
Scott: Pretty much any time I've ever had that worry, someone always comes out and is like, yeah, your food will be ready and whatever.
Scott: Just a minute.
Scott: It's like, okay.
Scott: Now it's still, if you're, if you're still worried about it, just ask now when it comes to don't ask you like quickly enough, everyone else is going to be done eating and you're still going to be eating there.
Rym: When it comes to bad food, you've really got away the risk reward ratio here.
Rym: If you're in a sleazy diner and your clam chowder comes out cold, just don't eat it.
Rym: And don't ask about it.
Rym: Just give up that $4 is gone.
Scott: Just let it be, just let it be.
Rym: But if you're at the fancy steakhouse and your steak isn't cooked right, and you point this out, they'll just bring another steak.
Rym: They won't even like, don't worry about them spitting in the food.
Rym: They won't even think to spit in the food.
Rym: They don't care.
Rym: But the, basically the less you're paying for your food, the less you can get away with.
Scott: I know it's like, you know, don't like, you know, and it depends on like the kind of complaint, right?
Scott: Like let's say you ordered a cheese, you're at a diner, right?
Scott: And you ordered a hamburger with no cheese and it comes out with a piece of cheese, right?
Scott: Tell them that it came up with a piece of cheese that you don't want.
Scott: You ordered no cheese, you know, and they'll come out with another burger with no cheese on it.
Rym: It might just be the same burger with the cheese scraped off, but that's what you get for a diner.
Scott: But that's fine though.
Scott: That's what you want.
Scott: But don't turn back.
Scott: If you, if they bring out a burger and you say, this is medium rare.
Scott: I wanted it medium at the diner.
Scott: You got, that's not good.
Scott: Don't do that.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Burgers of diners come out diner rare.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, medium only, only complain if they screwed up the actual order, the biggest one.
Scott: And I don't complain about the food being bad.
Rym: It really bothers me when I see people do this.
Rym: And if you order wine, you know, they bring the wine out and they like pour a little bit of it for you to check and they give you the cork to look at and they show you the bottle.
Rym: That's all one to prove to you that they're bringing you the actual wine you ordered because otherwise they're like, they don't say anything when they do this.
Scott: You're expected sort of know what's going on, the deal, right?
Scott: But they're not like checking to see if you think the wine is good, right?
Rym: To see one, to prove to you, look, you ordered a 97 blah, blah, blah.
Rym: I have brought for you a 97 blue, right?
Scott: Because what could happen is some restaurant could take a bottle that says 97 blah, blah, blah on it and put in Thunderbird.
Scott: Right.
Rym: And they want to prove to you that it's not Thunderbird, but when they do this, I've seen people get the other bird is not $30 a glass and they sniff it and they sniff the cork, which is silly.
Rym: If you sniff the cork, you don't know what you're doing.
Scott: That's all right.
Rym: Look at the car.
Rym: Don't sniff the car.
Scott: You're looking at the car to make sure it's not crumbled.
Scott: It should be in one piece.
Scott: And that means that the wine is not bad.
Scott: Also turned into vinegar.
Rym: If the wine waiter uses one of those twisty corkscrews, if you twist it in, then you pull the little levers as opposed to a wine key.
Rym: Don't ask them about the wine.
Rym: They don't know.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: They'll use like this livery wine key.
Rym: That means they know because at least someone, of course, you might see them twist the wine key in and then start yanking on it.
Rym: They don't know.
Rym: that happened at a restaurant near us.
Scott: The skill of their bottle opening is directly in proportion to their knowledge.
Rym: The best bottle opening I ever got wasn't in the fancy place in New York.
Rym: It was from this awesome waiter in Costa Rica.
Scott: Really?
Scott: This guy, how do you open it?
Rym: Well, he just had like perfect, like if you were, if wine bottle opening or in the Olympics, like all those other synchronized kind of specific movement arts, this guy got a 9.8 out of 10 and maybe a seven from the Italian judge.
Rym: Like it was perfect.
Rym: I don't know if anyone will even get that.
Scott: That's a good one.
Rym: I don't know if anyone remembers.
Scott: That's all right.
Rym: Anyway, but when they pour you that little bit of wine, that is for you to taste it and tell them if the wine spoiled or not.
Rym: So if you don't like the wine, that's tough shit.
Scott: Like if you ordered, you know, a man of Shevitz and you don't like how it tastes, you think it's nasty, but it's not bad.
Scott: It's not like, you know, turned into vinegar.
Scott: It's, it is what it is and it is what it says on the bottle.
Scott: But you ordered something that it turns out you don't actually like.
Scott: That's tough shit.
Scott: That's, you know, like you order a cheeseburger and then you find out you don't like cheese.
Scott: Well, that's your problem.
Rym: But now the difficulty with wine, of course, is that if you haven't had a lot of wine, you have no idea if you're fooling you or not, because there are some wines out there, some expensive ones that taste like ass.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: But they, they, they're supposed to taste like ass.
Rym: That's what they taste like.
Rym: It didn't go bad.
Rym: That's just what it tastes like.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: That's why I don't drink that shit.
Rym: But there's also wine that's really good.
Scott: That's cheap.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Simply, if you don't know, don't order either.
Rym: If you're order the cheapest wine, just whatever the cheapest wine and the color that you want is order that do not order the second cheapest wine.
Rym: The second cheapest wine on almost every menu is crappier than the cheapest wine.
Rym: And it is there solely for the people who are with a date or with other people.
Rym: And they want to be impressive and order wine, but they don't know about wine and they're cheap.
Rym: They don't want to order the cheapest wine because that's obvious.
Rym: So they order the second cheapest wine.
Scott: Right.
Scott: One thing you can definitely do though, is some restaurants have like these safeties, right?
Scott: For example, the, the number one of these is the macaroni grill, right?
Scott: Which is a chain, but it is an excellent Italian restaurant.
Scott: You know, I guess it's not super excellent, but it's pretty good.
Scott: They have wine on this honor system.
Scott: So you go in and if you don't know a wine to get, just get the wine.
Scott: They have like the macaroni girl wine.
Scott: It comes in a gigantic jug.
Rym: Actually pretty much every restaurant has this.
Rym: It's called the house wine.
Rym: So if you really don't know what to order at all, just order.
Rym: I didn't think other restaurants said that order a glass of the house wine.
Rym: Now they might ask which one, in which case, just admit to the waiter that you don't know anything about wine and ask them what they recommend.
Rym: And if they don't know, they will go back and ask the chef, the chef will say, give them whatever.
Scott: And at the very least, just try to figure out red or white.
Scott: Even I know that if you get that right, you're like 90% of the way there.
Rym: If you really don't know, drink the wine.
Rym: that is the color of the meat or food you were eating.
Rym: That's pretty much at least the closest color, but enough about wine.
Rym: Yes, we actually have gone on a while.
Scott: We got to talk about paying.
Scott: That's it.
Rym: We got, there's a bunch of, uh, quick one.
Rym: We talked about cutting and running.
Rym: If you sit down at a restaurant and like you're not getting served, even if you have ordered some food, like you've ordered food and it just hasn't come and it's taking way too long, like way too long, uh, warn them that you've got to go.
Rym: And if they can't rectify the situation immediately, you're perfectly within your rights to just say, look, we're leaving and not pay.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: You don't have to pay until you have eaten food.
Scott: If they put food on the table in front of you and it is like, smells like rotten, like, Oh my God, disgusting.
Scott: Just get up and leave.
Scott: As soon as you touch the food, you have to pay.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: If you, if you try to say that the burger was bad and you want a refund and you ate all of it, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Scott: You have to pretty much, if you are going to not pay as soon as the point where you touch the food, you can't, you have to pay, but up until then, don't feel bad about just getting up and leaving until you, you know, cause you should, if you have a reason
Rym: to.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Cut and run.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: All right, paying, paying kids one, uh, tax supplies.
Rym: I, it, it amazes me how many people in my life don't seem to understand that there is tax at restaurants.
Scott: pay the tax.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean like if you order something on the, on the menu, it says $15 is probably going to be like a good three, $4 tax.
Scott: It's really $20.
Scott: You're probably going to have to put down on the table, right?
Scott: Not 15.
Scott: So, uh, remember tax exists, especially like New York.
Scott: The tax is 8%.
Scott: That's a lot of money.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Plus, you know, tip 15 to 25%.
Scott: Add that in.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I mean, tipping is a whole separate issue.
Rym: We're not going to talk about the merits of taking tipping.
Scott: We're only going to talk about the reality.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: We're not going to talk about, you know, when to, when not to, because there are some very few cases where you shouldn't tip at all.
Rym: Wait, you know what?
Scott: There are some cases where you should tip a whole bunch.
Rym: I will give you the, if you are playing life per game theory and you are perfectly rational and practical and acting only in your own self-interest, here's what you do.
Rym: If you are never going to go to a restaurant again, or it is a restaurant that will not recognize you don't tip.
Rym: If you're going to return to a restaurant enough to where they will recognize you tip very, very lavishly.
Rym: And if you tip mediocrely forever, they will always bend over backward for you.
Rym: For as long as you go there, they'll bring free drinks, free food, free sushi, free, whatever.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: The neko did that to us for a while.
Rym: They give us like just free rolls.
Scott: It's good to have a restaurant that remembers you because then you will get things.
Rym: Ah, Jay's diner.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I mean, and you don't even have to tip extravagantly to get things.
Scott: Just tip like, you know, 17% and you'll get things.
Scott: Y'all like an extra dollar or two.
Rym: Well, of course we really love beyond at Applebee's when, uh, here's how to get into this whole, this final discussion.
Rym: We were at Applebee's all the time with our wag.
Rym: So there'd be like between 10 and 30 people who were disgusting gamers.
Rym: We're all friends with them though.
Rym: Nominally, we're all in a group and we'd all sit at like a gigantic table and then all the tables around it.
Rym: And in the end we'd get one gigantic check and everyone would throw in their money.
Rym: And I hope we all got accustomed to throwing in this certain amount and it always worked out.
Rym: And one day we went to Applebee's and like no one else went for some reason.
Rym: So it was just like three of us, three or four of us sitting at a little table, hanging out, doing the same thing.
Rym: we always do in a small group.
Rym: We all threw in what we normally throw in for the same amount of food.
Rym: We all order the same stuff.
Rym: We left a 115% tip and we realized this and we started calculating what we actually owed for our food.
Rym: And we discovered that someone was an asshole.
Rym: We didn't know who.
Rym: We only knew that it wasn't anyone with us.
Rym: And I've realized the crux of this is not so much that people are willfully trying to skip out on paying what they owe.
Rym: There are people like that, but this was not the case.
Rym: I don't think I've ever run into anyone where that was the case.
Rym: I think people legitimately don't actually calculate how much they owe and they think they're putting in enough, but they really aren't.
Scott: People don't seem to realize, A, how much the tax actually is, B, how much the tip actually is, C, drinks and advertisers, what they actually cost.
Scott: Someone will get like, you know, I always get water, right?
Scott: Pretty much.
Scott: Or I'll get a milkshake and occasionally lemonade.
Scott: And that's about all I'll ever get to drink at a restaurant.
Rym: Most of the time, just tap water or like wine or a cocktail, something big that I pay for, like on my own, because it's like if you get like a glass of wine, it's probably going to be like five dollars at least, if not more.
Rym: But more importantly, sodas, soft drinks, stuff like that.
Scott: They charge like 250.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And a lot of restaurants we go to, they charge three, four.
Rym: I've seen places charge five bucks for a soda.
Rym: Oftentimes they're not free refills.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So people sort of, you know, forget like how much those things actually cost.
Scott: I mean, if I go to a diner, I'll get French toast for five bucks.
Scott: Then I'll get water, orange juice and milk.
Scott: And the orange juice and milk are two dollars each.
Scott: So it's nine dollars.
Scott: And people, you know, like they sort of they look at like the entree that they order on the menu and because that's the biggest, most solid price.
Scott: And then all the other things there, you know, a portion of an appetizer, you know, or, you know, that they shared with some people and like a drink and a refill on it.
Scott: You know those are small and they don't actually see those, you know, they don't look at the price of the drink on the menu.
Scott: So it doesn't come into their calculation.
Scott: So they pay, you know, maybe their entree was 15.
Scott: So they throw in 18.
Scott: They owe like 25 and they don't realize it because they weren't, you know, actually calculating.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So one, if you're a smart person, the way to avoid this whole situation, always drink tap water.
Rym: Well, one, if you want to save money, never order a drink, just always get water because that that's free.
Scott: and watch out for those restaurants that try to sell you a bottled water, say tap water.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But they have to give it to you and don't order appetizers.
Rym: Or if you do whatever you actually order, note exactly what it cost from the menu and remember that and calculate exactly what you owe.
Rym: Just take, you know, add everything up that you owe and then add like 30 percent to it to cover tax tip and everything and put that in and have these numbers handy.
Rym: And then when the bill comes up short, literally, the only way to deal with this is to point out, look, I got this and this and this.
Rym: I owed exactly this.
Rym: Here's the tip I put in.
Rym: I'm out.
Rym: And then leave the table.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Because there is no way to resolve this situation.
Rym: And I hate to say this, but the front row crew, this happens too.
Rym: We're getting actually very close to figuring out who's causing the problem by eating with different combinations of people for a while and all the burning wheel games and everything.
Rym: We're real close.
Rym: We've got to narrow down.
Rym: I think there are.
Rym: there are four suspects and it's either some or all of them who are consistently shorting the bill every time the front row crew goes out.
Scott: It's definitely not malicious.
Scott: You know, I don't think anyone's trying to short the bill.
Scott: Everyone's throwing in money.
Scott: But I think there are just some people who, you know, neglect to understand, you know, the cost of what they're actually ordering.
Rym: Seriously, to avoid these situations for you yourself and to save money or to tap water.
Scott: And I mean, the worst is when I went to that Thai place and I think I paid for like three or four people's meals, you know, after I calculated how much money I actually got back.
Rym: Everyone actually owed with all the food we ordered.
Scott: I mean, that was you know, it was like this takeout place.
Scott: No one thought it was big money, but the bill was like over 200 dollars.
Rym: Well, because everyone's meal plus appetizers and drinks was like 40 bucks.
Scott: And everyone got like Thai's teas all around.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But seriously, tap water is the way to go.
Rym: You would not believe how much money I saved when I was poor at RIT, not getting appetizers and more importantly, not sharing appetizers with other people because they will screw you.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, how many times do you get an appetizer?
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like a Shumai and you get one of the Shumai and the rest go away.
Rym: You're like, but then no one else puts in money for the appetizer.
Rym: Right.
Scott: So it's like you ate one of the Shumai, even though you ordered it and you paid for all.
Rym: the drawback of this is that you mostly when you go with a big group of people, they're going to want to split the check evenly.
Rym: And that only works.
Rym: I mean, really, if you're eating at a place like, I don't know, the hibachi at the Necco, we go to where everything pretty much costs the same.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Everyone throws in 20 bucks.
Rym: You're good.
Rym: Don't let everyone just split the checkup.
Scott: It works.
Scott: it like a family style place, too, because everyone is all sharing every everyone's eating everything, you know, but don't pull.
Rym: Don't let people do that.
Rym: If you're going to order the tap water.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, I mean, think about this, right?
Scott: If we go to a steakhouse, right.
Scott: I order a 20 dollar steak.
Scott: Rym orders a 20 dollar steak.
Scott: All right.
Scott: I get a tap water.
Scott: Rym gets a 30 dollar bottle of wine.
Scott: Well, splitting that evenly.
Scott: Not bad, really.
Scott: Even if I got a 10 dollar appetizer and we shake, he ate one third and I ate two thirds of it.
Scott: Really unfair to split the bill evenly.
Rym: Now, I don't know what to do about the shorting people.
Rym: in the long run, though, and if you confront him or what, because it's not going to be that long until we'd like kind of mathematically prove who is shorting our bill.
Scott: Yeah, it's all right.
Rym: I don't think any of them are going to listen to the show anytime soon and everyone's coming out this weekend.
Rym: So if they don't listen, then maybe I can engineer the final test.
Rym: I need to figure out exactly who it is.
Scott: Maybe we should do is just go around the table and get the money from the people one at a time.
Scott: And then, you know, just be like, OK, Scott, give me your money.
Scott: OK, other Scott, give me your money.
Scott: OK, you know, Emily, give me your money.
Scott: And then you'd be like, you know, and then if someone gives you their money, that's not enough.
Rym: And that'll be that you got to know what everyone orders and how much it costs.
Scott: Well, if you're you're going to do the credit card thing and you just get, you know, you get the bill.
Rym: No, then you can't do it based on the bill.
Rym: That's why I said you have to note it before you give the menu away, because when you get the bill, it's going to say like chicken parm for and then the price will be that times four.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And you're going to have to do a little bit more math.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: You get a little calculator.
Rym: Plus, people don't remember what they order.
Rym: You know, often someone will come up to the table and be like, here's the shrimp, whatever.
Rym: And no one claims it because no one remembers what they ordered.
Scott: I remember what I ordered anyway.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: The other thing is, you know, if you're finished eating and you want to leave because this happens to us a lot and they didn't bring you the check yet, like get someone's attention ASAP to get that check.
Scott: Otherwise you're going to be.
Scott: you could be sitting there for a while.
Rym: No one better way.
Rym: As soon as you get your food, ask for the check immediately.
Scott: Well, if you know that you're going to be in a rush to get out of there, even like let's say you have a train to catch or a meeting.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Ask for the check as soon as you sit down or right after you order.
Scott: That way, as soon as you finish eating, you can get up and leave because you have the check already.
Rym: It's weird.
Rym: Like lately and it seems like it's getting worse.
Rym: I don't know why.
Rym: Maybe because people aren't eating out as much.
Rym: The restaurants want people to be in there longer.
Rym: So it looks like it's full.
Rym: Maybe the Lord of dessert, all that stuff.
Rym: But restaurants just don't bring me the check.
Rym: I've sat in places for like a half hour just trying to get anyone's attention.
Scott: I think it's also because we eat quickly than more quickly than average.
Scott: Maybe especially when there's fewer of us.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But when the crew when there's more people, the check seems to come at the right time.
Rym: The crew together will be in a restaurant for like two hours.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But when there's fewer people, we always end up waiting for the check as we eat quickly.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then, you know, pay and then, you know, play the not it game to see who has to go up and pay.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: If you want to get a trick I've always found where Peter and out here, I got almost nothing left.
Rym: Offer to pay with your credit card if you know that no one in your group will short and you will always end up with a surplus, even if you pay more than you need to pay.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: However, if people are shorting, not so much.
Scott: No, but yeah, if you, if you got a whole bunch of people who are paying the right amount or over, you know, pay with your credit card and you'll get a profit when you collect the cash from everyone else.
Rym: I think we're really Peter and out here.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I think we're done.
Rym: I had almost nothing.
Scott: That's how to eat at a restaurant.
Scott: The GeekNights away.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights, and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives, visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share-a-like 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.