Rym: Hey, it's Thursday November 12th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott over Skype, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: couches.
Rym: yeah couches.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So yesterday Emily, and I just stayed in the city and hung out at Scott's ultra modern swank apartment.
Scott: Yes, the luxuries of ultra modernists are plenty.
Rym: god damn example.
Scott: dishwashing Is automatic.
Scott: you push a button.
Rym: It was stylish and cool and in the city and and the worst part wasn't like the worst part I have worst stuck in my head from when we reviewed D&D online.
Rym: I get back home to beacon like today and suddenly beacon felt a thousand times more provincial than it used to.
Scott: It was like.
Rym: The thing is I was gonna buy a house in beacon, and I'm still like vaguely exploring that.
Rym: but For those of you who haven't been following the forum in the deeper details of the Rym and Scott experience the house I was trying to buy the dude.
Rym: I was buying it from totally skip town Like completely and the bank is like fuck.
Rym: We can't sell it to you until we foreclose on this guy foreclosures gonna take forever and be a pain in the ass.
Scott: It should be right.
Scott: in the perfect world you go to the judge you just show them some evidence like look this guy skipped town.
Scott: We're a bank.
Scott: We're the bank and the judge says he bangs the hammer And he says the house is taken away from that guy.
Rym: the thing is there's a lot of protection For people who like a family living in a house who like suddenly come on tough times to make sure that they don't Immediately get foreclosed on that.
Rym: sometimes once
Scott: a week once a week right for like an hour The judge go drives around town with the banks if they need to and they show them the houses that no one is in and They say judge give us this house, and the judge bangs his hammer on the grass and says okay Then
Rym: I come back.
Rym: I'm like I was on vacation Jesus.
Rym: So I failed and I got my 20 grand deposit back and I lost a couple grand worth of like paying my lawyer.
Rym: Luckily this lawyer because he threw.
Rym: he was so sure he could get the house.
Rym: I had him on retainer And I only paid him like this initial fee And I only had to pay him all the rest of the money if I got the house.
Rym: So he basically did all this work for nothing Same with my realtor.
Rym: Yeah, oh wow.
Rym: Yeah, she works for me Yep, and she worked for me for over a year and like did a lot of work on my behalf And she got absolutely no money.
Scott: nothing It sucks.
Scott: yeah, you should you should give her a present or something.
Rym: Yeah, the thing is I had like all the you know my whole thing the Horatio thing.
Rym: we haven't been on an FNPL lately So I can't bring up the whole Horatio hornblower metaphor.
Rym: You know Horatio Nelson But the idea that you know the people who are successful who wants to know exactly how much to leave to chance you wait for That Horatio moment and whenever there's a Horatio moment you make the big move and you otherwise Never make a big move unless you're forced to and you defer all decisions until you cannot defer them any further.
Scott: That is precisely correct.
Rym: That's like the game theory way to succeed at everything.
Scott: Yeah, you should you know you should send like some go to the flowers website.
Rym: I'm gonna do something for me like.
Scott: I am sorry that you worked all this time and got nothing.
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: like imagine if you worked at your job all year on like a project and then at the end They just decided not to use it And then they didn't pay you and they took basically if you worked half a day on it for you know a year They just took half your money away.
Rym: So pretty much.
Rym: I had two other Horatio Movements and one was buy another house in Beacon because their houses prices dropped even more and it got the point to where I could Basically buy one of those McMansions like a big one straight up.
Rym: just no trouble at all.
Rym: So I sent her a list of like.
Rym: these are the nine houses near the train station that are all nice and mansiony that I would like to look at and A week later.
Rym: She came back.
Rym: I just got the full info yesterday, and she's like yeah Seven of those are short sales and the last one is currently in foreclosure.
Scott: Well that means the last one you know might be out of foreclosure soon enough.
Rym: the last one had been converted into three apartments.
Scott: That's not what I live in one and rent - Yeah, yeah, but look at the kind of be kind of fun to live in an interesting.
Rym: I did that though I did that for a while.
Rym: remember when I lived in Fishkill in the box.
Scott: Yeah, no, I mean you if you owe it would be more.
Rym: You know if I owned it.
Rym: if I'm the jolly landlord I come home And I'm like sup Jim living in apartment X waiting for that.
Scott: I mean you live in all three of them at once.
Rym: I have like that'd be weird That's what I'm saying.
Rym: But basically it's all like this gigantic pain in the ass and it got to the point to where it was basically impossible to buy a house in Beacon without drama.
Rym: So I was like all right.
Rym: I got money.
Rym: now Let's just look like further down closer to the city buy a house and like one of the up more fancy Half the size of the one I was looking at caused more than twice as much.
Scott: Why don't you check out some Dobbs Ferry?
Scott: I?
Rym: Did I look around?
Scott: it's apparently starting to get happening?
Rym: Yeah, so I looked around and I was just fail fail fail fail fail.
Rym: And then I looked on the other train lines, and it's actually looking Connecticut looking like Stanford.
Rym: I don't want to take the Connecticut trains.
Scott: rich people live there.
Rym: Yeah, but those trains of Metro North notice how they're the least reliable.
Scott: Well, that's because they have a lot of some of the.
Scott: a lot of the Connecticut trains use the overhead cables.
Rym: The catenaries are actually better.
Rym: the delays are due to other issues With like where the tracks are the catenary.
Scott: the thing is the catenary trains.
Scott: the layout of the interiors is far less efficient And they're less big.
Scott: so there's a lot less seating, and there's more standing.
Scott: well except for but and this are it's impossible to get parking and it's money.
Scott: when there is parking it's much more expensive.
Scott: and The only other thing about them is that those catenary trains have bark?
Rym: I was about to say they have the bars in the cars.
Rym: I mean when I take this right now It's like on the beacon train.
Scott: It's like you got to buy your alcohol and then get on the tree every
Rym: now And then I see someone like buying like five beers or like a bunch of wine and then getting on the train
Scott: Whereas in the Connecticut train that guy that is you know standing at the you know in the in the terminal There's
Rym: just a bar.
Rym: it'd be bad though because if I had a bar on the train I would pretty much hang out in that bar every day.
Scott: That's a lot of people do.
Scott: yeah, you know there's a. basically the seating in there is like these little circles.
Scott: It's like you know sort of like a lounge And there's a little tiny table in the middle of the circley bit And then you know and you can also sit at the bar, and you can stand
Rym: Yep, so all that aside My other plan my other Horatio plan other than buying a house at the bottom of like the economic downturn Was to buy land and sit on it and pay it off because you can buy land really cheaply and then build my own.
Rym: Build my own goddamn mansion on it because I'm the goddamn Batman And you can't for it.
Scott: they no one's foreclosing on any dirt I know.
Rym: so I found this lot And it's basically remember when I first found out that you could climb out.
Rym: beacon is all that stuff up there.
Rym: When I first found that out is because I watered up this random trail.
Rym: The lot is basically the two acres in front of and including part of that trail.
Rym: It's got FiOS.
Rym: It's got electricity City water city sewer gas.
Scott: they ever have FiOS on the mountain, but they don't have FiOS over near the car dealers.
Rym: They have it here.
Rym: now.
Rym: If I was staying here, I'd get it.
Scott: well You're renting.
Scott: so it's hard to get FiOS if you don't own it because that means that you install a bunch of shit And they might not.
Scott: you know I'm sure Mary wouldn't care, but I mean it's like yeah, but so I'm all excited.
Rym: I'm like you know what I'm just gonna do it or at least I'm gonna check it out.
Rym: So I get you know my realtor to check it all out and everything's good.
Rym: It's like this is exactly the perfect lot for your Rym.
Rym: You can build your mansion.
Rym: I got a builder to check it out, and they're like yeah This is perfect building you can have like a super big completely dry basement and everything the city was like.
Rym: yeah You can subdivide it.
Rym: you could build an apartment building and a house.
Rym: So I'm like hot shit.
Rym: And it was only a hundred and fifty grand.
Rym: the taxes before you build something on.
Rym: it was like a thousand dollars a year.
Scott: I would build a house And then I would build a garage a two-car garage And then I would build like a whole thing on top of the two-car garage.
Scott: that was basically like a space of Awesomeness like just a one big room three house.
Scott: No wouldn't have.
Scott: I wouldn't put like a kitchen or anything in there.
Scott: It'd just be one big room, and it would be like.
Scott: you know the special room like us you know.
Rym: So I'm like all right.
Rym: pull the trigger get me like get me everything I need build a skywalk to it or something.
Rym: get me everything.
Rym: I need to buy this land And I got word today.
Rym: She's like somebody already bought that land two weeks ago.
Rym: So I looked at all the other land and all the other land Sucks, it's like 40 grand for a half-acre way.
Rym: far away from the train station I found one.
Rym: it was like 30 grand, and it was like a nice lot And it was near the train, and you know I couldn't buy it.
Rym: There's a gigantic rock on the property like Too big and so it would have been so expensive to move that rock to build a house.
Rym: You know how expensive it is to pay people to smash a rock you can't.
Scott: That would be badass.
Rym: however that would cost like at six or seven hundred thousand dollars to build because why don't you build the house such that the rock is a structurally integral part of the house a Door fortress exactly yeah, so I might just fucking move into the city.
Rym: Like.
Scott: I'm like 15 minutes to work, but I got at the tray at the subway with Emily this morning Yeah, and it was you know one of those days with the subway.
Scott: Just like is like traffic something something Scott.
Rym: It took me 31 minutes to get to work.
Rym: It sucks Because I got to take the end down to the seven.
Rym: then I can get on the seven Express that goes right to Grand Central.
Scott: Well, yeah, you could you could do that.
Rym: the thing is It's a lot faster.
Rym: take the seven Express because seven Express goes by like every three minutes.
Rym: There was almost no one on mine.
Rym: Yeah, I had a seat the whole way.
Rym: the only delay I really had was that I didn't realize I was at Grand Central on the seven.
Rym: so I ended up taking it to Bryant Park.
Rym: Oh, good.
Rym: I was like what the fuck am I?
Rym: then I get out.
Rym: I'm in Bryant Parks.
Rym: I had to walk back across But then Basically most of my waiting was because I didn't look at the schedule of the end train.
Rym: So I just walked to the subway and I got there like as an end left side to wait.
Rym: like that happens to me every Goddamn day I do it like 12 minutes for another end to come.
Scott: as I'm walking to the subway.
Scott: every goddamn day one pulls up and I'm like just like well fuck and then I have to go and wait on the platform for the maximum possible.
Rym: The worst thing in the world is when you're walking up to a subway and you hear the train like coming in.
Rym: You're like fuck fuck fuck.
Rym: You're fumbling with your metro card.
Rym: You're like like smash it into the sheen and bend it and you can't get in.
Rym: you're rushing and you always have to make That decision of do I run or do I just give the fuck up?
Scott: Because why am I in a hurry to get to work?
Rym: You know That was my philosophy when I used to drive to the Bronx every day Like I'd see people speeding and I was like why the fuck would I ever speed on the way to work?
Rym: Speed on the way home.
Rym: Yep, but like anytime the road was blocked which happened kind of frequently because of the you know, the Basically, the sawmill Parkway is like the second worst road in the world.
Rym: The thing is I would just like pull off to like a diner and eat breakfast.
Rym: I wouldn't even bother trying to get to work.
Scott: The thing is I think the phenomena of walking up to the subway and it pulls up and then you it's you're like damn it You can't get on it cuz you're just like it's 30 seconds too late.
Scott: Yeah, that phenomena is completely because these are you know above ground subways.
Scott: They're up, you know elevated rail tracks.
Scott: If the subway was underground you wouldn't see that it was coming into the station until you're already down there.
Scott: So you wouldn't even know if it like it's train.
Scott: Yeah Like seconds before you got down.
Rym: but at the same time like in Grand Central for example many times I'll like be walking like toward that stairway down to the six and I'll hear it coming in and it's like Well, how do you know that's not a four or five?
Rym: Well, the thing is whatever one I want I hear one coming in.
Rym: So then there's a decision of I have to think do I run?
Rym: is that the train I want?
Scott: I basically never run.
Rym: and then you'd like you've got it.
Rym: You can kind of peek your head around as you're walking down the stairs and you see like, ah, it's the four I wanted.
Rym: doors are closing.
Rym: fuck Here comes the six gonna take forever.
Scott: I just never run.
Scott: I don't care anymore.
Scott: Yeah, even if I lose what 15 minutes, that's nothing compared to what I lost in Beacon.
Scott: So it's like oh shit.
Rym: Yeah, the only thing is I can't listen to 15 minutes of a podcast.
Scott: I can watch a whole TED talk while I'm on the platform.
Rym: I'll have to read more and watch more like portable media.
Rym: But I can't really use the laptop or do anything intensive on the commute because it's so you can.
Scott: you can read a book or you?
Scott: Can listen to something you can watch a video on the iPhone and not cuz it's so short.
Rym: It's really not that short.
Rym: It's because there are like multiple interruptions along the way.
Rym: It's like a walk gotta sit gotta walk again sit again walk again sit again walk and then I'm at work.
Scott: Yep, and you also even if you're standing on the subway, you got to dodge people dodge people dodge people.
Scott: Yep, better try to get on and off the train.
Rym: So we'll see.
Rym: maybe I'll just move into your building.
Rym: I'm gonna start looking at apartments.
Scott: There's other buildings are out here.
Scott: There's actually a big big building.
Scott: That's real fancy looking.
Scott: They're still building it across the street.
Scott: You could just wait for it.
Rym: Yeah, I might But the only fancy the big thing I got to do now is my original plan was I got all?
Rym: we got all this furniture.
Rym: We're kind of just like deferring decisions because if I bought a house I would just buy like my half of all of it.
Rym: cuz you know house needs furniture.
Rym: I don't.
Rym: we're gonna do with that gigantic ass kitchen table and like all that like my gigantic wine cabinet.
Rym: I'm not bringing that to an apartment in the city.
Rym: That bed will fit.
Rym: I mean, it's a queen-size bed the same size.
Scott: Oh my bed.
Rym: Oh, yeah Give it to someone.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Maybe I'll ever get it.
Scott: We have to sell.
Scott: I think.
Rym: well first We might have to have a front row crew who wants our shit party.
Scott: Yeah Something actually a lot of this stuff I'm just gonna.
Scott: I think we should put out on the lawn and beacon and be like free.
Rym: Actually, you go in a knot and all them might.
Rym: they might be able to use your little bed because they got a lot extra space.
Scott: They want it.
Rym: maybe I'll see if they want it, I don't know.
Rym: we'll figure it out.
Rym: We also got to figure out what to do for you.
Scott: It's not free, but I kind of need money.
Rym: This would be the first year in a long time that I have not been the host of the New Year's party.
Rym: I've got.
Rym: I have to nominate someone to carry on the tradition at least for one year until we figure out.
Rym: I'm thinking with money next like next next year.
Rym: We should just rent like a fucking ballroom or something in the city.
Scott: Yeah So speaking of in the city, right.
Rym: so in the summer in the city in the summer in the city More and more of my house shit is taken care of.
Scott: so I'm gonna start doing some city stuff that I could not do before.
Scott: Yeah, so so boxy announced today that they're finally making a boxy box a piece of hard.
Rym: We were like the Roku.
Scott: Yes, so there is gonna be some sort of release launch something something in Brooklyn, December Something.
Scott: you can go with the boxy blog and there's a post about it.
Scott: So I RSVP'd for it.
Scott: so I'm gonna go check it out and Hopefully get one because I think if I had one of those I don't need to buy a Mac Mini.
Scott: and if it's really cheap Like a hundred bucks, even if it's 200 bucks It's like well no need to buy a $600 Mac Mini.
Scott: a boxy box does everything I need.
Rym: Yeah Oh, you know else we can voice stuff off on.
Rym: if they're willing to drive to this old house is the listeners.
Rym: I know a lot of you listeners are poor like punk college kids.
Scott: We can sell you anyone needs like beds or a desk that consists of cinder blocks and a piece of wood or a TV An old dresser.
Rym: I remember when you bought that cinder block thing.
Rym: Like you think like the cinder block desk is the cheapest cheapest option.
Rym: It was actually slightly expensive for because you got the nice cinder blocks and the nice piece of wood I got.
Scott: I got like six nice cinder blocks and like a big nice piece of wood and then I had to like.
Rym: I Sanded and stained the piece of wood and it was not that much cheaper than the desk.
Rym: I just bought.
Rym: However, it was actually a lot nicer in the end because I bought the shittiest fucking desk.
Scott: Yeah, remember that desk at RIT?
Rym: We tried to move it and the top just like fell off and cracked into.
Scott: Well that remember the desk that I bought at RIT.
Rym: That thing was.
Rym: that thing was legendary.
Scott: this new IKEA desk though is pretty good.
Scott: It's about the same size as the cinder block desk only no cinder blocks and it's got this nice rolling file.
Scott: That's pretty good.
Rym: Yes, though Even if I don't live in the same building if I live in the area You know all the concerns the listeners had of like oh shit and all the stuff I was planning like I was trying to figure Out.
Scott: there are other areas too.
Scott: Don't just limit to yourself to where I am.
Rym: I know I'm.
Rym: actually I found some places in Midtown that I'm looking at and some places on like Park Avenue.
Rym: Yeah, I'd love to live on Park Avenue.
Rym: across from Central Park.
Scott: There are some places like big apartment buildings a little bit west of my office.
Scott: I could point, you know, like they all have banners hanging on the side saying move in here.
Scott: call this number.
Rym: The other thing that makes it more complicated is that I don't get my raise until like next month.
Rym: So, I don't know how much I'm getting.
Rym: I mean, I'm gonna I gotta get at least like five percent.
Scott: I don't know if or what I'm getting but they actually I just got the form.
Scott: That's like the self-assessment form.
Rym: I'm like, oh shit About pretty much if I get I calculated if I get a 15% raise or more I can afford.
Rym: like luxury.
Scott: You can already this.
Scott: what I'm in is considered luxury.
Rym: I'm talking like luxury luxury.
Rym: It's weird, you know luxury not just considered.
Rym: Yeah, like, you know all you non New Yorkers and I didn't realize this.
Rym: You know how like you see in New York or whatever they'll say like in the Bronx luxury apartment versus normal apartment.
Rym: It's not like the rest of the world.
Rym: normal apartment means there's no wall the ceiling leaks and there's a body in it.
Rym: Luxury means normal apartment.
Scott: Yes luxury means it's modern.
Scott: It has new things.
Scott: It's clean.
Scott: There aren't rats.
Scott: That's what luxury means.
Rym: Yep, and beyond that there's basically decadent like living in like down down Not downtown, but like in those people live or like to do city called a palace.
Rym: I look into the city.
Scott: If down in the financial district, you know There's a whole bunch of like ultra fancy apartments that are actually relatively cheap because people don't actually live down there Because it's actually really boring, but there's big big buildings with fancy fancy apartments.
Rym: Yeah, my community be real easy.
Rym: I take the four to Grand Central.
Rym: I'm at work
Scott: Yeah, and you know, but you would you know, you could say
Rym: I live on Wall Street But I work for Wall Street, but not on Wall Street Yep, but mostly it's that if we're both living in the city all the stuff I was we're putting together to do the show better with Skype in and like recording ahead on weekends This is the show like fucking normal again.
Rym: But anyway things of the day, it's Thursday.
Rym: It's fast and loose GeekNights for the karate fast gentleman.
Rym: No, this is what we'll see.
Rym: how much actually.
Scott: I got one more thing to say that we should have included in the previous bit.
Scott: You were all talking like oh you should do the Horatio thing.
Scott: Just go for it, right?
Scott: Yeah, you know what the Horatio thing to do is.
Rym: Just run away to Europe.
Rym: no, what's the ratio thing?
Rym: more literally the Get a houseboat and just like.
Rym: And normally in a show like that or in a book like that you expect him in the sea to be like, all right I'm at war at the sea.
Rym: I can't wait for the war to end.
Rym: Horatio was like man.
Rym: The sea is great land sucks.
Rym: I don't ever want to go back.
Rym: Fuck the land Like when the wars and he's like yes the war ended.
Rym: ah shit, I gotta go back home to my wife.
Rym: Oh good.
Rym: She died of smallpox.
Rym: But the ratio thing was like buying land right now would have been a Horatio thing.
Rym: if I can't buy land Then the next ratio thing is just fucking move to the city and throw away all my shit.
Scott: Why don't you do the free yacht?
Rym: Because I don't know enough about yachts to deal with the free yacht.
Rym: There's another free yacht problem get this.
Rym: Do you know how many yachts there are for sale in?
Rym: Parts of the world where basically people can't get their yachts out because the only real way out is past Somalia.
Rym: There are luxury yachts like queuing up that can't go past.
Rym: Very few ships can deal with that sort of thing.
Scott: So if your boat isn't good enough you just you won't make it through the rough.
Rym: yeah very few people have boats.
Rym: Yeah, we'll see.
Rym: I was thinking about.
Rym: you know I'm not a sailor.
Rym: We'll have to ask one of our more adventurous listening.
Rym: You've never been to the West Indies.
Rym: Let me tell you Oh Oh Captain laudanum, but anyway things of the day.
Rym: This was pointed out on the forum and then it also appeared on FARC and I have to talk about this kid because this kid is So.
Rym: so like this guy gets it this kid is gonna grow up to be if not exactly Like us.
Rym: he is going to be awesome great things.
Rym: They're gonna come out of this game Because he's doing the same kind of shit.
Rym: I used to pull in high school But now there's an internet to where everyone's gonna find out about it.
Rym: Basically This kid is 10 years old.
Rym: His name is Will Phillips.
Rym: He's the caption on his picture on this article says Will Phillips freedom lover.
Rym: And it's not just that he's smart and cool.
Rym: his parents are equally smart and cool, which is the rare thing.
Scott: You don't get a smart and cool person from non smart cool parents.
Rym: occasionally you do but then I said that often Yep, and sometimes you get the kid who's not so smart and cool, but the parents are cool.
Rym: But this is the rare confluence of both.
Rym: Also given the situation to prove to the world that they are the way they are.
Rym: And this whole thing just reeks of that scene and Donnie Darko when the parents get called the principal's office and the principal explains what Donnie Darko did and dad's like Really?
Rym: That's what he did.
Rym: That's awesome.
Rym: Basically the kid is smart, which apparently is a big deal.
Scott: I just want to say this whole story by the way is is just more Fire more wood on the fire for why we should separate people based on smartness in school more.
Rym: beyond that I want this to be a movement and I'm now.
Rym: I'm basically not gonna stand up for the pledge ever if ever.
Rym: I'm in a situation where I should stand up for the pledge until gays can get married Because that's kind of what this kid is doing.
Rym: basically, you know the whole story you can read the article He decided not to stand up for the pledge anymore.
Rym: Well, I always stood up for the national anthem, but I didn't sing it or put my hand on my heart in protest of the war.
Scott: Yeah, that's what I always did is I was just stood up, but I didn't.
Rym: yeah Cuz you gotta do you gotta do the half, you know Put forth the gesture of like.
Rym: I agree with everything that song stands for but my country is not living up to it.
Rym: Yeah, so I got to go halfway.
Scott: That's what I do on the national anthem.
Scott: That's what I've been doing on the national anthem for like decades.
Rym: Anyway, yeah so but basically this kid was like I'm not gonna stand up for the pledge anymore because Gay people aren't you know, no, there's no freedom and justice for all if gay people don't have freedom and justice.
Rym: Yeah, and this is one of many times this kid has apparently taken a reasonable stand and basically the teachers and all the people around him acted like the way you expect and the kid Basically responded the way smart people do.
Rym: he's like everyone around me stupid.
Rym: Everyone around me is loud and there's.
Rym: they're overreacting and they're acting with their emotions, but I'm not backing down.
Rym: no matter what You should read this story.
Rym: It warms every cockle that is in my heart.
Scott: We need to just go around the country and we should.
Scott: it's easy to detect kids like this if you're smart.
Rym: I got.
Rym: here's a quote.
Rym: Here's a quote.
Rym: He's referring to the teacher.
Rym: that was like freaking out and yelling at him.
Rym: Quotes and then quoting again because I'm quoting the kid and I'm quoting the article.
Rym: She the teacher got a lot more angry and raised her voice and brought my mom and my grandma up.
Rym: Will said I was fuming and I was too furious to really pay attention to what she was saying.
Rym: after a few minutes I said quote.
Rym: with all due respect ma'am.
Rym: You can go jump off a bridge.
Rym: He was sent to the office and given up given an assignment to look up Information about the flag and what it represents and the kid came back.
Rym: and then you read the story.
Rym: That's when the kid came back with the epic smart righteous indignant snark.
Rym: This kid is so cool.
Rym: I want to interview him on GeekNights.
Rym: I'm gonna try to contact his parents.
Rym: be like, can I interview your kid on my radio show?
Rym: I promise I promise I'm not a pedophile.
Scott: You have to make sure it.
Scott: to let him know that we're like, you know This is not like the news.
Scott: trying to like, you know, make a big thing that this is just.
Scott: you know nerds Trying to praise other nerds and smart people.
Rym: if I can I want to give this kid a TEDx talk.
Scott: Oh Shit.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, because that that would get us some publicity.
Rym: our TEDx is a ten-year-old speaker.
Rym: Who's actually good?
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: the end of the article says and I quote somewhere Thomas Jefferson smiles.
Scott: It's like who wrote this article.
Rym: I don't know wrote the article, but it's on the arkta Written the article the opposite way, right?
Scott: You could have written the article like smartass kid won't say the pledge.
Scott: Fuck this kid and his parents.
Rym: Yep, or even worse gay kid.
Rym: That's my thing of the day.
Rym: Will Phillips if you find this podcast for whatever reason you're a goddamn hero in my book.
Scott: Yeah, so if you're that if you don't like this kind of kid, you're not Even better.
Rym: There's a picture of this thing.
Rym: There's a picture of him.
Rym: I'll bet he looks exactly like so many the kids that like the summer camps with all the geeky shit you used to go to.
Rym: Maybe he's like this geeky little kid.
Scott: Yeah, so I got new TV.
Scott: All right, cuz the episodes gonna be our couches, right?
Rym: Yes Yeah, sure.
Scott: Okay, so I got.
Scott: the other thing was a TV.
Scott: I guess I don't do an episode on TVs.
Scott: That would be kind of silly.
Rym: Well, it'd be tough because I'm not up on the technology.
Rym: I have to do research again.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: But one thing that I knew is that you know, basically when everyone knows this at least I hope you know Everybody knows it.
Rym: Yeah, everybody knows.
Scott: Yes, when you go to Best Buy or something All the TVs are set on vivid mode or Store demo mode, which is basically all the colors are super saturated and like everything just kind of looks.
Scott: Yeah, basically what they do is they change they crank the contrast and the brightness and the saturation way up.
Scott: That's why like when you go to the store all the TVs are like, whoa, that's amazing You know because it's just like the colors just like ah The thing is right.
Scott: While it looks amazing psychologically speaking if you actually watch TV like that with those settings on all the time a It'll hurt your eyes.
Scott: It's kind of not comfortable and to the colors are just wrong Like, you know.
Scott: and the thing is, you know, you might not realize the colors are wrong, but they are so wrong wrong wrong.
Scott: So I was trying.
Scott: I knew this right and I so of course when I went to the store to look at TVs I switched them to normal mode instead of vivid mode, but that's not really enough, you know it's like you have to calibrate to get the actual correct colors on a display whether it's a monitor or a television and To do this you need like some test patterns and some instructions and all these sorts of things.
Scott: You know, the only way to do it perfectly is with expensive equipment But you could do it 90% perfectly with just some test patterns.
Scott: So I went online.
Scott: I was trying to find some test pattern discs to help me out and all of them apparently suck.
Scott: So it's like and they were expensive too.
Scott: They're like 20 30 bucks.
Scott: I'm like fuck that, right?
Scott: So I didn't even bother.
Scott: I just put my TV in normal mode and let it be that way and I'll calibrate it if I have to later.
Scott: I don't.
Scott: it's too much effort.
Scott: regardless.
Scott: I found this awesome thread on the high def forum, right and what they have here are pictures of Uncalibrated TVs and Calibrated TVs side by side, right?
Scott: So it's like you look at one picture and it's an uncalibrated TV and you're like, oh that looks alright, you know It's a high-definition picture Lots of bright colors.
Scott: and then you look at the calibrated TV and then you compare the two at the same time and you're like Oh my god, how come in the calibrated one?
Scott: It's not white.
Scott: It's blue.
Scott: You know, the difference is just like oh shit.
Scott: So if you are one of those cuz someone on Twitter was like skeptical.
Scott: they were like, yeah those Calibration just don't do shit.
Scott: and I was like, uh, no, actually they really do do something.
Scott: They're sort of necessary You're?
Scott: you don't know you're talking about.
Scott: so here is the proof.
Scott: if you do not believe that your TV has the quote wrong colors Coming out of it.
Scott: Then you need to look at all of the awesome pictures in this thread.
Scott: It's actually really long and like.
Scott: there's a lot of people, you know, calibrating different TVs.
Scott: There's like five pages worth of You know posts and images and also it's pretty good and it's it's fun to look at.
Scott: also like yeah different things here Ah crap, you know what?
Rym: I didn't take into account New York City income tax.
Rym: I'll have to pay an extra four grand a year in taxes.
Scott: Yeah, I'm paying the extra.
Rym: That's all four grand.
Rym: It's a lot of money.
Scott: Yeah, it's it's monies.
Rym: It's like fifteen hundred dollars plus three point two percent of all the money over fifty grand.
Scott: Yes, something like that, huh?
Scott: Oh well Yep, it's the cost of living.
Rym: Well, I refuse to live in Jersey.
Scott: So yeah, there's.
Rym: no I'm living there.
Rym: Oh my god, one of my co-workers even like yeah Why don't you just move to Jersey?
Rym: and I was like, do you like living in Jersey?
Rym: and he was like You know Jersey's not so bad Bergen debacle fuck you Bergen.
Rym: if you're gonna commute to New York like Bergen is the county, you know If I was in Bergen, I would do something very specific.
Rym: I would work from home one day, right?
Rym: Sunday for a New York company.
Rym: now, it's interstate commerce.
Rym: Then I would sue.
Rym: I would email the city or send them a certified letter saying I work to this day Bring charges against me and then when they did I'd sue him.
Rym: interstate commerce.
Scott: Yeah It'd be interesting but I pointed out I would just.
Scott: I would just do straight-up defiance.
Scott: I would open a store and open it up.
Rym: I pointed out something even better because in my department everyone other than my boss lives in Jersey in that County.
Rym: You know once a week like every now and then one of us is on support and if we get paged we have to work.
Rym: It is illegal for them to work on Sunday.
Scott: You looked at the law.
Rym: Yeah Yeah If you live in Paramus, especially uh-huh, so I don't know.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: how did I told them they should take it to our boss and be like, yeah I can't.
Rym: I can't respond to pages on Sundays.
Scott: Sorry law Yeah, that would be interesting.
Scott: cuz right instead of you know them the employees suing what they should do is they should just be like Sorry, I can't respond to pages on Sundays, right and then at your company will do something about it.
Scott: Hey our employees who happen to live in your town are technically not allowed to.
Scott: you know Do work on Sunday when they're on call.
Scott: We're coming after you, you know They would probably just all that would happen is they would pass an exception in the county, you know legislation Anyway, huh?
Rym: But then yeah, I'm sure you could use that exception to do awesome stuff like sell things.
Scott: He's the IKEA open.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, anyway, so the metamucil Couchy oh You keep for every time.
Rym: that's why I say metamucil?
Rym: because yeah, I think you need it.
Scott: So metamin it.
Scott: I Was actually looking at some fiber pills in the store the other day.
Rym: Are you having some some pooping troubles?
Rym: No one just looks at fiber supplements.
Rym: No, it's just like I'm gonna look at some fiber supplements.
Rym: That's a fun thing to do.
Rym: They think either I haven't pooped in a long time or I pooped way too frequently.
Scott: The kind that you have the powder.
Scott: I don't want to do.
Scott: that's nasty I don't do that, right.
Scott: so it's looking to be pill related ones, right and I'm looking and it's like okay pills.
Scott: It's like 15 bucks.
Scott: You get a whole bottle full of pills like a hundred or so Right.
Scott: Yeah, so I look at the instructions, you know what the instructions say.
Rym: What do they say?
Scott: take six pills a day?
Scott: And you know how much fiber that is not enough.
Rym: How many I guess how much I'm gonna go with 70% of your daily recommended dose.
Scott: how many how many grams?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: You wouldn't ask unless it was really high or really low a million For what four grams?
Scott: four grams is how much I could get with like two pieces of bread.
Scott: So it's like I'll just use a different bread that has fibers in it and fuck this frickin, you know, wow.
Rym: So anyway met a minute.
Rym: the details will be forthcoming but we can at least tell you guys all now I Have officially gotten a license to run a TEDx.
Rym: So we are going to be running a TEDx in Connecticut and In the summer, there will be many more details to come.
Rym: I have to clear the press release with the TED Organization before I issue a press release and get all the details, but we're gonna run it.
Rym: We're basically we're only going to invite the members of Connecticut for the first of these TEDx's.
Scott: So you should become a member of Connecticut and then you will get an invite to TEDx.
Rym: Yes, and if this goes well, ah You can foresee many more TEDx's run by myself and Scott.
Rym: If this goes poorly, I don't know.
Rym: Maybe the TED organization will shoot us.
Rym: I don't know how it works.
Scott: What's the worst case?
Rym: the worst case scenario is I commit seppuku and shame because I've sullied the TED name.
Scott: No, but I mean can they like sue us?
Rym: Basically, if we screw it up, they will not give us future licenses for TEDx's.
Scott: but that's it.
Rym: Yeah, that's pretty much it.
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: Unless we defame them or libel them or slander them.
Scott: Yeah, we will.
Scott: we will libel them with false praise.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: We're like they cured my cancer with their lectures.
Scott: Anyway, so if you book the book club selection is hitchhiker's guide to the galaxy.
Scott: Just be just the first book.
Scott: none of the other books None of the you know, you can read those if you want But we will not discuss them.
Scott: only the hitchhiker's guide to the galaxy by Douglas Adams.
Scott: So read that book and there will be an episode discussing it in the near future.
Rym: But I want to talk about the TEDx for one more minute.
Rym: one more.
Rym: you've one more muscle.
Scott: So one if you don't get sued by Metamucil.
Rym: good Just if you want to give a TED talk a TEDx talk for us don't apply.
Rym: We're not going to be accepting submissions.
Rym: However, if you want us to get a specific person who you think would give a good TEDx talk Email us at GeekNights at front row.
Rym: crew calm and we will consider your nomination.
Rym: If you can think of someone who does you think you want to see?
Rym: you thought of someone.
Rym: I thought like five people already.
Scott: I just thought of someone.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: I want to invite some really weird people.
Scott: I'll tell you right.
Scott: remember it said when we're done with the show after we hang it up.
Scott: Just say Scott tell me the person you thought of during the show and I'll tell you I swear to God.
Rym: if you don't remember I Swear to God.
Scott: I can't really forget John Taylor Gatto.
Scott: No, but that's a good choice.
Scott: Bring that one is even alive.
Rym: Yes Anyway, the only other met a minute thing.
Rym: obviously GeekNights is still fast and loose with Skype.
Rym: We don't know how much longer that'll go on But we'll get back to our regularly scheduled audio once our our personal lives settle down.
Rym: and that's it.
Scott: So couches Yeah, I mean So I just bought this couch from Ikea.
Rym: It's a really nice couch.
Rym: It's like super modern design like the nice stylish low couch with the chase on the side of it.
Scott: It's basically what it is, right?
Scott: It's an l-shaped catch But it's not an l-shaped like the curved ones where someone's gonna sit sideways.
Scott: I mean you could you know, but basically everyone's supposed to you know, three seats.
Scott: everyone sits forward But the rightmost seat is long.
Scott: So you basically you don't even have an ottoman.
Scott: It's just basically a long seat.
Scott: You just lay down.
Scott: It's like a little you know chase.
Scott: So the right seat is long and the left seats are just normal seats and then you know There's three cushions and it's nice and square, right?
Scott: It's this dark gray color Which is you know, it's good because most every all the other furniture of the room is black.
Rym: Well, the cool thing about it was that it's also a queen-size bed.
Rym: But you know, we're hanging out at Scott's apartment.
Scott: It's queen size or you think it's full size.
Scott: It's queen size.
Rym: It's queen size Alright, but the thing is we were laying on it right or sitting on it and I'm looking at I'm trying to figure out like I expected it to unfold in a certain way to become the bed.
Rym: The way it unfolded was not at all what I expected but was in retrospect a much smarter way to do it.
Scott: Yeah, basically the you know, it's an L shape so you have to fill in that area You know in the middle of the L to make a square so you pull out basically underneath the non L part.
Scott: You know, basically it's basically a love seat with like a law or the chase attached to it at the hip, right?
Scott: Underneath the love seat.
Scott: You just pull this box straight out and then it goes straight up and that's it.
Rym: Tada, tada You don't have to unfold anything.
Scott: it just comes out and up and then goes down and in that's it and it's pretty s. Actually, it's pretty nice because there is sort.
Scott: there isn't really an under-the-couch situation So much so you can't really lose things under there very easily.
Scott: The other thing is that the the long part lifts up and the storage underneath so you can put the cushions in there when you know When you're using it in bed mode and you can also put things under there like, you know store things Which is good because it's like, you know, you don't have enough closets in a tiny apartment.
Rym: You can have some storage right in the middle of the room.
Scott: That doesn't take up any extra space.
Scott: like imagine it like think about a living room.
Scott: a couch That's big takes up most of the living room.
Scott: Imagine if like the inside of the couch you could just put stuff.
Scott: it's like Damn, like Rym would always shove things under the couch in Beacon.
Scott: You know that didn't belong there.
Rym: I was sort of there like my weights and some Scott Johnson's.
Scott: Yeah, that's considered like inappropriate and messy but putting it in when you actually have a storage bin like this Then it's not considered inappropriate or messy.
Scott: It's considered Okay, and cool, even though it's basically the same exact thing storing stuff under the couch.
Rym: Of course, I do recall Way back.
Rym: We moved into colony the apartment that Scott and I lived in at RIT Which was basically luxury compared to most of the other apartments at RIT and it was luxury compared to what I Was the middle of the road right?
Scott: I mean cuz the you see was luxury but you had.
Rym: What did you say capstone?
Rym: Yeah, I mean you see what the hell is that?
Scott: I didn't say you see what do you say?
Rym: And the Perkins was slightly newer and fancier, but at the same time kind of dumpier like it was weird.
Scott: It depended on which.
Scott: they were all different and strange.
Rym: But then there was River Knoll Was a hole and racket Club was our.
Rym: oh my god racket Club was like.
Rym: Racket Club was a collection of like 50s temporary housing like these really really really nasty old like 50s era townhouses in Like a sub a suburb and then on the hill was an abandoned hotel that RIT had converted into dorms.
Scott: Then there was the RIT Inn and Conference Center Which is basically.
Scott: RIT bought this Marriott and turned it into the RIT hotel and What they did was they were like, oh shit We don't have enough housing for all these students But these students have.
Scott: some of these students have guaranteed housing from us So we'll put them in the hotel that we own.
Rym: that was a mixed blessing for those kids.
Scott: Yeah, it's like whoa, I get to live in a hotel for free.
Scott: Oh, I have to live in this faraway hotel Yep, but the thing is in colony.
Rym: we had like this nice one-bedroom apartment with a separate kitchen and like.
Rym: it had a foyer Kind of thing and it was actually pretty big all things considered.
Rym: But I remember we were like we moved in and it looked like a real house.
Rym: We had like the piano.
Rym: we had a couch and a loveseat.
Rym: We had all real furniture.
Scott: I had that old kitchen table for my parents.
Rym: Yep, like it was weird.
Scott: It was the kitchen table of my youth.
Scott: I was sad to see it go Like.
Rym: you walked around colony and you look in our apartment like through the window and you saw like a nice house Like we're normal.
Rym: actual people would live like a family could have been living in that.
Rym: you look in the window next door and you would see like a table that had been broken in two and the pieces were still laying around the room and
Scott: there was a hole punched in the
Rym: wall and they didn't have any furniture except the broken table and some like coffee table chair Things and like a beanbag that looked like it had vomit stains on it.
Rym: And as you as you walked around colony Every apartment looked like that.
Rym: as far as I could tell we were the only people in colony who had furniture.
Scott: Yeah, I mean most of it was basically they took dorm stuff and they just had a lot more space.
Scott: So it was spread out and sparse.
Scott: Yeah, and they just.
Scott: it was basically like living in.
Scott: it's like why don't you just live in?
Scott: The dorms dude.
Scott: Why did you even bother?
Rym: You know coming to me was like how often I look and see just like broken Furniture laying on the floor like I'm knocked over desk that no one ever picked back up.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: All right No one had curtains except us either.
Rym: as far as I could tell We only had actual curtains in the living room and the bedroom.
Rym: we had ghetto curtains and in the kitchen We had that bed sheet that I hung over the window.
Scott: Yeah, but at least it was something to hang it on over the window.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah where I am now That's my problem is I've got curtains.
Scott: I just can't get the freaking bar up there.
Scott: I'm gonna try some self tapping screws.
Scott: I'm gonna go investigate that line of.
Rym: but the only reason we really had furniture Is because my dad basically gave me all the furniture.
Rym: He didn't need anymore.
Rym: so he gave me that wine cabinet and like a bunch of bookshelves and a bed and That couch in that loveseat.
Rym: The sad thing those couch the couch in loveseat like they were great.
Rym: That was like.
Rym: that was that made our apartment the place to hang out for many years at RIT.
Rym: We like the center of the crew after my couch basically died and we left it behind.
Rym: Well, we left the loveseat.
Rym: No, we left the couch behind.
Scott: Yeah, you're right the couch.
Scott: We brought the loveseat.
Rym: loveseat still in beacon the uh, here's the deal.
Rym: the couch and loveseat were white with a floral print By the time we took them out of colony.
Rym: They were basically dark gray
Scott: dark gray
Rym: Surprisingly dark
Scott: and as dark as my new couch, which is dark on purpose, but still they were Not good,
Rym: they're so ruined like I feel like I should just burn the loveseat that I've got in this
Scott: Outside of colony once there was a burning couch,
Rym: you know, it's weird how to this day that memory I don't think stupid college kids.
Rym: It's kind of like this heartwarming memory of the time in my life When I lived in what was effectively here is Greenwood when just
Scott: it's like there was a time in your life where you could look Out your window and there would be a couch on fire on the grass right outside the window And that was perfectly normal and acceptable.
Scott: It's just like a burning couch.
Rym: Yeah I wonder who did that?
Scott: that happened like, you know anywhere like in nor outside of like a college residential setting.
Scott: It would be like what the fuck a burning couch.
Rym: So I remember like I walked past the burning couch and I'm like, huh and I just went into the apartment like didn't think everything.
Rym: I was like Scott this burning couch.
Rym: He's like really we walk outside.
Scott: There it is Far enough away from any buildings to actually set anything on fire.
Rym: eventually campus safety came over the campus safety guy I remember because by then the fire had gone out.
Rym: It was just like the the skeleton of a couch and by char all around and he had this look of.
Rym: are you serious?
Rym: These god damn it you kids.
Rym: But that was all like it was gonna get rid of this cat.
Rym: I Kind of miss those days of just you know The weirdos just doing their weird shit around you like here in the screaming and bang.
Scott: No, I really want to.
Scott: you know If I had a jillion dollars still I would open I would buy an apartment building or a compound or some kind of Residential condo something and make it geeks.
Scott: only somehow, you know get around the housing laws.
Scott: Everyone else gets around them.
Rym: Yeah, they're building you're living in now.
Rym: imagine if it was only geeks.
Rym: I know right.
Rym: Oh, you know what happened?
Rym: They'd be able to put stuff in those hallways geeky stuff.
Scott: Yeah, I'd like to put just like a plant out I could put I could put a dorm to this day.
Rym: I think I think you want to plant there.
Rym: just because you read Stefan wolf and he talks about that plan in the like student of the apartment.
Scott: Because you know, it'd be less echoey.
Scott: But no, I was looking at doormats and I can't just get any doormat.
Scott: I have to get a nerdy doormat.
Scott: There's one from think geek that says there's no place like one to seven dot over that over that one.
Rym: I've seen that that's a good one.
Scott: It's 40 bucks.
Rym: It's not worth 40 bucks.
Scott: No, I might just end up getting a normal cheap one.
Rym: That's totally lame Because it's weird how the culture of Like the culture and style of couch is like in any like nice city and apartments are like anywhere trendy.
Rym: Yeah, most people have like the modern or the ultra modern couches like they have the low squared off kind of couches.
Rym: but you go to like any house like an actual house outside of a city city and People have the same like l-shaped kind of couch, but it's like the curvy shape with the really puffy Sometimes the floral print because they have more room to put it in.
Scott: if you have a big-ass living room You can get like a big-ass sectional thing, you know No problem and fit it and it will work well in your giant room.
Rym: Well, we had one when I was a kid and no one ever sat at the corner of it.
Rym: It was just wasted space and all the space.
Scott: When we go over to their house the whole couch fills up with people.
Rym: when I was a kid the couch in the in the Living room as opposed to the family room Had like a queen size bed that came out of it or the part where the queen size bed came out of could seat like three Or four people.
Rym: then at the corner bit that no one ever sat on except maybe the dogs occasionally.
Rym: And then it had two more seats with a little island between them and the island had cup holders and a place for a phone And stuff and both of those seats reclined.
Scott: Yep, I've seen those that's exactly.
Scott: Yeah My relatives have something similar to that and when basically the family when we go over there It fills up completely with people sitting on it and every time someone gets up someone else goes up spot and jumps onto it.
Scott: Yeah so That's how that goes.
Rym: Yep It'll be weird to not have big couches like that all over the place because I can't even if I get an apartment in the City unless I make like.
Rym: my raise is crazy and I make like three or four hundred thousand dollars a year I can't afford a place big enough to have like 20 people hanging out in it.
Rym: I mean look at now and like people come over to hang out in Beacon We've got like, you know the couch in the loveseat and they're both full of people.
Rym: people are sitting in the chair People are sitting on like every surface and every like item and people are also sitting on the floor and still some people are standing.
Scott: People are going to the kitchen people are in other rooms people are on the stairs people are in the bathroom and the toilet.
Rym: Yep, New Year's even worse God.
Scott: Yeah, that's what I'm.
Scott: that's what I'm talking about.
Rym: New Year's I'm talking about just like even a game at this point when we play burning wheel.
Scott: Yeah, the other thing about cow, right?
Scott: Is that a sectional couch, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, whatever.
Scott: But if you you know if you got a lot of space But the modern couch is not only are they square and modern looking But if you have a small amount of space you need to use it efficiently and it's a lot easier to just imagine in your Brain, you know ways to use space efficiently when things are square if things are rounded or puffy.
Scott: It's like it's.
Scott: Well, I realize something on a less efficient use of space.
Scott: It's hard to calculate the more efficient use of space.
Scott: It's like it was hard to calculate the way to curve the stealth bomber But it wasn't hard to calculate the f-117 that was more flat and angular.
Rym: Honto honto rock and roll Bamba.
Rym: But I had this crazy revelation, right so With your ultra modern couch.
Rym: you did what all the trendy people do which is smart Which I wish we'd thought of it.
Rym: fucking RIT is put the couch in the middle of the room Because that's something is like, you know, I was basically right.
Scott: every time I've ever put arranged furniture Basically my plan has always been put all the furniture against the wall bookcase against the wall desk against the wall couch against the wall TV against the wall, right.
Scott: and the only thing I wouldn't put against the wall would be like coffee table.
Scott: You know cuz that or sometimes I'd think okay the recliner can sort of be a little bit inwards, you know Yeah, but everything would always be against the wall.
Scott: So my limitation on furniture would always be I guess kitchen table wouldn't be against the wall.
Rym: Kitchen doesn't count but every house I lived in with the same way like all the houses as a kid with one exception.
Rym: But I'll get to that because that's part of the revelation.
Rym: Like they were all like that everything went around the walls.
Rym: We moved to the colony.
Rym: What's the first thing we did?
Rym: we put all the furniture against the walls and then a year later or two years later?
Rym: We shifted it all like a hundred and eighty degrees along the walls, right?
Scott: So I was looking in the IKEA catalog and I see it's like everything in the IKEA catalog looks amazing Like I want to just if I had a zillion dollars.
Scott: Like even though IKEA stuff is not the most expensive best quality furniture in the universe.
Scott: It's functional It works and the price is good, you know, and it actually looks really great in the catalog.
Scott: I would even if I was mega rich, right?
Scott: I would just like have IKEA people come in.
Scott: I'd be like fill this house with furniture make it look like the catalog.
Scott: All right, and I looked in the catalog and every time I saw a couch it was never against the wall.
Scott: It was always in the middle of the room sort of a faraway and the behind it there'd be bookcases.
Scott: and I was like, oh So here's my revelation.
Rym: here's why we never thought of that.
Scott: I thought back because we didn't look at the IKEA catalog for a half hour thinking how do I do that?
Rym: Just that I went back to the house.
Rym: I lived in 4185 Harvard Street in like Detroit
Scott: Harvard Street
Rym: Harvard Street and in that house, we had a pretty big living room and We had a couch against the wall One wall and basically had like a foyer with like this cool French glass door like to get into the house You walk in and it's like a kind of a like a rectangular room kind of long.
Rym: So there was a couch against one wall a big couch and the loveseat was Perpendicular to the couch facing away from the front door and against one of the walls on one edge.
Rym: But otherwise in the middle of the rooms, there was like 10 feet of space behind it Toward the front of the house.
Rym: And so we made it basically made like this L-shaped area that was the living room and behind the couch was like more space.
Rym: It was a lot like what you did in your apartment if you had multiple couches basically and a bigger space.
Rym: Yeah, but the space behind the couch Was really never used for anything.
Rym: you want to know why non Ultramodern or modern couches are really really tall and when they're tall like that it disrupts the flow of the room and it feels like more of this boundary and People end up like they don't walk behind it.
Scott: They don't see stuff like how much room there is on the side of the couches.
Rym: if there's more room like enough room It's basically like a separate room.
Rym: But if you have an ultramodern house, it feels like the same room if the couch is low like that.
Rym: I think that's why we never thought of it.
Rym: had we had a low couch We would have done it without even thinking we would have been like duh.
Rym: That's where you put it.
Scott: Yeah Anyway, can we pause the show for a second?
Scott: Cuz I have to poop real bad.
Rym: Okay Have a good poop It was alright.
Rym: Okay, then.
Rym: So where were we talking about couches couches?
Scott: I think we should talk about the fucker.
Rym: just you know, so We needed a couch.
Scott: basically we were gonna take that crappy ass love seat with Rochester to beacon and we were gonna bring both of those couches with us the ones that had turned from white to not white.
Rym: So, you know aside from the whole story of the move which that could be a whole show in and of itself.
Rym: But we didn't tell it already.
Rym: That was that was a crazy time driving that truck.
Rym: I think I knocked over every corner trash can in my path in Rochester until I got it on the freeway.
Scott: Yeah, but anyway we were gonna bring these two couches but then a couch came out of nowhere.
Rym: Emily's parents were like, oh we have this old sleeper sofa.
Rym: That's really nice.
Rym: You can take it if you want.
Rym: So we were like fuck.
Rym: Yeah, so we basically threw that all that one couch away like we just left it outside immediately.
Scott: No, I thought we just left it there and Kevin.
Rym: Yeah, we had cats effectively throwing it away leaving it there that couch I think he said he threw it out.
Rym: Yeah He was like, I'm not keeping this But anyway, so we drove out to Emily's parents house.
Rym: We got this couch and it was a sleeper sofa kind of an old one really nice.
Rym: It was exactly what we needed.
Rym: it weighed Approximately nine thousand pounds.
Scott: Yeah, cuz I mean it was the.
Scott: it was the old-school style, you know It had a whole mattress in it that folded in under the cushion.
Scott: So you take the cushions off and they unfold this bed and the bed is like this, you know It's this big metal folding contraption going on and it way, you know It's a big bed frame basically inside an already heavy couch.
Scott: So it's like yeah that weighs a lot Yeah, and also it was long and unwieldy and difficult to lift.
Rym: cuz you know You got this frame isn't really held in there that well now We haven't thought our clever plan through so we we wouldn't have been able to deal with this thing on our own.
Rym: But luckily Pete took the day off work and actually helped us move in.
Rym: So I recall I was trying to lift that thing and get it into the house and Immediately Pete was like our.
Rym: let's move this fucker.
Rym: fuck Jesus fuck Christ Fuck me.
Rym: in it the word fuck was said more than any other words.
Rym: the next half hour after we decided to move that thing and That's the couch became the fucker.
Rym: The worst thing is we finally like after a lot of work and a lot of time We get it just into the couch or into the house and we did bangs against the wall.
Rym: We immediately like bang it into the wall because it's being like gash in the wall.
Rym: we had to fix that and clean it later.
Rym: Yeah, we're like, ah great.
Rym: We just move into this house already ruined it so we manhandled the thing after another like 10 minutes in the living room against the wall and Pete's like Not only am I not moving it beyond this point, but I am never again in my life moving a sleeper SOPA.
Rym: So help me God who does not exist in heaven Fuck you.
Rym: Fuck this couch.
Rym: I'm sleeping on it to assert my dominance.
Rym: That's right, and he did sleep on that couch and he asserted his dominance.
Scott: Yes, there's dominant over that couch.
Rym: Fuck I don't know how we're gonna get that couch out of here.
Rym: We're like free.
Rym: if you can get it out I have a solution Leave it set it on fire.
Rym: Then it'll be easier now because most of the weight is that steel frame.
Rym: the steel frames gonna weigh just as much if we burn It.
Scott: you could remove that part and just only take the rest of the couch Just the stuffing and then the upholstery.
Rym: Yeah, I Don't know this was that but this was a cop-out show and I think we're running out of steam.
Rym: Let's just end it.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm.
Scott: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.