Rym: It's Wednesday February 11th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We review the new anime movie.
Rym: well new ish anime movie sword of the stranger.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So after the New York comic-con we thought hey we came into the city We want to do something other than just the con.
Rym: otherwise you know why'd we take the train into the city?
Rym: so?
Rym: We figured we'd go and see Coraline.
Scott: and well first we figured we go to the sushi conveyor belt.
Scott: well Gorge ourselves The expensive place.
Rym: before that even we decided hey Let's get up early go into the city go downtown and get some dim sum.
Rym: and I think we all woke up independently and said yeah Going back to sleep.
Scott: I could have done the dim sum, but no one else was gonna.
Scott: You can't really dim sum on your own that doesn't.
Scott: it doesn't work.
Scott: - yeah, it doesn't like dim sum for one.
Scott: They're like huh usually it's like.
Scott: you know dim sum for eight.
Scott: That's more the correct number plus dim sum for one.
Rym: You're just gonna find me dead with like nine empty egg custard plates.
Scott: I know right It's like that's.
Scott: the other thing is that you want to get a variety when you dim sum You don't want to get a whole bunch of one thing, but the smallest servings are like four dumplings.
Scott: So it's like if you take the dumplings you got to eat four of them.
Scott: But if you got four people you can eat one dumpling of each guy And you're all good.
Rym: so we ate the.
Rym: we had a ton of kaiten sushi like probably more than we should have.
Rym: I had an Unnecessarily large beer like it was.
Rym: it was larger than was prudent shall we say.
Scott: it was a salaryman's beer.
Scott: It was.
Rym: it was the kind of thing where you got to drink it slam it down on the table and go.
Rym: But alright we we did that and we wanted to do something else and call it a night.
Rym: so alright Let's head down to the AMC.
Rym: Let's see Carlisle in 3d.
Rym: I'm excited.
Scott: normally I don't want to go to the movie theater so much unless it's something I'm not gonna see.
Scott: otherwise yeah Such as the topic of the show or a 3d movie, which I can never see at home cuz it's 3d.
Rym: It was crazy because we also just went to see the movie.
Rym: We're talking about tonight I know right.
Scott: so it's like I hadn't been to a movie theater.
Scott: I get that wasn't you know?
Scott: like The one that shows the one at what's the school the sunshine?
Rym: no the one where we went to see Anyway indie art films at indie art theaters they did.
Rym: or See at the art theaters.
Scott: the point is movie skycrawlers and the other one anyway.
Rym: Yeah, the point is we also.
Rym: it was kind of a decadent weekend.
Rym: We took cabs everywhere.
Rym: cuz when there's three people it's really not that much more.
Scott: We're going crosstown and going to places.
Scott: with that You know you could only get to buy cab feet and bus plus cab like eight bucks.
Rym: Bus fare for three people six bucks well free because I have infinite bus fine four bucks.
Rym: cuz I don't.
Rym: okay I don't take buses all right But all right, so we take a cab over to the AMC and we go in and five o'clock showing sold out But there's a 710. so all right.
Rym: Let's go.
Rym: Oh wait a minute.
Rym: It's not Saturday.
Rym: It's Sunday.
Rym: That means I have to be up at work at like 430. so now I can't do it.
Rym: I'd already stayed up late every other night that week.
Rym: it was And think about this because I went to the New York comic-con Saturday and Sunday, and I stayed out late Friday.
Rym: I basically went into the city every day with no break for last week the weekend and now this week Wasn't?
Rym: I wasn't doing well, so I bailed.
Rym: I totally.
Rym: just I bailed.
Rym: I walked out.
Rym: I was gonna take the train home and go to bed.
Rym: so Scott and Emily all right.
Rym: They're gonna stick around.
Rym: They're gonna see the 710 showing.
Rym: they're debating the logistics of this.
Rym: they're standing at the kiosk and Apparently it's sold out while they were buying the tickets.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I put it's a touchscreen to buy tickets You know.
Scott: so there's no actual ticket selling people.
Scott: so I push the buttons, and I'm like tickets 7 o'clock to Purchase slide card, and it's like sold out.
Scott: Sorry.
Scott: I'm like what I go back to the screen And it's at 7 o'clock sold out, and I'm like huh it must have sold out while I was pushing the buttons.
Rym: So fail.
Rym: we all walk back to Grand Central together in time to see that we have had the worst possible timing for a train that we could have possibly had.
Scott: Yeah, we pretty much showed up at the train station, and it's like the train going to Beacon left Just now.
Scott: so we got to sit there for like an hour until we can get on the next train.
Rym: Yeah, I like went up to my office across the street and surf the internet for a while and got a drink And it was it was a good time.
Rym: Yeah We're not really gonna cover the New York Comic Con so much yet because I got to put together all the interviews I got And suffice to say it was it was fun It was what the New York Comic Con is.
Rym: their gaming content was not the kind of gaming content you get from a gaming con.
Scott: It was a whole bunch of booths a lot of which were selling comics some you know selling old comics some selling news I'm selling cheap some selling expensive some selling junk, but they're gaming content.
Rym: They really hyped it up, but it was basically the showroom portion of packs But there was no play games portion to go along with it Mmm, so it was like you could go play the new Ghostbusters game or fear - and all these things.
Rym: I did a bunch of that, but there was no like Luke cranes running a burning wheel game.
Rym: check it out.
Scott: Well upstairs in the upstairs part was like oh, yeah, I went up there.
Scott: There's like a wad.
Scott: see fest going up on up.
Rym: You know what was going on up there.
Rym: you want to do a dungeon delve.
Rym: they had that.
Rym: yeah had that covered if you wanted To play a while raid very slowly with pen and paper Yep, but they had that covered.
Scott: They did not have You know like big open area with a bunch of tables and a bunch of board games.
Rym: I got to say more.
Scott: of course It's a comic con so I mean wad see is pretty much the extent of the gaming you can expect.
Rym: it amazes me That Connecticut is Fast becoming the best gaming con I attend and it is a lot of gaming con.
Scott: well We got to go to those decks slash dreamation cons in North Jersey.
Scott: see what they're like.
Rym: yeah.
Rym: But I'm both excited and leery of things like that because I used to go to a lot of because their website looks like it's A very larper ish our way kind of situation.
Scott: You know what I'm saying well.
Rym: part of it Too is that those are very old-school.
Rym: gaming convention is indeed yes I used to go to a lot of gaming cons before I went to anime cons or even knew they existed.
Rym: you're living in Michigan.
Rym: I'd go to like Michigan when I was in middle school and play D&D with a bunch of 40 year old guys.
Rym: and you know hang out there.
Rym: my Parents barely understood what it was I was doing.
Rym: they dropped me off at some convention center and pick me up a day later and have no idea where I was and what I was up to.
Rym: but those cons There's a certain time in your life when they're fun And I don't know if I can deal with old-school gaming cons anymore.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I get to.
Scott: I haven't gone to.
Scott: you know quite as many and I yeah I got to go there at least once.
Scott: I mean Luke crane goes, so it's got to be something going on there.
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: but speaking of which we're gonna have a lot of good stuff from the New York comic-con because I got a quite in-depth interview with Luke crane about the mouse guard RPG, and then I got a Very enlightening interview with David Peterson about the mouse guard RPG And I also learned the Luke crane slayed a dragon with 36 dice.
Rym: It was quite.
Scott: this is burning.
Scott: We're not supposed to have drag.
Rym: No, you're supposed to have dragons, and you're only supposed to defeat them with 36 dice.
Rym: all right But yeah, we'll cover more of that later.
Rym: It's uh it's Wednesday night not Tuesday.
Rym: So anime manga comics And I don't really want to talk about the comic-con because all my news from the comic-con is gaming stuff.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: There's there's some comic news.
Scott: the comic-con that you know I guess None of it really care about.
Rym: it's more than I don't have all my stuff together And I don't have my interviews together, and you know I'm gonna let you all in on a secret.
Rym: I didn't put it all together, and I don't want to edit it tonight.
Rym: That's the only reason we're pushing.
Scott: this is another secret right a comic-con really You know doesn't have a lot of stuff going on for us.
Scott: I mean if you're someone who's like you know really follows like you know the DC Universe or something There's gonna be all kinds of news like ah bat.
Scott: This is what's gonna happen to Batman.
Scott: This is gonna happen to Superman.
Scott: Oh my gosh.
Scott: Oh my gosh, but if you're not into that The other kind of news you'll get there is like oh my god Maybe a little bit of what TV shows are coming or maybe like what toys are coming out.
Scott: Oh, no, you know all this sort of direct that we also Emotionally get about.
Rym: it is if you want to see people who do the geeky stuff that you like exactly.
Scott: But I'm saying that there's no news.
Scott: there's stuff to do, but there's no news Commentary you know.
Rym: just review the Kana.
Rym: It's not worth an entire show, but it's worth a front bit at least.
Scott: Yeah, I guess I got enough to say about a front bit.
Rym: I just I didn't put all my stuff together.
Rym: I have all these interviews on the Marantz that I didn't even listen to yet hmm.
Rym: Oh and also gave in Taika over there and We talked to them.
Scott: we learned about how they handle the booths.
Rym: they handle their booth pretty much the same way We handle our booth except that they have people who are paid to deal with stuff.
Scott: The other problem with them handling their booth the way we handle our booth is that it's not easy to talk to them.
Rym: Yeah, I mean if you come up and talk to us at a con especially if we have a table half the time We'll be like yeah, that's great.
Rym: Yeah, we got to go and then we disappear.
Scott: yeah And so you know us actually legitimately trying to talk to them for reals Not gonna work out too.
Scott: Well when they're at the booth because they're just like uh-huh.
Rym: yep One great secret one little tidbit that I did discover.
Rym: it's more gaming stuff, but I think they were coached by Robert coup.
Rym: I think they were too, but I got to get this out there.
Rym: at the penny arcade expo We we brought up burning wheel at the Q&A thing and I remember that Taiko I'll use the there soon is I think yeah, they're stage names.
Scott: He said specifically burning wheel is the shit.
Scott: that is what he said.
Rym: said those words exactly.
Rym: there are videos of it mm-hmm.
Rym: So on Saturday, I went up to the table.
Rym: I was like you guys are awesome blah blah blah, so you said burning wheels awesome blah blah blah and The.
Rym: he looked like a deer in headlights.
Rym: He was like oh shit.
Rym: Oh shit, and he had no idea what I was talking about.
Rym: no clue But don't worry we've got machinations along that front And I've got a ton of interviews and there will be New York comic-con coverage in The future.
Rym: if you really want to know what happened at the con, and you can't wait another two weeks Search for New York comic-con and they have a link to like all the coverage in the world and all the YouTube videos in The world.
Scott: yeah, really.
Scott: It's mostly people buying stuff people talking to artists.
Scott: You know That kind of thing.
Scott: this you know it's a comic-con.
Scott: It's a bunch of booths.
Scott: It's not like.
Scott: you know events.
Rym: Well, no There's a ton of events But only if the problem with comic cons really is that the events are usually there.
Rym: They'd be really fun to go to like.
Rym: I'd love to go to a lot of these panels But you either have to be press so you can just skip the line or wait for like two hours Even then or pay five bucks.
Scott: a lot of the panels.
Scott: You know they're not fan panels They're industry panels, and they're mostly just.
Scott: you know they're not so exciting.
Scott: unless you're really into whatever.
Scott: It is that you know.
Scott: these people running the panel do like.
Scott: if you're.
Rym: you know I am because the IGN theater had a bunch of Astro Boy stuff, and they had oh, yeah, that was the theater.
Scott: That's just mostly showings.
Scott: It's basically a video room.
Rym: They also had some early releases of trailers and things and a lot of people saw Astro Boy stuff.
Rym: that made them Hopeful.
Scott: as to the movie yeah, but I mean anything.
Scott: you all trailers.
Scott: It's very easy to make a hopeful trailer.
Scott: It's very hard.
Rym: I Point out to you the Dragon Ball live-action trailer.
Rym: Yeah, someone thinks that's good.
Scott: someone thinks that they Dragon Ball fans think it's good.
Rym: No they don't.
Scott: Those aren't real Dragon Ball fans.
Rym: Anyway, do you got any news here?
Scott: well actually there was a news a comic news at the comic-con?
Scott: That while is not so exciting I think.
Scott: but there is something that I'm sort of going huh, maybe about.
Rym: right man died again.
Rym: Well, no Batman died.
Scott: no Batman's gonna die.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: actually I don't know Batman actually might be dead.
Scott: I forget what the deal is.
Scott: I'm not I don't pay that much attention.
Scott: But there was like some comics called like Batman Rises and Batman Rises Rest in peace.
Scott: and I think there's some comics called like battle for the cowl or something.
Scott: so I think there is like.
Scott: But I think Batman died and everyone else is like fighting over who is bad or something like that.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: clearly that's only happening in an alternate universe that eventually will collapse into the real.
Scott: yeah I have.
Scott: no I have no clue.
Scott: That's like that's like hints I get from like pictures.
Scott: you know what I'm gonna say that I might have seen for like a second.
Rym: I have my own personal can't like Rym cannon Batman.
Rym: It's pretty simple.
Rym: it is Beat ass followed by the Dark Knight Returns, and there's no other Batman.
Scott: alright, so spider-man right Spider-man spider-man right.
Scott: so if you don't read Marvel Comics?
Scott: You probably don't know this.
Scott: if you do read Marvel Comics you almost definitely know this right.
Scott: there are regular old Marvel Comics like you know Amazing spider-man or the Avengers or x-men right and then they have these ultimates And it's like ultimate spider-man ultimate x-men.
Scott: You know ultimate whatever right and the ultimate ones are sort of separate right like a few years ago.
Scott: They started with like ultimate spider-man number one.
Scott: it had nothing to do with anything else that you know.
Scott: I mean they were sort of retelling the same stories, but it wasn't the same.
Scott: you know it was different, and it was sort of like a clean slate and That way it would be really easy for someone to sort of you know catch up on the whole thing without reading comics going back To the 60s.
Scott: you know you can just read ultimate spider-man, and it's available in trades And it's all modern and you know relatively recent so you can just get all of it.
Scott: So it was no problem.
Scott: Just read all the issues of ultimate spider-man.
Scott: so what they're doing apparently is You know they're going to stop all the ultimate books.
Scott: They're like you know gonna be like up.
Scott: That's it, and they're gonna reset them to number one again.
Rym: Now at first though are they gonna retcon this BS together into something or what?
Scott: well You know the ultimate stuff all on its own sort of goes together.
Scott: It's like a self-contained cohesive unit right and now they're resetting the cohesive unit.
Scott: So I was like huh, you know Maybe is it just?
Scott: they're just gonna keep doing that.
Scott: that way you can sort of get on to these like short things And then you know they can.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: but apparently the deal is it's actually when even though It's resetting to number one.
Scott: It's still gonna be the same ultimate universe Just fast forward in like two years.
Scott: You know two fictional years in the future from whatever year It is in the ultimate universe, huh?
Scott: So if you've never read them before you'll be able to just start reading at the new number one.
Scott: I have a. but if you have read the old ultimate you know and now you're reading the new ultimate after it resets You'll sort of see some stuff that other people don't see.
Rym: I have a hunch.
Rym: My guess is that within ten issues there is going to be very important stuff from previous ones That's gonna come back in and what makes sense to new readers at all.
Scott: Yeah, I think it's sort of like hey You're a new reader.
Scott: come and read the ultimate universe.
Scott: you reset it for you But they didn't really.
Scott: but then you're gonna.
Scott: you know They're basically you're gonna have to.
Scott: then they'll hook you in and they'll hook you in to going back Right and buying all the trades of the original ultimate universe.
Rym: We're definitely gonna start seeing.
Rym: see Issue 289 Marvel X.
Scott: No, actually there's actually a lot of discussion about those.
Rym: see, you know issue number things Right, we know when I first was reading comics that were they were all over the place until I saw one of those Which I didn't.
Rym: I didn't actually see one right away.
Rym: I thought that was a joke.
Rym: I didn't think that actually happened.
Scott: No, no, see the thing is right that they stopped doing that around the late 90s early, you know They just don't have those anymore, right?
Scott: so the problem with that is They didn't change the way they wrote the comics.
Scott: So basically you would read something Someone would make a reference to something that happened in some other issue and there's no little note.
Scott: They're saying, you know see issue 36 for more info.
Scott: Stan the man, you know that didn't that wasn't there.
Scott: So now you just have no fucking clue and you don't even know where to look.
Scott: so it's like should they keep those in?
Scott: It to be stupid and corny?
Scott: should they take them out?
Rym: You know what the correct answer is Have stories together such that you don't just like the green arrow shouldn't just randomly show up out of nowhere and he hasn't been in the story yet.
Rym: and then the only way that makes sense is if you know that he was involved in Some other comic and that's why he's there.
Rym: Yeah, you know proper storytelling.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: Yeah, I feel don't assume, you know If someone's reading a book you have to assume that they have not read any other book ever and you have to do that for Every single book.
Scott: now, that doesn't mean you know, like with the Stan Lee book where every single issue They take three pages to describe, you know, the origin story and how they got their powers and what powers they have.
Scott: You know every single issue be that's a little bit unnecessary Right, but you know, it's still very very possible You know to tell us and if you know, you can't you know do that in a single issue.
Scott: They don't have issues, you know have trades.
Scott: only You know if Don't print.
Scott: It's every self-contained unit you publish needs to stand alone.
Scott: So if an issue is too small to stand alone, you shouldn't have the issue.
Scott: It just shouldn't exist.
Rym: But anyway, uh one thing if they actually just reset if they would ever just say look We are making a new comic called spider-man.
Rym: It's starting with issue one.
Rym: It is in no way in any way connected to any previous work that we have ever published.
Scott: That's what I did with the first ultimate spider-man.
Rym: But now.
Scott: but now it's connected to all the other ultimate books.
Rym: Yeah, so great.
Scott: And now the new ultimate spider-man which is gonna be number one again will be somewhat connected to the old alt.
Scott: So it's sort of like, you know They did do exactly what you just said when they came out with the ultimate universe years ago.
Rym: Spider-man, I can't I don't.
Rym: I don't want to read x-factor x-force and x-caliber to find out what you don't.
Scott: you only have to read Ultimate, you know.
Scott: and the thing is you really don't have to read all the ultimate books You just have to read some of the other ultimate books.
Rym: That's already.
Rym: I'm not happy with that.
Scott: Yeah It's like, you know They made a new universe that was smaller and self-contained and you can easily get all of it.
Rym: But I read x-men and then during the executioner song I read x-factor because it told me to and then I read x-force and then I I found out about x-caliber.
Rym: then I quit reading Comics.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know when someone reads Naruto all they ask is that you read Naruto, right?
Rym: And if you need to tell a story about some other characters Imagine if Naruto like suddenly Goku shows up and like saves the day and then says something cryptic to our know And then you're gonna go right now.
Scott: It's like if you need to say, you know say concentrate on the villains of Naruto for like a few chapters, right?
Scott: You don't put out another separate manga called, you know, Naruto villains, you know number one and say yeah This takes place in between Naruto chapters 36 and whatever.
Scott: You just make the next chapter of Naruto be that You know instead of if you need x-men to cross over with spider-man, right?
Scott: Don't take you know, don't tell people who read spider-man to go read a certain x-men issue.
Scott: Just take that issue and make it the next issue of spider-man.
Scott: You know they do.
Rym: you know how they could still make money if they did that if they released him in trades instead of issues?
Rym: Oh, yeah, so it was big stories then like they're the spider-man trade one, two, three, four, five six.
Rym: Spider-man trade seven is Also the crossover with blah.
Rym: So if you read blah seven, it's also the crossover with spider-man.
Scott: So it was saying so.
Scott: basically it would be like this is spider-man volume seven.
Scott: This is also x-men volume three.
Rym: Yes, and if you want to make money you publish them with different covers in separate lines.
Scott: So the nerds buy both but they have the exact almost the exact same thing in the hook.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Yeah, it's it's foolproof.
Scott: Yeah, that's you know, that is actually somewhat better than you know what they do all right.
Rym: anyway I don't we don't.
Rym: I don't really want to belabor this point because yeah I think you all know how we feel about these issues.
Scott: Yeah, I think I will buy the new Number one just the one issue because I get it at a huge discount.
Scott: Just to you know, check the deal to know what's going on.
Scott: I'm Brian that I'm gonna buy number two But I got you know, it's gonna cost me like a dollar.
Scott: So I'll check it.
Rym: All right I got a bunch of quickies here because I feel like they're all worth mentioning But they're not.
Rym: I don't have a lot to say about them penguin.
Rym: No, Monda is getting a movie.
Scott: I like penguin.
Rym: Oh man, I do too.
Rym: So I'm kind of excited about this.
Rym: I'll I expect it to be fansubbed and I hope to see it.
Rym: Spice and wolf which was a show that had one great episode and then never went anywhere and Stopped watching it and it turns out it's crap.
Rym: Yeah has a sequel.
Scott: Yeah, you know there's a lot more.
Scott: it feels like there's a lot more anime sequels lately and a lot less new shows.
Scott: You know, I keep seeing like such and such and such, you know, Monogatari such and such and such guy Dan You know, it's like alright, really?
Rym: Those are just words though.
Scott: I mean the thing is at least they.
Rym: that's like saying Final Fantasy and Phantasy Star online.
Rym: That is one thing.
Scott: one thing I can say though about a lot of these anime though is the sequels is that they actually cover Them up with like clever names for the sequels rather than just calling them two, you know, or three or you know They actually change the name of it or they put a colon like it'll be such and such colon something instead of just such and such.
Rym: - but seriously the first episode of Spice and Wolf.
Rym: I actually despite the fact that I expected it to be some crap moe a relationship garbage show.
Rym: It was really like good and well animated and cool and the style was good.
Rym: The atmosphere was great.
Rym: I thought it was a great episode.
Rym: I expected a lot from that show surprisingly and then I learned to never Reset my hopes higher ever From my initial expectations of anything.
Scott: I just expectations low.
Rym: They were so low and it the first episode was enough to let me reconsider.
Rym: and I was so wrong.
Rym: that show went Nowhere.
Rym: and now it's getting a sequel.
Rym: Why?
Scott: Well, everything's getting a sequel.
Scott: I think it's just because they don't.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: they risk averse.
Scott: You know, usually when people are risk averse they go with the sequels instead of with the new properties that are you know much riskier.
Rym: And I got one more bit here Akira Toriyama.
Scott: Okay, I think you're talking about Akira.
Rym: No saw the trailer Kineta For the Dragon Ball live-action movie.
Scott: that oh DC.
Scott: Well, so he did.
Scott: does he does nothing to do with the live-action?
Scott: He didn't know it exists or what?
Rym: Well, he saw the trailer and and I'll give you the quote but one if you have not seen this trailer yet It is the feeling that you will get is identical to the joke in animators Nina about a live-action Pokemon.
Rym: Yeah like Good God.
Rym: But he had this to say.
Rym: I'm quoting the translated statement as the original creator.
Rym: I had a feeling of huh?
Scott: I Don't even like Dragon Ball, but if the guy who made Dragon Ball it says, huh?
Rym: Actually the quote goes on.
Rym: that was out of context.
Rym: basically says but you know These are all ultra high caliber people and maybe it might be a way for the fans to appreciate it as a new Dragon Ball of a different dimension.
Rym: Perhaps this might become the great masterpiece of power Uh-huh.
Rym: It's hard to tell.
Scott: I think if you want to appreciate some Akira Toriyama, I think you should Look for some doctor slob.
Scott: Oh, yeah, or you should.
Scott: you know, you know place in Chrono Trigger.
Rym: I don't admit the original Dragon Ball is pretty funny.
Scott: The regular old Dragon Ball not Dragon Ball Z not Dragon Ball GT.
Rym: Dragon Ball is pretty fun
Scott: regular old Dragon Ball if you understand it and as a comedy and you get the jokes especially if you can, you know read the manga first of all and Get you know, there's a lot of Japanese jokes in there that are harder to get.
Scott: if you can do that That's pretty worthwhile.
Scott: but Dragon Ball Z anime.
Scott: It's not happening.
Scott: Nah, so I got.
Scott: if you're gonna do if you're gonna watch a fighting thing At least watch just like fist in the North Star is like this.
Scott: at least heads explode.
Rym: So I at least I got.
Rym: Bring up one more thing.
Rym: This is just too crazy.
Rym: So this is a little bit old but not many people have seen it.
Rym: unless you dig through anime news network konami claims that upper deck is Counterfeiting Yugioh cars.
Scott: Wait a minute.
Scott: usually Counterfeit, I mean there have been counterfeit cards since you know way even before magic.
Scott: right.
Rym: konami is suing Upper deck, I mean who distributes yugioh?
Scott: counterfeit cards were always like, you know shady dude in the mall.
Scott: They were never upper deck legitimate card maker.
Rym: No as I I don't understand what's going on because that gets really complicated.
Rym: like Upper deck sued them back and there's this other company involved now and everything's going crazy.
Rym: but as far as I can tell my my guess and I there is no Defamation libel or slander here at all because this is a random guess from an uninformed, dude Saying that right now.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: I want to get sued.
Rym: My best guess is that upper deck might have been just printing Counterfeits or allowing counterfeits to be printed and or distributed through them in order to get around some internal licensing or quantity deal with konami and there was probably some.
Rym: basically there was probably a very tenuous business relationship between all these companies and It was.
Rym: the business relationship was probably basically just a beehive.
Rym: Yeah I don't know.
Rym: and someone came over and knocked that beehive over Coming out.
Scott: see I don't I'm out of collectible cards games, you know, so I really don't pay attention so much and quote.
Scott: So I don't even know like who you know who makes which who publishes which games.
Scott: all I know is that Watsy makes magic.
Rym: That's seriously no hearing.
Rym: That's the name.
Rym: upper deck really surprised me.
Rym: I did not expect upper deck to be involved in something like this.
Scott: Yeah, it's they're a legitimate game maker.
Scott: Why would they be counterfeiting cards, you know?
Scott: So it's.
Scott: it's.
Scott: that's pretty strange.
Rym: I don't know what the you know, the real Identified upper deck as the source of 22 counterfeit rare cards being repackaged and sold by vintage And I don't know.
Rym: of course they go on to say this threatens to undermine the integrity of the game Including because the game has integrity.
Rym: Well, see, I don't think they are aware of the fact that the champion at yugioh in Rochester New York was none other than a 20 ounce already opened bottle of vanilla coke.
Rym: That cat that bottle of vanilla coke won one of the biggest yugioh tournaments in Rochester.
Scott: Yeah, they sure did and you might think over him.
Rym: No, I'm I'm not kidding to a degree that you would be surprised about.
Scott: so Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: I just this actually thinking about this story got me, you know thinking again, right?
Scott: What if there was a collectible card game, right Just like, you know magic or whatever, right?
Scott: But there were actually anyone who wanted to.
Scott: it was an open gaming system and anyone who wanted to could print cards and any card That was actually printed properly and you know couldn't be wasn't marked on the back that it's not a in any way.
Rym: But that's got that simple.
Rym: That's not a collectible card game.
Rym: It's a customizable card game.
Rym: Well, I mean, they're all CCG's customizable collectible card, but customizable and collectible are possibly exclusive to one another.
Scott: Mmm, I guess it would make it, you know, there wouldn't be any a lot of collecting going on.
Rym: You wouldn't have to worry there would be.
Rym: no, you know The old magic the gathering problem of I have more money than all my friends.
Rym: I bought the best deck.
Rym: I always win.
Scott: Yeah, but then again, you know, the thing is you would have to have the cards, you know You couldn't just print the cards yourself unless you had a really really good printer because they would stand out from the other cards.
Scott: Well, it had to be printed.
Scott: You know the answer is to make it a game that can be played on either laptops or yes, but I was thinking right Let's say there were like three or four companies that were all publishing like Yu-Gi-Oh cards, right?
Scott: Yeah It would be this crazy race of like.
Scott: every company would try to make more and more ludicrous cards Like they would all just make I win cards.
Scott: That way you would buy from their their expansions instead of the other people's expansions.
Scott: it would get really silly.
Rym: Oh, okay There's a little more information here.
Rym: Now.
Rym: All right, the lawsuit originally actually was filed against ten John Doe's uh-huh, and Recently, they amended it.
Rym: dough number one and two are now upper decks to operations in California and Nevada Mm-hmm.
Rym: There are still eight more John Doe's.
Rym: This is a wide and and frightening ring of counterfeit.
Rym: and one last thing.
Rym: they've got a picture here.
Rym: I don't know if this is legit, but on animators Network There's a picture of a authentic card and a counterfeit card.
Rym: The counterfeit card looks like I printed it out out of an inkjet.
Scott: Yeah, so if upper deck was doing it Why wouldn't the counterfeit cards be basically exactly identical to real cards?
Rym: Well, here's a posit if you will.
Scott: in fact, they wouldn't be counterfeit.
Scott: They would just be Extra printings or hit him at cars.
Rym: enterprising individual who worked at one of these upper decks was taking the files used to make these and Using them on a shitty printer printing extras and then selling them.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, yeah, that's the thing.
Scott: It's like his.
Scott: Konami.
Scott: tell upper deck exactly how many of each cards are allowed that they do.
Scott: it's sort of crazy I'll bet they do.
Scott: I you know, it could be.
Scott: I'm feeling there's some sort of situation here of.
Scott: you know Konami, you know gave upper deck the license to print the Yu-Gi-Oh cards in the u.s.
Scott: Right, but now they're like Hey, we should print them ourselves and make more money.
Scott: Oh, we need to get our project to stop.
Rym: You know that sort of thing, but at the same time these counterfeit cards seem to actually exist.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean anyone could make counterfeit cards.
Rym: Yeah, but it's just I don't.
Rym: there's too many bees coming out of this hive and I can't figure out what's going on.
Rym: It's not?
Scott: I have no clue what the deal is because I don't even know who makes the stupid card.
Rym: and no no But anyway, it's not the bees it's things of the day.
Rym: so mm-hmm I got a lame one because I thought it was cool.
Rym: Toriyama since he came up actually drew a picture of a Yumi Hamasaki as Goku for an album that was coming out.
Scott: Oh, really?
Rym: It's kind of cool.
Rym: So here's a picture of it.
Rym: You can look at it.
Rym: It basically just looks like a Yumi Hamasaki in her current form Dressed up as Son Goku.
Rym: You know, I say her current form because she is basically a transformer.
Scott: Yeah, you know Jeff Lemire did an album cover for somebody really?
Scott: Yeah, huh?
Rym: It looks pretty.
Scott: it looks pretty cool.
Rym: I should do an album cover for someone.
Scott: Yeah, you need to get on that.
Scott: So, I don't know is it a week or two ago?
Scott: I forget right I took an episode was it a Tuesday episode To educate the punk kids about The day the music died?
Scott: right?
Scott: and I don't.
Scott: I don't think it was a Wednesday.
Scott: So I have to re-educate on Wednesday for people who did not listen to the other show, right?
Scott: basically, you know imagine if you know Elvis the Beatles and you know Led Zeppelin were in a plane crash and they died.
Scott: Well, you know how different would the world be today?
Scott: crazy different super crazy different.
Scott: Well Back in the day 50 years ago a Plane did crash with three musicians of that caliber on it and the world is crazy different from how it should be.
Rym: And the three musicians were Buddy Holly Richie Valens and the Big Bopper, you know If you don't understand why the world is different Bill and Ted's excellent adventure can really clear that up for you.
Scott: Oh, yeah, actually, yeah absolutely So To do a thing of the day to help educate the punk Wednesday kids to talk slowly because you're trying to think of what you're Actually gonna say.
Scott: no, I know exactly.
Scott: I'm gonna say I have here an anime music video To one of the Big Boppers.
Scott: Well, in fact the Big Boppers most popular song ever Oh and it is also one of the best music videos of anime Ever is a classic and it has never been a thing of the day.
Rym: It has never been a thing of the day.
Rym: I've thought about using it as a cop-out thing of the day.
Scott: Well, I'm using it as a non cop-out thing of the day Right now.
Rym: well played Yes.
Scott: Yes, indeed.
Scott: I Needed to come up with and you know, this is this really is.
Scott: it's one of the best music videos ever one of the greatest songs Not much else.
Rym: we can say.
Scott: yeah great anime You should check it all out.
Rym: So recently we were treated with a screening in a theater of an anime movie Which is a rare enough event to where we pretty much can't pass that up.
Scott: Well, I mean, you know whenever they happen we see them.
Scott: That's pretty much.
Scott: I think.
Scott: I've seen every anime that was in theaters for the past like five years.
Rym: Yeah I mean I remember I saw Innocence in theaters and then it's been just about almost everything since that.
Rym: I missed Tekkonkinkreet which I'm sad about but that was my.
Scott: oh, yeah, I didn't see that one.
Rym: Yeah, that was entirely my fault.
Scott: But I saw I saw innocence.
Scott: I saw Miyazaki movies going back to spirited away.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I just remembered RIT anime.
Rym: We rented out the local actual movie theater to show Spirited away.
Scott: Yeah, that's right.
Rym: Yeah good times, but we were able to see a brand new anime movie Sword of the stranger.
Scott: it's not that brand new isn't it actually from o7?
Rym: it is from o7 late o7 But it's as brand new as movies like that are for people like us.
Scott: and yeah, it's effectively brand new in the u.s.
Scott: I mean, I don't remember ever seeing fan subs of it, even though they may have existed.
Scott: I don't remember seeing you know bit Torrance or being.
Scott: I don't remember seeing it in theaters before and there's no DVD of it.
Rym: I honestly did not know this existed until they announced the American release me either.
Rym: But sort of the stranger is uh We're gonna review it.
Rym: Don't worry.
Rym: No spoilers here at all.
Rym: We're not gonna talk about it super long because there are few enough anime full-length motion pictures that are out there let alone that are good and that are new.
Rym: also that I Could not in good conscience spoil one because if you're an anime fan You should seek out pretty much every anime movie that comes out in America like without question.
Scott: Yep, even if it's well except Pokemon, you don't to watch the Pokemon.
Rym: Are you kidding?
Rym: Snorlax is more ripped than you.
Scott: That's that's like the first Pokemon movie.
Scott: You don't need to watch like, you know, the other ones I mean, they're on like Pokemon movie like 20, right?
Rym: You can't see 20.
Scott: You don't need to watch like all that hundred and one-piece movies either.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: Yeah true I'll give you that well played.
Rym: Yeah, but sword of the stranger Directed by now this.
Rym: usually we talk about the director, but I honestly didn't know anything about endo and I You didn't do a lot that I have a lot to say about.
Rym: so I'm afraid I don't have much to say.
Rym: I could do A bunch of research and pretend I had something to say.
Scott: no, but the key thing here is studio bones did this movie?
Rym: Yes, now you might if you don't know who bones is up cowboy bebop Eska flown.
Scott: Hey Um, what's the other one?
Scott: didn't they do FMA - maybe they did a Wolves rain.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So of course this movie looks amazing.
Rym: It's done amazingly.
Rym: It's got a lot of.
Rym: it's got a lot of talent behind it.
Rym: It's a big movie.
Rym: It looks like it was high-budget really well animated and relatively high-budget Compared to movies I have seen.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean this wasn't like a major like, you know It didn't have as high a budget as like the sky crawlers or anything, you know, which had plenty of you know Big-time monies, but it had a bigger budget.
Rym: didn't say I don't know a one-piece movie But sword of the stranger is pretty much.
Rym: I'm not gonna say it's a throwback and I'm not gonna say it's an homage necessarily, but it is definitely.
Rym: if you like an old like samurai in Japan kind of movie either live-action or anime This is like already gonna be one of your favorite movies.
Scott: It didn't feel to me like they were doing an homage or a throwback or anything nostalgic or anything like that.
Scott: It felt to me like they were just making a movie in a well-traveled genre instead of you know People trying to you know avoid Well-traveled genres or you know do something new or do a combining genres or a twist.
Scott: They just sort of said hey Let's make a samurai movie.
Scott: All right, sure and they did.
Rym: Yep, and I think the reason why I mean I feel like a lot of people will look at it and think at first impression This is homage or something like that.
Rym: but really I think a lot of the feelings I had like that were due to nostalgia for Anime like this that I just haven't seen in a long time.
Rym: It's it was a fun engaging Interesting.
Rym: It wasn't like a great movie.
Rym: This was no Citizen Kane here.
Rym: There was no cowboy bebop.
Scott: Yeah, this isn't like this isn't a movie that's gonna you know, knock you off your feet and go.
Scott: Oh, man That was like a movie for the age is gonna be remembered forever in greatness and greatness and it's not going to tell give you any particularly profound Feelings.
Rym: It doesn't.
Scott: Yeah, it's not exactly the most intellectual It's it's people cutting each other up.
Scott: But
Rym: it was something I guess maybe because the last anime movie the last two anime movies I saw Were the new Miyazaki film which is fantastic but it's it's deeper and there's more to it than this and sky crawlers, which is a very
Scott: heady,
Rym: yes, uh Oshi tacular movie.
Scott: Oh, she's a glad.
Scott: I think it's oh she tastic.
Rym: No because it's shero tastic.
Rym: It's oh she tacular Because oh she does not TASM all over you when you watch this film.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: Maybe it's just oh, she awesome.
Rym: I mean Shiro basically.
Scott: Oh sheet.
Rym: Oh But shero basically it's kind of like Wagner if you go to a Wagner opera Wagner basically rises from the dead comes out on stage and Ejaculates all over the audience for like seven hours.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Does he have that much in him?
Rym: Are you kidding?
Rym: Have you seen any of his opera?
Scott: Haven't seen his?
Rym: Shiro Manga are like that only with Shiro TASM.
Rym: Shiro TASM's all over you right, but oh she doesn't really get it all over you.
Rym: he kind of puts it there and You have to kind of go and get it from him.
Rym: Like if you go up to him and say oh she I see you made a movie I would like you to fill my mind with things that I barely Understand and make me feel kind of bad about myself by the end.
Rym: He will fulfill that All right, so but he won't.
Rym: you won't get it all over.
Scott: So sort of a stranger is the samurai movie.
Scott: It's in Japan, there's a kid and his dog and they meet a samurai And he's dangerous.
Rym: Two strangers come.
Scott: you know what it is.
Scott: Well, it's got the buddy movie aspect, right?
Scott: They don't get along but they stick together sort of like samurai Champloo, right?
Scott: It's like why are we together?
Scott: Okay, we stay together.
Scott: Why are we together?
Scott: I hate you.
Scott: No.
Scott: Oh shit.
Scott: I'm unprotected.
Scott: Yeah, we really should protect her right, you know that sort of situation.
Rym: In general the movie really like.
Scott: Yeah, like we hate each other We really like each other.
Rym: the story the characters like all the basics of this movie from the buddy part on are they feel at first really predictable and trite like you look and you're like.
Rym: It's obvious what's gonna happen and the movie follows up like a very expected format But at the same time it pulls an eska flown a in that Eska flown a was just a magical girl.
Rym: fantasy move like show like it.
Rym: that was it but it was so well executed that any feelings that the genre had been played out or any feelings that it was just rehashing or it was predictable were Completely destroyed by the fact that it was executed.
Rym: probably as well as that genre can be executed.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I feel like a lot of shows and books.
Scott: and then you know just genre Storytelling.
Scott: these days all across the board people are trying to you know Do things different and people sort of.
Scott: it feels like people have forgotten how to just you know Pick a genre and just tell that kind of story even though that kind of story has been told a million times.
Scott: Tell another one and just do it really well.
Scott: And I mean if you just tell you know I mean there's a reason people have been enjoying samurai stories for many years The reason people have enjoyed, you know adventure stories for many years or buddy stories.
Rym: There's a reason why they're good why your Jimbo was turned into fistful of dollars, which was turned into cause I know your Jimbo million other movies that are basically the exact same movie.
Scott: Yeah, I mean cuz it's a good kind of story that works.
Scott: so there is a lot to be said for just taking a story a kind of story that has been told a million times before and Telling a new story that fits right in line with the old stories.
Scott: But it's just well done.
Rym: but this movie Departs from that a little bit in that it tells the old classic story in the classic style and it's really well executed.
Rym: But there are I'd say like 15 moments not really like the plot kind of goes along the way you expect and I'm not gonna talk about the end because While the end is able to be seen coming in some ways.
Rym: It's not in other ways.
Rym: And again, I don't want to risk spoiling anything.
Rym: But the rest of the movie will it will periodically you expect something because you know what this genre is, you know how these movies go and then something just Completely different and crazy and sudden happens instead Like a character that you expect a certain thing to happen with just like fucking gets killed like that.
Scott: Yeah, there are actually a bunch of characters in the movie, right?
Scott: And I
Rym: don't know
Scott: it felt like, you know Sometimes you watch like a like a summary movie right for something Like a TV show and there's a summary movie that the summary movie will have Characters that were somewhat important in the TV show like side characters and they'll sort of be they'll sort of stand out in the summary Movie, but they won't get a lot of screen time.
Scott: So it's sort of like they're sort of like huh?
Scott: What's up with that?
Scott: and it feels kind of weird, right?
Scott: This movie had some of that where there would be a character who obviously was designed, you know They didn't have a name necessarily or maybe they did But they had a design as an important character would have you know, not just a background character, right and Maybe they would get a little bit of screen time a little bit of prominent screen presence for short moments Even though they weren't really involved in the plot very much or anything like that.
Scott: You know, they didn't really hinge anything on these characters.
Scott: But you know then in some fight or other the character would die or they would kill someone or something would happen.
Scott: It's like, you know, wow that they put in like this whole character designed them Significantly and then they were sort of actually, you know, they didn't even really need to be there.
Scott: That could have just been a background, you know, looks like everyone else character and I gotta say when that is done.
Rym: Well, I like I really enjoy movies where all the characters like where the character that is just a bit character Even if it doesn't all come out on the screen if the character is themselves a strong character for what little part they play it's like a lot of.
Rym: it's very easy to make movies and films where You have your set of main characters and everyone else is just a background character, but like in sort of the samurai Every single person on the screen has character.
Rym: like when there's a bunch of soldiers lined up when there's a big thing going on near The end like all their faces are different and when when something happens, it's kind of an epic scene what happens?
Rym: It is definitely one of those Oh Moments when when someone gets put up on that pole and then someone goes well, it's time and does something Yeah, I think that was a good scene.
Rym: But you see all these soldiers reacting to this event and they all react differently Like they took the time to make every soldier be a little bit unique and react in a little bit of a unique way.
Scott: Well, not every single soul.
Rym: No, not like like you look and you see like a bunch of soldiers reacting in a positive way But a bunch of other ones mixed out kind of balking and then a couple like ready to go in the opposite way But then kind of stopping way.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's not just like, you know The leader of the army and then his you know, just my followers to do exactly what he does, you know And they don't even have faces.
Scott: It's like, you know His his like head.
Scott: few guys actually have a little bit of character to them Even though you don't really know their names or anything and you know, they have.
Scott: you know the distinctive, you know designs Like obviously someone designed them as if they were a character with a name And then they sort of act on their own a little bit even though the screen time is short.
Scott: And
Rym: that's also I think what gave this movie the ability to have all these kind of Oh Snap moments that kind of pull you out of the genre and make you go Oh, wow And like you forget what kind of movie you're watching and just get drawn into the moment of they totally just killed that guy.
Rym: Wow, or or try not to spoil anything because there's a couple of really good ones there.
Rym: Yeah There's quite a few good ones there and there are some scenes where in particular one guy dies at one point and the way he dies is So reminiscent of the scene in snatch where someone else dies.
Scott: Yeah Now a few things I got to say right.
Scott: first of all one thing that bothered me and this isn't the movie's fault Right, but in the theater we watched it in they there was almost definitely something wrong with the projector.
Rym: Clearly the bulb was like burning out and they didn't replace it.
Scott: Yeah, and we watched it.
Scott: Basically.
Scott: It was a digital projector.
Scott: So basically it was just like watching, you know a DVD on a giant screen, right?
Rym: Yeah, we definitely have to watch this movie again in a better form.
Scott: Yeah, because like there were scenes, you know most scenes you could see everything that was going on But there were some were like, you know, it was.
Scott: it was just dark, right?
Scott: It's like I remember one scene in particular like someone drops a dark object Onto the floor in a dark room and then it sort of rolls around and it's like you can hear it rolling.
Scott: But I couldn't see it rolling because there wasn't enough contrast because the bulb and the projector was dying Right.
Rym: Well, it doesn't really.
Rym: it's not relevant to our review at all.
Scott: So no, no, no.
Scott: But you know, it just it sort of bothered me a little bit and it was sort of in my mind while I was watching It.
Scott: whatever.
Scott: but also we watched the dub.
Scott: There was no subtitle version.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Let's review the dub at the end.
Scott: All right, I want to.
Rym: I want to say I don't want dub review to uh get on or in my movie review Because you kind of got to review them separately because the movie itself stands on its own.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Well It is.
Scott: Oh, what else should we say about the movie?
Rym: Well, I had a lot to say, all right All right, so you're done.
Rym: You got nothing.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I mean, you know, it's a samurai movie.
Scott: I don't want to spoil it.
Scott: We you know, how many times we got to say that, you know, there's a it's a buddy movie.
Scott: It's fun.
Scott: Yeah, that's I think that's really what it is.
Scott: It's just fun.
Scott: You know, it's not Anything epic.
Scott: It's just you go in you watch this you have a lot of fun.
Scott: for how long is it?
Scott: 90 minutes?
Rym: Well, i'll put it this way.
Rym: This isn't a spoiler but the movie is is a movie where you start with a small plot that grows into a bigger plot and Clearly there is a large epic plot building toward the end that involves the world.
Rym: But the way it happens is that half of that big plot Doesn't happen through the movie.
Rym: like you see things in the movie that allude to the future of japan like the rise of shoguns and all the the beginning of a long era of political turmoil in japan.
Rym: and there's a lot of kind of Set up for the real world history of japan in the movie which adds a lot and is interesting.
Rym: and two The one thing that they do is that the big epic plot Has mystical trappings, but the movie is straight up real world.
Rym: No magic.
Rym: None of that bs at all Really?
Scott: Well, there is a little bit of science fiction going on.
Scott: Well, very little yeah, but it's it's.
Scott: yeah I think it's sort of it sort of fits and actually it's hard to notice.
Scott: if you don't pay attention You might be like what the fuck but it's actually.
Scott: it's pretty important But it's you know, if you don't pay attention, you're not gonna you're not gonna realize what the deal is.
Rym: I guess the movie is is there is depth here to where.
Rym: while this is just a fun movie and you can just enjoy it Just we You should pay attention to because it does have some things to say and it does.
Rym: there's a lot of allusion to history And there's a lot of really good just background and atmosphere.
Scott: it's also a lot of allusion to like, you know, it's almost like there was.
Scott: uh, Like you're expecting it to go in a certain direction.
Scott: But really instead of it going in that direction, they just leave something unexplained like, you know, it's like hey That seems like that could have been caused by time travel.
Scott: Are they going to explain time travel later?
Scott: And they just never do You know and they just leave it at that.
Scott: It's like huh?
Scott: Well, I wonder how that was then and they just don't because it's not relevant to the the one story You're paying attention to.
Scott: so it's almost as if like you're watching this story unfold, right?
Scott: And you're getting these side bits from other stories, but those aren't.
Scott: the story you're watching unfolds.
Scott: All you get is the side bits from them and it sort of hinted that there may be things that happen in those side stories.
Scott: You know these other characters or something that are you know crazy or might be worthy of stories.
Scott: You know a whole movie on their own, but they don't tell them to you.
Scott: So you're just sort of you know left with these hints in the feeling Of you know a larger movie than what you're actually getting.
Rym: but at the same time The movie does not disappoint in that it doesn't just turn into the big epic magic thing at the end.
Rym: No, it doesn't.
Rym: is very much one of those Real world mundane endings.
Scott: Yeah, I was kind of hoping for a robot at the end, but it didn't happen.
Rym: Well, that's the thing because you know The.
Rym: the basic plot is that there's this boy and the movie begins.
Rym: he's running away from a burning temple and a monk is like Smuggling him out.
Rym: He runs away on his own.
Rym: He's got this dog.
Rym: The dog is so cute and well animated.
Scott: by the way, the dog is badass.
Scott: the dog is not so cute.
Rym: The dog is cute and badass.
Rym: Also, the main character kid is also like really funny and cute like, you know There's actually a lot of humor going on in this movie.
Rym: there is but it's really kind of I don't want to say slice of life But it's it's humor that is contextual kind of like when music like background music in a movie Is contextual as opposed to like.
Rym: it's like the difference between a movie that makes a joke That is for the benefit of the viewer versus a movie where a character makes a joke for the benefit of another character.
Rym: There's no like external humor unless you're the kind of person who's going to crack up when a guy gets shot with a thousand arrows.
Scott: Oh, man, that was pretty fun.
Rym: It was like that.
Rym: But like all the humor is humor between characters which makes it feel a lot more real because Sometimes it's lame humor But it's lame in this real way and the characters are really fleshed out and really complex and really three-dimensional.
Scott: speaking of getting shot with a thousand arrows, right the movie has You know, like usually a samurai movie will have like lots of gore.
Scott: I mean look at even like a kenshin, right?
Scott: You know, it's got like all blood all over the place talking about the oav not the tv show, right?
Scott: You know and this had you know some level of gore type stuff going on, but it wasn't Like.
Scott: it wasn't like each of the killer or anything, you know The gore was.
Rym: it wasn't few and far between and when it happened it was kind of it was there to Impress upon you that yes, people are dying and this sucks.
Scott: Yeah It's like it wasn't you know, extremely gory for the sake of gore's sake but it wasn't toned down gore for the sake of Not grossing you out sake.
Scott: it was like a guy got cut.
Scott: look.
Scott: Oh, we're gonna draw a guy who got cut.
Rym: That's what happens when you get cut.
Scott: Yep, and you know, so some of the parts were a little bit, you know Ew, but they weren't crazy.
Scott: Ew, you know, it was sort of like, you know, just right and the you know cutting didn't happen That often that you were just.
Scott: you know, it was just blood all over the place, you know It.
Scott: just in the fighting scenes there was blood and in the fighting scenes the action was sort of done in a in a somewhat interesting way where All the action was really fast and there was.
Scott: it was lots of you know Sort of blurry motion effects going on and you know They kept giving you like a bunch of different crazy camera angles during all the action scenes.
Rym: It depends because it alternated between the shaky cam, you know Zoom in zoom out like like a real person trying to watch what's going on and cutting to the angles.
Rym: But it would also cut to long shots of very like well choreographed bits of the fight.
Scott: Yeah, you know sometimes it was you know a little bit hard to to follow, you know Like every single move in the fight like, you know a punch and a kick and a slash.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I didn't really have that problem like to me.
Rym: I felt like the fights were Either they were choreographed in 3d completely and then they figured out what angles they wanted and they put it all together Or it was so well done that I feel that way.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I you know when I during the fight scenes, I just sort of felt like you know Ha fight fight fight fight fight fight.
Scott: I couldn't really you know, like follow the fight so much until I really Except for when someone actually got hit then it was like, oh so hosons.
Scott: I got hit.
Rym: All right I disagree at least halfway and then I feel like a good half of the fight scenes were Choreographed and very direct and I felt like I felt very in the action.
Scott: I didn't feel that much in the action.
Scott: It just sort of felt like, you know action action action action, but not following it, you know, like, you know Like there was any sort of flow to the fight or I you know could like be like, you know I wasn't feeling like, you know for one side or the other.
Rym: All I can say is that I pretty much completely disagree with you on that point.
Scott: Nah, you know, you know, I do I mean, I didn't say he does but I you know, i'm just saying I know what you're saying.
Scott: I just I watch like the fights in cowboy bebop and it's like oh, yeah, you know It's you know, like he ducks and then he dives to the side and then he kicks over the table Right, so yeah that one fight there weren't that many fights like that.
Scott: No, but there you know, there there weren't that many fights.
Rym: really if you watch cowboy bebop again Yeah, but there are a lot of fights in this and enough of them were Similar to that or had at least one or two long shots within them.
Scott: I think that the the fights I think what it was that the fights didn't have lots of punctuation in them.
Scott: They were just sort of like these flows.
Rym: So you just said they didn't have any flow.
Scott: No, they was just.
Scott: it was just you know a smooth.
Rym: i'm basically because I feel that your criticism is unwarranted.
Rym: I I really want you to back it up because I don't see it I.
Scott: the fights were just you know, just like a smooth blur and so they were smooth.
Rym: so they had flow.
Scott: You know, these are all subjective terms.
Rym: But you said both that the fights had flow and that they didn't have.
Scott: well even at this I wasn't feeling the fights.
Scott: I mean I could see that they were going for an interesting style in the fight But I they didn't feel.
Scott: you know that exciting.
Scott: It just felt like you know a blur of action.
Scott: That was not you.
Scott: you couldn't really follow it and then you only went like at the end you saw.
Scott: Oh that guy won.
Rym: I'm gonna go the opposite and say that I was.
Rym: I really felt like I was in the fights and I felt every moment of them.
Scott: I I would prefer a different kind of fight, but I see that they were going for something that you know I haven't seen anywhere else, but I guess I just I still disagree.
Rym: Now you can disagree all you want, okay, we'll have to let the listeners watch it and see.
Rym: yeah But this movie is it.
Rym: There are so many points where the main character is doing stuff.
Rym: Well, they got the samurai guy no name and all I can think is i'm too old for this shit.
Rym: This definitely was like a cross between an i'm too old for this shit movie and a samurai movie.
Rym: Yeah, yeah because it was while it was a buddy movie It had a lot of i'm too old for this shit buddy movie as opposed to other kinds of buddy movie.
Scott: Yeah, the other kinds of buddy movies are like, you know, they're not too old for it.
Scott: They're just sort of reluctant to be with the other person.
Scott: It's like they would be doing it on their own if they weren't with the other person.
Scott: But this is like if I wasn't with this other person I wouldn't be doing this at all.
Scott: Yeah, i'd be sitting at home going.
Scott: Ah Plus I gotta say They're not only they're not only reluctant to be together.
Scott: They're reluctant to even be doing anything.
Rym: uh in the I mean We gotta wrap this up because it's late and i'm tired and we got people coming over and we got a crazy weekend coming up.
Rym: But suffice to say i'm gonna keep saying that those words tonight.
Scott: Stop saying.
Scott: suffice to say.
Rym: suffice to say.
Scott: This is plus.
Scott: the other thing is you keep saying suffice to say.
Scott: you're supposed to say.
Scott: suffice it to say.
Scott: Uh, you're leaving out the it.
Rym: Uh suffice to say.
Rym: however, I believe can work grammatically and i'll back that up.
Scott: What are you sufficing to say?
Scott: because the implies Suffice it.
Rym: you realize that the implied sentence is.
Rym: it would suffice to say that.
Rym: Yeah, what i'm saying?
Rym: Well, you're leaving out an it so you've got no subject But implied grammar is perfectly okay in a lot of situations in english.
Rym: Yes, you can have implied subjects.
Rym: In fact in imperative sentences.
Rym: I mean go is a perfectly valid sentence because man though No, it's it.
Rym: Yes scott.
Rym: That's what the word imperative means.
Rym: It's an imperative sentence.
Scott: So you're telling.
Scott: Is it basically when you say suffice to say so you're basically telling the listener to suffice.
Rym: scott That was an example.
Rym: I was not using that as the absolute rule.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: Uh, yeah.
Scott: Yeah Anyway, who's supposed to suffice?
Rym: suffice to say?
Rym: Or it shall suffice to you for me to say that this is a really fun Fantastic movie that I highly recommend you seeing.
Scott: it's a fun movie.
Scott: I don't know if I would use the word fantastic.
Scott: I would say Very good or well above average.
Scott: that is also worth seeing it's not you know, it's not bad.
Rym: It's fantastic because I had a great time watching it.
Scott: I had a very good time watching it.
Rym: I wasn't thrilled plus I point out I was very very content.
Rym: You're always so down on things.
Rym: It's a movie that i'm willing to and not only willing but want to see at least one more time.
Rym: That alone makes puts a movie in the top 20 of movies i've ever seen.
Scott: I could live without seeing it again.
Rym: I want to see it again.
Scott: So that I do not actively want to see it again.
Rym: Okay, if it was on I would watch it.
Rym: Okay, we've established that you're down on things.
Scott: We established that you're far too up on things, you know, you know The listeners would say that you were far too off on.
Rym: there were 11.
Scott: They were 11 was way up and I think the listeners are dumb.
Scott: All right, if you don't think they were 11 is great you're stupid.
Rym: we may or may not do a show tomorrow.
Rym: We'll see next week.
Rym: We'll be back on track with the normal schedule and good night.
Rym: I don't know what I was doing there.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the rss feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and rpgs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front road crew.com Or you can send audio feedback via odeo.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an odeo on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in itunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.