Rym: It's Thursday, March 31st.
Rym: I'm Raymond.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we ramble a bit about why game companies point out flaws and pretend to fix them.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So, what's today's date?
Rym: Today is Tuesday, March 31st.
Scott: So tomorrow is?
Scott: Uh, Wednesday, April 1st.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: And tomorrow, at what?
Scott: Did we decide 7pm?
Rym: Uh, yeah, sure.
Scott: Is that for reals?
Rym: Yeah, sure.
Scott: Alright, 7pm tomorrow, Wednesday, April 1st, 2009.
Scott: We will be doing some live streaming type action that will involve many awesomeness, including you asking us questions and us answering them with aliveness.
Rym: It's GeekNights Live.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: So, this will involve Ustream, this will involve Twitter, this will involve, I guess, uh, The Forum probably.
Scott: Maybe we should use the Skype, the GeekNights Skype a little bit.
Rym: I don't know if we'll use that.
Rym: I don't want to set that up downstairs.
Scott: Yeah, but, you know, just for people to send in messages, you know, not to talk, but to, uh, you know, just a way for people to get their questions in live, you know?
Rym: Yeah, basically like Scott'll watch the Twitter and the something and I'll watch two other things and we'll just kinda, we'll go live, we'll go with it.
Rym: We'll see what happens.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Also, the suffice to say, so I created an account for GeekNights on Twitter and suffice to say, so you can, you know, send messages to those.
Scott: I'll watch them.
Scott: I guess I'll watch my own if I can manage that many things on my one little laptop and, uh, we'll answer questions, do a little, well, I guess it doesn't have to have to be questions.
Scott: It could just be call us in with whatever you want to say and we'll respond to whatever we feel like responding to.
Scott: You know, that's the beauty of it not being voice of it being, you know, text is that we can just sorta look at it and ignore what's poop and respond to what's not poop.
Rym: Plus, you'll get to, uh, see us.
Rym: We'll be sitting on the couch, I guess.
Scott: Yeah, we'll guess we'll sit on the couch and do this.
Scott: And, uh, so that's, that's going to be a special thing tomorrow and we'll probably also record it and put it on the Internet.
Scott: It's, you know, afterwards, I guess I'll let you stream record it also because you stream can do that.
Rym: Yeah, might as well.
Rym: It's a, it's something that we should have done a while ago.
Rym: We just never thought to.
Rym: So we figured, you know, we'll start spring with, uh, something cool.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Especially since a jobless God, we got a lot of free time to actually do stuff.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Jobless God.
Rym: Well, one of us does.
Rym: I don't have any free time.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Sucks.
Scott: So that's, that's tomorrow.
Scott: Uh, if you missed it, um, it's recorded and you can, uh, I'm going to go after we're done with the show, I'm going to make sure to, you know, put announcements for it and everything like all over.
Rym: Just remember it is April 1st, 2009 at 7 p.m.
Rym: Eastern daylight time.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I don't know if I don't want to get a tweet like a year from now asking me a question on the show.
Scott: And don't come asking me, right?
Scott: Like what time is that in my time zone?
Scott: You can go to Google and you can type in, you can go to Google and type in 7 p.m.
Scott: Edt in, you know, um, GMT and push enter and it'll tell you, all right, you don't need to, you don't need to ask us to cover your time zones.
Scott: This is the internet.
Scott: You have the internet.
Rym: That was quite a preemptive complaint.
Scott: I know.
Rym: I didn't see that being a concern.
Scott: You're listening to this show.
Scott: Someone already came up to me with that concern.
Rym: Really?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, wait, was the concern that it'll be at a bad time for them?
Scott: No, they were just like, what's that in GMT?
Scott: And I'm like, you can figure it out on your own.
Rym: Actually I've with Google, it's getting to the point where I pretty much have to think in GMT all the time at work.
Scott: I know.
Scott: But you know, people just for people out there, you know, Google is the ultimate converter, right?
Scott: You can go to Google and type in like 7 miles per hour in, you know, uh, like furlongs per nanosecond and it'll tell you seven miles to the hog's head yet.
Scott: Google will tell you that all you have to do is literally go to Google and type in like, you know, five, uh, you know, dollars per hour in yen per minute and it'll tell you, you know, so you can, you can type in, convert anything to anything.
Scott: As long as it's a valid conversion, you can't be like seven ounces in miles.
Scott: That doesn't work.
Scott: So a parsecs, I don't know if parsecs are in there or not, but you know, it's got pretty much all metric and English units and also antiquated units that are, you know, precisely defined.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: You know, like feet and inches.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Furlong score, all that stuff.
Scott: It understands.
Scott: So if you go and you type in, you know, five 34 PM GMT.
Scott: in, you know, uh, I think they get it.
Rym: I think they get it.
Scott: It will tell you.
Rym: Ah, but uh, you know, I was, I was at an ad office for a certain kind of meeting.
Rym: I'm trying to skip all the like reason.
Rym: I was there and everything, but it's one of those high rise buildings in Manhattan and we're in the meeting and you know, I'm facing the window and it's this corner like giant conference room.
Scott: It's the window.
Rym: Now I'm looking out the window and it's kind of like this internal area.
Rym: Like the building is a big L so there's a space between the two and then you're looking at the courtyard area and like four stories down is the roof of another floor in the building.
Scott: Ah, alrighty.
Scott: Alright.
Rym: So I'm sitting there and I see two maintenance guys come up to the window opposite me and they're like looking at it and talking to each other and I'm pretty much trying to pay attention to them while sounding like and looking like I'm paying attention to the meeting.
Rym: And then they open the window and I think, oh, they're doing something with the window.
Rym: And then one guy just hops out the window and is now standing on the one and a half inch ledge holding himself in by the bottom of this flimsy ass window.
Scott: Usually they have a little strappy thing that they sit on.
Rym: No strap.
Rym: He's just, he pops out, he's holding onto this thing.
Rym: Then he grabs onto the ledges.
Rym: Now he's holding onto the ledge.
Rym: Let's go to the window and he starts washing the outside of the window.
Scott: That's not how you're supposed to do it.
Scott: You're supposed to put this little strap out there with a little hook.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, I think, I think everyone knows that that's what they should be doing, but this is, I don't know.
Rym: No, he didn't fall.
Scott: He did this to be an expert.
Rym: He did this to like 10 windows, but one I could, all I could think about was that Ted talk about work and then two, all I could think about was that someone really needs to call OSHA.
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Scott: Those two things are both correct.
Rym: The worst part, he gets to like the fourth window and he gets out and he's starting to wash.
Rym: the top and the bottom of the windows started sliding down.
Rym: and now I'm thinking, is he going to notice before it gets all the way down?
Rym: And if it does, will he be able to reopen it from the outside?
Rym: And it's going down slowly, slowly, slowly.
Rym: I see him look and he goes like, ah, and he shoves his foot into it.
Rym: Then he stands there for a minute.
Rym: Like he's trying to figure out exactly how to deal with this.
Rym: I don't think he could have lifted his foot without falling.
Rym: So we kind of shimmies down and like worms the window up and jumps back in, collect himself, crawls back out, puts a stick.
Rym: So the window can't close all the way and continues washing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, while I agree with that, Ted, talk about work, the strappy thing isn't really that inefficient.
Scott: It's it's actually pretty cool.
Scott: I mean, it's not like, you know, they're forcing them to use the like, you know, the lift with the winches and whatever.
Rym: You know, the thing is, there is a lift with the winches.
Rym: I saw it.
Scott: It was at the bottom.
Scott: It might not have been for him.
Scott: It might have been for someone else.
Rym: It was for window washing.
Rym: I can see no other purpose.
Rym: And if it were not for window washing, then clearly the man who maintains the winchy thing and the man who maintains the window washing need to talk.
Scott: Well, is is the thing is that in the city you'll often see lots and lots of just construction stuff right all over the place.
Scott: But it all belongs to different groups.
Scott: It's like that belongs to the MTA.
Scott: That belongs to its own by the building.
Rym: It was on the building's roof for the building.
Rym: The building is owned by one person.
Scott: It could have been, you know, owned by a contractor or, you know, anyone.
Scott: So it's like you can't go using someone else's shit.
Scott: If you're like, get a repair building and the painter is there and he's got one thing, you can't use the painter shit.
Scott: It's got.
Rym: I doubt that was the case.
Rym: I'm pretty sure they just don't want to use it because it takes too much time to use.
Scott: Yeah, but the strappy thing does not take too much time to use.
Rym: Well, apparently it does, because it's a much better idea to risk your life to wash windows.
Scott: Maybe guy just so, you know, nonchalant about it.
Rym: Or maybe he's like the tenth guy.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: Then everyone else noticed.
Rym: And that pretty much destroyed the rest of the meetings.
Rym: Everyone watched him.
Rym: One guy.
Rym: One guy was like, I should yell and see if he turns.
Scott: Should I like shot us?
Scott: How far away was it?
Rym: He was about 20 feet away.
Scott: Oh, really?
Scott: You could have got like a spitball over there or something.
Rym: Maybe one of those office rubber band shooters.
Scott: Gattling some nerve action.
Rym: No, I'd felt like it wasn't a day to murder someone.
Scott: You wouldn't.
Scott: It wouldn't be murder.
Rym: I'd be manslaughter in the very least.
Scott: I don't know about that.
Rym: That would most definitely be manslaughter.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Uh, the lawyers in the forum, I believe will concur.
Rym: Manslaughter in the third degree, in the very least.
Scott: The guy is the one who's putting himself in the danger.
Scott: The nerve does not add any danger to the situation.
Rym: I beg to disagree.
Rym: Plus, remember the legal system in the US, I believe they call it like the paper skull theory that even if you don't intend to hurt someone, if by some fluke and he was
Scott: the one who hurt himself by not following the instructions,
Rym: you go, you go tell a judge that, yeah, I saw this guy hanging off the edge of
Scott: it.
Scott: No, I just happened to shoot a nerf arrow out the window.
Scott: I didn't even see the guy.
Rym: I just happened to shoot my gun out the window.
Scott: Yes, my nerf gun.
Scott: It's my real gun.
Scott: I throw a paper airplane out the window.
Rym: My gun plane.
Rym: Anyway, so it's Tuesday.
Rym: What do you got for me?
Scott: So everyone in the internets is talking about, you know, well, the game developers conference just went down, right?
Scott: So there's all sorts of stuff that came out there and everyone's mostly been talking about this on live thing.
Scott: And basically the premise here with this on live is that everyone now who wants to play fancy games right with fancy 3d and fancy sound, right, needs to go and get a fancy machine, be it a big powerful computer or a multi hundred dollar Xbox 360 or a multi hundred dollar PS3, right?
Scott: Well, cloud computing is all the rage.
Scott: So the idea with on live and fundamentally it's not such a bad idea is that you don't have to get a fancy computer.
Scott: Why should you have to buy a big fancy computer?
Scott: You're never going to, you're, you know, just for games, right?
Scott: Instead we on live, we'll have all the fancy computers.
Scott: You won't have to buy an Nvidia GP or anything and we'll just send the finished rendered video to you.
Scott: The same way we send television to you.
Scott: Hi debt.
Scott: We'll just send you high definition video and you'll just send your controller presses to us over the internets and we'll do all the hard 3d work on our side.
Scott: Uh, thus you won't have to buy a fancy machine.
Scott: You'll just basically have to stream video from us and stream a controller button presses to us and you'll have awesome top of the line gaming.
Scott: And in fact, you know, if, if games upgrade and they need even more horsepower, you don't have to upgrade anything.
Rym: Now I feel like penny arcade probably dealt with this in the most summary fashion, but physics pretty much tell me that this isn't going to happen.
Scott: Well, I mean it could happen, but the problem right now is, is this right?
Scott: Online games have lag, right?
Scott: That's even with a really good internet connection.
Scott: You got to ping you to some number of milliseconds.
Rym: The lag is not between me and my computer.
Rym: Exactly.
Scott: My computer and the server.
Scott: So what happens then?
Scott: So let's say you're playing counter-strike, right?
Scott: When you push the button on the mouse to shoot, the shooting happens instantaneously.
Scott: There's immediate shooting going on now where that shooting hits, you know, and the people that you see in the game, right, might not actually be exactly where you see them.
Scott: The game uses a predictive model to draw them where they are probably going to be.
Scott: And it corrects, you know, that location.
Scott: If the network, you know, tells us that the prediction is, you know, not correct.
Scott: So, you know, the lag is sort of in the back end rather than in the front end.
Rym: It used to not always be that way.
Rym: A lot of early online games, the lag did appear in the front end.
Rym: I remember the first time I played Quake 1 online and I had a modem at the time.
Rym: So I dialed into this thing and I'm trying to play Quake and I'd hit walk and my guy would just kind of move and not go anywhere for a little while and then jump forward suddenly.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Now, if these online people were talking about, you know, games like say Checkers or, you know, even something more advanced than that, like, you know, DDR I guess could work, right?
Scott: Kind of.
Scott: Maybe not really.
Scott: No.
Scott: Something that's not a real time game, you know, a game where you take turns or a slower game like Tetris.
Scott: A game like that would work just fine.
Rym: A game like that has no need for a system like this.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: There are only two ways to look at this technology.
Rym: Either they're crazy or it's a phantom console.
Scott: That's what I was just going to say.
Scott: is this thing really, really reeks of phantom console to me.
Scott: You know, their idea people, in case people don't remember, was that they were going to make a console you plugged into your television because, you know, PC gaming, the major problem with PC gaming is that high end PC game is expensive and difficult.
Scott: You have to install all these programs and get into work and configure them.
Scott: They were like, Hey, we'll make this phantom console.
Scott: You just put the CD rom from a PC game into it and it'll just work.
Scott: We'll just make a system where PC games just work.
Scott: That way people won't have to configure them and fuck with all that shit that normal people can't screw around with.
Scott: Of course, that was nutter failure.
Scott: In fact, that's a lot more difficult than what these on live people are talking about.
Scott: Now, I think that there is some potential in this on live idea in making, you know, high end gaming more accessible to the masses.
Scott: the same way Quake Live sort of made it a little bit, but I see the technological hurdles making, you know, actual like FPS game playing very, very frustrating unless the box on the consumer end has more horsepower than they're letting on, thus giving it the ability to at least, you know, do some prediction and things like that.
Rym: But even then, I just, I feel like they won't be able to wrap games in a way, like they'd have to do a lot of changes to the games to make them work well in something like this.
Rym: And I can't see that being worth money.
Rym: All the hardcore gamers already own PCs, people who there aren't that many people who can't afford a fast PC who want to play the small number of games that require the fast PC.
Scott: Well, one one thing that someone was talking about that might actually sort of work out right is, I don't know, people remember back in the day, right?
Scott: Do you?
Scott: Well, there's the remember the BS Zelda, right?
Rym: The Zelda with the satellite, the one that a lot of people for a long time didn't actually believe existed.
Rym: Yeah, partly because it's called BS Zelda.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But there was also do you remember the Sega Channel?
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So the Sega Channel, for people who don't know, was you had a Sega Genesis and you put this cartridge in the top of it, right?
Scott: And that cartridge like hooked up to your cable television.
Scott: And so what you did is the turret, you tuned your cable television into the Sega Channel.
Scott: almost no, even if you wanted to get the Sega Channel, almost no one had a cable provider that actually offered it.
Scott: So it didn't matter.
Scott: And now you could through the cable television as basically functioning as the internet, because this is pre internet, right?
Scott: Would sort of get Sega games.
Scott: You could like, you know, choose demos and then just sort of play them over the Sega Channel.
Scott: Um, so I think what they might be able to do with this right is they might be able to be like, okay, you bought cable television, you bought satellite television, you're in a hotel, you know, whatever.
Scott: Here's a game controller to go to the cable box.
Scott: So it's like, huh?
Scott: And then there'll be just channels you can tune to that will have games.
Rym: This is no different than most hotels have that N64 controller sticking out of the TV, right?
Scott: So basically what they're going to do is just, you're going to, when you get cable, there's going to be some channels that have games on them.
Scott: And some people, you know, might, you know, who aren't big gamers be like, yeah, why should I buy an extra box?
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: This is enough gaming for me.
Scott: You know, how many people out there are just, you know, like they're not, you know, they're not quote casual gamers and that they like, they want to play crappy flash games and that's it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it's like they have a PS2, they have a few games, you know, like they get some GTA and some Madden and that's really it.
Scott: You know, that this might go for them.
Rym: I highly doubt that because people like that will just use something like game tab or there, there are a million other solutions that already exist.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I think if they can get it on a lot of cable networks that it might, I don't think they will.
Rym: I, cause I think honestly that cable networks are going to be dead in not that bad of a set as a separate situation here.
Scott: So, but the thing is, you know, think about you get, you get, you go, you call up your cable, you know, your get, you call up to get some internets from someone, right?
Scott: And they just give you a game controller with your, you know, kid modem or whatever it is.
Rym: I still don't think they can overcome what they're trying to do, what they say this is going to do really is impossible for, from almost any perspective because the kinds of games they seem to want to have and the way they want this to work just wouldn't really work.
Rym: And your method is more the idea of you just kind of download the, it'd be like the Roku, you just kind of download or cash the game locally and then just play locally.
Rym: You're not going to be playing these games with other people.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The multiplayer aspect is really sort of questionable and the cashing locally sorted.
Scott: That's not what they're doing because they're not going to have any 3d hardware locally.
Scott: It's all going to be remote.
Rym: So you can't, I just, I don't think there's any market for this, any viability of it.
Rym: And I, it's either a scam or these people really don't know what their product is.
Scott: I really, I really do think that it is not going to ever occur.
Scott: It's definitely has the highest probability of being like the Phantom game consoles.
Scott: It's total vaporware.
Scott: It's never going to really exist, but one day it could exist with faster, you know, internets and such.
Scott: And, uh, you know, there is a way to maybe get some people to use it kind of, but I just, it's going to be something that happens like three or four more times down the road.
Scott: You'll start getting it.
Rym: You're a lot more optimistic about this.
Scott: I'm fairly optimistic at all.
Scott: I'm heavily pessimistic.
Scott: The, I'm telling you this on live company is going to be right.
Rym: There's no way, but the fundamental way that they're going about this, I think is the wrong way to go about it.
Scott: Just kind of fundamentally, I think it could work in the, in the, in the distant future when a internets are faster.
Rym: See, but even if internets are faster, you run into the, I mean, one of the things we ran into at work when we're working on like latency for market data and stuff is the speed of electrons and the speed of light.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: We calculated the minimum possible latency we could get based on how long it would take an electron to follow the path.
Rym: And then we shot for that and we achieved that and we couldn't get more than that.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: There's nothing better.
Scott: Nope.
Rym: So maybe, you know, this could work.
Rym: I take this all back.
Rym: They could actually pull this off because if they use quantum entanglement, there would be no lag.
Scott: So the thing is, I think that there is a, the problem is while you demand and I also demand say zero lag and like, you know, the FPS department, right?
Scott: I think that, you know, people out there will, we'll deal with some milliseconds of lag between pushing the button and the gun shooting.
Scott: And I think, you know, as long as they can get that to be very small and not like noticeably frustrating, I think that, you know, 50 milliseconds won't frustrate the vast majority of people.
Rym: It'll frustrate us, but not, I think it will frustrate anyone they would be marketing to because using this for simpler games, there are much better ways to go about it.
Scott: Like I said, remember like the Sega channel that was just broadcast like you could, it wasn't, but what it would do is it would bring like high end 3d type of HD FPSs and things to people who currently can't play those things at all because inaccessible to them.
Rym: I don't think they'll be able to achieve that on any level.
Scott: I don't think they will now, but you know, some years from now, I don't know.
Rym: I'm pretty doubtful.
Scott: Now they're going to fail and be vaporware.
Rym: But anyway, there's this other article on slash dot.
Rym: It's called a. game companies face hard economic choices.
Rym: I believe that they might be faced with full life consequences.
Rym: I don't think so, but this is a long article and there's I wonder what is going to happen with the game industry?
Rym: because basically we're running into the situation where one, the economy is down, so people aren't going to pay as much money for coming back now.
Rym: Well, the stock market's coming back.
Rym: That doesn't necessarily mean that the economy is coming back, but to even the economy is down.
Rym: A lot of people are out of work.
Rym: Jobs are, you know, there's trouble on that front and games haven't gotten cheaper and in fact, in many ways have gotten more expensive.
Rym: and not only that, games cost a lot more to make now than they used to, at least for consoles since I'm not really going to worry about pc games because they're still kind of the minority and world of warcraft really makes the rest of them not matter at all.
Scott: But like steam is starting to make some moves though.
Rym: They are bit by bit.
Rym: But then again, the games that are really rocking steam are the cheap games now.
Scott: Well, we're not going to get into that discussion.
Rym: Well, there's that whole thing where when they lowered the price of left for dead, the sales skyrocketed to it like a crazy.
Scott: It's like they lowered the price by half, but the sales jumped more than 50%.
Scott: thus they made more money by selling it for a lower price.
Rym: Yes, that's relevant to what's going on here because one of the figures they bring up is that it costs about $25 million.
Rym: They say to make a game for a current generation console.
Scott: Oh, a big fancy one.
Rym: Well, which they consider to be a normal game like in a title.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: It cost about 10 million to make for the last generation.
Rym: I don't know if that includes inflation or not, but even if it does, that's still a lot.
Rym: That's a big difference.
Rym: And gameplay wise, there aren't that many differences between the two generations.
Scott: And now that sales are down and there's so much competition, I know that money goes into, you know, voice actors and 3d and fancy graphics and, and you know, mark cut scenes and marketing.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But the real issue here is that game sales are not what they used to be coupled with the fact that it costs more money to make games and there's more competition.
Rym: because, you know, we talk about this a lot, the whole can't compete with the past, but quake live really illustrates this more than anything.
Rym: We've got a game that came out when I was in high school.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Late nineties, quake three, right?
Rym: It's already been made.
Rym: Like it's done.
Rym: It doesn't cost any more to make the game.
Scott: It's already done.
Rym: So they just take this, re-release it, put some stuff around it.
Rym: They cost almost nothing to make compared to what the game cost to me.
Rym: I mean, making a website is a lot cheaper than making a 3d game and it's doing well enough to where it's real competition for brand new FPSs that come out.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There's people, there's a lot more people playing quake live than there are playing like FPSs that just came out.
Scott: You know, I mean, I don't know, but what's this?
Scott: What's what?
Rym: So, so how many people are playing quake live?
Scott: Thousands.
Rym: And how many people are playing these fictional FPSs you're making up?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: There's probably, you know, there's, not a lot of people playing.
Rym: Playing what?
Scott: I don't know what, but that unreal something that just, that was on, that was super cheap on steam, like the newest unreal tournament.
Scott: No one's playing that.
Rym: That was a newer unreal tournament, right?
Rym: Not a re-release.
Scott: I'm pretty sure the one they were selling on steam for cheap was the newest one.
Rym: What about the halos and all that?
Rym: Is there a new halo?
Rym: When was the last halo?
Scott: I don't know how many people are still playing halo three, but it's only on the X-Box.
Rym: How many people are still playing counter-strike?
Scott: More people are playing counter-strike than anything else ever.
Scott: And it will always be that way.
Rym: Actually, what was surprising, I went to play counter-strike the other day and all the servers were still there.
Rym: And for, for a lark, I logged into a team fortress two to take a peak and a lot of people are playing.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: But they're all playing the same maps when it came out and they're all playing.
Rym: Like it's weird how the game is so static now.
Scott: But anyway, people have played left for dead also.
Rym: And Reggie even.
Rym: they have a quote from him that they say it takes about 1 million sales on the Wii to turn a profit for the average game.
Scott: Well, for a big game.
Rym: I mean, if you make, if you may keep saying big game, but all the people in these articles are saying average game.
Scott: Well, I'm talking about like, you know, if you stretch, if you break out, right.
Scott: You can't tell me right that you need to sell a million copies of like Tetris for the DS to make money.
Scott: You know, you can't tell me that it takes a million sales of mega man.
Scott: I said for the Wii, all right, mega man nine did not need a million sales.
Scott: That doesn't count.
Rym: They're not counting the virtual console or anything like that.
Rym: They're talking about disc games, like Wii games, games that are in the store with the Wii logo on them there for the Wii.
Rym: All right.
Scott: But you go to the, go to the store and look for like the crappy Wii games, like the ones that were obviously thrown together in like, you know, a few weeks just to like for some licensed property.
Scott: Like, you know, generic cookie cutter platformer for kitty cartoon show number three does not need a million sales to profit.
Scott: I'm just, this is what Reggie is saying.
Rym: But anyway, and the average game on the Wii seems to sell about 150,000 copies.
Scott: It's about right.
Scott: If you take all the crap games into account.
Rym: See, I don't know.
Rym: I don't know what these numbers are exactly.
Scott: No, because Nintendo is not going to tell you shit.
Rym: Yeah, but it was interesting that Reggie would say something like that in the first place.
Scott: Yeah, I guess, but I don't know.
Rym: I just, I feel like there's going to be a big change in the industry because all the indications are that games are overpriced and really, but like I think they're overpriced to a frightening degree.
Rym: And I think that the sort of price equal and people just expect a new game to cost between 40 and $60 out of well, because I mean, look, the NES games game out right way back in the day.
Scott: Atari games, the prices were like all over the place.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But when you got to the NES, the price on new games was like $50.
Scott: They were all $50.
Scott: There was really not much fluctuation at all.
Rym: Like not Mario three and we're $60, 65 when it came out.
Scott: But I think that those are retail markups.
Scott: I think the MSRPs were always $50.
Scott: And I think that that was, you know, Toys R Us and other people, when they saw that this was a big demand game, they raised the price up a little bit.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: That's, I don't know that for sure.
Scott: But that's my, that's my guess.
Scott: But anyway, you know, there wasn't a great deal of price fluctuation and it seems like people never really thought about changing the price for video games.
Scott: They just always left it at $50 because that's what they were.
Scott: But in, you know, as we got to finally the Xbox 360 PS3 generation, Microsoft and Sony were finally like, um, yeah, these games are getting more expensive to make.
Scott: And they started to look at the price and they raised the price to $60.
Scott: ish, right?
Scott: For newer games.
Scott: Whereas the Wii said, ah, look, we'll stay at 40 and 50 or whatever, you know, we're not gonna, we're not going to raise the price.
Scott: And handheld game prices have always been around $30 for, you know, a handheld game that was brand new at least.
Scott: And just no one, at least in the United States is like, there hasn't been an actual changing of prices on video games to see what the market value actually is.
Scott: And you know, no one's actually ever done it.
Scott: They've never lowered the prices to see how many more you'll sell.
Scott: They never raised the prices to see how many less you'll sell.
Scott: There hasn't been experimentation at all.
Scott: It's just sort of been the price.
Scott: They're what they are because that's what they are.
Scott: And no one messes around with it.
Rym: And I would guess that honestly, that the industry as a whole is, it's not a conspiracy.
Rym: It's just that they're worried that if they start lowering prices, the games are going to hit what they're actually worth on the market.
Rym: And I think there's so much free content out there now, both pirated and legitimate that the, I guess the cost that people will pay in lieu of any other option is very, very, very low to the point that they will not be able to make the big budget games that they've been making.
Scott: Well, see, actually, I think something slightly different is that if you look at steam, right, steam has shown that if you lower the price, right on some crazy awesome game, right, that the sales just are.
Scott: so the numbers on it are just so crazily large that it's all right.
Scott: You know, if you come out with, say, a new Zelda game, right at the same time, can that really be definite?
Rym: Because so they lower the price on some games, those games now not only are they really cheap, but they are competing with far fewer things because you're only competing with things at the same price point.
Rym: Now, if every game was that price, maybe those sales were just spread out and the same number of games would get bought, people would just have more options again, and they'd pay less overall.
Scott: That's a very good question.
Rym: That's what I worry because you don't only you only have so many hours in a day to play games, even if you're in college, I could only.
Rym: I only spent, you know, tops 20 hours a day playing Counter Strike.
Scott: I think what you might see, even if all the games went down to like twenty dollars, right, big ones, right?
Scott: I think what you might see is at first you would see, you know, people going holy shit and they could just have, you know, so much money.
Scott: It's like, you know, the kids who would normally go and sell back a game and then, you know, to buy two or whatever, you know, stuff like that.
Scott: Right now, you're going to see people like buy a shit ton of games, crazy shit, tons of games and sales temporarily for maybe even up to six months to a year would go crazily high.
Scott: You just get crazy numbers of sales all over the place as people buy up all these great games at low prices.
Scott: But then I think over time, as people had these, you know, come to these realizations of having a shelf full of games that don't get played, would go back to just buying, you know, the number of games that they can buy at, you know, whatever price they can get.
Scott: But I think you will also see a perpetual increase sales among kids, you know, gamer kids who have, you know, not so much money, but would now buy more games if their prices were lower.
Rym: Well, I think the biggest concern, you know, competing with the past is that unlike other media movies and CG and all these things, at least with video games, the curve of, I guess, technological advancement or the maturity of games as a platform, as a medium, all these things really flattened out in the last few years to the point that the differences in terms of gameplay and even graphics between cutting edge games and slightly older games and then older games and older games and older games is not as much as it used to be.
Rym: I mean, the difference between the Atari and the Nintendo was like VHS and DVD, chocolate and shit.
Rym: But now the difference between a PS two game and a PS three game to many people is not that much.
Rym: And people like, I mean, PS two is still the biggest console out there.
Scott: Games are still being made for PS two might go down to one hundred dollars real soon.
Scott: Actually, it is going down to one hundred dollars real soon instead of one hundred and thirty, which is what it's been for a very long time.
Rym: But we're getting to this gameplay and accessibility and just desire wise, flat plateau of gaming, where people who play games are just as satisfied playing a game that came out ten years ago as they are playing a game that came out satisfied
Scott: playing an iPhone game, you know,
Rym: even gamers, not not just, you know, 80s nostalgia gamers, but just self-identified gamers will often play a game that's five or six years old because they couldn't play every game that came out in nineteen ninety nine in nineteen ninety nine.
Scott: Yeah, it's weird.
Scott: It's like you don't see really discussions of graphics anymore.
Scott: I think it's actually sort of disappeared, you know, where the you know, I mean, you know, I used to always you know, there would always be like one punk kid or two who would come along and be like, oh, man, this is so much better.
Scott: The graphics are so much cooler.
Scott: That hasn't happened in a very in a relatively you know, I can't remember the last time places
Rym: on the Internet,
Scott: probably, but I can't remember the last
Rym: time
Scott: I had to slap down a punk kid for that, you know, and I think, you know, the we sort of came and they had the right idea in that, you know, gameplay matters and let's change it up.
Scott: But they didn't.
Rym: Well, they started to a little bit and then they said, oh, never mind.
Scott: And now they just releasing GameCube games with Wii controls.
Rym: That kind of happened with the DS.
Rym: I remember games like Kirby's Canvas Curse.
Rym: Yeah, there were all these kind of games that were like, let's try to do something different.
Rym: And now the games that do really well in the DS, other than like the cooking mama and those sorts of things, you know, Castlevania, which is just a Gameboy game.
Scott: Yeah, at least the two screens are put to very good use.
Scott: That was a great idea.
Rym: It was.
Scott: And the you know, the microphone, very bad idea, right?
Scott: Local wireless multiplayer.
Scott: Very good.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Not integrating it with the Wii.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Rym: Very bad.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Touch screen, you know, is just, you know, it's it's OK.
Scott: It's it's, you know, but it's usually just used as like, you know, menu selection or something along those lines.
Scott: You know, games, they actually play a game with the stylus as the control.
Rym: Well, there's that, you know, Phantom Hourglass, which I think did a pretty good job with.
Scott: that was OK.
Scott: I was OK.
Rym: It was an interesting concept and it's worked a lot better than I expected.
Scott: I think, you know, the GTA game actually uses it, you know, as a menu selector down low.
Scott: It's like you have a PDA that you can sort of poke at.
Scott: So you go to the PDA menu and then you use the stylus to navigate your PDA to check your missions and your, you know, buy ammo and stuff like that.
Rym: But at the same time, like a lot of games that they like Chrono Trigger added the menu at the bottom.
Rym: And it's still just so much or advanced for us.
Rym: You could just click where you wanted your units to go.
Rym: It's so much faster to use the pad and the buttons in those games.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: But I think that it would be possible to have the stylus be faster if the interface was implemented better.
Rym: And some of those, I guess the gist of all this, you should read the article.
Rym: There's there are a lot of interesting tidbits in it that are kind of unrelated and decontextualized.
Rym: So there's not a lot of useful real information in this article.
Rym: But the relevant quote, I think, is, quote, the key is just that more importantly, these are too expensive and there are too many choices.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And think about if they lower the prices, there are just as many choices unless only one person lowers prices and other people don't.
Scott: I think the key is that if you want to make money with games, you have to a make your game as cheaply as possible while still getting it done.
Scott: Be you have to.
Scott: your game has to be different from the other games out there.
Scott: No more.
Scott: You know, the cookie cutters are not going to do it anymore.
Scott: You know, another FPS that just looks different is not going to work.
Scott: You need your game has to be set apart from other games for reals.
Scott: Three, you got to get your game on like every platform in the universe, from like the iPhone to the Wii to that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There's no reason to not put your game on every single place that it can can be played.
Scott: And you're going to have to find the price point at which you get the most profits, you know, whether that's one hundred dollars or five dollars or whatever, you got to multiply price by sales and figure out that that's basic economics.
Rym: That's not useful at all.
Scott: But the thing is, people haven't done that with games in the past.
Rym: They try to.
Scott: No, they really haven't.
Scott: No one took the risk of setting a different price point until recently on steam.
Rym: Well, on steam.
Rym: Yeah, there have been other experiments in that front.
Rym: I think more.
Scott: But no one ever took the risk on actual real deal games because it was too big a risk.
Rym: But I don't think it's so much the risk factor, except if everyone else is charging fifty dollars.
Rym: I know I can get away with charging fifty dollars.
Scott: Yeah, but maybe you would make more money going forty dollars.
Scott: Maybe get more sales.
Scott: You know, you don't know.
Scott: No one's going to risk trying to find out because you'll make enough with the fifty.
Rym: But I mean, according to the article, people aren't making enough.
Rym: And that's the problem.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, now they're not.
Scott: But they were.
Rym: I mean, it is said that of the quote, four hundred eighty six games that came out for the Wii, only sixteen sold more than a million because most of them are terrible.
Rym: And nine of those were first party.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Nintendo made more, you know, great Nintendo games like they make that punch out is going to sell a million.
Scott: I'll tell you right now.
Scott: Guaranteed.
Rym: I'll buy it.
Rym: You'll buy it.
Scott: Not now.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: The thing is, I have so many games to play.
Rym: I don't need it.
Rym: No game is worth me buying when it comes out anymore.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Wait, why should I get it right away?
Scott: There's no need for right away.
Rym: So will it?
Rym: will it become, you know, not you can't compete with the past, but you can't compete with the bargain.
Rym: But maybe this is why so much of the industry is focusing so hard on trying to prevent for sale.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Because if if you just wait a year and buy the game in the bargain bin for five bucks, there are so many games out that if you play every game a year behind, you'll never pay anything for game.
Scott: I think it's just.
Scott: I think the next generation there's no good is not going to be physical media anymore.
Scott: It's going to be over physical media for games.
Scott: I think it's done.
Scott: It's going to be all download.
Rym: I don't know what to I mean, it's good for almost every reason in the world, except for the fact that I can no longer lend my games to other people.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Well, I think the solution to that would be just steam should let you, you know, give you get rid of the game from your steam and put it on someone else's, you know, and if but they have no vested interest in allowing you to do that.
Scott: No, I think we need a law to force them to do that.
Rym: Ha.
Rym: A law to force the ability to transfer.
Rym: DRM protected me to transfer digital property.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: To enforce the right of first sale on digital properties.
Rym: That would make me buy a Kindle.
Scott: Yeah, it's not bad.
Rym: If I could just give someone else my e-book when I was done with it.
Scott: If you want to put copy protection on digital property, you need to still allow a mechanism for, you know, the right of first sale.
Scott: for, you know, I should be able to, you know, I mean, if there's DRM, usually it means everyone has an account.
Scott: I should be able to delete a WiiWare game from my Wii and add it to my friends.
Rym: We, you know, see now this is one of those situations where the market will never, ever, ever, ever, ever provide that.
Scott: No, there's never, they'll never do that.
Scott: It can only come out of only come from a law that demands it without regulation.
Rym: That can't happen.
Scott: Nope.
Rym: So, uh, I don't know.
Rym: I'm a strong advocate of regulation and laws to protect first sale video games.
Scott: Yeah, I'll do that.
Rym: Even though it'll probably go one step toward destroying the video game industry.
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: I think there needs to be a law for sale on digital.
Scott: I think there needs to be a, uh, destruction of the video game industry should just be a general, uh, there should be a, uh, just a, like a general law that says right of property transferral.
Scott: You know, if you, you know, pay for a good or service, you should be able to transfer that good or service to another party.
Scott: Uh, you know, by any terms you wish, you know, just, uh, unlimited, you know, unrestricted resale.
Scott: It's actually, if you think about it, not so much a regulation as an enforcement of deregulation, you know, it's basically saying everyone has the free market right to transfer their things to others.
Scott: You know, it's sort of, you know, protecting capitalism more, you know, saying that there is no right of free sale is the anti-capitalist way.
Scott: It's preventing, you know, the market from doing what it wants is preventing people from, you know, it's restricting economic freedom of peoples.
Rym: Well, I'll go one step further and say that the video game industry, I mean, if things like this happen or if this guy's right and the whole model is collapsing, I frankly kind of hope that the entire video gaming console PC market as it is completely collapsed.
Scott: It's always great for things to be, we always see as people who love change that we are, we always want things to collapse because whenever things collapse, they're never gone forever.
Scott: They always rise from the ashes.
Rym: Either you rise from your grave or you have 400 years of darkness.
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: I don't think.
Rym: if this, I want, no, I want like five minutes of darkness and the new games.
Rym: I don't want four years of darkness.
Scott: It'll rise from the ashes.
Scott: People will always want video games and people, you know, people will finish the games they got and they'll be like, I was speaking more generally.
Rym: You don't want everything to just burn down.
Rym: I mean, I don't want, no, it will never burn down completely, but no, but like I don't want society to generally burn down around me.
Scott: No, that's not a good idea.
Rym: I just want the video game industry to burn down around itself.
Scott: And then already once after the Atari, it'll probably, you know, sort of, you know, they'll probably be just sort of an actual revolution in gaming.
Rym: But anyway, that all aside, things of the day.
Rym: I love mashups and this is my favorite new mashup.
Rym: They mashed up the movie Amadeus, which it always surprises me how many people have never seen it.
Scott: It's kind of long, so it's not, it's not too surprising.
Scott: It's not that long.
Scott: It's, it's, it's kind of, isn't it, isn't it multiple?
Scott: I remember it being like multiple VHS tapes, so it must be like, it might be two DVDs for the movie.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I can go look it up, but regardless, it's not that long a movie.
Rym: It's a pretty good movie and I'm just, I guess I'm surprised because I've, I was actually forced to watch it in school.
Scott: I watched it in school multiple times and it's, I really, it's kind of like that thing in super bad.
Rym: It's, I don't know what I can say.
Rym: This is brilliantly done.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: This is a pretty funny right here.
Scott: It's a lot more funny if you've seen Amadeus.
Rym: It is, but it's, it's funny.
Rym: Like you'll get the joke, you know, you're going to wonder, you know, what are they doing?
Rym: What is this?
Rym: And then it'll happen.
Rym: You'll be like, Oh, I get it.
Rym: Penises, but they keep, it's just the same joke, you know, kind of building and building and you've already, they've already given you the joke, but somehow it just gets funnier and funnier and funnier as you watch.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Um, so check this out, right?
Scott: Uh, you know, I've imagined before, right?
Scott: A game of Mario where someone else, you know, sort of controlling the level, right?
Scott: Sort of an adversarial platformer.
Scott: Well, someone here, they didn't really make that.
Scott: This is more of a programming kind of tool, you know, just an editor kind of fun thing, not so much an adversarial game, but they made super Mario brothers one, but someone else while you're playing Mario can control the game with the mouse.
Scott: So they can like pick up a Goomba and put it under you to kill it.
Scott: Or they can pick up a Goomba and drop it on your head to kill you.
Scott: They can pick up the mushroom and throw it down a hole.
Scott: You know, they can pick up a turtle shell and you watch, they, they play through in this video, worlds one, one, one, two, one, three, and one four.
Scott: And they do some pretty interesting stuff.
Scott: Uh, you know, especially in world one dash three with some of the moving platforms and, uh, with King Koopa.
Scott: So, uh, you should, uh, you should watch this.
Scott: Uh, you know, you can fast forward a little bit.
Scott: You'll get the idea, but it's, it's pretty fun.
Rym: We need to make a game like that.
Rym: I mean, remember north versus south.
Rym: That was a good game that had that it had the kind of adversarial platformer.
Rym: One person's trying to beat the level.
Rym: One person's dropping monsters.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Or in this case, southerners or northerners, depending on who's playing, always play the north because they get an advantage.
Scott: I always played the north also.
Rym: So what are we talking about tonight?
Scott: Well, basically, you know, this is sort of a, it's hard to, you know, put a label on this topic.
Scott: That's very clear, but basically I've noticed a recent trend in gaming, especially video gaming, pretty much only video gaming, where, uh, the marketing for games, you know, um, is sort of saying things about games that are not true, right?
Rym: Not just hype though.
Rym: We're not talking about regular hype.
Scott: We're not just talking, we're not talking about things like bull shots or, you know, things that are just, you know, lying about features, right?
Scott: We're talking about people who are coming up and bragging that their games are fundamentally different in some way.
Scott: They're, you know, they're, they're a complete, you know, this game is a revolution in gameplay.
Scott: It's totally different from whatever, you know, fallout three, it's a totally free world.
Scott: You can do anything.
Scott: Oh my gosh.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: You can do anything except tell the radio, a radiation immune mutant to push the button in the radioactive room.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: Children.
Scott: The reality of the game is that, no, really.
Scott: It's just exactly like every other game in this genre.
Scott: No different.
Scott: You didn't have a revolution whatsoever.
Scott: And in fact, you know, this game is just like all the others.
Rym: I guess what, what really makes this stand out and why it's a topic for me is that it's not just that they make these claims, it's that they kind of identify exactly what the flaws are in an existing genre, like a type of game.
Rym: It'd be the equivalent of saying, yes, Mario one was a great game except for the fact that I can, well, there's nothing wrong with Mario one, so I can't really use that as it's not really no, but you know, taking like an MMO.
Rym: Well, MMOs are great idea, but you know, it's just a grind and it's all just parallel.
Rym: So I say, all right, my new MMO, there's no grind and it's completely non parallel.
Rym: Everyone's, you know, the whole world affects the whole world and that's just not true.
Rym: It's just a wild clone.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It's like you said.
Scott: you recognize that the problem with MMOs was grind and then you came out with, you said you weren't going to do grind.
Scott: You said you were going to have an MMO.
Scott: that's different.
Scott: And then the game you came out with was grindtastic.
Scott: So really what, what, what the fuck?
Scott: Really?
Rym: I mean, it just, it amazes me that people will so accurately identify what's wrong with the genre and then just not do anything about it.
Scott: And then say they are, well, I mean, look like, you know, there's, there's like the RTS is right.
Scott: We'll be like, Hey, you know, the problem with RTS is that you have to click so much and it's all about who's clicking the fastest.
Scott: that determines the winning.
Scott: We're going to make an RTS full of strategy and tactics.
Scott: And they use the word strategy and tactics, but I don't, you know, and if their RTS was full of strategy and tactics to be great, but I don't think they know what strategy and tactics means.
Scott: Cause when I play their RTS, sure.
Scott: There are these surface level differences where someone who, you know, is perhaps, you know, not really thinking about the game very hard might notice these, you know, like slight touches and think that they're clever and good.
Scott: Like, you know, I played that, um, that, uh, Warhammer 40 K RTS Dawn of War two, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like, you can do some cool stuff.
Scott: You can tell units to like, you know, go into positions of cover and, you know, you can have all these options of customizing units, but there's no strategy and tactics.
Scott: It's just a really complicated rock, paper, scissors.
Scott: You have all these options that make it seem to someone who doesn't, you know, look at the fundamentals that, yes, this is full of strategy and tactics.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Look, it's not about clicking the fastest.
Scott: It's about taking cover and having the right guys in the right positions and using the right guys against the right guys.
Scott: But that's rock, paper, scissors, using the right guy against the right guy.
Rym: But at the same time, that's not a hundred percent fair because all games boil down to either randomness, solviveness or rock, paper, scissors.
Scott: That's correct.
Scott: But the thing is, is that they, you know, the, when people, I don't know if the company itself, I didn't read a lot of their marketing, so I don't know if they can be blamed, but a lot of people told me, you know, yeah, if you want to play an RTS that isn't about clicking the fastest, you should play these.
Scott: But really there was a whole lot of clicking the fastest going on in that game.
Scott: Um, so what's up?
Scott: Why did, why did you say that?
Rym: If, uh, if, if it wasn't true, I mean, it's not like this is a new phenomenon though.
Rym: I mean, remember Dai Kitana?
Scott: Yeah, but that game didn't really make the sort of specific claims.
Scott: They did.
Rym: They talked a lot about.
Rym: this game has amazing AI.
Rym: Like the AI in this game is going to be so great.
Rym: Like you'll feel bad for the people you kill because they're so smart.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, fear sort of people always talk about, Oh, fear has this great AI.
Scott: Oh, all right.
Scott: The AI in fear isn't, you know, I've played the demos of fear one and two.
Scott: The AI in fear is not any better than the AI and any other FPS.
Scott: It's simply that the enemies have more things that they can do.
Scott: You know, they can jump over a railing or hide behind something.
Scott: It's not a better AI.
Scott: They're not any smarter than the bad guys in any other FPS, just that they have more things that they can do.
Scott: And being able to do more things does not make you smarter.
Scott: It just makes you appear smarter.
Rym: But then what makes you smarter?
Scott: If the things they choose to do in the, you know, it's the, the, the process of deciding which of those things get done.
Rym: The problem there is that what if you just make them perfect?
Rym: They decide the right thing to do every time.
Rym: And as a result, they always beat you.
Scott: So that actually good AI.
Scott: Oh my gosh.
Rym: No, I don't think good AI necessarily necessitates that.
Scott: I didn't say that good AI.
Scott: The to me, that means that the AI is smart and will do the smart thing, you know, and, and, but it won't necessarily make a very good or fun game.
Rym: So, you know, I would say the good AI is AI that is unpredictable in a, cause I mean, even when monsters, you know, bosses and games like Castlevania or whatever, or FPS is, there's always the boss and they either work in patterns.
Rym: You have to figure out the patterns and know when to dodge, or they have like a set of 15 or 20 or a different things they can do and they'll randomize them or they'll decide them.
Rym: But it's very rare that I am caught off guard by something or that something.
Rym: it's not just that it acts randomly.
Rym: It's that it acts in a way that I cannot either one predict what it's going to do or to recognize the randomness.
Rym: A monster actually, they came close to that surprisingly.
Rym: Like I was really surprised by this, but then I eventually figured out what was going on.
Rym: But in Castlevania, there's this monster, the new Castlevania on the DS that will like, you'll see it every now and then.
Rym: It's like, I forget exactly what it's called.
Rym: You have to take a picture of it, but it just stands there not moving.
Rym: And when you get close to it, it does all these things.
Rym: And it was really unnerving to fight it because it was so static.
Rym: And yet at the same time, so unpredictable that it took, it scared me more than anything in any game has for a long time.
Scott: Wow.
Scott: It's saying a lot.
Rym: Of course.
Rym: Then I ran into the monster four or five more times and then I figured it out.
Rym: And so much for that.
Scott: But yeah, that's, you know, a good AI would be, you know, when you play a game like quake, you know, against human opponents, right.
Scott: There's no pattern to them.
Rym: Yes, there is.
Scott: Some people are, but good people, you know, they either they have like, you know, the perfect move, which is just, you know, that's what you do every time.
Scott: Cause it's the perfect thing to do.
Scott: Or, you know, they, I mean, I don't do the same thing every time in the same situation when I play multiplayer games, you know, I mix it up, you know, sometimes I go left.
Scott: Sometimes I go right.
Rym: You really want to have AI that emulates what people do.
Rym: You just have to have them bitching and moaning and swearing all the time and periodically accidentally killing themselves in the corner with the rocket launcher.
Scott: That works.
Scott: But you know, if you wanted to have a really a good AI, it should be like playing multiplayer.
Scott: No one would want to play multiplayer anymore.
Scott: And games, they say that they've got multiplayer.
Scott: They say they've got AI like that, but they don't.
Scott: They're just full of shit.
Scott: Their AI is no better than anyone else's AI.
Rym: But I guess I wonder why no one, I mean, people always say they're like, they identify the problem in the genre, but they don't actually do anything about it.
Rym: Why doesn't someone just make a game that like, why doesn't someone make an MMO where there is no grind?
Rym: Zero.
Scott: Well, they did.
Scott: It's called Puzzle Pirates.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But even then Puzzle Pirates, the way you play the game, the puzzles get kind of grindy over time.
Rym: You're not grinding to level up, but you're still kind of grinding at these puzzles that you don't, they don't take any mental effort from you anymore to sell your shit.
Scott: Well, I think that Puzzle Pirates, the key is the, you know, the, the puzzles of sailing and such like that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like if you're just, you know, sailing, it's not really so great, but I think the multiplayer puzzles in there, you know, are pretty great.
Scott: And also the ship combat puzzle is pretty great.
Scott: You know, it's those direct combat puzzles and puzzle parts that are good.
Scott: The supporting the captain of the ship puzzles are busy work.
Scott: And you know, if you like doing that, that's cool by you, but I don't, you know, I think that those are a little bit grindy.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But well, I guess the issue was that Puzzle Pirates is popular, but it's no world of Warcraft.
Scott: No, it's not.
Scott: And I
Rym: think the answer, I think what's really going on here is that for any given genre, the things that
Scott: we
Rym: recognize as being wrong with the genre, not just we as me and Scott, or we as people who recognize these things, but the industry too, I mean, people,
Scott: they make
Rym: a new MMO and they say, no grind in this MMO, or, you know, the grind is not so bad.
Rym: Or they, they, they identify that the grind was a problem.
Rym: I think what they really recognize is that players secretly want the grind, but will go to the game expect, you know, they say no grinds.
Rym: They say, yeah, the grind is bad, but they don't really recognize in themselves that they secretly like the grind.
Scott: Well, speaking specifically on the, the issue of grind, it's pretty much obvious at this point that people, they don't like grinding, right?
Scott: But what they do like is basically getting rewards and upgrades and power ups, right?
Scott: And they like, you know, to just get more powerful and more powerful, more powerful.
Scott: That's why things like desktop tower defense, or, you know, any flash game that has upgrades in it, people love that shit, but in a persistent because they also care about the rate of getting upgrades versus the other people around them.
Scott: That's true, but that's in a, that's in a multiplayer, but in a, you know, just even in single player games, people love to constantly get upgraded.
Scott: You know, there's this cycle of, you know, play, play, play.
Scott: The difficulty starts to get a little hard, but then we give you an upgrade and the difficulty goes back down.
Scott: So the game has this cycle of get starts out easy, gets harder, then gets easier again, because you got upgrades then gets harder.
Scott: Then it's easier again, because you get upgrades.
Scott: It's this, you know, tension and relief cycle hard that you lose.
Scott: It never gets so easy that it's boring.
Scott: So even though you are grinding, if that cycle is balanced psychologically, it's people love that shit.
Scott: It's like, so it's like, it's literally like psychologically addicting the way that, that if you can get that cycle just right and wow, has that cycle, like exactly dead on, they have like mastered that, you know, that
Rym: I think players will recognize that they don't like grinding, but not recognize that they like all the effects of grinding.
Scott: Well, the thing is no one, they won't realize that they're grinding.
Scott: And if that cycle is in balance, because they'll be getting levels so often, they're like, Oh, you don't have to grind.
Scott: You only feel like you're grinding.
Scott: They know they're grinding, but you don't, it doesn't feel bad unless you, it either gets so hard, unless you go a long time without getting an upgrade or it gets too hard or it's too easy and pointless and you have to do it for a million years.
Rym: It doesn't feel like grinding, even though it is, but I've noticed that among the, you know, the so-called hardcore players they'll grind and they'll even talk about, ah, I had to cowboy, you know, I ground my way up to this.
Rym: I ground up a new character, grind, grind, grind, but they act like they don't like it.
Rym: And they express like, ah, it was a chore.
Rym: I had to grind, but I feel like it's this almost affected desire to show off that did the grind.
Rym: Like, look, I did it.
Rym: Look at me, the grizzled, tired man.
Rym: I stayed up all night and I achieved this.
Scott: I think what it might be actually is sort of a, while you're doing it, you get the good feelings from, you know, the cycle of reward.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But I think that afterwards, you know, when you, when you look at the, you know, you're all tired and the time you spent and what you actually got out of it, there's a, there's an amount of regret that comes out.
Rym: I don't think it's real regret though.
Rym: I think it's, or if it's real regret, it is covered up by the fact that people will say they don't like the grind.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Scott: is that, you know, they, they say they don't like it, but when they're doing it, they do like it, you know, but they don't, it's a question.
Scott: Do they actually like it or is it just, you know, the psychology of the brain tells you to like, I think with the grind, they don't like it while they're doing it.
Rym: And afterward they, they, they like the rewards and they like all the other things about it and they like the respect.
Scott: I mean, it seems like you get respect if you, well, it's like a mouse who doesn't like to push the button, but he likes eating the food.
Scott: So he pushes the button and gets the food and then says, I hate pushing this button, but he keeps pushing it to get more,
Rym: but I find it interesting that more and more, I feel like the game industry is marketing games saying that, look, here's a problem that we recognize with a genre that you also recognize.
Rym: we are going to lie and say that we fix it.
Rym: So then you will play the game and pretend that we fixed it.
Scott: A similar thing that they'll do, is they'll come up with something incredibly ambitious, some incredibly futuristic science fiction idea, you know, like we're going to make a virtual world that is effectively, and they'll describe like cyberspace, you know, from like Tron or something to be like, oh, it's going to be like cyberspace for reals.
Scott: And then what's the reality?
Scott: Is it second life?
Scott: It's nothing like cyberspace.
Scott: Is that even close?
Scott: You know, or they'll say, oh, we're going to make this like amazing role playing experience.
Scott: And what is it?
Scott: It's just like, you know, it's just a system that does D and D for you.
Scott: It's not a role playing experience whatsoever.
Scott: You were full of shit.
Scott: Or they'll say, oh, it's going to be like this great storytelling thing.
Scott: What is it really?
Scott: It's a, it's an RP.
Scott: It's a JRPG that has 10 endings.
Scott: Oh, or, oh, we're going to make this great system of, you know, morality, you know, what is it?
Scott: It's a one stat that either goes towards good or evil and everything in the game is black and white, you know, bioshock.
Scott: Oh yes.
Scott: This is a big morality thing.
Scott: What does one decision?
Scott: good or good or evil?
Scott: The end good or evil.
Scott: The end it's either murder the children or send them star Wars game, light side or dark side.
Scott: The end, right?
Scott: There's.
Scott: no, it's not really real morality going on there.
Scott: It's just good or bad.
Scott: It's just a decision.
Scott: Good or bad checkbox.
Scott: But they play it up like, oh man, big time role playing big time storytelling.
Rym: But it's, it's weird that people like I'm a play, the players recognize the problem.
Rym: The industry recognizes the problem.
Rym: The industry will say they solved the problem when in fact they didn't.
Rym: And the players will just agree with that, even though nothing changed.
Scott: Well, I think that the thing there is that we, uh, have, you know, some people are just unable to like, you know, analyze games the way we analyze them in our, you know, in the way we do, you know, looking at the fundamentals, tearing away all the surface level coverups, looking at the math, looking at the game theory of the thing.
Scott: So they don't recognize, you know, when they play an RTS and they can tell their guys to take cover and they have 10 different weapons to choose from.
Scott: That's just so cool.
Scott: There's the obvious strategy.
Scott: Look, look at, I got to choose the right weapon.
Scott: That's oh man.
Scott: And I can tell them to cover over here or cover over there.
Scott: I can tell them to run, you know, and they see that as, you know, strategy.
Scott: Whereas we realize actually all those things don't actually matter.
Scott: Only these parts actually matter.
Scott: All the rest is just fluff.
Scott: So when we, by being able to see through the fluff and the stuff that doesn't matter, we re you can see that nothing has changed.
Scott: Whereas other people who aren't able to see because they don't, you know, they haven't studied these things quite so intensely as we have, they, they believe it because, and I think actually the game, the people making games, I think that very few people in the video game industry actually study strategy and tactics and game theory or any of those sorts of things.
Scott: They don't even realize that they're, they say, our game is so strategic, right?
Scott: It's not.
Scott: Remember that guy at PAX, he showed you, uh, remember there was that game where you have the squad and you sort of click around.
Scott: What was that game called?
Rym: I forget, but it was, it was really fun until I realized that there were three colors and it was paper, rock, scissors.
Scott: I downloaded the demo on steam.
Scott: game was rock, paper, scissors.
Scott: That's all.
Scott: it was is, Oh my God, there's some red bad guys.
Scott: I better send my blue soldiers to fight them up.
Scott: There's some, you know, green bad guys.
Scott: I'll send my red soldiers to fight them.
Scott: And that whole game, that's all it was.
Scott: But you know, the guy at PAX, the guy who made the game from Australia was playing it up like it was like this big time strategic thing when it was no such thing.
Rym: I think it's more a psychological kind of complicity into this where, so, you know, I reckon people recognize the problem, but they also at the same time don't actually want it to change, but they think they want it to change.
Rym: So all you have to do is constantly tell people that you have changed things and made a different game and they'll continue to play it even if it's the same game.
Scott: That's very possibly.
Scott: If you just change enough surface level stuff to make it look different when it's fundamentally identical, people will believe is different.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I just, I feel like this trend is going to continue and I feel like I feel like we're seeing it more, but I can't be too sure about that because again, I could die.
Scott: Well, yeah, but I think the, another fun, a problem here is that we can see these problems and agree upon them, but the actual solutions that, you know, to these problems, the real solutions where we wouldn't be calling bullshit on them are require such advancements in, you know, incredibly, incredibly difficult fields.
Scott: Like, you know, we need pretty much like an actual AI, like a computer that is intelligent for reals.
Scott: You would need, you know, like a computer that could, you know, win it, go every time.
Scott: you would need something so ludicrous to make a lot of these things happen that it's just not gonna happen.
Scott: It's not, you know, it's not possible, or you need to make a game that would solve the problem, but it wouldn't be fun because it's, you know, psychological, you know, psychology wise, just people wouldn't enjoy playing it unless they were like us, which is barely anybody.
Rym: I guess I just find it really interesting that we have an industry that will point out flaws and offer false solutions and that works.
Scott: Yeah, that, that is quite interesting.
Scott: It's sort of like, you know, and it's, it's funny because the flaws they're pointing out, it's like in their own shit, right?
Scott: It's like saying, yeah, that RTS we made is crap, but this RTS we made fixes all that crap.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Why did you tell me your old thing was crap?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: We kind of rambled this whole episode and I'm kind of hungry.
Scott: Yeah, I'm very hungry.
Scott: Let's go.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our frapper map, and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights, and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an Odeo on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.