Scott:
Rym: Hey, it's Tuesday, November 24th.
Scott: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott over Skype, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We talked about ping and latency and I think bastards Let's do this That it feels like it's been forever since we did a Tuesday show.
Rym: cuz like.
Rym: Yeah, it has been forever.
Scott: since we did a Tuesday.
Rym: I've been playing Left 4 Dead 2 a whole bunch.
Rym: I don't think I've really talked about it.
Scott: on the show the last time we did a show it wasn't out yet.
Scott: I mean let me if I click to the archive and click on Tuesday.
Scott: Let's see the last one was November 10th So it's been 15 days.
Scott: wow it's a Tuesday show and a Tuesday show.
Scott: before that was October 6th So it was like a month between Tuesday shows In between the Castle Crashers show and the D&D online show.
Rym: lately has been practically impossible to do a show.
Rym: So we'll see how many we get out before the new year But we'll get out as many as we can.
Scott: these skype probably squirt out more poops than shoes.
Rym: Skyping days are definitely coming close to an end.
Rym: There's no worry about that punk kids.
Scott: Yeah, you know we'll see how that goes.
Rym: Hey, we'll see how that goes.
Scott: You know it's Thanksgiving so I'm gonna be all full not gonna be ready to do any podcasting.
Rym: Well, I said I'm talking like next year the skype is gonna end.
Rym: I'm talking like January.
Scott: you like it escape to end.
Scott: You're looking at you.
Rym: so I mean I for a while when I first we're gonna do the sky thing I was like you know what I could make Scott sound a lot better.
Rym: I could do some post-badass napping.
Rym: I haven't even changed the filters.
Scott: Well, you know it.
Scott: I got a slightly better microphone headset thing, but it's still.
Scott: It's very difficult to get you know something like that.
Scott: cuz even if I get like some awesome I've been.
Scott: I had a bajillion dollars, and I got a giant awesome Amplify preamp and microphone and everything and then I swear can I do?
Scott: I get?
Scott: I get an optical input into my sound card And then my sound card as you know sends it over the PCI Express bus into the computer And then it compresses it and sends it over the network hole over Skype.
Rym: Well if we were doing this super long-term, we'd probably just do the record on both sides thing.
Rym: But we're not.
Rym: this is you guys are lucky.
Rym: We're doing any shows at all.
Rym: It's been kind of crazy up here.
Scott: Yeah, between holidays moving more moving Jobbing left for dead Playing video games lots of left dead Live in.
Rym: there's not that much time for podcasting, but god damn is left for dead like We'll do a full review of it later.
Rym: But I mean left for dead - it is different enough from left for dead one that I do not in any way I feel bad about having to have paid for it.
Scott: Well.
Scott: No I Wasn't.
Scott: I never felt bad about paying for it.
Rym: Before I played it I was kind of worried that it was too soon to have a new game as opposed to just Updates or extra.
Scott: that's the thing that I was upset about.
Scott: right is I'm still upset about it.
Scott: Actually.
Scott: is that why did they make it a separate game?
Scott: what they could have done right is what did they add?
Scott: They added four new characters right.
Scott: they added five new campaigns and melee.
Scott: they added like a Lot of different new special undeads.
Scott: you got the the jockey the charger the spitter The.
Scott: is that it?
Rym: the director is pretty much completely different in terms of how it like.
Rym: The whole game mechanic is different.
Rym: the AI is bad, but like the actual zombie AI and all that stuff I think yeah, they also.
Scott: they have the semi-special zombies like in each level.
Scott: There's one kind of zombie.
Scott: That's not a special zombie, but it's not a normal zombie either.
Scott: It's sort of like the in-between zombie.
Scott: Yeah, like the one with armor or the one in a hazmat Has mad suit Right or the clown right.
Rym: um we had a man in a hazmat suit, but look what happens if we expose him to pay.
Scott: Anyway the The thing that bothered me wasn't that oh I don't want to pay for more left for dead because I knew it was gonna be just fine and worth the money.
Rym: well Me too.
Scott: Oh, they was that.
Scott: why didn't they add all that stuff to the original game?
Scott: because I want us.
Scott: I still want to be able to play the original left for dead with the melee weapons and the Special zombies, and I want to use the old characters on the new maps and the new characters and the old maps and the melee Weapons on both and the special zombies on both, but they didn't do that.
Scott: so now It's like if you play the old left for dead maps with the old characters You don't get no melee weapons you only get melee weapons on the new map.
Rym: See that's why because you know play.
Rym: I played left for dead one again after I'd played to a whole bunch to try to compare To figure out like what exactly is different when I'm playing and I realized that one Left for dead one really like the optimal strategy was basically for humans Clipping on top of each other walking as a unit with guns pointed in four directions
Scott: Yes, and what I'm saying is they could have sort of at the same time as putting out left for dead two.
Scott: they could have reinvigorated Left for dead one because if it had the special zombies and the melee weapons and all that business in the old game it that Game suddenly would have this.
Scott: it would have been improved, but why bother?
Rym: I mean really why bother?
Rym: why not?
Scott: It doesn't take that much work to do that.
Rym: It probably would have compared to how much money.
Rym: It's gonna make you I mean, it's still a business.
Rym: It's not like they can do this completely out of the goodness of their art.
Scott: They would have made the same amount of money either way.
Rym: No, it costs less to do what they did.
Rym: now There's no reason to do that.
Rym: plus I'm sure there will be either updates or expansions that maybe they'll even sell DLC like all of left 4 dead 1 with the left 4 dead 2 stuff.
Scott: I've noticed that valve.
Scott: you know they really like to just not charge.
Scott: You know they just all the updates on the PC are totally free, and they only you know give the shaft to the Xbox.
Scott: Yeah, yes three people plus I guess.
Rym: semantically I can kind of see like the difference between two and one Because the gameplay in effect is almost completely different.
Rym: I mean look at left 4 dead 1. you're like however characters like hunkered together.
Rym: the strategies are pretty solid like yes Because there aren't any special zombies.
Rym: No, it's not.
Rym: it's not just that it's that the the way hordes come in and the way zombies attack.
Rym: You can get away with splitting up the group a lot more even on the harder.
Scott: They could have added the better zombie AI to the old game too.
Rym: Yeah, but I'm saying because semantically not games not.
Rym: I'm saying that semantically like it's a different enough game and different of experience that it could warrant calling it a 2 instead of a 1. now whether or not they should have put that stuff back into left 4 dead 1 there's absolutely no economic reason to do so.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Scott: They should have done it.
Rym: Why?
Scott: Just because it would be so much more playing action going on now.
Rym: I think people because the thing is no one cares ever just playing left 4 dead 2 because it's great.
Rym: hardly anyone's playing left 4 Dead 1 anymore except the people who can't afford to.
Scott: yeah, but people would play left 4 dead 2 even more if they could.
Rym: You know if they took left 4 if they added all of the left 4 dead 1 stuff into 2 I could see that.
Rym: But there's no reason to have like if you had left 4 dead 1 they add stuff to it.
Scott: No, what I mean is not like that.
Scott: what it should have just been is you know Call it left 4 dead to call it whatever you want.
Scott: But there's only.
Scott: you only have one game in your steam list and you double-click on it And it has all the campaigns all the zombies all the characters all the maps all the everything in one game.
Scott: That's what I want.
Rym: Yeah, but it probably would have cost more to do that.
Rym: So I bother.
Rym: I mean the man.
Scott: How much more difficult is it to make a separate game on the exact same engine than to just take those Scott Scott?
Rym: You never think about this.
Rym: from the practical perspective.
Rym: It would cost more than zero dollars and they would not make more than zero dollars more money.
Rym: I don't think it makes a who would have bought and as to because of that that wouldn't have all that I mean who would have bought it that didn't already buy it.
Scott: because of that there were some people boycotting.
Scott: So I don't.
Rym: I don't think those people would have bought it.
Rym: Anyway, they were only boycotting because left 4 dead 2 came out too soon and they were.
Scott: they were boycotting for exactly what I'm telling you.
Scott: I wanted an expansion and not a sequel.
Rym: That's just cuz.
Rym: I didn't want to pay for a full game pretty much.
Scott: No, they were.
Scott: I would have paid the same price if it was an expansion, but you bought it.
Rym: you bought left 4 dead 2 So you're not about it.
Scott: I would have bought it no matter what it's still great.
Rym: Yeah, but Scott You're gonna buy it no matter what is the price or timing.
Rym: you're gonna buy it no matter what.
Rym: I highly highly doubt that there Was any abs at all?
Rym: No economic incentive whatsoever for them to have done what you wanted them to do.
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: I Disagree, I just think it's a business move.
Scott: The point is that you said originally Right that the reason that people were upset is because of timing or pricing and that is not why people are upset.
Scott: people are upset Because it was a you know separate thing and not an addition.
Scott: Jay would have been practically no effort to make it an addition.
Scott: It's the exact same engine I think.
Rym: one you underestimate the effort.
Rym: and two I mean look at the old maps like the.
Rym: the new AI wouldn't have worked well with the old map.
Rym: They would have to restructure everything.
Rym: I Don't I highly doubt it would have been a problem Alright, but they didn't do it and there was no reason to so they didn't.
Rym: Plus, I mean most of the people I see complaining online were complaining about the fact that why are they making a whole new game?
Rym: So soon?
Rym: because they didn't want to pay for a whole new game.
Rym: They didn't really dwell on any minutia.
Scott: But on that feeling they're gonna come out with left 4 dead 3 about a year from now.
Rym: Yeah, they proved that this is an economically viable.
Scott: Hopefully they will make left 4 dead 3 add-on.
Rym: Definitely not.
Rym: I would in fact I would bet you a large sum of money that if they're probably gonna follow the trend of Every X whatever just make a new left 4 dead game and I'll keep making them till they don't sell the new ones anymore.
Rym: so how would you like it right if you're playing counter-strike beta 7 and Then counter-strike beta 8 came out and then beta 7 disappeared because it was the new game?
Scott: Right and not only that but all of the maps in counter-strike beta 7 were gone forever and they're all new maps every single version.
Scott: and you can never play the old maps again because they were dead.
Rym: and They're all new weapons, but you can you just go play them.
Rym: you can just play them.
Rym: You just play them in left 4 dead 1 if you want to.
Scott: Yeah But that no one playing it anymore.
Scott: the server is all shut down because they're separate dedicated Servers and people stop playing it and the game just disappears.
Scott: So it's the same way that you can't play tribes 2 anymore.
Rym: So would you just not played counter-strike if that were the case?
Rym: Would you have probably?
Rym: Yes, so because all I was sick of dust I would have been great if every version of the beta they had all new maps.
Rym: Yeah, but you're still pining for Thunder only because it was actually that map was kind of broken.
Rym: I only pine for it because it existed for such a short span of time.
Rym: I never really got to play it.
Rym: Same with left for 10, but it's still there in left 4 dead 1.
Scott: Yeah, but that one's going away eventually you're not.
Scott: you can't get a versus game of left 4 dead 1 eventually You know, so if you feel like you want to go back to that multiplayer like the verses of left 4 dead is really Not like people get sick of the campaigns.
Rym: There's much more incentive to want entirely new campaigns all the time Plus I'm sure later on.
Rym: I mean think about the brilliance of valve.
Rym: You know.
Scott: now we have ten campaigns and you know.
Scott: So if you get bored of the five that are in the current version Sure, it's gonna be good.
Scott: when the next version comes out You're gonna get five more but maybe you'll get some more excitement.
Rym: You know a year from now if you could go back to the original You have to always think about everything a gaming industry does from the economic business perspective and what's gonna make more money if they keep Making new versions, you know, it's gonna make more money.
Scott: I'll tell you what's gonna make more money right think about it this Here's how it makes more money comes along right now, right and they they haven't bought either game, right?
Scott: They're gonna buy just left 4 dead 2. but yeah, if it was an expansion they would buy both games.
Scott: So they're actually selling less left 4 dead ones because left 4 dead 2 is not an expansion They've probably.
Rym: they're probably assuming they can just drop left 4 dead 1 at this point.
Scott: What's the economic incentive for that?
Rym: because it done.
Rym: why if you're not selling more copies of it There's no reason to keep the servers online unless you'll take off enough fans.
Scott: Servers are run by normal people not by them.
Scott: Remember it's dedicated servers.
Scott: It's not valve servers.
Rym: Actually initially valve host is a lot of the servers.
Scott: I've never seen a valve hosted server in my life.
Scott: Uh-huh, not since the one have I seen a company hosted server regardless.
Rym: They're not gonna do what you want.
Rym: They never will and they're probably gonna release.
Rym: In fact, they're probably at some point gonna start releasing DLC.
Rym: That is hey all the campaigns from left 4 dead 1 for 15 bucks and left 4 dead.
Scott: They wouldn't charge money for it.
Scott: They just do it for free.
Rym: Yeah, they charge money for it.
Scott: No, they've never charged money for any additional maps or anything on the PC.
Scott: They've given almost a hundred updates to Team Fortress 2 all of which have been free.
Scott: Yep for now Yeah, so they're never gonna charge for DLC on the PC on Steam.
Rym: I'll bet they will at some point.
Scott: I mean not for a valve product.
Rym: I'll bet at some point they will.
Rym: money is a powerful lure.
Scott: I do not see it happening.
Scott: All right anyway.
Scott: So let's talk about some other gaming news.
Scott: NS2 is actually gonna come out I guarantee it at this point because a map maker for NS2 came out.
Scott: They actually released it.
Scott: if you have pre-ordered NS2 either the deluxe version or the regular version You can go and download the NS map making.
Scott: the NS2 map making program that they you know.
Scott: I guess it's the beta of it.
Scott: I don't know if it's the.
Scott: it's not the final version But it's it's good enough to make maps and there's plenty of screenshots of maps people have made and video tutorials and all this stuff and you know what This It's.
Scott: it's a bit might be early to call this and also I personally don't have that much experience with game map making.
Scott: at least You know FPS game map making.
Scott: But I'm pretty confident to say that this is the greatest game map maker that has ever existed For two reasons.
Scott: number one It's usable like if you've ever tried to use like the original like the world craft Which is the half-life map making thing or if you've tried to use the unreal level editor, they are not easy They are a huge pain in the ass.
Scott: They are not fun.
Scott: They are not intuitive.
Scott: They're just a mess.
Scott: This is actually something that a normal human being can figure out how to use and make maps with and it's actually you know I my experience is with AutoCAD and I was able to just like sit at this and be like Oh I know exactly what half these buttons do and I only needed tutorial for the other half and I was just yep looked at it Drawing walls drawing good ground put textures on things.
Rym: well part of it is this is the whole situation where whenever you're trying to make something the best way to make a great product is to have some other idea in mind and just make the tools that are useful to make your real idea and the tools themselves will Usually be better than whatever your idea was.
Scott: Is that happens often?
Rym: and and part of it with this?
Rym: I mean, they're a small team.
Rym: They have to be efficient.
Rym: They basically made the editor do all the intelligent defaults for the for anything you wanted to do to make like a map For a FPS.
Rym: it does everything just exactly the default.
Rym: if you want it.
Rym: I mean, alright, I put a texture or something on the top.
Rym: It assumes it to ceiling makes it point and connect all the walls automatically.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: The other thing is that Apparently when you can't test this because you don't have the actual NS2 game yet You only have the map maker.
Scott: But apparently if you have the game and the map maker you can have them open at the same time and you can edit the map Right in the map editor and then it will be edited in the game in real time.
Scott: So, you know so it's not one of those situations like now where it's like you make a map you compile your render You go to the game you play you exit the game you render.
Scott: you.
Scott: could you know edit, right?
Scott: It's you edit the the map while you're in the game to get.
Scott: you can get it just right like immediately and oh my god I can't wait to see that in action because That'll be so sweet, you know you move to the left window.
Scott: you got two monitors.
Scott: one monitor you go in the game.
Scott: We're walking around.
Scott: you see that the hallways too short.
Scott: So you extend it a little bit, you know, you go.
Scott: Okay, the hallways long enough.
Scott: now the skulk doesn't you know, you're?
Scott: you get a skulk in there you see up.
Scott: I can see the skulk hiding but he's not completely concealed in the dark.
Scott: So you make the ceiling a little higher and now the skulk is concealed and you're like, okay That's a good, you know size cranny above the door.
Scott: You know that that's gonna make some pretty good maps right there.
Rym: I think I'm gonna focus right away on some sort of marine race.
Scott: You're working on your gorge race map, right?
Scott: You have a gorge.
Scott: he jumps and he makes it onto the platform.
Rym: Well, then clearly if he can make it it's way a little further away.
Scott: He did have the gorge jump again.
Rym: He Best part about gorge race is the fact that it takes like an hour for anyone to get past the first couple of rooms.
Scott: Well people have gotten kind of good at it now So they usually don't start fucking up to like room thing is even if you're good at it There's a thousand fuckheads preventing you from completing it.
Rym: Anyway, that is true.
Rym: I mean when there are 40 gorges trying to make the jump that you have to be exactly perfectly time for Doesn't matter how good you are 40 gorges bring you down with the knee that breaks pulls ten men down.
Scott: Yes, that is correct.
Scott: So yeah If you haven't already pre-ordered ns2 and there's something wrong with you go and pre-order it.
Scott: if you can even pre-order 95% of people apparently have pre-ordered the deluxe version But you can pre-order the non deluxe version for like 20 bucks and you'll get access to this map maker and the map maker Alone is worth a lot more than 20 bucks.
Scott: So sweet sweet deal right there.
Rym: So speaking of games you can pre-order.
Rym: Apparently within the beta for heroes of new earth.
Rym: you can Pre-order the game heroes of new earth.
Scott: I want to talk about a lot of I think a lot of betas do that You know, it's like hey, you're in the beta.
Scott: You must care about this game, please pre-order.
Rym: Yeah I just I needed a lame segue to get into that game because we got beta keys and some formats are talking about it.
Rym: I played dota a bit back in the day and basically here's a new work.
Rym: I have three ever.
Rym: When I was a kid, I'd work.
Rym: I have one and two as well.
Scott: I Don't know.
Scott: I never saw you had Warcraft 3 ever.
Rym: I Have a lot of games.
Rym: Anyway, anyway, dota was this mod and basically it was kind of like a tower defense But not really.
Rym: you control like one dude and you like run down a couple different areas and fight guys.
Rym: and it was kind of fun back in the day.
Rym: and It's one of those games kind of like a we always pine for like tribes 2 or doom 2 or like these certain old like gaming Experiences like ah if only games they were exactly like a weapons factory back in the day.
Rym: well, the people who play dota have been saying the same thing about dota that we've been saying about our games and The shit talking stuff and some people long story short are making the spiritual successor to dota called heroes of new earth.
Scott: There's actually a few games that are basically You know taking the same model of this, you know, pretty easy model.
Rym: I mean think it's basically everyone controls some sort of hero.
Rym: You have kind of World of Warcraft style fighting.
Scott: It's an RTS where you control one guy.
Rym: pretty much It's an RTS control one guy But it's also at both ends is basically gauntlet because you've got monster generators on both sides.
Scott: The first dota was released in 2003 when we were at RIT.
Scott: you never played it ever.
Rym: I played it.
Scott: When did you play it?
Scott: I tried it.
Rym: I didn't like it.
Scott: I Remember I don't believe you've ever played the original defense of the agents.
Rym: Have you ever played it?
Scott: I Saw my brother play it.
Scott: He was big on the Warcraft 3, but I never played.
Rym: I was never good at Warcraft 3 or 2 or 1 or Starcraft.
Scott: I was good.
Scott: I was never good at Warcraft.
Rym: I'm not even talking good on the like among good players.
Rym: I'm talking like I would get trounced by pretty much anyone If I try to place.
Scott: I could play Starcraft right and I open it up and I say new skirmish Which is just you know Basically a multiplayer game against the computer one-on-one against the AI on the basic map.
Scott: no matter which class race I pick, you know protoss zerg or Terran I die pretty much immediately.
Scott: There is nothing I have.
Scott: no I can play the single-player Starcraft and you know, eventually beat it, you know, that's weird.
Scott: It's like a single-player RTS, you know the campaign.
Scott: I can sort of eventually win any one of them if I just keep playing.
Scott: But the like actual multiplayer thing where two guys start blank, you know, and you just go I just die.
Scott: I can't do anything.
Rym: the game was that the RTS like that I was the best at was actually command and conquer and red alert.
Scott: I was slightly better at command and conquer but not by.
Rym: but even then my the only craft one I was.
Scott: I was okay.
Rym: My only strategy was basically most of the people I played against were the kind of people who would like try to build this whole Base,
Scott: so I just wanted to do I
Rym: would just wait a little bit and then just send tanks and tanks and tanks and tanks and just destroy all their shit And win.
Rym: and that was it.
Scott: That's my problem, right?
Scott: It's okay.
Scott: I either you know, I'm trying to.
Scott: I tried to build a base, right?
Scott: Well, the other guy sends units after me and I can't defend myself.
Scott: Okay, so this time I'm gonna defend myself.
Scott: So I build some guys and then I start building my base, but the tanks just keep coming.
Scott: They just keep coming and I'm like, how is he building so quickly?
Scott: It's like I built.
Scott: so I'm like, okay, I'm gonna build as quickly as I possibly can and I try just one resource collector.
Scott: I'll try to resource collectors.
Scott: I'll try three.
Scott: I'll try.
Rym: every reason.
Rym: bad idea.
Scott: One tank factory two tank factories one barracks two barracks three barracks.
Scott: I'll try every possible combination to get quicker building of units and None of them are anywhere even half as fast as the other thing is The AI.
Scott: the AI is faster than me and I'm like what.
Rym: I would say that maybe you're not clicking fast enough.
Scott: It's done.
Rym: Like maybe you don't.
Rym: you didn't memorize like exactly the timing of everything.
Rym: But I point out in advance Wars, which is turn-based.
Rym: You have the same problem.
Rym: You'll be like, yeah I got my two tanks Let's roll and I've already got like mega tanks on every city on the map.
Rym: and I'm like pick is so long Starcraft.
Scott: you can cue up the units.
Scott: You can be like build three of these and one of those and when that's done immediately start building this and I'll cue it All up.
Scott: and it's still not fast.
Scott: I'm like what.
Scott: I have no clue What is good?
Scott: I even watched like some Korean guys, you know videos on YouTube.
Scott: No clue.
Scott: What's going on?
Rym: it's completely Right, but I don't want to.
Rym: I don't want to really get into heroes the new earth because it's a beta and we played it a whole bunch.
Rym: I'm still playing it every now and then but Regardless of the game which is basically to sum it up.
Rym: I feel like they got all the wrong things, right?
Rym: It's like they're trying to be so true to the origin to dota That they're like bringing all these old bad game mechanics forward.
Rym: It's like they've forgotten what made games like that fun.
Rym: It'd be like if I was making a new FPS like Team Fortress 2 styling and I bet wanted to base it on like mega TF.
Rym: and What I took from mega TF was like bad graphics and broken controls.
Rym: I was like, that's what made it a good game.
Scott: yeah, I think the people in general they just don't when they're they're making games that are sequels or You know Homages or anything like.
Scott: if someone made an xcom now They wouldn't put less things in it than the original xcom had.
Scott: they would always add more.
Scott: It's like oh we got to add, you know more different weapons.
Scott: We got to add more different units or they boil it down.
Rym: They're like, what if we just make it an FPS?
Rym: Yeah, right.
Rym: Let me look at two examples Actraiser Actraiser one.
Rym: There was the pretty crappy side-scroller.
Rym: It wasn't that bad compared to other side-scrollers and the fun but kind of mindless town part But everyone kind of liked the town part and people were like wow Actraiser was really popular.
Rym: Let's make a sequel.
Rym: Oh, but we got to get rid of something.
Rym: Yeah, get rid of that town part.
Rym: No one liked that We wanted.
Scott: we wanted a game.
Scott: That was only the town.
Rym: Oh my god, imagine versus Actraiser with versus platforming - oh Man, I want that both.
Scott: Yeah versus Actraiser straight up, you know, but it's like when you make a Modern, you know remake of a game like you're gonna make a mule today, right?
Scott: Mule was pretty great and there was you know.
Scott: But you remove you don't add you remove the bad and you polish the good You don't add and you really have to consider what made the game good.
Rym: I mean the bidding mechanic in mule was really really good But the choosing land mechanic was really really really bad and it's not even like we can say Oh well like the kids or the amateurs or like the anime situation where When the fans who grew up in consuming the media are the ones making the media they like lose perspective Because Nintendo even is guilty of this.
Rym: Wario ware on the GameCube was like one of the greatest games ever.
Rym: It was crazy popular.
Rym: It was like.
Rym: People loved that game as a party game.
Rym: Yeah, but I'm not sure how many other people I see a lot of other people really liked it in the same way that a lot Of people like Mario Party like I think was a similar vibe, but then they're like, yeah, that game was really popular.
Rym: Let's take out all the parts that people actually like and put it all this bullshit that we thought they liked.
Rym: It's like they didn't have any clue why people like the original game.
Rym: Yeah Anyway, yeah, but that all that aside I mean dota either and it will HON.
Rym: you're there like it or don't?
Rym: is that kind of game?
Rym: But any of those kinds of games I have to I have to warn everyone out there regardless of any factor in the game itself a Game is shaped by and shapes the community of people who play it and every game has a different community.
Rym: I mean you look at Counter-Strike kids with their faggotry and you look at NS people, yeah, the NS people with their gorg cheese jumping.
Rym: Yeah, every community is different.
Rym: I've never in my entire life Run into a more shit-headed gaming community than that that is.
Rym: within the HON beta These people made Counter-Strike look like a paragon of ivory tower righteousness and politeness.
Rym: Yeah a Good fucking god.
Rym: I I've never been sworn at so much over a voice chat that barely worked ever.
Rym: Then in the fly time I played.
Scott: I think the problem the problem is is basically right is that this is a game that's you know five on five right.
Scott: and You know in NS Let's say someone on your team is stupid and they're an alien.
Scott: they don't spend their resources.
Scott: that hurts your team pretty bad But it doesn't completely ruin your team.
Scott: Completely right.
Scott: it's not ultra devastating in this game.
Scott: the dota and the dota's like games if it's five on five or even worse Like three on three or two on two.
Scott: if you're really good, right?
Scott: You can't.
Scott: there's nothing you can do to carry the team.
Scott: you need everyone on your team to be good.
Scott: So if one person sucks, right?
Scott: You basically lose no matter what you do.
Scott: It's kind of like Left 4 Dead Sort of yeah, so if they suck you're gonna kick them, right?
Scott: So noobs have a hard time getting into the game because anytime they try to join a game to get kicked All right, but it's goes so much worse than that.
Rym: I mean the first time I play another problem.
Rym: I was like, all right I've never played before.
Rym: So I joined a noob.
Rym: only it was like first timers noob only four on four.
Rym: So I join it the game starts I get sworn at and kicked within 30 seconds.
Rym: I because I Walk like basically I walked around a little bit and someone was like, oh my god He's not buying something something something.
Rym: and then they swore at me and then they kicked me.
Scott: Yep Also, I played a bunch of games against people I knew who were also noobs, right?
Scott: So I actually won a lot of games, you know.
Scott: and Then I tried to go find some noob games against internet people and I got kicked out of a game that I was too noobish for.
Scott: and then I found a server that was like noobs only but if they had a number there's like a score.
Scott: you have that Like rates how good you are.
Scott: and my score was kind of high because I had won a bunch of games against people even though They were against noobs, right?
Scott: so my score was like 1500 something and they were like Everyone at the title of the server or like the game was like 1400, you know or less.
Scott: So anyone who had a score higher than 1400 they automatically kicked them before they even started the game and I was like I joined 1500 but I'm like, dude, I'm a total noob.
Scott: Do not kick me, you know, and they So I was.
Rym: I was a noob.
Scott: But because they put so much value in this little ranking number that you have That's the whole problem The community like.
Rym: if they're so focused on these stats and like the win/loss ratios that people are just the shit.
Rym: Cockery knows no bounds.
Rym: YouTube comments are more civil.
Scott: I mean Blood Bowl has also has like a score right but the score in Blood Bowl is not a how good you are score It's a house.
Scott: It's like a how many points in your Warhammer army score, you know.
Scott: It's like I've got you know, super awesome players on my team.
Scott: So you don't want to play against me if your team isn't leveled up yet, you know, that's what that score is.
Scott: So that makes sense, you know.
Scott: and people could just start a new army whenever they want in blood war a new team.
Scott: So you could just if you want to play with people who have you know Leveled up guys.
Scott: You just make a new team every time you play and you'll always have a basic Football team with no levels or skills special crap or anything like that, you know, and some people do that They're like, hey, you know a thousand point army, you know teams only and that's all they do.
Scott: But other people level up their teams and they're like three thousand point teams, you know.
Scott: So whatever but doesn't it?
Rym: the community in that game is Almost enough to make it.
Rym: unless you play with friends like straight-up friends.
Rym: It is impossible to play.
Rym: don't even try.
Scott: Well, it's a closed beta.
Scott: so, you know There are other games in that you can get Warcraft 3 and then get the original dota.
Scott: I think there's also Some a mod like this for the dawn of war games.
Scott: I'm not sure.
Rym: and I find my Warcraft 3 and play it again that you don't have yeah, and then There's All the way back.
Rym: you just straight up like command-and-conquer.
Rym: Wanna play some versus command-and-conquer a DOS box.
Scott: I get we could but I have no skills.
Scott: that I was thinking maybe we should buy, you know, the What's it called the new red alert?
Scott: Yeah, like the new red alert game, but I played the demo of it and it was a fast clicking, you know.
Scott: Maybe we should.
Rym: you know, it's not.
Rym: you got a master turn-based strategy games before we move into the RTS is with you.
Scott: Maybe we should just play like, you know Starcraft just plain old Starcraft and I could just somehow Figure it the fuck out.
Rym: I pretty much just throw zerglings and if you can overcome my strategy Which is throw zerglings as fast as I can.
Rym: I got nothing.
Rym: That's all I do.
Rym: It's the same thing.
Rym: You know, what was that game?
Rym: Were you like you throw the bases from the bases and then like they're all connected by chains We play that.
Scott: Oh moon base commander that games actually really good because it's like scorched earth.
Rym: But the problem with that game was all I would do is there's a little like creeper mines.
Rym: I would basically just send them constantly because a lot of people couldn't deal with them because they couldn't aim their little shops.
Rym: So anyone who wasn't actually good at the game that would be.
Rym: That was my only strategy.
Rym: if you could defeat that that you could just like march over and destroy my base.
Rym: There's nothing I could do about it.
Rym: I couldn't hit anything.
Scott: Yeah, there's basically another game that's in this same genre But it's it's one of those games where it's free.
Scott: But if you pay money, you just get better guy you get better heroes for paying real money.
Scott: So it's not.
Scott: I don't think that's one you want to play now.
Scott: probably I forget what it's called though.
Rym: So if you want to play a game like this, I feel like yours of new earth is the best.
Rym: but That's like saying that World of Warcraft is the best MMO.
Rym: It is 100% true Okay But anyway things of the day.
Rym: do not watch my thing of the day.
Rym: if you have not yet seen the Ultimate sci-fi classic total recall with Arnold Schwarzenegger.
Rym: It is It is a great movie.
Scott: Instead you should get your ass to Mars.
Rym: Get your ass to Mars Start the reactor.
Rym: God that movie.
Rym: This is one of those videos of every blank from blank.
Rym: It's every death in total recall including those goldfish.
Rym: It is so great.
Rym: I and you know, I like this movie but it totally reeks of early 90s action movie gunfights.
Rym: a lot of people die a Lot more than I remembered dying.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know the movie is like.
Scott: it's actually separate from the action parts, you know It's it's.
Scott: you know You seem to remember like all the sort of highbrow sci-fi stuff that goes on in it because it's probably the highest brow Schwarzenegger sci-fi action movie there is.
Scott: But see you remember that because that's the part that really hits you emotionally.
Rym: forget when he's got the the movie.
Scott: It basically is discovered in action scenes and bullets flying everywhere.
Rym: He stabs that dude with that thing near the end right to the face Yep.
Rym: Yeah, and then that guy explodes.
Rym: It's good movie.
Rym: But if you've seen total recall, this is every death in total recall.
Rym: the movie is some minutes long In fact, it's almost four minutes long
Scott: Yep, so despite, you know The awesomeness that is like I don't know the mouse guard RPG and despite the awesomeness that is burning wheel It is still my opinion that the greatest role-playing Game book ever created is the second edition Monster Manual.
Rym: There's something beautiful about that book.
Rym: regardless
Scott: Regardless of you know the game second edition Dungeons and Dragons and what you might think about that game that Monster manual just as a work of art and a book on its own regardless, you know, even if you take all the gameplay mechanics out of it is Such an amazing book.
Scott: not only does have a ton of monsters in it one per page By the way, you'd learn a lesson.
Scott: third edition Monster Manuals and fourth edition Monster Manuals One monster per page.
Scott: an amazing really cool piece of fantasy artwork for each monster Right now not for some of the monsters all of the monsters every single one.
Rym: I also point out I just want to point out that a lot of the monsters were kind of risque in this weird way like I was thumbing through because I have my second had Monster Manual and like the level of detail it goes into as to like what kelpies do to you and Like some of those like weird plants and something there.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: There's some weird stuff going on in that book.
Rym: I gotta look up some of the people who wrote the actual text with the sheer number quantity the variety of the monsters and the you know, the the non Game related details about yeah, like all the ecology and everything.
Scott: It's like the most imaginative Like a bestiary I think to ever exist on the entire history of.
Scott: you know Fictional bestiary to ever exist, you know, and so it's such a great book, you know I I don't know why I don't have a copy of it.
Scott: I probably should get one.
Rym: I Daddy two copies.
Rym: I think I do have to actually because I have.
Rym: I have like one that was busted.
Rym: I've won this in slightly less bad condition.
Scott: I'll try to find like a really good condition one.
Rym: I also have the old binder with all the inserts.
Scott: I'm in sort of a. I don't like the binder.
Scott: I like the book Plus.
Scott: the binder is too many months.
Rym: Yeah, I realized all my second at D&D books will not fit in a single book box.
Rym: Now many book boxes stupid skills and powers and all that bullshit.
Scott: so some guy named Dan meth at least that's his name on Vimeo and it said yeah, he's He made a music video.
Scott: He made a song and an accompanying music video called monster manual, which is a You know, it's.
Scott: it's a send-up for this amazing book and the song.
Scott: honestly, I'm not a big fan of the song.
Scott: It's not the greatest song at musically speaking, but it's fun.
Scott: and it talks about the monster manual and they have cute artwork in the video and The lyrics are pretty good too because you know, he talks about how the monster can see in both, you know Aerial planes and he.
Scott: you know how the the beholder lives mostly underground and such-and-such.
Rym: I put it on the same level as that Super Mario RPG video.
Rym: We use way back in the day.
Scott: I don't remember that one.
Rym: You don't remember that one here in the forest.
Rym: It's very scary.
Rym: Okay, yeah that one I feel like it's on the same level of quality.
Scott: Let's see how much the monster manual is gonna find one on the Amazons or the eBay's.
Scott: I'm coming up with all the third and fourth edition ones.
Scott: Ah, I Got it.
Scott: I got to do some better searching.
Rym: So while all Scott's doing that the meta minute GeekNights is odd super bonus double secret probation hiatus for a while.
Rym: So we're doing shows whenever we feel like it and Scott's coming in over Skype and the studio over here is a mess as I'm slowly packing up the house to give it up and probably by January sometime GeekNights is gonna be back to normal scheduled normal audio quality normal everything.
Rym: and Actually, I think the show is going to improve in quality quite a bit because I'm gonna get an extra two hours of sleep every night.
Scott: Oh, this guy has a used like new copy on Amazon for $16.
Rym: that might be worth it.
Scott: Let's see.
Scott: Oh, there's new ones.
Scott: Oh from the new ones.
Scott: The cheapest new one is $34 and 18 cents.
Rym: You probably want the slightly used one.
Rym: as long as it does not like that Used ones.
Scott: you can get used ones for eight bucks.
Scott: used good condition seven dollars and eight.
Rym: Well, watch out I bought that used Prince of Nothing book.
Rym: And it said like pretty used what used good used very good used except it said like used acceptable something like that.
Rym: But it was perfectly fine Except that it smelled like fried fish.
Rym: Like really really really strongly of fried fish to the point that I eventually threw it away because it smelled so much like fried fish.
Rym: I didn't want it stinking up the rest of my books as it was funny.
Scott: There's plenty of used copies in Amazon.
Scott: I'm sure I'll.
Scott: maybe I could pick up a cup, you know, I'm in a no money spending mode So, I don't know if I should buy one now.
Scott: I don't really eat it.
Rym: meta.
Rym: a minute aside What else do we have in the meta shows gonna be back on track in January?
Rym: We don't have any contests going on.
Scott: Well, we don't have any contest but Scott really likes cornucopia.
Rym: is gonna spoil that right now.
Scott: Cornucopia is a totally awesome and it was a couple years ago that I said Hey everybody make some geeky cornucopias for Thanksgiving and I know it's the day before Thanksgiving and in fact you this will probably go You'll if you're.
Scott: you're probably not downloading this late at night unless you're a super fan.
Scott: So you're probably getting this on Thanksgiving or afterwards, but regardless If you make a geeky cornucopia, that would be totally awesome.
Scott: Send a picture a video.
Scott: you could just make a picture instead of actually making an actual cornucopia.
Scott: also, you know just Photoshop something and It would be totally awesome.
Scott: Nobody has even come close to the quality of the boo cornucopia, which is the best.
Scott: But yeah, yeah cornucopias are totally sweet.
Scott: I like them.
Scott: send me one I'll be happy.
Rym: Once again, we are in charge of panels for ConnectiCon.
Rym: there's going to be a lot more gaming content at ConnectiCon next summer And panel submissions are open for ConnectiCon.
Rym: so send us your panel ideas and the.
Scott: the current book club selection is The hitchhiker's guide to the galaxy by Douglas Adams.
Scott: Just the first book.
Rym: I'm surprised you paused that long and did you say Douglas?
Rym: Douglas, I don't think anyone gets that.
Rym: I think that's too.
Scott: I think that some of the listeners get Douglas.
Rym: Hi kids if you get that email us.
Rym: I'm curious.
Rym: I'm sure someone gets email us and explain why we say Douglas the way that we do That's not easily Google a bull.
Scott: So that's not Google Google.
Rym: So back in the day right long long time ago the day when I had quake one and A dial-up connection and then I switched to a cable modem.
Rym: So I have quake one and a cable modem and I had never played quake one online before Because previously with the dial-up I couldn't make that shit work.
Scott: You want you could dial your friend directly and play against each other.
Rym: I did that with doom - I did that with command and conquer.
Scott: I did it with like heretic and hexen.
Rym: actually I have kind of a funny anecdote about that because I used to also play a lot.
Rym: Where you could do this serialized thing?
Rym: We're like you connect to one person Locally with a serial cable and use the server thing and then you dial to someone else.
Rym: you could play with like three people.
Rym: But yeah, it barely worked, but a lot of the null modem cable.
Rym: I had a null modem cable and in fact we had two computers now.
Rym: so very often my brother and I would play either command and conquer or Doom against each other but we always had they gotta bring that option back where you can just take a USB cable connect two computers and Directly and then you know.
Scott: because right now because think about it, right if you have two laptops in a in like a Starbucks crossover cable people don't have a crossover cable What I do in fact, I carry one in my bag.
Rym: It's one foot long Everywhere with you.
Scott: Yeah, this is one foot long More than once all right, so even if you had the crossover cable and you connect the two laptops the network cards It's not trivial.
Scott: It doesn't just automatically go doodoo and just work you have to do Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Rym: Scott you think a null modem just fucking worked.
Scott: No, what I'm saying is if they made USB cables they would they could make it with a driver.
Scott: just work, you know for game.
Rym: anyway I've got command and conquer.
Rym: We always had to like take turns.
Rym: who use the 486 and who use the Pentium Pro?
Rym: so My brother was on the Pentium Pro Or the 486 and I'm on the Pentium Pro.
Rym: We're playing command and conquer and every now and then the Pentium Pro would screw up and like the mouse driver would just like go Whack and sometimes the 486 would too.
Rym: but in this case the 486 like while we're playing his mouse drivers went whack and the mouse is like going all over the place and he couldn't click on anything anymore in the middle of this game.
Rym: and He's like this command and conquer game sucks.
Rym: We got to stop.
Rym: I can't click on anything anymore, and I was like so I guess it's just Conquer She's there was no more command And he was like, yeah, whatever and then he turned off the game.
Rym: That was the end of that.
Rym: But I was playing quick one online For the first time ever and I found the IP address of a server On a website on a website and I connected to it and I ran around immediately.
Rym: Well, no, I ran around just fine But my guy kept like stuttering and staggering and then there was no good netcode back in the day.
Rym: So I clicked shoot to shoot a rocket and like two seconds later a rocket came out of my guy.
Scott: Man the first time I tried to play a game online.
Scott: See I didn't have a cable modem until I didn't have good internet That wasn't.
Scott: that was faster than 56k until I got to RIT.
Scott: I mean I had used faster internet at school But not in my house.
Scott: and it wasn't until after I'd been to college that my parents got some DSLs, you know.
Scott: But I did have my very own 56k modem on my very own phone line.
Scott: So the house, you know, the modem downstairs did not interfere with me before the cable modem.
Rym: We had two phone lines, but 336 modem That sucked.
Scott: Yeah, so I had my very own K-modem actually still have.
Scott: or did I give it to Scott Johnson?
Rym: I don't know if you gave if he wanted it or if you just put it in a box He was taking to his house, but I think he's got it.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: but that was my modem and I could.
Scott: I couldn't really play that many games online.
Scott: I could play Diablo 2 online because that didn't really Pretty much.
Scott: I tried to play half-life online and basically what would happen is you would I would start up and I would appear Right, and then I would just be standing still and I couldn't move at all.
Scott: Right, and I didn't realize what the hell was wrong.
Scott: I thought my thing was broken, you know Cuz Diablo 2 worked online for the 60 modem tribes to actually surprisingly worked with the 16 modem.
Rym: Surprisingly well, it was kind of like scary really good netcode.
Rym: But at RIT I realized oh is just because my you know, yeah you see you guys all forget We're like highly paid New York City computer professionals.
Rym: now there was a time my friends when we were Stupid because you see the Rockets came out of my quick guy like two seconds after I hit the button and everything was all stuttery.
Rym: So I went to the forum that I got the server IP address from and I was like what the F I'm trying to play online but the Rockets come out of me like two seconds after.
Rym: is something wrong with the server?
Rym: Why is it doing this?
Rym: And someone else responded they're like, yeah the same thing happens to me, but that happens on every server I play on.
Rym: I think you have to change something in your game.
Rym: and This thread goes on for a little while and then this guy posts and he basically says oh my fucking god Are you guys serious or you're just trolling?
Rym: And Long story short.
Rym: I learned about the word ping and then I used Alta Vista and I learned about latency And I learned about hops and I learned about IPs and I learned
Scott: that ping
Rym: Sucked and I decided
Scott: that
Rym: I would never ever in my life accept a ping greater than a hundred.
Rym: Yeah, I mean basically Ping greater than one.
Rym: you had fucking problems with quake one.
Rym: that netcode was useless.
Scott: Yeah, I mean for those of you who are not familiar with the technical details, right and many people are not.
Scott: you know Is that when it comes to internet speed?
Scott: Right, there are actually two different factors.
Scott: You have to worry about.
Scott: there is bandwidth and latency.
Scott: right.
Scott: bandwidth is how fast you know How much data can you get in a unit of time?
Scott: So if you have a bandwidth of five megabits per second, you can download 10 megabits of data in two seconds, right?
Scott: It's simple math.
Scott: Latency is the time it takes for a packet to go all the way from your computer to the destination And for the response to come all the way back, right?
Scott: So let's say I'm gonna.
Scott: I want to download 10 megabits from Rym, right?
Scott: I send him a message like, you know It goes all the way across the internet to his computer and says give Scott the 10 megabit file.
Scott: Then he sends over the 10 megabit file And as soon as the you know from the time the 10 megabit file the beginning of it touches my computer It'll come in really fast because I have lots of bandwidth, you know.
Rym: I hope that to most people are rolling their eyes at this.
Rym: I really hope
Scott: I hope but That message the amount of time it might take to get to Rym and for the file You know for the front of the file to get all the way back to me could actually be a really long time So it actually won't start downloading for like a second.
Rym: Maybe now here's an interesting thing I realize.
Rym: now, you know, I went I keep by the time I went to RIT I already had a pretty wide knowledge of computing and like network stuff and Almost all of that came from trying to play games.
Rym: I mean all I learned about IPS and something
Scott: pretty much everything I know about computers and trying to make games work
Rym: on old DOS PCs yep, and even in Windows like IP addresses and networking and connecting to servers and like a latency and hops and packet loss and
Scott: the desire to play a game Motivates the gate the PC gamer to learn about how computers work.
Rym: and I think I'm gonna say Motivated because you really don't have to know a lot of that stuff anymore.
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Scott: Is that now with console gaming and PC gaming that quote just works.
Scott: There is a lot less things to motivate kids, you know, who are gamers to learn how computers.
Rym: I'm not saying it's a bad thing.
Rym: I do not want to go back to those days.
Rym: those days sucked But no, but as a kid think about it.
Rym: I was just a kid.
Rym: I wanted to play quake After about a week of learning all this stuff to try to figure out why my rockets came out two seconds after I fired.
Rym: I Was like doing trace routes to count how many hops it was to servers and I decided to only play on servers that were less Than three hops from my house.
Rym: and like I compiled this list of like good servers I posted to my local forums and got like communities together.
Rym: I learned all I learned so much networking.
Rym: It was crazy and it mattered a lot more.
Rym: back then like nowadays Like I can play NS with like a ping between 70 and about 200 with no serious issue.
Rym: Back then like the ping just killed you like you couldn't even play.
Scott: Yeah, cuz think about it, right if the ping is milliseconds, right?
Scott: Which is one thousandth of a second, right and you don't think that's that's very long at all But it's actually forever in computing time, right?
Scott: So if you're paying is 200 milliseconds, that means that you know Let's see one fifth of every second right is basically lost.
Scott: you're playing at a delay So you see someone else move.
Scott: they're actually like way behind where you thought, you know or ahead of where you thought they were.
Rym: You know, they're not where you see them because now it's a delay and it gets even worse.
Rym: I mean thing.
Scott: and if it's like if it's a slow paced game like a turn like chess that doesn't mean anything.
Scott: It just means you their move will show up, you know, not noticeably later.
Scott: But if it's a real-time game, like if it's a shooting game It's a fast game really fast.
Rym: So a slight delay makes a big big difference and I mean old games didn't handle it very gracefully.
Rym: I mean think about all the how complicated would be to handle it gracefully.
Rym: ten different people on the server.
Rym: They all have different ping times.
Rym: Do you just make the server like where does it?
Rym: where does this computer show me?
Rym: Where you are if my ping is 180 and your pings 400 because you're reacting to things Later than I'm reacting to the same events?
Scott: Yeah, if I shoot into the middle of nowhere on my screen I shot into the middle of nowhere, but maybe by the time that bullet information gets to the server Someone else is standing there now.
Scott: So does it kill them?
Scott: or because on my screen no one was there?
Scott: Does it not kill them nowadays?
Rym: Are very good at being predictive and just kind of handling that well I mean back in the day like in quake 1 and quake 2 and all those games and even RTS.
Rym: is You like?
Rym: it was weird how sometimes people would be mad at the high ping bastards.
Rym: You know, oh you high ping bastards.
Rym: You always disappear around corners.
Rym: You're all jaggy because some netcode Basically gave high pingers kind of an advantage in a boy also.
Scott: Well, they would complain about high ping bastards because if you had a 56 game modem and someone else had a cable modem They were playing the game on basically almost no delay for the server.
Scott: So it was a smooth experience for them.
Scott: Thus it was pretty easy for them to actually play effectively and you were playing a shaky jaggy game.
Scott: So a high ping bastard was like damn you the game is actually working for you.
Scott: I can't play for shit.
Scott: It's all jaggy Alright, but a low ping bastard.
Scott: you see if you had the low ping Sometimes it was an advantage because even though the game sucked for you.
Rym: Well, you always wanted the low ping.
Scott: I Mean, yeah.
Rym: Yeah, but some games give an advantage to my pig.
Scott: right if you had the high ping then everything was all shaky and jaggy and You couldn't.
Scott: you know?
Scott: It's so you could play.
Rym: you could pull tricks in some games like getting around people because they just couldn't shoot you you were jumping On the screen so much.
Scott: Yeah, but in like Halo, I know that people like my cable modem.
Scott: now This is the first game modem.
Scott: I've had that actually has this.
Scott: there's a button on it.
Scott: It's the hold button.
Scott: It basically turns off the internet when you hold the button down.
Scott: I don't know who decided to put those buttons on cable modems, but they're there and Apparently there are people who would like put their foot on this button Right next to their TV playing halo on the Xbox and they would tap the button to sort of lag themselves out a little bit When they were gonna die and it would mean that they wouldn't get hit.
Scott: It was like this they could cheat with it, you know by adjust by basically turning off the internet for a second.
Rym: Awesome I used to shoot like that at the realm because if I was about to die in combat before they fix that I would totally just pull my network cable out.
Scott: Oh And it logged you out instead of dying.
Rym: Yeah, good because I didn't want to.
Scott: you know, I'm even in the middle of a fight.
Rym: Do you know how much fucking experience you lost.
Rym: if you died and if you lost an item well shit That's 80 hours of your life gone.
Scott: Why did you waste 80 hours of your life?
Rym: I was stupid.
Rym: that was back when I played MMOs.
Rym: a lot Mmo a lot the only em of the first MMO.
Scott: Well the first 3d mmm.
Rym: Nope the first graphical MMO It was 3d.
Rym: Nah kinda kinda anyway All right, yeah, so so where were you going with this?
Rym: cuz you're mixing mixing up high ping and low ping quite a bit.
Scott: I was low paying is the guys who were the playing is nice and high ping is the guys where everything is slow and she.
Scott: Sometimes you hate the low guys because they're they're getting good games and sometimes they hate the high guys because Their game is all shaky and it's making it hard to hit them and they're basically cheating.
Rym: Well nowadays, I really not only do I only hate the high guys just cuz I don't want to deal with them But I've been spoiled my whole life.
Rym: I mean even in the quake one days once I learned network stuff I played on bunnies server, which was 26 ping 26 about and that's pretty good for you know, the quake one era on a cable modem And then I got to RIT Where I would have single digit pings to a lot of those servers on campus.
Scott: Well, first of all We were playing in a lot of servers that were on the RIT campus and second of all Even when we played on servers that weren't on the RIT campus, we had an OC 3 connection.
Scott: Basically, the ping was never above 10. if the ping was above 10.
Scott: I wouldn't play on that server.
Rym: Yeah But it's weird.
Rym: I got so spoiled by that That I actually have a little bit of trouble now playing a game like NS outside of RIT because my ping will be like 50 or 60 and I don't know if it's just psychological but I can kind of feel it like Like I'll play and I like I'll keep missing like what the fuck's going on.
Rym: and I look at the ping is like WTF but there's not enough NS servers.
Rym: I look at that's like the best ping and server from here.
Scott: You know, I mean that's the thing is in beacon.
Scott: the pings were actually, you know I've when I first got to beacon with the cable modem.
Scott: I was sort of like This isn't good, but actually beacon the internet we have there.
Scott: The cable vision is pretty good.
Scott: The the pings are not too high.
Scott: you can play on NS servers like a ping of 30 ping of 40 You know, you can.
Scott: you can get a good game on over there.
Scott: It's not RIT.
Scott: It's not college, but it's good Here with the Time Warner.
Scott: I mean I had I was having some problems and I tried to play Left 4 Dead 2 and I was like what the hell Is this.
Scott: but I solved those problems.
Scott: They were not what I thought they were but regardless of that I mean I have it working now.
Scott: It's not unplayable like it was when I had the problems But the pings are still ludicrously high.
Scott: I mean, I'm surprised that Left 4 Dead 2 is so playable with like a ping of a hundred something It's actually it works Like I'm not noticing.
Scott: the ping is too high but it is too high and I can't really get a lower one without like running the server myself or something like that because I Think it's really bad on this internet connection to this day.
Rym: I mean we were at RIT and it was just like that.
Rym: the infrastructure and the internet is so important to my life like the internet is Possibly the most important like utility in my life after electricity because I can buy water.
Rym: You can't shower and water you can buy it off I can put it in a tank buy bottles of it.
Rym: But like the internet is just like the kind of life I lead without the internet I'd lead a completely different life.
Rym: and Yet the internet at RIT was so many orders of magnitude more reliable and faster and stronger.
Scott: It's even faster now.
Scott: who knows what they've done to it.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: I just can't even imagine.
Scott: Maybe they've got three OC3s.
Rym: Daddy.
Scott: They got an OC48.
Rym: Maybe they daddy to OC3.
Scott: Well, yeah, RIT to OC3.
Rym: Yeah Well, we had that one on internet to where half the game servers were too, which was even better.
Rym: That was like our private internet.
Scott: It was nothing but pirated software and games and it automatically routed you over internet to whenever possible.
Scott: You didn't even have to know about it or do anything So it just worked.
Rym: but it's so hard to leave that environment and this is why I still feel that Someday, we would we could be able to make like a geeky apartment complex.
Rym: We're like everyone together gets an OC3 and it's basically only nerds live there who care about nerdy things.
Rym: And it's somehow we can get an internet to also If we make it an educational institution of some kind and pay whatever we got to pay.
Scott: That's fine by me.
Rym: I'd be willing to give up internet - I just want a ping of one like I used to have.
Scott: I want a ping of negative one like I used to have.
Scott: Basically it was really a ping of zero because I would you know The server was right next to me on a stupid fast network But it was so fast that that the old FPS is didn't know what to do.
Scott: So they calculated is negative one then.
Rym: I mean it's such a different world though Like like my work now my non gaming life my working day job life, right?
Rym: We worry about latency to the point that calculating the speed of Electrons based on the physical distance between data centers We use that as a benchmark for the lowest like cutting your ethernet cable shorter and like it's the minimum length just to you Know.
Rym: basically we use that measure as a kind of objective measure of.
Rym: this is the floor of latency We can get between these two sites and then we get real close to that latency that we measure based on the speed of electrons.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know, it's it's actually latency is not just.
Scott: you know I don't want to get techie on the game day.
Scott: But you know, it's an issue for a lot of things like Synchronizing clocks and synchronize, you know, it's.
Scott: and the thing is right is a lot of people nowadays they're coming with internet connections like like on your phone and you know the for the you know, the F dues on your laptop like the little cards and things and Those internet connections on your phone and such.
Scott: they have a lot of bandwidth, but the latency on those is horrible Absolutely the worst.
Scott: if you try to play like counter-strike on with your cell phone Your ping is gonna be like a thousand.
Scott: so people are tell you know acting like the future is gonna be all this wireless Internet but really that wireless internet.
Scott: even if the bandwidth goes way up and we get the coverage and we fix a lot of the Problems of the congestion and all that the pings are still so high that a lot of internet Applications are just not going to work with that kind of latency.
Scott: You can't play games with that kind of latency no matter what the bandwidth is.
Scott: You can't synchronize clocks with that kind of latency.
Rym: No Well, actually you can.
Rym: synchronizing clocks even with high latency is really easy so long as the latency is symmetric Asymmetric.
Scott: as the thing is the latency is constantly changing.
Rym: It can change as much as it wants as long as it's symmetric for given sets of routes on average then it works.
Scott: See like the way the phones do it I think is they just keep
Rym: updating you
Scott: and like the clock isn't actually synchronizing with a proper NTP It's just sort of updating the time on it, you know to the minute
Rym: Actually, I've been looking more and more into PTP the precision time protocol.
Scott: Oh Very interesting anyway, but yeah gaming wise it's sort of like we're moving to this future of netbooks with you know Build connecting to the cell phone network, you know, Google Chrome OS, whatever.
Scott: This is really really gonna hurt gaming.
Rym: Well, it's only going to hurt real-time gaming where reactions matter.
Rym: I mean, that's true.
Rym: a lot of gaming does not require that.
Rym: sieve for does not require that.
Rym: even a lot of RTS's don't require that because you don't need to.
Rym: the game reacts slower than you're clicking.
Rym: All the clicking is is the command interface, but the game itself is following those commands on the server.
Rym: So even if you have high latency all that means that you're reacting more slowly.
Rym: but if you don't have to worry so much about Like who can see what and when the server just handles that and also predictive stuff is really really made this a lot less of an issue than it used to be.
Scott: yeah, but if you look at like You know even Wi-Fi just regular old Wi-Fi adds a significant amount to your ping.
Scott: and you know People are like getting their Xboxes and Wiis, you know, they don't have internet near wired internet near the TV most people.
Scott: So they're getting those on the Wi-Fi and latency not so good, you know when you do that I mean, it's playable, but it's it's not great.
Rym: Yep, but the netcode is kind of covered it.
Rym: But I think we're getting to the point to where netcode will not be able to cover it up any further than it already has.
Rym: I mean we've gotten to the point where for a lot of games a hundred ping is manageable.
Rym: I mean back in the quake one days hundred ping was on fucking playable.
Rym: You just might as well not even bother.
Scott: It's also gotten to the point where people are just like, you know games are just automatically matching you up.
Scott: They're not even letting you showing you the list of servers or the fact that there is even a ping at all You know, which is somewhat annoying to me because like I want to see and pick the low ping server.
Scott: But on the other hand, I think it's you know, if you just hide it from most people They're not gonna know the difference.
Rym: Yeah, it's tricky.
Rym: I mean I still feel that having like the dedicated servers there and you look at the list of servers is a better way to foster a Long-term community, but at the same time a lot of the people playing don't want community and that would just confuse them.
Scott: Yeah, I think I think it what it needs to be is an option like in Left 4 Dead 2.
Scott: It's not an option, but they should have it there.
Scott: Just put it in a hidden menu for the cool people
Rym: Yeah, but even I mean I guess my advice to all you punk kids is learn a little bit about networking in the very least learn how to trace route and Count how many hops and figure out how to turn on the net graphs in like half-life so you can see.
Rym: I mean if you're Getting choppy gameplay a lot of people will say or complain like I did back in the day.
Rym: Why is my game so choppy?
Rym: I got a great video card.
Rym: Check your ping check your packet loss check all that stuff.
Scott: You might know if the game is not choppy and single-player and it is choppy and multiplayer.
Rym: Well Well most likely you might have a weird bug, but it might be.
Rym: I guess This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website if you like what you hear.
Rym: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives Visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: as long as you give us credit Don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.