Rym: It's Wednesday, January 7th.
Scott: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights tonight, K.O.
Rym: Century Beast!
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So at work We kind of through various means ended up acquiring like basically the whole floor that we're on in the building.
Scott: Did you have most of the floor ready?
Rym: We had a lot of it But now we've got like enough of it to where we're gonna do major construction and because we the whole thing about our office That's cool is that all the walls are glass and there are some people or groups that have I guess separate rooms because you know Various reasons we don't want the thing to be one giant room.
Rym: So we've got glass walls everywhere just to make it still feel open and everyone can kind of see everyone and talk to everyone.
Rym: And we have video Conferencing running all the time between all the different offices conference rooms and things and even around the world like every office We've got has 24/7 video conference with like the conference rooms and all the other offices.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: It's actually really cool, but Now that we've got all this new space that old companies were in we're going all out.
Rym: So we're like knocking down all the walls between all the spaces and replacing it with these other companies have like big offices or what?
Rym: Well between all of them we got a lot of space.
Rym: So, you know we got to knock down all the walls and basically they built the new space completely based on all our new designs And everything and now they moved a bunch of people in there And now they got to move people out of the second space that we got a long time ago Into the first space so that we can move people.
Rym: basically we're shuffling all around and my department which is only four people Anyway, that's how badass we are got Put into one of the old conference rooms near where we used to be.
Rym: So now I effectively have a corner office, but it's on the wrong corner of the building.
Rym: So I basically get to look at the back of Pershing Square and like 41st Street.
Scott: Yeah, hey like those there's a lot of like windows depending on which side of the building you're on.
Scott: You could be looking at like an alley or you could be looking at like the water.
Rym: It's like well like some streets.
Rym: to like 42nd Street is like a main street.
Rym: So if you go to a 33rd Street or 41st Street It's mostly like the backs of big buildings as opposed to the fronts of smaller buildings.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Yep Yep, so it's all like loading docks here working in a conference room.
Rym: Well, we turn the conference room into our office.
Scott: You brought desks in there.
Rym: actually, you know, we got desk.
Scott: or did you just have?
Scott: are you just sitting around one big table?
Rym: You know how we got desks.
Rym: hmm because so many, you know, the economy's bad.
Rym: So a lot of other companies aren't doing really well.
Scott: You just took them from the companies moved out the office.
Rym: the building basically said look we own all this stuff down We don't want it.
Rym: So anyone who wants it take it.
Rym: So we took it all and we're yeah Why not?
Scott: the worst is you can sell it.
Rym: So I got this brand new desk and the four of us have this like corner office and we're private from everyone.
Rym: but the problem what I was worried about?
Rym: they moved while I was on break and That room Woman space is one cold mother.
Rym: That room was so cold.
Rym: Like it just it was in a freezing room.
Rym: So we got boiler heat on the windows that we turn all the way up and it's bearable.
Rym: But the only reason it's bearable is not because the room is a comfortable temperature But because the air conditioning from the ceiling is fighting to grim death with the boiler heat from the windows.
Scott: Why is there air conditioning?
Scott: that's on.
Rym: there's no way to turn it off.
Rym: Really It's an old building now old.
Rym: the Lincoln building is.
Scott: yeah, but I mean usually each floor has like control.
Rym: Yes, so we could turn it off thus ruining the entire rest of the floor, which is also all ours and making it too hot.
Scott: You know, that's how it is.
Rym: No, so basically we've got this kind of like having to humidifier and a dehumidifier fighting.
Rym: Wow, so as a result, there's like this constant whirlwind in the room.
Scott: It's better than our office Of a floor but there's one in control for the whole office, right?
Scott: But basically it's a blower into a vent and then you can either get heat or cold out of this vent, right?
Scott: But it's a long event with many openings.
Scott: It's like the end of the vent doesn't get blown out very much But the beginning of the vent gets a lot of pressure right because it's one long vent.
Scott: So if you sit like the way end of the vent the temperature is totally different than if you sit at the way beginning of The vent.
Rym: well, it didn't help that the one of the people in HR didn't like the fact that the vent in their office Which is also being renovated basically points at them from the ceiling.
Scott: Yeah, I hate that too.
Scott: That's it's like you put a desk with a vent blowing at it.
Scott: That's the worst because even if the air conditioner is set just right that person is wicked cold.
Rym: Not only that but the contacts dry out apparently.
Scott: Yeah that too.
Rym: So she just put a piece of cardboard over it, but that increased the pressure on the rest of the floor.
Rym: We're not allowed to do that.
Rym: Yes Let's because I have Two and a half computers under my desk, which are all kind of high-powered.
Rym: They're being space heaters and because I'm up against the boiler heat My desk is basically a kotatsu.
Rym: It's kind of awesome.
Scott: Like I should go buy a kotatsu and bring it over everyone.
Rym: But I kind of get like way under my desk in this giant leather chair that I also purloined from failed company.
Scott: I don't like leather chairs.
Scott: It's not a fan neither.
Rym: Do I but leathers chair?
Scott: I guess if I had a leather freedom chair, you know as the material be okay.
Scott: But I'm leather chair like the big cushy executive chairs.
Scott: They suck They look impressive, but they don't Better than really cheap office chair.
Scott: That is true.
Rym: So that's what I got rocking.
Rym: I basically my desk is a kotatsu.
Rym: I keep the Linux box that I don't use on.
Scott: apparently.
Scott: Did you see there's no law about like the temperature of a workplace?
Scott: So there's a guy who's got like a pizza place and he's keeping it really easily.
Scott: turn the heat off Because the employees forgot to turn the heat off one night and so now there's just no heat for the employees and it's freezing cold.
Scott: awesome, yeah, but you know, so It's weird because you go to an office and everyone's always fighting over the temperature in most offices, but there's no law.
Scott: They the boss could just say we're turning the heat off tough shit or we're turning the heat all the way up We're gonna melt you all fuckers like in the summer.
Scott: The boss could just turn the heat on.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Scott: Nothing you can do about it.
Rym: Well, I remember a long time ago with the AC.
Rym: we don't have anything important in the building obviously But the AC the supplementary AC to our tiny little like backup server room went out.
Rym: So we just opened the door and it was fine.
Scott: Yeah, usually is of course then you're you know, negating the security of the door.
Rym: Well the door I can see because the walls are all glass.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Yeah Anyway, so check this out right check in.
Scott: All right, so I go to work this morning, right?
Scott: And first I scrape off my car with the ice.
Rym: Oh my god There was like a centimeter and a half of ice on my car.
Rym: I was I. basically I body slammed my door to knock enough ice off to open it.
Scott: Yeah, that wasn't really wasn't necessary.
Rym: But I get up hours before you and I body slam was the only way into my car.
Rym: I guess Bellybuster would have done it.
Scott: I go to the choo-choo.
Scott: I get on the choo-choo I'm listening to something and sort of nap in a little bit, right?
Scott: And I wake up to get off the choo-choo and you're still not at work.
Scott: No, I'm starting to collect my things, you know and My head is not there.
Rym: Did someone steal the head off your head?
Scott: I don't know if they took it from my head, but I I didn't even get off the train.
Scott: I know I had it on the train for sure because there's no way I would have made it from my car to the train Without Realizing I would have died just without realizing my winter hat was not covering my ears.
Rym: It's too cold.
Rym: You just wouldn't have made it.
Scott: Oh, I wouldn't I wouldn't wreck.
Scott: I would have known that I wasn't wearing it.
Rym: Oh my god I almost didn't make it to the platform today.
Rym: I was running late anyway, cuz I had to body slam my car open and you fell down.
Rym: I didn't fall down.
Rym: I didn't fall down once but I almost fell down like 15 times.
Rym: So and I have the worst thing is I get to the platform.
Rym: This guy's like watch the ice.
Rym: I'm like, whatever.
Rym: Okay And I refuse to slow down because that guy warned me and it was like dignity time.
Rym: I don't need your warning.
Scott: Yeah, I wore my boots today said I'm a problem.
Scott: But I was.
Scott: you know, I looked under the.
Scott: I looked above the seat.
Scott: I looked in the adjacent seats.
Scott: I looked above below around everywhere on the whole car and you know, the doors are gonna close and my hat was not there.
Scott: Someone must have taken it either from me or from my.
Scott: I don't know where they took it But it's it wasn't there.
Scott: So someone took it.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I'm I'm leery of thinking that someone stole.
Scott: I don't know they stole it, but they might have taken it.
Rym: But why?
Scott: maybe it was like attached to them.
Scott: I mean it is wool.
Scott: It could have been a static cling deal.
Rym: What so some like fat lady gets to work and she's got like four people's hats stuck to her gigantic gargantuan body.
Rym: I mean why?
Scott: oh maybe you know It was just on the seat next to me and someone you know sat on it and maybe it got into their bag somehow.
Scott: How could that possibly have the same way that a bundle of wires gets tied up and knots on its own?
Rym: You put yeah, we've identified that first hand.
Rym: You know, we're gonna make a YouTube video of just a webcam of like Christmas lights in the closet.
Scott: Yeah, just roll them up real nice.
Scott: Put them in the closet put a camera on there and just watch them.
Scott: time, you know, do a stop-motion time-lapse.
Rym: I think the real issue is you have more than one kind of cable together.
Rym: Like I had a bunch of like pay-to-cables and a bunch of like USB and shit together.
Rym: But I put one of my old scuzzy cables in there and like the next day those cables were done.
Scott: That sucks They're still tangled anyway.
Scott: So my hats gone.
Rym: Well, do you have another hat?
Scott: Yeah, but it kind of sucks.
Scott: That's why I bought that newer one.
Rym: You wanna I got a backup hat.
Rym: It's terrible.
Rym: No, it's my backup ski hat.
Scott: I think Dollar, I think if the if the Giants wins on Sunday, maybe I'll buy a Giants head.
Rym: Giants head Why not?
Rym: I don't know Sam.
Rym: by some anime head by like a Gurren Lagann kind of head It's not gonna have with ears coming out of it.
Rym: I can maybe a big square print of a character's face.
Scott: So also right You know work we did the secret Santa thing All right, and I bought chocolate because I decided I was you got to do something clever like when I worked at IBM.
Scott: No one did anything clever because everyone clever was laid off.
Rym: Remember at IBM when I basically had a package full of liquor bottles But when they opened it all the liquor bottles were empty other than water and there was actually a bunch of anime DVDs in there.
Rym: Well, I just mean or the Unix an who gave a copy of the Star Wars Christmas special.
Scott: That's a good game.
Scott: But no so Someone got me a typical Best Buy gift card, right?
Scott: So I'm just like ah fuck, right?
Scott: What am I supposed to buy with this?
Scott: So I went to the Best Buy website and just sort of loached for like.
Scott: the first thing to buy and I bought this.
Scott: there was a DS game for learning Japanese and the thing was the only one.
Rym: So that's what that game was you opened yesterday.
Scott: So is it's like my Japanese coach is actually made by Ubisoft, which is a real game currently.
Scott: Yeah Well, it's published by Ubisoft.
Scott: It's made by Scanning something something.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: So I tried it out and It's terrible, it's good and bad at the same time.
Rym: not learning Japanese.
Scott: I'm learning more than none.
Rym: Can you say You are shocked?
Rym: Can you say my name is Scott Boku?
Scott: I don't have to say name Boku.
Rym: No, not my Something.
Scott: so yeah.
Rym: No, but mostly say like Boku.
Scott: Ah, I guess yeah, I know it taught me why and it didn't teach me What part of speech is why it's.
Rym: it's like something that doesn't exist in English, yeah, it's like a.
Scott: It's sort of like an article but not you put it after the subject and before the whatever, okay Yeah, but no I so I'm doing.
Scott: I'm doing like the hiragata stuff right and it's like it shows you wanted It's like this is ah, and then it's like this is a Right, so I'm looking at him real careful like, you know.
Scott: And then it's like, okay, and then it gives you an ah, and it says trace this.
Scott: So I'm tracing it with the stylus, right?
Scott: And I'm like a high traced it with the stylus.
Scott: and then when you trace it with the stylus It says ah, and then you and then it fades to gray and it says trace it again And then it's white and it says, you know trace it again Right.
Scott: So I do it three times and I'm like, okay all good, right?
Scott: Then you know it comes up and you go read a little bit more the lesson and then it's like, okay Here's a blank square draw ah, and it's like oh fuck.
Scott: Because when you're tracing it three times in a row you're just doing you know You do it you do it and then you do it one more time.
Rym: But if they just give you a blank slate and they're like, ah, it's like oh, yeah Yeah, I remember when I was I got to start practicing again, especially if Emily and I are gonna go to Japan.
Rym: I got about halfway through learning my hiragata, but I got to a point where I could read it pretty quickly But I had a lot of trouble writing it.
Scott: Yeah, writing it and the worst part right is that this thing's complex thing I ever wrote was Gankutsu.
Scott: Oh, yeah, the thing will teach you like, okay, here are all the tea ones like, you know, tate to date, right?
Scott: I'll tell you today, too Yeah, but then it's like if you put the little quotation mark, it turns his daddy.
Rym: do they do know doesn't it?
Scott: do G?
Scott: I forget which one turns to G. I don't know tie goes to da anyway, right?
Scott: It's like it's.
Scott: it just tells you that like on one sentence.
Scott: It's like oh, yeah By the way, if you put the quotation mark, it changes them all to the other letter.
Rym: that makes it really easy.
Scott: It does make it easy, but you never practice.
Scott: It never does the practice test things with that other letter So you don't actually like learn them.
Scott: And then it's like when you're when you're doing the practice things like the letters real big like it takes up almost the whole screen.
Scott: But when you've got like the smaller font size, you can barely see if that little quotation mark is there or not.
Scott: So it's it's a little bit rough.
Scott: It's sort of like it feels like someone sort of just threw it together rather than actually, you know scientifically and using education Knowledges to make something that is easy to learn.
Rym: Maybe we should go with the the you know Expensive lazy option and just buy one of those Rosetta's no stone things.
Rym: The thing
Scott: is the way the Rosetta stone thing works at least from what I heard and what I saw a guy using it on the train to learn Hebrew right is it gives you Like all these pictures and then it gives you the word and you got to click on the right picture That goes with the word or vice-versa.
Scott: It sort of works like that from what I saw.
Rym: I don't like that.
Scott: Okay, so I don't know if that's worth Whatever they charge for the stupid Rosetta stone.
Scott: This was $30.
Rym: so Yeah, all right.
Rym: Maybe I'll try it out.
Rym: Yeah, I want to see this thing.
Scott: Yeah The thing is that does have like a lot like if you actually go through with this thing It might not be like the best at learning and you might have to just sort of you know Force yourself to do a lot of the stuff that you know, it doesn't help you out with but eventually it teaches like a whole shit.
Scott: Ton of kanji are in that little DS cartridge apparently.
Rym: So anyway, there is actually some anime news here And I actually want to talk about it because I didn't notice that.
Rym: I didn't know there were rumors about this Until I saw rumors confirmed.
Scott: That's cuz we don't read like anime forums and shit.
Rym: Well, pretty much if anime news network is the AP wire Here I go, yeah, but turns out Koji Masanari who was the director of One of my favorite shows ever read or die the OAV that not the TV the manga?
Rym: Well, no, he I think he also directed the TV.
Rym: Okay, but I can't really blame him for that.
Rym: Anyway, read or die.
Rym: if you have not seen the read or die OAV Three episode OAV.
Rym: right the title tells you what it's about.
Rym: read or die.
Scott: Then should we should name our book club?
Rym: that I think we should.
Rym: it is so.
Rym: so it has been said and so it shall be done.
Rym: Read or die is one of the most epically full of win things ever made the OAV at least.
Rym: Yes, it is epic in a way that is hard to describe.
Rym: It is a show where a character will create a gigantic paper airplane and then you will all write it.
Rym: But yet it is neither Comical nor undramatic that this has happened.
Rym: And in fact instead of thinking what the fuck you're thinking.
Rym: Oh my god Is that awesome?
Scott: Meanwhile, they're fighting against you know, freaking like Goku on his cloud with an extending stick.
Rym: But anyway Apparently he is making his first feature film.
Rym: It is going to be called the space show.
Scott: Sounds good to me now.
Rym: That's the kind of title that leads me to believe it'll be similar to read or die in terms of how awesome it is.
Scott: I hope so.
Rym: I really hope so.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: Anyway, there aren't a lot of anime full-length features these days anyway.
Scott: So anyone that you know, like it anyone at all?
Scott: I'll take what I can get as long as it's not like another Pokemon movie.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Oh, he did do a read or die TV And he did storyboards for bunt openers and enders and I that's not so bad and he produced it.
Scott: He's fully responsible for the travesty.
Rym: Yeah, but at the same time it Probably made money.
Scott: Maybe I don't know.
Rym: I watched it all the way through really.
Rym: I was living alone.
Rym: I'd nothing.
Rym: I also.
Rym: that was the era of my life when I didn't even have internet access or a cell phone that worked because I lived on that mountain.
Rym: I watched a Gunslinger girls at about the same time.
Scott: Did they have cable television up there?
Scott: No satellite?
Rym: not well We didn't have satellite at the house, but you couldn't get cable even if you wanted to buy.
Rym: I was renting some rich lady's house and she was never there.
Rym: So it was basically her house.
Rym: I watched every DVD she owned which wasn't that many.
Scott: If only I had Netflix in those days, I know oh My god that said the DVD bag.
Rym: like all three back every day I would drive a half-hour down the mountain and park at this elementary school and sit in the parking lot on the top of The slide where I got cell service and call people in my boredom.
Rym: So yes, I watched all of read or die TV and all of gunslinger girls And if only you had had like, you know, something like coke don't okay in those days.
Rym: Oh my god You realize during that time?
Rym: That is when I got all s ranks on everything I could in both of the original GBA advanced wars.
Scott: All right Anyway So, you know Hatsune Miku, right?
Rym: In fact because of Emily I've got the Hatsune Miku mixing box including the DVD and the chibi little PVC staring what's on the DVD bunch of stuff.
Rym: I haven't really fully explored explored it yet.
Scott: It's not the software so don't think that yeah, but basically I found out Basically from this anime news network article that there are things I didn't know right this yo Yamaha's Vocaloid software engine, right?
Scott: And that's the thing that lets you do this sort of typing lyrics and notes and making someone sing it.
Scott: but This other company Krypton right is basically what they do is they make sort of like voice samples for Vocaloid.
Scott: so it's not Yamaha that's doing these character things it's Krypton is making these character things that you sort of put into Vocaloid so that you you know and You know they get sort of like famous people to are very talented people to do them like.
Scott: there's a there's a gak poid I think it says here right, you know done by gak and whatever.
Scott: so They got There's a new character for their new one, right?
Scott: So this is the third one because it was Hatsune Miku then it was those twins, right?
Scott: And now it's the third one.
Scott: The third one is named Megarin Luca.
Scott: She doesn't look as hot as Hatsune Miku as far as I'm concerned but She is done by Yuu Asakawa.
Scott: They had her do the voicing for it and there's a couple demo songs You can listen to like Amazing Grace and some other song and it sounds okay But it still sounds like Vocaloid, you know, it's.
Scott: it is what it is And I'm sure that if people like this character, they'll be flood of internet stuff.
Scott: Really I think the problem with this character at least that is the visit.
Scott: the graphical design of it Is.
Scott: it's more like a Square Enix character where there's a lot of stuff on her, you know It's like she's got the boots with a lot of laces and then a sock leg thingy and then a you know an armband.
Rym: Miku isn't super complex.
Rym: She's got what the tie and the long sleeves and the big hair Yeah, it's mostly the tie is like the only real accessory.
Scott: This girl's got like two belts and a bunch of neck shit.
Scott: No one should have that many belts Yeah, but yeah, I guess we'll see if this character becomes as popular as Hatsune Miku.
Scott: I doubt it, but Maybe I maybe people would be able to make like better music with her voice.
Rym: I don't really want to go through it all because if you care, you'll just go to a website and read the list.
Rym: but The the anime industry is recovering from the I guess crash it had earlier.
Scott: Well, no, it's not the industry's not recovering.
Rym: The industry is consolidating which is the closest thing to recovering.
Scott: we're gonna see So more like spoils of war.
Rym: so a lot of good titles that got lost You know genie on titles are being picked back up mostly by one funimation.
Scott: Yeah, but funimation just had big layoffs.
Rym: Well that think about it lay a bunch of people off, right?
Rym: So now I have a lot fewer people to pay, you know, really contract my operations Pick up a whole bunch of already put together titles and just re-release them in thin packs super cheap to build capital and wait out the bad times.
Scott: Oh Wait, it says they laid off at least two people from funimation North America.
Rym: That was probably like 60% of their staff.
Scott: Yeah, it says last.
Scott: it says a while ago in July.
Scott: They cut staff by 10%.
Scott: so now they got two more people.
Rym: Oh, I totally didn't realize that Koji Masunari was the director for the miko 2010 anime.
Scott: Oh, dude, miko 2010 is like the wind miko 2010.
Scott: It's not the manga though.
Scott: No the manga porn porn but the anime Hilarious not poor god.
Rym: We watched that when we were freshmen at RIT.
Scott: It's basically a story about a sex bot that gets a job at working at a radio station as like you know the host of a talk show but in The manga she's a sex bot and she's sexting it up.
Scott: But in the in the show She's a sex bot but she never sexes it up.
Scott: So it's it's just that comedy.
Rym: Didn't we only get to watch that because the tape Nazi basically translated it himself From the SVHS masters like that.
Rym: he got from a friend in Japan and he showed it only to the RIT anime club And he wouldn't give it to anyone.
Scott: Let's see if I can.
Scott: I guess I'm gonna have to.
Scott: I don't know if it's gonna be available on any bid torrents or anything.
Scott: I wonder if any.
Scott: I just looked at a couple.
Scott: I didn't see it.
Rym: I'll have to look cuz someone else had to have done it.
Rym: Otherwise we have to track down the tape Nazi and steal his SVHS.
Scott: Yeah, great.
Scott: That's what we need an SVHS.
Scott: That'll be real useful.
Rym: and I guess one more thing I've got We're not gonna really review it yet.
Rym: Obviously because one it deserves a full review - I don't feel like we need to review it before any of you have seen it because the Summed-up review is see it.
Rym: It's fantastic.
Rym: But Miyazaki's new movie ponyo by the sea We uh, we acquired an advanced copy and we watched it and it is absolutely Amazing.
Rym: like if you didn't like howls.
Rym: it kind of goes back to what makes Miyazaki movies.
Rym: Awesome It is so awesome.
Rym: Like I I'm not gonna even say anything else.
Rym: if you can see it see it.
Rym: It's gonna get a theatrical release in the US.
Rym: So if you live in any major city, you will definitely be able to see it in a theater And it is definitely worth seeing in a theater.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty good.
Scott: But it's not like the most amazing Miyazaki movie ever.
Rym: No, it's not but it's a fantastic movie.
Scott: It's all right.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Yeah, I would call it fantastic.
Scott: It didn't blow me away.
Rym: All right, I would say it was.
Rym: I mean it had lots of cubies.
Scott: I was better than howls moving castle.
Scott: Yeah, sure That's not saying much how.
Rym: this was pretty good.
Scott: I think the only problem now I think like howls moving castle like without Calcifer the talking fire.
Scott: It had nothing.
Rym: I think the problem with howls was that it had too much Unexplained stuff from the book that you wouldn't know what was going on unless you read the book.
Scott: That's true like in Pawnee.
Rym: Oh the the few unexplained things don't really matter at all to what you're watching.
Scott: I didn't think anything was unexplained.
Scott: I just thought it was sort of it was like Pawnee by the sea was like a shorter story that felt like it was extended with like lots of scenes of you know, just Awesome animations and cool things going on, but you know not.
Scott: it was like it.
Scott: the plot was actually very short and simple.
Rym: No, I really liked it and you'll be able to see in the theater.
Rym: So hold out if you live in a city.
Rym: Yeah, we'll review it.
Scott: I liked it.
Scott: I just didn't think it was like, oh my god amazing spirit of ways.
Scott: Oh my god amazing.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: All right, so other than Spirited or other than all the other Miyazaki movies An animated feature that has come out recently.
Rym: that was better paprika.
Rym: How recent was that though?
Rym: a couple years couple years?
Rym: Is that recent?
Scott: What do you quit?
Scott: Okay, so if you're gonna Say compared to anything that came out.
Rym: It's the best thing in the last five minutes Plus, I think I could put it in the top 15 or 20 anime features Maybe top 50.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Maybe I'm thinking 15 or 20 when I think back to all the anime movies I've seen.
Rym: a lot of them are fun, but vampire hunter D.
Scott: It's like sky crawlers more.
Rym: I like sky crawlers a lot.
Rym: Consider them fairly equal.
Rym: Yeah, I guess one was more enjoyable, but one had a lot more interesting things to say.
Rym: I Think you can figure out which one was which people.
Rym: Anyway, the movie is great and it kind of reverses the trend of how and I think goes back toward more Miyazaki ish roots.
Rym: Yeah, plus it definitely in the opening bits has the.
Rym: yeah, it's Miyazaki.
Rym: pollution's bad We know let's go.
Rym: Yeah, right.
Scott: He also really really likes to do like swarms of shit, especially if it's blobby shit.
Rym: Yeah, but I kind of like doing that a lot.
Rym: I like how the blobs of sea water are kind of like he did it in Princess Mononoke Did it in spirited away did in this movie?
Scott: Just you know, lots of you know move lots of moving swarms of blobs.
Rym: Yeah, meanwhile shiro not so many blobs.
Scott: No shiro is not really about the blobs.
Rym: It's mostly people sitting quietly while being oppressed by their own existence.
Scott: Are you talking about oshi?
Rym: Yeah, yeah, it was like shiro doesn't have blobs, but then I was like, I admit it I was talking about she but there's so intertwined in my mind because it goes in the shell that I kept saying shiro.
Rym: now I'm an oshi.
Rym: shiro has blobs, but they're blobs of a different source.
Rym: So anyway things of the day this has nothing to do with anime.
Rym: How about yours?
Rym: Comics awesome good enough.
Rym: I'll go first then because mine is totally irrelevant.
Rym: It's a video by some guy at RIT about how to take a shower at RIT and I bring it up only because he makes a couple of good jokes, but I realized why this video was made.
Rym: It was a project for freshman year in Richmond or FYE which at RIT is a class that they added when we got there as freshmen and The reason for the class is to teach people who suck How to not fail and moving out of their parents house.
Rym: It is like the worst class ever and if you don't take it you don't graduate.
Rym: It's not even worth any credits.
Rym: You just have to pass.
Rym: you have to attend it and not be flunked in it, but the grade doesn't count for your GPA.
Scott: I remember that class.
Scott: that class was a joke.
Rym: The class was like if you're gonna have sex use a condom.
Rym: if you're gonna drink don't drink until you puke.
Rym: If you get a credit card don't spend all your money.
Rym: Here's how to shower.
Rym: Here's why you should shower.
Rym: Here's how to go to class.
Scott: I barely remember it.
Rym: I kind of remember it because I actually it was mine was in the dorms and it was on a Friday.
Scott: I was also in the dorms in that room.
Scott: That was at the bottom of What building.
Scott: was it?
Scott: the one right near the ATM machine?
Scott: ATM not ATM machine and the one we played board games in a few times.
Scott: Oh, yeah, it was in that room.
Rym: It was the only class at every RIT I ever had on the dorm side and it was only class I ever had at RIT on a Friday because I didn't get to pick it and I couldn't get out of it.
Scott: No, it's right near the the ResNet whatever room, you know what I'm talking about.
Rym: So one thing I would like to point out is that when his little shower caddy falls off the thing That's because those things were designed to not hold anything up.
Rym: they would fall down if you put more than like a pound's worth of even a half a pound of weight on him.
Scott: Wow and
Rym: Because RIT showers were like that and because I had nothing better and because I suddenly remembered how disgusted I was at the majority of people entering RIT and colleges in general Who kind of needed a class like that because as I would like to point out
Scott: that's the funny says the thing.
Scott: this video is Sort of a stupid YouTube video whatever.
Scott: but the thing that makes this video Powerful is that you just think of watch it realizing there are seriously no joke people who need this video.
Scott: Otherwise, they won't know what to do.
Rym: one time I went to the shower guy was just standing in the bathroom naked trying to dry himself with that hand dryer Really?
Rym: Yeah, one time I found poop in one of the showers.
Rym: Awesome.
Rym: Yeah, you know how many time one?
Rym: You know how many times people would be in there barefoot and then like a month later, they would totally have funguses.
Scott: That was the funniest part where he said yeah one guy would go in without flip-flops.
Scott: They'll have fungus up to his kneecaps.
Rym: That's kind of lame but you know what that That video was not a joke to at least a third of the people who took my freshman year in Richmond class with me.
Rym: Wow, these were people who would like seriously my class.
Scott: last two quarters also.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Yeah like in the middle of class They would ask like we'd have the little Q&A at the end where we could like ask anything about RIT and one kid was Like.
Rym: so, how do I like not fail out of class?
Rym: Like I keep going to class, but I'm just not doing really well and like what do I do?
Scott: Be smart.
Rym: so the teachers like all right, so, uh, do you study?
Rym: he's like, yeah, well, I didn't really buy any of the books.
Rym: Do you go to class?
Rym: he's like like try to.
Rym: yeah You know what that kid wasn't in the second half of freshman year in Richmond because he totally failed out of RIT.
Rym: Good.
Scott: Yeah his money paid for your education.
Rym: It was either that or I was gonna use the videos of the riot at RIT because I found those suddenly out of the blue.
Scott: so Quite often me and other people, you know yell about hey Monthly.
Scott: comic books are stupid.
Scott: We should get rid of them, right?
Scott: Why do we still have these stupid little pamphlets?
Scott: and why are they raising the price of the pamphlets from 350 to $4?
Rym: probably because the market for Comics in that form is contracting due to the fact that the majority of those comics are marketed at it Increasingly shrinking due to old age and death demographic of people who must buy them all.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, So here is an editorial on a blog on news or Amma.
Scott: And basically it's a guy saying we should kill the monthly, right?
Rym: We should let me guess.
Rym: Is your thing of the day the comments of people replying to this?
Scott: Well, the comments are okay, too, but basically, the thing is that he brings up a point that is Interesting and somewhat new and that is why it's a thing of the day.
Scott: mostly the big point he brings up is that Putting out, you know, even if you excuse the format and the price or whatever right.
Scott: the idea of coming out with a small amount of comic every single month like Only works if you're you know Marvel or DC that doesn't work for anyone else, you know for anyone else like being you know Just coming out with a pamphlet that is of comic every month doesn't do it.
Scott: I mean who?
Scott: who really out there writes like serial stories that can be told in incredibly small Installments at four dollars apiece besides Marvel and DC with their superhero soap operas Nobody.
Scott: so it's like.
Scott: it's like yeah I guess you know the fact that because that format is there and all these other people are somewhat forced to buy into that format even though it doesn't match the art they are creating, you know, it's sort of like if All these painters were forced to use like a small canvas when they're to like and then you know They were actually making really big paintings.
Scott: You had to sort of put all these little small canvases together to get the big painting.
Scott: It's like now that's it's.
Scott: it only works for the people making small paintings, which there are only two of all right, huh?
Rym: Yeah, all right.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I didn't need any more reasons to dislike the business model.
Scott: No, but honestly there are a shit ton of comments that are sort of they range from like yeah Fuck the monthly to all.
Scott: the monthly will always be here.
Rym: So when we were at RIT, I want to make you all realize how old we are compared to half of you But at the same time how young we are compared to the other half of you.
Rym: There were no Digital fan subs like what that came about in the course of us being at RIT like when we got to RIT.
Rym: Well, there were none.
Scott: Well think about this everything in my senior year of high school Watching like a Kira on a VHS, right?
Scott: I own freshman year of RIT.
Scott: DVDs started to get popular but like people were buying Ps2s which were brand new to get the DVD player.
Scott: Yes DVD standalone DVD players were so expensive.
Rym: We think about this when we got to RIT.
Rym: None of us had DVD players because those were a crazy extravagance.
Scott: I know one had a DVD ROM either.
Rym: I had a DVD ROM but whoa So old, you know.
Rym: because they were expensive it could only play single-layer discs Because I couldn't afford DVDs.
Rym: I didn't have any Right.
Scott: So we were buying anime on VHS, right?
Scott: The like I think greasy can had some anime on DVD.
Scott: that was like insane try gun on DVD, which is crazy.
Scott: I was like, oh my god, it's on DVD the store.
Scott: Holy shit.
Scott: I didn't realize that right?
Rym: Well, not even that.
Rym: but it was that there were no like we did.
Rym: there weren't DVDs available to us.
Rym: We have DVD players and there were no digi subs like the first digi subs Like we're that year like the eskaflowne movie was one of them.
Rym: And even then there was like contra.
Rym: I had.
Scott: I had real media files of try gone on my hotline sir.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: Those are like 120i.
Scott: Yeah, it was How he watched it.
Scott: All right, and I was getting tapes out of the VHS tapes from the club See checking them out regularly now This.
Rym: is it that the thing?
Rym: that may it was hard to get into anime if you weren't already into anime at that time.
Rym: But being at the RIT anime club in RIT they had like 400 or so VHS tapes of Fan subs fan subs.
Rym: most of it was stuff that you couldn't buy.
Rym: it did not exist outside of VHS tapes and SVHS tapes.
Rym: So we had this bonanza and they were free to check out if we were members of the club.
Rym: So, you know the front row crew at the time, you know and extended parties.
Rym: Hey, we're like eight or ten of us.
Rym: So Every club each one of us would take out three tapes.
Rym: So we'd get 30 VHS tapes and by God if we didn't watch all of them by the next anime.
Scott: at the very least you watch The three you got on your own But usually the ones that were sort of communally watchable were immediately watched Communally.
Rym: now the cool thing was we'd go up there and we didn't know like I didn't know what?
Rym: Anime was what other than we didn't know.
Rym: shit man if I knew now if I knew then when I know now good God I mean, I remember a point when someone said yeah, they're showing episode 5 of cowboy bebop.
Rym: Yeah, that's the one where spike fights vicious.
Rym: and I thought Cowboy bebop a guy named spike fights a guy named vicious.
Scott: That'd be good.
Scott: I was like, that's a real interesting name for a show.
Rym: that can't be good.
Rym: and then I learned yeah But what we would do is I would go up there all of us and they only let a few people into the library at A time.
Rym: so we'd get up there and I'd go over to the tape Nazi or one of the eboard members And they all knew their shit.
Rym: I'd be like, hey What should we watch?
Rym: and they would just pick a tape up and be like watch this.
Rym: and they were always right?
Scott: Almost always right.
Rym: Well, they were always right in one way or the other either that it was good and should be watched or it was bad and should be Watched.
Scott: So anyway at one point we picked up a VHS fan sub tape of something called I don't know who picked it or why.
Rym: I think you did did I don't know pretty sure was you but it was called KO beast and it said one through three on it, right?
Scott: So and I think we also got two through seven.
Rym: We got it all.
Scott: we got it all on two tapes.
Rym: So long story short The the common thing to do at RIT for us was we'd all get together in one of the lounges probably Peterson.
Rym: But later on we moved into saw and we'd all sit around and we take the VCR.
Scott: cuz no we watch this I'm pretty sure on a on the tiny TV with the built-in VCR.
Rym: Oh, right We probably did because the TV lounge anyway, there were.
Rym: we had two VCRs between all of us.
Rym: We had my VCR that we can only use if we found it a TV that wasn't being used that we could get the cords to.
Rym: Otherwise we had to use the combo TV VCR which barely worked and had a smaller screen.
Scott: It worked just fine.
Scott: It was just very small.
Rym: Well, very small means barely worked when there's 10 or 15 people trying to watch.
Scott: Yeah, it was smaller than our monitors.
Scott: That's how small it was.
Rym: So what we would do is we'd hang out late it like on a Saturday morning.
Rym: We all get together eat breakfast at Gracie's.
Rym: then we just like watch anime for like all day and all night.
Rym: Yep, so One night, you know, we were watching anime for like several hours and then it's like, I don't know like midnight and someone's like Hey, let's watch this KO thing.
Rym: I bet it's a fighting show.
Scott: so we watched KO beast and I Remember that a we all liked it.
Scott: I remember that.
Scott: be the openers and close it.
Scott: Well, the openers are really awesome and memorable the one Daba Daba opener for the first set of shows And the rock and roll bomber opener for the second set.
Rym: I was real tired like we were.
Rym: it was late and we put this thing in and I was fading fast and thinking to go Into bed.
Rym: the opener alone caused me to stay and watch this entire show.
Scott: I remember that it was about three animals a tiger guy a bird guy and a mer girl and I remember that Dr.
Scott: Password and that's really all I remembered of this show.
Rym: I remember that it was about giant robots as well Forgot I forgot that it was about.
Rym: I remember the earth was cut in half and I knew Intuitively because I figured it out later.
Rym: But right around that time I'd started to identify, you know in my anime fandom voice actors I liked.
Rym: I didn't know their names I didn't know who they were But I always be pretty sure like that's the same guy who plays this guy that I liked in that other show And I could pick out like three voice actors.
Rym: I didn't know who they were and I knew that Bud Minh was one of those voice actors.
Rym: I liked Yep, and that he talked in English all the time.
Rym: It was terrible I say.
Scott: I forgot that until I watch it again.
Rym: And I remembered one other thing and I remembered this like so clearly that when I watched this show again recently like I knew this whole scene from beginning to end.
Rym: but There's a scene where the computer has a custom-made trap for each one of them.
Rym: And I remember Bud Minh's trap so clearly because it's one of the funniest things I've ever seen.
Rym: I don't know why it cracks me up so much, but it just does I forget what the trap was And I just watched the show again.
Rym: It's when he's like on the trapeze like he doesn't want.
Rym: like he's like they won't get me They won't get me.
Rym: and then just like a bird swing appears He's like joy, and he jumps out there.
Rym: He's swinging back and forth singing to himself like Alright, I remember now, and then that giant mace just fucking wrecks him out of nowhere.
Scott: It's good stuff now.
Scott: so Yeah, so we got the show on DVD somewhat recently.
Scott: It's a legal US DVD.
Scott: you can buy it right and we both.
Scott: I ripped it and watched it on my iPhone Rym.
Scott: I think.
Scott: watch the DVD.
Rym: one thing the show didn't actually get released in the US until like 2003 Really, yeah, it wasn't on VHS or anything.
Rym: It doesn't look like it.
Rym: Well.
Scott: That's interesting.
Scott: It's just one team.
Scott: It's two TV.
Scott: No three three DVDs, right?
Scott: I Don't know how many DVDs.
Rym: You know what it is seven 30 or so minute OAV Episodes that were made over a course of multiple years.
Scott: yep And you know the first set has the.
Scott: you know that's.
Scott: one thing about the DVD is that since I had watched old fan subs I knew that the show had multiple openers on The DVD.
Scott: the only opener is the rock and roll bomber open, which is crap.
Rym: I remember we were gonna show it to people because we got these DVDs.
Rym: So I put it in and the second opener plays, and I thought I had the wrong DVD or something was messed up.
Rym: So I'm like trying to figure it all out.
Rym: No.
Rym: They just for whatever reason they took out the funny.
Rym: You know The
Scott: first opener is on the DVD in the extras section But they don't actually use it on the episodes and it'll confuse you because you'll start watching the show and at the end of the Opener it'll say KO beast three and you're like what do you mean three?
Scott: Where's one?
Scott: Where's two?
Scott: Because he's just they're using the third opener for every single episode which is annoying.
Rym: now while that opener is pretty good I mean, I really like a rock and roll bomber.
Scott: I mean rock and roll bomber is awesome.
Rym: Oh, you know me side ooh three two ones.
Rym: Let's go that.
Scott: ah is it three two ones.
Rym: Yeah zero Rockin roll bomber hey.
Scott: Oh, I think it is this hello.
Rym: It doesn't matter that song is awesome.
Scott: It is awesome, but the ones have it.
Scott: have it have a song is also awesome.
Rym: Yes, and the thing the one thing I guess I didn't realize when I watched the show the first time was that it's really Primarily like.
Rym: I remembered it as being like 80% comedy 20% robot.
Rym: It is like 50% comedy 50% robot like straight-up robot show.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: I didn't.
Scott: I don't know why I didn't realize it or remember it But this show is actually a lot of robot goings-on.
Scott: I mean, it's not Super robot and it's weird because while there's lots of robot going on like they're sort of there.
Scott: But it's not like.
Scott: the show is about the robots.
Scott: It's like somehow they managed to concentrate fully on the characters despite robot fighting.
Rym: But at the same time is that there's definitely a little bit of poking fun Homage at robot shows because all the cliches are there in kind of messed up ways and like they'll all conform in the big They'll form into the big robot right.
Scott: and usually when you form into the big robot, let's say Voltron, right?
Scott: What happens?
Scott: everyone is in the central control room instead of in their individual cockpits, right?
Scott: When they form into the big robot in chaos entry beast the three characters get stuck in these tiny little balls and like this little Like triforce and they can't really move and they're crammed in there and
Rym: like controlling the robots
Scott: like another dimension
Rym: Yell at the robots and the robots kind of listen to them.
Scott: Well, the robots sort of are smart and do their own thing even when they're not in them.
Scott: So, you know the robots is sort of like their own characters that just don't talk which is kind of cool.
Rym: I guess Yeah the show There's a lot of little like.
Rym: it's a goonie show It's you know, like there's wacky comedies nowadays like the wacky comedy anime that Dave Riley always makes fun of like, oh, hey Someone got punched.
Rym: It's a wacky anime.
Scott: excel saga is like a wacky anime.
Rym: This is wacky before that kind of wacky.
Rym: it's the old kind of wacky.
Scott: Yeah, that's definitely what it is.
Scott: And I really got the slower pace to it.
Scott: It's less extreme It's just got.
Scott: it's got fewer fewer jokes a little bit more subtle jokes.
Rym: a lot of the jokes are like throwaway references to other shows or like throwaway references to pop culture or just Throw away references to fucking.
Rym: I don't even know.
Scott: or they'll be.
Scott: they'll be wacky things that are sort of subdued Like just the fact that the bird people use lots of English words, you know, it's not really like extreme comedy It's just sort of subdued.
Scott: They're speaking English words randomly.
Rym: Hey, baby, I'm the bomb.
Scott: Yeah, but it's kind of funny when they say something in English.
Rym: Oh my god, Bud's not his dad I don't know.
Scott: Is it his dad or his grandpa?
Rym: It's the elder of the bird village who kind of looks like a cross between Uncle Sam and Colonel Sanders.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I think it looks more like Santa Claus, but short with a hunch, but the fact less fat.
Rym: But they there's this scene and the dove one the dubs terrible.
Rym: I'm not don't dubs terrible.
Rym: But anyway He they asked him a question and you know a plot question and he thinks for a minute and got mumbles to himself and I'm going to quote exactly a B C D E F G H I J K L M N O P Oh.
Rym: and then he answers the question like what You just started saying the alphabet in English and then answers the question or like at one point the show.
Rym: You know, it's a robot show comedy show.
Rym: one episode opens and they're like playing mahjong and it's totally.
Scott: that's the episode.
Scott: We're in the cave.
Scott: They can't get out and they have no food.
Scott: So it starts and they're playing mahjong and whoever loses gets eaten.
Rym: That is one of the funniest scenes in the show when they just try to eat.
Rym: I'm not gonna say who but it's just cuz.
Rym: Maymar is like clinging on to him Just like she bit him and just wouldn't let go and he's running away.
Scott: You know who I forgot about?
Scott: that's probably the best character in the show huddle Maymar's mom.
Rym: Oh my god She's one of those Characters.
Scott: Oh, yeah That's my kind.
Rym: That's another thing.
Rym: It's kind of.
Rym: it's only used in parody and it's kind of underused now.
Rym: but that was like that was one of those anime tropes of all.
Rym: just like The evil girls always have complicated hair or complicated hair girls are always evil cliche.
Rym: You don't see that so much now because they all have complicated hair.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: That used to be a big cliche.
Scott: Yeah, cuz we know.
Scott: nor than like the good girls in the shows, right?
Scott: I would always have like this real simple hair like just straight or just short, you know, that's it.
Scott: But like some girl would have like some like crazy hair that was just all over the place and that obviously meant that she was.
Scott: Because no, you know good character would set up crazy hairstyles that are all over the place.
Rym: But chaos entry beast is kind of a. it is an old show is made in like the early 90s.
Scott: Yeah, it's an early 90s show.
Scott: It's it's actually.
Scott: it's pretty good animation because it was an OAV.
Scott: So it actually looks like a sort of a later 90s show but with a less digital color technology.
Rym: But you know the animations pretty good animation kind like it holds up like if you look at you don't see.
Scott: it's not like.
Scott: You know, there aren't like lots of animation errors or anything like that.
Scott: It's like it was an OAV.
Scott: they tried hard on this shit and apparently it was popular enough to make three sets of it.
Scott: You know normally, you know, if it was if it wasn't popular, they would have stopped after the first set.
Scott: So that's that's pretty good right there.
Rym: Well from what I read now apparently it was originally like they made the original OAV in like.
Rym: oh here we go 92 and it went.
Rym: you know went over.
Rym: Okay as far as I can tell they didn't make the second OAV which you know on all the rest of the show until late 93 and Apparently the second project was pushed heavily by Ito and something project before which was like his studio at the time.
Rym: Mm-hmm Like they really pushed to have this thing get finished Uh-huh.
Rym: I don't know how it sold though because those numbers are not accessible to me.
Scott: No, not really.
Scott: Oh We're forgetting the most important part, but we should just Akumaka All right, so that is the other thing that I remembered from this show that It was like.
Scott: I guess she was the most memorable thing until just now and I forgot it Right is a character called Akumako and like I remembered Aku Oh, there were times where I could remember Akumako, but couldn't remember what show she was from and basically she's his little devil character That floats around near the bad guys and whenever someone's gonna die.
Scott: She's like yes Yes die so I can eat your soul.
Scott: and she was just like a fork and a knife and she wants to eat souls.
Scott: And I watched the show again and she was still there.
Scott: She was still funny but it's like she almost doesn't even exist.
Scott: the other characters like Hardly ever even recognized her existence except for maybe two or three times.
Rym: well V darn does because he like he's kind of.
Scott: He says something to her like a few times But that's.
Rym: and then once V shown like smacks her Those are in the lava and kills her cuz she's so annoying and scary.
Scott: Yeah, but most of the time like she's just like yes.
Scott: Yes, give me your soul and no one says anything.
Scott: It's like she's not even there.
Scott: You could edit the part you could edit her out and you wouldn't even notice.
Rym: but a lot of things in the show kind of Come out of nowhere like the fact that and the thing is you never learn about Akumaka.
Scott: Like why is she there?
Scott: Why are there?
Scott: why they're devils that eat souls, why is he a mage night?
Rym: What is a mage night from?
Scott: it's a dude.
Scott: It's a dude with electric armor, obviously why?
Rym: Actually, there's a V darn manga that was separate really.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: I don't think it was ever translated.
Rym: Wow I kind of wanted.
Scott: one thing I thought was interesting though was how you know V darn is sort of like the henchman of the Real bad guys, right?
Scott: But eventually the real bad guys don't need him anymore, but he keeps going on his own.
Scott: Yeah, I sort of you don't see that happen too often whether just like the big bad guys just be like screw you henchman We don't need you anymore.
Scott: Go you're not work.
Rym: Go away.
Rym: Well, the thing is the original like the feel V darn and vision.
Rym: they kind of start out.
Rym: They're basically Team Rocket.
Scott: Basically, yeah.
Rym: Yeah, but the show is a lot.
Scott: that V shown is pretty smart.
Scott: rise in Team Rocket.
Scott: They're both idiots.
Rym: Well, I don't me out there's pretty smart.
Scott: so I guess me out is Akumaka I guess But Akumaka was a lot stupider than me out.
Rym: So the plot if you wonder is basically that the earth was split in two.
Scott: Literally just two hemispheres went boop and no one knows why but it's in the opener But it's ancient history.
Rym: the three main characters Juan Daba Daba Daba his last name Bud mint by the way is voice-acted by nother not other than pumpkin head koyasu my man.
Scott: The thing is he doesn't sound like his usual self because he's not.
Scott: it's not a be shown in type character.
Scott: Yes, he is.
Rym: He's totally be shown in type character.
Rym: Well, he tries to be tries to be.
Rym: he gets all the ladies until he turns into a chicken pretty much.
Rym: Yeah Who is the mayor?
Scott: She's a mermaid.
Rym: Yes, and she's she's kind of awesome.
Scott: She's kind of cute too.
Scott: Yeah, she's awesome.
Scott: I like her.
Rym: don't forget Tuttle the sea turtle who is basically the only smart one who always just kind of hangs back.
Scott: It's basically the smart trusty quiet reliable guy.
Rym: and don't forget doc at all.
Rym: pass a while.
Rym: You need charm Passo his daughter.
Scott: She's the magical girl who's like the plot device.
Scott: She basically effectively a living McGuffin.
Scott: her.
Rym: her Plot consists of screaming Juan's name and then making magic shit happen.
Scott: Yeah accidentally, you know.
Scott: It's just like every other anime where there's a girl with a magical pendant who's you know, activates all the magic stuff.
Scott: That's her.
Rym: and I just want to point out you'll see it when you watch this show, but The big evil bad guys in the end are basically whack-a-moles.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, they kinda are.
Rym: I'm gonna say this if you want to see some people might balk and calling this old-school anime But it is of the school that is older than the current school.
Rym: There is a school older than the old school if You look at current anime.
Rym: This is old school.
Scott: Yeah I mean, it's like it's weird because it's like there's old school older school and oldest school like the different School.
Rym: it's like the difference between watching Tobor the eighth man versus watching eight man after.
Scott: It's like 80s astro boy versus 60s astro boy, you know, but I highly recommend KO century beast one.
Rym: It's super cheap.
Rym: You can get the whole thing for like nothing.
Scott: Yeah, this is not.
Scott: if you can find it No one's gonna charge you a lot of money for it to.
Rym: this show is kind of classic and I think it's kind of Underwatched and underrated.
Scott: and under no, I think it's just under no.
Scott: and the thing is it comes off as a little bit furry.
Scott: But you know because it's basically about you know beasts versus humans.
Scott: That wasn't a concern for me Yeah, but the fur in is really there's.
Scott: no there's no scary.
Scott: fur in is just like they happen to be animal people.
Rym: whatever I don't know.
Rym: I didn't I didn't think to myself.
Rym: Well, is this furry?
Rym: Well, is it scary furry?
Scott: Remember when what's-his-name did the awesome chaos entry beast cosplay?
Rym: Oh my god We'll have to talk about that someday.
Scott: pictures of it around.
Rym: I'll find him.
Rym: I'll make that a thing of the day.
Rym: That was one of the.
Rym: that was quite a cosplay.
Scott: Yeah, I like that.
Scott: It was great how they like showed up at the last second and then they got voted into winning.
Rym: No, we vote they got second place.
Scott: Oh, did they?
Rym: because the crowd actually, you know who won that cosplay?
Rym: No, Emily Really?
Rym: That was Emily who won with her.
Rym: Well, I'll talk.
Rym: I'll save that for what.
Scott: that was the Princess Mononoke costume.
Rym: That was a good guy before Emily and I were dating and I as far as I was.
Scott: he even had like little boots on That costume as far as I was concerned.
Rym: She was just this really Incredibly cute girl who showed up to the anime club and it had a little cape and it had a little masky thing.
Rym: Yeah, so basically the club voted to give her first place and then this like professional cosplay got second place partly because it While it was awesome, it lacked heart and it showed up late.
Rym: Yeah Oh Man those were good days, but KO century beasts.
Rym: Well, if you haven't seen a lot of older anime It'll really kind of put you into that old-school watching anime move.
Scott: Yeah, really, you know, it's not like the greatest show in the universe, but it makes you feel like it's 1999 When you watch this shit, yeah, like this show.
Rym: really this was my fandom back then.
Rym: I mean if you like this, you should probably watch like it's a.
Scott: it's got a lot of nostalgia powers.
Scott: So if you don't feel that nostalgia it might weaken the show for you the way around that Watch it late at night with a group of people definitely Definitely in that genre of watching it alone.
Scott: You might be like, okay, it's an anime big deal But if you watch it like anime club with a whole bunch of anime fans or at a convention with a bunch of sugared up Kids, it'll be pretty awesome.
Rym: If we get the the secret Otakon plan I can't reveal what that is yet But if the secret Otakon plan comes to pass this show is so being shown at midnight.
Scott: No, I don't know.
Scott: there are better things to show at midnight.
Rym: Yeah, maybe at 11 before the midnight showing.
Scott: well say we got a. what's a plan?
Rym: Yeah, but I got ideas for the show, but If you like this show watch like I don't know the old birdie the mighty or like I don't know.
Rym: I'm trying to think of a good segue and maybe the new birdie the mighty watch birdie the mighty Show is like chaos century beast.
Rym: There aren't many Those.
Rym: if you like robot shows watch this because it will.
Rym: they will point out other robot shows in a big way.
Scott: Koto-cha is a little similar a little bit.
Rym: Yeah, it has that similar like.
Scott: it's around the same Time-frame and it's also a comedy.
Scott: doesn't have robots though, but you know a little bit.
Rym: Yeah You know, this show is just worth watching if you're an anime fan.
Rym: I feel like you should have seen it.
Scott: Yeah, I do.
Scott: I do think it's unique though in that most robot shows tend to either be you know the sort of like, you know, super serious like a Gundam or a gassaraki kind of thing or There's sort of like messenger sort of you know kids wackiness go guy gar.
Scott: This is sort of like a weird.
Scott: Where do you see like the comedy robot show?
Scott: It's not something you see too often At least I can't really think of any and it definitely it does play it straight about this time.
Rym: But kind of you know slayers will always kind of be like it's dumb and certain awesome and hilarious.
Scott: There'll be one episode about a fish man But eventually it gets around to a serious fantasy plan.
Rym: even during the series It'll always keep.
Rym: it'll periodically jump back to the comedy.
Scott: Yeah, they'll be like it's like in a funny episode a fish man episode.
Scott: They'll be jokes the whole time, but in a serious episode They'll just be like, you know, five to ten jokes at random spots.
Rym: But they'll be short jokes You know and slayers will always have a place in my heart for the fact that it was the first show I saw where someone took a sweat drop and tried to kill someone with it.
Scott: Yeah, it was a good one.
Rym: and Anyway, this isn't the Slayer show.
Rym: Yeah, those slayers has a similar fandom era for me.
Scott: Yeah, slayers like fantasy plus comedy and it's sort of like the same level of comedy as ko beast almost except Maybe it has more quantity of comedy.
Rym: But this show does have a plot and the plot actually despite being a primarily a comedy Isn't that bad?
Rym: like it plays itself pretty well.
Scott: It's an average anime plot, you know bad guys are up to no good.
Scott: There's a little bit of mystery of what Gaia is.
Scott: the characters don't really know what they're doing, but they're doing it.
Scott: Anyway, they're all kind of idiot jerks and in each episode like weird stuff happens like that to repair the robots.
Scott: But the guy who was gonna repair the robots is actually like two pigs who were standing on top of each other.
Rym: Oh my god I loved him.
Rym: that episode in particular that whole episode was so slayers because they're like in the town Eating all the food in the inn and then everything gets destroyed.
Scott: So is the episode where the bird down all the bird town.
Rym: Yeah, if the show like it jumps genres a whole bunch, but it always comes back to robot show Mm-hmm.
Rym: I don't know what else we can say.
Scott: I'd recommend it's not allowed to say about seven episodes without spoiling the whole thing.
Rym: I just I'd really recommend checking it out.
Rym: It's kind of short, you know seven episodes.
Rym: It's super cheap.
Scott: Seven episodes is it right?
Rym: Yeah, you can totally get it.
Rym: I bought the whole box set for like ten bucks.
Rym: Damn And I don't know I really liked it.
Scott: Yeah, I You know, I remembered it.
Scott: I think my memories of it were more fond than the reality of watching it again, but I wasn't like.
Scott: oh, this is terrible.
Scott: It was better than a lot of the anime that I does new today.
Rym: I definitely felt the desire after I finished every episode to watch the next one which that's kind of rare now.
Scott: I didn't have a strong desire, but I did watch the whole thing without you know Stopping plus.
Rym: we watch it like on the train the really to get the experience.
Rym: watch it with friends way late at night.
Rym: Yep, this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four Different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution Non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.