Scott: It's Tuesday September 8th.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym, and this is GeekNights.
Scott: packs 2009 in your face.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: and we are back from packs 2009. it was it was like the best packs ever.
Scott: Why are you spoiling it like that spoilers?
Scott: Yes, I mean we.
Scott: we went to packs last year And we were like oh my gosh the best card in the universe.
Scott: and then I was going again this year And I'm like well, I wonder was it actually the best card in the universe?
Scott: I mean was I just like real excited?
Scott: was I hallucinating?
Scott: Are they you know?
Scott: was it a one-time deal?
Scott: is it gonna be that good again?
Rym: I mean I remember you know our first Otakon and we were like amazed by it.
Rym: as time went on we got more and more Jaded and also you know only the two of us went last year so the rest of the crew Basically had to listen to us every day for the next six months.
Rym: talk about how great packs was.
Rym: no every other com sucks To the point that I don't think anyone believed any anything.
Scott: We.
Scott: I began to not believe myself much like when I watched Evangelion then didn't watch it for many years Then watched it again.
Scott: packs is the same way and of course the same exact result.
Scott: I watch it again the second time and I say What the fuck was I thinking this is better than I even thought it was the first time I?
Rym: It was such a great convention, and it was.
Rym: it was better than last year part.
Rym: I mean the mystique was gone.
Rym: But at the same time what replaced it was?
Rym: I left before knowledge and the ability to plan and for like I knew what to expect.
Scott: Mm-hmm yep that helped a lot plus.
Rym: I played a lot more games this year as definitely You know that's.
Scott: one thing is a gaming convention.
Scott: Play fucking games.
Scott: It's you know.
Scott: I mean like last year I didn't play nearly enough games.
Scott: you know what?
Scott: some of the most fun times at a gaming convention They're just playing games.
Scott: so any time I didn't have something I forget.
Rym: just bam playing games first before we continue into the full review of facts And hopefully we'll be able to get through all of this tonight without having to extend into Thursday But we'll just make a real long one.
Rym: welcome all of you new listeners to GeekNights.
Scott: It's a hope you exist.
Rym: there are four different nights of GeekNights, so this is Tuesday night.
Rym: You know gaming.
Rym: I apologize to our regular listeners that we're doing another Tuesday's show too soon.
Rym: We should have been doing a Monday show, but we were still in Seattle.
Scott: I think it'll make a much better packs show because we are doing it so quickly.
Scott: after the packs.
Scott: We won't forget everything and I have a bunch of notes here too, but you can all relax.
Rym: unlike last year We will not do three hour and a half long shows about packs.
Scott: No We'll just do this show.
Rym: and that's it though that might let you in on how excited we were after last packs.
Rym: But you know the story of packs we wanted to go since the first pack since we heard there.
Scott: This is only I think packs number six or seven.
Scott: so yeah, we haven't missed too many.
Rym: We could have gone to all of them.
Rym: We just didn't want it enough.
Scott: we'll go on all the PAX East's and hopefully they won't be bad.
Rym: Oh my god, but we came back.
Rym: We went back to packs, and it was the best thing ever.
Rym: so new listeners Gaming is just one quarter of what we do.
Rym: so Mondays are science and tech and Wednesdays are anime and manga and comics and all That stuff and Thursdays are things that sometimes get us in trouble and weird stuff.
Scott: And although this will be the last this would be the only Packs episode I can see in the future.
Scott: the near future at least all the Tuesday episodes are probably gonna be packs related things.
Rym: We've probably planned the next two months worth of Tuesday episodes.
Scott: Yeah, like well like next year's Another packs will happen at least next six months, and then it'll be PAX East And that'll give us the next six months and so and so on so forth.
Rym: so blah blah blah.
Rym: if you're new join the forums.
Rym: They're great yada yada, whatever.
Rym: That aside before we get into facts I want to say this and we say this all the time and everyone if hack says this But the enforcers you guys made that can't happen and like it's not just you know we're saying this
Scott: Individual
Rym: enforcers very specifically and directly made our personal packs better for being cool and helping us out more than once.
Scott: Yeah, I wanna let's see which which enforcer is totally awesome.
Scott: all the enforcers managing the Raven theater Ah the Raven.
Scott: all the enforcers in the Wolfman theater equally awesome.
Rym: I'm still.
Rym: I'm so sad that we stole.
Rym: We'll tell that when we get to all the enforcers at the.
Scott: bring your own computer area.
Rym: Oh my god For some dudes.
Rym: I forgot all your names, but I gave you business cards if you were cool.
Scott: There's who handled the main events all the enforcers who are giving out the badges.
Rym: Seriously the enforcers at packs are like a breed above and beyond the staff of any other convention.
Rym: It is telling that more than one packs enforcer said had a disparaging comment to make about soccer account the local anime con out there and They basically express everything that we always say that anime cons have terrible staff and packs has solved the.
Rym: how do you have good staff?
Scott: Problem all the enforcers of the tabletop check-in check-out.
Scott: all the enforcers at the retro game and all the enforcers in the DS lounge.
Scott: Uh all the other enforcers I didn't really hang out with anyone in a utility any.
Scott: all the enforcers around utility kilts.
Rym: Okay, what says it best is that at the very end when gave and taiko come out for the omega-thon finale And they thank all the enforcers.
Rym: He doesn't just say you know.
Rym: Thank you enforcers.
Rym: He says basically thanks to all the people who are dedicated enough to take on the black this year.
Rym: Yeah, that is the level that the packs enforcer is at one pack.
Rym: It's kind of like the old saying one riot one Texas Ranger One packs enforcer is worth like 20 Otakon gophers and at least like five or six Otakon staff.
Rym: Sorry Otakon, but seriously yeah, that's right.
Scott: Okay, so let's do our chronology.
Scott: So we don't forget things.
Rym: Let's jump right in now.
Scott: We got in the train.
Scott: it was a train in New York.
Rym: Well, we basically we had to drive to Scott's to Emily's and Alex's apartment walk to the train to the train station.
Scott: so car feet Took the trains in New York train car feet train.
Scott: We had to take a bus bus to the airport car feet train bus and a plane.
Rym: Carfeet train bus plane and a taxi taxi, and then we were a pax and because we stayed at the Sheraton We were basically like a hundred feet away from back.
Scott: It was pretty much the closest possible hotel, which is awesome.
Rym: Not as good of a hotel as the red lion though I'm going back to the red line the red lines only a block farther away, and it's better.
Rym: It was just so much better.
Scott: Yeah, no the closeness was really really nice.
Rym: Yeah, I was always kind of surprised I'd stagger out of packs at like 3 a.m.. And you know and suddenly.
Rym: I'm already like in my hotel.
Scott: Yeah, I'm definitely getting the Hilton for Otakon cuz it's just so worth it.
Scott: like you don't even realize how far the Renaissance is Until you've been closer Anyway, so yeah, uh let's see what.
Scott: Oh JetBlue right JetBlue's new terminal at JFK is totally awesome.
Scott: It has a Muji store.
Scott: if you're flying somewhere Go JetBlue at JFK.
Rym: if we're not chills for JetBlue Scott is just a JetBlue fanboy.
Scott: You see that terminal.
Scott: you seem to terminal like that your last terminal.
Rym: however it helped us out because you know one trouble I always have at conventions is not remembering to carry business cards around and when people give me business cards.
Rym: I lose them In the Muji store of all things we're looking and Scott says hey business card holders.
Scott: well I was I was just in the store looking around.
Scott: then it came to my mind a Business card holder would probably be something this store has and it's something I need and they had a selection of three.
Rym: Well, here's the thing Scott was looking.
Rym: He's like check this out We should get it.
Rym: and I point out that now the one you're looking at is inferior because the one I'm holding has two Separate sections.
Scott: well I had seen that one already And I dismissed it because it was ludicrously expensive compared to the other one and I'm like who the fuck needs two slots?
Rym: Ah two slots.
Rym: the magic is that one slot is for your business cards and the other is for everyone else's business card.
Scott: And once I realized this key piece of information we purchased the double slot business card holders on the Muji store.
Rym: of course I've got these stack of business cards in front of me.
Rym: I have to email everyone that I talked to at the con.
Scott: all right so moving on very quickly cuz we don't have a lot Of time we got to get right up to the pack stuff.
Scott: Oh, I mean guy crow was on our airplane.
Scott: We didn't talk to him though until later.
Rym: Yep, not that much later I mean Friday morning.
Scott: Yeah, I know right, but yeah, I was like is that a guy crow?
Scott: and then yes It was but I don't really have much to say to him because I all I know is that he's a famous game reviewer But I don't really read his reviews or know anything honest.
Rym: all I know about him is that David Riley is a fanboy for him.
Rym: He is almost gar for him.
Rym: It's kind of funny.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if say Yahtzee who wasn't there or James Rolfe was there.
Scott: I would add something to say to them, but I didn't have anything to say.
Rym: to end guy crawl Say we got our badges Thursday, so one cool thing this year They kind of they pushed the badge pickup over to the Grand Hyatt.
Rym: They had this whole separate like function area set up.
Rym: one little room over there was taken up by this LSU thing that we'll talk About later.
Scott: that was oh, yeah, basically, it's the start of college football season.
Rym: We'll talk about it right now.
Scott: Okay So Louisiana State University people were all over Seattle because their first game was an away game against I guess WSU.
Rym: I will say one thing over there.
Rym: anyone who thinks gamers are immature those LSU people were Thousand times more annoying.
Scott: basically the whole city of Seattle was occupied by Paxers and LSU people.
Rym: yes But I know Pax people did not.
Rym: at restaurants while everyone's trying to eat start shouting slogans as loud as they can and banging on The tables.
Scott: yeah, you only do that at the game guys.
Scott: Keep you know at the game.
Scott: totally awesome at the at the dinner at the restaurant not totally awesome.
Rym: now The great thing is and this is still my Karthago Delendim S for all of the stupid anime conventions that don't do this Pax mails out the badges so we literally showed up and Emily had to pick up her badge.
Rym: She didn't pre-reg in time to get it mailed to her.
Rym: so we walk in and the enforcer who knows what's up is like All right, you go that way, and oh you guys special go this way, so we walk two different ways.
Rym: We both end up in the same room the same empty room except for some enforcers.
Rym: There are more enforcers in that room than there were people needing badges.
Scott: yep And then we just got our badges immediately because it was no line.
Scott: cuz everyone got the mail to them.
Rym: You know it's so great.
Rym: You know I go to Pax, and it's like guy I am Rym from GeekNights, and they're like shall I warm says crack pipe.
Rym: here says badge Warmed.
Rym: I got an account of like who you again We lost your thing.
Rym: go to this other line.
Rym: Exactly right.
Scott: so we got our badges.
Scott: It was a wonderful experience getting our badges.
Scott: Then we went and did because last year me and Rym spent the whole Labor Day in Seattle.
Scott: So we did all the Seattle touristy stuff like the Space Needle.
Scott: But we weren't staying Monday this year and Emily and Alex were there who had never been to Seattle.
Scott: So we quickly after getting our badges did a whole bunch of Seattle touristy stuff such as Seeing the chocolate pasta down at the market and eating some buns of the Chinese bakery.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: That's sticky rice.
Scott: Yeah, I was good.
Scott: Tell about the sticky rice.
Rym: It was it was his magic.
Scott: I just had a normal bean bun.
Rym: It was this mystical sticky rice.
Rym: It looked like just sticky rice, so I got it.
Rym: But as I'm eating it I come across a little pocket of chicken curry a little pocket of sausage a little pocket of squash.
Rym: It was beautiful.
Scott: It was if I would have known that that I see.
Scott: I didn't notice the sticky rice.
Scott: I had already bought my bean bun.
Scott: I was too slow.
Scott: I could have gotten that sticky rice.
Rym: I missed out.
Rym: That was that was one of the better sticky rice as I've eaten.
Scott: all right.
Rym: So the only real thing I have to point out is that one they knew they were gonna sell out Gigantic pre-made banners saying we are out of badges.
Rym: do not even try yep with a little sad Hey signs all over the convention center.
Scott: No badges.
Scott: Anyway, all right, so we also.
Rym: we hung out with.
Rym: you know our PAX friends.
Rym: We have the Azen posse and the West Coast crew.
Rym: But the head of that is basically row and Jeremy who are two awesome listeners and friends that they're there.
Scott: as far as I'm concerned They have.
Scott: they're now at the top of the listener chart.
Scott: They're number one listeners.
Rym: I gotta give a shout out to robe largely because she made these GeekNights buttons and Went around doing the PAX forum button ear thing.
Scott: Oh, yeah, there's a button ear thing.
Scott: Basically, you know what Otakon like if you make buttons, you'll sell them in artist alley.
Scott: well, it packs everyone makes buttons or at least a lot of people do and Then you basically trade buttons with everyone else who's also a button person.
Scott: So it's like hey, I've got a thousand buttons that are mine that identify me and then you got buttons.
Scott: So I'll trade with you and I'll trade and then hopefully if everyone makes the same number and everyone has one for everyone Everyone will end up with the same button set at the end.
Rym: Well, except that a lot of industry people make buttons too and they'll have limited.
Rym: like one guy was like I got 700 come and get him.
Scott: Yeah, we got the Ninja Turtles buttons.
Scott: We're so cool.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right, so Okay, so we went to bed Thursday.
Rym: one thing I'll note, you know, we hung around we went through this GameStop because I had not pre-ordered Leighton and I needed something to do in the downtime and There is nothing sadder than seeing the people who work at the GameStop Next to packs who have to work at the GameStop during packs.
Scott: I know right?
Scott: what?
Scott: To work for the entirety of packs, you know Cuz they only have to work eight hours and packs goes late so they could have gone to concerts But still I got a hit.
Scott: that sucks ass.
Rym: You work at GameStop and you live near packs.
Rym: make call your sick day in for next year now So but everyone else already called the sick day in.
Rym: you don't know the dates yet.
Rym: I don't think.
Scott: as soon as they announce the dates be like just those are the dates you quit the game stuff.
Scott: Anyway, oh, oh we ate dinner that was totally awesome at this.
Scott: basically it was a buffet and it was expensive.
Scott: It was like $25 all you can eat, but it was all you could eat sushi's and awesomeness.
Scott: So Scott Johnson's dad would have been very happy with infinite crab.
Rym: There's this one packs guy.
Rym: He was definitely a packs guy and he walks up and he literally just fills a plate over a foot high with crab legs And then he goes back to his table.
Scott: you'd grab 83.
Rym: all right enough about us and our personal BS before packs.
Rym: We're talking about packs.
Rym: So Friday morning we had you know, we're speakers in this year's speakers got a special privilege.
Rym: We got to walk into the expo room an hour and a half before the mobs got in.
Rym: that that alone practically made my packs because I was able to do everything I wanted to do except play left for dead or Starcraft 2 because They're it.
Rym: despite the early entry and these small number of people There were lines for both of those that I was not when I couldn't play Diablo 3 Starcraft 2 or left 4 dead 2 because it was basically early entry for media people and speakers.
Scott: so we got into this room.
Scott: we had 90 minutes to see this room and All the media people were doing all that and we couldn't so and not that I you know thing is any of those games I'm probably you know either not either gonna buy like left 4 dead 2 no matter what
Rym: or
Scott: Probably not gonna like the Blizzard games, so
Rym: what amazed me was that for so few people in the room I would had to wait like 15 minutes to play left 4 dead.
Scott: I know actually I was considering buying Diablo 3 Even though it's a click fest.
Scott: I don't know why though why?
Rym: I don't know I can click faster than you.
Scott: I just wanted to check it out anyway.
Scott: the so yeah We saw a ton of awesome shit in this room.
Rym: first off You know the biggest thing that stood out was the Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles turtle van.
Rym: It is like a personal Ninja Turtles turtle van.
Scott: it actually drives.
Scott: They drove it there.
Rym: Yeah, we talked to the guys who were running it.
Rym: They couldn't answer many questions, and we seem to ask all these weird questions that caught them off guard But they're like uh yet drives.
Rym: I guess we drove it here.
Scott: Yeah, it was full of all sorts of Ninja Turtles.
Scott: you know Memorabilia's and merchandise is.
Rym: they had like a signed cell and like all the original toys some old like pewter miniatures of the turtles.
Rym: I don't know if those were direct or bootleg or what.
Scott: no I think those are front for like.
Scott: they were video game.
Scott: They were a Tabletop miniature related weren't they?
Rym: well they were.
Scott: they were like reaper minis.
Rym: right they were but they died.
Rym: they didn't.
Rym: I wasn't sure.
Rym: it looks like they may or may not have been at least initially Fully licensed because they're kind of blob.
Rym: you couldn't even really tell what they were.
Scott: well They were just poorly made.
Scott: and back that you know they were based off of the comic book art and such.
Scott: and anyway Yeah, awesome Ninja Turtles action going on over in the new turtles van.
Scott: I think they were promoting a new turtles game.
Scott: I don't even know Ninja Turtles were awesome and that they had a van.
Rym: But behind that you know walking further in what stood out more than anything.
Rym: and we talked to this guy.
Rym: We used up like half of our time in this early like check out just talking to this guy.
Scott: There's this company geek chic, and they basically make Heirloom guys like with a you know with a camel the other kind of chic.
Rym: Yes Yes, they make heirloom quality geek furniture like you're a gamer.
Rym: They make like an $11,000 custom like Tables a lot cheaper than $11,000.
Rym: Yeah, I didn't say they didn't know okay But they like.
Rym: they make these amazing custom for you gamer tables like.
Rym: basically you talk to them And you say things like.
Rym: you know I am this kind of gamer.
Rym: These are the things I would like a table to be able to do to accommodate my gaming And they'll make it for you, and this is some high quality stuff.
Rym: They're not carpenters.
Rym: They're cabinet makers.
Scott: Yeah, I learned that that was very good They.
Scott: I learned a lot of stuff from these guys But you know the best thing about this right?
Scott: how many times you go online and you see like someone made a gaming table And it's got secret message compartments Or it's got little drawers or it's got a little place like the DM to put his screen Or it's got like a piece of plastic.
Scott: you can move the minis around you know and put the maps under it.
Scott: Basically these guys they had it all and it's basically for reals.
Scott: get your gaming table Not some shoddy thing made by you and your you know garage And the prices are very reasonable and the From what I could tell the amount of service they provide and the quality level were extremely high And like they had a table you could get for like less than $2,000.
Scott: It was crazy and like goddamn a dining room table usually cost more than that.
Scott: so never dining room table That is more than just a table cost about the same as dining room table.
Rym: fuck Yeah, you got to check out the pictures I uploaded one.
Rym: this guy was really dapper Robert Gifford the guy the degree his title that he gave himself for the company is Instigator.
Rym: nah excellent Robert Gifford was very dapper Lee dressed And he gave a like the.
Rym: it wasn't really a sales pitch because we were just talking to him And we're going to interview him soonish.
Scott: Yes, we won't go too long about but these tables fucking amazing.
Scott: gonna get one as soon as I have a place to put one.
Rym: I just.
Rym: I have so such a vision of the table.
Rym: I want and I'm willing to pay almost anything for it.
Rym: I mean that like the glass over it like underneath you can.
Scott: So you got these eat leaves right.
Scott: so it's a dining room table.
Scott: if you flip the leaves over It's felt surface, so it's like I. you can play some nice games on there.
Scott: if you remove the leaves now You have a pit.
Scott: at the bottom of the pit is a whiteboard.
Scott: Then if you don't want to use the whiteboard you can put some pieces of paper maps over the whiteboard and then a piece of Plastic on top of that to hold the maps down and play like battle tech or your war hammer.
Scott: It's all whatever salted.
Rym: all the tables have cool names But the Sultan line of this one is basically the maximum table They had like this system where every every spot where a player would sit you can fold down the top to your own Personal little cubicle.
Rym: basically.
Scott: so you have like a screen built in and you have like three card Filing drawers and and the game master set up.
Scott: there are dice pits with like rubber bumpers in them.
Rym: It's not a GM screen.
Rym: It's like a GM module that slides out and opens up.
Rym: These tables were so cool.
Scott: The only thing is with these tables basically I kind of actually it'd be great if we got the table because it would force us To play RPGs that had five or fewer players in a GM.
Scott: You couldn't play a bigger game with it.
Rym: Yeah, you can't.
Rym: the maximum Sultan they had listed was a seven player plus GM table seven players.
Scott: We have stuff more than that though.
Scott: Anyway, well for our one game right exactly all right, so geek tables up.
Scott: so then over next the geek tables There's this company steel series with mice and keyboards and that sort of stuff.
Scott: And I was like you know usually you'd look at those companies like razor or whatever who make like the gaming peripherals And you're like oh, whatever you know that's kind of silly.
Scott: I mean last year.
Scott: remember the gun mouse that some company had.
Rym: the thing is all these things are usually cool But not worth the money exactly.
Rym: that gun mouse was surprising.
Rym: like we thought it was stupid.
Rym: We scoffed at him, then I tried it playing some counter-strike, and hey this is actually pretty good.
Scott: So I went.
Scott: so you checked out what steel series had just sort of while I was standing there And actually what they had was pretty great.
Scott: I mean they had this mouse called.
Scott: I think it was the Forget the name of it.
Rym: regardless.
Rym: what Scott pointed out is that this mouse?
Rym: Was designed with me in mind because Scott doesn't care as much about this sort of thing.
Rym: But I am like.
Rym: so like I'm so picky about my mouse And I will diddle with the tiniest adjustments to the sensitivity This mouse.
Rym: you save the sensitivity settings in the mouse.
Scott: you can also Like set like different key bindings in the mouse.
Scott: you can make those buttons on the side.
Scott: You could set like the button on the side to be Semicolon or three or whatever.
Scott: just all the settings are in the mouse itself.
Scott: So you don't need any special drivers or software to set the mouse up.
Scott: you just spin week.
Scott: There's an LCD screen on the bottom of the mouse And you can spin the mouse wheel and push the buttons on the mouse to change the settings.
Rym: It's totally crazy, so he showed me you can change the sensitivity down to a single individual CPI.
Scott: It was I got to get plus and then you can set the polling rate exactly equal to your vertical refresh of your monitor.
Scott: That that's a really good at 70 like yeah 75 Hertz monitor 75 Hertz mouse plus the coolest thing You know it doesn't have a hump.
Rym: It's a normal sized and shaped.
Scott: Yeah, it's like a lot of the gaming mice like especially the razor ones.
Scott: They look all weird.
Scott: this mouse just a totally normal looking mouse the thing I like most about it.
Scott: You know as I mean those settings were cool, but I don't really need them.
Scott: well first of all the mouse is reasonably priced Like only 90 bucks.
Scott: I think right was that the mouse was just so smooth on the mousepad like did the.
Scott: the level of friction was just oh So luxurious.
Scott: I think I might buy the mousepad even though the mousepad was and he is a ludicrous $35 for that particular mousepad.
Scott: That's something I'm gonna use every single day of my life for a long long period of time.
Scott: I think it's worth the $35 for that good feeling in my hands much in the same vein as the air on chairs we bought.
Rym: it's just I got.
Rym: Well, I got an error as I value freedom.
Rym: I value air.
Scott: Anyway What else was awesome in there?
Rym: I forget what game they were promoting it.
Rym: sadly their promotion must not work that well I didn't pay attention to what it was.
Rym: there was this gigantic, and I mean Some sort of like action RPG walk around hit things with the sword game Pneumatic horse and supposedly the guy who was running it and who made it was like he did this for Jurassic Park.
Rym: Yeah, he was one of those animatronic types, and this thing I've been on like bar.
Rym: you know stay on the rocking bull before.
Rym: this was that times a thousand and Basically, I'm looking at it I was like can I ride it?
Rym: and he's like that guy's about to ride it.
Rym: just sign this waiver.
Scott: the waiver was basically waiver Was like riding mechanical horses is an extreme sport.
Rym: you may die.
Scott: Of course the thing wasn't surrounded by like inflatable.
Scott: You know big like back.
Scott: It was necessary.
Rym: the thing is it's funny because you couldn't eat like you had to be pretty Skilled even to get on that thing because there's no like stirrup.
Scott: a fat guy went before him and had a trouble getting on.
Rym: Yep, but when I got there I basically had to like jump and then bounce and then like haul myself up.
Scott: But I would have gotten on from the back cowboy style.
Rym: I held on for 30 seconds.
Rym: I'm very proud of myself.
Scott: that guy got two guys before.
Scott: you was like a pro.
Scott: He stayed on for a long time.
Rym: Yeah, the thing is this thing.
Rym: it threw me off with an amount of force that was unexpected Shall we say so I get thrown off.
Rym: I'm laying there.
Rym: I throw up the horns like yeah And then the guy controlling it has the horse look at me because I'm still laying there.
Scott: It was like a demonic horse too with like glowing eyes And they had like a smoke machine.
Scott: so smoke is coming out from under it You know as a horse from hell Right
Rym: and the horse comes and looks at me in the crowd like oh And I look up and I see the horse looking at me and then a second later right in the mean bean machine.
Rym: Yeah, imagine.
Scott: It's like imagine the mechanical bull strikes back like you're like you already threw you off and out head butts you.
Scott: The thing is I was stupid.
Scott: I just stopped playing the video as soon as Rym fell off so I didn't catch that part.
Scott: I Gotta learn for now on whenever I video something video over.
Scott: That's my lesson.
Scott: I learned.
Rym: So speaking of that things of the day my thing of the day is the video Scott took of me riding the horse.
Rym: I'm still sad you didn't get the shot of the horse getting me in the mean bean machine.
Scott: Yeah, my I hope this.
Scott: I haven't uploaded the video yet, so this might be a fail thing of the day.
Scott: We'll see.
Scott: I'm pretty sure it'll work though.
Rym: Just worst case.
Rym: We'll get it up like tomorrow.
Scott: Yeah, I'll get it up.
Scott: Don't worry my thing today is something.
Scott: I'll talk about later in this episode.
Scott: Basically there was some awesome case modding action and the bet the winner.
Scott: the best case modder was this guy from NFC Systems so his website is my thing of the day.
Rym: That was pretty cool.
Rym: Oh, yeah, all right.
Rym: so back to the expo Hall.
Scott: I played Miles Edgeworth investigations for like 30 seconds.
Rym: you basically hit the stylus against the screen a couple times and walked away.
Scott: Yeah, I just checked and to see what kind of thing it was and it was freaking Edgeworth investigations I didn't.
Scott: you know.
Scott: I'm gonna play it for reals and buy it so what do I need to play it there?
Rym: We played Super Mario Brothers week, which was about.
Rym: it was exactly what I expected.
Rym: It was as fun as I expected the can.
Scott: the only complaint Controls are a little not smooth.
Rym: the control more and more Nintendo.
Rym: like all the Mario games the controls are a little more loose.
Rym: Then you know they.
Scott: basically I want the controls to be tight like Mario 3 or Mario.
Rym: That's what I was about to say.
Rym: ever since Mario 3 every game after that has been slightly more loose.
Rym: Yeah, Mario 3 was perhaps the most precisely controlled Mario game ever made and then Mario Super Mario world was only slightly less Precisely controlled.
Rym: this game was real loose, but otherwise it's super fun.
Rym: We're just gonna buy it.
Rym: I don't need to review it any further than that.
Rym: It's exactly what it looks like Tatsunoko vs.
Scott: Capcom.
Scott: I looked at it.
Scott: It was Tatsunoko vs.
Scott: Capcom.
Rym: Yep We saw Suro that game.
Scott: we talked about Episode about Suro and we said it was out of print.
Rym: It's back in print.
Rym: the company picked it up so you can just go buy it.
Rym: They had a whole thing a display about it.
Scott: I don't buy it yet.
Scott: They were selling it there, but they said the release date was coming soon.
Rym: I think they.
Rym: I don't know if they were selling overstock from before or if they're selling reprints or what but it's bad.
Scott: Did we add the business card?
Scott: I forget what the company was.
Scott: I feel bad.
Rym: I got it laying in my pile.
Rym: I've only gone through the pile of people that I have to email back in a timely manner.
Scott: Yeah, we'll make In the.
Scott: we'll put a bunch of show notes for this episode.
Rym: Basically Scott played Forza 3 and then I played Forza 3.
Scott: Was that actually Forza 3?
Scott: I'm not sure which Forza it was.
Rym: Pretty sure it was 3.
Scott: It had 3 screens and a steering wheel and a surround sound And a seat and pedals and the whole thing.
Rym: It was basically the maximum setup for that game, which it's cool You know, we talked to the guy who was running the thing.
Rym: He basically pointed out that with the Forza series they have this feature that if you're hardcore and you have three Xboxes Three copies of the game and three screens you can do this three screen thing.
Rym: But they basically it's not designed to sell the game.
Rym: He admitted that no one buys that game because it hasn't.
Rym: They only do it as a gift to the fans of their series of racing games Mmm, because they know that a lot of their fans will go hardcore and make like rigs with three Xboxes.
Scott: And the thing is I played it with the three screens.
Scott: I realized after getting off and watching Rym play that I never looked at the left or right screen ever.
Scott: Right and two there was a rear-view mirror on the right screen that I never looked at.
Scott: Yeah, but once I looked at it while Rym was playing it was a damn good-looking rear-view mirror Let me tell you.
Scott: but yet Forza 3 if you like realistic racing games, that seems like a winner to me.
Scott: Oh, so I'm not a big fan of them.
Rym: So at the Activision arcade racers at the Activision booth And I'm pretty sure I didn't see anyone talking about them remaking these this might be one of the originals from back in the day.
Scott: That wasn't the Activision booth.
Scott: It was the retro merch booth.
Rym: I it to me in my life is the Activision booth?
Rym: Okay, because they had among the Atari 5200 and Commodore's for sale The Activision bucket brigade patch the one that if you took a picture of your screen with a high enough score from kaboom on the Atari And mailed it to them.
Rym: They would send you this badge.
Scott: Yep, but yeah There's a booth.
Scott: that's all that was at PAX last year and this year that sells all sorts of wicked retro shit Like holy shit retro stuff and it's for sale.
Scott: It's not like yeah, we're just a little museum.
Scott: It's like holy shit.
Scott: They're selling this crap and they got a lot of it.
Scott: So I try not to spend too much time at that booth because I could be there all fucking day.
Scott: But it's always good to just stop by it real quick.
Scott: See like a few amazing things.
Scott: that way it'll be.
Scott: that booth will be amazing year after year after year because I doubt they're gonna Get more retro shit, right?
Scott: They sort of have all of it already.
Rym: We very much wandered around everything else.
Scott: Oh, we played this an R-type co-op That's coming to the Xbox Right bringing you can push a button to switch it from 3d mode to retro mode graphics wise like Instantly all you want.
Scott: and it was R-type and it was co-op and we me and Rym played it and we sucked ass But we had infinite lives.
Rym: That's the thing.
Rym: It was hard as balls, but one of the co-op modes is how many lives does it take you which is super fun?
Scott: Yeah much more fun than you die.
Scott: play the first level a million times.
Rym: never play level 3 because That's the best way to get better is to be forced to play again, yep We played some of the packs 10 games.
Scott: Osmose was a one that I played the most time.
Rym: Osmose is my favorite.
Scott: I didn't play at the closure one.
Scott: I wanted to play that I didn't get to.
Scott: but yeah, we're gonna have to play those on our own time and You know.
Scott: then maybe do another episode on them or something.
Scott: But you can go online and fight.
Scott: get the list of what the packs 10 games were.
Scott: They were all looking pretty good to me.
Scott: Let's see anything else going on and out of the glove.
Rym: But oh, yeah This company use the gloves company.
Rym: Peregrine had a glove and people there was a line to use it and I just didn't.
Rym: I didn't Have time.
Rym: we spent all our time talking to the geek cheek guy and riding that horse.
Rym: Yeah, but I'm not sure what it was But it looked like it was working pretty well and people seem to be digging it.
Rym: But I have a feeling it's cool in the way that that gun mouse was cool.
Rym: I don't know how applicable it is.
Rym: So if anyone tried that out, let us know how it was.
Scott: Basically the what it looked like to me is you could.
Scott: yet you put on this glove that was sort of had like, you know a motion-capture rig kind of stuff, you know the same thing they use for that and You would bind different gestures physical hand gestures to different keys on the keyboard like they opened up.
Scott: I saw during a demo someone was doing Like.
Scott: they opened up notepad and a guy was basically moving his fingers and all sorts of letters were appearing on the screen.
Scott: So like you would go you would take this and you would go into a game and you would like bind like index finger You shoot and middle finger is jump or you know, whatever you are wave your hand back and forth, you know.
Scott: So I wonder how well it works.
Scott: I didn't get to use it myself, but it existed.
Scott: And I noticed no one was trying to sell stupid VR goggles.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: We got to wait on it every year There's some VR goggle that's better.
Rym: But is there not at the point where they're great yet?
Scott: Yep, and I my guess would be that the glove is in the same sort of position But we had a little bit of time before our first panel.
Rym: So we wandered around, you know Like the console freeplay the tabletop area the console freeplay was completely empty, you know kind of just started a
Scott: brand new You know opening of the con
Rym: and the cool enforcers were doing the same kind of thing We used to do when we ran like the Picasso con gaming area.
Rym: They were just setting up random challenges.
Rym: guy was like if you can beat quick man's level and get to quick man Don't even have to beat quick man.
Rym: You win Scott.
Scott: I was dying.
Rym: Scott was unable to get to quick man.
Scott: You know that I can do it right?
Rym: Of course, we stumped him when we pointed out Hey, can I go to flash man's level first beat him?
Scott: And then the thing is you try to beat flash man without dying without any weapons.
Rym: Well, what you do is you beat everyone in the order to get to quick man and then you beat quick man's level Right with flash man exactly.
Rym: actually flash man is pretty easy to beat with the standard gun.
Scott: Yep, he is.
Scott: but the problem is you got to get to him and then beat him without dying.
Scott: I mean usually what will happen if you try to beat flash man right away is you can beat him right away But you'll die at him and then beat him with your next life.
Scott: So to do it without dying is something special especially on difficult mode as opposed to well real regular mode as opposed to easy mode Right.
Scott: Yeah, it was basically get to quick man Which means the only real dangerous stuff is the lasers that instantly kill you.
Scott: and you know, I can do it.
Scott: I'm the Mega Man 2 guy, but I didn't concentrate very much.
Scott: We're chatting it up.
Scott: I had to go to a panel.
Scott: I took two tries at it.
Scott: I got pretty close.
Scott: I didn't make it.
Scott: I probably could have done if I went back later, but I could do it.
Scott: I just don't want to Want me to do it after?
Scott: You know the show I don't know.
Rym: we'll save it.
Rym: We'll do some event with quick man.
Scott: Maybe in the future I could definitely do it.
Rym: There's no question about but this was all just lead up.
Rym: You know extra time before.
Rym: you know, our first panel beyond Candyland in the Raven theater Friday morning.
Rym: So we got there early and the bonus round was there before us and we actually Because the bonus round wanted to film some bonus round in the con with their backdrop before you know They left the room.
Rym: They basically made our panel beyond Candyland 15 minutes late.
Scott: Yep That's alright because our panel was full and it was great as awesome panel.
Rym: I was so amazed when we get to the room and we see you know They're like the route.
Rym: there are a lot of people in the in the bonus round thing But there are a lot of people lined up way early to see beyond Candyland.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know there wasn't much else going on at the con at the time and you know Our panel was had a good name people like board games.
Scott: I noticed that even though there was a lot of tabletop action going at the con a big watsy presence big tabletop area.
Scott: You know all the tabletop tables are busy constantly full the whole con.
Scott: There wasn't that much tabletop panel action, you know Relatively speaking to the amount of tabletop gaming that there was.
Scott: so, you know The fact that we were one of the few tabletop panels with beyond Candyland, I think helped us out.
Rym: One cool thing though.
Rym: We finally, you know, and guy crow was on our plane So we actually we talked to him because he was on this panel and we're all hanging out.
Scott: He was on the you know, the bonus round.
Scott: So when the bonus round was leaving, we're like, hey you ain't guy crow.
Scott: Yeah, I saw you on the plane.
Scott: What's up?
Scott: Yeah, that was it.
Rym: The funny thing was though that they you know quiet in the room they filmed the what the the segment for bonus round with the backdrop of bonus round and It took me back to us trying to do stage things.
Rym: as opposed to the kind of live GeekNights We do where they do like ten takes and keep the guy to do three takes.
Scott: He flubbed it, you know, and it was like, oh everyone does that.
Scott: Okay Even the semi this real professional guy flubs it so we're all good, but the panel went crazy.
Rym: Well, like people freaking loved it people loved it so much.
Scott: They came to our other panels because our first was great.
Rym: You know the first panel, you know We're like who here knows who we are.
Rym: and like four people raise their hands.
Rym: our second panel on Saturday.
Rym: Who here came here because they saw our other panel and like half the room raised their hands.
Rym: Yep and beyond D&D as far as I can tell was like 75% people who came because of our other panels and 25% people who missed beyond D&D attacks last year.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: That's very good.
Rym: It was great.
Scott: I mean it would have been better though to have completely different people fill up the room three times because then we get the widest Coverage but then that also means our first panel sucked and no one wanted to come back.
Rym: But I will call beyond candy land a huge success because for the entire rest of the con Like numerous times like every time we're in a panel room.
Rym: We are in a tabletop gaming room.
Rym: Sorry We'd see people playing like learning how to play like settlers or Puerto Rico or teeny or curricular or something and almost every time They were people who weren't really tabletop gamers who went to the panel and then because of us played one of the games We recommended at PAX.
Rym: Yep, that made me so happy.
Scott: In fact during our beyond candy land right this guy from joystick was in the audience.
Rym: Oh, yeah, Kevin.
Rym: Yeah, Kevin was pretty cool.
Rym: And the saddest thing was he gave me the business card and we're like, hey Let's do something cuz joysticks trying to do this this segment.
Scott: Apparently joystick has some column that's like about tabletop games.
Scott: So he's like, hey, I'll interview you for this column.
Rym: We're like, okay sure whatever and Kevin's pretty cool.
Rym: The problem was he was busy and we were busy and basically the entire rest of packs was hey you want to do this thing?
Rym: No, I gotta do this.
Rym: Hey, you ready now?
Rym: Oh, no, I gotta do this back and forth.
Rym: It's basically neither.
Rym: we were never both free at the same time for the entirety of the con.
Scott: That's all right.
Scott: But basically he he bought Puerto Rico because we said it was so awesome.
Scott: So that was that was pretty cool.
Rym: Yep, so we'll let you know what comes of that.
Rym: We're gonna try to do the phone interview Maybe tomorrow.
Scott: sometime this week We also met up with him at dinner on Sunday and he gave us a copy of risk.
Scott: Halo Wars We'll see about that risk.
Rym: Halo Wars The.
Rym: you look at the box and all I could think was this looks like a joke from something awful Photoshop contest.
Scott: Oh my god, it's so true, but it isn't.
Rym: it is so dead serious.
Rym: It's an actual game.
Rym: It's real.
Rym: I have it.
Rym: We're gonna play it.
Rym: We're gonna review it.
Rym: We have to.
Scott: so, you know, we the one.
Scott: the thing is right.
Scott: we scheduled our panels.
Scott: We told them we don't want to miss any of the concerts.
Scott: We don't want to miss the keynote.
Scott: We don't want to miss the mega strip panel.
Rym: We don't want to miss right and amber and everyone we worked with.
Rym: setting these panels up was super cool And they basically were like, yeah, whatever you want.
Scott: So we had to run from beyond candy land to the keynote and we get to the keynote and they're like well We can't promise you'll get in and we're like fuck.
Rym: Ah, so I have my speaker back and I'm planning like if I don't get in I'm going to pull rank something I never want to do it packs.
Rym: I'll do that like anime cons, but I would never want to be that guy Who's like, you know who I am?
Rym: Let me in right but I was preparing like what I was going to do to get into the keynote No matter what.
Scott: so we get at the end of the line and realize like We're like, let's get in line.
Rym: Anyway, what do we?
Scott: what else we gonna do expecting line to get cut off?
Rym: The funny thing was we met all these punk kids in line who saw like our panel and then had gone to the line.
Rym: We had to do stuff before we went and they were like, wow you guys have to stand in line, too Like yeah, yeah.
Scott: and then Miracle came down.
Rym: We're getting scarily close to being let in.
Rym: we're like we're gonna make it.
Rym: we're gonna make it We're gonna get into this room.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: Yes, it was a miracle.
Scott: the thing is the reason we got in the room is because they rotated the room 90 degrees.
Scott: They didn't rotate the actual room.
Scott: They rotated the chairs and they moved the stage to the other side of the room Which means right that they fit a ton more chairs in there.
Rym: First of all, plus the room was Horizontally vertical as opposed to horizontally horizontal.
Rym: So as a result instead of having you know The why is deep instead of wide they had two screens up on the side of the stage and then they had two more screens.
Scott: It was like they're four screens hanging for the ceiling.
Rym: It was insane and while sitting near the front for pretty much everything we did was really cool.
Rym: If you sat way in the back You had this great spectacle of the stage in the middle and then these four screens splayed out in your peripheral vision.
Scott: It was awesome no matter where you were in the room.
Scott: I could not imagine a better layout for a main event short of an actual auditorium.
Rym: Ron Gilbert for the keynote gave an amazing keynote up to par with last year.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty much covered the same topic as last year too of hey, we grew up doing all this old shit.
Scott: I mean last year right it was Ken Levine talking about.
Scott: I grew up with Logan's run comics Yeah, and it's in this year.
Scott: He's like I grew up on programming for the Atari and an old TI calculator.
Rym: Yep, Ron Gilbert though he get these the two keynotes I've seen at Pax's are just so inspirational every year by the end.
Rym: I'm sitting there thinking man.
Rym: This is it.
Rym: This is what I want to do.
Rym: This is why we're here, and I'm just like super inspired and I want to like make stuff And just like it drives me crazy every year.
Scott: yep immediately following the keynote there was some hustling and Gabe and Tyco came out for their Q's and A's.
Rym: It wasn't as epic for us as last year because you know last year We went up, and we asked a pretty epic question, and I remember we were like I'm Rym I'm Scott and then Jerry's like wow it's like you guys have a show and we're like well
Scott: we do
Rym: This year.
Rym: I was.
Rym: I was like let's ask a question.
Rym: Scott totally wussed out.
Scott: So I was like what are we gonna ask?
Scott: you got nothing?
Rym: I know okay question you had nothing.
Rym: I had a good question.
Rym: I asked him.
Scott: you know I guess your question was good.
Scott: relative to some of the other questions It wasn't like a yeah, fuck yeah question.
Rym: but what I wanted to know was about because I found out they got someone to do art for the Panel rooms this year.
Rym: because remember you know Jerry kind of randomly was like Let's name them and name the panel rooms the wolf man theater the the Raven theater the unicorn theater.
Scott: So serpent is the big was yep.
Rym: this year They had little crests on every panel room.
Rym: very cool for its theme.
Rym: So I was wondering if I could find out what they were gonna name the PAX East rooms And they haven't even thought about that yet.
Scott: Hopefully I can name them.
Scott: I'll name them the Dragon theater.
Rym: no I Mera I would go with a completely different theme like something way out there in the completely off the wall From the ones before now.
Scott: I would continue with the magical beasts.
Rym: No I would go out like name them all adjectives Like the burning theater the intense theater the angry theaters something crazy, okay, it's okay But I would still go with the magical beasts, but why you already made that you get four more magical beasts.
Rym: Magical beasts a completely separate theme that is just so separate all aquatic beasts.
Rym: So what the aboleth?
Rym: yeah, that's a good one.
Rym: That's the best name for theater.
Rym: yet the belay wait Maybe maybe you combine them because how do you name an inn in any Dungeons & Dragons game?
Rym: the?
Rym: Adjective in verb or the adverb the adjective animal anything like that adjective.
Scott: animal theaters.
Rym: so a grunting bore rusting codpiece codpiece.
Scott: oh Man what if you actually themed up like you actually like decorated them like inns and taverns?
Rym: You know packs could do that because of their philosophy of having like.
Rym: you know Anime cons have like the one staff.
Scott: You know you can make one like a tavern one like a space cantina like a Star Wars.
Scott: Actually, there was a Star Wars cantina.
Scott: It was like a LucasArts sponsored room.
Scott: That was just a bit.
Rym: It was very well put together, and yeah, this is the big Star Wars promotion.
Rym: It was very well put together.
Rym: that good music playing and you could get a sith smoothie for a couple bucks.
Scott: Yeah I did not get a system with me.
Rym: They were also taking green-screen pictures of people who are in costume.
Rym: They're actually pretty good-looking.
Scott: Yes, another the Q&A questions were particularly Amazing like oh man epic lols.
Scott: at least the thing is.
Scott: we left early.
Rym: We didn't hang around because it went on way too long.
Scott: Yeah, they really should limit the Q&A lines or something.
Scott: I don't know what they should do.
Rym: not because it's really enjoyable.
Rym: I just it was okay.
Scott: It only wasn't as good as last.
Rym: It only went on way too long because I was hungry.
Scott: Yeah, I was also very not been hungry.
Rym: They wouldn't have not have been too long.
Rym: yep Okay, the other trouble is that they it's great that is democratic But it's tough to screen.
Rym: people are gonna ask a good question versus people are going to be really annoying.
Scott: Yeah, this very relative to the questions you would get at say an anime convention.
Scott: the questions are pretty damn good.
Scott: The thing is they just none of them were like oh my god amazing questions You know.
Scott: and it most of it is like not even questions.
Scott: It's people coming up and telling their story.
Scott: like you know I came here from all the way across the country.
Scott: Oh, man's I'm selling the cookies cookie Brigade.
Scott: Oh, man's and you know those things.
Scott: It's basically everyone make your packs announcements is what it really is the guys who their friend couldn't make it.
Rym: So they made a cardboard stand Awesome, and then they Dave and Tyco let the standee come up on stage, and they look a picture with it.
Rym: I saw that standee all around the con like playing games hanging out with people.
Scott: I feel bad for the guy who was in the picture of the sandy who didn't get to come see.
Rym: now what I would do If I were them is I would have made a standee a fake one or maybe one of myself and just use it as an excuse to get to do all this stuff on the Illusion that I'm doing it for my friend who couldn't make it
Scott: exactly because that standee
Rym: was like a free pass to do anything cool.
Rym: You wanted to do with that kind yep next year sadly.
Rym: I expect to see like a hundred standees.
Scott: So there was a panel on Friday, and it was a Friday night.
Rym: Yes, it was Friday.
Scott: Yep, the winning sucks panel.
Scott: It was so weird because we looked at the schedule before packs and we put a panel in.
Scott: losing should be fun And we see on the schedule a panel winning sucks.
Rym: Well, no it was designing for failure.
Rym: Why winning sucks, and it was done by Jason booth Who's the senior technical designer at Bioware?
Rym: right so big guns kind of guy?
Scott: So we look at this right before looking at who what the name was of the person we're like.
Scott: did they rename our panel?
Scott: We're like no.
Scott: They just put two panels with the same idea.
Rym: what whoa think is there's nothing one.
Rym: There are a ton of panels that basically cover the same topic.
Rym: impacts.
Scott: I know I know But so we're like whoa.
Scott: so of course we had to check out this other panel that did the same exact thing.
Rym: we did Yep, and it was pretty good.
Scott: the guy definitely took a more a lot of good informations But he was he.
Scott: he just sort of spoke monotone Lee you know and read his.
Scott: you know stuff that he had to say.
Scott: Well even from that then when he was doing the Q&A he got a lot more dynamic.
Rym: He took a very textbook approach to it, and he talked a lot.
Rym: He basically covered in a half-hour The like the kinds of topics that if you're already working with games at all you already know all this.
Scott: yep But it was you know it's the kind of stuff that someone with his job has to think about.
Scott: you know like you know You go to a company, and you know you're making a video game, and you're gonna say yeah look We're gonna make it so that you know if you get shot the player lays on the ground and can't do anything.
Scott: And you know you had to sell that to the person you're making this game for.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: do you really want to let you make a game like that?
Scott: So it was.
Scott: it was pretty interesting stuff going on.
Rym: so along his lines They reminded me back to the keynote of the whole theme that Look at the people who did the keynotes and a lot of the people who are the big developers at these games now these game Studios and making games.
Rym: they're by and large people who like tinkered and had programming skill and like we're forced to Push themselves and create early on and I don't know what I see this trend where they're like now There's so many people who want to work in video games, but a lot of these people do not have computer skills like.
Rym: they're not Hacking nerds.
Rym: They're just gamers.
Rym: They're people who play games who want to make games.
Rym: It's almost the exact same thing that happened to anime after the first couple of generations of anime directors.
Scott: It's definitely all interesting.
Scott: also I noticed in the keynote and it's some of the other panels and such there was like.
Scott: People were really really like they.
Scott: a lot of these game professional people just couldn't get over the fact that Roger Ebert says he doesn't think games are art and Like.
Scott: they just kept bitching about it and obviously everyone disagreed with it.
Scott: and obviously Roger Ebert is wrong though He may be right about many other things and his columns are usually very entertaining if you read them online.
Scott: But it's like the game like professional people just like couldn't get over that and they mentioned it like at a bunch of battles.
Scott: And I thought that that was interesting because he said it's so long ago and it's still like, you know Killing these people that this dude said this.
Scott: it's like come on get over it.
Rym: And I was still like Scott pointed out kind of sad that almost all the panels were either like meta panels about game journalism or like meetups and things like that or they were primarily about the video game industry and almost Nothing about any other like other than us.
Rym: There was almost nothing about any other kind of game.
Scott: There was a GM a game a GM panel Art of the Dungeon Master aka the art of being the eye in a World of Warcraft raid.
Scott: Yeah You know, there were a lot of panels that were like, you know, hey, you know, you know this group, you know Like we do this show.
Scott: Here's our panel.
Scott: We do this show.
Rym: There was also the.
Rym: I got laid off.
Rym: now what panel that Alex went?
Scott: said he went to this panel.
Scott: That was a strategic game design.
Scott: But actually what he said what it was about was a guy had actually had all these really really interesting Statistics about like, you know games that have a trailer sell this much.
Scott: games with a demo sell this much.
Scott: game with a trailer and A demo sell this much times with no trailer and no demo sell this much.
Scott: now.
Rym: this that data was fascinating.
Rym: It was also horrifying because the games that sell the most are the ones with a good trailer and no demo.
Rym: if you have a demo Your games probably not gonna sell that.
Scott: a lot of people get all they want from your game out of the demo and they never Need to play your game anymore.
Rym: Think about it If you make a game that is a novel concept like it has a concept and that is what is selling the game like it?
Rym: does this new mechanic or something?
Rym: a Gamer type person once they have played that mechanic unless it is a mechanic of death will have no need to ever play it again.
Scott: Here's a perfect example trying.
Scott: if I saw the trailer if there was no demo, I would have just bought it.
Scott: But there was a demo.
Scott: I still haven't bought it yet.
Scott: Yeah Well, you know I might buy it when three people want to play it, but I haven't bought it.
Rym: Pointed out about that explosion game, you know the guy who blows himself up to do stuff.
Scott: It's a great awesome one of the pecs 10.
Rym: I don't think so.
Scott: I think it might have been.
Rym: I'll look through.
Rym: but anyway He pointed out that it's a great and novel mechanic for 25 levels and then it's 25 levels of.
Rym: they ran out of ideas.
Scott: Yep All right.
Scott: So let's see.
Scott: What else happened?
Scott: Is that all for Friday?
Rym: keep petering out?
Rym: I thought you had notes.
Scott: I do but I lose my space in the notes.
Scott: cuz I don't have a marker cuz I'm idea screen iPhone screen.
Rym: So after that we're hanging out in the DS lounge lounge to none of those other sissy lounges and one thing.
Rym: Pax was trying to break the world record of the most DS is played in one space at the same time because The world record was like 300 and something.
Scott: Yeah, I figured they would get up to a thousand something, but they only got what 900 I think they blew it away by - you know by getting like 300% more but they still it wasn't.
Scott: I thought it was gonna be thousand.
Rym: I didn't think it would be because People didn't care.
Rym: I didn't want to bother like getting my DS out going up there waiting.
Rym: Yeah Oh, well, but that night the concerts that you know, the Monday concert this year They really a concerts won.
Rym: on Friday concert the problem this year wasn't really a problem per se but they the concerts were definitely led toward Saturday like Saturday was the big Concert and Friday was a lot more laid-back and a lot less looked forward to by a lot of people.
Scott: a lot of people seem To leave the Friday concert early, even though it ended with MC front a lot I mean a Friday had on a Monoguchi who they're okay I mean, I'm not like a huge fan of them, but they put on an okay show.
Rym: I guess I like them but I like their music in the background or while I'm playing games.
Rym: They don't like it so much like as an active concert.
Scott: Yeah, then those Metroid metal.
Scott: They were pretty cool You know, it was like it's sort of a combination of a bunch of different guys from like, you know arm cannon and some other.
Scott: you know video game metal bands and They played Metroid metal they were.
Scott: their name was not false advertising and it was Metroid songs in metal and there was okay.
Scott: But it wasn't like, you know, oh my god is the greatest.
Rym: But by then the front came out and did his usual front set and it was awesome.
Scott: I'm see front a lot like the house.
Rym: I love em.
Rym: see front a lot Oh shit even though it Definitely a lot of people like the place was barely Crowded at all by the end when we left.
Rym: like a lot of people walked out after the first.
Rym: it was Very late, in fact, I brought my pit boy puppet to the Friday concert and Early on there's a whole bunch of other pit boys.
Rym: So we all get together almost everyone with one left before Metroid metal even came out.
Rym: I was like the last one there.
Scott: Yeah Anyway, that was pretty much it for Friday.
Scott: We went to bed after those concerts.
Rym: I was just.
Scott: I was so wrecked I was wrecked and then we woke up on Saturday.
Rym: Luckily Our Saturday panel on Saturday was not until like 1130.
Rym: So we had plenty of time Or no, I think it was a 1030 regardless.
Rym: It was not as early as the Sunday panel.
Rym: So losing should be fun.
Rym: We had to move up to the Wolfman theater.
Rym: now I know for the Friday panel beyond Candyland We had asked if we could get two wireless mics and they pulled some shenanigans and got one.
Rym: So Saturday we go to the Wolfman theater and we're like, can we get wireless mics?
Rym: and they're like, we don't have any.
Rym: Yeah, some other theater took him yesterday for some panel that asked for him and I was like, ah, damn it That was us.
Scott: We started from our future selves.
Scott: Damn it, damn it, damn it.
Scott: we stole from The the Wolfman theater to the Raven theater and then we went from the Wolfman theater the Raven theater to the Wolfman theater.
Scott: Thus we didn't have wireless mics for losing should be fun.
Rym: losing should be.
Rym: fun though was in a bigger theater the Wolfman theater Yeah, and there are crazy ton of people 100% but it felt like 90% and it was definitely more.
Scott: it was actually the most Attended panel because it was a bigger room and it was 90% and also people kept trickling in as the panel went on.
Rym: I think it was full by the end.
Rym: Yeah, it might have been and like one guy walked out But his cell phone was going.
Rym: so
Scott: it was really weird because basically I had to hold this mic that was intended only for people Sitting at the table and I was holding it up in the air so I could stand and if I would have sat down No one would have seen me because I would have been behind this table.
Scott: Meanwhile not on a raised platform I cleverly took the podium.
Scott: There's only one podium.
Scott: It was not very not fair at all.
Rym: Well, you could have taken it.
Rym: You just didn't want it enough.
Scott: I took it first But it was he was sitting on the podium was a sort of in a bad position all the way on the right wall.
Scott: Much better to be in the middle of the room.
Rym: Losing should be fun when really well people seem to really dig it.
Rym: the the moment in that panel the two times I've run it that is the moment I wait for is when I put up that slide of that.
Rym: choose your own adventure book UFO 5440. yeah, cuz that's when like everything clicks for the audience.
Scott: Apparently that book changed Jared Sorensen's life in some way.
Rym: I Readed that book from like my elementary school library Yeah, and I didn't realize it was broken because I just like read the book chrono like page by page just to see all the endings.
Scott: Yeah, it was a good panel panel.
Scott: also we got really good questions at the end of that panel.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't do too many, but they were all like really great question.
Rym: I left like 10 minutes at the end for questions and and even afterward people ask great questions And it was just.
Rym: overall it was a great panel, and I was glad we did it.
Rym: I'm gonna.
Rym: we're not gonna do this panel again But what I'm going to do is break it up into two or three separate panels and do them over the years Like I want to do a panel just about victory conditions, and then a separate panel about losing in role-playing games.
Scott: Yep, so is this one who went into the PC area or not?
Scott: I don't remember well.
Rym: The thing is I want to point out that when we walked out of this panel You know Jared was there at the panel.
Rym: I think Luke was in the audience to Lou Crane and Jared was like that was a great panel too bad.
Rym: Everything you said was wrong.
Rym: Yep, but no all his point was and he's right.
Rym: I just didn't make this clear enough.
Rym: He said that if the future of all game if the future of gaming and losing is you know the dwarf fortress style enriching the?
Rym: World procedural content generation, then there will be no more narrative.
Rym: and he had this whole like Question and response and this whole like criticism of my panel.
Rym: and the only response I had was yeah I didn't make it clear that it's not the end of all of gaming.
Rym: It's just that procedural content like that will fill in the gaps and the background for the narrative.
Scott: Yeah, that's you know there's a lot to be said there And you know you can't say everything there is to say in a 60-minute panel.
Rym: Well, that's the.
Rym: that's the thing with all.
Rym: three of the panels We did at PAX were not the kind of specific detailed like very in-depth panel.
Scott: They were very much the low-hanging fruit of you guys gaming panels the kind of the kind of panels We do or the kind of things to get you thinking not to make a big statement or anything.
Rym: yep But we're gonna now that we've gotten the low-hanging fruit out of the way We've got to do the crazy specific like awesome.
Scott: I want to do some panels like about real like Individual games like this is natural selection.
Scott: You know or this is Puerto Rico.
Scott: I want to do that kind of stuff You know.
Scott: I wonder how many people want to see it though It's hard to say.
Rym: I'm gauging that we gained a following by the end of packs.
Rym: So I think next year and impacts East we're going to be able to.
Rym: People will come to our panels just because we're running them regardless of what the title is.
Rym: hopefully So we'll get like this following half and hopefully the other half will be random people walking in.
Scott: Yeah, it sounds like about that.
Scott: I don't remember if this is when we went there, but it's like about the PC gaming and we didn't go there till later.
Scott: Yeah, I just want to talk about it now.
Rym: Just cuz I remember it because right after this we went to the tabletop gaming area, and we played that little Tile game.
Scott: hive all right the hive game.
Rym: It was a fun little game.
Rym: you have these like.
Rym: you have little hive and you place all your pieces Then you jump them around.
Rym: you try to surround the other person's queen and while it's a game That's fiddly and feels like it go on forever You it is a game where a clever player can force equip a mate effectively, and I liked it.
Rym: I might just buy it.
Scott: you know that where you gonna find it.
Rym: I'll find it somewhere eBay if I have to.
Scott: That's not the kind of game.
Scott: It looks like it's easy to get but yeah, it's interesting game.
Scott: We had little bugs, and you you put them out and you position them And you you know.
Rym: Scott thought he had me because he went for the quick victory.
Rym: the problem was for the direct room.
Rym: He's quick direct victory, so he you know he's almost surrounded my guy.
Rym: But then I basically just locked in all his guys who were surrounding my guy.
Rym: He couldn't finish it, and they're just leisurely surrounded his queen and ended the game.
Rym: He couldn't stop me yeah.
Rym: Well the only way to stop me was to put take all of his pressure off of my queen.
Rym: it was great Yep, it was okay And we didn't actually play.
Rym: But we taught these cool people who were inspired by our panel to play Puerto Rico.
Scott: well No first he played blackest with some people.
Rym: Oh, yeah, we ran into those people who played block is with him And then we played Puerto Rico.
Scott: yep, well we taught the same people how to play Puerto Rico.
Rym: Yep But we didn't actually play it and we didn't get to play all the way through.
Rym: we played a couple of rounds and Definitely it is so much better to have someone else teach you a game than to learn it yourself.
Rym: Yeah, yeah definitely I feel like we should run panels that are basically learn out like an hour-long panel learn how to play Puerto Rico and teeny.
Scott: Well, that's why I'm sort of excited to get some gaming space at PAX East as opposed to you know some panel space because I Can just basically teach people games all day.
Scott: and the best thing is you go to a gaming con.
Scott: right it'll take you a long Time to learn how to play a game for the instruction book like possibly an hour if it's a complicated game worth playing and then You basically lost an hour of your convention.
Scott: if someone taught you how to play the game you could have saved 45 convention minutes.
Scott: That's a big freaking deal all right?
Scott: So it's all about teaching people how to play games and then learning how to play games from other people.
Rym: so pretty much right after that though the reason we had to bail is that we had to go line up for the make a strip and then you know go get some food and The make a strip did not actually happen at that point.
Rym: and after basically we get there And we line up we get it really good seats And it's delayed a little bit.
Rym: so basically we sat there, and they did a Q&A again.
Rym: They didn't even have Jerry there because he he formed babby yep, so it's Scott Kurtz and Gabe.
Scott: right.
Scott: well Mike Krahulik and Basically, they're trying to get his you know computer to work at the Photoshop.
Rym: I'll sum this up greens We sat there for 45 minutes while he clicked on the same resolution over and over again And it didn't work.
Rym: and meanwhile people ask questions, but I got to say They were answering the questions pretty funnily, but Gabe and Tycho together is where the magic happens.
Rym: They just like the answers were classy in the wide well sense, but they were not Full-on classy.
Rym: they were not.
Rym: they were not as classy as they could have been.
Scott: yeah I wasn't lining up for more Q&A I was lining up to see make a strip, and I did not happen.
Rym: so eventually We just bailed and got some food at that awesome.
Scott: Kurtz did mention Kate Beaton so he gets points.
Rym: he did and we wooed with a few other people that would.
Scott: yep That was pretty you know.
Rym: Anyway, yep, so if you went back to tabletop hanging out There's some more.
Rym: a Luke Crane was running a whole bunch of burning wheel on Some burning wheel with some sort of like court of undead something something.
Scott: I want to play that.
Scott: what the hell was that yeah?
Rym: I walked in one before and one player was pleading his case before the court, and I heard the words your honor I did not know with the time that they were vampires.
Rym: Yeah, it was so great.
Scott: whatever that game was Luke I want get.
Scott: send me a copy and a PDF also.
Scott: I want to play it now.
Rym: apparently Luke is running like.
Rym: he ran this campaign.
Rym: There was a continuation of a campaign he ran at PAX last year.
Rym: I didn't know this I didn't hear this and also Jared Sorenson of all people had never until that time played the sword.
Scott: Oh my gosh.
Rym: so he was kind of geeking about it and he was the elf.
Rym: and It's hard to be the elf because you feel like you can just kill everyone and take the sword But that never works out.
Scott: No It doesn't.
Rym: but we grind into some other people later who played the sword and they loved it and people People are really diggin.
Scott: It's a mouse guard demos.
Rym: I saw yeah, and later I was happy.
Rym: you know I got to talk to taiko for a brief moment And he recognized me enough to be like yeah, I heard some people were playing this playing mouse guard at this con.
Rym: I was like yeah, it was yesterday.
Rym: You missed it.
Rym: He was like.
Scott: The thing is I think he's just really good like what he.
Scott: you know the way he ties like you go up to him and Say hey, how about the game summer flange, but yeah, I heard about that summer flange.
Rym: No, no because he mentioned mouse guard unprompted to me.
Scott: really yes, huh?
Rym: I'll talk about that later when it happened.
Scott: But basically where we played a bunch of Dominion with row and Jeremy and where you know we saw all the people playing Dominion Dominion is a game like if the game got really popular on board game geek, and I checked it out and basically It's a game.
Scott: That's a collectible card game, but it's not collectible right.
Scott: so that makes me excited because that's what I always wanted.
Scott: But then an anime Boston.
Scott: we opened it up, and I read the rules and I was like These rules don't look so good.
Rym: from reading the rules the game looked a bit shit, and I guess here's the deal.
Rym: We didn't back it.
Scott: the game was hyped up big time, so you know what.
Scott: I don't knock it without trying it.
Scott: So it packs.
Scott: someone knew how to play.
Scott: we didn't have to teach it to ourselves.
Scott: It's fucking awesome, I bought Dominion and Dominion intrigue online today, it's already shipped.
Scott: It's coming.
Rym: It's not a hardcore game in the old sense like.
Rym: it's not a Puerto Rico or a teeny, but it plays quick.
Rym: It's real fun.
Rym: It's just it has these novel mechanics that I want to pull into other games.
Scott: Oh, yeah, the whole making your deck while you're playing as a new set coming out Dominion seaside with some water cards.
Scott: So I'm all about Dominion.
Rym: get as much Dominion as you can and the game is so different every time you play because you Kind of create the world in which you're going to make the game basically.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you bought.
Scott: you get this box of cards, and there's like all kinds of different cards in there But you pick ten different ones every time you play and if you get multiple boxes.
Scott: There's just so many exponentially more combinations of ten cards you can pick to play the game with.
Scott: so it's like oh fuck.
Scott: Yes, you can play this game forever like with three sets.
Scott: You're never gonna run out of combinations ever.
Rym: right This game will entertain you for a long time, but like one game like this the final scores are like I think row one with I can't.
Scott: the first not 23 the first game.
Scott: I won by one 28 over your 27 yeah, and the second game.
Scott: my final score was negative one.
Scott: yes I got hose.
Rym: Scott score was negative one in the curse game where basically we went through the entire curse deck in like Like almost nothing is everyone kept getting cursed constantly.
Scott: I and I won the first game because I managed to get rid of a lot of my curses But in the second game I was just burdened with too many curses.
Scott: I couldn't do anything.
Rym: But then we had a really nice game was like the opposite of the bastard game where it was mostly constructive stuff and everyone else Tried to do some cool combinations Doing look what felt good of playing like.
Scott: I got like a whole bunch of markets and they played him success.
Rym: I'm playing all these combos.
Rym: He's like market market market market market.
Rym: meanwhile I just bought silver and I bought provinces silver provinces silver provinces And I just won the game with a million points.
Scott: Silver is definitely the way to go for reals And gold and a lot of gold - gold is okay gold is great gold is you kidding?
Scott: I like gold.
Scott: you got to get rid of your copper.
Scott: That's the thing that's getting rid of the copper and the curse.
Rym: I was trashing copper.
Scott: Yeah, you make more room.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Also.
Rym: I got all these cards.
Rym: Let me discard out of my hand.
Rym: It was great.
Rym: Yeah now as we're walking around down to the bodega Yeah, they go to get some beverages a little known secret in tabletop gaming that area.
Rym: go down the escalators out of the convention center Turn right go right across the street.
Rym: There's a bodega.
Rym: get all your beverages there.
Rym: They got every beverage and they also have.
Rym: they also have a mini snap mini crunchy doughnuts 25 cents ice cream sandwiches And the guy who runs is pretty cool.
Rym: We ran into a guy who had nothing to do with Pax But he's just like some guy who works in the area like he owns a business.
Scott: I mean, you know, I think he worked at a steakhouse as a waiter and he was like, you know what?
Rym: Pax is like the best thing to happen to Seattle.
Rym: you guys spend so much money.
Rym: Seriously.
Rym: Yeah, and you're all cool Mm-hmm.
Rym: Yeah, people didn't have as many good things to say about certain other unnamed cons that happen in Seattle.
Scott: Yeah, we played this game called a quarto.
Rym: It sucks.
Scott: It sucks It's just.
Scott: it looked like some sort of abstract strategy game But really it's just the left-right game and there's nothing to it.
Rym: Yep Scott won it like all of the three times we played it and then we put it away and that was the end of that.
Scott: That's the end of that.
Rym: but there was this game.
Rym: We're walking out to the bodega and we see these guys these people playing this game With all these plastic dog figures really big ones and they had them all lined up like in a row.
Rym: So we're like man does the game play that where you guys just bored.
Rym: but they're like now the game plays this way.
Rym: And I was like this game looks like it sucks and they're like, yeah, but we're gonna try it.
Rym: So I gave him my business card.
Rym: I was like, alright, I do a radio show.
Rym: Let me know how bad this game sucks when I forgot about it.
Rym: like two hours later I get this phone call from number I don't recognize and this guy's just like that dog game sucks ass and that's it.
Rym: That's all he said.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So it's good to know a lot of people playing interesting games Like.
Scott: there's a lot of people played this game wasabi.
Scott: That was like a sushi making game.
Rym: Jared was intrigued by that game.
Scott: Yeah, I was intrigued by it as well You know, it looked good.
Scott: I mean I get to play it.
Scott: but you know What are the games that I see people playing as primarily I saw people playing munchkin and Dominion and one point.
Scott: I taught like 10 people how to play a curricula at once.
Scott: That was pretty good.
Rym: That was actually on this day you.
Rym: basically we saw these people playing a curricula Learning how to play and we're like they're like, yeah, we were inspired by your panels.
Rym: We just got the game.
Rym: We're gonna play it.
Rym: So Scott's about to teach them how to play and I noticed next to them is another group of people and I thought they were Playing a curricula, but no they were trying to learn.
Rym: so I was like Listen to that guy.
Rym: He'll teach you how to play.
Scott: So I taught everyone how to play a curricula laser.
Rym: I met one of the guys who played a curricula in the bathroom and he's like, yeah, I totally won Hahaha, so at this moment, you know We realized there's this big Steve Jackson area and we see of all people Steve Jackson.
Scott: I saw it on the Twitter's like Steve Jackson signing under the escalator.
Scott: and behold there he is under the escalator.
Scott: Yeah, I we saw seen him in like five years.
Rym: So we we went up to him and Philip Reed was there too is another.
Rym: he's the CEO of Steve Jackson games.
Scott: they're making man Steve Jackson games like the munchkin must be making them so much fucking money.
Rym: Oh my god, especially, you know munchkin is kind of cool the way they've got it like, you know while we're talking some guy comes up who's a fan of Steve Jackson and games and they gave him this coin and It.
Rym: they have the rule for the coin changes like whenever Steve Jackson game feels like it.
Rym: So you go online.
Rym: you can find out what the rule is.
Rym: If you've got that coin, it changes the game of munchkin with everyone else you're playing.
Scott: I am.
Rym: So the munchkin wasn't that good early on because it was just kind of this Okay card game, but now that it is nothing more than a meta game.
Rym: It's like it's cooler in my eyes.
Rym: It's a game.
Rym: it has that magic of what magic the gathering had before the internet.
Rym: You'd show up at a game and someone whiffs out this crazy card and you're like, oh shit.
Scott: Well, I mean, you know It's a non collectible game that plays like a collectible card game sort of which what I like about?
Scott: You know Dominion, but it's not actually a good game.
Rym: Oh, it has desire to play but it has all these meta rules and it encourages meta gaming.
Rym: I mean if you wear munchkin merchandise you get a bonus.
Rym: Yeah So what if a guy comes with like a hundred munchkin t-shirts on?
Rym: yeah Oh, man, so we go up to Steve Jackson and we won't tell the whole story again.
Rym: But we got closure on the previous Steve Jackson story.
Rym: the last time we had talked to Steve Jackson There were unresolved issues.
Rym: We got closure on all of them.
Scott: Yeah, it was very good time.
Scott: Steve Jackson was awesome.
Rym: We're gonna try to like get an interview with him.
Rym: or actually I'd really like to talk to Phillip Reed because that guy seemed really Really cool.
Scott: Yeah, definitely seemed like he knows going on But
Rym: apparently the Steve Jackson story at PAX was that he personally did not go to the last packs But people in his organization did
Scott: and he had all these like guys who had shirts that were like, you know Like they're like.
Scott: they're like Steve Jackson games secret crew or whatever.
Rym: So he basically he was forced to go to PAX and he was like PAX was super awesome.
Rym: But there is more Steve Jackson.
Rym: We'll get back to that.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: so after all that we're walking around looking for stuff to do before the lineup for the crazy awesome Saturday night concerts and We see the bring your own computer area and Scott's like, why don't we just see if we can get in there?
Scott: Well, actually we forgot to mention on Friday.
Scott: We went into the you know, use a computer they provide for you area Which is all these Dell machines like hundreds of them.
Scott: It's crazy.
Rym: I'll say this.
Rym: it would have been cool Except that steam and valve are assholes when it comes to land gaming and they basically fucked packs.
Scott: Yeah Well, I mean the thing was if you wanted to play a game that was installed like if you wanted to play counter-strike or tf2 You were in business like it was you know, the thing is you want to play some NS?
Scott: Sorry, no go.
Rym: not only that you couldn't even log into your own steam account because of the way valve runs.
Rym: these things Yeah, tags had no control over that.
Rym: those like what can I say?
Scott: Yeah, it's basically all those machines are provided by sponsors I'm pretty sure like Intel Dell Steam whoever, you know, whoever provides them.
Scott: I don't even know right?
Scott: so it's not something to see.
Scott: You know packs has a lot of control over but you know they basically install games on there and that's what you can play.
Scott: and if case you didn't bring your own computer and a lot of People go in there and play because a lot of people want to play Team Fortress 2 or Left 4 Dead or whatever.
Scott: So there you go.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It was okay and a lot of people were playing Left 4 Dead.
Rym: But then you know, we wanted to go into.
Rym: bring your own computer area, but you need a special badge.
Rym: Look at penny arcade and Pax's brilliance.
Rym: The best way to stop theft is just you.
Rym: you can only go in if you brought a computer.
Rym: Yep, so it already limits it to.
Rym: the people are into that sort of thing.
Scott: So I go up to the guy, you know, there's like foreign forces at the door.
Scott: There's no way you're getting in that room unless you brought your own computer, right and I'm like, hey, listen, I'm a speaker I didn't bring my own computer But I just want to go around and look at the sweet modded rigs in there and the guys just like come on I'll show
Rym: you around.
Rym: Well, no first he's like.
Rym: no, I can't let it just let you in.
Rym: He's like but you know what.
Rym: just follow me I'll take you around man.
Rym: So he takes us in and we got to look at like all the awesome cases.
Scott: Yeah, and that was where I saw.
Scott: the winner You know of the mod case contest was the NFC systems guy and is it was a deserve to be the winner.
Scott: It was so fucking awesome.
Rym: I gotta say though that that case with the vacuum tubes on it I thought it was cool and while the judges gave them a bad criticism for the external power supply I thought the external power supply was awesome.
Scott: I think I think the external power supply was awesome.
Scott: I think he just needed to style up the external power supply for some extra awesomes.
Scott: Yeah, it was basically just an external power supply.
Rym: The cool thing is it was like an entirely different con in that room.
Rym: It reminded me of the land part as they used to go to.
Scott: when I mean basically, right?
Scott: You look at the way Pax goes and there are a lot of enforcers who stay in one area Like the like.
Scott: if you look at like the console area at Pax was basically the equivalent of all of game katsu.
Scott: Right as they say game katsu in there.
Scott: if you went in that room and didn't leave it It was no different than being a game in the game area of katsu kata not leaving it All right minus the arcade machines going in the PC land area.
Scott: It's basically like going to any old land party and you just don't leave and a lot of people just went to that land party And that's that was their con the land party.
Scott: It's totally awesome.
Rym: I'm thinking for Pax East.
Scott: if I can swing it with ax East everyone bring your own computer.
Rym: It's NS2 tribes - I don't know because we're viable.
Scott: we called it.
Rym: we still have to talk to Khalil and all we have to set up what we're doing for Pax East.
Rym: we might be doing Too much stuff at Pax East.
Rym: we might be much like Gabe and Tycho ghosts at Pax as in we're only doing events and then we disappear.
Scott: This is like we're gonna have people do arrange some of this stuff in our name.
Scott: We're gonna make it happen.
Scott: Even if we're not physically they're making it happen.
Rym: Yes, but Pax East we can't talk about Pax East But bring your own computer to Pax East trust me.
Scott: I'm gonna bring in mine.
Rym: I'm gonna have to upgrade mine before I bring it.
Rym: I'm not hardcore enough.
Scott: I just need to get one of those carrying straps for mine.
Rym: So the Saturday night concert freeze-pop had new songs Totally awesome, even though the dude retired.
Rym: Yeah, that was sad But you know what?
Rym: It was.
Rym: it was very.
Rym: it was a very touching moment when he announced his retirement and then as like this final like the big Song for him they did for his spot forever.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It almost brought a tear to my eye.
Rym: It was really cute.
Rym: But Paul and storm I was surprised.
Scott: like how many freeze-pop songs I knew it's like.
Scott: oh I know all these songs.
Rym: It's funny because freeze-pop was a band that was basically catapulted to newfound success like a re success because of these games.
Scott: But they know it.
Scott: It's not like it was like, you know, oh, we're not.
Scott: we're trying to avoid it.
Scott: It's like they know it and they embrace it.
Scott: They're like, yeah, we know that we're.
Rym: They like.
Rym: it was very heartfelt when they pointed out that look you guys had packs like people like you.
Rym: You made us happen Mm-hmm, but now I'm glad people know who they were.
Rym: You know early on like like I'd say six months before packs.
Rym: I only knew freeze-bop as that band that did.
Scott: Alex said he didn't know who they were until they played that song which of course is the last one they played.
Scott: But anyway, yeah, so Paul and storm come out and I didn't really know who they were at all But I knew that they were obviously Some sort of geeky and awesome people because they they sang with emcee front lot a little bit.
Scott: Yeah the previous night.
Scott: So I'm like, huh?
Scott: I wonder what how those people do.
Scott: I don't know any of their songs.
Rym: I enjoyed them thoroughly.
Scott: They were like the best.
Scott: I mean like Jonathan Colton was awesome.
Scott: But like I knew his stuff.
Scott: so like Paul and storm I didn't know their stuff.
Scott: So it was like oh shit.
Scott: This is fucking great.
Rym: I'm gonna do everything.
Rym: I want to see if they'll do an anime con.
Scott: They're gonna be in New Haven with Jonathan Colton in the relatively near future.
Rym: No, I'm going to do everything in my power to get them to come to Connecticut.
Rym: Imagine that fuck.
Rym: Yeah, that would be like the biggest thing ever.
Rym: Yes I don't know.
Rym: I gotta try.
Scott: but Joe Cohen and Paul storm in Connecticut.
Rym: Joe would probably like Connecticut.
Scott: He's it lives in Brooklyn.
Scott: Why doesn't he?
Scott: you know, he'd come on over.
Scott: We'll work on it.
Rym: Yeah, but the thing is with Paul and storm is like some of their bits were funnier than other bits.
Rym: But the bit where they were doing like they were basically doing impressions of other musicians.
Rym: That was like the funniest thing they did.
Scott: song was awesome.
Rym: Oh, there's also every time they did something for the ladies They definitely combine the filthy kind of songs with the stagemanship.
Scott: Well, I mean, that's the thing is the most problem with filk is that filk usually means no talent.
Scott: You know one thing that I realized That was a burn.
Scott: one thing I realized is that all the musicians that they had at PAX this year We're like like I didn't really fully realize like the at the crazy high levels of musical talent that were present on the stage Like the dude like emcee front lots bassist like also played guitar also played the kazoo very very well.
Scott: you know, it's like.
Scott: Paul and storm are obviously incredibly musically talented.
Scott: They could play all sorts of stuff.
Scott: You know, it was just sort of like, you know how talented all these people were.
Scott: You know You could tell.
Scott: I could tell like I I'm not musically talented.
Scott: I can tell by the pics, but I can tell musical talent when I see it.
Rym: But the thing about Paul and storm, you know what they really remind me of Dana Carvey.
Rym: It's the musical stand-up act you think.
Rym: so musical stand-up is so wonderful because I think a Dana Carvey plus Simon and Garfunkel.
Rym: How rare is it to have someone who is both musically talented and comedically talented?
Scott: Yeah, kinda.
Rym: I mean Paul and storm.
Rym: I look forward to seeing you guys in the future.
Rym: You guys were great And I got download all their musics and of course Joko the fact that Paul and storm sang backup vocals for Joko like Joko Turned together.
Rym: So it's sort of like, you know, Joko basically does the same set and like every year Like it was the exact same thing - the Rick roll Yep, and he didn't got Rick rolled by the audience instead.
Rym: That was so beautiful.
Scott: Then he's like, yeah, I deserve this.
Rym: He comes out everyone share the car gets quiet.
Scott: One thing is that last year it seemed like John, you know, obviously, you know This is probably not true.
Scott: But at least Jonathan Coulton's presence on stage last year was sort of like, you know, yeah, I'm doing the concert All right this year.
Scott: He was like smiling and he couldn't like contain himself this year.
Scott: So, you know that was a much awesome.
Rym: But what you know?
Rym: the audience gets quiet and before he can start singing and suddenly you're all these people yelling in the background And then you realize that they're all in unison.
Rym: It was beautiful Yeah, but he basically did the same set he did last year and I have a feeling that he does the same set at every.
Scott: You know, when is he had a new song?
Scott: that's a reason.
Rym: come on Joe co-writers new songs But he's probably right.
Rym: him now while it was basically the same set He had Paul and storm singing backup vocals with him And that made it like was like all the songs over again because it added so much I had Molly the girl do.
Rym: clearly that was really good.
Rym: Ooh lay lay ooh, coo lay lay.
Rym: Does anyone get that joke, maybe?
Rym: I All started when I drink 40 glasses of money as a side packs is great because I can make inside Baseball jokes about gaming and like three quarters the audience will get it.
Rym: I make anime jokes about recent anime at Otakon and no one has any idea what I'm talking about.
Scott: Yep Let's see.
Scott: What are we?
Scott: are we winding down here pretty much on Saturday at least.
Rym: Yeah, so Sunday Sunday we couldn't Seattle.
Rym: I love you, but you do not have the breakfast that you we can get in New York.
Scott: Yeah, you have crepes, but you don't have like fucking bagels or there's like one bagel place.
Scott: That's like down by the water.
Scott: That's hard to get to and wasn't open when we needed to be open.
Rym: However, what Seattle does?
Scott: where the fucking breakfast sandwiches?
Scott: Yeah, basically need a bacon egg and cheese on a croissant.
Rym: The only quick breakfast we could get was at the bodega.
Rym: I had a can of Red Bull and a KitKat for breakfast.
Scott: on morning I went to a deli and I got three pancakes for three dollars is fucking awesome.
Rym: You know what I can say in New York while it was a KitKat and Red Bull breakfast It was a white chocolate KitKat.
Rym: We don't get that shit.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: We went to that the Mexican place in the mall and we got an orange juice and a quesadilla for breakfast.
Scott: That was actually a really good breakfast.
Scott: that totally revived me.
Rym: However, why does that place not have breakfast burritos?
Scott: He could have gotten a burrito burrito.
Rym: That was too much.
Scott: Yeah, I needed like the egg salsa burrito with some cheese and some peppers and onion.
Scott: That would have been a fucking.
Rym: but we get into the convention Early with our badges to go set up for beyond D&D because this is 10 fucking a.m People are already lined up.
Scott: I don't know how the hell they got in there.
Rym: people snuck into the con before they were supposed to and got in line for beyond D&D with normal attendee badges and the Enforcers to their credit who were at the room did not kick them out did not say hey, how'd you get in?
Scott: They were like, all right.
Scott: Yeah, the room did not fill.
Scott: But the room, you know It started out about half full and then the rest sort of filled in as the panel went on.
Scott: I can't blame people for not showing up.
Scott: It was about 10 a.m.
Scott: On Sunday.
Rym: It was about 75% full when we started and it was about 90% full by the time we ended.
Scott: Yeah, it was good.
Scott: It wasn't a bet.
Rym: None of our panels had a bad turnout, you know, yeah I mean it was we had more people there than we got at anything in Connecticut, but we ran beyond D&D.
Scott: It was a pretty difficult running of the end.
Rym: I was a little tired.
Rym: I got.
Rym: I got sidetracked once or twice.
Rym: We were definitely not fully on game, but Scott was on fire with the jokes.
Rym: He made up for me being so tired.
Scott: Hey, we let's see.
Scott: And then right.
Scott: so here's the awesome thing is that we noticed when we arrived To the beyond D&D that one of the panels in the room They basically have black tape and they tape over panels when they're done
Rym: We
Scott: noticed that one of the panels in the middle of the day like 1 p.m On Sunday was taped over even though it didn't happen yet.
Scott: I don't even know a panel it was so it was cancelled.
Rym: I'm like, okay, so we're in the room.
Scott: We got our awesome enforcer in the room and Jared Sorensen is like I want to do action castle.
Scott: So suddenly I'm like one of the panels in this room is canceled.
Rym: Yep, so we go to the enforcer.
Rym: We're like, hey, is there really nothing in this room at one o'clock?
Rym: and he's like as far as we know.
Rym: No, we're like we have something crazy.
Rym: Awesome.
Rym: You could run just trust us.
Rym: Give us the room.
Scott: So they call up.
Scott: Khalil white is someone we've interacted with frequently, but never actually met and he shows up.
Rym: finally Yeah, because they're like, yeah, it's no this would never happen at any other con.
Rym: This is why Pax is awesome.
Scott: Of course, he shows up and he's the awesomest dude.
Rym: So basically the enforcers are like this is totally cool.
Rym: we just have to make sure that mr.
Rym: White is okay with it.
Rym: so he shows up just for the panel and I'm very pleased to meet him in person.
Rym: But he basically said you know what?
Rym: It's really stupid that we haven't talked in person before this and we're gonna be talking to him about Pax East Very shortly.
Rym: He works for read exhibitions managing the Pax East and West and yes Apparently his office is like right next to Pete to Tara who we work with.
Rym: Yeah, so Pax East is gonna be crazy.
Rym: awesome because we like we have some insight into things They're planning on doing and we have avenues to get people to do them better and cheaper.
Rym: Yeah So anyway, that was awesome.
Rym: And of course we had Jerry.
Scott: of course, he let us have the room at 1 p.m For the action castle.
Rym: Yep So we had Jared and Luke in the room and they stood up and waved and then we told every basically This panel that was not in the schedule.
Rym: we managed to get a lot of people to show up for this panel.
Rym: That was not scheduled.
Scott: Yeah, we did the tweets.
Scott: everyone tweeted.
Rym: I walked into every tabletop room and I was like, alright guys this game come play a game with us in the theater.
Rym: Yep, and we had a lot of people to show up and Jared ran action castle.
Rym: now while we were waiting for this to happen There was some downtime.
Rym: So between the two we played Citadel's.
Rym: we taught some people how to play this game.
Scott: We didn't finish that game though.
Rym: while that game was going on I randomly ran into gave in Tyco.
Rym: Yeah, Scott was in the room and I was on my way to the bodega and someone tasked me on the shoulder and they're like Hey, can you take a picture for us?
Rym: I'm like up.
Rym: Okay, and then I turn around.
Rym: I realized that standing in front of me or gave in Tyco.
Rym: So I took a picture of gave in Tyco and some guy Alright, and then you know, I talked to him for a little bit and Tyco, you know, Jerry unsolicited is you know, I'm like.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I ran the beyond D&D last year and we're running stuff this year and he's like, oh, yeah You know what?
Rym: I heard there was some mouse guard going on on at this con and I was like, yeah It happened on Saturday.
Rym: Sadly.
Rym: He's like, ah, damn.
Rym: But then you know, I couldn't bother them.
Rym: They're obviously on their way somewhere.
Rym: so I congratulated him on forming babby and then I let him get on his way and Luke and Jared kind of bump in and Luke's like blah blah blah blah blah and invite.
Rym: they invite those two guys to come to Action castle and to their credit Jerry pulls out a schedule.
Rym: They probably the schedule that Robert coup gave to him.
Rym: He's like don't deviate from this.
Scott: Yeah, actually no Robert coup looks like now cuz I actually saw him a few times at the convention.
Rym: Yeah, I can't stop him though because he was a busy man I kept running into him and every time I was like I want to bother you but just go on your way.
Rym: But he pulls out his schedule and he looks at it and he has something circled at one o'clock.
Rym: She's like, ah, I can't go.
Rym: Yeah, but I see later.
Rym: Hey Steve Jackson's back.
Rym: So I go to Jared.
Rym: on the Jared go invite Steve Jackson to your action castle.
Rym: and he did.
Rym: and Steve Jackson came to Action castle, uh, what did he come to?
Rym: Action Castle, that's correct.
Scott: He came to the action castle.
Rym: Oh my god action castle was so crazy.
Scott: And again, you know, my plan was to grief the action castle and Jared's like.
Scott: you can't grief it right?
Scott: All you get is like one move.
Scott: What's the worst you can do?
Scott: like go up the tree and down the tree again?
Scott: It's like, you know go backwards, you know, you can kill self you can restart but you can't really.
Scott: you know You can't do that much damage.
Rym: So I see Scott, you know, I didn't play I just took pictures of the audience.
Rym: I see Scott like standing there like on a mission and he gets up there and he's like drop lamp, right?
Scott: So the thing is from playing action castle.
Scott: before I knew that you start with a lamp in your inventory.
Scott: Nobody in the whole game had checked the inventory yet So no one else knew.
Scott: so I go up there and I drop lamp and Jared makes a face and he's just like he says You drop the lamp.
Scott: Nobody picked up the lamp and they went all the way to action gasps.
Rym: In fact, they got so far They saved the game without the lamp.
Scott: They saved the game in the princesses chambers.
Scott: They didn't have the lamp.
Scott: They had to go all the way back and get the lamp and then all the way back again.
Scott: And then when I got my I only had two turns because there were a lot of people in line.
Scott: on my second turn I climbed the tree.
Scott: It took a long time Just because I could and we had to go up the tree and down the tree Though the cool thing was.
Rym: this is why Pax is so great.
Rym: Why the enforcers are so great the dude.
Rym: I'm sorry I forgot your name.
Rym: You're like my best friend who was like right like all these people running the Raven the Raven theater managers.
Scott: Yeah, those guys are the best.
Rym: He was like, okay.
Rym: What does action castle entail?
Rym: We told we explained it to him.
Rym: We didn't you know normally wait like if we're at Otakon and we need like something special We basically have to like explicitly explain like this then this then this then this then this forever and even then they'll still cock it Up here.
Rym: All we did was explain what action castle was and he was like, so they'll line up in front of the mic.
Rym: We're like, yep.
Rym: He's like got it and he walks away.
Scott: He
Rym: took the line turn style style Through the chairs lined up at the back of the room and formed the entire line inside the room and he had everyone who already Did their turn walk out the exit at the front and get in line at the back of the room again?
Rym: He came up with this on his own Immediately and all the other enforcers made it happen and he didn't need to ask anyone for permission either.
Scott: He just did it.
Rym: Oh my god packs.
Rym: You're like you guys seriously.
Rym: I cannot give you enough props.
Scott: Enforcers are like something so simple but yet compared to the others such a big deal and it's all that little simple shit That makes the con 10,000 times the awesome you who take up the black.
Rym: I salute you But we've got the line and I see Steve Jackson in line.
Rym: He came he's in line and he is clearly having a great time Yep.
Rym: So he is one person away from taking his turn and the dude in front of him walks up with that grief Look and says reset game resetting and Welcome to action.
Rym: gas and Jared looks at Steve Jackson.
Rym: She actually looks at him and they both shake their heads and Steve Jackson says load save slot one now loading.
Rym: And then he did.
Rym: I wonder how many people in the room realized that was Steve Jackson.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: people even know Steve Jackson is one thing I can say Steve Jackson But he tweeted later and he was like action castle was amazing.
Scott: Yep Totally awesome.
Scott: No, it's like super wicked awesome.
Rym: It was really interesting to run action castle or to see it run for a group of gamers.
Rym: cuz you know Jared ran it for us at Connecticut, which was mostly non gamers and Like the crowd was in one way worse at action castle because they didn't understand text adventures But in many ways much better because they weren't jerk griefers.
Scott: They didn't even think just they were just playing it straightforwardly.
Scott: They didn't know any text adventure stuff.
Scott: They didn't know to save and load.
Scott: They only knew to save because Pete told them that.
Scott: you know, Pete gave it away.
Rym: It's interesting how the people who had played a lot of games were proud like their prior experience hurt them in action castle because they they had these preconceived notions and it was really interesting.
Rym: and Jared and I talked about that a lot after action castle.
Rym: Yes, very very interesting, but it took 30 minutes.
Rym: the game ended.
Rym: They won with the score I believe 98 out of 100 because they didn't give the rose to the princess.
Scott: after they they gave her the rose to the princess But they didn't do it again after loading the game.
Rym: So yeah yep, but and After it all, you know, we had a half hour left in the room and instead of you know Kicking us out or whatever.
Rym: The enforcer was like you guys got the room for a half hour.
Rym: Got it want to do anything cool.
Scott: So we just took questions for half hour.
Rym: So me Jared and Scott we sat down and we had by then, you know Other people were like don't stay unless you have nothing better to do seriously.
Rym: So only about 60 people stayed and we're like, alright, we can take like three or four questions.
Rym: Do not use semi-colons in your question.
Rym: don't make a statement to ask a good question.
Rym: Seriously We'll totally get all great questions.
Scott: The greatest question was the guy who was like.
Scott: you play all this wide variety of games and I'm like I'm about to explain Oh how I play this wide variety of guy.
Scott: He's like no.
Scott: No, my question is right.
Scott: So I was answering the wrong question first of all and then he's like, you know where is there still room for gaming to grow?
Scott: and I was like, oh man, what a great question.
Scott: and Actually, we talked about the unfulfilled potential.
Rym: Yep, and it gave me a bunch of ideas for panels, too.
Rym: So dude, if you're listening email us and tell us who you were because you realize you inspired three brand new panels that we're gonna Do at cons?
Scott: Yeah, it's a very good question.
Rym: Like the unresolved potential is going to be a whole panel.
Rym: That's basically going to be why Nintendo build potential.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Yep, but we did this panel.
Rym: It was really fun and I got to say I want to do one.
Rym: I want to get Jared and Luke to do like their own panels at cons.
Rym: Doing a Q&A roundtable with Jared Sorenson was really cool because He has insights that we do not see and we agree.
Rym: You know We disagree on a lot of big points in gaming But it amazes me how much we agree on.
Rym: that doesn't come up when we normally talk because we don't talk about the things we Agree on but then someone asks us a question and we all like have the same answer.
Scott: I know right?
Scott: Let's see.
Scott: Let's talk about a bunch of little shit that's going on.
Scott: Oh, we bought some PAX merch before they sold out.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: We got the PAX 2009 t-shirt.
Rym: I'll say this again, you know way before we asked for I still I owe the two people who sent me those pit boy puppets Crazy prizes and someday I'll get them to you and I'll prop you again on the show and you'll probably you forgot all about it.
Rym: But we got paxo 9 t-shirts.
Rym: We were unable to get packs away t-shirts because they sold out like right away.
Rym: I don't think I'm going to ask for a PAX t-shirt though because it would have been a pre-worn one.
Scott: Yeah, I don't want that.
Scott: Nah I See there were like famous people there like like Bill Amand had a table that the Foxtrot guy We didn't talk to him because you know, there was no line because he was like I was like in it.
Rym: say to him though I will I know we stood there.
Rym: We're like.
Rym: does anyone have anything to say them other than other than like fan stuff?
Rym: and we're like no So we own away.
Rym: but one thing dude looks almost exactly like the way he draws Jason if you look at him from the side.
Scott: Oh for reals Like Jonan Vasquez is there but I don't know what he looks like.
Scott: and he wasn't.
Scott: he was just an attendee.
Scott: He wasn't like as far as I could tell doing anything special.
Scott: So it's like.
Scott: how would I even know I could've been playing a game with him and not even know one thing and I'm gonna I got it If I don't get a hold of him.
Rym: everyone everyone talked to Jonathan Colton in whatever way you can.
Rym: One of our things the day from the long time from a long time ago was called a story from North America.
Rym: Yeah, we were going to show it to him Like.
Rym: I wanted to show it to him on my pre and be like.
Rym: you can do something cool with this you if anyone.
Rym: But you know he was gone on Sunday And I didn't get a chance to talk to him before the concert on Saturday.
Rym: So I want him to see this and do something cool with it.
Rym: So help me out people out there.
Scott: the NS guys from unknown worlds are supposed to have a booth totally bailed.
Scott: They didn't and that sucked because that was something I was looking forward to and it wasn't there.
Scott: so fuck though.
Scott: No, fuck them.
Scott: No, not great.
Scott: But come on guys.
Scott: What the hell?
Scott: Seriously, I wanted to see you then again.
Rym: Hopefully they'll be at PAX East.
Scott: Hopefully we'll see Oh before one of our panels these guys who are making a mod like an expansion or something for dawn of war 2 were there and Basically dawn of war 2 is that Warhammer RTS that I had a hard time with because it was basically just a million times rock-paper-scissors.
Scott: But apparently what these guys have made is they made a defense mode.
Scott: That's co-op.
Scott: So it's like co-op defense dawn of war and I thought that was pretty cool.
Scott: So that's like wow if the game was that from the get-go, I probably would have played it a lot more All right.
Rym: So after beyond D&D we met this guy on Matt Youngmark and we talked to him a little bit and he writes choose your own Adventure books.
Scott: Oh, yeah that guy totally awesome.
Rym: I was reading though when he gave us a free copy of zombocalypse now Which is one of them and I gotta say it's pretty great.
Rym: Yeah Like it brings back all that fun and choose your own adventures in a big way and he's also like a cool gamer guy Like we talked to him for a while.
Scott: Mm-hmm Pretty much everyone we talked to.
Scott: like I just walk up to random people and start talking to him Like I would just like I'd see people in the game room and I just go up to him Like there are two people playing.
Scott: block is like we sat down to play that hive game And I saw the two people across through him were playing.
Scott: block is and I just sort of looked at him.
Scott: I'm like, ah block is and they're like they picked their head up like, huh?
Scott: Then after he finished the hive game, I just walk over like I'm like block is.
Rym: let's go In general like packs far in a way.
Rym: I did not run into anyone scary anyone douchey anyone jerky.
Rym: no one was like a fanboy wouldn't leave me alone.
Scott: and The scariest person that I saw who at packs that I can remember right Jackson?
Scott: No, no the in the Wolfman theater.
Scott: So they what some of the enforcers in there must have had Dolphies because there were Dolphies at the enforcer desk.
Scott: However, they don't know who they belong to but all of the enforcers in that room were totally chill and not scary Dolphie people even though there were Dolphies there.
Rym: so But it said it says some serious part of acts about Dolphies on a desk that even like Otakon anime.
Rym: But any anime can we go to I'll be.
Rym: basically when we're not doing panels have to largely hide not not necessarily from like listeners or fans or people but just we have to hide in general because Otherwise, we'll have like these mobs that won't go away and like I would know if I was out getting dinner at Otakon I would never tweet where I was.
Rym: good God I need time away at packs.
Rym: I tweeted where I was all the time.
Rym: I'd like tweet like hey We're eating dinner here and like cool people would come and say hi Everyone was cool.
Rym: Everyone we played a game with was cool.
Rym: If you played a game with us just email me because one thing too I gave my business card out to a lot of people that I just like played one game with and hung out with.
Rym: I Would not give my phone number out and my direct email out that liberally at any other convention.
Scott: Yeah, the Noxonator showed up when you're eating dinner on Sunday.
Rym: yeah, because I tweeted out I was like hey anyone cool We talked to you saw our panels come say hi And he came.
Scott: so we were just sort of eating a dinner at the elephant and castle which is pretty good I think.
Scott: and then you know you know we're sort of going in not the most exciting dinner conversation But then this fan shows up, but it was totally awesome.
Scott: We got someone cool to talk to you for an hour about good stuff.
Rym: Yeah, we actually met a decent number of fans and people out there.
Rym: I can't give shout outs to all of you.
Scott: I don't even remember.
Scott: there are hundreds of people that were like oh, yeah, fuck.
Rym: Yeah, yep We spent a lot of our time hanging out with Rowan Jeremy.
Rym: yep.
Scott: So in the line for the end of packs right which we were very close to the front of that line we've played Zeus on the loose with Jeremy and Which is an okay little silly game.
Rym: You know one aside for the the lineup.
Rym: They got these people to do like line entertainment where you could text in and like vote for memes And like and then they'd show the meme and vote for stuff and play these games.
Rym: And they generally packs as always does a really good job of entertaining the line.
Scott: They know there's a line and no waiting in line sucks.
Scott: So they always just try different things to sort of entertain the people in line.
Rym: what amazes me Is that you know a long time ago our friends Yuko and Conrad and Ananth showed us power thirst Bear blast.
Scott: I don't even remember power thirst until you showed it to me the other day.
Rym: Oh, I remembered it because I always found it funny and every now And then it's relevant to things.
Rym: and just like I I don't know I found that mean really funny.
Rym: power There's run into.
Rym: so I showed it to Scott randomly for some reason.
Rym: then I showed it to like Emily randomly and then Not that long later.
Rym: It had this resurgence like at PAX.
Rym: It was voted up like twice, so they kept showing it.
Rym: I Don't know why like power thirst suddenly came to the front of the mean, but be mean pool Mm-hmm Alright, so then they had the beach balls.
Rym: people are on penises on him because the logo on the beach ball kind of looked like a penis.
Scott: He did kinda.
Scott: Oh, I forgot to talk about the swag bags and such right so and the wristbands and all that.
Scott: So like you get your badge in the mail, right?
Scott: So how do you get your swag bag or your wristband for the concert?
Scott: well in the line in the morning?
Scott: You just give them out like crazy.
Scott: the swag bag had like a freaking t-shirt in it and a video game in it Lord of the Rings online like it hold like The actual game was in there of course.
Scott: It's an online game right.
Scott: so they're making their money from the subscriptions And there was just all sorts of crazy shit in there.
Scott: I managed to pick one up on Saturday cuz I didn't pick one up on Friday.
Scott: I got my concert wristband also.
Scott: You know.
Scott: that's how that goes.
Scott: So yeah the end of packs the omega-thon final Dun-dun-dun.
Rym: the only bad thing I have to say about packs is every year the omega-thon final starts crazy late.
Scott: Yeah, they're really good reason.
Scott: They got to work on making it start on time.
Rym: No here's my idea on how to resolve it.
Rym: assume it's going to start late and schedule the start time an hour before it's actually going to start and But in front of the curtain.
Rym: here's what I will do What I would do if I can get all the stars in line.
Rym: Obviously, I'm not speaking on behalf of packs or super art fight.
Rym: But what if super art fight just ran in front of the curtains while like in the room before they did the omega-thon finale?
Scott: I also have another idea.
Scott: You should.
Scott: they should have both the the semi-final and the final rounds of the omega-thon Concurrently.
Scott: you know the four then the two then the one all at once instead of having the two rounds be separate Concurrently wouldn't work when I at the same time.
Rym: How do you know who won the first round?
Scott: I mean at the same time slot.
Scott: Yes, they would right so they would do the both rounds together.
Scott: that way It would sort of build you have the added excitement of the tournament effect because a lot of people don't go to every round of The omega-thon you know.
Scott: so put both both the final rounds together.
Scott: that way It's like whoo.
Scott: you know it's a bigger thing rather than just okay play game good go home.
Scott: You know which is sort of what it is regardless.
Scott: the reveal of what the final game is is always epic and I Could have guessed it had I thought about it more, but I didn't.
Scott: I'm not gonna say I did when I didn't.
Scott: The final game was epic as always.
Scott: Fucking skee-ball.
Rym: ah that I got to say one thing excellent excellent choice.
Rym: everybody up there sucked at skee-ball That's true.
Rym: I could have eaten all of them.
Scott: That's right of course Gabe all it beats I go at skee-ball as always man.
Rym: You know Jerry talks a big talk, but he's not good at video.
Rym: Dude you look like a little like he had all this majesty and stage presence.
Rym: like he's big.
Rym: He's larger than life when he's on stage As soon as he went to throw that first skee-ball.
Rym: It's like he shrunk into a little old lady Yeah, and he's like.
Scott: he's like he's trying to like everyone.
Scott: come on.
Scott: Let's get loud, and then he sucked.
Scott: He's like everyone quiet quiet You know.
Scott: he's like you couldn't make up his mind, and he I don't think he tried very hard either man thing is they?
Rym: Look at the first round.
Rym: told all where you know the one guy gets a score and the second guy realizes that all he has To do is get all 20s to beat that score, so he just got all 20s.
Rym: Yeah, played super conservatively.
Scott: no one what.
Scott: no one got a hundred.
Scott: I think there was like one or two fifties.
Scott: That was about it.
Scott: You know it's very bad skee-ball playing by everybody.
Scott: But you know it was kind of interesting because it was the runner-up from last year against someone else the someone-else ones.
Scott: The guy's been the omega-thon runner-up twice in a row.
Rym: he's going to be an omega not next year.
Scott: third Dude if this guy if he I think he might have a secret strategy of Like.
Scott: he has skills, and he's gonna be the runner-up in the omega-thon forever plus.
Scott: I would not want to play that dude in video games.
Scott: He's probably incredibly badass Like omega-thon semi you know non-winner like runner-up twice in a row or three times in a row I didn't even know anymore.
Scott: That's a dangerous gamer right there.
Scott: watch the fuck out.
Rym: But overall like other than the line for the end packs was just like perfect and awesome.
Rym: Everything about it was great everyone.
Rym: We met was cool.
Rym: if you met us email us And you know we'll totally respond and talk to you.
Rym: don't don't feel like we're just gonna ignore you.
Rym: Yeah, I gave you that business card for a reason.
Scott: so anything that I can remember about the packs that we did not mention
Rym: I'm sure there's a ton of stuff left to talk about in like a brief follow-up on Thursday There'll
Scott: be many details of reviewing individual games and talking with specific Interviews with people and all that sort of stuff in the future.
Scott: this episode has gone on long enough.
Scott: I gotta upload and yep, I hope the Chinese restaurants still open.
Rym: one last thing I will point out.
Rym: there was a con.
Rym: there was a Pax Flu a con SARS as happens at cons like it was the.
Scott: it was the swine flu.
Scott: apparently
Rym: yes So far Robert Koo is tweeting out and pointing out that there has been at least one straight-up confirmed case of h1n1 You know flu at packs And they're asking anyone who tests positive After they get home to email him with your flight numbers and all this information so they can track what's going on and probably work with the CDC, but Emily and Alex both have it.
Rym: They're probably gonna get tested tomorrow to find out if they had the h1n1.
Scott: somehow Scott And I came out unscathed, but well I was really dry and scratchy in the throat area and I thought that was just the usual really you know Dehumidifying air conditioning of staying at a convention center all day.
Rym: I think we've got silly was and fought it off.
Rym: I really think I got it and fought it off.
Scott: I might have it's tough call.
Rym: well I was exposed to it up like several months ago, and I got sick, but I didn't get sick.
Rym: water is poison survived it Yeah, so so as our friend Lisa who is an expert in these sort of things points out Yeah, she's going for a doctorate and everything.
Rym: She's super smart.
Rym: if you get it now And it doesn't kill you You're probably in a great position because this might.
Rym: this is the beginning of probably the second wave of it And if you know it probably won't turn into a deadly like crazy deadly thing.
Rym: But if it does and you get it now you have a good chance of being pretty okay when it comes through in force.
Rym: Yep, so don't feel too bad as like.
Rym: just make sure you you know Get treated, but seriously if you're sick And you went to PAX and you're listening to this and you didn't go to a doctor go to a doctor.
Rym: go to a doctor.
Rym: You might have the swine flu, and if you do have the swine flu email Robert Koo and tell him yes And tell him your flight number.
Rym: Yeah, all right shoutouts again to the enforcers to gave in taiko to everyone at PAX.
Rym: It was crazy awesome.
Rym: Everyone we met was awesome.
Rym: everyone seemed to love our panels.
Scott: I can't remember a single non awesome part of PAX.
Rym: I cannot think of any not having breakfast and the NS guys not being there with the possible exception of the party that I ran At a send 2002 a long time ago, and even then that is that is rose-colored glasses.
Rym: No convention has ever been better than PAX 2009. for me No convention other than that has ever been better than PAX 2008 for me.
Rym: Yeah, and PAX East is coming.
Scott: It was not an illusion.
Scott: PAX we remembered it being awesome much like Evangelion.
Scott: It was awesomer than we remembered Either because it was awesomer this year than last year, or it's just you know that much more awesome.
Scott: PAX is the win.
Scott: everyone else.
Rym: the bar is raised you're way under it And now I'm gonna eat some Chinese food and go to bed.
Scott: I hope they're still open.
Rym: good I gotta go to work tomorrow.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at Frontrowcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.