Rym: It's Tuesday June 9th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We interview Alex and Emily developers for Muse games.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: You know it's funny How the less time we have to do some sort of news or thing of the day or anything?
Rym: The more news there is and it's not just on Tuesdays.
Rym: It's pretty much every day of the week.
Scott: Well, they had the stupid D conference They had the stupid e3 and they had the stupid Steve Jobs all in like the same two weeks.
Scott: You know I think from now on right.
Scott: I mean basically last year.
Scott: at this time There was also a Steve Jobs, and it's the year before right you know cuz that's pretty much.
Scott: I think the iPhone is always gonna get updated in June every year forever.
Rym: Yeah, but look the iPhone got updated right after the pre.
Rym: Hey we had e3.
Rym: yeah I know right you think did you see all those other cell phones that were announced?
Scott: You know what I realized today.
Scott: Verizon doesn't have shit for phone.
Rym: Yeah, they don't.
Rym: I Was actually t-mobiles got the g1 sprint got pre AT&T got iPhone Verizon got dick for dick And I mean I was actually looking to check when my contract like that day the contract my expire expires and all that stuff.
Rym: But yeah, they said hey upgrade your phone get a new contract, and they didn't have any good phones.
Rym: No, I could get some like normal crap phone.
Scott: Yeah, it's a Tuesday episode technically speaking.
Rym: yes We should talk about vid games.
Scott: you want to talk about any e3 whatnots.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: we should well probably Have to do a show about several of these announcements.
Rym: I mean there's so much to talk about.
Rym: we haven't even talked about how NS is available NS - we can pre-order it.
Scott: Oh, man, we didn't.
Rym: yeah, no shit That is the day that I did not expect to come as soon as it did.
Rym: yeah that came out of no.
Scott: and again There are people out there of Duke Nukem forever pre-orders Plus.
Rym: there's the the new Zelda game and the other new Zelda game that was hinted at.
Scott: oh, yeah, that doesn't count.
Rym: Well they basically by all they had to do is release that screenshot, and it wasn't a Miyamoto who said yeah There's a reason he doesn't have a sword and everyone lost their shit.
Scott: How about that Metroid game?
Rym: Yeah, I'm actually looking forward to that.
Scott: about that For Mario for swords Mario game that could.
Rym: the thing is that could be what the Mario remake on the DS Should have been.
Scott: I like how they're acting like four swords doesn't exist right.
Scott: It's like they make this game Basically four swords, but they're acting like they just came up with this brilliant idea.
Rym: I know I mean four swords in my opinion was one of the better games Nintendo ever put out.
Scott: yeah Well, I think what happened?
Scott: is it just so few people like actually played a lot of those things from that era Except for us the era when Miyamoto was sad.
Scott: yeah So they can like they can pass off that shit again, and I think however I think that the platforming aspect will make that game a lot more frustrating.
Scott: I mean it was bad enough in Zelda that you'd have people setting each other on fire And you know I'm talking about the not on purpose times.
Scott: You know the on purpose times are perfectly okay, but in this game Record.
Scott: yeah in this game.
Scott: There's gonna be plenty of on purpose pushing the other guy in a hole But I think there's gonna be even more accidental pushing the guy in the hole, and it's good.
Scott: It's not gonna be good.
Rym: Well it depends on this.
Scott: you have four skilled players.
Rym: if they were if it were set up such that four people could go Say the worlds were the little boards were like Mario 3 boards, and you can all go in different directions.
Scott: Yeah, I think it keeps you on the same screen.
Rym: see that that's from what I've seen.
Rym: well four swords was good with the same Screen in the splitting you could also make a really good game if people can just go off.
Scott: Yeah, they really need to do that.
Scott: No.
Scott: I don't think there is a game like that where they should really make a DS game.
Scott: Everyone can just go off on the same map.
Scott: you know and not all the thing is like.
Scott: you know.
Scott: There are some games like that where you can just go off, but it's usually bad to go off.
Scott: You know you need like two people in the same place to like navigate a puzzle or something like that You know.
Scott: so you want to stick together or force and also fight the bad guys at the same time to kill them quick.
Rym: Four swords rewards you if you run off by giving you jammies But it hurts everybody because you can't actually go forward.
Scott: Well it also doesn't let you.
Scott: it lets you run off But doesn't let you run up very far keeps you in the same place.
Scott: I'm talking about a game where it's like let's say it's a big Final Fantasy dungeon even a roguelike and you can just run off.
Scott: It's basically a local MMO.
Scott: It loads the whole instance and everyone.
Scott: not only should you go off, but you can.
Scott: well Not only can but should you.
Rym: Nintendo barely scratched the surface with those the idea of that of you having your own screen with hidden Information and they did.
Scott: the DS sort of does that without any help.
Rym: one games do it.
Scott: well I mean advance wars with fog of war.
Rym: advance wars is probably the best multiplayer game on the DS.
Rym: still Yeah, I mean look most games.
Scott: They have multiplayer, but it's joke multi.
Rym: It's always some weekend like Castlevania You know beat the other guys time.
Scott: Yeah They always have.
Scott: why do they feel the needs like put in this joke multi.
Scott: well actually the the puzzle games Tetris puyo pop those Have good player Mario Kart if it didn't have snaking you know those sorts.
Scott: But you know why?
Rym: I can tell you why.
Rym: because then they can put that multiplayer logo on the box.
Scott: Yeah, and grab the games have like some sort of joke ass Not even worth playing multiplayer.
Scott: listen if this is a part of your game.
Scott: That's not even worth playing.
Scott: don't put it in there I know someone's gonna say oh might as well right it can't hurt.
Scott: Yeah, kind of can hurt.
Scott: It's just there's.
Scott: there's spending time and money making that shit.
Scott: They really made another level.
Rym: They really like like I. the thing that bothered me is playing the old like Chrono Trigger remake And they basically added an entire crappy version of Pokemon to the game.
Rym: Whoa you can go you can go into this area and raise monsters and fight them like why?
Scott: But does it have any connection to the actual game part?
Rym: don't think so.
Scott: so it's just this.
Scott: tacked on on the side thing.
Scott: I think you can basically Chrono Trigger plus bad Pokemon on the same cartridge like Mario and Duck Hunt on the same cartridge.
Rym: I think you can get some sort of item.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I walked in there to see what it was and I walked right back out and take that game facts.
Rym: Anyway, we're gonna cut short.
Rym: We're not gonna talk about all the e3 stuff.
Rym: We'll let that ferment for a while.
Rym: Maybe we'll do an extra Tuesday episode next week to catch up, but tonight We have an interview with two game developers Emily and Alex who work for muse games and live down the street.
Rym: Yeah It's the Emily and Alex of the front row crew who also happen to be game developers.
Rym: Yes for real game developers - not like you know Not like a lot of people are game developers.
Scott: Yeah, right like what was that guy who made the game for the GBA?
Rym: Nintendo didn't accept that guy while he was crazy.
Rym: He gets a lot of points for determination If you consider those points.
Rym: well boy, I didn't.
Rym: what are you gonna redeem him for?
Scott: another negative point?
Scott: There's a space for crazy space boy space boys.
Scott: You need a billion to add up to one regular point.
Rym: but Emily and Alex work for muse games a small game studio and there they've made a game elementia that you will link to.
Rym: that you can play and We're going to interview them shortly.
Rym: We already did and now we're just gonna play the audio from the interview.
Rym: We conducted last night.
Rym: Well, thanks to all sorts of microphone shenanigans There are somehow four microphones plugged into this mixer board here of varying quality shape and size.
Rym: We've got.
Rym: we've got Rym and Scott as always on the SM 57 or 58.
Scott: No, they're not 58.
Scott: We need to get some of those.
Rym: Yeah, we do.
Emily: and here's Emily on the headset.
Scott: That's the Radio Shack.
Scott: piece of shit is the technical term.
Rym: Famous microphone.
Rym: someday we will sell that on eBay.
Rym: That was the first GeekNights microphone.
Scott: Yeah That'd be great.
Scott: imagine if like, you know say I don't know some famous radio guy was like.
Scott: He made a radio show and he was like a kid in High school and he had the microphone that he used like man.
Scott: What if I go I could go find my like fisher-prize tape recorder somewhere?
Emily: I think that every little kid had that fisher-prize tape recorder.
Emily: because I've got all these, you know, they're.
Emily: they're kind of preschool audio dramas.
Emily: Many of them concern like the alternate adventures of Peter Pan.
Guest: They're like really really weird.
Emily: or or like.
Emily: there's this one where we're having a trial for a rabbit and like it was.
Emily: it was actually kind of funny because it showed that even as like six-year-olds we had a Pretty good grasp of how the legal system worked like there was a prosecutor and a defense.
Emily: Did you chew on this thing?
Scott: we had ones that were.
Scott: they were like little books and then they came with the tape that Went with the book as he would.
Scott: you sort of listen to the tape while you read the book at the same time and you Get the sound effects.
Scott: They would read to you or whatever, but then on the reverse sides.
Scott: It was always record whatever you want.
Emily: I Still think the best thing was my mom dug out a whole bunch of tapes I had made when I was a little kid and there was one where it was just I would turn the tape recorder.
Emily: I carried it with me everywhere.
Emily: And so I turned the tape recorder on at random times.
Emily: And so you just get these conversations from like 20 years ago.
Emily: It was kind of wild.
Emily: There was one where my mom was trying to get my toddler sister To get in the car and go to the clothing shop and my sister was being really uncooperative.
Emily: So it's just this exchange, you know, it was.
Emily: it was kind of funny.
Emily: It's really nostalgic to listen.
Rym: I have an hour of screaming and horrible noises mixed together in a loop that I then would Randomly just play.
Guest: You were so much fun for your parents party guests.
Scott: Remember the retro arcade.
Scott: guys said that he had like a vinyl audio recording of his parents wedding and he restored it for them.
Emily: Oh, yeah, that's kind of awesome man.
Guest: It is cool.
Emily: That guy is cool.
Rym: But the main reason as we mentioned
Emily: in the beginning
Rym: that we have these extra microphones here is that we actually you know Independently of Emily and Alex being friends of ours and such they are both Game designers working in the actual gaming industry making And pretty much we get the question either email to us or in the forums at least once an hour Asking us how to be a game developer and what it's really like or something to that effect.
Emily: Yeah, I remember a thread in the forums There was like a kid in high school who was like, this is what I want to pursue as my career You know, does anybody have any advice?
Emily: and actually there were quite a few people like Mancun, for example who actually have worked in the game industry and Immediately started giving this kid advice and warnings and like sometimes you'll have to work on pretty princess pony games Even if you
Scott: don't want to you know Really seems like in a few.
Scott: there's like a few jobs that like in any sort of geek area, you know There's always like some job that someone wants like all the skater kids want to like be Tony Hawk for a living.
Emily: Yeah,
Scott: all the gamer kids want to be like, you know, John Carmack for a living
Emily: Programmers want to work at Google or animators want to work in
Guest: Pixar Literally every programmer to whom I ever heard the question asked at RIT would say yeah, I want to make video games.
Guest: Yeah, like literally everyone.
Rym: So I guess the first question is how did you two?
Rym: well first, what do you both actually do?
Rym: I mean, I can't explain to my grandma or my mom or anyone what I actually do for a living.
Rym: So what do you actually do?
Emily: Well, I'll go first.
Emily: It was it's actually kind of a small studio.
Emily: So I actually my work is a lot more varied than it probably would be if I worked for a big studio like EA.
Emily: I do Concept.
Emily: my my official title is a virtual world character designer And so I do Basically all the art assets that go into the games.
Emily: I do the character design, you know start out with Photoshop paintings and model sheets and then I go into 3d modeling.
Emily: I texture and sometimes rig.
Emily: I had some help with rigging Characters from an intern we had.
Emily: he's still a very good friend of mine.
Emily: But So modeling rigging, you know, basically the the 3d character creation from start to finish You know, I do a lot of the animation as well Design environments I do.
Emily: I guess one of my main things lately is I've just been producing a ton of textures for For this virtual chat that we do and so it's like, you know fashions for avatars and Like 20 t-shirts a day or something, you know.
Emily: So, what about you Alex?
Emily: What do you do?
Guest: Well, I program things.
Guest: I would like to be more specific than that, but I really can't be I don't know.
Guest: you said It's a small studio and we all kind of have to wear a bunch of hats.
Guest: Yeah, so I do graphical effects I do game logic.
Guest: I do low-level networking stuff.
Guest: I occasionally dabble in the website.
Rym: Yeah, well, what's your actual job title?
Rym: because I remembered being something cool.
Guest: Yeah, I am a virtual world architect, which I agree sounds really cool.
Emily: It's basically I do almost a little bit of almost everything design the framework of every single game we do and You you also do some artistically oriented programming like you do our shader development and particle simulations and stuff like that.
Emily: actually many of the the programming Things that you do have a have a visual effect in the final product.
Guest: Yeah, I mean it's Effects programming which is I guess the the best I can come up with for an actual field.
Guest: for that it falls into this weird line that kind of straddles the the pure engineering and pure artistic ends of things.
Guest: I'll agree.
Guest: It's one of the more fun parts of my job.
Rym: So to really illustrate I mean, you know people always ask how do you get into the gaming industry?
Rym: How did both of you get into the gaming industry?
Rym: Because it's it seems like it's an impossible task for the majority of people who have ever lived in this earth.
Emily: Well, I think part of the thing is it seems very daunting because a lot of people they try to go for the big industry, you know the big houses and Competitions very fierce for like say EA or or other like valve or something like that.
Emily: But with with me I I'm working for a startup.
Emily: So I Ended up getting into it by a kind of lucky lucky chance here.
Emily: I did a character design contest right when so sauce the parent company of muse games was starting out and That was back my senior year of college and I remember spending one night in my dorm room.
Emily: I think it was like on my birthday or something was the deadline Drawing these two characters for this design contest and I got second place.
Emily: I didn't win but in return they kept in contact with me and I come in and test their web applications for their travel website.
Emily: and so I got to learn, you know, all the different people in the office and we became kind of friends.
Emily: and Then one day a few months later I found out that they were looking for a character designer and I was just graduating.
Emily: It was like a month before I graduated.
Emily: So I ran and I was like me me seriously.
Emily: That's what I do.
Emily: and It worked out and they looked at my portfolio and decided that I was good enough and they hired me.
Emily: And Alex you were kind of.
Emily: that was kind of funny for you too because This is a lesson in the importance of connections.
Guest: I got hired Networking and I the guy who had previously done my job had quit suddenly for personal reasons of his own yeah, and They needed a graphics program.
Guest: and I happened to be a guy who'd done graphics programming at least a little bit Even though I wasn't doing it professionally at the time, but that was like your master's was in.
Guest: It's what I had done in school.
Guest: I had done, you know computer science, but I kind of focused on graphics Graphics programming broadly.
Rym: Well, plus you did that RIT special.
Rym: Hey stick around a little longer and you get a masters.
Guest: Yes, that means you have to call me master.
Guest: I'm hoping you do that.
Rym: Did you get to wear that special hat to a graduation?
Scott: I have a hood.
Guest: Yes, I was in the right place at the right time the right place being looking for a job in the New York area the right time being when the Social sauce needed a graphics program.
Emily: Oh, man, did we ever?
Emily: we were like you totally saved us.
Emily: I was.
Emily: I was very worried for about a week.
Emily: They're like, oh my god, our main programmers gone.
Emily: What are we gonna do?
Guest: and as a result because I'm working for tiny little startup studio My first job in the games industry is as the Lee basically the lead developer of a studio Which is really not something it's possible to do any other way.
Guest: This is normally an industry where as I understand it you have to do a lot of grunt work before you get to do cool Stuff.
Scott: Yeah along those lines.
Scott: I mean, I think that a lot of the punk kids out there, you know They want to be make video games.
Scott: I you know I get the feeling that a lot of them think that they just are sort of gonna get the Miyamoto job where you say what?
Scott: The game is gonna be and then it somehow it is.
Scott: So what like, you know, you told us what you do on a broad level, but like, you know What do you do on like, you know the micro level.
Scott: you go into work and is it?
Scott: you know It's not.
Scott: you're not playing video games all day.
Emily: Can I say something real quick?
Emily: That one of the things is good about Going the indie route and working for a smaller studio is we kind of do this a tour thing where?
Emily: Every game that we've created so far seems to be somebody's pet project.
Emily: Like the game that we're going to be talking about today was basically Alex's creation and like sledding was Brian's and The the next game is Austin's.
Emily: so it's like having such a small team.
Emily: you do get to have a lot more creative freedom and input into the Types of games that are being created but on a day-to-day basis, I'm It's late to any other.
Guest: it's like any other programming job.
Guest: I have a list of bugs.
Guest: I go and fix them.
Guest: or I have a list list of features that I need to add to the software or I have you know the vague plan for a new piece of software that I'm in the process of either Writing out or prototyping
Emily: and I guess it's the same for me where it's not every day that I'm doing like You know original characters.
Emily: It seems like a lot of the time I'll just go into work and make like 50 chairs or something like that or or texture a bunch of crates.
Emily: I remember having the conversation about making license plates and like 90% of Any computer job, it's just making the license plates In some ways in the ways in the ways of the geek I guess.
Rym: so I guess very specifically like just you know.
Rym: Let's get us up the notch a little bit.
Rym: Let's let's engage on the high level as we talked about last week.
Rym: Yeah, what?
Rym: what specific skills or I guess classes from school?
Rym: Would you say came the most in handy?
Scott: Or previous experiences also?
Guest: well I Work in mostly in C sharp, which is a language.
Guest: I had never used before I came to this job.
Guest: But at my previous job, I had to learn Python Perl and PHP which were also languages I had never used from until that job.
Guest: So it's especially if you're a programmer you have to be flexible you have to be able to pick up a new language as Needed pretty much the right tool for the right job.
Scott: Yeah, I can.
Scott: I can definitely echo that times a billion.
Scott: I mean, I've never had a job where I you know, I mean, you know, I worked at James.
Scott: I had to do Ruby which I didn't really do before so much and I mean I've done Python sorta But now is the first time I'm doing it for super reels.
Scott: times a hundred, you know.
Scott: And the job I got right out of college I did PHP and MySQL which I had sorta kind of maybe done in one class kind of not really
Emily: Well, I think one of the most important things once you get out of college is that a lot of the times you're going to Be teaching yourself.
Emily: So make sure you go around the internet and find any available resources and tutorials and everything I feel like I've gotten a lot better at for example modeling and texturing since I graduated college.
Emily: I mean most important classes I think for a character designer would definitely be like fine arts and figure drawing.
Emily: You've got to be able to look at something and then Be able to create a character from it.
Emily: You've got to have a good grasp of anatomy.
Emily: Whether or not you do 3d or 2d.
Emily: It doesn't matter.
Emily: knowing the human form is going to be Absolutely essential to anybody doing video game art Also?
Emily: Yeah basic if you're if you're 3d artists just take a lot of 3d classes, you know.
Emily: Make sure you get a very well-rounded education and don't just focus on one Aspect.
Emily: do modeling rigging, you know programming too can be very useful For for rigging.
Rym: so it's interesting how in this whole discussion The the topic of designing games from a game a pure game perspective hasn't come up at all.
Guest: We haven't gotten there yet.
Rym: It seems like most kids who want to get into the gaming industry always think oh I got a great idea for a game Are they?
Rym: but it how much of the job is actually?
Rym: Designing games from the game side versus implementing.
Rym: This is a loaded question, obviously.
Guest: Well, well, the design is a relatively small part of it on the one hand But that's not to say it's a small thing.
Guest: if you're gonna actually Specify a design at the level the design of a game at a level that you could then go and implement it From an artistic or a programming standpoint you need to get really frighteningly specific.
Guest: I have somewhere Probably about a 10 or 15 page document.
Guest: That is the original design doc for elementa.
Emily: It's completely different.
Guest: Yeah The game that it came out of it is actually very different from what that document originally specified.
Guest: Because The thing that is most important, of course is that the game should be fun.
Guest: Your game is not fun.
Rym: change it, you know A lot of professional game developers could learn that.
Emily: but we went through so many stages of play testing and got so much feedback.
Emily: I think you developed the original game within like three weeks or something.
Emily: It was like inside of a month, wasn't it?
Guest: And then Engine which Going to go into game development get a proper engine.
Guest: because if you want to go into engine programming That is a fine and good thing But that is not game development and do not fool yourself.
Guest: But if you're going to go into game development and write your own engine It's not worth the effort 90% of the time the love guy did it, but he's crazy.
Guest: It's not what I would recommend as your first project.
Scott: Well, I think the thing about making engines for most of the people who've made engines is that you know You have to sort of if you're gonna make an engine.
Scott: it's sort of in the service of a game, you know It's like they didn't just make the quake engine and they make quake later, you know They made the quake engine for quake because there was no engine available that suited their needs or is even close.
Scott: Yeah I mean In the making of a you need to make an actual game on the engine while you're making the engine so that you actually make The engine usable.
Rym: well, even half-life.
Rym: I mean half-life itself.
Rym: They took the quake engine that already existed and they modified it to suit their own very heavily though But they did.
Rym: they took a basic engine and modified.
Rym: they didn't just write anything from scratch.
Emily: Well, I feel like especially for all you aspiring bedroom coders out there you'll just save yourself a lot of work and produce probably a better-looking product.
Guest: if you Go for an engine that's already created It will save you a huge amount of time and headaches over very very minor things and as Emily suggested you'll be able to get a playable prototype of your game in a week or two.
Guest: and That first playable prototype is really important because that's gonna tell you whether or not your your basic concept is actually worth playing.
Guest: All the design docs in the world will only take you.
Guest: so far the design doc and you know Analysis of the game from a mathematical theoretical standpoint can help you in the right direction But it won't itself.
Guest: let you synthesize a fun game.
Guest: that theory doesn't seem to be developed yet.
Scott: Well, I mean, did you have any like, you know, you you would think right on paper at least that you know The designing of a fun game, you know.
Scott: without you know, the trial and error method we would be somewhere in the psychology department.
Scott: Did you have any like, you know psychology peoples on board?
Guest: not as such no That's a hobbyist.
Emily: I mean you've thought a lot about the psychology of games.
Emily: Yes
Guest: The most directly psychological like the thing I can think of that came into the design was actually in terms of visual design because that is what's gonna Turn people off or on to your game before they even have a chance to experience your clever mechanics, whatever they are.
Scott: Do judge by the book by the cover despite the saying as to not do so.
Emily: It was kind of weird because I remember we we ended up doing the visual stuff.
Emily: It actually wasn't a very taxing project.
Emily: as far as art design went, you know Because there wasn't a lot of 3d modeling It was it was mostly just these 2d character cards these illustrations that I had to do And I remember I I presented these mood boards to show like what I was kind of going for and I remember our boss Had some reservations.
Emily: he said, you know, I don't want this to be really heavy and dark and medieval looking.
Emily: I you know, even though it's got this alchemy theme this and mythology going on I want it to be approachable much more hardcore.
Guest: in the original It's kind of lightens over time, which is fine because it wasn't necessary to the game.
Emily: he wanted it to be more approachable and less, you know hard fantasy looking and I remember over that weekend.
Emily: I did a series of five sketches.
Emily: I did like a digital painting and a medieval kind of like illuminated manuscript looking and I did one that looked kind of Disney esque.
Emily: and then I did this cut paper design and It was funny because even though it was one of the simplest Illustrations it seemed like everybody really like that one.
Emily: It almost ended up with kind of this children's book Theme to it and I think that definitely changed the atmosphere of the game quite a bit.
Guest: It was I still feel a very striking design and it's not one that You really see in any other game at least none that I can think of.
Scott: Yeah, I mean you see you see it in South Park and such.
Scott: but you know, you don't see that in video games too often.
Guest: Yeah, I feel like there's some recent game that has this kind of like ripped cut paper theme going.
Guest: It's in a slightly different direction than ours The blurst one the paper moon.
Emily: They did all with sharpies and stuff.
Guest: But yeah the Anyway, it was a distinctive style and I think the distinctive style is gonna help from the that initial appeal point of view.
Guest: It's it gets eyes on it, which is always helpful.
Emily: So do you want to talk about a little bit how the actual game mechanics changed over time?
Scott: Yeah, it was Like how the game works, you know, like just the basic, you know, don't need we don't need the rule book.
Rym: We just need tell us the concept you started with and then we'll go from there through the evolutions All right.
Guest: Well as you may guess from the name of the game elementia It's about elements the before classical elements earth air fire water And it's a 2d kind of tile laying strategy game.
Guest: the The original idea of the game, I think it actually on some level came out of a conversation I had with you two guys over Japanese food.
Emily: I remember that time we were at the neko But it was.
Guest: have these four elements have each of them provide a different benefits and then using them in concert is the strategy you have to develop and On top of that was developed to this Sort of cyclical element beating another rather than the usual Well more usual two opposites each of which, you know can strike hard at the other.
Guest: It's everything beats one thing and is beaten by one other thing.
Guest: in this perfect circle If you've played the fire emblem games, it's very similar to the weapon triangles in there.
Scott: Yeah, they axe the spear in the sword.
Guest: Yeah, this case it's fire beats air air beats earth earth beats water water beats fire or crystal warriors.
Scott: Well, that's what is the.
Scott: so it cross ways.
Guest: it's just even Yep, so you have that.
Guest: you have the the tile laying which is There are two purposes to it.
Guest: There's the Arrange things so that Elements are adjacent to one another and provide the bonuses you need.
Guest: and there's the chain everything up to make attacks with since The way we do you do the attacks in this game the more elements of the same color it passes through the stronger it is.
Guest: So what we were trying to do is to create this tension between you want to stretch out in this long twisty chain but that's inherently fragile and you want to bunch things up to Produce all the adjacency benefits and protect each other and heal each other and all that good stuff.
Rym: So did you start considering multiplayer from the start or single-player only or what was your thinking along those lines?
Guest: multiplayer was in mind from the start.
Guest: the Original idea for the multiplayer was this crazy shifting alliances thing.
Guest: I'll say right now that a lot of stuff from elementia.
Guest: I cribbed from one board game or another.
Guest: The tile laying was originally basically straight out of T&E to take her son Euphrates Although it's kind of drifted since then.
Guest: This alliance mechanic that it has also drifted from since then was inspired by Dune and it ended up Actually managing the alliances was going to be too complicated for what it would have gotten us.
Guest: So we stuck to a strict.
Guest: it's either a versus game or a co-op game.
Emily: there's actually a fair number of maps that you developed and Do you want to talk about like the way the placing the elements?
Emily: changed because for a while it was a draft and there were like cards and And then there was a point system and there originally it was.
Guest: it was this card draw thing and that ended up being Basically wasn't adding anything anymore.
Guest: So again, if a mechanic isn't helping get rid of it, you don't need the extra complexity.
Guest: I mean the later development of this game was a battle with removing extra complexity.
Emily: Yeah It's just keep it simple.
Guest: Keep it simple and that was It's a very distinct thing between Four games which is on some level how I started thinking of this and a video game, which is what it actually is In that a board game.
Guest: usually when you play it you sit down and there is someone there to teach you.
Guest: that is Kind of a big crutch that board games can lean on and they can have a lot more Complexity and still appeal to a lot of people.
Guest: where for a video game has to be entirely self-taught Even if you're playing multiplayer You're usually not playing multiplayer with someone who's gonna walk you through every action and teach you all the mechanics Even when they're willing to.
Guest: they're not in the same room and it's really hard to do that over text chat or even voice chat.
Guest: If you they can't point at the screen.
Scott: Yeah, that's so true.
Scott: I mean like how many times do I get like a flash game?
Scott: and even if there are instructions I like maybe look at the controls and that's it.
Scott: If I look at anything at all before I just click play and start playing and it's such a short attention span with a video Game you just you know, if you can't figure it out right away.
Scott: It's like that's it.
Scott: You're done.
Guest: people aren't willing to read instructions and they aren't willing to figure it out for themselves.
Rym: It's it's it's catch-22, but it's weird because as much in the games as I am I'm like that.
Rym: I mean I sit down.
Rym: I'm a wreck the dead by getting any as game.
Rym: I take it home I put it straight in and I'd start the game.
Rym: I hit a. see what ate.
Rym: it hit B C would beat.
Rym: it hit them both.
Rym: I just try every button combination and then I'd go and that was it.
Scott: Yeah, it's really hard on the computer though.
Scott: Cuz you have a keyboard with so many buttons that if you're gonna use it at all It's.
Scott: you know, it's whoa.
Guest: You're of a mindset that you'll sit down to do that to a game and you'll actually do that until you figure it out.
Emily: Some people just go.
Emily: Oh, this is complicated.
Guest: Yeah, say it's complicated.
Guest: I don't want to bother Mmm, is that?
Scott: did you see that a lot in the testing like, you know, you'd get someone to play the game and they be Like I was too complicated.
Scott: What do I do?
Guest: Yeah, the the UI went through numerous revisions as a result of all that.
Emily: That was probably the biggest challenge in getting the game ready for release was getting the UI so it wasn't confusing.
Emily: people seemed like no matter what we did or how we designed the The wheel at the bottom showing the the progression of the elements.
Emily: Everybody was like, what does this do?
Emily: I don't understand this game at all.
Guest: Yeah, so there were a lot of iterations.
Guest: There was again complexity being stripped out where it wasn't absolutely strictly necessary and in the end I think we actually came up with something pretty cool and All this iteration and forcing us to think about it did help the final product.
Scott: Yeah I mean that's something I've noticed a lot.
Scott: actually is that you know When I when I look at indie games and when I look at professionally made games It seems like the indie games have these really good ideas But they really struggle on like a lot of basic things like controls and interface and these sorts of things and the professional games Often might not have much interesting going on in terms of the actual game.
Scott: But the interface is always correct and the you know, the the controls always are work and are well calibrated and all that That's what you get when you can hire a dedicated interface designer.
Emily: Yeah, seriously We did have an intern that you'd let him test stuff.
Guest: and yes You you need testing.
Guest: in any software development in game development You need more and additional kinds of testing than I think in any other kind With possible exception of life-or-death stuff like air traffic control.
Guest: Yeah, seriously because in addition to testing the the pure functionality of it You need to test that very subjective.
Guest: Is it fun thing?
Guest: and you need to test that on people who have never played the game before?
Guest: Which becomes increasingly hard to find as you you run through your list of friends who are willing to test and
Emily: all sorts of people Like, you know, you want to try to get different Demographics to test it and see okay So this is big with board gamers, but does this 30 year old lawyer lady like to play?
Emily: No, but we do have Once once a month we have this open open studio night where it's it's the muse games game night where you can Come and eat free pizza and test the games so that that actually helped a little bit in getting a variety of people to Just give us their basic reactions on the
Guest: huge help.
Scott: Yeah The cost of the pizza.
Guest: Oh, yes totally so.
Rym: did you ever get frustrated showing someone a game and trying to not explain things to them to see if they figure it Out on their own and seeing them clearly not figuring it out, even though it's so obvious to you.
Guest: Yes But I was helped in this in that Before we ran the first of these game nights I'd been flipping through various Game design documents from other companies.
Guest: valve in particular is as a huge resource of stuff.
Guest: They just put online.
Guest: It's their old GDC presentations and that sort of thing.
Guest: One of which was about the importance of hands-off testing where You the designer don't sit there and walk walk someone through the game you stand back and you watch their reaction See when they flounder and see when they're really picking it up quick and stuff like that.
Emily: And it's hard because it's like, you know having played the game so many times and being so familiar You at least I end up kind of lacking a perspective.
Emily: So I just want to be like no no see that's how you do it But you just got to force yourself to let them Figure it out on their own and acknowledge if they can't figure it out on your own you're doing something wrong.
Emily: Yep, that's what you're gonna work on tomorrow.
Scott: Games do exist that people figure out it on their own.
Scott: And so if yours isn't then that's Hopefully it is now.
Scott: So does your game have any sort of?
Scott: Musics going on.
Emily: Oh, I love the musics.
Emily: It was an acquaintance of our marketing guy and the guy who designed the website Austin and There was this composer that he knew and we sent him some demo tracks and One of the things my my vote was I was like I want something kind of ephemeral kind of like that end of time from Chrono Trigger.
Emily: and he wrote back.
Emily: He was like, I love Chrono Trigger.
Emily: He's actually a pretty big video gamer.
Guest: So and that's when we knew we had probably found the right guy.
Emily: Yeah His tracks turned out really nice Nicely, I don't know how you describe it kind of Bells and piano and it's not too overpowering.
Guest: it's it's not like a grandiose score, but I mean this is It's kind of a contemplative game and I think the music reinforces that.
Scott: yeah, you have sound effects like, you know.
Scott: Yep, did you make them or did you just buy them or what?
Guest: Yeah, we have a sound library that was minimally massaged by me wearing a sound designer hat And I I created the particle effects to go along with With those sound effects.
Emily: So like if you click on the fire attack, there'll be like flames.
Scott: And it was so that you see you're listening to the sound and then you had to make an animation that match.
Scott: It was opposed to vice-versa opposite, wasn't it?
Guest: We really needed sound in this thing.
Emily: Yeah, I think the sound adds a lot.
Emily: I mean people.
Emily: You know when?
Emily: when you're not actually creating a game I guess people don't realize how much Just simple sound effects will add to the overall product.
Scott: Well, I mean think about that Terminator game for the NES that soundtrack Yeah, where everything was the same exact noise No matter what happens you shoot you get hit Or Atari.
Scott: Yeah, so do you guys have like a?
Scott: you know, you're you're not a big game studio.
Scott: You're probably not selling this thing for like $50, right?
Scott: So is there a?
Scott: what is the money-making strategies you got there?
Emily: It's the game.
Emily: the core game itself is is free playable to anybody who has the unity plug-in.
Scott: Is that also free?
Emily: Unity plug-in is completely free and I'd actually recommend you download it.
Emily: I mean, I know a lot of the people listening to the show are probably really leery of installing any you know plugins on their computer.
Emily: But there's this browser plug-in that works with the game engine that we use unity 3d and allows you for 3d game content in your browser.
Guest: and it's not just us we're using it.
Guest: There are a few big companies who are using it and there are a million little indie game developers using it.
Guest: So So far as I know there's nothing else that is actually really doing this right now in terms of Letting you put 3d stuff in a web page.
Guest: There's the the nascent Google Mozilla efforts.
Guest: But yeah, even those there may be 3d, but they're not a full game Proprietary - I mean there's like the quick live.
Guest: Yeah Application an instant action, which is just a wrapper that lets it install any application it wants.
Emily: It's basically like the 3d version of flash is I guess the easiest way I've heard it explained.
Emily: But so you install the plug-in you go to our site and the games there to play But we will release further maps and other characters through the store.
Emily: and The part of the thing with elementia is it's got this mythological theme and there's all these.
Emily: You know the Sun the moon Saturn you know Jupiter very very Greek mythology oriented.
Emily: and I guess Half of the characters as of yet are free and the other half they have different powers different special abilities.
Guest: you can buy them for a for a pittance in the news game store and Because I know someone out there is gonna ask this because it's the question I would ask No, you do not get the inherently better characters by spending money on them About this.
Guest: The additional characters do provide you with other options.
Guest: They're all.
Guest: the characters are asymmetrical.
Guest: They provide for very different play styles But we were very careful to try to not make any of them strictly better than the others because the people who spend money are Not just gonna win.
Guest: No, we've seen how that ruins.
Scott: So it's not the Korean model it's just sort of a you know People who are big fans and want to want to do something Having a free demo and then you pay for the full version.
Emily: Yeah, and That one of the things I think is really good about the game is one.
Emily: it's.
Emily: it's two-player multiplayer four-player multiplayer.
Emily: It's either versus or cooperative.
Emily: It's you know, it can be played totally solitaire.
Emily: and The thing with the maps is you made a whole bunch of different variations where the Plague the enemy grows in different ways and there's different obstacles and stuff like that.
Emily: lay out of the board changes with each new map.
Guest: Provide some replayability there.
Rym: Yeah That stuff really reminds me of the miasma from Crystal Chronicles Wasn't it?
Guest: based in part on the fungi from Nausicaa Valley of the Wind?
Emily: Because it used to be called putrefaction before it was called the plague and I I thought the sea of corruption.
Emily: So I spent like I don't know three or four hours Just digging up pictures of mushrooms and that black mold in Michigan and Nausicaa.
Emily: I looked at all these weird plants from Nausicaa and So the the gloppiness of the of the enemy is it's a little a bit based on that.
Emily: It's kind of moldy.
Scott: So you said it was a. it was a browser plug-in.
Scott: So does it work in all the browsers?
Scott: I mean like Safari 4 just came out today.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: probably doesn't work in that right.
Guest: I'm not sure.
Guest: Safari 4 it does work in Safari doesn't work in Safari 4. it probably will shortly.
Guest: It works in IE Mozilla Chrome Safari on Windows and Mac.
Guest: there is no Linux version Unfortunately, there is demand for this and they've.
Guest: the developers of unity have said that they're looking into it, but they haven't gotten to it yet.
Emily: They better do my facial morph targets before they do that.
Scott: It works, you know, like, you know me but I mean like when you make a website, you know You always have to worry about all the different browsers.
Scott: Does this have a problem with that or no?
Guest: The unity itself is actually very good about cross browser compatibility.
Guest: There are occasional wrinkles with the cross operating system compatibility because it uses different Layers to talk to the hardware, but even those are relatively minor.
Scott: I'd say you know You wouldn't like recommend one browser over the other for playing it.
Scott: You would just say we use whichever one is the one you're using.
Guest: Sadly, I have to generally.
Guest: yes, sadly I have to make a ding against Firefox and that Firefox apparently has terrible memory management on some level And it causes weird garbage collector hiccups.
Guest: There's nothing you can't play through.
Scott: So that's Firefox 3 you're talking about.
Guest: That is Firefox.
Scott: I'd be interested in Firefox three and a half.
Scott: Have you tested that out?
Guest: I have not.
Guest: I'll have to do that.
Scott: That'd be interesting.
Scott: Yeah That's enough technical whatnots.
Emily: So you guys have played the game right.
Scott: I played it a few times a little bit.
Scott: I played it while I was having beer and pizza after work Of course, I think I've only played the actual finished game though, like once or twice, you know, I played the Unfinished game a few other times.
Emily: I remember you were very obsessed with the old man.
Emily: You're like old man.
Scott: Well, I like the characters.
Guest: Lemon party You brought it up, not us.
Scott: Rym brought it up.
Rym: Lemon party.
Emily: This is not good promotional material.
Scott: The characters are all you know, it's like.
Scott: it's like on the one hand.
Scott: They're like all you know, sort of, you know stylistic But they're also sort of cute and quirky in a way, you know, it's like they do all have a lot of personnel.
Scott: Yeah, it's like when I. it's like whenever I play a video game with characters, you know, like a fighting game or whatever You know, it's like there's always some characters obviously better or worse, right?
Scott: But I try not to pick based on that.
Scott: It's like when I play a board game I always pick green because I like green.
Scott: so when I play a video game and there's a character selection I try to pick a character that looks, you know, you know as something I like, you know.
Scott: So if I'm playing Street Fighter, I'll pick you know M. Bison because he I just I just like his look better than I like The other people, you know.
Scott: or I'll pick You know Siegfried in Soulcalibur because he's a big knight with a giant sword and all the other people are sort of.
Scott: I'm not interested in them, you know, so You know in in this game There's sort of like this quirky old man with a cane and he's sort of like whoo.
Scott: His head's like leaning over a little bit and he's sort of like, you know He reminds me of sort of like, you know, like the sort of silly old man in a lot of animes and whatnot.
Emily: I should do you a little animation of him just to make you happy like take After Effects and be like I was that he's not animated in the actual game.
Emily: No, he's not animated.
Emily: I didn't have time to do that.
Scott: I was making t-shirts You plan to like, you know, I mean, you know not.
Scott: the game is like done and out, right?
Scott: Yes, it is So are you going to continue though to you know iterate upon it or are you just gonna you know?
Scott: Leave it be and move on.
Guest: Um, well, that's partly gonna depend on What feedback we get about it?
Guest: I don't think any of the other games we've released have ever actually been finished So I see no reason to expect that for this one.
Emily: But on the other hand, part of the reason why I didn't animate the characters on the character cards was that we do have two other games in the pipeline.
Emily: This is really only our second full game release.
Emily: I mean, we have that virtual world chat, but that's not really a game per se.
Guest: Although in fairness, a lot of the technology we developed for that fed into all our other games.
Emily: Yeah, definitely.
Emily: And actually, it had the most art asset creation for it.
Emily: But so this is like our second game game after Extreme Sledding.
Emily: And there's two other games in the pipeline.
Emily: Can you tell us anything about them, or is that still a proprietary secret?
Emily: What do you think?
Emily: Can I say the buzzword for the one?
Guest: I think we can say one magical word about one of them.
Emily: Air pirates.
Rym: That's two words.
Guest: Oh, no.
Emily: Air pirates and airships.
Emily: Be prepared.
Rym: So having actually brought this game to completion from the beginning as kind of people just getting into the gaming industry, what did you learn?
Rym: Like, what would you have done differently from the start making this game?
Guest: Well, one, I have a much greater grasp of how much complexity you can actually expect people to pick up on, especially for a little browser game.
Guest: And it has taught me to rein in my ambitions for the future.
Emily: And I don't know.
Emily: As far as I'm concerned, like I said, it was a very simple game as far as art asset creation.
Emily: But I think one thing that really left an impression on me is, you know, GUI design is incredibly important.
Emily: And I should definitely start earlier in the design process with developing a GUI.
Emily: And like each iteration, each change in gameplay, you've got to adjust your ideas of the layout of the interface.
Emily: And I guess the interface, we really started working on that way late in the game.
Emily: We had like a very standard boxes thing--.
Guest: It was crappy with the [INAUDIBLE] --for a long time, yeah.
Emily: So I think every time Alex changes a gameplay element, I think I'll also have to look at it, and along with our other design people like Austin, and kind of brainstorm about how can we make this particular iteration very intuitive and playable.
Guest: If you're one of those aspiring game developers out there, I have a piece of very, I think, cogent advice for you.
Guest: Inevitably, if you're a wannabe game developer, you have in mind some huge sprawling game.
Guest: Statistically, from what I've seen, it's very likely to be an RPG, but it doesn't have to be, with a million really cool and novel mechanics, and really great graphics, and a really awesome story, and wonderful music.
Guest: And that's great.
Guest: And that's a great thing to shoot for, but you have to understand you're not going to make it on your first try.
Guest: It's kind of like-- You have to be willing to focus on the things that are really important about the game, the most important elements, whatever they are.
Guest: Make those work.
Guest: And if you can add stuff that works with them rather than against them, great.
Guest: But if you can't, leave it small and perfect.
Emily: Well, it's kind of like how I was when I first entered film school.
Emily: It's like I really wanted to do this big epic feature thing.
Emily: And then I realized, no, just concentrate on getting a damn good three minutes worth of footage, and then start to increase your ambition.
Emily: But yeah, start small and start solid.
Emily: Come up with something really well thought out, and then you can start to work your way up the ladder.
Guest: Do not allow yourself the luxury of saying, I know this, and this, and this.
Guest: This one part.
Guest: I'm kind of fuzzy on, but I'll figure it out later.
Guest: No.
Guest: Sit down and figure that part out now.
Scott: Or else it'd be Dwarf Fortress.
Emily: I don't know.
Guest: I don't think that's where Dwarf Fortress has issues.
Guest: I don't think so.
Guest: It has issues.
Guest: I won't deny.
Scott: I just wanted to rip on Dwarf Fortress.
Emily: So you too, review time.
Emily: Do you like the game, yes or no?
Emily: YN?
Scott: I don't know if I've played it enough to figure out if I like it or not.
Scott: I got to play it a few more times.
Scott: Because definitely when I played it most recently, it was way different from what I remembered.
Rym: Because we were playing like that beta beta version on the right.
Emily: I remember I was playing the beta beta version version.
Emily: We were all sitting in front of the TV that I played the beta beta version.
Scott: And it seemed kind of because like I would put out a whole bunch of balls and they would die really slowly.
Scott: And it was sort of like it was that, you know, it was like I was.
Scott: I couldn't tell if I was winning or losing.
Scott: And, you know, I could put so much stuff out.
Scott: And it was just sort of like this attrition kind of thing.
Scott: But when I played it more recently against Alex, it just sort of got creamed immediately.
Scott: So it was definitely a much tighter game.
Scott: where you can you can.
Scott: It was a very significant winning and losing.
Rym: Well, there's definitely the increasing cost.
Rym: as you do one action more and more to discourage the, you know, obvious, make a whole bunch of red and then destroy a whole bunch of stuff with that red.
Emily: I like the increasing price mechanic.
Emily: I think that added a lot.
Scott: I think what it is to sum up what I was saying is that in the earlier version of the game, it felt like your individual moves mattered less.
Scott: And in the more recent one, each move matters a whole lot more.
Scott: And so a wrong move here or there can be the difference.
Scott: So there's actually significant decisions being made all the time.
Scott: And that is that is definitely a good thing in a game that I like, at least.
Scott: I don't know about other people.
Guest: I think it was Sid Meyer who said the immortal phrase that every game designer should know a game is a series of interesting decisions.
Scott: Yes, that is correct.
Rym: I guess I I feel like it'll shine the most in multiplayer because knowing that there's a human making these important decisions on the other side always means a lot to me.
Rym: And of course, you all out in the forums can just play this game with us.
Emily: Just please play this game.
Emily: Everybody listening, please.
Emily: Emily asked you, please go check it out.
Rym: I'd be very happy if you have things to say.
Rym: Good or bad.
Rym: Just post them in the forum.
Guest: Yeah.
Guest: Or email us.
Guest: We're there.
Guest: We'll listen.
Emily: Yeah, we're.
Emily: I mean, seriously.
Emily: Thank us.
Emily: We're front row crew.
Rym: Just yes, you've got the rare opportunity to talk directly to the game designers about a game they made.
Emily: Yeah, and we might actually listen to you.
Emily: That's a rarity in this business.
Emily: Except with tribes, too, where they listen to much.
Scott: Let's not go down that road.
Scott: So the game is.
Scott: so the game is a browser plug any thing.
Scott: And like, you know, other browser games like, say, desktop tower defense, they get like they get posted in like a whole bunch of different sites.
Scott: Is your you know, is it possible to put like unity game on like the congregate and all sorts of places or is it only at your website?
Guest: It is.
Guest: It is possible to put a unity game on any site you want.
Guest: I don't believe congregate supports them yet, although they have.
Guest: I've heard internal mutterings that they might eventually.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: You know, I could see it partly just because unity does.
Rym: It really serves a different purpose from flash and it does 3D.
Scott: Well, it's definitely more game centric.
Scott: I mean, is unity used for anything that's not a game?
Guest: The closest non game thing I've seen it used for is educational simulations of various kinds, sort of architectural visualization.
Emily: Oh, I've seen I've seen architectural stuff done with it.
Guest: But it is very specifically a game engine as opposed to Flash, which is this animation tool come programming tool.
Emily: Yeah, actually, I think in terms of game, like the the programming side of it, it it manages the physics and stuff very well, which Flash does not do.
Emily: Anyway, amuse games.
Emily: There aren't really any unity game portals right now, but we're kind of hoping that maybe someday our site can become a hub for independent developers, you know, us as a studio, but also us as a community for unity.
Scott: That's definitely a good thing to go for.
Scott: I mean, nothing succeeds today without building a community around it.
Emily: That's the big part of it.
Emily: Yeah.
Scott: Podcast game, open source project.
Emily: And another part of our our business plan is even though we're a very small team, we're about five people.
Emily: We we really want to make games that are fun to play multiplayer over the Internet.
Emily: So both multiplayer and single player is one of the requirements for every game we do.
Scott: So you had five people.
Scott: about how long did it take, you know, from like let's make a game to well, from let's make this game to it today.
Emily: Well, Muse, Muse Games itself was was launched on April 14th.
Emily: But this game has been in development since when about, um, it's a few months ago.
Guest: I spent about a month doing the original design document, but that was not the only thing I was working on.
Guest: Yeah, that's the thing.
Guest: It's really hard to think because, you know, we're always doing about two weeks to have a what I would actually call a playable prototype and then about another three weeks to a month of work to get it to the final state.
Guest: Again, interspersed with other projects here and there.
Guest: That's why it's actually been more like two months since the design document was finished.
Scott: Two months is pretty good for, you know, an entire game.
Scott: I mean, at that rate, you could make, you know, six games a year.
Scott: And when you're you know, at least from what I've seen, if you're making small games that are probably not going to be like, you know, stupid, popular all over the Internet, it's, you know, quantity is is a good thing to have.
Guest: That is roughly what we're shooting for is a game every two months, and especially now that the site is up and we can focus our energies on the actual games.
Emily: Yeah, that that was a big part of it.
Emily: There was a lot of, you know, creating icons for the store and stuff like that.
Scott: And since we all have many hats, so you won't have to do that again because they'll just know this.
Emily: The site is there and we can really hone in on doing the, you know, about eight weeks of full on game development if stuff goes well.
Rym: So the game is Elementia, Moo...
Emily: Elementia!
Scott: Muse Studios.
Scott: But the link is on frontrowcrew.com.
Emily: Musegames.com.
Rym: Yep, there will be links in the show notes.
Rym: You can find that.
Rym: This was Emily Compton and Alex Strawberry.
Rym: Serious.
Guest: Jerocher Ernst.
Scott: I know his name.
Scott: Why don't you know it?
Guest: Well, he does know my name.
Guest: He just knows it only in translation, apparently.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week, covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights, and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com.
Scott: Or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Scott: Just click the link that says Send Me an Odeo on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives, visit the website, which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution Non-Commercial Share-A-Like 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it, as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.