Rym: Hey, it's Tuesday, February 17th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights that we talk about all those old sim games.
Scott: See your mom Let's do this.
Rym: Yeah, we were actually up in Albany this past weekend.
Rym: It's been a while since we've left the geek house.
Scott: Oh Yeah Albany it's colder There's less people there It's farther away from civilization More people there than there are in beacon.
Scott: Oh, yeah, but I'm talking about just you know more general geography Not specific geography.
Scott: I mean, there's more people in Albany than there is in our backyard.
Scott: You know, do you got a?
Scott: you got to compare the same radius?
Rym: I don't know how it's really relevant though because you spend your whole time inside.
Scott: Yeah, that's correct.
Scott: Well, we went outside a little bit a little pretty much.
Rym: we just got the crew together to celebrate one of our elders birthdays.
Rym: yeah, I got him an Xbox and Played a little bit of mouse guard.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Well, we made characters.
Scott: We didn't play anything.
Rym: Well, the thing is mouse guard like burning wheel.
Rym: character creation is in and of itself a game.
Scott: Yeah, you know We'll probably talk about this more when we actually talk about it.
Scott: Yes, you know the the mouse guard character creation It's like when you make a character in burning wheel or even if you make a character in D&D.
Scott: The act of making a character is in and of itself like this fun activity Like I get to sit there all day burning characters choosing life paths, right and mouse guard.
Scott: a good thing They did is they made it more collaborative.
Scott: So it's actually sort of the beginning of the game.
Scott: is the character making?
Scott: everyone sits around and does it.
Scott: But I think the act of doing it is a little bit less fun than the burninating.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: It definitely it creates a different kind of character.
Rym: Yeah, it does which is important because mouse guard kind of really pushes you in a certain direction.
Rym: role-playing.
Scott: Yes So yeah, but uh, well you have to be you know in the mouse guard You can't really can't be like you're not you're not gonna make a mouse who's you know Equivalent life paths were born in the gutter.
Rym: peasant peasant peasant peasant.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty much you have to be at some point.
Scott: Join the mouse guard is good actually, you know is on the side of the mouse guard.
Scott: You can't.
Rym: of course that shouldn't be as much of a concern.
Rym: It's just when we play burning wheel, it seems like everybody wants to be the asshole traitor.
Scott: Well, you're not gonna get in the mouse guard for the asshole traitor.
Rym: Yeah, but like in burning wheel everyone's the asshole traitor I know right except me.
Rym: I'm the good guy.
Scott: Well, yeah, I could talk more on this based on things that I have learned recently But I will not.
Rym: because yes, I don't want to drag on and dive, you know tangent the show too much But suffice it to say oh We'll be talking about mouse guard a lot more in the days to come.
Rym: Basically, we just have to play it a whole bunch of times first.
Scott: So I actually playing not just the character.
Rym: Yeah, so I can jive all the things that Luke and David told me about it with my actual experiences.
Rym: Mmm, but we I got that interview.
Rym: I got at the comic-con.
Rym: I listened to it again on the train.
Rym: It was pretty fantastic.
Scott: You should give me it.
Rym: I'll get it out.
Rym: I got to edit it together a little bit.
Scott: I would just want to hear what it was without the editing.
Rym: All right, maybe I'll put it in experimental feed someday.
Scott: Ooh Yeah raw uncut, you know, you could also just give me a copy cuz I'm right here.
Rym: Yeah, I could.
Rym: It's actually right here on the Marantz.
Scott: Yeah, that would be nice.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So, so, let's see.
Scott: What's news?
Scott: Oh, I know what's news.
Scott: the pirate Bay One of the best websites on to internets there was big news because they're having Ted trials alright, so basically the European RAA Swedish whatever equivalent right basically all the record labels is to you know Took the Pirate Bay to court.
Scott: mostly they took the three guys at the head of the Pirate Bay who actually you know run it and one guy who gave them a bunch of money who sort of a Sympathetic rich guy in Sweden, right and they're taking that.
Scott: that's who the trial that is being charged here.
Scott: and You know, there was like questioning like oh no Is this the end for the Pirate Bay even though they've managed to avoid the law?
Scott: You know and beat the law and courts up until now for so many years.
Rym: Well do primarily to the way the legal system is over there.
Scott: Yes Will they continue to be awesome and beat the law?
Scott: or will this be?
Scott: Doom for bit torrents, right and I mean I was just using Pirate Bay the other day to get legal things.
Scott: So You know if it goes down that's not good for the world.
Scott: But so I was going oh no like two days ago.
Scott: We were all like, oh no, is it gonna go good or bad?
Rym: Oh, no, I was pretty indifferent.
Scott: to be honest I'm not in I'm.
Scott: I definitely want the Pirate Bay's to win but you know I do in many regards.
Rym: But at the same time it wouldn't affect me that much if it went away Partly because something else something else immediately appear like before even.
Scott: well, I mean, that's the thing is that there are plenty of Pirate Bay equivalent slice.
Scott: the thing is they all sort of suck, you know, it's like they have bad searches They have a shit ton of nasty ads or you can't trust them or their torrents suck.
Scott: You know, the Pirate Bay is actually a decent clean website, you know Like how many other torrent sites are there out there that they could go after Mininova.
Scott: right is that still around?
Rym: I have no idea.
Rym: Yeah, I just remember, you know at RIT and kind of the the peak of the post Napster piracy days I would go to where sites and it would basically be 99% horrible pornography ads and every now and then the crack I was looking for.
Scott: Usually if you clicked on that you had to get like three rars from three different sites and click on a bunch of viruses?
Rym: Yeah Yeah, of course I always got them on RIT computers and then copied the clean crack I got at the end from the RIT computer.
Scott: if you could trust the crack is clean.
Rym: Well, usually the crack was something along the lines of a CD key.
Scott: Yeah, if it was a CD key generator, I would just generate the CD key on another machine write it down in a piece of paper Bring it and maybe write generate like three or four just to make sure just in case.
Scott: Yeah, then bring them over.
Rym: Those were good days.
Scott: Yeah No But the so far the Pirate Bay went to court for one day right and in the first day they came out with the arguments and I was reading and they were actually Like surprisingly able to make their points in court and it was sort of a. I was like wow This is a Court of Commons.
Scott: almost, you know, it makes our court look like, you know Frickin, I don't know a kangaroo cart.
Scott: He has something like that.
Scott: I was gonna say like Like what's that Wild West show?
Scott: What's the dude's name?
Rym: I Can think of like 10 Wild West the one with Annie Oakley.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I forget.
Scott: I'm so stupid.
Scott: That makes our court look like that.
Scott: so, you know and they were basically like hey look we don't actually share any files There are no illegal things on our server.
Scott: All we do is have these torrent files and all our users are doing these things and we're not filtering, you know.
Scott: So it's sort of like that DMCA exception argument.
Scott: It's like, you know, we are not making any publishing decisions there We're just providing this service to any torrent legal or illegal and it's not our you know bag to say yes or no, right?
Scott: So they made this great argument in court.
Scott: So the next day Apparently the lawyers for the the record labels, you know The bad guys were like, oh but apparently they understood what was just said to them and they were pretty much like off.
Scott: These guys don't have any copy illegal things on their servers anywhere now didn't they?
Rym: Couldn't?
Rym: they have looked at the website and figured well good then again if they're not text They might not have been able to figure it.
Scott: Well, that's just is.
Scott: they were basically look clearly the other people don't understand the technology here but apparently now they do or they do more so and apparently the judge and whoever also Understands and as a result, they pretty much had to drop half their charges.
Scott: So, I mean the Pirate Bay guys could still get a huge fine and they could still have up to two years in prison.
Scott: But that's the most they could have Assuming they're found guilty of all the remaining charges and get the maximum everything.
Scott: So so far.
Scott: It's it's Pirate Bay to Everyone else.
Scott: negative one and we'll see what the final.
Scott: we'll see what the final score is pretty Hiccups hiccups.
Scott: Yeah, we'll see.
Scott: We'll see what the final score is pretty soon.
Scott: But right now looking good for the Perot in.
Rym: So not along those lines at all.
Rym: there's this article in slash dot and people were kind of Overreacting to it, but at the same time it's one of those things where the concept itself brings up a lot of points.
Rym: I'm sure you saw it But the headline was that the European Parliament basically wants to add a quote Red button for shutting down video games.
Scott: What do you mean a red button?
Rym: Well, I can read the actual quotation here.
Rym: parents should have a quote red button unquote To disable a game they feel is inappropriate for their child says EP internal market committee Until Peggy online is up and running.
Rym: I don't know what Peggy is.
Rym: The report proposes fitting consoles computers or other game devices with a quote red button unquote To give parents the chance to disable a game or control access at certain times.
Scott: Well, okay, you know, but that's not something needs to be legislated.
Scott: all you need to do is just have parents who can go and Push the power button.
Rym: Well this that's what bothers me pull the plug out of the wall.
Scott: That's what you don't need legislation for this.
Rym: Like I said, that's what bothers me the fact that I mean one.
Rym: there shouldn't be any legislation about anything like this.
Rym: Anyway, because it's ludicrous, but to the fact that anyone would be an advocate of this.
Rym: I mean Can't parents.
Rym: I remember when I was a kid.
Rym: if my parents didn't want me to play Mario They wouldn't let me play Mario and there was nothing I could do about that.
Rym: Yeah, what are the?
Rym: what are these kids today that they can somehow get away with?
Rym: that?
Scott: I think whoever this guy is he should sit down and watch the episode of South Park where you know Cartman has all the nannies and then the dog trainer Right because he basically, you know, they take the Xbox away from him he plugs it back in they take it away He plugs it, you know, I think that's what.
Rym: that's what he needs there but it worries me that this sort of thing is eventually going to actually get legislated through because Video games are still the rock and roll of our era.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know You should ask him.
Scott: He was probably listening to rock and roll be like, hey What would you say if your parents had a button to just turn off your tap, you know turntable?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: well, we don't actually need a button.
Scott: They could have unplugged it at any time It's not you know, no, of course, we're completely ignoring all the other factors.
Rym: Like I don't know that this is completely technically infeasible.
Rym: kids are smarter than their parents.
Rym: They would just get around it anyway.
Scott: Yeah, how's this button supposed to work now?
Rym: apparently follow-up articles noted that the red button was a metaphorical construct only but that doesn't make any sense because All right, it's a medical metaphorical concept.
Scott: still how it already exists.
Scott: It's called the plug going into the wall, but I don't know.
Scott: it's called the power button.
Rym: I don't understand it's called the spanking at any point.
Rym: something like that I can't imagine.
Scott: Not that I advocate spanking of children.
Rym: I can I advocate other spankings?
Scott: Okay, if you know what I mean, I'm curious.
Rym: continue.
Scott: What do you continue?
Rym: What kinds of spankings.
Rym: do you advocate Scott the sexy kind?
Scott: Apparently that wasn't.
Scott: I didn't.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I didn't realize it needed to go beyond the innuendo.
Rym: What kind of spanking is the sexy comment?
Scott: all the kinds that don't involve children?
Rym: All the kinds.
Scott: Can you think of a spanking that does not involve children?
Scott: That is not sexy.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: I can someone I can very much.
Scott: It's sexy to somebody.
Rym: I point out in Horatio when they catch that traitor for like the second time.
Scott: That wasn't a spanking that was a lashing.
Rym: No, that was a spanking.
Scott: it could.
Scott: it wasn't a paddling.
Rym: He put him over his knee took off the guy's belt and hit him on the ass with it Repeatedly Thinking that's a belting.
Rym: That's a belt.
Scott: spanking involves the hand.
Rym: does it now?
Scott: Yes does.
Rym: Anyway, I guess it was interesting to watch this article primarily because the internet went crazy about it, you know rambling You know, how could a red button work?
Rym: It's completely infeasible.
Rym: all these all the obvious arguments, but then the counter argument was you people are idiots.
Rym: It was just the red button thing was just metaphorical.
Rym: But then the response to that is but still what do they mean then?
Rym: because if it's metaphorical they're still implying that there should be Some sort of legislated way for parents to control their children that parents should already be able to control their children.
Scott: Yet you can already.
Scott: this we don't need.
Scott: not only do we not need a law for this We don't need anything for this.
Scott: It already exists.
Scott: As I said the power button the power cord.
Rym: Well, there it is.
Rym: It kind of does illuminate the deeper issue that there's a lot of talk about.
Rym: we need to protect children from the internet and Kids need to be like you got to watch him and there's stalkers and all this stuff.
Rym: But I guess I I don't know.
Rym: I feel like I should point out that when I got a computer my parents and the rest of my family Basically knew nothing about them and I had a hundred percent free rein to do whatever I wanted.
Rym: Yeah, me too I was online unsupervised for most of my childhood and Nothing bad came of it.
Rym: No, not really.
Scott: I think the major problem here is that Is not that you know, there is a power cord.
Scott: There is a power button, right?
Scott: It's that you know What was that?
Scott: one of the the cartoons with the nerdy guys where the dad couldn't turn the computer off?
Scott: Remember?
Scott: Oh, yeah, right We have a situation where you know parents still have authority over their children.
Scott: just you know in in but they Don't have.
Scott: you know, their kids are smarter than they are so they can't.
Scott: you know you you in the olden days Right a parent was smarter than the kid and pretty much everything like the old Bill Cosby.
Rym: all the bits about how they try To avoid getting hit with the belt, but they'd always hit hit with the belt, right or like, you know It's like oh you try to sneak out of the house.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, guess what?
Scott: I try to sneak out of the house, too.
Scott: I know everything there is to know about sneaking out of the house and you get caught every time.
Rym: Oh my god, you know the Simpsons isn't really funny anymore but I ended up randomly watching a recent episode and there's this whole thing where Lisa was gonna be bad and My margins basically like uh, yeah, whatever you can't get out.
Rym: You're locked in your room.
Rym: so she's like hey and she goes out the window and she starts to climb down the tree and she jumps to the ground into Marja's arms and she says Bart fourth grade.
Rym: You've got a lot to learn missy.
Scott: Exactly Right, it's like the thing is.
Scott: you have parents now.
Scott: these parents didn't have vid you game.
Scott: So I guess, you know younger parents did.
Scott: we're getting you know, we're getting to that time.
Scott: But the older parents, you know 40, you know pluses did not.
Scott: so their kids are doing things that they don't understand.
Scott: So the kids are actually able to beat parents at.
Scott: you know, I guess it's not even the parents game It's just they could just beat their parents.
Scott: and that is why The parents and older people feel they need Legislation or technology or something to help them, you know Keep their kids in line because now their kids are smarter than them.
Scott: if your kids are smarter than how do you keep them in?
Scott: Control they're just.
Scott: you know, you can't you can't do anything.
Scott: the same thing happens to teach.
Rym: See the trick is I wouldn't in this case.
Rym: I wouldn't necessarily say Smarter more that well not smarter overall, but there's a. it's not even intelligence so much It's just knowledge alone provides power over parents to children.
Rym: these days even if the children have no like they're not smart They don't have any like really real aptitude for this stuff.
Rym: No, but if they have knowledge It's like a magic spell that no parent can get around Mmm, but then again no matter how smart the kid is in that regard The parent can just take away the computer and not let the kid go outside.
Scott: so Yeah, but I mean, you know, usually a parent is too stupid for that kind of thing.
Rym: again, I wouldn't say stupid I would just say I don't know knowledgeable or timid.
Scott: Oh, well, maybe.
Scott: but also, you know, sometimes it's just a little ludicrous Like okay, no TV.
Scott: They turn they push the power button on the TV.
Scott: So the kid goes, okay It's like go to your room and take the TV out of the kids room.
Scott: Okay Kid like tunes into TV on his iPhone.
Rym: Clearly you take away all the kids stuff and you put him in his room with nothing.
Scott: That's the thing is you don't even realize that it's you know, and then the kids got a hidden game gear with a TV tuner.
Scott: You know the kids have so much electronic shit the game gear TV turn.
Rym: It won't work anymore.
Rym: Today's February 17th.
Rym: Oh my god We have to make a digital game gear TV tutor, I know it's done, you know, the saddest thing is I Desperately wanted one of those.
Rym: I had a game gear and every day I was like mom can I have the TV tuner?
Scott: She's like no It's a kid had that at summer camp the best possible place to have.
Rym: Oh my god That kid must have been a legend.
Scott: We were it was summer.
Scott: We were watching baseballs in summer camp.
Scott: I mean heroes get remembered Baseballs, I mean, this is the place where you don't even have radios and we had baseball.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: now this past weekend We got you know an Xbox 360 and it's interesting because as much into gaming as we all are This was the first Xbox 360 in our in the front row crew, basically It's kind of surprising.
Scott: I think Wyatt has one, but we never go to his house.
Rym: So effectively he does not have one.
Rym: I have not seen it.
Rym: I cannot prove it.
Rym: Yeah, but yeah, he had an account.
Rym: so I guess you're right.
Scott: yeah, he has one trust, but we got one.
Rym: Adam had one and of course we got Soul Calibur 4 and We played it.
Scott: We played it a whole bunch because I didn't played it all because you and Nuri had to go home early You know, I had you know, she had to go home far away and I had to go to work today.
Rym: It worked out for the best because we went.
Rym: I mean yesterday you we basically went to dinner and got seafood and gluten.
Rym: But we played Soul Calibur 4 and I have two things to say.
Rym: I kind of want to review that game a little bit in depth later, but one Everyone sucked at it at first because we never really played three.
Rym: So we were a whole version behind already and the timing and a lot of stuff has changed quite a bit.
Rym: but one by one.
Rym: like at first we're playing and Then suddenly Adam starts kicking all our asses and then Wyatt starts kicking everyone's asses.
Rym: But Adam and then I start kicking everyone's asses But Wyatt as one by one.
Rym: we all figured out like the gimmick or the trick or the timing for this new game And I really like Soul Calibur 4.
Rym: It's a lot better than Soul Calibur 3 and I think if I play it enough it might supplant.
Rym: Soul Calibur 2 is my favorite Fighting.
Scott: I can't do that.
Rym: Ah, you didn't play it.
Rym: It's pretty good.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Rym: The thing is everyone in the room agreed it sucks to play a Soul Calibur game without a GameCube controller.
Scott: Well, I mean how much different is it really?
Scott: I mean you only really need the stick and For but
Rym: as you do but the way the four buttons are
Scott: in a diamond like every other controller Yes,
Rym: but with the GameCube because of the way it was structured It was much more viscerally correct on this kind of low raw level.
Rym: It just felt right.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know you're talking about.
Rym: Well, everyone seemed to agree.
Rym: I mean half of that was the fact that everyone was used to the GameCube controller.
Scott: I think 80% of it was.
Scott: you're used to the game controller.
Rym: Not just me.
Rym: It was everyone.
Scott: Well, everyone else is also used to a GameCube controller for Soul Calibur.
Scott: Yes, but I think the other half of it and we kind of we were playing with some ps2 Soul Calibur people or Xbox Soul Calibur people they'll say oh the game controller is so bad.
Rym: No, I've heard a lot of people say that they prefer the GameCube controller Even if they had a ps2.
Scott: I never heard such a thing.
Rym: I think I've heard of it.
Rym: is the the difference between the way you use the thumb You can rock the thumb on the GameCube controller You have to move the thumb a little bit more and in a different way on the Xbox controller But anyway holding the Xbox controller properly.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: I am Scott good Yeah, you didn't even play it.
Scott: I have an Xbox controller.
Scott: So I know how it goes.
Rym: Yeah We'll see you play some Soul Calibur 4.
Rym: We'll see how you do.
Scott: But anyway, I don't wanna play Soul Calibur 2.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I kind of disagree.
Rym: I think you just stuck in the past and you're nostalgic and it's a better game.
Scott: No, it's not.
Rym: but I have two things to say.
Rym: one It is a better game and it is.
Rym: it is incredibly enjoyable and it's great.
Scott: No, I don't think so.
Rym: Okay, mister Hasn't even played it ever.
Scott: I don't need to play it.
Rym: Okay, I I don't know.
Rym: so you're saying that you're you forming an opinion on a game you've never played.
Rym: yeah Okay, that's great.
Rym: But what was your whole thing?
Rym: Don't knock it till you tried it.
Scott: I don't need to try it.
Rym: Why not?
Scott: because I have enough information about it.
Rym: Okay, what is wrong Scott with Soul Calibur 4?
Scott: It's not Soul Calibur 2.
Rym: Okay Anyway, the two the two things I have to say about it is that one it's a fantastic game and we had a lot of fun but to Yoda Really really feels fucked up like the Fed like we're playing fine and then someone picks Yoda and it's like ah Like no one could deal with it.
Rym: But that was mitigated a little bit by the first time we played on the Star Wars stage and that was hilarious.
Rym: I don't know why but that was like inexplicably hilarious.
Scott: Where is the Star Wars stage?
Rym: It's in the Bay of the Death Star Where the Bay we're like the Millennium Falcon is kept like you'll see outside star destroyers going by in a big space battle going on And it plays Star Wars music.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, it's fantastic.
Rym: But the problem is you look at Yoda and you just want to cry.
Rym: Yeah, it took a while.
Scott: every time we played everyone's like I swear Understand why they put Yoda on the 360 and Darth Vader on the ps3 because the ps3 is black and the Xbox 360 is green.
Rym: I don't think that was the reason.
Scott: that was definitely the reason.
Rym: but do you do you have any evidence for that captain evidence?
Scott: That's that's definitely the reason.
Rym: did you can you back that up?
Scott: It's obvious.
Rym: Is there any evidence at all any any citation anything?
Scott: Yes Look it up on two internets.
Rym: I'm sure.
Scott: but You know, I think even though as stupid as both of them are to be in that game, you know I'd rather have Darth Vader even though I'd rather have a 360 than a ps3.
Rym: It just it doesn't work.
Scott: at least Darth Vader's the same height and has a sword.
Scott: Well, yeah, you know uses a sword more like how the other Soul Calibur people use their swords.
Rym: Never mind the fact that doesn't make sense.
Scott: or non swords?
Rym: I am very happy that Siegfried is a good guy again, and not only is a good guy.
Rym: He's like a super good guy.
Rym: Yeah 10 he.
Rym: you look at him you're like if ever there was a paladin.
Rym: is that dude right there?
Scott: I mean, I played Siegfried in soul edge, right?
Scott: I've been playing him since and when they he became nightmare I was like, alright, I can still change him to the non nightmare costume and he's still control.
Scott: Well, well the not as nightmare costume The non nightmare at all costume.
Rym: He's still kind of evil and messed up looking.
Scott: No, not really.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: He's just a dude wearing armor.
Rym: Anyway compared to uh Soul Calibur 4 where he's just like this gleaming Silverman.
Rym: Yeah, kind of sexy.
Scott: No, yeah, but you know, he'd still controlled mostly the same way.
Scott: You know guy with a big sword moves kind of slow good range lots of damage, you know.
Scott: But having him separate from nightmare again is a bit nice.
Rym: Of course, I have a newfound Rekindled love for Cervantes.
Rym: I Always hated playing as him, but I learned that there's a a really cheap combo that is basically - vertical backup - vertical backup and it took a while for people to figure out a way around.
Scott: Well, I think a problem we always have is that no one in our group is actually one of those really good fighting game players and if anyone like that came along we would just all lose every time and never be able to win.
Scott: and so as a result like our level of fighting game play is like so in some Difficult to ascertain, you know realm.
Rym: Yes, it most definitely is but here's the main reason Why Soul Calibur 4 is better than Soul Calibur 2.
Rym: In 2, if you button mashed against anyone But an expert you could win like about a quarter of the time just by kind of button mashing.
Rym: in 4 if you button mash you just lose like you can't win.
Rym: There's no way Yeah that that that really makes the game for me.
Rym: I like it and I I think you're just stuck in the past old man.
Scott: Meanwhile, I got you can have your Yoda there, you know.
Rym: And every time someone played Yoda, you know what.
Rym: you know who.
Scott: no one else plays either link.
Scott: no one plays link either Scott You know what?
Rym: Also, I want to point out they added new characters and Hildy is the motherfucking business.
Scott: Don't really care who needs any other characters besides the existing size of Aldo besides Siegfried slash.
Rym: But anyway, my thing of the day even though Soul Calibur 4 is far superior to Soul Calibur 2 is this collection of Characters from other video games made in Soul Calibur 4's game like character creation thing.
Scott: See that's always funny when people do that shit.
Rym: These are so well made.
Rym: It is amazing.
Scott: Well, you already did you know, but the vault the dancing fold those the dancing Voldos for Michael Jackson Voldos, right?
Rym: This is better.
Rym: This is really good.
Scott: All right That it.
Scott: Yeah, that's it.
Scott: All right, so Let's see, I got like a whole bunch of things of the day.
Scott: I got to pick one of these All right.
Scott: I'll pick this one here a lot.
Scott: I don't know how long ago months many months maybe even over a year ago I don't know.
Scott: I did a thing of the day.
Scott: There was a guy named at least his internet's name was cicada at the time.
Scott: He changed his internet's name to Tetix t-e-t-t-i-x, right and he made some cool ship tunes, you know, basically Original music in the style of you know, eight slash 16-bit video game music.
Scott: You know and I liked his songs a lot.
Scott: and is he gives away all his music's for free on his website.
Scott: So I was like, hey check it out.
Scott: So recently I discovered This guy made some videos on YouTube demonstrating how he makes the music using a software program called propeller heads reason and I Reason.
Rym: well, I have a quote-unquote demo of reason right?
Scott: I've known about and used reason in the past.
Scott: It's you know.
Scott: If you know how to use like an actual synthesizers and sequencers and all those sorts of machines To make music then you'll know how to use reason, you know Cuz basically you enter the way the software works.
Scott: is it just gives you it works just like the physical devices work It just gives you a bit, you know a virtual interface.
Scott: She's just like yeah ten synthesizers and sudden there's a rack and ten synthesizers appear, you know as if you actually had ten synthesizers.
Scott: It's hard to say synthesizers a lot In grant in many times in a row.
Rym: actually use reason a whole bunch way back at RIT when costume when I took that digital Music like composition.
Scott: I mean when I had it, you know the demo I was able to make some bloops and bleeps and such.
Scott: But I wasn't able to make really good.
Rym: I made some pretty rockin Techno tracks, I must say they weren't getting you any DJ jobs.
Rym: No, they weren't.
Rym: but they were.
Rym: they were pretty rockin for what I expected.
Scott: I would make yeah But he's got these videos here and he shows you how to use reason not just to you know Make music but specifically how to make.
Scott: you know how to fake and bake right chiptunes.
Scott: So if you want to like I don't know make a Megaman remix or something.
Scott: You watch these videos and you should be well-prepared to make your Megaman remix in addition.
Scott: I want to point out I Recently tried out that if you don't know about this for the DS there is a program you can get called Korg DS 10.
Scott: That is basically all the program is is a Korg.
Scott: well to Korg Synthesizers that are identical right and you you know a little drum machine and a mixer and you know a few other things on a DS Cartridge.
Scott: so you can use your DS just to make music as if you had all this cord equipment and Not having any musical knowledge.
Scott: just you know, sort of knowing the basic functions of these sorts of machines.
Scott: I don't know any of the advanced functions.
Scott: I was able to turn this program on Use it for like a little bit and make some music.
Scott: that sounded kind of okay pretty quickly You know get.
Scott: I made some drum loops and a little, you know synth loop and it was it was alright.
Scott: So if you like to make music I and I highly recommend you get and you have a DS To go.
Rym: get the Korg DS 10, whatever it is It's played with it for like I don't know five minutes and it was real fun.
Scott: Yeah Essentially, you know and the main thing I have with synthesizers in general, right?
Scott: Is it like I can get a synthesizer and a sequencer, right?
Scott: And I can turn the knobs on the synthesizer to get cool sounds to come out and I give like oh, that's a cool sound That's a cool sound.
Scott: right but I can't do and this is what you need to be able to do Right is you know?
Scott: You know You've got it when you can imagine a sound in your mind and then turn the knobs to make that sound come out.
Scott: That's what I need to learn how to do.
Scott: go in reverse You know, I could turn the knobs and hear the sounds
Rym: my methodology with with you know Real synthesizers or with that was pretty much to sit there Make a sine wave or a square wave or something and then just mess with it until it sounded cool And then use that.
Scott: for my see I can do that already.
Scott: But I want to be able to like, you know Think up a techno song in my head and then push the buttons to make it happen.
Scott: That's what I want to be able to do and I'm not anywhere near that point because I don't know half those knobs do If I don't even know what less than half the knobs do so in 1991.
Rym: What was that long ago?
Scott: 1991 how old are you?
Scott: I was nine.
Rym: I was also nine nine Nine I was not.
Rym: well I was nine by the point in 1991 When Sim City was ported to the Super Nintendo Entertainment System.
Scott: Oh my god, so it was out.
Scott: Regular Sim City for the non Super Nintendo was out before then.
Rym: Yeah long before.
Scott: Oh god When did regular old Sim City come out?
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I have no idea because as much I was I wasn't really super into PC gaming other than didn't it originally come out for like You know the Mac The Amiga I believe really was that the first system.
Rym: it was on Amiga and the Mac actually.
Rym: So we were I don't know anything beyond that.
Scott: We were less.
Scott: we were less than nine.
Rym: Yeah, well the thing is when it comes to Sim City in particular.
Rym: I was not really a big PC gamer until like the quake one era like the quake 2 era mega TF team fortress all that and It wasn't really until the SNES started to fade that I became a full-on PC gamer.
Rym: So I really only played like scorched earth and stunts 40 racing and you know mule and stuff like that.
Rym: But I never actually played Sim City until it came out on the Super Nintendo.
Scott: I played Sim City at my friend's house I think for the first time.
Scott: I must have been in middle school Right and he had you know a Mac and he had it on the floppy disk and you you put it in.
Scott: No, I think he actually had an external hard drive maybe and it was the original Mac version in black and white Sim City 1 And it was.
Scott: it was actually.
Scott: you know today the game is not so great But it was pretty alright back then.
Scott: but you could do weird stuff like, you know use only railroads.
Scott: That was great.
Scott: You never had traffic problems.
Rym: Yeah There was no reason to use roads unless you wanted those stupid casinos.
Rym: Exactly what I would do is I'd build a whole bunch of roads in the middle of nowhere And then I'd bulldoze him after I got my casino.
Scott: No, that's a good idea.
Rym: Oh But it was Sim City.
Rym: I didn't even get it when it came out.
Rym: I kind of I found out about it through Nintendo power of all things.
Scott: I didn't even realize it was on the Super Nintendo until like after but it was actually wasn't one of the release games.
Scott: Uh No, it was a very early release.
Rym: I remember that anyway It definitely was not one of the release games.
Rym: Scott the Nintendo came out.
Rym: Oh, no, wait a minute It wasn't a release game in Japan and I don't think it was actually released game in America.
Rym: But it came out like right after.
Scott: see that's what I said It was.
Scott: it was one of the earliest releases for the Super Nintendo in the u.s.
Rym: Yes, but the release games as I recall were games like radical psycho machine racing.
Rym: I think wasn't a zero release game.
Rym: f-zero was out right away.
Rym: a pilot wing pilot wings Mario World, obviously Obviously, yeah anyway, but I remember as a kid.
Rym: I wanted this game Desperately like I wanted Sim City more than any other game possibly because I owned Almost every other SNES game that was out because there weren't that many yet.
Scott: Well, I didn't want it that badly.
Scott: I think what it was is like.
Scott: I played it at my friend's house pretty often and I sort of felt like if I had Wow.
Rym: in Japan the launch games were Super Mario World and f-zero.
Scott: That's it.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: Wow.
Rym: in North America We also had pilot wings Sim City a Sim City and Gradius three.
Scott: See I was right I didn't realize.
Rym: Grady's three came out that early.
Scott: I didn't either.
Scott: Wow, that's pretty crazy.
Rym: I uh my I don't know.
Rym: Maybe I'm getting old.
Rym: it all kind of blurs together before 1995.
Scott: well put one on the evidence list of Scott's memory better than rims Okay.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, anyway, I didn't I didn't want Sim City that badly and I played it at my friend's house And I also.
Scott: in summer camp we had color max and we were playing Sim City 2000.
Scott: I think this must have been in like seventh or eighth grade summer team
Rym: in Starbase, which was like this local You know, it masqueraded as like a local space camp at the local self like the Air National Guard base But it was really half like super space stuff and half so.
Rym: you want to join the Air Force, don't you don't you?
Rym: Don't you don't you?
Rym: well, but it had some memorable times like we got to Hang out and actually use the military f-16 like fighter jet fights flight simulator Which was kind of awesome, especially because while the other kids were doing it I saw the console on the side that lets you.
Rym: it had two buttons of interest button.
Rym: one was cockpit fire button.
Rym: two was irrecoverable cockpit fire.
Rym: All I can say is that that button got hit a whole bunch of times before people figured out what I was doing.
Scott: So that was.
Scott: it's possible to have a cockpit fire that's recoverable.
Scott: apparently I Mean you're sitting in this thing.
Scott: I don't imagine there's a lot of room in there, right?
Rym: It moved around in like full six degrees.
Rym: It was like it was like afterburner times ten.
Scott: It was a yeah Yeah, you know, but even then right the graphics I mean in the early 90s or whatever.
Scott: Probably we're not even as good as like the we they're probably.
Scott: it was all blocky Got a horizon look like it looked like virtual virtual racing.
Rym: Oh, no.
Rym: No, it was black and white Really?
Rym: Whoa on the screen.
Rym: You got a horizon line and vectors Whoa, so worse than virtual raising but it made up for that by having a full f-16 cockpit.
Scott: Yeah, well not to diss virtual racing.
Scott: I love virtual racing.
Rym: That game is awesome.
Rym: Yeah That's one of the best racing games ever.
Rym: Yeah, definitely.
Rym: Oh my god, but We play.
Rym: we didn't even have SimCity, but we played this ghetto like sim moon base game Just about moon bases.
Rym: Let me tell you that game was broken.
Rym: I had to make roads on the moon But there were no cars on the moon and apparently the roads didn't even do anything.
Rym: Wow, there were a lot of like bad ports and people trying to make like SimCity games that were terrible.
Rym: And I remember someone ported SimCity the ti-85, but it basically didn't work.
Rym: and so yeah, I was gonna happen.
Scott: No, so I played SimCity 2000 at summer camp, right and that's mostly when we were there.
Scott: You didn't have a lot of time at a computer at once and your save games, you know It was a crapshoot if they'd be there the next time or if you'd be sitting at the same computer the next time.
Scott: So, you know, I mean it was a summer camp computer lab in the in the.
Scott: you know, early to mid 90s It was SimCity 2000.
Rym: That's highfalutin.
Scott: I know right.
Scott: So you're lucky if you could play it at all.
Scott: and pretty much all we did there is we would always type in the code And the code.
Scott: yeah, the code for SimCity 2000 on the Mac was porn tips gazardo if anyone remembers that.
Rym: See I went the other way.
Rym: I did the more complicated thing where you do a bunch of stuff and you type.
Rym: so that wasn't on the Mac that was on The Windows version, but then you get a negative interest bond and that just gives you money to do all the stuff you want To do.
Scott: well, you would open up the debug menu and you could do whatever you wanted in there.
Rym: You could do that too.
Scott: Yeah, but there's also that the DOS code.
Scott: That was the one we had to like.
Scott: click click in all these different places, you know It is, you know specific sequence of some kind and whatever.
Rym: but it was weird.
Rym: I like games like this really like they show to me the progression of myself as a gamer.
Rym: nothing really kind of elucidates how far I have come as a gamer in terms of skill and aptitude and What I consider cheating or not or what I consider fair or not or what utility I get from a game.
Rym: Then playing games that I played as a child when I'm older and have more reason and experience and knowledge.
Rym: Mmm, because when I first played SimCity It was kind of like when I first played games like Simon's Quest or Zelda or a lot of games Not Zelda but Zelda 2 specifically.
Rym: I was often very bad at those games and part of it was because I didn't analyze the games I kind of just played.
Rym: like when I played SimCity like I knew I would come up with basic strategies Like I don't like pollution So I'm gonna build all my industrial stuff around the outside edge Because then some of the pollution is gonna go off the map and it doesn't count.
Rym: Hooray.
Scott: Oh, that's a good thinking.
Rym: That was like my first thinking.
Rym: Mm-hmm, but I would have these weird utilities Like I would go after certain things and I wanted like big blocks of buildings that parks everywhere And I would never like analyze the game and play optimally.
Rym: So the game in a way was more fun at first because there was a lot of replay value and cities would rise and fail.
Rym: And I remember one moment in particular where this is when my mother decided that video games were Amazingly advanced was when I was playing and I ran out of money and I was patient inpatient.
Rym: So I raised taxes like 20% and all the people started leaving my city.
Rym: And I was like mom all the people are leaving my city and she's like did you do anything?
Rym: And I look well, I raised the taxes and she was like wow What's that tell you about the world?
Rym: I was like that I shouldn't raise taxes.
Scott: No, that's I had the same kind of experience.
Scott: I mean when I would play Sim City without cheating right I would try.
Scott: You know, there were some strategies I used like I knew that.
Scott: you know If I put a zone any square of zone zoned land that was too far from a road wouldn't develop, right?
Scott: So what I did is I you know, still I wanted to make bigger blocks.
Scott: so what I did is I made bigger blocks of Zoneage like I'd make a residential that's so big that the middle ones wouldn't develop.
Scott: But then in the middle I would always put forests or parks or something like that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: that way all the residentials would be near parks But they would also all be near enough to the road to build and I would just.
Scott: basically I would always go for something You know other than strategies like that.
Scott: You know put a police station every so often so the whole map is covered with police and put a fire station every so often And those sorts of things right.
Scott: other than that I went for like what was aesthetically pleasing to me You know, I liked.
Scott: I like grids and I liked, you know I'd have a highway right up the middle and across the other middle and highway couldn't build a highway in Sim City.
Scott: No, I'm talking about Sim City 2000. highways were useless though I know right, but I went for.
Scott: I wanted to be aesthetically.
Scott: I like seeing that big highway.
Scott: They just go all the way across in a straight line, you know.
Scott: And yeah I liked having to connect to the neighboring cities and then I would always customize the map to be perfectly flat With a flat coastline so I could build everything completely straight and
Rym: then
Scott: I would put water exactly so I could put the water pumps in a grid and get the most water from the water pumps in the fewest in the smallest possible Space and it would be just enough water.
Rym: That was part of the big problem with Sim City 2000 just enough water to give everyone in the whole city water The the optimal.
Rym: if you're gonna play that way what you had to do was make a giant pyramid waterfall And cover it with hydro plants, oh you did that way.
Scott: so I just built like, you know the fusion plant.
Rym: I did that once and at the top was my mansion.
Rym: No, I built.
Scott: I just build two fusion plants next to each other and then that would be it.
Rym: You could power the home get a fusion plant right away unless it cheated.
Scott: Well, you know eventually you just you know You keep going for it and going for it and going for it and then eventually right you Get the city to a point where it's profitable.
Scott: you set it on cheetah and since you know 486 100 megahertz you just go to bed and wake up and you have a bajillion dollars and then you build two fusion plants.
Rym: See, I guess part of the problem was that I would play these games.
Rym: I didn't really analyze them that much but I would start to fall into the mysticism of gaming in the days before you could easily Find answers to the core mathematical questions of how a game works.
Rym: Like I would wonder the launch our colleges really launch know more things like.
Rym: alright I have residential industrial and commercial.
Rym: how far apart can they actually be?
Rym: How much do things need to be connected by roads?
Rym: Where do I need roads?
Rym: What do the trains do?
Rym: specifically does it matter where that train is because often the train would get stuck somewhere and like if I have two Discontiguous sets of roads does that matter?
Rym: And I've wondered about all these things and I started to figure them out bit by bit Like I realized eventually things that really were dumb like a police station didn't need access to roads.
Rym: So I would build like nine grids You know three by three of like residential and in the middle where there was I couldn't.
Rym: Road couldn't get there So I couldn't put a residential.
Rym: it would never build up.
Rym: I'd put the police station there or the fire station there to maximize my space usage
Scott: mmm,
Rym: and as I went on I optimized and optimized and figured out all the math and everything of the game and Then one day I realized that the game was stupid because I had solved it and all I was doing was implementing my perfect algorithm.
Rym: And as long as my city was always profitable All I had to do was let the game wait until I had enough money to do exactly what I wanted to do And there was no more game.
Scott: It's pretty much the whole game right is?
Scott: there are is that the rules are secret You know, it's like if let's say SimCity was a board game But it was exactly the same game with the exact same rules, right?
Scott: the only thing is that you did it all by hand with you know, you figured out your money with a paper and a pencil right and Such.
Scott: then there would be an instruction book and the instruction book would say, you know If there is a space of land that is X spaces away from the police station Then it's crime will be equal to such and such and such.
Scott: and the only reason SimCity was challenging it All was because you didn't have that instruction book because it was kept secret from you.
Scott: I mean you knew Generally that a police station Decreases crime and you know if farther away from police stations you get the more crime there is that you knew that Generally, but you didn't know the specific details of exactly how much crime exactly what radius.
Scott: So you didn't know if that you bear building too many police stations if they were too close to each other if they were too Far, but if you knew that information and it was you know, then the game would be Trivially stupid.
Scott: you would just know Oh I need to build these many police stations exactly these many spaces apart and that's the best way to Do at the end.
Rym: and I guess the trouble with the regular SimCity was that because the game had these rules But at the same time it was simple.
Rym: You could solve the rules and then there was no more game.
Rym: It wasn't even a game of like.
Rym: create an interesting equilibrium because the game was simple enough to where it all kind of petered out.
Scott: Yeah, then if you do play the game without cheating and without waiting overnight to get a million dollars Then you do.
Scott: you don't just have the implementation of the algorithm.
Scott: You also have to sort of Transfer between these equilibrium states of like, you know, you know equilibrium state small city equilibrium state slightly larger city equilibrium state slightly larger city.
Scott: and if you in the course of growing the city out where you know ended up in a non-equilibrium state you can get stuck and run out of money and have to pull back and then go out again or You could screw up everything and it would.
Scott: you know, basically there might not be a way to fix it And you know that posed a slight challenge.
Scott: but still it really comes down to the fact that a lot of the rules were secret.
Rym: Yeah, but at least with SimCity 2000 despite the fact that by then I bought a book that explained everything as I was done with That BS and I didn't want to figure it out on my own but not so much so I could like cheat or whatever but just so I could know the rules of the game going in and Thus I could work on the more interesting things like making aesthetically pleasing cities that worked.
Rym: Mm-hmm and that was a lot more fun because the game was more complex.
Rym: so I could make a Realistic city like I could make the subdivision I lived in and it kind of worked.
Rym: Yeah, kinda Actually where I lived it worked really well.
Rym: The thing is I live in a very SimCity looking place.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is the SimCity 2000.
Rym: you always end up with just a screen full of arcologies and then what well that that's the Problem that everyone playing Wow has to.
Rym: eventually you hit the end game and the end game of SimCity is you have built a launch Arcology.
Rym: now you wait until you have enough money and you build another launch arcology and eventually you have all launch Arcologies in a perfect grid and then two fusion planets in the bottom, right?
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know the.
Scott: I think the dark ology was more aesthetically pleasing.
Scott: the launch arcology was all black and sort of Industrial shit living.
Scott: No.
Scott: No, that was like this deed.
Scott: the second one I'm talking about the one right under the launch arcology the cool Blade Runner looking.
Scott: Oh, yeah You know the dark o Arco it was.
Scott: it was like I had all sorts of lights all over it.
Scott: Industrial one was like the one with the UFO on top of it, right?
Scott: or was that the forest one?
Scott: I don't remember.
Scott: I don't remember either but the dark o was like awesome looking cuz I never cuz.
Scott: it was like.
Scott: it was like Yeah, welcome to the evil Empire, but the launch arcology was like we have a happy glass dome.
Scott: It looked like a Gundam Colony.
Rym: Yeah, I kind of ignored those things because at that point the game was no longer interesting.
Rym: I'd start over.
Rym: The real trouble was that the other way to make the game interesting was to introduce Disasters.
Rym: but in Sim City, they were never fun.
Rym: They just sucked and there was no like interesting way to combat them.
Rym: Yeah, it basically just delayed your eventual victory or defeat on Sim City 2000.
Scott: There were some fun disaster kind of thing.
Rym: Well the fact that you could deal with like the Coast Guard and the firemen and the police exactly around the rioters.
Scott: Yeah, the riots are pretty fun because you put the police around the rioters if you had a riot and then they would start A fire.
Scott: so you need to also bring out the firemen and if you're lucky enough to have the military base You could deploy the military.
Scott: They were real helpful if like the alien came or something.
Scott: That was good times.
Rym: Well, the trouble I had there was that I would never like.
Rym: I always turned random disasters off because that was I know right But I would be playing and I'd be doing fine I have a big city and then inexplicably I would suddenly decide to destroy that city and I would and I would just activate like Every disaster five times and then just let it all fall apart and then turn the game off.
Rym: Yeah, if there's a god I hope he doesn't play the world the way I played Sim City.
Scott: either that or I would like, you know I'd build a giant city or load up a giant city save game And I just let it go and then turn on all the disasters and just play the disaster fighting game because the city Managing game was done.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, that's why you don't want to play the rebuilding game exactly exactly.
Rym: But I don't know.
Rym: Sim City I feel like a game like now.
Rym: I really enjoy Civ 4 and I think part of it's that.
Rym: the kind of game like that that I can enjoy is The game where there is emergent behavior and I'm directing that emergent behavior to some degree But not completely like.
Rym: I want a guy to civilization but I want the Interactions in the game to be complex enough to where I can't a hundred percent predict the outcome of what I'm going to do And I just I want to see interesting things happen as a result of my small changes.
Rym: Mmm, I basically want a complex state machine that relies Heavily upon what I do with a kind of you know snowball effect in terms of randomness like strange attractors.
Scott: Yeah, that is something.
Scott: is that in Sim City.
Scott: You didn't really have a lot of happenings other than disasters Like, you know, I mean the news stories really were just either good or bad.
Scott: You didn't really you know.
Scott: There wasn't.
Scott: lots of you know Strange and interesting things that could occur and that you couldn't relate them directly to anything you did.
Scott: It was sort of just like, you know, the news articles basically like, you know complaining about crime And it's just the crime meter going, you know up.
Scott: so you had to build more police stations.
Scott: You know, there wasn't sort of like this direct thing of like, you know, oh You you know bulldoze that thing.
Scott: and now therefore, you know There's a riot because of that thing and it the riot is in that area and you didn't have things going on like that.
Scott: so It didn't really you couldn't.
Scott: there wasn't a lot of you know connection between the things you did and then the things that happened.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Well like Sim Earth was the worst for that.
Rym: I mean I played all these Sim games and Sim Earth like was just inexplicable.
Rym: Like I had no idea what was going on.
Scott: I had no idea how to play that game and I had no instructions.
Rym: I understood the science Like you said the atmosphere and the cloud cover and all those things.
Rym: But what happened on the planet never seemed to have anything to do with what I did to the planet.
Scott: Well, I mean look at another look at the other sim games like sim ant.
Scott: right.
Scott: sim Ant was like this great game and it was.
Scott: the thing is the beginning of that game was so fun.
Scott: You were this one ant and you would go and get food and you'd make more ants, right?
Scott: You go and get some food and make some more.
Rym: it was fun except for the fact that again nothing you did really matter.
Scott: That's the thing.
Scott: is the things you did early mattered because you could at the beginning if you screwed up you could fail To you know succeed right but as soon as you got one that one ant colony going really strong It was pretty much invincible and would do its own thing.
Scott: So then all you would do is you would send ants to the adjacent square of the map Right and then you would do the same thing again only would take you a lot less time and now you would have two squares of the map under solid control.
Scott: Once you had two squares of the map under solid control, you never needed to control the ants again.
Scott: All you did was say yeah send the flying ants to the next square.
Scott: You waited send the flying ants to the next square wait And eventually you just clicked on every square until you controlled the entire, you know backyard and the house.
Scott: And the thing is obviously that wasn't the way the game was intended to be played.
Scott: because like if you actually Controlled the ants in the house, you know, it was cool You'd be like crawling on the stove or on the grill or you know The kitchen counter and the lawnmower and the dog and all these things going on.
Scott: But just by you know sending, you know, the reproductive ants to the next square, you know You send enough of them and you're gonna take it over no matter what's going on over there.
Scott: You never have to look at that stuff.
Scott: So obviously the mechanics of the game sort of defeated the design and The game was you know, it's like they had this fun game, but then you didn't actually have to play the fun game Because you had all those meters.
Rym: like exactly should you be digging tunnels more or doing this more or doing that?
Scott: It's sort of like that total war Shogun II game that people talk about right?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: I remember that game had this cool RTS kind of mode Rita, you know control these armies and formations and things.
Scott: but when I see people actually play the game Like they don't actually do that.
Scott: They do that maybe in the beginning but then for the rest of the game They just play on the big map, you know saying yeah attack this next area.
Scott: Okay attack this next area and not actually doing the real-time strategy part.
Scott: It just does itself.
Scott: and that's sort of the same thing to happen with sim ant.
Scott: is they had this cool ant Controlling game that you didn't have to actually play once you did it a little bit.
Rym: Yeah, and sim earth again just didn't make any sense and it really I don't know.
Rym: It's difficult to strike this balance between a game or you have full control.
Rym: But then if the game expands at all, you're now micromanaging a bunch of crap You don't care about.
Rym: like a lot of like even Civ 4 gets to that point We're just I don't want to micromanage all the crap.
Rym: Yeah, I don't want to deal with it.
Rym: I'm done.
Rym: at least in Civ 4 I could split off the Eastern Greek Empire into the Byzantine Empire and they'll just be friendly to me.
Scott: Well, I think you know what you really need to do, you know in a game like that And I there might be a game that does this, you know I haven't seen one yet right?
Scott: is you want to make the you know, bring the game bigger, right?
Scott: You want to.
Scott: you want to sort of zoom out and then play a different game, right?
Scott: So something like Civ 4 right.
Scott: the way you could do this is I know in Civ 4 you can group units Right, but let's say for example in Civ 4 when you get beyond the point of having just a few cities, right?
Scott: it could zoom out and Just be like, okay forget cities, right?
Scott: Those three cities over there are now a state and these three cities are a state.
Scott: you only manage the states.
Scott: You don't micromanage the cities at all.
Rym: You know, basically I can sum this up What Spore should have been but wasn't right.
Scott: and then right instead of building say a battleship You can't just build a battleship anymore You tell the state to build a naval fleet and then you control one naval fleet, you know And you sort of.
Scott: and then if you need to zoom out even more, right?
Scott: It's you have a planet or the country right and you just click on the other country and you're still playing a complex game.
Scott: It's just as you know.
Scott: The game you're playing grows and grows and as you get ahead and you have too many small things Just group all the small things up into a bigger thing and zoom out and now you're playing the same game again Only with you know different graphics to make you to give you the feeling that you're playing it on a bigger scale.
Rym: yep, and no, I don't think anyone's really done that yet because otherwise you have either the super micromanage or the Options you choose don't actually make a difference.
Scott: Yeah Basically what it would be like it's really no different than starting the game over right?
Scott: I mean think about it.
Scott: You know you place it for right?
Scott: I got one city.
Scott: I'm playing this game right.
Scott: when we zoom out It's sort of like I'm starting the game over with like back to one city because I'm down to like one state.
Rym: But no, it's more that you start on.
Rym: you start the next game or the next stage of the game.
Rym: But what you start with and what options you have depends upon how you beat the first game and the color of that Depends upon that.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I really more and more.
Rym: I just like to see the emergent behavior And I like to see what happens in the rest of the world even the stuff I wasn't doing anything with.
Rym: like.
Rym: I love nothing more than watching Tokugawa go to war with someone.
Scott: Yeah, you don't want to play dwarf fortress because dwarf fortress.
Rym: It's so obtuse to watch and control.
Rym: That's the thing.
Scott: it has all those things, but it doesn't.
Scott: the user interface is just so terrible.
Rym: well Also, there's the problem of demystification.
Rym: I know Knowing that Dwarf fortress is actually very simple under the covers and most of the CPU utilization and all that is caused primarily by Poor programming.
Scott: well, it's not about the CPU utilization It's the fact that you know regardless of the fact that it's programmed poorly in the user interface is bad.
Scott: It does have this emergent behavior going on, but it's not worth getting to.
Rym: it's so Obtuse and the controls are so bad and the interface is so unreasonable.
Scott: Yeah, but if someone just took the game and actually put a real interface on it and programmed it properly that would be it.
Rym: Yes, it would but it's not it's not.
Rym: I wish it could be.
Scott: yeah, it can be.
Rym: I mean for now.
Rym: I'm stuck.
Scott: You know I've got what sim earth Yeah Sim or the CEO speaking of which actually one of the better sim games least what I think is sim tower.
Rym: But sim tower was crap suck.
Scott: and the thing is people don't realize.
Scott: you know all these a lot of these other Sim games.
Scott: I'm not sure which ones are made by will right and which ones weren't but sim tower was actually a Japanese game.
Scott: Just called the tower and they bought it and brought it to the US and called it sim tower.
Scott: But it really it was.
Scott: it's a Japanese game, and they have it on like.
Scott: it's actually really popular in Japan.
Scott: It's still like there's a DS version of it in Japan called.
Scott: You know the tower and such and such It's.
Scott: you know it's still played over there a lot, and you know It wasn't like the best sim game in the universe.
Scott: It wasn't like Sim City 2000. good, but I still kind of liked it.
Scott: The only thing that bothered me was that you sort of had to you know build the tower like so wide.
Scott: It was really hard to keep it aesthetically nice and also a lot of the game boiled down to elevator Management, and it's like they had these arbitrary limitations like how many elevators you could have and how you could set them in such.
Scott: There's pretty much no way to make a tower with a lot of good stuff in it and also have elevators that were smooth You know and in traffic free because of those limitations.
Rym: Yeah well plus Problems with games like that.
Rym: in general for me now is that I when I was younger and had more free time to just dabble I could just play you know open simulation style games forever But I don't have that much interest in them anymore.
Rym: and a game like like anytime.
Rym: The way to progress.
Rym: in a game the only thing preventing me from progressing is Letting the game run by itself and build up a bunch of money and then coming back and doing something.
Rym: That's like playing Wow I got to just wait before I can do the next thing I want to do.
Scott: well at least in Wow right you can click faster to get more money, right?
Scott: You can go to a field somewhere and kill rats or whatever you kill in.
Scott: Wow you know and Tower was just tower.
Scott: all you can do is wait.
Scott: It was basically as long.
Scott: at least today We have faster CPUs.
Scott: you could put it on cheetah mode and get a zillion dollars like three seconds.
Rym: Sim tower was just a draw a fun tower game coupled with progress quest Kinda.
Rym: every time progress quest hit a certain level you came back.
Scott: You don't have money to do the stuff you wanted to do yeah But I mean there were some things you sort of had to plan out like if you put certain things too close to each other They would be in trouble.
Scott: It's like you had to also sort of plan things out in a certain way.
Scott: you had to have enough maids for the hotel and have the service elevator for the maids and Make sure the maids weren't too close to the actual hotel rooms because then the people there would get mad that make the maids are Making too much noise too much noise.
Rym: I think it's.
Rym: how dare the maids be living outside of the side?
Scott: I know.
Scott: Meanwhile you go to a real hotel the maids have a little room on every single floor right there.
Scott: You can see them, and it doesn't bother anybody.
Scott: You know it made no sense whatsoever.
Scott: It was also cool to like.
Scott: you know some of that game.
Scott: It just made you manage like you'd build a movie theater.
Scott: to make money You had to keep going into the movie theater and buying new movies to show all the time.
Scott: So it's sort of like up keeping all these different little things around.
Scott: And I don't know.
Scott: the other thing about that game is that base?
Scott: is that you could build residential like apartments?
Scott: But it was completely stupid to do so because it was really hard to keep people in them.
Scott: They made so much less money than hotels and offices ever did so I just never built them at all.
Scott: no There's no reason to.
Rym: I can't say though that I spent a lot of time playing SimCity 2000 back in the day.
Rym: Oh, yeah I would often have like SimCity 2000 going in one window And I'd have like Civ 2 going in another window And I would just play one while the other one was in the background on whatever speed it could manage building up money.
Rym: Yeah, so SimCity be in the background.
Rym: I'll be playing Civ 2.
Rym: I'd be listening to music I'd be chatting on IM.
Rym: It was like not none of those games could ever Occupy my soul attention at any time.
Rym: there was never a point when I could just be playing Civ 2 or just be playing SimCity and be enjoying it because So much of the time was.
Rym: I'd already decided what I wanted to do and now my brain was idle while my hand did it.
Rym: So I would like do all these things at the same time And I don't know I. the only reason I don't do that more is that now games like that are too complex to do that But yet still not complex enough to completely get my attention.
Rym: Yeah, yeah like Civ 4 I have to pay a lot more attention to.
Rym: I can only like listen to a podcast and play.
Rym: I can't Also be chatting with people Mm-hmm.
Scott: I Don't know.
Scott: I just I got SimCity on my iPhone and it's basically the same thing as SimCity 2000 a little different.
Rym: I I played a couple of Sim cities after SimCity 2000 a little and I'd the spark never came back.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: I think is there a 4000?
Scott: I know there's a 3000.
Rym: there was another one.
Scott: There's probably just been called SimCity 4 I don't even know.
Scott: but I know I played 3000 for like a little bit and like I think they added like Trash, you know trucks and things like that.
Rym: But yeah, well, I remember SimCity 2000 added the water Even though the water worked in inexplicable and often stupid ways.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, it didn't make a lot and the subways that suck to draw completely and just were a pain in the ass.
Scott: I always did the subways but because I always had a perfect grid it was easy to do the subways.
Scott: I would just put you know a subway Station on every single block corner since the blocks are big.
Scott: remember because they I would always put the parks and forests in the middle Of the blocks so the blocks are big.
Scott: I would put one subway station on like the southeast corner of every intersection and then I drew this big grid of green subway tunnels Under the ground and that was it.
Rym: Yeah, of course if you're playing the game legit, the subway is so expensive.
Scott: You can only build tiny bits at a time and then you had to wait Yep, and then you would just build the next one and wait and build the next one.
Scott: The thing was if there was like a big Like structure on the corner I had to bulldoze that whole structure build the one subway square for the station and then you know The the structure would rebuild sort of around it and it would sometimes prevent, you know Three by three or four by four structures from being on the corner.
Rym: Actually, one thing I remember kind of randomly is that in SimCity regular SimCity at least on the SNES if If a fire started somewhere and destroyed like three like parts of a zone like an airport or anything After you bulldozed it you could build something else there before it came back.
Rym: Mmm, so you could build like, you know A three block by three block residential zone because they were all like what this blocks in SimCity.
Rym: You could then bulldoze like one whole side of it and overlap another residential zone and then you just get houses there.
Rym: Mmm, I don't know what effect that had on the math of the game.
Rym: You can do it.
Scott: You sure wasn't like a bug.
Rym: I'm absolutely sure I did it all the time.
Scott: Well, awesome.
Scott: Yeah, I guess so.
Rym: I don't know this kind of petered out Games like this Haven't been a they can't.
Rym: no one has executed a straight-up Sim game like this in a matter that can catch my attention nowadays.
Scott: Well, I think also part of what it is is not just what we said before but you know The the micro managing and the complexity is that the games are really sort of sandbox.
Scott: see It's like they don't give you so many goals.
Scott: it's like you play SimCity 2000. your goal is what get a bigger city get more stuff and Not screw up.
Scott: It's like it's sort of vague.
Scott: So you really have to have your own.
Scott: you to bring your own motivation, you know to bring your own thing that you really want.
Scott: and If you don't have that if you don't really want anything if you don't care so much that it's just not gonna work.
Scott: It's like, you know.
Scott: But then again, if you do have some motivation of something you want to make then it is gonna work really well.
Scott: And I think we see that in other games today that have lots of user-generated type content things You know like in a little big planet or whatever is, you know, you may not be a sim game, right?
Scott: You're just you know making puzzles or whatever, you know maps and things.
Scott: But you have this idea of something you want to create and then you create it and in SimCity You know the SimCity game is.
Scott: you have an idea of a city you want to create but you can't just create it Or play this whole game.
Scott: you have to cheat or you have to work within these confines of these rules in order to make the thing you want to make.
Scott: so It's like if you're playing the game to make something then you have these rules getting in your way.
Rym: But if you're playing the game with some other, you know It well if you're playing the game to beat the rules and win then the end result is a map filled with our colleges Exactly Exactly.
Rym: Plus it always bothered me that elevation unless you were doing something for aesthetics Only hurt you in SimCity 2000.
Rym: It never helped you.
Scott: Yeah, you know, it was cool that they had, you know mountains and things like that Reticulating splines.
Scott: Yeah, cuz it was like, you know, hey his sort of real geography and that was neat.
Scott: But all I did was make the game Frustrating because you couldn't actually build anything on it and it always just got in the way and made things difficult.
Scott: It didn't actually, you know, it's a bad.
Scott: That's why I want to make a flat map because it was just freaking annoying dad I think a flat map with an ocean or a thing was.
Scott: I really wanted to build like bridges or tunnels But they were always just a pain in the butt and they were never Optimal compared to the real solution which was get enough money to bulldoze it all flat.
Scott: exactly exactly.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has Everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.