Rym: Hey, it's Tuesday, August 18th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight games of Tron.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: When I play Civ 4 I'd like to be the good guy.
Rym: I like to think I am a good leader.
Rym: I like to build libraries And universities and have all this culture and I generally try to like.
Scott: I played kind of this really nice Standard game that I always know and you know you always play and there's always one AI does the jerk.
Rym: I'm looking at you, and you don't want to be the jerk right, but today You know I've been playing on the train And I decided for once to really just go all out because I just can't.
Scott: I tried.
Scott: I just can't be the jerk.
Scott: like every time I try to attack people and pester them It's like you know.
Scott: I noticed that the computer when they're a jerk.
Scott: They never actually give a real attack.
Scott: They just sort of pester.
Scott: I Try to do a real attack and I always expend all my resources attacking and I fall behind that I lose.
Rym: you haven't played much Civ 4 have you because when?
Rym: when the AI attacks especially if it's Tokugawa They tend to wait and wait and wait and then one round you see like 40 elephants sitting right on the edge of your borders, and then they'll ask you for like can you spare some optics?
Rym: And if you're like no, they're like okay war.
Rym: and if you're like yes, they're like okay war.
Rym: But on the train I was Zulu and I had these all these spearmen.
Rym: I'm trying to play my normal standard game, and I kind of almost roleplay when I place it for.
Rym: But then I'm looking at all these Spearmen that I built and I noticed that the neighboring civilization Which is currently the number one civilization of Charlemagne has nothing but horse archers.
Rym: and Yeah, I destroyed his civilization And I'm rolling across the time being the jerk.
Scott: That's just taking the low-hanging fruit.
Rym: He was more.
Rym: He was far higher than me more powerful than me.
Rym: He just happened to have an army that consisted primarily of horses, and I happen to have almost nothing but spearmen.
Scott: no Well, then you had an army of horses and spearmen didn't you?
Scott: so then I invaded everyone else on the continent And I've basically been alternatingly declaring something if you can conquer someone else early in a game of Civ 4 especially if they have a bunch Of technologies you basically have this huge upper hand.
Scott: now for the rest of the game It's game over.
Rym: especially Civ 4 has all those cool options like having them capitulate to you or becoming a vassal state of yours.
Rym: Yeah, all sorts of cool stuff.
Rym: The moral is I got to stop playing so far on the train.
Rym: I'm not getting anything else done.
Scott: Yeah, so I knew it was gonna happen.
Scott: You know I've been riding this train for a bajillion years.
Scott: It's gonna happen one day.
Scott: It's gonna have some stomach trouble on the train.
Scott: It was unpleasant.
Rym: have you for the first time in your life pooped on a metro north train?
Scott: now I've pooped on the train a handful of times before.
Rym: I'm talking about in the bathroom not in the vestibule But This is an unpleasant pooping on the train.
Rym: Is this gonna be one of those epic stories like Scott naked on the bathroom floor when he's sick?
Scott: No, it was more like I was walking towards the train.
Scott: I sat on the train as soon as I sat down.
Scott: I didn't feel so right.
Scott: I got up, and I had to pester the guy next to me which I was like sorry whatever I went to the bathroom, and I pooped.
Scott: and you know those train toilets.
Scott: luckily I got one that was pretty good and worked and no one else needed to use it during the whole train ride But you know they don't have a lot of water in them, so you can really see your poop pretty well.
Scott: I'm not gonna gross anyone out though.
Rym: as we know from German toilets It's good to see your poop.
Rym: in fact You should look at your poop because it's a good indicator of your health And it's nasty.
Scott: poop looks a lot different when it's just sitting there than when it's falling into a big pool.
Rym: Part of it is there's something clean and sterile not really, but just viscerally.
Rym: when you see poop, and it's in like water It's like all right.
Rym: It is in a toilet where it should be.
Rym: all is right with the world But when you see human poop And it is not submerged in water that most of the time indicates a severe dysfunction in some manner.
Rym: Yeah, either someone is pooped where they should not have pooped.
Rym: So At least you did not lose.
Rym: don't shit your pants.
Scott: No, no, but I had to pester the guy next to me again when I had to poop a second time.
Scott: Oh, but one.
Scott: the interesting thing right is not the pooping right which is just what was it?
Rym: Dave Riley said the best thing in the world is pooping and the worst thing in the world is too much pooping right.
Scott: so it's that You know.
Scott: when I had to poop the first time the conductor was coming down to collect the tickets And I passed him on my way to the toilet.
Scott: It was in the rear car.
Scott: He didn't ask for my ticket.
Scott: when I walked past him all right, I pooped all right.
Scott: I came out of the pooping and went back to my seat.
Scott: He never came and asked for my ticket.
Rym: How far were you along the way?
Rym: because I've noticed there's a point after which they don't seem to care anymore.
Scott: Well, it was just like a one-stop train.
Scott: It was beacon first stop.
Rym: Yeah, they only check once on that train.
Rym: It'd be trivial to get where I'd that train without paying as long as you're willing to Sit in that bathroom for a little while.
Scott: so I did, but it's like.
Scott: I walked right past him right He was going from the back of the train to the all right Scott conductor on a train.
Rym: Here's what he thought that guy has to poop.
Rym: Nothing in the world will put me in between him and pooping in the place He should be pooping because I'm a conductor and I've encountered after there should be after I poop the second time Right.
Scott: instead of going back to my seat and pestering the other guy again I just sat down on the floor outside the bathroom just in case you know.
Scott: But I made it to beacon.
Scott: sitting there also was really weird when I sat in my seat.
Scott: It was a window seat that saw like it was cool The air conditioning was working but that Sun hit my face to the window is just like murder.
Scott: so it was better to sit on the floor so the Sun couldn't get me and Then poop on one side on the other.
Rym: you had no way to win.
Scott: the conductor Right was right there when I was sitting on the floor didn't pester me.
Rym: So again Scott you see a guy get up on the train where people normally don't get up and head to the bathroom twice.
Rym: Then he sits down outside the bathroom on the floor.
Rym: You did not want to disturb that man.
Rym: less poop appear also, I.
Scott: It seems like the people who'd run the parking at the train station.
Scott: They it seems like they're only coming to like write tickets like once like every few weeks.
Rym: Yeah, they call me for that.
Rym: I got a ticket today.
Scott: Yeah, really today Yeah, cuz I parked up on the street cuz I didn't get a spot.
Rym: I think they back right like they only go and check like a spot check.
Scott: Yeah, I think that I parked up on the street today And I did not get a ticket cuz I ran onto the train so fast without paying.
Rym: they just didn't care.
Scott: No, I think they're not checking up on the street.
Scott: We should just park up on the street and get.
Scott: we'll get away with it.
Rym: I'm not gonna do that.
Scott: why not?
Rym: cuz I like parking, you know Remember I get there early enough.
Rym: I can park like right.
Scott: next to the thing is the trick is most people try to park up On the street near the right-hand entrance.
Scott: I park up on the street on the left-hand Hill.
Scott: so basically I just walk up the steep hill and I'm at my car And I walk down the steep hill and I'm at the trains, you know.
Scott: And it's actually not really any farther than say parking in the faraway parking spots.
Scott: It's just uphill.
Scott: So that'll deter many a larger individual indeed, but you know as long as it's not raining.
Scott: It's totally awesome.
Rym: Thing is if I get that house, I'll be living so close to the train station.
Rym: I'll just walk or bike every day.
Scott: Yeah, that's the thing Really?
Scott: Well, I might permit expire because they didn't want to have to deal with it.
Scott: if I you know Cuz I'm gonna move hopefully relatively soon.
Scott: I'm gonna start turning up the heat on my Investigations even though I got a ticket But I don't want to bet to pay a bunch of money for parking in the meantime.
Rym: The ticket was so cheap that the fact that I have not paid for much was the ticket.
Rym: It's like 40 bucks 40.
Rym: Here's the thing.
Rym: I'm not paid for parking in over a year of parking.
Scott: Wait, so it was 40 for parking in a metered spot without.
Scott: yeah Whoa, cuz it was only 20.
Scott: I got 20 for parking in a permit spot without a permit.
Rym: Well, I don't know why it was 40, but it was there.
Rym: and the thing is I didn't pay the $3 or whatever For over a year.
Rym: so kind of add it up.
Rym: Yeah, I still win.
Scott: Yeah But now I'm gonna go to.
Scott: I'm gonna.
Scott: I'm gonna get parking up on the street and I'm not gonna pay until I get Another ticket up there.
Rym: too bad.
Rym: I can't do the RIT thing.
Rym: I know it wouldn't work of where I used to keep a bunch of parking tickets and whenever I parked illegally I would just put one on my car and then no one would bother to run me another one.
Rym: Yeah, because I already had the policy of one ticket per violation per day.
Rym: Mm-hmm That worked real well until one day I saw a guy standing there holding the ticket waiting for me to come back to my car.
Rym: He was like, what's all this?
Rym: And my response.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I left my car here for like a week.
Rym: You got any gaming news Gaming news.
Rym: I don't think people want to hear more about pooping and parking.
Scott: Yeah, there is one gaming news.
Scott: That was today.
Scott: That was gigantic.
Scott: I guess to some people is that the slim ps3 rumor is for real.
Rym: Let me tell you I was surprised at how slim it is.
Scott: Well, it's actually not that slim.
Scott: I think the pictures make it look a lot better.
Scott: When you look at it in pictures next to the actual three original ps3, it's not that slim.
Scott: It's like, you know, it's basically like original ps2 sized, you know, it's.
Scott: it's not like this is tiny.
Scott: It's just tiny compared to the gigantic monster.
Scott: That is you know, the original ps3.
Scott: It's like calling a camera tiny because you know next to Godzilla it's like oh, yeah sure.
Scott: Camera is tiny.
Rym: Yeah, sure Okay, fine compared to the original Xbox.
Rym: It is perhaps portable perhaps.
Scott: The thing is is actually, you know, it actually looks a lot more pleasant.
Scott: You know, it still doesn't have any freaking games and the price is I guess reasonable.
Scott: now, right at what?
Scott: $300 with 120 gigs that's not bad.
Scott: But so the system I guess doesn't suck anymore, but still has no games.
Scott: So, I guess it's a blu-ray player if you really want one.
Scott: but digital is the win and blu-ray is to dead.
Scott: So that's all I got to say.
Scott: I mean, you know if there were good games of the ps3 and I Had video games and I needed more video games because I have more video games than I know what to play Right, then I might consider one if I already had a 360, you
Rym: know, it's funny.
Rym: thinking back It's amazing how much people seem to be vested in this fight between Sony You know the HD DVD and the blu-ray when really it was kind of like the Crimean War there were no winners.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know, I mean blu-ray is sort of the quote winner.
Scott: The thing is right blu-ray still isn't.
Scott: you know, there aren't enough players first of all, right?
Scott: they're not cheap enough even though they're getting cheaper and the discs are still too expensive for anyone to care.
Scott: and most people are happy with DVD.
Scott: and I think I read somewhere that you know Even though blu-ray is quote one there are more HD DVD players out there in people's homes than blu-ray players.
Rym: Where'd you get that?
Rym: some guy on the internet?
Scott: There was some guy on the internet.
Scott: It was an.
Scott: it was like a little stuff.
Rym: Are you sure it was some guy on the internet?
Scott: I can show you the link.
Rym: Are you sure it wasn't?
Scott: Nothing.
Scott: Yeah, believe it if you want to.
Scott: but it said a thing on the internet said that there were more HD DVD players in people's houses and blu-ray players in people's houses, so There's this article and I'm not going to talk about the article.
Rym: The article is well-written and there's a lot of good discussion about it.
Rym: But on Tetenhammer the question that has been asked the the the point of all this is quote The balancing act the challenges of class balance in massively multiplayer online games.
Rym: so there's this huge article and People talking about the article on slashdot and other places.
Rym: It's like every.
Rym: there's this monkey in the room that no one's looking at the monkeys pooping on everything.
Rym: Yeah, he's destroyed the walls.
Rym: He's parked his car.
Rym: We shouldn't have.
Rym: but no one is talking about the the monkey or maybe the monkey shouldn't be doing that.
Rym: They're all debating like the the hat the monkeys where they can't think outside the box.
Rym: But this whole thing the whole discussion hinges on the age-old That the problem that has existed since the first mud the very first mud when they're in since freaking.
Scott: You know hero quest or D&D.
Rym: it's existed in the first game where there were classes.
Rym: some guy playing a fighter looked at some guy playing a wizard and said this is bullshit.
Rym: wizards are more powerful than fighters.
Rym: and There's been this kind of unwritten assumption in all gaming forever that in any massively multiplayer game or even any multiplayer game the classes all have to be either perfectly identical or perfectly balanced equal but different.
Rym: and Every piece of gaming literature just about that I encounter on a daily basis or anything anyone writes about or articles like this.
Rym: People always seem to just assume this truism guy it brings you back to our packs panel, but I'll get to that later.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Why doesn't anyone ask why classes have to be balanced?
Rym: Why can't you make a game where they're actually unbalanced?
Rym: I think it would make a better game.
Rym: I think make things more interesting.
Scott: the reason is because when you're playing a game of combat right say for example D&D fourth edition which is the prime example of this right and the only thing people are really doing is fighting and you get rewards for winning at fighting.
Scott: right if One person has like a hundred attacks that are all wicked powerful and awesome and the other person all they can do is like poke things of the stick Right what?
Scott: and the whole game is fights the whole time The person with the hundred attacks of awesome is gonna have all this fun doing all this awesome shit and the person who can poke Things with a stake is gonna sit there being bored with nothing to do.
Scott: and so When you have a game like that you need all but consider this the common incentive for winning these things.
Rym: So what the game gives you in reward for doing what it is that you were doing is usually XP Which makes you level up, but if everything's balanced and everyone levels up at the same rate based on the same stuff You're not really gaining anything.
Scott: You're just kind of unlocking content because it's not versus It's just grind your own self hamster in a wheel action.
Rym: the other.
Rym: the real trouble is that MMOs really if you look at it they don't reward that many behaviors in game and When they do they often do it in a very shallow manner.
Rym: and there are games that have tried to do other things.
Rym: I mean I knew someone who very unironically played a dancer in Star Wars galaxies and only cared about dancing But the game.
Rym: how much was there to reward people who are good at dancing?
Rym: Compared to how much was there to roar people who are good at killing shit mm-hmm.
Rym: and What this brings me to is one this article.
Rym: you can read it.
Rym: I think almost everyone gaming is missing the point and I think There's this almost greater problem of.
Rym: there are a lot of assumed arguments in gaming like the console wars No, the PlayStation is gonna win.
Rym: No the Xbox is gonna win.
Rym: No, the Wii is gonna win.
Rym: and no very few people make the point of.
Rym: maybe There's no such thing as winning or maybe we need to look at this from a different angle And I think that's that's what happens in any sort of realm.
Scott: right is when gaming was new right there was.
Scott: no there weren't even Genres.
Scott: just every game was a game.
Scott: You know like what genre is Donkey Kong?
Scott: I guess a platformer?
Scott: Maybe what?
Scott: now we have genre is like pac-man a pac-man I mean, but now people look at a game like a war game an RTS once and labels and You know like you know standard tropes.
Scott: They can't escape them They can't think outside of them.
Scott: once they have this you know framework to think within Yeah, you get all this can't think of anything else outside of it.
Rym: It's like all this conceptual baggage where you think well Yes, so it has to have this and this and this.
Scott: there's this idea I forget what the idea is called that actually like language limits What the ideas people can have like.
Scott: well are you know it's.
Scott: I'm not saying whether it's true or not But I'm saying there's an idea out there that I was about to say that there there are many arguments again.
Rym: Yeah, sort of thing.
Scott: I'm just saying there's an idea out there that you know people can't think of ideas that they are unable to express with you know languages that they know and True or not that's basically you know.
Scott: sort of the same idea that we're seeing here Is that you know people had this sort of like this language of gaming right these ideas of gaming and people can't.
Scott: it's very difficult to be able to think of ideas in gaming that are outside of.
Scott: you know the nomenclatures
Rym: But anyway at the penny arcade expo in Seattle, which is coming up over the holiday weekend It just so happens that one of the panels we're doing there one of three is Losing should be fun which attacks one of the kind of assumed truisms of gaming that Losing socks and winnings awesome and that gave the goal of all games should be to win.
Scott: interestingly enough There's an.
Scott: I looked at the panel schedule.
Rym: Oh, yeah some.
Scott: they apparently write.
Scott: some other guy He's actually a game industry professional has a panel called winning sucks And I read the synopsis and it sounds like he's got the same idea as us.
Scott: And I wonder why they thought that they should give the same.
Scott: You know two people submit almost the same panel idea, and they schedule both of them.
Scott: I think that was a mistake.
Rym: I don't know but whatever I'll go to his panel, and it's hard to say because I kind of you know after packs much like we do with every other convention I kind of sidestep the standard process and just have contact.
Rym: so maybe the people I talked to Just gave us the panel, but then the normal process brought this other panel in through the normal channels.
Scott: who knows how it happened?
Scott: But I just think it's kind of weird and it'll be interesting.
Scott: And I'm sure the I'm you know the other guy's panel sounds pretty good actually.
Scott: so I'm gonna check it out.
Scott: You know to make sure and you know we'll handle it professionally.
Scott: It'll be all right.
Scott: It's not like it's a competition.
Scott: Oh, no, we had the same panel.
Scott: I guess we had to hate each other and be all versus bloody blood.
Scott: no obviously We agree with this dude from what I can tell.
Scott: so we should be all buddy, buddy.
Rym: But in the Raven Theatre on Friday 1130 beyond the Candyland Oh, man, that's us.
Rym: and then in the not the Raven Theatre But the as I'm looking through the schedule over to the sun, maybe Unity Wolfman theater at 1030 on Saturday losing should be fun.
Rym: and then Sunday Sunday at 10 a.m.. Our headlining panel the panel that we're hopefully going to retire after next year beyond Dungeons and Dragons.
Scott: So basically we have like the first panel every morning.
Scott: Yeah, so it's pretty awesome for us because basically like we show up at the con early every day We do our panel, and then we the rest of the day do whatever we want.
Rym: the other thing I'm really excited about is this year We get a privilege.
Rym: I don't know if we got this last year and didn't take advantage of it But we actually get a privilege for being panelists.
Rym: we can go into the exhibit hall an hour and a half before the doors Open.
Rym: it's pretty and unknown worlds is gonna be in there.
Scott: Yeah, we're gonna go talk to the NS guys.
Rym: I'm going to talk to them until they get a restraining order.
Scott: Yeah, so how's that skull bitey bitey bitey bitey?
Scott: It was just bite them.
Rym: No, I'm going to hold my upper body perfectly stationary and jump very slowly Mmm, and demand that babblers come back, but anyway things of the day.
Rym: What do you have for me Scott?
Scott: So I was looking around for thing of the day.
Rym: that sounds dangerous.
Rym: You kind of wound up to that.
Rym: I heard that whole intake of breath like I didn't find much.
Scott: that was gaming related.
Rym: I got like five things of the day.
Scott: Oh my delicious links are like text shit cuz I'm all Tekken lately.
Scott: There's that freestyle running guy who like College humor videos, which I didn't watch today, but anyway, I did find this.
Scott: It's actually two things and I'm sure I'm late to the party.
Scott: I'm sure that these are very old and I came to them and discovered them very late, but you know what I'm admitting it.
Scott: So that's fine.
Scott: other people, you know Some people come up, but it's only a problem if you find something old on the internet.
Scott: if you're like Hey, this thing's totally new and awesome, you know present it as if it's old and no one will tell you dude That's an antique right?
Scott: So anyway, what this is is two flash games.
Scott: I'm not sure if there's more.
Scott: they're on new grounds.
Scott: They're called Megaman verse Ghosts and goblins and Megaman verse Metroid.
Scott: and what it is is pretty much you play Metroid Except you're not Samus your Megaman or you play ghosts and goblins, but you're not Samus You're not what's-his-name Maxim is his name, right?
Rym: I don't know Max.
Rym: Well, I was never on Maximo.
Rym: I think maybe I was never all that up on the quote-unquote lore of ghouls and ghosts and ghosts.
Scott: I can't forget the dude's name.
Scott: But anyway, it's man.
Scott: What it's like that game.
Rym: Fuck that game.
Scott: That's true But your Megaman is said of that guy.
Scott: Basically these games like this is a really great concept really great graphical execution really great remixed music Execution.
Scott: they let you change the controls, which is nice.
Scott: They got some nice options, but the controls themselves are shitty and thus the games are relatively unplayable and frustrating.
Scott: but it's still worth, you know a poke at both of them for a few minutes just to check it out and Hope that somebody else comes in and you know makes a fix.
Scott: I do want to also say I Don't know the name of this game, but apparently on Xbox Live Arcade.
Scott: There's a new game.
Scott: That is a Metroidvania type game And it apparently is the holy shit awesome times a billion from what I hear.
Scott: So if you have an Xbox Just go find whatever this game is that I don't know the name of?
Scott: That was so helpful, wasn't it?
Rym: That was great.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So for hopefully not all of you read Kotaku, but I have to link this because it's just too cool.
Rym: this is a collection of Artistic renderings of link in many different styles.
Rym: There are many many pictures here.
Rym: They're all fairly badass.
Rym: But I really really have to point out and stress to you the one that is basically link as Thor He's smoking.
Rym: He's got a giant sword and more muscles than Wolverine.
Scott: Wolverine doesn't have any muscles.
Scott: Yeah, you know who has muscles.
Scott: strong guy.
Rym: He's got a beard too, he's very just kind of Scandinavian and badass.
Scott: Watch out.
Rym: so we we couldn't come up with the show because we could come up with a show.
Rym: I came up with it just now we did but prior we couldn't come up with one because I didn't really have a chance to Play Blood Bowl yet, and I'm not really playing any new games.
Scott: I heard of a video game drought right now.
Rym: All my hopes are pinned on Starfy and NS2.
Scott: I downloaded Starfy.
Scott: It's just a sort of a platforming game.
Rym: It's like sort of a platforming game.
Scott: Oh, well, you might like Starfy.
Scott: But anyway, I only played it for like 10 minutes.
Scott: Anyway, you know after PAX which is in like, you know, we'll only have to do one more show before PAX.
Scott: So the thing is after PAX there's gonna be a glut of gaming.
Scott: I can almost guarantee it.
Scott: It's like every gaming company is holding back for PAX.
Scott: I can just tell.
Scott: but anyway There is if you don't know there's a. there's a new Tron movie coming out and Tron is like one of the most important geek Things there is in gaming and movies and animation.
Scott: It's total crossover in all areas.
Scott: But I watched the trailer and it was totally awesome.
Scott: at least the trailer was awesome.
Scott: Who knows if it's actually gonna be awesome, but you know, whatever.
Scott: but yeah Tron is something I like a whole lot.
Scott: You know, I mean like.
Scott: I think about video games and it's like you play a lot of video games But you wouldn't actually want to really play a lot of video games, right?
Scott: It's like would you really want to be in the world of Counter-Strike?
Scott: No, not really.
Scott: That would just suck.
Scott: Do you really want to be in the world of Donkey Kong?
Scott: No, that sucks big time, right?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: Hyrule would be too bad to live in not too bad depending on who you were and what was going on at The time but you know what Tron like.
Scott: all I want is fucking real VR Tron.
Scott: I would never stop playing that game in a million years just riding bikes and throwing discs.
Rym: It's not much better than that.
Scott: So the thing is there in honor of this new movie that's coming out Which by the way, we'll have a Daft Punk soundtrack.
Rym: You know, what's really funny I Didn't know this and original Daft Punk soundtrack.
Rym: Scott comes home and he's like You're never gonna guess who's making the soundtrack for the neutron movie and I'm like, uh, I don't know Daft Punk You totally knew.
Scott: I just saw the tweet or something.
Rym: Basically, you know what I thought.
Rym: I thought to myself who would it be awesome if it were that?
Rym: it's definitely not and I was like Daft Punk.
Scott: but anyway the.
Scott: In honor of this new movie We will talk about all the.
Scott: there are many video games that are Tron that involve Throwing discs or riding bikes.
Scott: let it and many of them are good.
Rym: There's gonna be really through at least in terms of the bus.
Rym: start with bikes.
Scott: Yeah bikes Definitely.
Rym: there are two like completely opposite philosophies about this sort of game the top-down view and the first-person view.
Rym: And I'm gonna say right now.
Rym: I think they're equally awesome and that we should have both.
Scott: Yes, in fact, you know, why not have a game where you can just push a button and change the view?
Scott: I think GL Tron can do.
Rym: here's the thing.
Rym: if I can't have the choice and I want to win top-down always There's no reason to ever be first person.
Scott: Oh, yeah first person just makes it harder, but you know It's harder and more thrilling it does.
Scott: it definitely makes a lot more thrilling but it's cool if everyone's playing first person because then it's like it's all.
Scott: you're getting closer to the real Tron that I'm looking for and actually didn't the the Arcade guy the retro arcade guy say he had like some crazy diss of Tron machine?
Rym: He did but I remember him saying that it was really difficult to move and dangerous to move and incredibly rare.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is I've seen screenshots of the diss of Tron arcade game.
Scott: I don't think I've ever actually played it like the original diss of Tron.
Scott: But anyway, we'll talk that's that's a disc game and we haven't played it so much.
Scott: So, I'm sorry It's probably one of the most important Tron games that we're not gonna talk about.
Rym: I mean honestly the one I played the most in my life was snafu for the Intellivision Yeah, which is basically Tron but it was four player Tron and it was in.
Scott: it had like a million different modes And there's also Tron for the Atari which is basically this.
Rym: to this day the music just like will pop into my head randomly especially whenever I see Tron related things.
Rym: just The game was cool because not only could it be like many many player and I had these AI that would kind of play With you.
Rym: if the game turned out to be just for like computers left It would go in like super fast mode and just they would.
Rym: you would see which one won and it was really cool.
Scott: Yeah I spent at least a thousand hours of my life playing that with my little brother and my grandma And I said the thing about the the the bike games right is that it's basically everyone is basically a line that you draw.
Scott: you're drawing a line and everyone draws their line at the same speed and you basically If your line bumps into something a wall or another person you lose.
Rym: They're not.
Rym: there are not always walls.
Rym: Sometimes it wraps.
Scott: Sometimes it wraps.
Scott: It's true.
Scott: but if you if you bump into someone's bike or someone's line or you know a wall that doesn't wrap you're dead and it's whoever's alive at the end is the winner.
Rym: and It's funny because it's like this mix of strategy.
Rym: Yeah, it's not like who goes faster, right?
Scott: It's all about positioning and reflexes and well, well, well, it's technically.
Scott: it is a perfect information complete information game technically But it has speed to it, right?
Scott: It's like the thing is the same way.
Scott: the Tetris has speed.
Rym: the game is still discreet because it's on a computer.
Rym: There are units of movement.
Rym: So if you have just like Tetris But if you have the speed down it is literally nothing more than a game of plotting out the perfect strategy and it is Mathematically a solvable game.
Scott: Yeah, some of them you can move diagonal and some of them you can't though, right?
Rym: You had the best in.
Rym: not one was the Atari one.
Scott: when you can move diagonal Yeah cross over other people's like paths diagonally.
Scott: as long as you're in the right spot You can turn your path on and off.
Scott: Yeah, you could also like Drive into someone else's bike, you know, but not into the line.
Scott: So if you hit the if you crash into them directly and then turn away that you can actually avoid them and snap through to the other side.
Scott: and that's really good because it sort of avoids like the Pointless endgame of oh you've cut off, you know 51% of the board on your side and I've got 49% of the board on my side.
Scott: if we both play perfectly and don't slip up I lose thing.
Scott: I'll just kill myself.
Rym: Scott never played perfectly.
Scott: So I play perfectly.
Rym: we talking about should we whip out the Atari again?
Rym: Maybe film it.
Rym: We'll have a.
Scott: Maybe we should play some GL Tron - which is far more exciting and modern it is.
Rym: It's also a lot more difficult.
Scott: Yeah, GL Tron if you don't know is basically a 3d Tron that is open source pretty old Like it's it's.
Scott: it's been around for a long time.
Scott: It's all.
Scott: it's a Linux game, but it's all.
Scott: I think you can run it on pretty much fucking any computer that has open GL.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: and basically it's just Tron 3d.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: That's all there is to it.
Scott: It's just modern and fast and good-looking.
Scott: and you know, you did it looks like actual Tron.
Scott: In fact, it looks better than the first Tron movie a lot better.
Scott: But you know, it's out there and I think if you want to play a Tron bike game You just go get GL Tron.
Scott: Maybe I'll put a link to the to the website in the in the show thingy.
Rym: But basically, I don't know there's something about these sort of kind of very simple very direct competition games That to this day.
Rym: I always fall back on them.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know what it is.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's like just you know, there's a lot of competitive games out there the sort of complex and fiddly part Straight on mono a mono.
Scott: They're so simple draw a line versus the other guy drawn a line like outlaw shoot the other dude.
Rym: They're so simple play some fucking out and they're so, you know that minute to learn a lifetime to master situation.
Rym: but I think the simplicity of the rules and the directness of the competition creates this sort of Competitive intimacy to where you and the opponent, you know When you play a game of say Puerto Rico or Tigers and Euphrates against three equal Amazingly skilled opponents and it's a completely different game from playing against noobs.
Rym: in a game like this You you know that the other player has complete and total awareness of the game.
Rym: You cannot trick them.
Rym: Yeah, you know, you cannot trick them.
Rym: It is so.
Rym: it's almost like you are both the same person at the same time in the competition.
Rym: It's this really weird transference that I've only ever experienced in very simple very direct competition games
Scott: I think and I think that is part of the reason why I want to play like Tron in real life so badly, of course without the chance of dying, but you know, yeah
Rym: You know what happens when you fall down because
Scott: you combine cuz you know Tron even you know Whether you playing this game the game, you know It's like some games.
Scott: when you make them 3d or fancier they change fundamentally like say Mario.
Scott: Not that 3d Mario is bad, but it's fundamentally different when it's Mario 64 versus Mario 3, right?
Scott: But Tron whether it's like VR and you're actually riding bikes with light trails behind them or whether it's Atari with big Pixelated blocks just moving around a grid.
Scott: That's incredibly low resolution.
Scott: It's the same exact game.
Scott: The only thing is that the 3d VR one adds sort of like the roller coaster thrill of riding a bike at high speeds Whereas the Atari one does not have such a roller coaster, you know Thrill to it.
Scott: But otherwise, it is really the exact same thing in terms of the game and the competition.
Scott: It's just so pure that it cannot be spoiled by enhancing it Unless you made it a different game in which case it's no longer pure now.
Rym: disc wise though I got to say my favorite Tron II.
Rym: this game even though it's really it captures I guess the spirit and the feel of Tron discs, but yet is nothing like Tron discs at all.
Rym: Yeah is ricochet which was like this mod that came with half-life in like back in 2000.
Scott: I don't know if you could.
Scott: I don't it might cost money now or if it's free.
Scott: I have no idea.
Rym: I don't think it's free unless you already have it, but and no one plays it.
Rym: I think we have to go check on steam unlike every other game that we want to play that You know that old games that are difficult to get together.
Rym: We got to set up VPNs or anything.
Rym: If you guys listeners all get ricochet.
Rym: We will play with you.
Scott: Ricochet is a game.
Scott: That's actually easy for everyone to get together and play ricochet.
Scott: Basically, it's a half-life 1 mod.
Scott: It was free for us at least.
Scott: I don't know if it's free for anyone else nine years ago nine years ago, and basically the way this game worked is an FPS and You.
Scott: there are different kinds of maps, right?
Scott: There's the dual maps and there's also the free-for-all.
Scott: everyone go all the time maps, right?
Scott: And you basically this is platforms and every platform is a big disc and Each platform has triangles next to it and you step on a triangle and it bounces you through the air to the next.
Scott: You know another platform so you basically bounce between these platforms by stepping on these triangles.
Scott: You can't jump all you can do is move and Throw discs and you have three discs that you can throw and once you've thrown the three discs you need to wait for them to regenerate before you can throw them again and The discs bounce off some of these walls like, you know Depending if there's a wall there for you to throw a disc at there's some.
Scott: Sometimes the discs might teleport if you throw them into a teleporter.
Scott: so you can throw a disc like in one direction But it ends up coming at the guy from another direction.
Scott: That's like power-ups and it is power-ups like freeze discs and triple discs and all that stuff.
Rym: He was just again so simple and so direct.
Rym: I mean we used to at RIT and even when we lived here we would play this game for like Six hours without stopping in.
Rym: like, you know There'd be ten people on the server and you just all took turns doing duels and watching the duels.
Scott: It was just some of the servers even set up to where I give this ten people.
Scott: Five duels happen at once and then it keeps mixing the people up based on who won a new lost.
Rym: This game is just so amazing and it doesn't really need to be updated at all.
Scott: No, it doesn't need any changes.
Scott: It's already.
Scott: it's perfect.
Rym: You could make the graphics better, but the gameplay was absolutely perfect.
Rym: It was a little bit tiny bit not necessarily buggy but fiddly.
Rym: Yeah in that, you know There'd be often be the situation where if two players jump and run into each other.
Rym: There was a fine art to making sure that they died slightly before you.
Scott: Yeah Cuz you could die by either getting a. you could die by getting hit by a chainsaw disc, right?
Scott: And basically if you didn't use any of your discs, you still had all three of them.
Scott: You could push secondary attack to throw a chainsaw disc and if that hits someone they were their head just popped off and they died.
Rym: Or you could die by being a dumbass and either falling or getting knocked off, right?
Scott: So you could fall off the map just by jumping improperly by stepping on a triangle and then like Pushing some arrows in the air in a way that made you fall off.
Scott: or if you got hit with a regular disc You didn't actually die.
Scott: You just got pushed a little bit.
Scott: so if you got you someone can throw their regular discs at you and push you off the edge which would kill you.
Scott: and of Course if you jump up and you bump into someone in the air, you're both gonna probably die.
Scott: But whoever dies first is a loser.
Scott: So there's always that situation.
Rym: It's just you know, what it is.
Rym: a is an elegant game from a more civilized age Absolutely.
Scott: I've always loved how they were like advanced players to do stuff like.
Scott: you would hit a triangle to jump in the air and usually you don't want to touch any arrows when you're jumping because That'll just knock out like loop around.
Scott: Yeah back on the same platform It's like, you know If you just don't touch any arrows at all after you step on a triangle you will land perfectly on the destination platform Assuming nothing else bad happens to you.
Scott: But if you do push some arrows properly you can like land on a platform that you're not supposed to land on.
Scott: like, you know Normally this arrow points to that platform over there.
Scott: But if I you know push left when I step on this I'll actually land on that platform over there.
Scott: And that's how you get advanced play and just totally own noobs By jumping and landing behind them when they don't think it's possible.
Rym: Plus there was this chainsaw in the back being like fencing where someone could use the chainsaw Which is the instant kill if it hits you.
Rym: but you could block discs that were shot at you with your own discs Yeah, and you could.
Rym: you could do like the one two where you block and you also shoot and then it was just so great.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: I want to play it right now.
Scott: Yeah, we should.
Scott: we should play it later.
Scott: But there's also the kinds of situations like at the beginning of every match if it was a duel, right?
Scott: It's like you get a little bit of time to walk around before the duel starts.
Scott: Of course, you can lose the duel before it starts by falling off which you just suck, right?
Scott: But you can also sort of posture, you know, it doesn't let you throw discs for like three seconds.
Scott: It counts like three two one go and then you can start throwing discs.
Scott: so what'll happen is either a the players will sort of stay far away from each other and you know sort of go in or They'll get right up on the same platform as each other and sort of go And then maybe start the match off trying to do a chainsaw
Rym: right away.
Rym: that's another thing.
Rym: that the whole a lot of these old games like NS and this game have the ready room or the like Pre-match stuff for players.
Rym: that this whole psychological thing when when you start a match of ricochet Yeah, especially back then when there really wasn't voice chat Yeah, like you just kind of you'd see these two avatars kind of chest bumping and jostling for position.
Scott: In the the all the every man for himself mode Basically every time you die You just immediately respawn and it's a gigantic map that's got like multiple levels of altitude.
Rym: speaking of altitude I should point out aiming is only in one plane.
Scott: Oh, yeah, the game is effectively two-dimensional, right?
Scott: Even though it's a 3d FPS.
Scott: You can't aim up or down.
Scott: You can only aim straight for you.
Rym: Look up or down.
Scott: Yeah, you can't duck or jump.
Scott: You can only jump by stepping on the triangles But if you shoot it shoots out in a plane.
Rym: So if you shoot in the air and someone else happens to be in the air at the same time you can hit them.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: So play ricochet good God.
Rym: Yeah, there's like no one playing this game anymore.
Scott: No, but in the in the every man for himself mode when you die you immediately respawn and there's multiple levels of altitude.
Scott: So it's like this Platforms in level one two and three depending on the map and it's just a whole bunch of people all at once trying to kill Each other as many times as possible, but it's totally awesome because unlike the dual mode right where you're worrying about one person There's these discs that is coming at you from all freaking directions and like.
Scott: there's all about the timing.
Scott: This is in both modes the timing of the power-up.
Scott: It's like, you know, the power-up will always appear like after this so many seconds.
Scott: It's like you'll be like, okay jump jump jump jump.
Scott: the power-up should appear now jump grab the power-up.
Rym: You know that's something a lot of old deathmatch style FPS has had would they?
Rym: there'd be the quad damage that would appear at a semi-regular or a regular interval and everyone knew where it was and all the advanced players knew exactly what it was gonna appear because they Were kind
Scott: they would you know, they wouldn't stand around and camp it like a new wood, right?
Scott: They they would time their mat their way.
Scott: They're walking around the map such that they will appear in that room at the time when the thing appears and just grab it Immediately and then be out of the room or they'll pointedly be on the opposite side of the map.
Scott: Yep, if they don't think that they can get to it They'll.
Rym: they'll be far away from where there were all these ways of Causing this kind of very specific ebb and flow of gameplay that I think a lot of modern games have lost in their rush for complexity.
Scott: Hmm one thing that's really cool about ricochet is that you know, you get these different power-ups the ice Disc which would freeze the other player allowing you to easily shatter him with a triple disc.
Scott: the the triple disc Which allowed which allowed you to throw three discs at once and sort of you know The joke that only we get There was what were the other power-ups?
Scott: Oh, there were the fastest that you could throw really fast.
Scott: The whole bunch of them power up stacked.
Rym: So if you You shot three fast discs, yeah, that was just something so simple.
Scott: like that.
Scott: It's like you could get triple speed ice discs and just be like new new new new new new new new and throw like a million Discs everything.
Scott: if you manage to collect three power-ups, it often didn't matter.
Rym: the power-ups were neat and powerful But they weren't necessarily game winners.
Scott: Yeah, I know right?
Scott: It's like, you know, oh no the other guy got the power-up.
Scott: It's gonna be like 30 seconds before another power-up appears.
Scott: He throws like a whole bunch of ice discs at you.
Scott: They're just normal discs that happen to freeze if they hit you.
Scott: So just don't get hit.
Rym: and if you're getting hit anyway Don't get hit and don't fall off right.
Scott: the guy might have the triple discs.
Scott: So there's nine discs bouncing around looking for you, but he could just as easily hit himself with those if he's not careful.
Scott: Yeah, because one of them might be aimed at you, but the other two might be bouncing off the wall sitting him in the ass.
Scott: So it was always kind of fun like that.
Scott: And plus when people get the fast discs that let you shoot a whole bunch of just real quickly they'll tend to just go nuts with them and not be too careful with them and Often hurt themselves because you know your own discs can hit you.
Scott: do you remember it's ricochet?
Scott: these discs are bouncing.
Scott: No, they did not.
Rym: they didn't knock you back though.
Scott: No, but they you can reclaim them.
Rym: Basically.
Scott: No you did you could But you could also hit yourself with a chainsaw, which is not, you know, it didn't kill you.
Scott: It didn't.
Rym: did Just be a lot of play like I throw just behind me as I'm jumping forward knowing that it'll bounce and land on the platform I'm going toward because I expect him to jump to that platform away from with the chainsaw.
Rym: But then the disc I shot behind me hits him before I get there.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Oh my god You also got more points if you killed someone with more ricochets.
Scott: Oh, yeah, that's right.
Scott: Every time you kill someone it tells you how you killed them.
Scott: So it's like you killed him with a chainsaw blade that ricocheted twice big points.
Scott: You know you killed him with a direct hit with a normal disc, you know You were standing right on the same platform and you just threw a disc directly at him and hit him straight on one point.
Scott: Big deal, you know, you killed the other guy cuz he fell off.
Scott: no big deal at all Really, you know your dis bounced like five times and then hit the guy after going through a teleporter.
Scott: a billion points.
Scott: The thing is those things usually have by accident.
Scott: Yeah, I Mean you can usually get one or two ricochets or maybe a teleport kill on purpose But not a multiple ricochet and teleport kill is usually luck.
Rym: So do we have any other disc games to talk about?
Scott: I wish I had played disc of Tron more.
Scott: I mean, I've seen it and it's basically an old arcade game where you know this.
Scott: it's really.
Scott: it's sort of 2d ish 3d ish.
Scott: You know you stand on a disc you can sort of walk around it and throw discs to the other side But it's I don't really know how it plays.
Scott: I'd have to get like maim and try to play disc of Tron just to see how it goes.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: were there any other Tron games?
Scott: Yeah, they're a whole bunch But yeah, I haven't played enough of them pretty much.
Scott: All you really need to know is that the game of riding light cycles Which basically is the game of drawing a line and try and trying to get the other guy to bump into your line is a Great game and the game of just throwing shit the other guy trying to hit him is a great game.
Scott: And those are just these two really pure and simple games that were based off a movie about video games.
Scott: Think about that, right?
Scott: I mean It wasn't like someone invented these games and then someone made a movie about them like say Mario Brothers the movie Right or doom the movie or Halo the movie.
Scott: This is.
Scott: there was a movie about video games in general and they came up with these two games for the movie and they happen To be amazing games.
Scott: When does that happen?
Scott: Only once ever.
Scott: That's it right there Tron.
Scott: so There you have it.
Scott: play Tron games so that you'll actually know what the hell's going on when you watch this new movie That's coming out And if you haven't seen the original movie Frickin see it before you see the new movie because I from the trailer I can already tell The new movie is only gonna make a lot of sense If you've seen the original.
Scott: you're like not gonna know who people are and such and such and I like Tron.
Scott: Oh And Tron guy we saw him at Panko Con 2.0.
Rym: You know, I was about to stop but you kept saying things So I kept recording.
Scott: that's fine Tron guy.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm.
Scott: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.