Rym: It's Wednesday February 25th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We talk a bit about 1980s astro boy.
Rym: Let's do this You know Scott.
Rym: There's a rumbling in the distance some sort of Frightening sound not unlike the sex car that is.
Rym: uh it's coming, and I can humbling a rumbling is it in my stomach?
Rym: I guess you didn't need dinner.
Rym: No, no, no, it's a con season is fast approaching.
Scott: Con season is pretty much the whole year.
Scott: that mean I don't people call it season right and I guess Season is technically right.
Scott: It's like August cuz August has got.
Scott: you know like.
Scott: like you know late July August has like you know all the big big conventions.
Scott: You're forgetting to con, San Diego packs, right?
Scott: They're all.
Rym: they're all crammed in that one May which has anime Boston and ConnectiCon and a whole host of other ones.
Scott: That way kinetic ons in August also.
Rym: It's sometime in the Sun.
Scott: late July August is ConnectiCon.
Rym: It's hard to tell because kinetic ons website is broken again.
Scott: No, but no.
Scott: so it's like.
Scott: that's the con season.
Scott: now the thing is there are cons all year.
Scott: They're always con somewhere in the world Somewhere in the u.s.. There's a con pretty much every month at least probably more than one every month.
Rym: yes But in the Northeast in the summer is when most of the anime cons are that are big for geek Conventions all in the u.s..
Scott: It's.
Scott: but from late July to early September is when all the cons are.
Rym: yes.
Rym: So there is a con season, and it's rapidly approaching.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: July is a little bit away It's already a lot away and come May we have to start going to these cons.
Scott: Yeah It's not con season though in May.
Scott: It's just a con in May - maybe more cons.
Scott: Two cons in May, I don't know if I can do two in May.
Rym: I Don't know.
Rym: I'm pretty much looking at a B. Oh - con ConnectiCon fax.
Scott: All right sure.
Rym: wow you're so enthusiastic.
Rym: Maybe we shouldn't bother.
Rym: all right sure okay?
Scott: We don't go.
Scott: I'll do something else.
Rym: Regardless we are actually.
Rym: I figure I'll announce it now even though It's a little early because there have been many rumors about whether or not we will ever appear at anime, Boston.
Rym: people have been asking Us for like the last four years every year.
Rym: They're like hey.
Rym: Are you going to anime, Boston?
Rym: and every year?
Rym: It's like yeah, oh wait.
Rym: No.
Rym: It's the same time as some other con We go to or or they remind us like right before the con is about to happen like hey You guys doing a panel in anime, Boston.
Rym: Yeah, what is it see?
Scott: I mean if you're deciding whether you're gonna go to a convention or not as an attendee You can decide like a week or two in advance.
Scott: well unless you don't need that much advance notice.
Rym: Well you do for a lot of the big East cons because the hotels sell out and the tickets sell out.
Scott: well Yeah, yeah, but you know really I mean Otakon you need the hotel But you know you can take it just to point out kids if you don't already have your hotel room for Otakon You're probably screwed.
Rym: No
Scott: you could probably get one now, but it'd be rough, and you'd be shitty
Rym: yeah,
Scott: but anyway the No, but if you are actually gonna do something at a convention Maybe artists alley maybe a dealer room Maybe some panels that kind of thing you basically need like almost a year advance notice.
Scott: So if you come up to us like a few weeks in advance like hey go to anime, Boston in a few weeks It's like too late to remind us.
Rym: guys You know we could obviate that problem by simply remembering when cons are
Scott: yeah Yeah, the real
Rym: problem with anime, Boston was that literally every year for the past like seven years when I thought man I'd love to go to anime, Boston something was on that same weekend every time.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I don't remember something being on the weekend last time.
Rym: I had stuff on the weekend.
Rym: It wasn't cons It was just stuff.
Rym: just places did things like every year something came up sometimes.
Rym: It was con.
Rym: sometimes It was other stuff mm-hmm.
Rym: But the stars are in alignment this year.
Rym: because you might remember last year anime, Boston had some trouble with the registration.
Rym: It made all the news and we commented on it, and it just so happens that a good friend of ours Works with the anime Boston panels and programming staff And he was like hey you guys should come to anime, Boston, and I was like you know what.
Rym: yeah Let's fucking do it this time all right.
Scott: Yeah, I mean well We didn't go to Katsucon so to maintain the quota.
Scott: why the fuck not?
Rym: We're still nowhere near.
Rym: we set some records.
Scott: It's also a lot easier for us to get to Boston than it is for us to get to DC.
Scott: I don't know, but we know people in DC is like a five-hour drive from here.
Rym: It's really not that bad.
Scott: Boston is a straight shot in 84 East.
Scott: It's real easy.
Rym: He sees a straight shot on 95 south.
Scott: like think about how long it takes us to get to Connecticut.
Scott: It's like two and a half times that.
Rym: so almost as long as it takes to get to DC.
Scott: no like slightly longer than half the time It takes to get to DC.
Rym: point out that every year Connecticut takes us almost two hours to get there.
Rym: No, not really it has for the last several years because you remember every year.
Rym: We're like yeah, let's go.
Scott: yeah It doesn't feel that long.
Rym: there's no traffic on 84 around 684. this takes like an hour.
Scott: No, there's not gonna be that traffic, but it's been there every year.
Rym: Why is it not gonna be there this time?
Scott: They're gonna leave at a different hour.
Rym: Yeah We're probably went to Connecticut.
Scott: We would always do is be driving on 84 like.
Scott: well other people were getting home from work.
Scott: as we come home early Get in the car and go and thus be on 84 in the going home rush hour.
Rym: That is one thing we go to animate.
Scott: Boston will probably leave on like a Friday morning Thursday night.
Rym: most likely We're gonna head there Thursday during the day, okay We'll see what the situation is.
Rym: well.
Rym: That's what I'm going.
Rym: I mean.
Rym: I have vacation days.
Scott: I see I got to see about the days But yes, just quit.
Rym: we are most definitely attending anime Boston.
Rym: We're gonna be there guestie whatever and we're at least gonna do anime.
Rym: You should see and know your creators.
Rym: You know all our kind of typical fare And we're gonna do the late show again since we offer that way back to Katsucon is like the Katsucon Exclusive, and you know we didn't go to Katsucon this year.
Rym: So we're gonna see if this is gonna become the anime Boston exclusive.
Scott: all right well We'll keep shopping it around.
Scott: see if anyone's buying.
Scott: Alright that that's all we got for that.
Rym: That's all I've got.
Rym: You have anything exciting to say?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I thought we were gonna do some more stuff there, but is that not confirmed yet?
Rym: Well, it's not confirmed yet, so I don't want to say anything, but we there may be Two or three other events we do and I should also point out that we Will very likely have the illustrious Daryl Surratt on at least one of our panels.
Scott: if he if he shows up He'll be there.
Scott: Yeah, they're there many possibilities of things in store, but anime Boston is looking extremely likely.
Rym: I already got the hotel room.
Rym: We're going alrighty there.
Scott: So is it a nice hotel?
Rym: I have no idea.
Rym: I've never been to Boston.
Scott: Great alright, so what's going on in the news world here?
Rym: Low talk of someone who wasn't quite sure what he was gonna say and he was trying to finish out the sentence.
Rym: and well He came up with it.
Scott: That's right, so Yeah, is that asteroid movie is coming out right?
Scott: the CG one the head little trailer.
Scott: that was looking alright.
Rym: It was delayed in the not delay delayed.
Scott: They got some money not delayed got some money.
Scott: I don't know where the money's coming from.
Scott: I don't know how many people are gonna see it in the bad economy.
Scott: You know I mean there are people who know asteroid, but in the US Really he's got the bad economy.
Rym: from what I've seen movie ticket sales are actually going up.
Scott: That's because the movies are 3d.
Rym: It's not just that it's because it the Oscars was just now.
Rym: the same thing happened during the Great Depression.
Scott: Really, yes, I get to go study that entertainment.
Scott: alright But other forms of entertainment are going down the shitter outside of New York City.
Rym: movie theaters are pretty cheap.
Scott: No, it's that's true.
Rym: I mean not everyone pays like 25 bucks to see a movie.
Scott: Yeah, that's that's true alright.
Scott: But anyway Astro Boy movie alright looking pretty likely and IDW is a comic publisher.
Scott: right they publish the Dick Tracy books that I buy.
Scott: They're gonna publish that Bloom County reprint the rims gonna buy cuz he you know he can't get enough of that.
Rym: Well, I already have the first printing.
Rym: I might as well buy the last print.
Scott: Well, it's probably gonna be all fancy like the Dick Tracy one, too.
Scott: It's not gonna be like.
Rym: you know the old one Which is just like my old one is so old like it has stains from my childhood all over it.
Scott: Good reason to buy new.
Scott: They also do like Transformers comics and that sort of stuff right there.
Scott: They're pretty high quality comics publisher, and they are gonna do a four at issue.
Scott: Astro Boy miniseries, so it's it's a comic was turned into a movie and other movies turning being back turned back into a comic again.
Scott: So I think that's that's gonna be pretty interesting considering IDW is high quality.
Scott: the movie Maybe Astro Boy is high quality, so It.
Scott: I think I'll get the first issue.
Scott: You know or maybe get the tray.
Scott: who knows what I'll do?
Scott: But I'm gonna check it out in some some fat.
Rym: I would definitely say there's a good shot of this coming together in the right way for once.
Scott: yeah The thing is if it's just a comic of the movie.
Scott: Do you really need it if you see the movie?
Scott: It's like a lot of times that happens is like they'll make for example right you'll get x-men comics right then We'll make like an x-men movie Okay, and then they'll make x-men comics that are like the movie afterwards.
Scott: at you know after the fact It's like.
Scott: is that really like anyone who reads comics?
Scott: read the x-men comics the movie.
Rym: forget those comics are not meant to be bought by fans.
Rym: the Movie you know.
Rym: those are bought by.
Rym: those are bought by grandma.
Rym: who knows that Billy likes the x-man.
Scott: No, that's not possible because these things are only sold in comic book stores or grandma would never be able to go.
Rym: They're also bought by collectors who buy them to collect them.
Rym: yeah collectors don't even like that shit All right, then who buys them?
Rym: cuz they clearly make enough money.
Scott: I have no idea who buys them.
Scott: That's what I'm asking.
Rym: It's definitely not those people Scott.
Rym: I do see those things in bookstores Maybe but I saw a bookstore on the end cap has like all the comics of popular movies and all that crap together.
Scott: Yeah, I mean at least wing anime and manga section at least with things like Watchmen and 300 or whatever.
Scott: right they don't make a comic from the movie from the comic.
Scott: they just the original comic starts selling like crazy and Watchmen is selling stupid crazy like so stupid.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: I was looking at some of the numbers just in like the direct market whatever I think was no.
Scott: I think it was just.
Scott: I think that oh, I remember what the number was.
Scott: I think it was in this year if you only count 65% of bookstores that report to book scan which doesn't include Walmart even right it was like Multiple hundreds of thousands.
Scott: I think maybe like six hundred thousand.
Scott: It's something the ridiculous number of copies of Watchmen and this thing has been like up high on the list ever since it's been a trade.
Scott: so there are millions and millions and millions of copies of Watchmen sold which is like way more than any comic like It's approaching like Dragon Ball shonen jump levels in terms of how many people are buying this thing.
Scott: I don't know how many individual copies one person is buying.
Scott: I bought to See.
Scott: I buy another one.
Rym: I have bought zero.
Rym: Surprisingly enough you know.
Scott: I think you bought one.
Rym: I might have you bought.
Scott: you got the trade that we have is you you bought I did I?
Rym: Have no idea who owns that.
Rym: nor do I know where it is.
Scott: I don't know where it is either.
Scott: That's why I was thinking I buy another one.
Scott: It's good to have because I got the.
Scott: I got about the fancy hardcover one recently not the big absolute stupid one You know just the new regular old hardcover one.
Scott: that one's mine.
Scott: But I get a. I get a softcover one You know hand it out pass it around beat it up that sort of thing.
Scott: plus It has different colors than the hardcover one.
Scott: So it's good to compare because sometimes colors have some meaning in there, so it's not gonna be just the washed-out dr.
Rym: Manhattan.
Rym: you're gonna get the bright dark blue dr.
Scott: Manhattan exactly with his giant giant.
Rym: giant something yeah giant something.
Rym: But on the opposite side of things you know things not doing so well.
Rym: I'm sure if you're an anime fan You've seen all the hubbub on the internet that ranges from best buy is dropping their anime selection to best buy dug up Osamu Tezuka, and then stabbed his carbs.
Scott: I doubt either one of them.
Rym: But basically the deal here is that Best Buy is doing what a lot of stars are in this economy.
Rym: It's ours stars Shops in this economy and just in general that if something isn't selling well the agents they restructure How what kind of merchandise their stores carry?
Rym: I mean you think every media play well media plays gone every Circuit City Circuit City's gone.
Rym: But you think like back in the day you'd think every media play was the same.
Rym: you look at a media play.
Rym: you assume That is a media play.
Rym: there are many like it and mine is exactly like all of them, but that wasn't the case.
Rym: I mean if you went to the media play near RIT in Rochester They had an anime section that was almost as big as like their cheapo book section in the.
Scott: yeah Well, I mean think about it.
Scott: right if you've got say a Best Buy right in I don't know Tennessee Right it's gonna be a lot more country music in the music section.
Scott: right if you got if you got a Best Buy in I don't know Tampa is gonna be a lot more metal in the music section.
Rym: What Best Buy is doing really is they're just.
Rym: they're dividing up Anime into basically titles that sell and titles that only sell to a small number of nerds.
Rym: And they're only going to sell the titles that sell to a small number of nerds in the stores where they know the nerds are And they're not gonna sell them in the rest.
Scott: so in other words smart business.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much so.
Rym: as a result They're actually going to cut anime from from a lot of their stores not cut it entirely But drastically cut down to where you'll only see like the big selling top a titles And you won't see anything else there, and they'll get rid of all the overstock.
Scott: in other words common sense.
Rym: Yeah pretty much see.
Scott: I actually think this is good.
Scott: It's sort of a good medicine You know well, it's a bad painful medicine for the anime industry.
Scott: But it's sort of forcing them to do to fix their stupid ways right.
Scott: and that's you know We all.
Scott: everyone always talks about the crap factor right.
Scott: they get all these fucking end right.
Scott: when there weren't enough Anime being brought over to the u.s.. We complained Oh, there's not enough anime over here.
Scott: Then they brought every freaking anime in the known universe over here, and we're like whoa whoa whoa.
Scott: Why are you bringing all the crap over?
Scott: just bring the good stuff.
Scott: leave the crap in Japan?
Rym: I belong like Odine and Crystal Triangle exactly.
Scott: so the thing that's happening and the thing that hurt You know look at this the anime companies bring all this crap over right now.
Scott: The thing is when you're a publisher like an anime company Your goal is not to sell DVDs to people But to sell DVDs to media plays and best buys and circuit cities and Amazons.
Scott: as soon as you sell to the retailer You're good now.
Scott: They can Return it.
Scott: it's possible for them to return it to you of course.
Rym: It's not so good that all depends on the agreement.
Scott: I mean you can't return all things But usually that stuff is returnable to some degree right.
Scott: it's not like comic bookstores where direct market diamond where it's absolutely non returnable.
Scott: Right.
Scott: so they can return it somehow, but usually they don't.
Scott: usually go to a Best Buy.
Scott: they got this big shelf right depending on your Best Buy full of everything and They don't really return anything.
Scott: cuz stuff sells new stuff comes in and the only reason to return stuff is if you can't fit All the new stuff on the shelf right.
Scott: so even if like all the DVDs I you know even if you keep selling out of the popular stuff and restocking it and the Non-popular stuff just sits there taking up space.
Scott: right you don't really notice until There's a bad economy, and you're really really starting to try to push your profits up.
Rym: You know of course I guess I've noticed going into bookstores and things recently that like in general the manga section and almost every bookstore Has the same?
Rym: Physical stock that it had a year ago.
Rym: like I don't see many new titles.
Rym: I see just the same like Set of whatever sitting there And it just grazed through by the manga cows.
Rym: all that like ones are missing and the rest are all sitting there You know.
Scott: because what sells right?
Scott: Naruto bleach?
Scott: What's the?
Scott: what's the one with the?
Rym: I forget it doesn't matter if you can't remember.
Scott: You know you know the Full Metal Alchemist sells Regardless.
Scott: right yeah, you know.
Scott: so why had the other stuff barely sells?
Scott: now I like some of the stuff that barely sells You know but you can always get it from say an Amazon or something like that.
Scott: right if you're a retail store Carrying that you know and like the off chance it might sell is Really not good for you even though you know Fans would like you to carry it.
Scott: they'd like it to become popular But if it's not you're not making money And you're actually the anime companies are sort of.
Scott: you're sort of helping them be Stupid by buying all their crap and putting it on the shelves.
Scott: You're basically making it at least a little bit profitable for them to license crap that no one wants and thus they continue to license Crap that no one wants and sort of dig themselves into the hole that they're in.
Rym: well even band.
Rym: I had this to say.
Rym: quote translated this will be good for the business But it will make it a little harder to sell the less popular titles.
Scott: So just don't do the less popular titles at all.
Rym: But here's the problem.
Rym: even be the internal conundrum of the anime industry in America.
Rym: The more popular a title is in its raw form The less likely the fans are to buy it because popularity tends to come from fan subs and piracy and Then most of the people will watch their bleach or their whatever and that's it.
Rym: They're never gonna buy it.
Scott: It's obviously not true because you know this crazy Naruto scans lations.
Scott: But meanwhile Naruto is the number one selling manga.
Rym: it is, but you look at the comic selling list.
Scott: It's like Watchmen.
Scott: Naruto Naruto Naruto Naruto.
Rym: Yes, but even still the raw numbers are not that high.
Rym: if you look at the you know the book industry.
Scott: They're pretty high.
Rym: They're not that high and recently they've been dropping.
Scott: no actually Naruto I think has been on the actual like book list for like every single month all year.
Scott: which list You know like?
Scott: I guess like the book scan whatever whatever?
Scott: I don't you know the Nielsen thing that they.
Scott: so it's the same list that says a bajillion Watchmen's were sold.
Rym: all right.
Rym: So that list the list you can't name.
Scott: yeah, okay, but yet trust me it sells crazy.
Scott: They make shit money.
Scott: you know crazy shit money off it.
Scott: not bad good money, but that's the manga.
Rym: what about the anime?
Scott: Anime just doesn't make money.
Rym: That's what I was talking about Because the real issue here is that people especially a show like that.
Rym: It's almost a throwaway show.
Rym: I mean you watch it an episode once you're not gonna watch it again.
Rym: So there's no point in buying it.
Rym: the revenue model in Japan is primarily ads on TV coupled with merchandise.
Rym: in America the merchandise is all crappy secondhand only available to anime cons Especially since media play is gone, and they used to be the ones who really sold all that stuff.
Rym: Yeah, Chris I remember during the anime boom media play had this giant section of like Japanese candy and Japanese toys And they had all the same stuff that was in the dealers rooms at cons and now that they're gone I don't see that in retail stores so much.
Rym: They all have like this tiny selection, and that's it.
Rym: yeah, I Don't know what to do about it.
Scott: Well, it's you know any.
Scott: it's the problem of any niche Interest.
Scott: right if a small number of people really like something right they want it to be available.
Scott: You know they want to be able to get it And they want to be able to you know.
Rym: but at the same time the majority of fans It's not profitable to provide it.
Rym: well the only reason it's not profitable?
Rym: because the majority of the fans who?
Rym: Consume most of this media and anime is just one example.
Rym: There are a lot of things like this.
Rym: They like it they enjoy watching it they seek it out They'll spend a little bit of effort getting it But it's not worth paying for or putting any undue effort toward.
Scott: I mean yeah, that's exactly it.
Scott: It's like if you like something right all right.
Scott: You know how much do you like it right?
Scott: It's not just do you like it?
Scott: It's how much do you like it?
Scott: You know I mean like.
Scott: if I like something a whole lot like it's my favorite thing in the universe And I want it really badly.
Scott: I'll do a lot.
Scott: I'll pay a lot of money I'll do a lot of work.
Scott: You know just try to get it.
Scott: if I kind of like something like a little bit like yeah, I'd watch that.
Scott: You know I'm not gonna.
Scott: You know that doesn't mean I'm gonna pay money for it.
Scott: I only like it.
Scott: Maybe maybe I'd pay ten cents for it.
Scott: You know it's like yeah I like it, but not so much You know.
Scott: and if it wasn't available for ten cents if the only way I could get it was ten bucks I just would go without it.
Scott: You know I don't need it.
Scott: And that's that's.
Scott: the thing with anime is that there are very few people who need it bad Right need it bad enough to pay the price that they're charging.
Scott: and that's why you know bandai visual was so in the crapper.
Scott: because They're basically like yeah, let's go for the people who really want it bad want it so bad They'll pay $50.
Scott: the thing is there aren't enough of those people.
Rym: I mean I wanted everything they had to offer but even I wasn't willing to pay that I didn't want everything they had to.
Rym: Well, I wanted a lot of what they had to offer.
Rym: yes I would have paid quite a bit more than you'd expect, but still not even close to what they were asking.
Scott: I would have paid you know 15 20 bucks for some of those things they had again Not even close to what they were asking exactly.
Rym: But I honestly I it's interesting because the anime industry can really go in two directions.
Rym: And I feel like after there were this boom for a while and now that it's kind of fading I feel like this isn't going to affect the long-term industry.
Rym: in fact in General the drying up of anime stuff in stores isn't going to affect the long-term industry because the fan base is primarily Online now and technologically savvy at least to a minor degree.
Rym: so unless anime communities anime culture anime fandom and the industry Actually reach out and get the mainstream audience that they're recording and then they kind of abandoned Then retail presence won't mean anything And they've really got to focus on online business models and read like I don't merchandise at cons fan stuff.
Rym: They have to really go for the secondary streams of revenue.
Scott: I think the one thing that's gonna be key for the future of anime in the United States right is What's gonna be on TV cuz you look right?
Scott: We've got this generation of like you know teenagers right now who are into it right, but are Will the next generation be into it?
Scott: and even though they're watching lots of videos on the Internet's you know so some of them Are gonna be into it.
Scott: you know really you?
Scott: Ask people how they got into anime even us is because we saw something on TV even if it was an off-hour even if you know.
Scott: so I think the future of anime at least for the next decade or so is What is on TV?
Scott: What gets on TV?
Scott: And there's no anime on TV.
Scott: you can guarantee you that two or three generations behind this anime is gonna get less popular.
Rym: Well like I said there are two futures either.
Rym: They have to court the mainstream audience like they did to us.
Rym: I mean I saw a vampire hunter D And all I could think was this is the greatest thing I've ever seen.
Rym: I Have to see more things like this for the but it wasn't the greatest thing you've ever seen Back then.
Rym: it was like that.
Rym: I saw a vampire hunter D and for a fourth grader That was the best thing in the world.
Scott: yes for a fourth grade.
Rym: That's that's about what I think the target audience is.
Scott: I still like vampire Vampire hunter D is good, but it's not the best thing ever.
Rym: no, but it it's up there partly due to nostalgia But you know I saw it on TV partly due to hand the mouth.
Rym: the hand was so snarky.
Rym: Yeah but if They don't court the mainstream audience like they used to and if they don't do the obvious awesome thing like putting Golf manga in the golf magazine or just showing cowboy bebop and HBO and making a big deal about it Then they're pretty much gonna have to go with the secondary root of secondary income Internet fans their children kind of the completely side Demographic
Scott: the putting the golf manga in the golf magazine.
Scott: that when the economy was good We were asking for that because that's the big risk big reward move right instead.
Scott: They were sort of taking the just Spread out.
Scott: real thin low risk low reward Move, but the thing is it was low risk, but it wasn't like a smart move.
Scott: You know it was.
Scott: it was low risk if things stayed the same, so it was like it was a deceptively low.
Rym: I think the real problem was that the industry especially the anime side.
Rym: the manga side had it But in for different reasons.
Rym: they went into this like licensing frenzy, and they licensed everything because anime was selling like crazy.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I was buying a ton of anime for a long time And then I realized that I already had seen almost everything I liked and there wasn't much new coming out that I liked.
Rym: and then fan subs and everything went to crap.
Scott: and now I But yeah the Yeah, I forgot.
Scott: I was gonna say it doesn't matter.
Scott: we've talked about how anime is you know not doing so great for a very long time.
Scott: it's an Ongoing discussion that doesn't change very much at all, but don't worry because there is actually some upbeat news.
Rym: It turns out that Viz is laying people off and restructuring.
Rym: Maybe that's not it.
Scott: Yeah, basically I think what's gonna happen right now at least in the short term is during the bad economy.
Scott: There's very small anime companies are basically either going to die or do a CPM thing where they sit and do nothing and The bigger companies are gonna hold back.
Scott: You know Tokyo pops doing it.
Scott: You know it making its releases less frequent.
Scott: So you're getting you know one volume every four or six months.
Scott: is that every one or two months?
Scott: You know stuff like that They're gonna hold back and only do the bigger titles cut the lower titles or delay them Or you know get rid of them or whatever.
Scott: well I think anyone who's smart and they're just gonna be real conservative and then when the economy gets better They'll be able to try to make another move.
Scott: or maybe they'll get lucky and some other Naruto crazy big property will come out and they'll get it on TV, and it'll be Pokemon all over again.
Rym: see.
Rym: but actually What?
Rym: the way to the smart way right now to act is to look at the anime conventions and the fact that their attendance is Only growing and they're getting bigger and bigger, but at the same time from what I've heard Total this is just like based on rumors and hearsay, but I have heard that dealers and anime cons are having a real rough Mmm, and part of that is due to saturation and all sorts of reasons.
Rym: I could I could think of a few offhand But I think the main reason the fact that most of the dealers are selling the same crap You got like ten booths have the exact same Gundam model and the exact same pins.
Scott: Yeah, I mean the first time I went to that Otakon dealers room even that Ohio con dealers room, right?
Scott: It's like holy shit.
Scott: look at this stuff right.
Scott: and even that Ohio con dealers room was small real small But you know what.
Scott: they had stuff in there that looking back even now that was stuff that you don't see in dealers rooms nowadays.
Rym: They had you know some but it's not just the dealers doing this It's everyone.
Rym: every anime con is stagnated into the same thing.
Rym: They'll have the cosplay they'll have the same set of lame fan panels.
Rym: They all have the same set of pathetic industry panels.
Rym: Then they'll have like like everything they do is so rote and so set in stone that the fan base is kind of changing in this really generic way when what the industry should be doing is Actually doing something different at the cons.
Rym: I'm not gonna get into the details But if they did something different at the conventions They could spark interest in the terror in the properties that aren't well known.
Rym: But yet if known would sell like crazy.
Rym: in other words existing anime fan in other words intelligent marketing.
Rym: Yeah, yeah.
Scott: Yeah that you know, but hey people they don't have that like.
Rym: imagine if this they've never had.
Rym: Remember when we did that gecky goth panel at Otakon the the infamous rated Gerald gecky goth panel.
Rym: Yeah Imagine if the next day in the dealers room There had been one dealer that had just piles of sanctuary and eagle and the tree manga And just all of that stuff.
Scott: Well, there would have been a hundred people that were in that room who would have bought it.
Rym: There are more than a hundred people in that room.
Rym: I think I actually have the count on my little spreadsheet of every panel we've ever done.
Scott: Well, it was you know, the room was full.
Scott: everyone in that room probably would have bought at least something.
Scott: You know at least like one volume is actually now.
Rym: Imagine if instead of just Rym and Scott doing a panel about gecky guy that talks Somewhat about a few of these titles the industry put together a professional pack style thing about that manga Mm-hmm on the main event stage.
Rym: Mm-hmm, but it's not gonna happen.
Scott: No, I'm not gonna.
Rym: But there is one more thing that I do have to talk about.
Rym: This is very important anime news.
Rym: Like this is the most important anime news.
Rym: You're gonna hear in it for a while.
Rym: Alright, they have added Krauser sama to Street Fighter online.
Scott: Is Street Fighter online an actual thing made by Capcom?
Scott: or is it like something that they just call it's like a flash game?
Rym: Japanese software developer daletto is added the Johan's Krauser the second character.
Scott: I think that's one of those right metal city rock parody manga.
Rym: Apparently this anime news network article said glam rock and then they were forced to change it by someone who was angry.
Scott: Yeah, I guess it's one of those.
Scott: I think it's one of those online flash games where the guy just puts every freaking character in the universe You know so you could fight.
Scott: it's one of those things I think.
Scott: well, he looks 3d ish I don't know that though, but you know That's all I have.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Yeah Krauser is probably like the most powerful character.
Scott: I can't really imagine anyone who could beat him except Voltron.
Rym: But anyway things of the day, you know, it's not an anime thing But I feel like it gets stagnant if you only use things of the day related to the topic at hand.
Scott: Well, I don't know if it gets stagnant But I think it's actually.
Scott: there haven't been a lot of anime comic things of the day lately to use.
Scott: So it's sort of like you got to dig into the other bins or else you're gonna come up dry.
Rym: Well primarily I I just had to use this because it's too good.
Scott: Yeah, I would have used it on Tuesday if you didn't steal it.
Rym: This is pretty much the best text adventure I've played in a while.
Scott: I've played.
Scott: well.
Scott: if you want to talk about, you know actual like quality I mean, I've played some good text adventures lately, but this is pretty humorous.
Rym: well, it's up there because it.
Rym: it illustrates a lot of interesting points about game design and Goals and goal-making and all that sort of stuff.
Rym: but the name of the game will tell you everything you need to know need to know about it.
Rym: the game is entitled don't shit your pants and You just take it from there.
Rym: It's I.
Scott: Only thing you have to do to win is not shit your pants Yep, but in fact, um, you know losing is also a part of winning.
Scott: All right, so check this out.
Scott: this isn't anime comic related but it's somewhat Japan related.
Scott: It's because it's a lady in Tokyo.
Scott: she's a Japanese lady.
Scott: Yeah, and she knows how to play the ukulele And She made a ukulele And it's a cake Ukulele.
Scott: she made it like cake and she's like.
Scott: see the frosting.
Scott: it is imitation.
Scott: see this, you know Like ball of you know, this flower.
Scott: it is clay.
Scott: Now I'll play a song on the cake ukulele and then that's it.
Scott: I Like.
Scott: I like ukuleles.
Scott: I like cake.
Rym: Why don't you learn how to play one?
Scott: It's not easy.
Rym: It's not that hard.
Rym: I've known a lot of people who learned how to play the ukulele in a hurry.
Scott: Yeah, but if I'm gonna do that, I might as well go play the guitar cuz.
Scott: actually the thing is, you know Remember I will.
Rym: if you're gonna do that you might as well play the harmonica.
Scott: Well, see the thing I realized seeing this is all the the eternal problem, right?
Scott: It's like, okay I said this is sort of a tangent for Wednesday, but whatever right?
Scott: Yeah I said, alright if I can prove to myself that I will actually practice this harmonica, which is $10 Right who gives a shit if I don't actually practice.
Scott: It's not a big loss.
Scott: Then that means I have the you know, the will to practice something that is more expensive.
Scott: Right now the problem with the harmonica, right is that of course it did not practice So much at all.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: No, so that sort of sealed the deal.
Scott: It's like well, apparently I am NOT a practicer and I will not learn any instrument.
Scott: So do not buy any more instruments They're because you will not practice them.
Scott: The thing is right.
Rym: Is that You got the DS 10 Korg thing.
Scott: Well, the DS 10 Korg thing is is pretty good Yeah, but that has nothing to do with it that I get.
Scott: haven't learned any piano from it.
Scott: All I've learned is synthesizer.
Scott: its synthesizer is not I guess it's an instrument technically speaking, but you know No, but the thing is who they to play.
Scott: harmonica involves like learning all these skills of like, you know mouth dexterity Right, and while I played the clarinet and I have skills of woodwind It's not really the same mouth skill at all.
Scott: You don't have to like you only when you're playing a woodwind you just a YouTube video.
Scott: Anyone can learn to play the harmonica I know but you know in it was more of that sort of learning was necessary.
Rym: Whereas if I got say a guitar, I would argue that the guitar takes a lot more dexterity.
Rym: and But it's manual dexterity, which is much easier than mouth Dirty, I would argue the opposite.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It's just it's a.
Rym: it's a poor Justification - so are you gonna buy a guitar?
Scott: Probably not but I recently learned that you could get one.
Scott: That's like only like a hundred bucks.
Scott: Yeah, so They were like 400.
Rym: but you can just buy a guitar on Amazon.
Rym: you can buy a used one on eBay.
Rym: if you're learning It doesn't matter at guitars a guitar.
Rym: My brother had like an $80 electric guitar.
Rym: And you know what it worked just fine.
Scott: Is this like $100 USB?
Scott: one on thinking?
Scott: Yeah, it's like oh wow USB, huh?
Scott: So it's like.
Scott: I was thinking there are $400, which is why I was like getting the harmonica first, you know.
Scott: And I mean I did play the guitar when I was in fifth grade, you know.
Scott: And the only reason I stopped which was because I started doing band in sixth grade and I was like if I if I could Have changed one thing I would have not joined the band and would have kept playing guitar instead.
Scott: because imagine If I had kept playing the guitar since fifth grade, let's see.
Scott: I was 10 and now I'm 26 so I would have have 16 years of guitar experience.
Scott: I'll be rocking.
Scott: My whole life would be different.
Scott: Maybe instead I played the clarinet for Four years and then stop because it sucked.
Rym: see it doesn't suck.
Rym: You should have switched up to the soprano sax.
Rym: No, why not?
Rym: That's actually an awesome jazz instrument.
Rym: Because cuz why?
Rym: what's wrong with the saxophone?
Scott: Basically, it was nothing to do with the instrument.
Scott: That was the problem.
Scott: It was the fact that you know, I was happy in the sit-down band.
Scott: But then when you get to high school It's pretty much marching band or nothing.
Scott: and I was like fuck this marching band.
Rym: and then that doesn't have to be At least in most high schools I saw you could just join like the wind ensemble.
Scott: They did not have a wind ensemble and pretty much all they did have other bands, you know that to do.
Scott: But all of them were basically like marching band offshoots Like the jazz band was like a bunch of people from the marching band.
Scott: You couldn't just join the jazz band.
Scott: It was like everyone's in the marching band.
Scott: and then you know They sort of split up into the other bands and in the winter when it's cold They are the.
Scott: you know, the marching band is the symphonic band.
Scott: They just sit down.
Scott: So it's like you couldn't do one without the other.
Scott: the way it was set up there, huh?
Scott: And I was not, you know, very pleased with the the marching band situation and thus I don't understand why marching band is the business.
Rym: No, it is not is Most definitely the business.
Rym: I was.
Scott: it was to.
Scott: you know, the problem with marching band is that you know regular is too awesome.
Scott: You know, it's too terrible.
Scott: I mean it was.
Scott: it really was just too militaristic, you know It's like in.
Scott: that's what makes it go makes it terrible because you know think about it.
Scott: I even if I did it right they'd be like, you know, like I had friends in the marching band and they'd be like You know, uh, you know, I messed up and they made me do push-ups.
Scott: It's like yeah, if anyone told me to do push-ups, I'd give him the finger I'd be like fuck you Scott and then that'll be the end of that.
Scott: when
Rym: punk freshman showed up late to my trumpet rehearsals At band camp they were running laps around the football field while I watch
Scott: I would have said no and if you would have made me I would have kicked you in the nuts Which is why I would not have fit into marching band.
Scott: I was fine with the sit-down band because the sit-down band you walk in you sit down.
Scott: Everyone's hanging out having a good time.
Rym: the conductor, you know Scott I want to point out a good sit-down band is As the same amount of yelling and and the equivalent mental exercise of pushing.
Scott: Well, the sit-down band that I was in did not have this problem.
Scott: It was pretty much just like everyone having a good time playing music, you know I mean the conductor might point at you and if you're not doing something, right and you know.
Rym: But they wouldn't be yelling at you or I got yelled at or making you do anything, you know He's got you should watch no Damaic on table because that is pretty much a 100% doctor yelling at people.
Rym: a 100% Accurate view of what it's like to be in a band is the conductor yelling at people.
Scott: Yes Yeah, see that's that's why I wasn't gonna go for that.
Scott: I'm too.
Scott: I'm not taking orders Fragile of a flower for the marching band apparently, but no You're not talking about marching band.
Scott: You can't.
Scott: you can't because you see I will spike you.
Rym: almost 30 years ago Osamu Tezuka's Astro Boy got its second anime.
Scott: Well, yeah, cuz it was you know, it was so good.
Scott: It was you know, the first dish not the absolute first of course, but the first dish and bestest Anime in the 60s.
Scott: It is effectively the first anime effectively modern animation from Japan Yep, and you know, it was so popular and awesome and amazing and so was the manga.
Scott: but you know after the 70s and you know It came around to the 80s There was a whole new generation of children in Japan and the 60s Astro Boy was a little dated, you know They weren't watching black and white anymore.
Scott: Everyone had to color TVs now, so they needed a color Astro Boy And that's what they did now.
Rym: I do want to point out that it says on the anime news network that the 1980s Astro Boy is rated all ages and quotes nothing Objectionable, well,
Scott: there's nothing Objectionable, but if you compare it, you know people right now if you go to the store They actually recently put out DVDs of early Sesame Street, right like 70 Sesame Street and it says on those DVDs This isn't actually appropriate for children, you know These are for old people to have nostalgia not for children to actually watch in place of modern Sesame Street.
Scott: And you know, there's some good stuff on there like learning to count and such right slowly slowly slowly getting faster, right?
Scott: But if you actually watch them like there is some stuff in there That's like oh and you remember the world was a different place in the 70s And Stuff that was appropriate then is not really appropriate now You know, I mean not all of it is timeless.
Rym: if I had one word to describe the 1980s Astro Boy It is rough.
Scott: It is really rough.
Scott: I mean basically what it is is there they are.
Scott: there's not really an objectional content, you know, it's it's cartoon.
Scott: You know blow stuff up violence.
Scott: It's you know, there's no sex at all.
Scott: No, you know, no, you know and you know, the thing is is the morals of this.
Scott: every, you know Every episode of course has a moral right just like the manga and in the old show and everything.
Scott: but the morals are Very sort of serious and adult a lot more serious than the morals you'll get in like the GI Joe Episode streak where the moral of every episode was basically Astro Boy crying.
Rym: Why did humans make us this way the end?
Scott: Pretty much the what every episode has sort of a temporary character who will die who will die Tragically, you know or something terrible happened.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: and so for example There was an episode where the there was a robot who wanted to be president of some small country, right?
Scott: And there was an evil guy who hated robots who wanted to stop him.
Scott: But actually it turned out that evil guy was the guy who made the robot president and he died.
Rym: Who?
Rym: the robot president or the guy?
Rym: the guy See, I think what Astro Boy 1980s first off is fantastic.
Rym: I highly recommend if you're an anime fan watch it with a group of other anime fans.
Rym: Yeah, I mean it is.
Rym: it's a children's show and you'll watch it.
Rym: It's obvious It is a children's show and if you're watching it alone, you probably wouldn't get that much out of it.
Rym: But there's something about giving the over/under on How long it's gonna take for the character they show you to die horribly at Astro Boy's hands.
Scott: Yeah, actually I sort of think you know, there are a lot of Astro Boys you could watch including the yet-to-be-released CG movie.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So the thing is here, let me do the manga right, you know while you should read some of the manga I mean Dark Horse recently combined volumes one and two into a single book, you know I have that but I don't have any other volumes.
Scott: That's actually like, you know, you should read that to get the history of it.
Scott: but reading the old Astro Boy manga It's not Tezuka's like, you know mad.
Scott: He didn't have his full skills, especially early on You know, so it's it's not Must walk as mortal men at first until they attain their god, of course.
Scott: So it's not really like the most polished amazing thing.
Scott: You know, you're getting the seas gets the stories across.
Scott: There's some good artworks in there But really it's not you know gonna give you the full effect.
Scott: right you can watch the old 60s show Which is also I recommend you do that at least a little bit right, but it is horrendously dated.
Scott: It's like watching like, you know, mr.
Scott: Magoo or some other incredibly old, you know, even older to that cartoons.
Scott: You know, it's just so old and and so cheaply animated and choppy that you know It's not really gonna give you the full experience.
Scott: It's just giving you this sort of Historical experience.
Rym: but Astro Boy 1980 is.
Rym: I mean We're not going to talk about the newer Astro Boys because a lot of people what I hear from most people is that?
Rym: The new Astro Boy TV is really good.
Rym: But the dub is like painful to the point of agony.
Scott: Yes, and the thing is is you the new Astro Boy 2004?
Scott: I think you can get the whole thing on DVD in the US for like 20 bucks, but it's dub only.
Scott: So and I heard the dub is terrible.
Scott: So what are you supposed to do?
Scott: This is great new Astro Boy from 2004, but you can't watch it because it's only dubbed and the dub is terrible There's no subs.
Rym: So the answer is to watch the 1980s Astro Boy.
Scott: That is correct.
Rym: It's one thing.
Rym: you'll look at it and it looks better than American cartoons from the late 80s Even the early 90s even the mid 90s.
Scott: Yeah, I mean think about it Super Mario Brothers Super Show, right 90s Guess what.
Scott: this 80s Astro Boy from 1980 looks a lot better than that Whole lot better.
Rym: and if you don't if you don't remember the Super Mario Brothers Super Show and you think that if you have any respect for it, I commend I recommend that you go and Experience what it is to see that through the eyes of an adult.
Scott: I mean this thing has the animation quality of like Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles, which is like, you know middle 90s ish, right?
Scott: So and this is for 1980 eight zero.
Scott: Yeah, not 80s 80.
Scott: Yeah, so That's pretty damn good right there considering it's a you know, a TV show.
Scott: but now it's Astro Boy.
Scott: So they give it the full effort.
Rym: now It is a reimagining like a reset.
Rym: so it starts off at the very beginning.
Rym: and the thing about the 1980s Astro Boy because I said before it's rough.
Rym: the overview is thus a Scientist a robot scientist has a son that he neglects because he's so engrossed in his work.
Rym: The son after having a fight with his dad dies in a car accident alone and angry.
Rym: The dad so distraught remakes this job this killing robot he was making into a replica of his child and tries to raise it as though his son had never died.
Rym: and Then as the robot does not act exactly like his son.
Rym: He comes to hate it and eventually cast it away from his sight.
Rym: That is how Astro Boy begins.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, it's sort of weird, right?
Scott: It's it's that usually you see a story and it'll be like a scientist and an accompanying robot or monster Whatever it is, right and the scientist is usually the maker, right?
Scott: But meanwhile an Astro Boy asteroids maker like add to the first few episodes.
Scott: He's not there anymore.
Scott: It's like he made Astro Boy and cast him out and dr.
Scott: Elephant slash Oh China Mizzou, whatever his real name is, right?
Scott: He's the one taking care of Astro Boy.
Scott: He's the head of the Ministry of Science.
Scott: But if he if someone told him hey make a new make a copy of Astro, but he can't make a robot that good.
Rym: Yeah, I mean your rain she's nothing.
Scott: Yeah, he made your rain.
Scott: Your rain is not as you know, he made Astro Boy's family.
Scott: They're pretty stock They're not.
Scott: they're not Astro Boy quality.
Rym: Astro Boy's got some rice.
Rym: He's got some rims.
Scott: Yeah He's got a turbo and a supercharger.
Rym: and well, he's got a butt gun.
Scott: Yeah, but good That's the hardest part is the butt gun.
Scott: But don't shit your pants.
Rym: But and taking it from there Here at the trope, you know We used to watch Horatio hornblower as a group when we were in college.
Rym: Like we all get around and we turn on Horatio hornblower and yell and scream.
Rym: You want to watch her as your hornblower kinda after the show and take odds on who's gonna die and who's not gonna die.
Rym: And that's the bad guy.
Rym: That's the good guy.
Rym: explosions and we get all into it.
Rym: and Astro Boy is the same thing because every episode they introduce a sympathetic character and they are either going to die Tragically before or after learning their lesson.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And then Asher was just left to stand there wondering why humans made them this way.
Rym: and that's the end.
Scott: yep, it is some things that right.
Scott: first of all a lot of the stories in this are pretty much the majority of the stories if Not all of them are actually retellings of stories from the manga or the older the 60s anime but they're retold in a Easier to watch way that doesn't feel dated, you know, it holds up over time Whereas the 60s one sort of doesn't hold up so much, you know.
Scott: but the 80s one, you know, it tells these stories in a watchable comprehensible in modern fashion.
Scott: and Here are some things that I really like.
Scott: number one Whenever there's like a problem, you know you watch say, you know, I don't know any American cartoon in most anime.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Scott: and when there's a problem They'll always like they'll be an easy solution, but everyone just stands around like an idiot.
Rym: It's like Resident Evil 4 every time the big bad guy appears.
Rym: You don't shoot him.
Rym: You stand there during a cutscene Exactly.
Scott: Astor boy like he was pinned down and immediately like punches through the wall and flies away like So many.
Rym: the solution to every problem.
Rym: I have learned from Astro boy is to punch it in the stomach until it dies.
Scott: Yeah I mean and thing is Astro boy like doesn't hesitate ever like he was like, oh this danger whoo.
Scott: She flies right out the house, you know flies right to where the danger is punches it right in the face And he think you know, it's like.
Scott: he doesn't hesitate.
Scott: He goes straight for it and fixes it right away.
Scott: It's like oh the aliens are bad.
Scott: Boom.
Scott: He starts punching the UFOs and blowing the hell out of him And he starts just murdering other robots when they come to.
Rym: like.
Rym: the only person he doesn't murder is skunk.
Rym: That bothers me because skunk deserves it more than everyone else in this.
Scott: Yeah, it's like there's all these people that he you know, he sort of reluctantly murders like.
Scott: he's like, oh, you're a robot you're misbehaving You know, but you know and you're.
Scott: we need you to stop and you won't agree, but you're not evil You're sort of sympathetic But we can't let you continue and astro boy ends up murdering them or they end up dying.
Scott: Or even though I asked her boy didn't want him to die.
Scott: I just wanted him to stop.
Scott: but meanwhile the skunk who is like You know an evil mobster who continues to just do bad thing after bad thing after bad thing Astor boy doesn't kill him.
Scott: He just like lets him go all the time.
Rym: Well, no, they always arrest him.
Rym: I figured that out later.
Rym: They did every time they kept skunk.
Rym: They always put him in jail, but then in the next episode He's out again.
Scott: Yeah, and Atlas is like the best villain ever because it's like he's the bad guy, but he's not totally the bad guy.
Scott: It's like he's not evil like skunk, but he's you know, he's sort of like Magneto almost, you know where he's bad, but he just so different and not really straight-up evil.
Scott: But like that's the way magneto supposed to be.
Scott: I mean people have written magneto as Straight up bad and those people don't know how to write.
Rym: what is the equivalent of watching something involving Star Wars and thinking why don't they?
Rym: Just lightsaber the fuck out of whatever it is that's causing them trouble.
Scott: Yeah You never have to answer that question with astro boy cuz.
Scott: if there's a problem can be solved by punching and shooting.
Rym: Asteroid punches and shoots immediately with like if there's a big bad monster like a big machine appears like there's one episode where a giant Robot comes to kick everybody's ass.
Rym: He just immediately punches its arm off punches inside of it and then punches all its guts until it dies.
Scott: Yep It's good stuff real good stuff.
Scott: I mean the thing is when you remember that this is like a cartoon for kids, right?
Scott: It's like okay, you know punching and exploding robots is okay for kids, right?
Scott: But like there'll be a robot who's effectively a human character and he punches a hole right through its chest and it like It dies.
Scott: and then you see astro by crying or you know Looking like he's gonna cry and the episodes over and it's like whoa This is a kids cartoon.
Rym: Don't forget humans get it just as often.
Scott:  yes The thing is humans technically don't die in the show.
Scott: But really like you'll see a manned like fighter jet explode and you won't see any parachutes.
Rym: Yeah, there's none of that GI Joe BS in this.
Scott: Yeah, so there are people who die But you just have to you don't notice.
Scott: unless you look closely and you realize oh shit like a hundred people just got Brutally murdered.
Rym: Well except for the episode where astro boys the captain of that ship.
Rym: Oh, that was a great ever see a lot of people die on screen in that one.
Rym: Yeah That still is my favorite episode.
Rym: basically that was a really good one because you know The whole thing is Astro boy takes the immediate direct action.
Rym: He's always right.
Rym: He never lies.
Rym: He's pretty much perfect in every way.
Rym: That's kind of the moral of the show, you know, he's made to be good.
Rym: So he's good and he can't be but good.
Rym: but in that episode he's appointed captain of this expedition to Mars and Right away someone in the crew is like a damn robot Can't be the boss of me and astro boys responses basically shut your human face and do what I say.
Scott: Oh, yeah, that was that was great.
Rym: But astro I've checked the thingy a thousand times and it's flying.
Rym: check it again.
Rym: But sir, there's no need.
Rym: I said check it again That's right.
Scott: What gives them the business?
Rym: but then the guy tries to murder astro boy and that doesn't work.
Rym: No Right just comes back face.
Rym: That's what the best scene.
Rym: when astro boy makes it back to the ship He's like, I need to see you in my office right now.
Scott: It's like you're getting told what to do by what appears to be a little kid and is effectively a little kid.
Scott: I mean, he's a relatively new robot.
Scott: I mean, what's he?
Scott: not even a few years old Right.
Scott: He's just wicked powerful and he's a robot.
Scott: So he's wicked smart and he's in a body that looks like a kid robot, you know Really astro boys parents are younger than astro boy.
Rym: Think about that Plus just the fact that his parents kind of nominally control him.
Scott: But anytime something serious goes on he just punches a hole in the wall and leaves well, cuz really, you know, his parents are just there to sort of you know, if you think about it on sort of a meta level.
Scott: right what the show doesn't say is that the reason astro boy has a family is that he can Sort of live a simulated human life and be more empathetic with the human race and such and such and thus He won't be no turn out to be one of those robots.
Scott: He goes crazy and kills everyone and that's why you know He's all he likes humans.
Scott: if you didn't have a family and he was just living with you know The doctor and being a robot of science He'd be a lot more like some of the other robots you see in the show like, you know, who are just assistants And
Rym: daddy walrus would have straightened him out.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, that's you know, that's why he sent to school and such like that.
Scott: You know where you don't?
Scott: you don't see other robots doing these things.
Scott: you only see astro boy doing these things so much.
Rym: but I guess the real joy of this show is to watch it with a group of people who are in anime in some fashion and To just revel in what is good about the show and what is bad or doesn't make sense.
Scott: Yeah, I mean we're watching the dub on Netflix.
Scott: I haven't watched a sub.
Rym: if there is one the dub works just fine.
Scott: Yeah, the dub.
Scott: I mean there are some parts in the dub that are sort of ungood.
Rym: What is wrong with you?
Scott: Astro a lot of it is when someone's obviously trying to match lip flaps or there's a temporary character Who has a bad actor.
Scott: but astro boys voice is really good.
Scott: you get you know After a couple episodes whoever's voice acting him is doing a great job.
Scott: You know, the professor is due as a great voice, you know Rain has sort of a bad voice needs to work on that kind of works because she's kind of messed up.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, I mean, you know The voices are alright, you know, it's it's a. it's a good as dub as you're gonna get for that kind of thing.
Scott: You know, it's not quite as good as a cow bebop dub, but it's better than much better than the average dub and It's just fine.
Scott: If that's you know, if you're gonna Netflix stream it go for it, you know No reason to buy DVDs just to get the subtitles if you don't have to.
Rym: Yep I mean I'd highly recommend it.
Rym: if you're an anime fan at least watch like the first ten episodes of this to see what we're talking about.
Scott: And the key to getting the full enjoyment is just really think about exactly what you're watching.
Scott: You know notice like when something like heart and then think this is a kids show, right?
Scott: so when they go in to arrest the guy who with it in the death balloon episode and he points a gun at his head and Then they have to start that asteroids like run and grab the gun or whatever to keep him from killing himself Remember that was a show for like little kids.
Rym: Even better is the man.
Scott: the entertainment value goes way up when you think about that.
Rym: if you take everything at face value I mean a lot of times the show the show is weird and that much of the time It makes a lot more sense than other Anime or other TV shows in general at face value because there's a problem.
Rym: Astro boy like say he finds out where the bad guy is.
Rym: The next scene is him flying into their hideout and punching all of them Like immediately just cuts right to him busting into the ceiling.
Rym: He does takes the immediate direct action all the time But at the same time they'll just take all the kids in the elementary school class and send him on a field trip Unguarded into space.
Rym: Yep And then they lose contact with it and they don't have any like plan or means to save them whatsoever.
Scott: Well, Astro boys up there, but other than that they got nothing.
Rym: Those kids almost died in the cold vacuum of space like four times.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, there's a lot of.
Scott: there's a lot of.
Scott: you know, sort of sometimes the premises of the episodes are a little screwed up But what happens within the context of the screwed up premise is never screwed up.
Rym: if that makes any sense I guess I enjoy the show and I expect you would too.
Rym: and even if you don't it's a part of anime history.
Rym: You should at least have seen some of all the Astro.
Scott: if you're gonna watch an Astro Boy TV show You know like a lot, you know watch a little bit of the 60s one So you get your history read, you know, some of the manga.
Scott: so you get the deal with that.
Scott: You don't need to read all the volumes plus.
Scott: there's way too many of them and they're hard to get.
Scott: You know relatively hard to get.
Scott: the newer series like we said terrible dub.
Scott: So, you know, it's if you can get it subtitled by all means watch that.
Scott: it's supposedly awesome even though I've never seen it.
Scott: But I've heard the dub was terrible.
Scott: But if you're gonna watch a whole Astro Boy This 80s one is where it's at.
Rym: On that note we could watch another episode.
Rym: We're actually only about.
Rym: we're a little over halfway through it right now.
Rym: There's 52 episodes of it.
Rym: That's it.
Scott: That's a pretty good number I think because it's.
Scott: it's like a limited series, but it's not too short and since it's you know, very episodic But there are some sort of you know, continuing plot threads.
Scott: It's like Like think about Voltron.
Scott: right when you watch Voltron Every single episode of Voltron is pretty much they're always fighting You know row beasts that come from the biggest bet, you know, the only bet only villain is only one villain.
Rym: They always happen to solve the problem just before the end of the episode right in Astro Boy, right?
Scott: Every episode is sort of its own thing, but like there are so many episodes with Atlas in them So Atlas you'll get like an Atlas episode like once every five episodes or once every ten or something, you know, they're interspersed.
Scott: So it's like there's this Atlas storyline.
Scott: now Usually in like modern shonen stuff when you have a storyline with a villain all the episodes will be clumped up like so in Naruto.
Scott: It's like first ten episodes fight the guy with the big sword.
Scott: Next ten episodes fight the guy with the ninja stars, you know.
Scott: next ten episodes fight, you know It's like that or like one piece right.
Scott: first We fight the clown, you know in this arc and then we fight this right in Astro Boy The arc is spread out.
Scott: So there's the Atlas arc, but the Atlas arc isn't all at once.
Scott: It's not like ten episodes in a row of Atlas.
Scott: It's ten episodes spread out over the series of Atlas.
Scott: You know, it's like he comes and he goes.
Scott: it's ten episodes spread out over the series of skunk.
Scott: You know, he comes and he goes and I kind of like it more that way.
Scott: It's more like a cowboy bebop kind of thing.
Scott: You know, it's like vicious is spread out over the series.
Scott: It's not all at once and I think that actually gives a lot more power to.
Scott: you know, the character You know, that is the the villain in the in the series then putting them all together does plus It's just one thing it.
Rym: that really strikes me if nothing else and I hope it strikes you too that you watch this and you compare it to American television aimed at a similar audience in America, you know children of that age at that time and You can just.
Rym: it's so much more mature and real and kids learn a lot more from Astro Boy than they will for most of The cartoons that were on in 1980 in America.
Scott: Yeah Astro Boy.
Scott: It just you know, it's got.
Scott: basically it's got you know Three elements going on, you know, it's got the element of quality animation, right?
Scott: It's got the element of Science fiction and it's got the element of Non-simplistic morality and that's those are the three things Astro Boy has.
Rym: I mean It's like the different off not combined like a kid watching GI Joe versus a kid watching Macross.
Rym: Yep, exactly Maybe if we had more intelligent programming for kids, they'd do better.
Scott: Probably yeah, of course Avatar course, you know, it also helped a lot better if we didn't program.
Rym: Yeah, well now we have to program them.
Rym: I mean look no the moral of Astro Boy if we program them completely they're all perfect.
Rym: Yeah because robots never do bad on their own.
Rym: either someone makes them that way or they're completely sentient and self-moving and even when they You know do make them wrong.
Scott: Sometimes they're smart enough to do right in the end anyway.
Rym: But then they get exploded after falling into lava.
Scott: anyway Learn their lesson they're gonna.
Scott: they're about you know If someone is bad and then they learn that they were wrong and they repent or whatever.
Scott: they immediately die.
Rym: Oh my god, the worst was the Robeo and Robeo episode.
Scott: That one was harsh.
Rym: Everyone died except the two people who were responsible.
Scott: Yeah It's like basically what happens is the peep, you know, there's always the.
Scott: the good people are always You know tragic and they die.
Scott: but then the actual villains rather than die they're made to watch the Tragedy and and then they're forced to continue living and that is their suffering.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website if you like what you hear.
Rym: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.