Rym: Hey, it's Monday September 28th.
Rym: I'm ready.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight I cop out.
Rym: we bring you the tech news round up.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: And we're back from her last convention for a while now.
Rym: We can just kind of chill until what packs.
Rym: well We got a. we got a move.
Rym: I'm only talking about conventions.
Rym: We don't have any big conventions that are in the next couple of weeks.
Scott: There's actually this There's some stuff in the in the coming weeks.
Scott: There's a yahoo hack day thing that I'm going to.
Scott: probably not you got I don't know.
Scott: you got to sign up and get accepted Whatever.
Scott: There's also there's a GD GT They event that's gonna happen in the city on October 1st.
Scott: I think it's 7 p.m Yeah, probably not going to that.
Scott: I'm gonna check it out.
Scott: cuz they got big-time Sponsors like like all sorts like Microsoft and Sony and like it's gonna be big booths and everything like a mini CES.
Rym: almost it's on a Thursday night some tech thing Yep, and then I got stuff to do.
Rym: I'll check it, but I bring that up mostly because I know many new people are probably here after the New York anime festival, so We mentioned this.
Rym: remember GeekNights is four different shows and you're listening to the lint the neckbeard Linux show.
Rym: No I would recommend coming back on Wednesday when we'll talk about the New York anime festival and anime manga comics all the stuff you probably Expect.
Scott: I would not recommend coming back on Wednesday.
Scott: if you're a New York anime festival person you Hopefully know about anime and you don't really need to listen to Wednesday Even though you probably will learn something on Wednesday because we probably know more than you.
Scott: However odds are You don't know too much about technology.
Scott: if I know anime fans is actually surprising how few of them are technically knowledgeable.
Scott: Therefore you should listen to the Monday shows and learn about the technology which affects every person who lives in The entire world regardless of your interest.
Rym: just care about anime.
Rym: come on Wednesday.
Rym: We'll talk about anime.
Rym: Yeah, I've been watching some anime.
Scott: I haven't watched any anime.
Scott: It's all video games and board games I've been watching.
Rym: so of course I look everything got derailed when I started reading one of my trashy Temeraire novels.
Scott: Why are you eating trash?
Rym: It's good trash.
Scott: I'm all reading erudite stuff.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Mr.
Rym: Has seen all of initial D.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: I didn't say always.
Scott: I said now So I didn't say for the.
Scott: I didn't say forever either.
Rym: Since we're doing the the periodic tech news Roundup we're not gonna do any news in the first half of the show because that would be kind of stupid.
Rym: We what we do two news have a break and then just do a bunch more news.
Scott: Yeah, that's no good.
Scott: Plus we'll run out of news if we do that.
Rym: I got plenty of news.
Scott: All right.
Scott: But anyway, yeah I got a a little rant, you know, what really grind Scott's gears why we got to use someone else's, you know It's like but this is the bull There's grinding gears.
Scott: So what do we have?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: you want to call it when you want something I don't know.
Scott: It's a call it something but all the good ones are taken, you know, we can grant and whatever.
Scott: so basically the thing you know, what's?
Scott: I've noticed a lot of people lately as in the past year a few right they really really complain about.
Scott: you know This application is a resource hog.
Scott: Oh, it's not light.
Scott: Oh, it's using too many.
Scott: It's it's got using too much RAM.
Rym: Yeah Right, I wouldn't say that's a recent phenomenon.
Scott: Well, it doesn't matter.
Rym: I've noticed it was even worse back in the day when it was a serious problem.
Rym: I know if I open more than three IE browsers My computer would cry.
Rym: and you have.
Scott: you have approached the crux of my point here Right?
Scott: is that I've noticed these complaints more and more frequently.
Scott: like people will use one program That is like less feature-rich over another because it's lighter or because they have this perception of it, right?
Scott: That it seems lighter or they see it using less RAM on the RAM meter or it takes up less disk space.
Scott: All right.
Scott: First of all, if you have a computer that doesn't really have enough RAM to run modern application Just buy some more RAM buy some more goddamn RAM.
Rym: It's like five dollars.
Rym: boys this out.
Rym: my computer, you know I made a badass computer Years ago.
Rym: It's obviously not that badass anymore.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I'm only using about 30% of my RAM and that includes the cache right now.
Rym: Yeah, I've got four gigs of RAM.
Rym: I'm using almost none of it, right?
Rym: I mean I see both my cores are practically idle.
Scott: I mean think about it if you want and if anything right you want it to use more RAM, right?
Scott: It's like you got four gigs of RAM Like I do.
Scott: if only you're using two There's two going to waste.
Scott: your computer could be using those other two to go even faster.
Scott: and that's actually if using Linux Don't worry, you're all.
Scott: Linux automatically uses all your RAM as much as it possibly Aggressive disk cache.
Rym: I'm just noting Windows does not even in Linux.
Rym: right now I'm using less than 33% of my RAM including the cache.
Rym: I just have so much RAM.
Scott: I know Okay, so that's number one.
Scott: number two disk space.
Rym: Oh, one of my cores is doing something now.
Scott: drives are so So cheap you could get like terabytes for nothing.
Scott: So if a program takes up like a hundred more megs than the competitor That is not a reason to pick one over the other.
Scott: a hundred megs is so such a small amount of disk space.
Scott: I don't even notice it.
Scott: It's like effectively invisible.
Scott: Number three it is true that some programs just faster than others I mean Chrome is just faster than Firefox.
Scott: that I mean it.
Scott: it just is right.
Scott: It's you know, they're benchmarks to prove it.
Scott: But don't go by just your perception.
Scott: a lot of times you will perceive Something to be faster.
Scott: they it feels faster they say.
Scott: but then an actual benchmark shows.
Scott: No, it's just your perception.
Scott: Well, it's tricky because benchmark, you know, some UI element makes it seem lighter or seem faster.
Rym: Well one.
Rym: I would argue that unless you're doing large amounts of data processing Perception probably matters more than the benchmark, especially because most benchmarks are not terribly accurate to actual use cases.
Scott: No, no, but you can actually have you know, like, you know, UI And benchmarks.
Rym: as opposed to you know, a lot of benchmarks will just do like the render time or stuff like that If you've got an application that is measurably faster in the UI than another application and yet people perceive the other slower Application to be faster.
Rym: You have done something wrong.
Scott: Yeah, your application is doing something wrong.
Rym: Yes, but that's important.
Rym: especially, you know, we love open source software, but often not the best user interfaces.
Rym: Yeah GIMP.
Rym: I'm looking at you.
Rym: Anyway, I used to think that GIMP was a good interface.
Rym: then I watched someone who knew how to draw try to use the GIMP for more than five minutes.
Scott: Yeah, but the thing is, you know, anyway, we're not gonna get it.
Scott: Do it go down that road.
Scott: That's not the road.
Scott: We're going down.
Rym: That's Thursday.
Scott: My point is right is that when you you know, a lot of people, you know, it's okay to choose Chrome over Firefox Right, but it's because it's faster, which it is.
Scott: Don't go telling me you're using Chrome over Firefox because it uses less RAM You're not you?
Scott: unless you're using all of your RAM and you have no money to buy more right?
Scott: That's the only person who has a valid complaint about how much RAM it's using, right?
Scott: Maybe this is you know stability if you can measure, you know that.
Scott: yes This is crashing more than that other one, you know, and you can tell that the crashing isn't your fault.
Rym: Well one more which often is one possible but unlikely case is the low-power netbook That is true.
Rym: But then again, you're using all your RAM and you can't get more.
Rym: So there you go.
Scott: So, you know a lot of people they're just they're like picking, you know Which after deciding which application to use based on like these completely irrational factors of you know Some perceived increased resource usage.
Rym: Well at the same time, you know in my line of work This actually affects me To a great degree because one, you know, we a problem we will sometimes run into is that a trader, you know We're a stock kind of company.
Rym: Well, you install our application and complain that it's too much of a load on their system But we know how much load our application puts on someone's system and it's basically nothing.
Scott: Yeah it uses basically Gooey with a few buttons like effectively the same as like a visual basic app with some network data traffic.
Rym: It's a more complicated than that.
Rym: We have different things but regardless the actual reason for that as I've discovered is that in the stock world?
Rym: there's something called an OMS an order management system and that is what like The big bad trader at a company like manages all the or it's like the Bloomberg machine.
Rym: Nah, Bloomberg machine is something different.
Rym: Okay, but an OMS would be like McGregor Charles River.
Scott: So this is like it's basically a screen full of numbers I'm guessing.
Rym: basically an OMS is the thing where like the head trader of a company will put in like I Want my company to buy 10 million of this 10 million of that 100 million of that 40 million of that.
Rym: I only want to pay this much for that as much, you know All that stuff.
Rym: and then they allocate chunks of all this stuff to all their traders and then the traders Go and get it done in their little OMS is get these tickets of.
Rym: you know Get this done.
Rym: and then they use their discretion of duties.
Rym: Let me tell you are these things, you know The words resource intensive never meant much to me even in all the data processing that processing and audio and video have done in my life.
Rym: Until I loaded one of these bastards on my computer at work four gigs of RAM quad-core Brought to its knees for like two minutes while one of these things loads up And it was using all the resources.
Scott: See now that is a valid complaint right there, you know, but like, you know, I watch some of these stock traders.
Rym: They'll have like five monitors and like this quad-core like eight gigabyte 64-bit monster of a machine And they're still complaining about how slow it is.
Scott: I mean that that that tells me the application just poorly written because there's no reason that a program that just you know Does stock stuff should take up that much resource.
Rym: Well, you'd be surprised.
Rym: I mean think about the logistics of for example, say you have an application right?
Rym: Consuming market data.
Rym: It's not just you know, what do you I mean?
Rym: What do you think stock prices are?
Rym: It's not like.
Rym: there's just like this.
Rym: is the price now this?
Scott: yeah But that's see.
Scott: what I'm saying is that it's a poor architecture, right?
Scott: If you need like market data consumed and you have a trading company or like, you know Whatever, you should have some sort of centralized powerhouse machine that's doing that.
Rym: So it consumes it.
Rym: How do I get it from there to me?
Scott: and then the machine that you're sitting at is only getting the data it needs From your big nasty server in the closet.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So what data do I need there?
Rym: There are multiple levels of the order book for at any second.
Rym: the market data Problem.
Scott: it sounds to me like.
Scott: the problem though is the desktop is doing all the work and getting the data feed right into it.
Rym: That's not really the problem.
Rym: The problem is that even if you have big bad machines to get it and parse it there's still just so much data Mm-hmm, and you also you have to deal with it.
Rym: What if you're trying to route out to like algos or something like that?
Scott: Anyway, the point is but no the architecture.
Rym: But it's not crap for the reasons you'd expect.
Scott: when you're deciding, you know When you're choosing between various applications like you're choosing your browser, you're choosing your media player.
Scott: You're choosing your whatever, right?
Scott: base your decisions upon Rational factors and not things like.
Scott: it uses 10 more megs of RAM.
Scott: Oh, no That means it's worse because usually it's using those 10 megs of RAM for like some feature.
Scott: That's probably worth it.
Rym: Well, if you fall down that trap I mean I remember when the screen on my laptop just stopped working one day and I actually got it repaired for free under the warranty.
Rym: I was shocked.
Rym: I expected to have to pay like a thousand dollars to fix that Yep, and I got it all fixed.
Rym: But the tech who fixed it like he got it all done and first he pretended that it was gonna cost me like 900 bucks and then after I was like god damn it.
Rym: I went to pay.
Rym: he's like nah, I just fucking with you Yeah, but then he was like, you know now he was obviously a bait-and-swing.
Rym: He pulls the RAM out of my laptop.
Rym: My laptop has two gigs of RAM on one stick Mm-hmm, and he's like you got three slots here.
Rym: feel how hot that RAM is because you only have one stick if you buy Two more two gig sticks.
Rym: It'll even it out.
Rym: And I was like, yeah, thanks for fixing my laptop.
Rym: Give me my computer back with that Ram back in there.
Scott: Yeah, Ram is hot we know.
Rym: plus I'm like you realize how long it'll take for me to hibernate my computer with six gigs of RAM.
Rym: Yeah So true, yeah, so I you know, I have an opposite rant.
Rym: I have the exact opposite of a rant.
Rym: You see I led a very privileged life and until after I had graduated high school I never in my life held a job.
Rym: the closest thing to a job I ever had was like marching band in high school or I remember I used to charge local kids 15 bucks a half hour for Trumpet lessons and but I never had an actual job and I left Kyle.
Rym: I left all right.
Rym: God.
Rym: I keep thinking like college.
Rym: I left high school.
Rym: I had that summer of nothing.
Rym: So I decided I should get a job and get some money.
Rym: So I applied to work for the US Census the census 2000.
Rym: I was a payroll clerk and HR clerk and I did a bunch of other crazy stuff for the census for that whole summer and Let me tell you to this day.
Rym: It was one of the most fun jobs I ever had like.
Rym: working for the US Census was so unlike what I expected.
Rym: Pretty much everyone working there was cool because for the most part These were people who didn't need to work who wanted to work for fun.
Rym: They were like housewives who were like I'll get out of the house and work for the census and do a good thing and save the world and said to stop It's all cool.
Rym: And I was thinking about it and I'm not really in a position to work for the 2010 census.
Rym: I haven't even though I still have a letter of recommendation from like the regional director of the part of the census I worked for him.
Rym: They basically decided I was a badass and they were like if you want to work for the census in 2010 You can like run a regional office.
Scott: No, I wonder how much that pays.
Rym: not that much.
Rym: Do you leave absence to do that as much as I would like to?
Rym: They're not going to pay me even a fraction of what I make in my stock market stuff.
Scott: Yeah, but you would count things.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, but one thing I can say.
Scott: you thought you could send guys out and say listen There's five crab people living in Hudson Valley.
Scott: I was paid.
Rym: I worked 40 hours a week for that summer.
Rym: I was paid $11.35 an hour.
Rym: That's pretty good in for the year 2000 in Year $2,000.
Rym: That was a lot of money Yeah I mean.
Rym: and the thing is I think back and I remember when I got my first paycheck and it was like 400 bucks and I'm looking at this and I realized how much money this was.
Rym: It was all mine video games.
Rym: That's why I came to RIT.
Scott: That's why I got a job in high school as soon as I was legally able to and that is why I was able to buy computers and video games and all sorts of other stuff.
Scott: It's got privileged life.
Scott: My parents bought me all that stuff and that's why I am very glad I did not.
Scott: I was done playing Magic the Gathering by The time I was able to get a job.
Rym: Magic cards were just like swords.
Rym: It's a damn fucking good thing.
Rym: You never had money when you wanted Magic cards.
Scott: When I got a job I was tired of Magic the Gathering and I was tired of all stupid crap like that.
Scott: And all I wanted was computers and video games.
Rym: I used that money for one thing.
Rym: that job is why when I went to RIT I showed up with a $4,000 computer.
Rym: I mean, I had the baddest as computer in the world when I got to RIT.
Scott: It's also the first thing I did when I had my job, you know in high school working at the dry-cleaner.
Rym: See, that's another benefit.
Scott: I saved up and bought a Pentium 3 450 megahertz.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: Yeah, I remember I bought like an AMD like 900 megahertz with that thing.
Scott: It lasted a long time until I replaced it with that AMD and then I replaced the AMD with what I have.
Rym: now I'm only on my third desktop in my whole life.
Rym: Third.
Scott: God, let's see I had the 486 but that really wasn't.
Scott: that was a family computer.
Rym: Yeah, my first computer that I bought was that AMD 900 and then I bought the computer I'm using now.
Scott: You're only on number two.
Rym: Yeah, well in between remember my motherboard blew up, but that was an incremental upgrade.
Rym: Yeah, I went up to a Thunderbird.
Scott: I've had plenty of upgrades adding drives and all that, you know RAM and who knows what.
Rym: so Yep, yep, but what point of advice?
Rym: the first for all you nerds out there and all you punk kids.
Rym: you want some money.
Rym: Work for the census.
Rym: they pay real well, and you basically don't have to do any work at all.
Rym: It's just super fun.
Rym: Everyone's cool and they need tech people and the test you take to work for the census Basically amounts to can you breathe and can you add two two-digit numbers to each other?
Rym: Hmm You would be surprised how many people fail this test.
Rym: Yep Well, or you might not be depending on you know, yeah that was that was one of the first points when Rym became very cynical.
Scott: So, you know Rym was talking about the census and I was like man.
Scott: Census needs to get more technologies going on.
Rym: Yeah, Scott's like where's the fucking API for this?
Rym: probably like some busted old database.
Rym: He's really down on it.
Rym: So we go to the census website, you know census gov.
Rym: There's just API's open source tools.
Rym: You can get it all the data.
Rym: You can download.
Scott: there is a public domain Software package for the census and I'm like, oh shit I am all over this action.
Scott: But you know people always braille all these all these open source guys like probably don't even know about this Like everyone's ignoring it.
Scott: I'm so gonna rock the house.
Rym: I mean since this API the US government is generally very behind the times very crap when it comes to technology.
Rym: But there are tiny pieces of it that are very very well run and it the census of the United States is One of the coolest things our government does.
Rym: and it amazes me the amount of wargling and bullshit that the Republican Party basically is pulling out of the woodwork this year and I think I know why this is more Thursday.
Rym: But I want to point out to everyone out there The right-wing and the Republicans are basically getting to the point where they may.
Rym: a lot of people may boycott the census or fight against It even though the census is one of the few things that's actually directly in the Constitution.
Scott: Yeah, it says right in the Constitution not even in a law or anything else.
Scott: in the Constitution It says there shall be a census every ten years now to count the people with.
Scott: those aren't the exact words.
Scott: The gray has the word sense.
Rym: The greatest part about all this is that one part of the reason I think the right-wing is scared Is that in America there has been a huge shift in population toward, you know liberal places and cities and things.
Rym: and Also, there's been a big shift away from a lot of places where Republicans had majorities.
Rym: and one thing the census does for people They don't live in the United States.
Rym: Is that every time we do it That determines how many you know seats in the House of Representatives different states get how many votes they get in the Electoral College.
Rym: There's a good chance that all the so-called blue states are gonna get a bunch of seats and votes And all the so-called red states are gonna lose a bunch of seats and votes and they don't want that to happen.
Rym: However by boycotting the census the people who are losing the votes are basically saying don't count me Don't count me.
Scott: Do not find one less representative for you.
Rym: I can imagine the census 2010.
Rym: They're like, yeah, there are only eight people living in Kentucky.
Rym: Well, they only get one seat this year But we got two senators.
Rym: though if you're a punk kid and you have free time you need a job work for the census.
Rym: It's badass.
Rym: I still have my badge Not on purpose.
Rym: I actually lost it and got another one because you have to give the badge back.
Rym: Obviously It's like the scary-looking federal government badge.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And then I found like three or four years ago the one I'd lost.
Rym: Uh-huh, so I've got it.
Rym: I'm not gonna scan it in or show it to anyone because I shouldn't have it but it's really cool.
Rym: Got a federal seal on it.
Rym: If I ever really need to scam someone that thing will so come in handy.
Scott: You could go and pretend to be a census worker right now and then someone like it visited twice And then I'll probably get visited by the FBI Probably.
Rym: But if you're a nerd and you don't have time to work for the census Go check out all their open-source API data sets and do something cool like a mashup with Google Maps or something Google charts.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: before we get into the things of the day.
Rym: We were at a pretty cool gizmodo thing in the city over the weekend.
Scott: Oh, yeah gizmodo the website had this gizmodo gallery sort of a temporary mini museum Downtown in New York City, so, you know, we were in town for the New York Anime Festival on Saturday and we're like Hey, let's go down and check this gizmodo gallery while it's there.
Scott: So we go down and check it out and it was well worth our time.
Rym: the coolest thing.
Rym: We're walking tomorrow day.
Rym: We weren't like.
Rym: we knew pretty much where it was, but we didn't know like exactly.
Rym: So we're walking down the street and we see a crowd outside a building.
Scott: We're like that must be it.
Rym: and as we walk up in the distance We hear music and the first thing I think is that sounds a lot like Tesla coils and we get there.
Rym: There's a Tesla coil concert going on.
Rym: yeah, and the funny thing is you know, we just Emily and Alex had come with us to PAX and as we're walking up we See this crowd Emily's like.
Rym: that looks a lot like the crowd from PAX and I'm like, that's probably the gizmodo crowd.
Rym: It's mostly the same kind of crowd.
Rym: Yep All these hipster looking people wearing black and geeky t-shirts and being all hip.
Rym: Everyone has like all their smartphones out taking pictures of the Tesla coils.
Scott: That's the PAX crowd.
Rym: There was some really cool stuff there.
Rym: I the mud computer the the first Walkman.
Scott: Yeah, the first Walkman ever one of the first VCRs ever like this engineering model from JVC.
Scott: All sorts of crazy.
Rym: I gotta say the first Walkman was surprisingly impressive.
Rym: It was awesome primarily because you look at it and you're like you.
Rym: think about the Walkman like when we got him.
Scott: It was one of the better Walkman though Some of the later ones were cheap and crappy.
Scott: Sitting with Discman like I had this awesome old Discman.
Scott: but over time the Discman they just made him shittier and shittier.
Scott: They didn't make them better.
Rym: the original Walkman When the further revolution of the world when people were like carry music with you is So small and well engineered that today.
Rym: I would not feel that bad carrying something that lot size around.
Scott: It's made of metal.
Scott: serious business.
Scott: The original iPod has an actual wheel that actually spins, you know, the first Walkman's and even continuing.
Rym: in Japan They just by default had two ports for headphones in case you wanted to share music with a friend.
Rym: Where the fuck is that on my iPod?
Scott: That's right.
Rym: I got to use some crap splitter.
Scott: Yep, I mean it would take up some room in that incredibly small iPod, but even so I mean, you know It doesn't have that much room.
Scott: It's totally worth it.
Rym: Yep Anyway, it was cool.
Rym: I don't know what else I can say.
Rym: We'll link to like a gallery.
Rym: I mean, I didn't take any pictures.
Rym: There were so many people with smartphones taking pictures.
Scott: Yeah, one cool thing they had was a little stand where you could try out all the best of each Smartphone one for each operating system.
Scott: So there's six smartphones.
Rym: I love techie people, you know anime cons, whatever.
Rym: But at this kind, you know at this little gallery event I stood there and debated with like four people the merits of all the phones for like ten minutes and everyone was smart.
Scott: They had a 3d Etch A Sketch.
Rym: They had a 3d Etch A Sketch were surprisingly cool.
Scott: They had a machine that made pancakes.
Rym: They had a fancy In the back in the back.
Scott: They were just playing.
Scott: they're playing rock bad Beatles rock band.
Scott: and I was like, why is it?
Scott: What is special about this?
Scott: Why are they just playing Beatles rock band?
Scott: who gives a crap?
Scott: and then I'm like The TV is like a hundred inches plus.
Rym: it was like this gigantic plasma screen.
Rym: It was one of those beautiful things I've ever seen in my life.
Scott: It's like the biggest fucking television in the universe.
Scott: I was like, holy shit.
Scott: I didn't like you don't realize it cuz just like a TV.
Rym: I was like, oh, it's a TV Yep, and right next to them was the dude playing the laser guitar.
Scott: There's a guitar that you play it by this for laser beams and you break them.
Rym: actually way back when I was making a DDR pad I Sketched out everything I would need.
Rym: I didn't build it cuz I didn't have the money.
Rym: But remember I made that shitty as DDR pad.
Rym: I eventually got rid of yep.
Rym: well I had this idea make a laser DDR pad a DDR pad where the arrows were all recessed and just put lasers and you know Mirrors and sensors.
Scott: go for it.
Rym: And now I have the money.
Rym: I might just do it.
Scott: go for it.
Scott: It'd be totally awesome.
Rym: What do you mean that hard to do?
Rym: I mean that DDR pad.
Rym: I was not that Technologically or Carpentarily proficient back then, you know you could do.
Scott: actually you can make the DDR pad like nice and like, you know.
Scott: Instead of being metal you could make it like a nice like a just like like a dance floor surface.
Scott: If you did that it has to move.
Rym: it would have to be recessed though.
Rym: where all the things are It's just slightly so though.
Rym: The other problem is that there's one Dancing technique you can't do which is where you leave your foot down and just like lift up the pressure and put go back down.
Scott: You could you just plan to put the laser real low now because you have to still lift your foot?
Rym: I would not.
Rym: I would often when I play DDR.
Rym: My foot does not actually leave the pad.
Rym: Mmm, it would be cool though.
Rym: It's something maybe I'm doing.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I just thought it was cool.
Rym: I have an actual thing of the day.
Rym: So number way back.
Rym: I don't know how impressed Scott will be by this but I was there.
Rym: I had that that Martin Luther King auto-tune.
Rym: That was actually I thought pretty good and pretty inspiring.
Rym: All right, I thought it was pretty cool.
Rym: it made me I don't know very hopeful very very happy was a cool thing.
Rym: and You know suddenly people were making a ton of these things.
Scott: auto-tune is like the new hotness What exact like where all these people getting the auto-tune from?
Rym: you just buy it.
Scott: It's software Yeah, but I mean people obviously are not paying for it.
Rym: Uh Maybe I don't know.
Rym: I didn't check the Pirate Bay.
Scott: I see like what is the name of the program auto-tune?
Scott: Really?
Scott: Yeah, that's just it.
Rym: Okay, I could talk We just not get into it.
Rym: I could talk forever.
Rym: We will do a Monday show cuz we haven't done anything like this a while.
Rym: and on auto-tune?
Rym: Well, no on vocoders and auto-tune and all that stuff.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: I don't know anything about that I do.
Rym: I thought of that because Scott was trying to get me to do a show on DRBD and all this like cool Like shared file system stuff.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I want to know about yeah, and I'll do a show on it.
Rym: But I haven't been working on that stuff lately.
Rym: I've been writing bullshit Java code instead.
Rym: so I gotta go look at my configs.
Rym: But that aside someone put together an auto-tune.
Rym: that is basically a tribute to Carl Sagan who is One of the few people that I would really honestly consider a hero in this world.
Rym: Carl Sagan is just the man to a degree that you know None of you will ever.
Scott: none of us will ever obtain the same guy did both of these or a different guy?
Rym: I have no idea.
Rym: I did no research out what that so ever but I watched this like four times and was deeply inspired.
Rym: The sky calls to us if we do not destroy ourselves we will one day venture to the stars.
Rym: I'll still more glory as dawn awaits not a sunrise but a galaxy unless you already missed our chance.
Rym: Yeah, I'll do a hypothesis But seriously Carl Sagan for a whole generation of people before Scott and I and all of us.
Rym: You know our generation a whole generation of people became scientists And if you ask them it is pretty much straight up because they watched Carl Sagan's cosmos or they read Carl Sagan's cosmos and We need more people to watch and read Carl Sagan's cosmos and be interested in science.
Scott: Yeah, not enough science going on.
Rym: seriously.
Rym: watch this.
Scott: It is very inspiring and even people who are smart enough to listen to GeekNights are not understanding the science so much.
Scott: That's all I've got all right, so this isn't a big thing of the day.
Scott: It's just sort of you know little thing.
Scott: Basically, you know that the new browsers with the HTML 5 they're all gonna have the canvas element.
Scott: some of them already have the canvas Element but not all of them, but eventually they all will and the canvas element basically says hey web browser Make a square and inside that square.
Scott: I'm gonna draw shit, and I'm gonna draw whatever the hell I want now.
Rym: is that not?
Rym: the web developers dream the pixel placement on the screen right.
Rym: well It's not almost rhymed I'm mostly.
Scott: what it is is something they compete with flash right.
Scott: so you can make a game in there Or you can make you know some sort of animation in there.
Scott: Yeah, something like that.
Scott: The thing is this you can't really do 3d in there easily.
Rym: You can do it in that GIMP way.
Scott: Yeah, some people have done like Wolfenstein 3d in there.
Scott: You know which is sort of - you know you use 2d to make 3d But basically you're gonna have to write all the 3d code on your own.
Scott: You know cuz it's it's you.
Rym: all you have are the 2d drawing tool And you don't want to do that for anything other than an exercise.
Rym: I mean seriously.
Scott: so now in the latest Firefox nightly build right they have web GL.
Scott: So you can do OpenGL in the canvas.
Scott: 3d in the browser no plugins no nothing just a box.
Scott: And then you do 3d in it and they had the demo.
Scott: it has the spar like a spore creature rendered inside one of these canvas boxes, so Yeah, all those things that like add 3d to the browser.
Scott: You know like you know quake live and such not gonna need that in The future.
Scott: we're just gonna you know 3d game right in the browser.
Scott: No flash.
Scott: No nothing.
Scott: I'm looking forward to it.
Scott: probably a couple years out everyone will have it.
Rym: So without further ado it's time for the totally cop-out tech news round.
Rym: Oh, I feel like I should play some roundup music or something like you know like Like Western roundup, I think so all right.
Scott: That's all.
Scott: you go find some.
Rym: that's not happening, okay?
Scott: You want to start?
Scott: you got a tech news or you want me to go for tech news real quick I want to talk about.
Rym: you know this is slightly old news But I have something.
Rym: but remember news whatever.
Rym: we're more about commentary here on GeekNights But stack overflow which people have been saying they should do this forever.
Scott: I want to make up first of all that people know there is a website called stack overflow.
Scott: The website is basically you might know a website called experts exchange.
Rym: right I believe you mean experts exchange exactly.
Scott: It's a website where basically tech people ask questions And then they answer.
Scott: other tech people answer the question.
Scott: so if you need tech help you go there And you ask or you answer.
Scott: and The thing is the site requires money to get into.
Scott: it's not a free site.
Scott: So basically the obvious idea was hey Why doesn't someone just make a free experts exchange?
Scott: and while someone did it's called stack overflow And it's way better.
Scott: in addition to being free They also made two other sites server fault calm and super user calm.
Scott: stack overflow is really just for programming questions Server fall is for IT questions and super user is for all the other sorts of computer questions that are not for stack overflow Or server fault.
Rym: so they did.
Rym: what everyone's been clamoring for them to do forever is now They have made something that is basically stack overflow for everything.
Rym: stack exchange right.
Scott: so the way stack exchange is basically Hey, you punk kid whoever you are do you want to make your own question and answer site?
Scott: Maybe for gaming?
Scott: maybe for board games maybe for anime Maybe for bottle railroads, maybe for carpentry.
Scott: You give us money And we will let you make a website.
Scott: that is the same Software and stack overflow only for whatever your topic happens to be.
Rym: so I'm going to say straight up This is a terrible idea that is going to fail miserably and be a footnote in internet history at best.
Scott: Yeah I think that you know.
Rym: if this is going to collapse this for the same reason that dig and reddit and Basically everything else that is for a lot side wiki which failed before we even started.
Scott: we're gonna talk about that.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: So yeah, I agree with you.
Scott: That is not a good idea.
Scott: And the reason what you know one guy I was listening to stack is the reason why is such a depressing reason?
Scott: Well, I was listening to the stack overflow podcast right and basically you know.
Scott: you got Jeff Atwood Who's the guy who made the stack overflow with some other people and you got Joel Spolsky who sort of a?
Scott: Infamous character in the software development world.
Scott: right and the Joel Spolsky is the guy who's running the business part of you know.
Scott: But the stack exchange where is the Jeff that would?
Scott: he's just doing the stack overflow and basically It's like you know.
Scott: Jeff wanted to open-source stack overflow eventually not now but eventually and Joel was like no you can never do it then my stack exchange won't make any money ever.
Scott: and I think that basically they're a fool for trying the stack exchange model because number one they're charging way too much money Right and no one who pays that much money for one of these sites is gonna make that much money back.
Scott: Right I mean no stack overflow site is ever gonna be as big as the original stack overflow.
Scott: and two Right they should have just open-sourced it and made money the WordPress way whereas WordPress is making a lot more money than stack overflow is gonna make with the stack exchange.
Rym: Well the two reasons why I believe it's just going to fail outright is that one?
Rym: Dig only worked sadly when it was primarily a walled garden of the kind of the technological elite.
Rym: there was this high barrier to entry.
Rym: only like the really techie hit people were there and These were people who generally wouldn't shit cock all over everything mm-hmm.
Rym: And there are a million sites that you know like wiki answers and Google answers and Yahoo answers and all this stuff and they all Basically devolve into garbage unless they're continuously pruned and monitored by human.
Scott: well stack overflow is continued.
Rym: It's crowdsource to the same Relatively technological people and it caters to this very specific focus group.
Scott: Yeah Well, I think you understand that stack exchange is not is separate from stack or I do it like.
Scott: stack overflow won't be ruined by.
Rym: I think stack exchange is in and of itself cannot possibly succeed because What experts are you gonna get in all these fields who are also technologically competent?
Rym: And you're just gonna get people shit cocking if anything and even if you avoid the problem that any Collaborative internet with 2.0 kind of thing has if you ever get them non technological masses to use.
Rym: it is The problem that very few fields outside of science math and technology Have such specific questions with clear.
Rym: that is the answer.
Rym: answers Yeah, I mean in IT or you know I write like how do I make a script to do X in Python?
Rym: There's one answer Maybe two answers.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: How do I monitor this as an MP thing?
Scott: Or at least if there are multiple answers, they are either right or wrong.
Scott: There is no like questionable if they might be right or wrong.
Scott: They're they're working.
Rym: They don't I mean somewhat.
Rym: What's someone gonna ask?
Rym: How do I kayak right?
Rym: What kayak do I buy?
Scott: There's no objective answer to that and Yahoo answers sort of covers that kind of crap.
Rym: But I think we should move right on from this and decide wiki if that's something you were gonna bring.
Scott: But one more thing about this right is that even if you're not you're taught You know.
Scott: regardless of the fact that you know the question of yes There are answers or no there aren't.
Scott: Tech people sit at the computer all day Like if you're going from model railroad questions a guy who's working on his model railroad doesn't have you know a computer right there That he's gonna You know rush to every time he has a problem.
Scott: tech people are sitting at the computer when we have a problem We google it and stack overflow shows up in the Google results.
Scott: Model railroad exchange.
Scott: right that ain't gonna happen.
Scott: model railroad guys aren't sitting at the computer while they're model railroading.
Scott: They're in a room with the table with the railroad on it.
Scott: So unless they you know you make the user interface for your website a train It's not gonna work so well.
Rym: and also I mean think of this in general guy is the problem kayaking?
Scott: He's out in the water on a boat.
Rym: a programmer knows how to ask a question that another programmer can answer.
Scott: Usually you'd be surprised in Stack Overflow.
Scott: pretty bad questions.
Scott: Yeah, they also Google all their problems.
Scott: other professions Like carpenters don't Google all their problems the way programmers do so it's just by that very nature.
Scott: It's not gonna work, so well.
Scott: I think a gaming one might work.
Scott: Well it might work, okay For tips and tricks kinds of things like how do I beat this part true?
Scott: And I think that could do it really do a good competition with game facts.
Rym: Oh, it could destroy game facts.
Rym: honestly game facts has to die.
Rym: The culture of their.
Rym: you know text only ASCII file are.
Rym: the whole culture of game facts is just crap.
Scott: Hey, why don't we make a game fax is better?
Scott: I mean we could.
Scott: you know it doesn't even have to be Stack Overflow.
Scott: Let's just be like.
Rym: hey, that'd be really you know unlike every other idea We've ever had that would take like a month of us doing it like hardly at all Put it in the hopper.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, but we could put it near the top of the hopper.
Rym: It's much easier to do than our global currency.
Scott: Yeah, that has to wait.
Rym: Yeah, it does.
Scott: So yeah you want to talk about this, so here's the side wiki right basically 1994 called.
Rym: they want their idea back right.
Scott: basically the idea is an old idea, and I've seen at least two or three implementations of this idea.
Scott: and the idea is this Why do we need to have comments?
Scott: You know on the websites what we can do is we can just have some separate commenting system where people comment on URLs And then you visit the URL and then your browser will load up the comments for that URL.
Scott: So basically everyone is commenting on the web Sites all in one place and you can comment on any site on the whole net whether the site has comments or not.
Scott: And it's an okay idea.
Rym: it well.
Rym: It's at least in theory.
Rym: It's a great idea in theory because one there are a lot of times where there's something discussion worthy But many times people with certain agendas will not want anyone to comment in a way that can be associated with their content.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And two it's a great way to like crowds.
Rym: you basically would let you in a in the pre masses internet though it before the long November.
Rym: You basically could have had the internet the way Tim Berners-Lee imagined it mm-hmm, but now that could never happen.
Rym: no It's just impossible.
Scott: so the thing is basically everyone who's implemented this.
Scott: I've saw one a long time ago.
Scott: That was like a Firefox extension And it would open up a sidebar in your Firefox.
Rym: One of the earliest ones was you could stick post-it notes to websites that were translucent.
Rym: You could bring them in and out and move them around.
Scott: So Google's got basically the same thing again called side wiki and the biggest problem I have with it is you need Google toolbar to use it.
Scott: It's like fuck Google toolbar.
Rym: Yeah I don't want a fucking toolbar just to add this one lousy feature Right and two they say like moderation and all this stuff is coming already too late.
Rym: You've got to have that right.
Scott: you gotta have that right away It's no good.
Scott: and the second thing they call it side wiki is not a wiki It's just comments.
Rym: if it was any other people's comments if it was a wiki that'd be great of course.
Rym: It would just be the cockboat on every website of course of course.
Rym: see the real problem here What.
Rym: but well now there are two things.
Rym: the real problem is that again?
Rym: To be perfectly blunt and to use the you know angry video game.
Rym: there the masses shit all over everything And there's no way to stop them.
Rym: Yeah, but that aside Most of the people who are against this are not against it for any of the reasons.
Rym: We've brought up.
Scott: No, they're against it because they don't want someone to comment on their no comment site and all like that.
Scott: You know like a news website that forces you to log in to comment there.
Scott: They don't want you leaving a comment so that someone visits there like you know New York Times And then suddenly the side wiki opens up And it says shit cock shit cock poop poop poop plus back in the day You know these post-it note things.
Rym: they got sued.
Rym: everyone got like sued or threatened to be sued by anyone who would be affected by This.
Scott: it's vandalism.
Rym: All I have to say these people is that They have no more right to the metadata that is associated with their site But not on their site.
Rym: then they have to.
Rym: I don't know me talking about their website exactly.
Rym: That's all it is.
Rym: Yep, it's just a website, but the thing is what it.
Rym: it's almost what web 3.0 is going to be.
Rym: you know People talk a lot about what web 2.0 was and I think we all generally agree what that is.
Rym: No one really agrees.
Rym: know what web 3.0 is a lot of people use stupid BS phrases like the semantic web or whatever.
Rym: I Think web 3.0 is going to be when every computer is basically serving and receiving content in pretty much equal amounts Mmm.
Rym: That's going to be when there are no more IPs, but that IP v6 and all those things.
Rym: It'll be the day when there are not Monolithic gigantic web servers.
Rym: it is just everything is kind of peer-to-peer.
Rym: Everyone's a publisher and everyone's a receiver and It's actually a cloud.
Rym: It's actually a web.
Scott: It'd be the federated cloud where it's like.
Scott: you don't have you know the Twitter server.
Scott: It's everyone.
Scott: You know it's more the Laconica model even though the Laconica itself sucks.
Scott: It has the correct Architecture where every every community or whatever runs their own little server And then the servers federate and such or every person or a family runs their own server.
Scott: the world where everyone has their own.
Scott: Instead of one big storm cloud Everyone has their own little tiny personal cloud And then all the clouds can sort of send lightning back and forth like even to agree like Google Wave will probably go a long Way toward that.
Rym: but even the idea that that web browsers This is the one area web browsers can change fundamentally to where instead of being primarily a get pages and interact with them.
Rym: They are a share information and receive information.
Scott: Well doesn't the new opera have that?
Scott: it's a web server and a web browser to serve various things.
Rym: Yeah, I haven't played with it yet, so I don't want to talk about it.
Rym: I think it does have that though, but Extrude that into the future and that is what I would call web 3.0 because that is the next revolution.
Scott: Yeah, that's what the internet was supposed to be in the beginning But we got.
Rym: it's weird how the people who basically pioneered the internet knew exactly what it should have been and no one's like Everyone's basically moved away from that and now they're finally going back to slowly but surely Thing that really just I keep.
Scott: I can't say this enough times, right?
Scott: Computers are like 30. some personal computers are at least 30 something years old.
Scott: the internet I mean people normal people have add, you know internet access dial-up came around like what 15 years ago.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, right and People are still acting like this.
Scott: shit is new and world-changing.
Scott: Get with the fucking times.
Scott: if the computer can do it tough shit It's done game over if you don't realize it by now.
Scott: You're never gonna get it.
Scott: You're an old geezer.
Scott: Get in the backseat you're done.
Scott: you're not allowed to drive anymore.
Rym: No, because if computers are good enough, you don't have to drive anymore.
Rym: computers do it for you.
Scott: The point is if you don't get it by now, I mean look at this newspapers are dying.
Scott: now You it's not like this jumped out as a surprise.
Scott: you had 15.
Scott: Right, oh the music companies and the movie companies, what will they do?
Scott: 15 years?
Scott: That's a long time.
Scott: The music industry Everyone saw this coming.
Scott: Napster was in 1999 10 years ago and you still having a fucking problem Get with it.
Rym: We got it.
Rym: There's some topic there.
Rym: We could turn into a show but I'm not sure what other than just kill all the old people.
Rym: Hey hot mama, you want to kill all the humans.
Scott: kill all humans.
Rym: You realize eventually all humans will be old people compared to the computers.
Rym: good So so this is gonna be Galaxy Express in the end, is that where we're going?
Scott: No, it's gonna be Logan's run All right.
Scott: So all right.
Rym: That was your thing.
Rym: I get to do thing Real quick in New Zealand.
Rym: They have banned phones as satellite navigation devices.
Rym: This is ham-fisted bullshit.
Rym: This just reeks of every prayer.
Scott: I'll start with the time 15 years.
Rym: Australia and New Zealand when it comes to technology are a little more than fascist dictatorships.
Rym: It's just a disaster down there.
Rym: The only way it works is that a lot of people seem to just ignore these laws, but think about it.
Rym: They don't want people to be fiddling with their phones and cars.
Rym: So they've banned cell phones as sat-nav devices.
Rym: My son and even if you mount them on the dashboard, right?
Rym: So you have to buy a sat-nav device a dedicated one.
Rym: I think this was lobbying by like Garmin and I think so too because mice, you know The pre the ball the palm free.
Rym: one of the biggest things about it is that they made a deal with spring.
Rym: You get for free a sat-nav.
Rym: the same is what you have in your car.
Rym: if you mount that on your dashboard It does everything that one of those Garmin things does.
Rym: it tells you the directions.
Rym: It's all voice It's perfect.
Rym: And you know, they just made that illegal in New Zealand because they're stupid.
Rym: I don't have anything else to say.
Rym: people in government retarded unless they work for the census.
Scott: Yeah, right where they make nice public domain, you know software packages with nice open API's and everything all right, so I Very very soon.
Scott: It's the month of October and there's something special about October's and April's in that those are the months when Ubuntu appears.
Scott: So but to 910 which is Ubuntu 2009 October.
Rym: is this one gonna be an LTS?
Scott: No, the April's gonna be an LTS.
Rym: I'm gonna hold out then.
Scott: So for those you don't know LTS means long-term support.
Scott: That means if you install a long-term support version That means like you can leave it you can use it for like three years and if it's a server five years.
Scott: If it's a regular old version like the one that's coming out real soon is it only gets updates for like 18 months?
Scott: I think and then it's game over.
Scott: so you've got to keep.
Scott: you know If you're using every single version of Ubuntu you got to keep upgrading it.
Scott: But if you use an LTS, which is what I would use on a server You just use the LTS and you ignore the other six months, you know, October April releases and you only use the LTS ones.
Scott: Anyway, this this release that's coming out You know, it's got a lot of new goodies goodies all over the place Right, like Firefox three and a half and such, you know.
Scott: One thing it has that I think is the most interesting is the booting is a lot faster like they really really concentrated on the faster booting big time and Basically a long time ago like many releases ago They switched the boot system to this thing called upstart.
Scott: The thing is they didn't really take advantage of it full-on, you know It's like they put it in there, but they didn't really optimize it in the latest release.
Scott: They pushed it real real hard And if you have like a solid-state drive your computer's gonna boot in like fucking three seconds.
Scott: It's ludicrous.
Scott: Like I've seen it It's crazy.
Scott: So I really can't wait for that because my laptop has a solid-state drive.
Scott: in addition Phronix, which is this website that is very very Linux nerdy.
Scott: They posted they have this benchmark suite the Phronix test suite and they benchmark the Ubuntu alpha of what's gonna come out Or the beta or whatever it is and they compared it to Free BSD and it basically kicked the shit out of free BSD in all but a few categories.
Scott: So the next Ubuntu is gonna be pretty awesome.
Scott: in addition to you know, the usual updates across the board Also, I saw some screencasts of gnome then like the next like gnome 3.0.
Scott: Whoo big changes.
Rym: Oh good.
Scott: It doesn't look like, you know, I mean, you know a lot of time you look around at you know Like Linux desktops like a man they're copying OS X man, they're copying Windows this gnome 3. it's got like stuff I never even seen before.
Scott: I don't even know if I like it or not.
Scott: I got to use it before I can decide but I'll show you after the the show real quick like some of the stuff they Added like one particular thing is.
Scott: I think I'd have this whole like peek behind the desktop functionality.
Scott: It sort of reminds me of Windows 3.1 but not and it's like it looks like some of it was borrowed from the netbook remix.
Scott: I don't know what's going on, but it's a big change and Excited just to try out something new.
Rym: So I want to just mention The the reddit issue because it's hilarious.
Rym: Here's there's.
Scott: there's been a lot of these attacks recently on a wide variety of sites.
Scott: Is there to pull off?
Scott: Yep, but shitty security.
Rym: Here's the link from slashdot.
Rym: I'm going to read the the the headline of this article, which is actually on reddit and I quote what the fuck just happened.
Rym: I opened a comment thread in Firefox and my braids my browser went crazy and posted all this shit.
Rym: What the fuck?
Scott: Yeah Basically the sit.
Scott: I'll explain the technology of the situation.
Rym: It's really simple.
Rym: what they did, right?
Scott: So basically a cross-site scripting attack, right?
Scott: Is where you put?
Scott: JavaScripts onto someone else's website?
Scott: or you have JavaScripts on your website that do something to someone else's website or something along these lines.
Scott: Right, especially JavaScripts that are that are affecting your website, even though you didn't write them.
Scott: Basically what happens is a JavaScript like that, you know because of Ajax and various things can like can do things like post Comments or you know anything like a user can do with JavaScript can be done to the site.
Rym: So they did something similar with flash in that recent live journal exploit.
Rym: Yeah You know basically the flash that got called Would use the cross-site scripting to access some other application and edit the last thing you had posted to live journal.
Scott: Basically people are getting hit by this at this kind of attack.
Scott: big-time websites are getting hit by this all over the.
Rym: they're not easy.
Scott: I mean all you really need to do is get a. you know When you go to a website and you log in you click stay logged in So you're still logged in.
Scott: you go to some other website.
Scott: That is nothing to do.
Scott: Let's say you're still logged in to say Twitter you go to some other website.
Scott: That's not Twitter.
Scott: It's I don't know Google, right?
Scott: They could make something where you click on it and then it goes over to Twitter and does stuff with your logged in this.
Scott: Because Twitter is all not with the good security.
Rym: They're not.
Rym: they really are.
Scott: You know, this is one of those situations where it's easy to say Yeah, those people you got a pro crew comm you click on something and suddenly you're sending out a tweet.
Scott: You don't even realize.
Rym: but we you know We had multiple Forums and things on our web server in the past and there are even issues with us.
Rym: Just no one noticed him because we got rid of all that shit.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: But anyway the What happened here on reddit is somebody.
Scott: they found something found one JavaScript that basically says when you hover over a link do something and then they combine that with the.
Scott: You know make someone post a comment.
Scott: So basically you would go to reddit.
Scott: you would hover over a link and it would post a comment But it wouldn't just post a comment.
Scott: It would post a reply to every single comment on the whole page.
Rym: So think about it.
Rym: like three people visit a page exponential.
Scott: three people visit the page and suddenly you've got like three six now.
Rym: now Here, here's my joke on Reddit, how would anyone even notice?
Rym: I know right fuck read it seriously.
Scott: Basically, you know what happens right?
Scott: the comment that they're posting is the evil link itself.
Scott: So it's a beautiful page in this awesome way.
Rym: It's so beautiful.
Rym: Like I can't describe you how happy I am that this happened.
Scott: If you're making websites watch out for the cross-eyed scripting attacks.
Scott: You're not embarrassed like all these big-name websites.
Rym: how lucky we are to live in this time the first moment in human history.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: and if you are thinking of doing an attack cross-eyed scripting is real easy to do.
Scott: just learn some JavaScript.
Scott: It's a joke.
Rym: You can nail big-time websites real easy like yep and it's only it's going to get worse before it gets better.
Rym: and really I'm more and more of the mind that the only way to Get things like this fixed is to exploit them a hundred percent.
Rym: Yep, because if things aren't exploited people just don't care.
Scott: Mm-hmm Alright, this is uh, this is semi gaming news, but I'm approaching this from the tech angle.
Rym: Yeah, we can wind this down.
Scott: Sony's coming out with this PSP.
Scott: go you might have seen it around.
Scott: It's still not out yet.
Rym: Go go go.
Scott: It's coming out real soon And the thing is right.
Scott: there's been a lot of talk because it seems like you know I think I read the like EB and what Australia isn't gonna sell it and some other places just aren't gonna sell it.
Scott: It's not really gonna be a problem in the US but it's me a problem in other places.
Scott: We're like stores just don't want to sell this thing.
Scott: And the reason is there's no games for it.
Scott: all the games are download games.
Scott: So if you're a store you make all your money selling games at big margins and you sell the consoles.
Scott: that like no margin, right?
Scott: so why would you sell PSP goes at no margin.
Scott: if You're gonna not sell any PSP go games because there are no PSP.
Rym: go You know who's gonna sell.
Rym: you can sell it.
Scott: our accessories.
Rym: The fine thing is this is one more nail in the coffin of game stores for video games.
Scott: Well, I think it's a nail in the coffin of stores period.
Rym: but the other thing Here's the thing like a Walmart or a grocery store are the places where these things in things like this going forward in the future Will be sold because some stores will have to exist because you can't easily buy that stuff over the internet.
Rym: Yeah, mostly just food stores and clothing.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And even then I buy most of my clothing over the internet.
Rym: Yep, I even buy some of my food over the internet.
Scott: Now his is.
Scott: the other thing right is that Sony actually I found out they foresaw this problem.
Scott: They're not that stupid, right?
Scott: They knew that.
Scott: why would anyone sell this thing on such a you know, a low margin?
Scott: if there's no games?
Scott: The margin on it is actually jacked up pretty high and the retail some retailers are happy about it.
Scott: So the thing is why would you the consumer buy this thing with a jacked up margin?
Rym: Here's the answer here.
Scott: The answer is buy an old PSP that someone's training in for a PSP.
Scott: go That'll be mad cheap.
Rym: They're doing this just to get the retailers to carry him in the beginning and Everyone who knows better all this weight and buy one like next year when they have a massive price cut.
Scott: also if there's a built-in margin like that then places like Amazon are probably gonna be able to sell the thing for a big reduced cost because they're willing to suffer a much smaller margin being An internet store not a GameStop.
Rym: I mean like GameStops are basically glorified pawn shops at this point.
Scott: Anyway, yep, and in the end the People I would love to see some statistics about how many games that are sold back to GameStops were originally stolen from other GameStops.
Rym: All right, I got one more here and this wrap this up, yeah, there were a bunch of articles recently.
Rym: This is starting to happen more and more.
Rym: We're like a bank.
Rym: We'll just you know accidentally email their customer database to like this is a big one And this it's not like.
Rym: this is an isolated thing.
Rym: This is happening a lot and ISP emailed like their entire customer list to like half the people who got bills from them recently.
Rym: and the biggest one and this is the.
Rym: this is the one I'll focus on a Bank the Rocky Mountain Bank in Wyoming.
Scott: Why is the Rocky Mountain Bank in Wyoming and not Colorado accidentally sent?
Scott: They know the Rocky Mountains extend to collar and to extend into Wyoming.
Rym: But the point is this ill stands this gigantic confidential financial document to some dudes.
Rym: Gmail account Now one in the real world.
Rym: if someone mails you something in the physical mail accidentally They're fucked and by law you come shit.
Rym: law at the tough shit law It's not.
Scott: and but here if you mail me your social security card, that's mine now.
Rym: Well, it never belonged to the person who mailed it to you I know.
Scott: but I mean if you mail me a hundred dollars, you can't ask for it back.
Rym: It's mine.
Rym: Yeah, it's this whole protection thing.
Rym: So you can't like mail someone something and then mail them a bill later, right?
Rym: But basically, you know this company this bank mailed some dude this confidential information and then they'd realized they made a mistake and They went to Google.
Rym: and Google said you know what fuck you come back with a warrant.
Rym: That's right.
Scott: Google basically won't give you shit unless you have a subpoena or something.
Rym: So they found some stupid judge who agreed with them got a warrant and basically Google was forced by law to cut this dude this guy who hadn't did nothing wrong off from his email account with no knowledge No consent no Notification nothing.
Rym: they just locked him out.
Scott: now think about that for a second.
Scott: You're right, you know when it's email You're just sort of like, huh?
Scott: Let's say they sent the guy the stuff in the real mail.
Scott: That's the equivalent of the judge saying, huh?
Scott: They sent you a confidential document in the mail, huh?
Scott: We're just gonna have to cease the mailman's not gonna visit your house ever again.
Rym: In fact, we're gonna have to come and take all the mail we find in your house in case It's one of those documents and we're gonna destroy your mailbox with a sledgehammer just in case just in case.
Scott: That's basically what they did here and I'm just gonna sum this up.
Rym: We our governments need to realize that Email and digit and digital stuff like this has to be treated with the same respect that physical stuff.
Scott: does I mean?
Scott: the same problem is happening about these three strikes laws that they're getting thrown around in Europe.
Scott: Right, if you're accused of copyright infringement three times will turn off your internets.
Scott: Oh, really the same internets that my kids need to do homework and the same internets I need to apply for a job and the same internets that I need.
Scott: the Internet's does a lot more than one Thing.
Scott: email does a lot of things.
Scott: These are necessary services.
Scott: You can't cut off someone's entire telephone entire internet entire mail entire whatever just because there's one Thing wrong with it somewhere.
Rym: Well, we were talking about this actually you mean Emily the other night and I realized that if I lost access to my email For more than a day or so.
Rym: I am basically I'm unable to do a vast but like a large majority of the things that are necessary to my life Like my and not not my physical life.
Scott: I mean we're An email a lot less lately, but even so I do need it.
Rym: Well, that's cuz.
Rym: I'm the producer here I mean, I'm the one who responds like the 20 GeekNights emails every day and arranges everything but also my regular life and You know I can eat and there I can make all the like physical necessities of my life without all this technology.
Rym: But because I have all those things already people like us technological people we live I Guess socially on this like other plane of existence like Wil Wheaton says it best.
Rym: Hi.
Rym: I'm Wil Wheaton I come from the internet.
Rym: I have this life on the internet that cannot exist without all of these technological things and Taking them away basically cuts me off from this higher functioning plane of existence in which I exist for the majority of my time And forces me to live this other lower life,
Scott: yep,
Rym: and it is Internet.
Rym: access should be a utility email should be protected the way real mail is and should be like electricity.
Scott: You know, you just get it and that's it.
Scott: You got you got an IP address.
Scott: You should get a static IP address, by the way And you should just get an amount of bandwidth and then if you use more you pay more to be metered.
Scott: Fair metering though not BS metering like the cable companies want.
Scott: my mom Should pay five bucks a month because she all she does is barely anything and I should pay maybe a hundred because I'm doing a Ton of shit like uploading GeekNights episodes.
Scott: It really just comes down to their metering and as technology improves when we get fiber optic cables and whatnot The price got to go down to keep it fair.
Rym: It really just comes down to the fact that you know It's a buzzword and a lot of people don't understand what it means and this is not the show to talk about that.
Rym: net neutrality is Seriously one of the most important issues facing government in the industrialized world today.
Scott: Yeah, but it's very difficult because we want net neutrality.
Scott: But if we want the government to mandate net neutrality Then we're also giving the government the power to regulate and we don't want to give the government the power to regulate because they suck Ass at it.
Rym: Well beyond that it's difficult to convince Politicians that net neutrality is important when the majority of their constituents are the old men who don't realize 15 years old.
Rym: I'll make a more lucid point that That basically teen years These the majority of their constituents have no conception That it's even a problem and it would not affect them in the near future.
Rym: It's such a long-term Problem.
Rym: We can't even explain to these people what it is.
Scott: I think that's why a lot of people are saying It's like a red herring.
Scott: It's a red herring because you know, it's it's not.
Scott: it's not currently an issue immediately It's a long-term thing.
Rym: But in the long run I think it's going to have more far-reaching implications for our society as a whole.
Rym: Then even like the national health care debate right now has definitely which is scary to think about but I'm dead serious I think that health care reform right now will not be as meaningful to society in the long run as net neutrality will be.
Rym: yeah, I know people think because net neutrality is such a Simpler problem to solve Jesus.
Scott: and you know people think they're like, you know, okay Let's say we came up with some theoretical perfect health care system, right?
Scott: How significant a change is it really gonna make in a short period of time?
Scott: Basically, when you go to the doctor's office, you'll fill out different pieces of paper.
Rym: That's the kind of look at how much the world has changed in 15 years.
Rym: Yep, I mean it.
Rym: this is you know maybe I'm just inspired because I just watched this Carl Sagan thing a million times and I have this urge to read cosmos again, but The Internet has changed our society in ways that I think few people I don't think we mean Scott or even you know Some of the people at the top of technology Really understand the implications and ramifications of the Internet.
Rym: Everyone's trying real hard.
Scott: at least some people know that we have to try real hard to understand them.
Rym: But I think our society like society is being changed faster than even the people at the cutting edge Understand.
Scott: most people the vast majority of it's like this.
Scott: society is like not even Like it's like, you know society is made of people.
Scott: but it's strange in that somehow this sort of object like Non-human object that is society somehow All right That is people.
Scott: but is?
Scott: it is made of people but is not in and of itself.
Scott: It's getting ahead of all the people.
Rym: it's like it's the it's the intelligence paradox Or if you make it if you could ever possibly make an AI that can become smarter faster than you become smarter.
Rym: Eventually the AI will not need you because it can make a eyes faster than itself.
Rym: Mmm, and there's this exponential explosion of intelligence and the internet is almost doing that to our society.
Rym: I mean In Wednesday's show.
Rym: I think we talked about ghosts in the shell.
Rym: I remember talking about how Ghost in the shell that universe those ideas are more true to reality than a lot of people would be comfortable to admit.
Rym: and it's easy to say it isn't because you look and It's all this like cyborgs and physical world stuff.
Rym: But if you look at the society of ghosts in the shell, especially I think our society's cyberspace metaphor I think so much the cyber brain metaphor.
Rym: I think our society right now is close to surpassing what happened in ghosts in the shell.
Rym: on a societal level Maybe close ways.
Rym: think about how fast things change in the last five years.
Rym: go five years into the future.
Rym: Yeah, I I can't predict more than six or seven months out on tech, but it can't wait.
Rym: I can predict.
Rym: I've reasonably predicted, you know, five to ten years of politics at a time in broad strokes and I can reasonably think I see where Politics and where society and where health care and where all these physical things are going because they're evolving so much more slowly And yet I can't predict where the Internet's going months into the future.
Rym: No, and the internet is probably gonna have more ramifications in the long run.
Rym: Yep I think we should end on that because I kind of want to go to bed and I'm hungry.
Rym: Yep I'm not very good at singing songs.
Rym: But here's here's a try.
Rym: If you wish to make you must first Invent the universe.
Rym: space With a network of.
Scott: You might emerge somewhere else in space.
Rym: Some win else in time.
Scott: the sky calls to us.
Scott: We do not destroy ourselves.
Scott: We will one day Enter to the stars.
Rym: the storm or glorious dawn awaits not a sunrise But a galaxy rise a warning filled for a hundred billion suns.
Rym: Why is it of the Milky Way?
Rym: cosmos is full beyond measure Elegant truths of explicit interrelationships of the possum.
Rym: I believe our future depends powerfully on how well we understand this cosmos In which we float like a mode of dust in the morning sky.
Rym: But the brain does much more than just recollect.
Rym: it intercompares See the size.
Rym: It generates abstractions.
Rym: The simplest thought like the concept of the number one is an elaborate logical underpinning.
Rym: Brain has its own language for testing the structure and consistency of the world.
Rym: Still more glorious dawn awaits The galaxy was a morning film for hundred billion songs.
Rym: the right of the Milky Way.
Rym: the sky Calls to us if we do not destroy ourselves We will one day Ventured to the stars.
Rym: For thousands of years people have wondered about the universe.
Scott: did it stretch out forever?
Rym: Or was there a limit?
Rym: the big bangs of black holes Dark matter to a possible big crunch of image of the universe.
Rym: today It's full of strange sounding ideas.
Rym: How lucky we are to live in this time the first moment in human history when we are in fact visiting other worlds.
Rym: a Still more glorious dawn awaits not a sunrise but a galaxy rise a morning filled with 400 billion suns.
Scott: The rise of the Milky Way.
Scott: Glorious dawn awaits not a sunrise but a galaxy rise a morning filled with 400 billion suns.
Rym: the rise of the Milky Way.
Rym: The surface of the earth is the shore of the cosmic ocean.
Rym: Recently we've waned a little way up and the water seems inviting.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.