Rym: It's Thursday, June 4th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, levels of discourse.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: Today is Thursday, what's the day?
Scott: January 4th.
Rym: As I just said a second ago.
Scott: Wait, it's not January 4th.
Rym: June 4th.
Scott: June 4th.
Rym: It's one of the J months.
Scott: A few months off.
Scott: And on June 6th and 7th 2009 is the Museum of Comic and Cartoon Art Arts Festival.
Scott: In a new place.
Scott: It's not in the Puck building where it has previously been.
Rym: It is at the 69th Regiment Armory at 68 Lexington Avenue between 25th and 26th.
Scott: Ooh, in an armory.
Scott: I hope there's arms there.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: As cool as arms might be, I'm really gonna miss that vintage elevator in the Puck building.
Scott: There might be a vintage elevator in the armory.
Scott: It might actually be a really big elevator meant to transport arms.
Rym: They might not let me ride it.
Scott: No, actually a lot of the armory places are like just buildings that used to be armories But now are not armories in any way shape or form.
Scott: other than that They are big buildings that were previously armories.
Rym: But suffice it to say if you listen to GeekNights You will probably enjoy the mocha.
Scott: If you're a comic person, even if you just like reading the Sunday comics in the newspaper.
Scott: The mocha is a place to go and it is cheap.
Scott: It is like ten bucks to go there.
Rym: It's ten bucks.
Scott: And basically all you do is you don't even have to go there for that long.
Scott: You just show up, you pay your ten bucks You walk around, you look at every single table, and you talk to everybody and you hang out a little bit And then you go home and with a wallet empty and a sack full of comics that were probably not available many other places in the world.
Rym: You also pretty much get to meet the artists of any indie comic that you're reading.
Scott: It's like you go to a comic book convention, like a typical one And all the comic creators, some of them might be in the artist alley, but most of them, the high level ones anyway.
Scott: It's like you gotta pay for an autograph or maybe you gotta wait in line or they're on a panel.
Scott: At the mocha, you'll have some indie guy who printed his comic at Kinko sitting at one table And the table immediately next to him is a super famous guy And every table, the person sitting there is pretty much 90% of the time the person who made the comic and not someone else.
Scott: So the mocha is the awesome, and the win is ten bucks.
Scott: It's in New York City.
Scott: You can go Saturday or Sunday or both.
Rym: Are there any after parties that we should go to?
Rym: Because we missed everything last year, but the year before we went to that after party.
Scott: Oh yeah, I don't know about any after parties this year.
Scott: I did not investigate that situation.
Rym: We should go after party though, because kind of at the last minute half the crew is coming out to go to this thing with us.
Scott: Yeah, it being up in the 20 something-ish area, I think we should go to the conveyor belt sushi restaurant.
Rym: I think we will get some Kaiten sushi and then everyone but Scott will do karaoke.
Rym: that is also in the Kaiten sushi place.
Scott: Is karaoke in the Kaiten sushi place?
Scott: Yeah, upstairs I did not know this.
Scott: Yeah But I will not do any karaoke.
Scott: There's a lot more than ten dollars and it's stupid.
Rym: I don't know how you cannot like karaoke.
Rym: No human cannot like karaoke.
Scott: Most humans don't like karaoke.
Rym: I would argue that humans like karaoke.
Scott: Karaoke isn't the same thing as disco only I like disco.
Scott: I like disco too But I don't like karaoke and most people dislike disco and karaoke.
Rym: See the thing is there are two kinds of karaoke.
Rym: There's the lame American, you know It's a bar and there are drunk women at the front singing the same song over and over again And then there's rent a private room and hang out with friends singing.
Scott: Both kinds suck for the same reason.
Scott: Oh, you suck.
Scott: Anyway, so news time.
Rym: Yeah, I guess we don't have to do news.
Rym: It's Thursday.
Rym: It's the lounge Whatever.
Scott: I got something I want to talk about Something you want to talk about.
Scott: So there was an article in Newsweek, which is I guess which is real news, right?
Scott: Serious news, not internet news.
Scott: All right, one could say that The article was about Oprah and it called her out on all her snake oil bullshit hardcore Really?
Scott: So I was like, really?
Scott: In the real news?
Scott: And it was a big long article that got everything right And it talked about how there are these two good doctors who are on Oprah.
Scott: But there's all these other bullshit people and Oprah defends anyone who comes on her show.
Scott: And it really like picked apart Oprah's psychology And like, you know, how she why she's all fucked up in the head.
Rym: Oprah has already responded.
Scott: Oh, she responded because there was a. there was something about like she wouldn't come.
Scott: It said in the article that she wouldn't comment But there was like an official like two sentence statement or something.
Scott: Yes,
Rym: the statement is, quote, for 23 years, my show has presented thousands of That's
Scott: the statement, yes Yes,
Rym: that reflect the human experience, including doctor's medical advice and personal health stories that have prompted conversations between our audience and members of their health care providers, audience members and their health care providers.
Rym: I trust the viewers and I know that they are smart and discerning enough to seek out medical opinions to determine what may be best for them.
Scott: So she said nothing Right, and the thing is, right, she she says I trust the viewers, right?
Scott: But at the same time, right, one time she had someone on promoting some like Randy, you know, shit, and someone then like wrote her a letter that was like, yeah, because you I'm not getting chemo, I'm going to do the Randy shit instead for my cancer.
Scott: And then Oprah had to tell the person, you know, actually, you should probably go get your chemo and your radiation.
Scott: So you trust the viewers, but then you there you realize that you told them wrong and you have to correct them.
Rym: You see, the thing is, while people argue that Oprah has done a lot for communities in general, I still cannot forgive her for the fact that she constantly and blatantly just kowtows to idiocy and Randy bullshit.
Scott: Well, basically anything that's on her show is something she's promoting and endorsing and defending, right?
Rym: And she endorses and promotes way too much BS.
Scott: She'll just endorse and promote whatever, you know, and she's so, you know, she's not I mean, what really are Oprah's credentials other than I have a lot of money and I've been on TV for a long time and I know how to speak in a way that, you know, is makes my, you know, she's just a really good salesperson to a very specific audience.
Rym: That's that's our only came out of the woodwork already.
Rym: All the news I can find all the opinion pieces are people lambasting this article.
Rym: How dare they attack Oprah, a pillar of the community?
Rym: They're just attacking her because they're racist Racist, okay Or sexist or sexist?
Rym: It seems like it's equal parts race, equal parts sex Right.
Scott: Read the Newsweek article and know that's spelled wrong too.
Scott: That's great.
Scott: Read the Newsweek article.
Scott: The Newsweek article is 100% correct and anything that disagrees with it is wrong.
Scott: And if you disagree with it, you're stupid Stupid.
Scott: So Oprah's a bitch.
Scott: She has too much money.
Rym: So in some personal news, since we want to get right to the main bit, I think it's an interesting topic, but I'm sure many of you in the forums have seen all the rumblings and people who follow my tweet, tweet, Twitter, tweeter that I don't update that often because I hate Twitter, but I use it occasionally and I've been in the market for a house and I found a house and things are going well and it looks like very soon I'm going to be writing a very, very, very large check and becoming a member of the landowning gentry.
Rym: Finally, I will be able to vote.
Rym: I will be able to speak before the Senate.
Rym: I will get all the privileges of the landowning upper class.
Scott: That's, that, it's, it's 19, it's, actually no, it's 2009, not 1709.
Scott: So that When did this happen?
Rym: Yeah So you're saying that people who don't even own land have the right to vote?
Scott: I've voted.
Scott: You don't own any land.
Rym: I know That, that's a travesty.
Rym: Well How can, without the noblesse obligé, how can one possibly make complex decisions?
Scott: Well, in fact, the people who own land get fucked more because you have to pay the land tax that we, uh, we voted in, us non-landowners.
Rym: I thought taxes only applied to poor people and immigrants.
Scott: No, the taxes, in fact, apply more to the people with the land.
Rym: Well, luckily I have land so I can do something about it.
Scott: Uh, you prepared that well in advance.
Rym: Actually, no, I was going to make a different set of jokes But I can't tell you why, it's too stupid.
Rym: You still won't tell me what that is.
Scott: I wonder if anyone listening knows what that's for.
Rym: It's, uh, it's weird because I feel like I know what that's from, but I don't.
Scott: actually You don't, there's no way you know.
Rym: No, I know I don't, it's just too stupid.
Rym: But no, it's almost like I have an unreferenced pointer, I have this pointer and I see the pointer there and I say, all right, that pointer means I know what this is.
Rym: So I go in my brain to the pointer and it's not pointing anything It's a null pointer.
Rym: It's a null pointer, but I keep trying to reference it.
Scott: I will, uh, I will de-nullify your pointer soon enough.
Rym: Uh, okay You gonna wait for the crew to come out?
Rym: Because we have to show them a story from North America first.
Scott: No, no, it's not, it's not a video It's not a video?
Scott: No All right It's not, it's not something that can be gotten quickly.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So you ever wonder what happens to all those hats on the ice after a hat trick?
Scott: You don't get them back, I know that much.
Scott: I don't wonder what happens If you're throwing a hat, just, this is a note for people, right?
Scott: I was at the New York Giants Super Bowl victory parade Uh, wow, already two years ago And, uh, a kid in front of me, like, took his friend's, you know, Super Bowl victory hat And threw it to get it autographed Asshole.
Scott: The hat does not come back in, you know, it just doesn't happen.
Scott: So if you're getting ready to throw a hat on the ice, not an expensive hat Do not throw your fancy hat.
Rym: Well apparently the majority of hats that are thrown are either old, worn hats Like one that someone's been wearing forever Or they're just a throwaway hat that someone brought in a bag to throw in case there was a hat trick.
Rym: Exactly I used to, whenever I went to a hockey game, I always carried with me I had this really dumb hat that I hated.
Rym: It was just like, it had this, like, metal mesh on the brim.
Scott: Yeah, so you had a hat in one bag and an octopus in the other?
Rym: I didn't carry the octopus.
Rym: Octopi are too smart for me to feel happy throwing one on the ice.
Scott: They like it on the ice.
Rym: Nah, they're already dead.
Scott: They live in cold waters.
Rym: But I've seen octopuses thrown on the ice because I know it's a hockey tradition But it's much more prevalent in the midwest than it is everywhere else.
Rym: I mean, when I went to the Red Wing Stanley Cup playoffs back in the day, like '96, '97 They had a giant octopus thing called Stanley that would come down from the ceiling over the ice Called Stanley?
Rym: It was called Stanley, Stanley the Octopus.
Scott: That's not the thing to name it.
Rym: Little known fact, all you non-hockey fans You throw an octopus on the ice because there used to be eight games in the series Now it's seven, but they still throw octopuses because there are no seven-legged animals.
Rym: Yep But apparently, well, not apparently I found this article that explains what happens to the hats and it's kind of interesting.
Scott: What happens to the hats?
Rym: Oh, should I tell anyone or should I read the article?
Scott: Well, is it really that complex that you can't tell it quickly?
Rym: One, the players keep them, usually they take all the hats that aren't disgusting And they leave them in the dressing room of the player who scored the hat trick And he can do with them whatever he wants.
Scott: That's nice.
Scott: They throw away the scary hats The nasty hats the guy doesn't want to keep.
Scott: I would want all the hats, every single one.
Rym: Some teams actually.
Rym: what they do is they take all the hats They send them to a company just to get them steam cleaned really quick And then they donate them to charity.
Scott: That's good too.
Scott: You know, that's what happens to the, because you know the Super Bowl, right?
Scott: When the team wins, suddenly there's all these hats and t-shirts that say, you know New York Giants, Super Bowl 42 champions And all the hats and t-shirts that say New England Patriots, Super Bowl 42 champions.
Scott: They send those to Africa and places where, you know, no one in America will ever see them.
Rym: There was one time I did not, I had the hat, I did not throw it at the hat trick.
Rym: Whoa?
Rym: Because Sergei Fedorov scored two goals and he accidentally scored one against the Red Wings.
Rym: So it was technically a hat trick.
Scott: No, it's not.
Rym: The commentators counted it as one of the least.
Scott: It's not a hat trick.
Rym: Well, they lost the game too.
Rym: That's another kind of trick Of course, my brother, if you think I was into hockey, my brother, I remember he was Like the noise that came out of him was like a wookie dying.
Rym: There's also a picture here of a case, apparently the Columbus Blue Jackets.
Rym: Every time there's a hat trick, they put all the hats from the ice in this bin And they keep the bin on display And they've put every hat from every hat trick they've ever gotten since their first hat trick Which was in 2001 and there are not that many hats in there.
Scott: Well, it's not, it's a relatively new team and they're not that good.
Scott: Yeah, there aren't that many hats You know, they're not terrible, but they're not that good.
Rym: Okay That's all I got.
Scott: So I'm pretty sure this is not a duplicate thing of the day.
Scott: If it is, shoot me, right?
Scott: I checked the thing of the day feed and it was not in there.
Scott: And also I think I posted it in a forum maybe Just because I couldn't wait to post it somewhere.
Scott: But I'm pretty sure it was not a thing of the day.
Scott: Basically what this is, is a game called Wayfarer And what it is, it's a roguelike game.
Scott: If you've never played a roguelike game I think we've discussed them on the show previously It's pretty much a game just like NetHack or like Rogue, the original roguelike.
Scott: It's basically a dungeon crawl.
Scott: You walk around, you kill bad guys, you get treasure.
Scott: You know, you explore the dungeon, you know You see more dungeon as you explore.
Scott: The dungeon is randomly created You know, it's pretty much, you know, a straight up kind of RPG But not RPG in the good way, RPG in the dean.
Scott: It's like hero quest, one player.
Scott: That's what it is All right Right.
Scott: So Wayfarer is a roguelike Because most of them are sort of difficult to play and or annoying.
Scott: This is a web-based one that is Java powered, I think It's got some 3D action, but not really And it actually has a really good user interface And it makes it like a lot more pleasant to play A lot more accessible And actually sort of maybe a little bit fun And definitely a million times more fun than other roguelikes As far as I'm concerned Even though it's maybe less complex than other roguelikes.
Scott: But I mean, it's still alpha and it's already made it that far.
Scott: So I think there is actually a significant potential in this game And if you are bored and you got nothing better to do And you're on a computer with the web browser And you know, all the other games aren't really exciting.
Scott: you Why not?
Scott: It's free and it's an alpha, what the hell?
Rym: So onto the topic.
Rym: And we were inspired.
Rym: There was an article linked on Slashshot The perils of pop philosophy.
Rym: You should all read the article.
Rym: We're not really going to talk about the article in depth But it's a fantastic article Pretty
Scott: good
Rym: And it got us to talking a lot about the topic And then from there to this kind of broader concern That it's one of those things where the more I think about it The more I realize just how much it controls Or at least influences the interactions I have every day With every information source or destination in my entire life Including
Scott: this show.
Scott: even Definitely This show is a victim, right?
Scott: So here is the basic problem here, right?
Scott: Is?
Scott: the guy talks about The article references another article And the other article is discussing some philosophical topic, right?
Scott: And the guy who's writing this article Says basically Yeah, that other article is a load of shit, right?
Scott: But you wouldn't really know unless you were, you know, like a philosophy expert.
Scott: And he says here is my counter argument to that other article And it's a whole bunch of big fancy philosophy words That nobody who doesn't have a philosophy degree will be able to understand.
Scott: I didn't understand what he was saying at all.
Rym: What he basically, the gist of what he points out Is that if someone, it's very easy to make a stupid claim Or a fallacious argument It is very easy to refute that argument.
Rym: If you know about the topic It is almost impossible to refute that argument In a way that people who aren't familiar with the field Will see or understand.
Scott: Yeah, I mean by using all his big philosophy words And all his philosophy knowledge He was able to easily and trivially refute this other argument.
Scott: However, the only people who could understand and comprehend the refutation Were other philosophy experts And for him to make that refutation accessible to the mass populace He'd basically have to write an entire book Worth of normal non-philosophy talk, right?
Rym: And it goes further than this when you really think about it.
Rym: Because say someone makes a fallacious claim And even you're not trying to convince anyone else You don't have to explain the refutation to anyone else Just you're trying to argue with the person who made the fallacious claim.
Rym: Alright, you have ten different ways to refute them.
Rym: So you use one And they don't understand it Or you use two and they don't understand it Or you can't-.
Rym: Basically it comes down to the fact that you can't engage them On the level where the claim is fallacious.
Rym: If they're not able to engage you back.
Rym: They're not able to reciprocate Right?
Rym: So if I engage- If I make a claim at level one And someone else refutes it at level one Basically they're equal.
Rym: There's no real way to determine which one is right.
Scott: It happens with science a lot, right?
Scott: You get like some person who comes around And they're not an expert in science They don't know anything about, you know They know the world is made of atoms and molecules And that's about it, right?
Scott: So they come and say some bullshit about evolution or something And they're completely wrong.
Scott: But you go to explain why they're wrong And you're a biologist.
Scott: So the only people who understand what you're saying are biologists.
Scott: And for you to get this non-biologist person to understand why they're wrong You basically have to give them a university biology education.
Scott: first.
Rym: It comes down to the fact that the refutation of some kinds of fallacies Is in a higher order than the fallacy itself And it's not- So it's one order to make the fallacy But it is impossible to refute the fallacy without making a higher order argument.
Scott: And it's not just in arguing either It's just in general comprehension, right?
Scott: I mean, you know, some guy writes a newspaper article that speaks very colloquially And is completely wrong because it, you know, summarizes and generalizes.
Scott: But people understand it And it sort of makes sense on the level at which people are thinking.
Scott: And these people have never thought about the topic on a higher level And don't have the education or expertise or whatever they need To understand the higher levels of the particular topic.
Scott: And as it stands in that state, it makes perfect sense.
Scott: And they go on believing this thing.
Scott: And that's that, you know People think in their minds about things, you know People- some guy who's, say, I don't know, an engineer, right?
Scott: Will think about, say, you know, medicine in some simple way Because he's not an engineer But he's thinking about medicine in the highest order that he can think about medicine And he'll come up with something.
Scott: And thus he now, you know, believes something about medicine.
Scott: that's probably wrong Because, you know, he doesn't have the knowledge in that higher order in that department.
Rym: But what I really want to talk about?
Rym: We could go on and on about this specific topic But there's not a lot to say But I think the more general interesting topic is the interactions between people on the internet Or in real life where one person wants to engage on one level Another person can't or won't engage on that level.
Rym: Or the situation where you have a topic Where the only way you can have a meaningful conversation is to engage at a higher level.
Scott: Right, because all of the low-level things are sort of already figured out.
Scott: I mean, when you try to talk philosophy with your friends You might think you're all smart and stuff, but really It's all just shadows on a wall.
Scott: Yeah, right The thing is, right, you know, real philosophers, you know People who really know this shit and write books.
Scott: And, well, not everyone, some people write bullshit books.
Scott: But, you know, real philosophers, right?
Scott: Wait, wait, real Real We're getting some Scotsman in the house.
Scott: I understand that's a Faujo Andrew Scotsman.
Rym: But, oh, someone made a website of a graphic for every logical fallacy And the Andrew Scotsman was just an angry willy.
Scott: That's good.
Scott: But they, you know, they figured out everything you were saying And you're basically treading over well-tread ground.
Scott: You're rebuilding already built wheels, you know.
Scott: So, in order to sort of get into new areas of thought You really have to sort of learn all the, you know, things that have come before And crawl up to the, you know, to the higher level.
Scott: Imagine if, say, we're all, all of humanity together is building a ladder, right?
Scott: And the ladder is 10 steps tall and we need the 11th step.
Scott: But only people on the 10th step can build the 11th step.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: You're down on the third step You don't know the fourth step exists and you think you're all smart Figuring out the fourth step.
Rym: You know, you know what you just said?
Rym: It's almost word for word from the fourth way.
Scott: I know Stupid fourth way.
Scott: Oh, so close, but still crazy Right, you know, and it's sort of like, hey, if you don't, you know, see all the steps that are already there You're just, you know, what are you doing?
Rym: I don't think we need more analogies.
Scott: I think it's I love analogies.
Scott: I'm the analogy master.
Rym: It's a real world thing where I have this problem personally.
Rym: My interest in the topic is that many times I'll be in.
Rym: I guess I'm in low level mode.
Rym: when I'm walking around in the street I don't expect anyone to a stranger to out of the blue while I'm like walking and eating my baguette.
Rym: to engage me suddenly on a high level.
Rym: There's usually kind of like, we all go through this When you talk to someone, you don't know where there's the probe.
Rym: You probe each other.
Rym: It's like a protocol, a handshake Where you both feel out what the level of discourse is going to be for the remainder of this new conversation This new encounter.
Rym: You know, you make the comment about the weather.
Rym: They say something back about the weather.
Rym: You've established that baseline level.
Rym: You mention, you make an offering about politics.
Rym: You see if they make a high or low level statement And then you respond accordingly.
Rym: And then the discourse is set and you have your discussion.
Rym: But much like in Burning Wheel, the blossoms are falling setting.
Rym: I was thinking about this a lot In that setting, it's based in like old Japan.
Rym: So there are different levels of formality of the Japanese language And the rules in the game are that you test against another player to see what you as a group set the level of discourse.
Rym: as for your discussion And depending on the level of discourse Some topics are or are not allowed to be broached without a serious breach of etiquette.
Rym: And the same thing happens in real life.
Rym: I mean, say I'm sitting on the train and guy next to me says something about politics Like blah, blah, Obama.
Rym: Now I have a choice to engage them on their level Higher level, lower level.
Rym: I don't know really what their level is at.
Rym: But if they won't engage on the higher level Like if someone is just a Democrat or a Republican And the only argument they have for being a Democrat or a Republican is like the talking point of their pundit of choice on either side There is no possible way I can have a conversation that'll be meaningful with this person Unless I either force them to engage on a higher level Or I don't know, not talk to them and not have the... I guess it might be meaningful for them But how is it meaningful for me if they only have talking points?
Rym: I've already heard every talking point.
Rym: I already have a reputation for every talking point.
Scott: They can't comprehend any of them.
Rym: So what's the point of even discoursing?
Rym: What's the point of even engaging at that point?
Scott: Well, I mean, you know, to give you, you know In that example, I can't think of a reason to engage.
Scott: But for example, on our show We will often discuss things related to game theory, right?
Scott: But we will not engage the game theory topics on the highest level You know, and the point is that even though the audience Some of the audience, I'm sure, would understand it But most of the audience, we assume, does not And we try to, you know, say things in a way that they will comprehend them.
Rym: You know, we won't say "Oh, that's...".
Scott: You know, because I mean, we could end the show in like a second Like we're discussing a game, we'll be like "Yeah, that's just, you know, zero sum perfect information game".
Scott: "Oh, okay".
Rym: Yeah, well, how many states does it have?
Rym: 10 to the sixth?
Scott: Yeah, all right.
Scott: So, all right, but, you know, instead, you know When we're discussing on the show, sometimes we either A) We take the route of giving all the full We engage on the high level, but we break the words down And go on longer so that they get the full idea Or we simplify to get just given the gist, right?
Scott: And hopefully we can educate them over time and bring them up to the higher level.
Rym: How noble of you I know, right?
Scott: But, you know, there are many, I'm sure, you know That's on the topics that we're familiar with.
Scott: There are many topics for which we cannot engage on the high level.
Rym: For example, we'll say something about, we talk about viruses.
Scott: How many times do we say something stupid on the show?
Scott: Every day, we've probably already said 20 stupid things on the show.
Rym: How many times do we say something about viruses?
Rym: And then, you know, the next morning I get an email from Scott Johnson and Pete and Lisa Yeah, right Viruses do not work that way You know, or we say stupid things about like economics or who knows what else.
Rym: I mean, that other article really points it out is that The long form debate almost never happens in modern society Because no one has the patience and no one's going to pay attention.
Rym: And generally the people who are up for a long time debate or a long form debate Are the ones who are already trying to engage at a higher level in the first place.
Scott: Exactly, I mean, you know, and this goes back to that Neil Postman book that you disagreed with, right?
Scott: Where he was talking about how, you know, the medium is the message.
Scott: He talked about how Lincoln Douglas would, you know, debate for reals And people would sit there for hours and they would debate at a very high level.
Scott: And if you look at the old newspapers, you know, it was much higher level.
Rym: I guess I disagree with a lot of his conclusions Because a lot of what he predicted did not come to pass.
Scott: I don't know, that book was from the 80s, I think Yeah Right, so, I mean, you know, the major point of the book, though, was that, you know, The medium in which you are communicating, right, you know, modifies the message.
Scott: On TV, you can't have these long, boring things Because when you do, you get, like, that boring PBS news show that nobody watches.
Rym: But, Scott, I love things like that.
Scott: You do, but most people don't, right?
Rym: Yes, but I don't think it's.
Scott: And he talks about how, you know, this medium is, you know, The mediums of the olden days are better for the long-form, higher level.
Scott: And you look at the internets, right, the internet is good for Twitter.
Scott: They just shorten everything, the shorter the better.
Rym: Scott, I disagree that the medium forces the message.
Scott: It doesn't force, but it has optimized a particular message.
Scott: And even though you could put any sort of message in any sort of medium, It won't, no one will go for it.
Rym: No, see, Scott, I also disagree that it's even optimized for a particular message.
Rym: All it is, is that society itself, people generally are lazy And would rather not engage on a high level.
Rym: in most cases And even back then, I would wager that not that many people in the US Understood what was going on in Lincoln vs.
Rym: Douglas.
Rym: I don't know, do you How many people were all for the Civil War and the South?
Rym: They clearly couldn't win.
Rym: Any high level debate would have pointed that out.
Scott: Well, that was just because in those days, right, they didn't have the, you know, The amount of information that we have today.
Scott: Everyone knows everything about everything everywhere.
Scott: I don't want to get into Neil Postman because I disagree with a great majority But it's the same thing that you're saying now, talking about the high level and the low level.
Rym: But I don't think it has anything to do with the medium, it's just people.
Scott: I don't know about that.
Rym: People generally avoid the high level discourse Partly because high level discourse takes a long time.
Scott: The high level discourse was commonplace in the olden days.
Rym: Yeah, it was.
Rym: I don't think it was.
Rym: You look at the, you know, the "reading level" of, you know, as you go back in time Scott, I point out as you go back in time, you're looking at the reading level of a smaller And smaller subset of the literate population.
Scott: Is this true?
Rym: I mean, the further back you go, who is literate?
Rym: The wealthy aristocrats and the philosophers and the people like that The people with schooling, learning and knowledge.
Rym: You had a smaller, more literate set.
Scott: So what are you saying?
Scott: So you're saying that now, right?
Scott: You're basically saying it's no different now That even though the people are literate, they're still not as smart as the, you know.
Scott: So really, still, even though everyone can read the words technically Only the people who are actually educated and wealthy and whatnot are really literate.
Scott: Is that what you're saying?
Rym: I think there's a strong correlation.
Rym: Sadly Alrighty then You said that like you're going to use this in some sort of argument against me No, I just wanted to put that on the table.
Scott: Alright It's out there.
Scott: I
Rym: think it's more that the general, as we democratize access to distribution of ideas And consumption of ideas, that does not necessarily precipitate the full dissemination of those ideas Because every person, regardless of their abilities, is exposed to them But not everyone can get the same thing out of them.
Rym: I mean, an idea is a meme And a meme can spread And some people can take on and then retransmit larger memes than other people.
Rym: So maybe the same percentage of people throughout history just have the innate ability to handle large memes And some people can be trained to.
Rym: Some people can't Some people refuse to.
Rym: But the result is that if you add more people to the water where the meme virus is spreading That does not necessarily mean that that meme virus will spread to all those people.
Rym: And I think the problem with this pop philosophy idea?
Rym: Well not the problem with the idea.
Rym: The problem it portends Is that memes spread if they're compact little concise things.
Rym: That if more people can spread a meme, it's going to spread more rapidly.
Scott: Because if only one percent It's like, you know, if you go to baseball at any stadium, right?
Scott: The more people that you want to get to do something in unison The simpler it has to be, right?
Scott: If you want to get, say, 10 people to like sing a song You could do that.
Scott: You just give everyone the lyrics on a piece of paper, right?
Scott: But try to get a hundred people to sing a song.
Rym: There's one answer, soccer hooligans Ten thousand, they can be so drunk they can't see five feet in front of their faces.
Scott: They can sing that song Right, but I mean, you know, they can't sing, you know, say a complicated song.
Scott: And they have to, you know, getting them, they have to know that song in advance And they've trained and learned the song over a great period of time.
Scott: If you just get a bunch of brand new people, you can do the wave And maybe you can clap in unison And maybe you can say like one or two words in unison But it's very difficult to get them to say, you know, do a complex thing.
Rym: But if you let me finish my point and what I think was really happening I think what Postman was observing But now we can see it with hindsight more clearly Is that it's not the particular merits of any kind of media.
Rym: It's simply that more media is more bi-directional and unidirectional.
Rym: So now we kind of have a wider pool Where smaller pieces of information spread more rapidly and have more enduring power.
Rym: So simply because we have more low-power transmitters Instead of a few high-power transmitters Smaller, more low-powered pieces of information Are the ones that are more fit to survive in the broad population.
Rym: That's exactly what, you're not disagreeing with him at all No, because he's saying that the way the kind of media does it And he made all these arguments that television forces The transmission of the media is part of its kind.
Scott: No, but Is an aspect of its kind.
Rym: I'm making the much broader argument that it's the fact that it's transmitted at all Is the only factor Doesn't matter how it's transmitted All that matters is that it is transmitted in any form.
Rym: And because more information can be transmitted more quickly in general We self-select toward the smaller pieces of information.
Scott: That is one aspect of it, yes That's my whole argument.
Scott: Alright, so I think you're on a lower level then?
Rym: No, I really, I just, I don't, I think his book was kind of crap And I think he made a lot of good points But I think he made a lot of spurious conclusions.
Scott: Yeah, anyway.
Scott: So yeah, it's just, you know What is there, can we come up with any sort of solution for this problem, right?
Scott: We want more PR, if we have this great thing, right?
Scott: That we have basically the whole world almost, right?
Scott: Is able to communicate with each other Without, you know, any significant hampering of time Or amount of information.
Scott: Or, you know, we can basically get on webcams with everyone all at once, right?
Scott: So we want people to sort of get new things Instead of just, you know, continuing to mull down low.
Scott: We want, you know, the highest level, most useful, you know, conversations to be happening As opposed to people just, you know, basically bullshitting Thinking that they're on the high level.
Scott: It might be impossible.
Scott: It might be impossible Alright, so let's assume it's not impossible.
Scott: In what scenario would we, any chance of it occurring?
Rym: I think what it shows more is some of the, like.
Rym: I think it is either the root or the symptom of the root Of a lot of the problems we have in the world today.
Rym: I mean, look at the inherent problems of democracy.
Rym: Look at the national dialogue about any popular topic in the United States.
Scott: That is definitely, absolutely true.
Rym: Almost all the discussion of any topic boils down to.
Rym: I wouldn't even call them talking points.
Rym: They're just, like, the abortion debate.
Rym: A lot of the people who are anti-abortion don't have any argument or anything All they have.
Scott: A lot of people who are pro-choice don't really have much of an argument either You know, they just boil everything down to the, you know, these incredibly simple things When the issue is ludicrously complex.
Rym: Well, Scott, the thing is, with abortion in particular If you move to the higher levels, I think it's clear that one side has a Well, I'm not saying, I also agree that the pro-choice side is correct.
Scott: I'm saying is that many of the people who argue, even though they're on the correct side Their argument is not on the highest level And that, you know, I could actually, you know, in some cases I could argue for the wrong side using a higher level argument And beat some of the people on the right side who have a
Rym: lower level argument.
Rym: No, you can't beat them because someone who makes a Remember, someone who makes, in one particular field We're not arguing about the intelligence of our human Just about the capability to transmit and relay a single meme In the abortion debate, someone who can only transmit these small, pro- or anti-meme Cannot be affected by the larger meme in any capacity.
Rym: It cannot get to them unless you boil it down.
Rym: And it is possible to take a large, complex meme Make it compact and still make it true.
Rym: If you make a good argument at the high level And you boil the argument down to a very small, compact thing The end argument is still absolutely true And your little, compact thing is right.
Rym: The problem is, it's very powerful, but it loses kind of the redundancy.
Rym: It loses, like, its own self-referential metadata.
Rym: So it's really easy to corrupt it and use it for the wrong purposes.
Rym: Like, I make a boiled-down argument that is pro-choice, completely And while pro-choice, I think, is the absolutely inarguably correct philosophical And practical argument on all high level.
Rym: I think most intelligent people agree on that point But I can make a boiled-down argument that is pro-choice.
Rym: That is equally valid.
Rym: However, because it's boiled down, it's so broad and tiny now Broad in scope, tiny in reference It is now a powerful philosophical hammer that people can use To back up very poor, unrelated ideas.
Rym: It's the whole thing of libertarianism on the high level Is a great and fantastic field of debate.
Rym: On the low level, it effectively turns into the rationale for I do what I want, I do what I want Right And that's bad.
Scott: Well, I mean, you know, this makes me think of people Like, say, Ben Stein or Michael Moore, right?
Scott: Two people who are basically completely wrong about a great, great many things To the majority of the time, right?
Scott: And what they tend to do is they go and they make, you know, they make, you know, movies Or they get on TV and they talk And they're slightly above, you know, the lowest level, right?
Scott: They get lots of information in there, you know, usually And they're smart people.
Scott: Yeah, they're very smart, intelligent, right?
Scott: They know what's going on And, you know, they get their information, you know Even if their opinions or stances might be wrong Most of their information is correct, you know Their, you know, their core facts.
Rym: I'll argue the technically correct Right, technically correct, right.
Scott: That's what I mean.
Scott: But, you know, what they'll do is then they'll then deliver it in some sort of package.
Scott: You know, that supports basically anything You could take, you know, you could, like, take all the facts out of, say, a Michael Moore movie And make a movie that argues against Michael Moore 100% With the same exact facts just by changing, you know, the other parts.
Rym: And it's like The libertarian thing is the best example Where regardless of the high level rationale The low level pop philosophy meme is the rationale to do whatever you want.
Rym: It's the Hitler rationale.
Scott: Exactly So, and unless people are engaging at the high level If they're down at the low level, they can't really, that's it It's done.
Scott: There's nothing, they can't contribute.
Rym: It's almost like these low level memes At least these philosophy memes that people use to back bad ideas.
Rym: It's like you have a responsible gun owner And, you know, philosophers are all effectively philosophical brain gun owners.
Rym: They all have, they're responsible owners of very powerful guns.
Rym: But if you boil down your philosophy to a meme and you're not extremely careful.
Rym: That's the equivalent of taking your gun and giving it to someone who is blind and stupid And showing them where the trigger is and saying have fun I'll come back in a week.
Scott: Yeah, because, you know, to give, you know, I don't know, I can't come up with any.
Rym: But now look at this, look at what I just did.
Rym: If I take this argument and I boil what I just said down into a meme You could trivially use that to rationalize ivory tower bullshit.
Rym: That's true Keeping knowledge from the masses.
Rym: And it would be trivial to rationalize that with the pop philosophy thing I just spouted Because the high order argument is so long that it won't spread in the memeosphere.
Rym: I'll never use that word again in my life and I apologize for saying it.
Scott: Well, yeah, but yeah, a high level, a high level idea has lots of ifs and ands and buts And this and that, right?
Scott: I mean, look at something like, you know, discussion about like, you know, swine flu.
Scott: It's like, well, it could spread like this.
Scott: And, you know, the actual reality is incredibly complex Ludicrously complex, you know.
Scott: Actually, random aside People boil, you know, that complexity down into, you know, these simple ideas, you know Random aside And they use those simple ideas to make their decisions.
Scott: And really, no, it's very complex And your decision making, you know, is not taking the, you know, your, your is basically effective.
Scott: You might as well be acting randomly the way you're making decisions, you know.
Rym: So I guess there are two immediate questions.
Rym: One, is there a way to foster a society where the either the intellectually large memes can spread Or where the intellectually large memes have more weight regardless of how many people wield them?
Rym: Or where people, where these memes can be boiled down in such a way That people who aren't going to engage on the top level can still engage on a meaningful level?
Rym: Uh, people, uh Can any of these be accomplished?
Scott: Well, I don't know if you can engage at a meaningful level in an area.
Scott: if you are, you know If you haven't just learned all, you know, the things you need to know to get up there.
Scott: It's like if you haven't climbed the stair 10, you're not gonna, you're not involved in the 11th stair building.
Rym: I have run into many people in my life who I know are perfectly capable Of engaging me on a higher level than they do And they just don't Mmm.
Rym: There is definitely a difference between the people, between the will nots and the can nots.
Rym: Mmm, that's very interesting And I don't know what to do about that.
Rym: And then that raises the whole other ethical question of Say there are.
Scott: That's just the issue of, you know, apathy.
Rym: Yes, but even say there are will nots and there are can nots What do you do with the will nots?
Rym: What do you do with the can nots?
Rym: And how do you not make a meme for dealing with them that turns into genocide or eugenics?
Scott: Uh, you know, whenever we do anything like this, you know, it's always like, well, how can we fix the world?
Scott: Well, you know, you do what you can and that's it.
Scott: But it really
Rym: bothers me because it seems like every philosophy, no matter what it is No matter what it really says is boiled down generally and widely into I don't want to say a soundbite, but a meme so small in reference and so wide in scope That any possible course of action that any person could take in the entire world Whether it's good, whether it's bad, genocide, killing babies, whatever Is eminently justifiable if you use only low level memes.
Scott: Yeah, go and look at like, you know, people always.
Scott: One thing that people really like, I really like are like quotes, right?
Scott: You know, aphorisms perhaps?
Scott: Yes, you know, you find some famous person, a Thomas Jefferson or a Benjamin Franklin.
Rym: Those who would give up liberty for security deserve neither.
Scott: You find some quote and you say the quote and then someone else goes, Oh, that is very wise and makes perfect sense.
Scott: And then you say some other quote, Oh, that is very wise and makes perfect sense, right?
Scott: But it's great when you say like two quotes that are both so wise, like, you know, But they completely disagree.
Rym: Or, I mean, look, like those who give up liberty for security deserve neither.
Rym: You could use that to rationalize the taking away of security from people.
Rym: If you really wanted to Yeah You could probably argue for taking away liberty.
Scott: You know, I mean, you could look, Oh, the tree of liberty must, you know, From time to time be refreshed with the blood of patriots.
Scott: Well, you could take that to mean Vampires.
Scott: Yeah, you know, once in a while, you've just got to kill your own people.
Scott: That's just how it's got to be.
Rym: Maybe that is how it's got to be You know, maybe I think the problem is the academics always look for the ivory tower.
Rym: I think we need the crimson tower.
Scott: The crimson tower must be frequently refreshed with the blood of the academics.
Scott: Come here, Roux style.
Rym: No, I think the blood should flow upward.
Scott: So it's like Ganesh, the milk just goes up.
Rym: But that means we got to beat Newton because he's going to fuck us on this one.
Rym: All right I think we've exhausted this topic.
Rym: I think I've said every low level piece of discourse I have.
Rym: And don't forget this weekend, Saturday, we'll be at the mocha.
Rym: You'll find us Saturday, not Sunday.
Rym: Very likely Saturday We will post somewhere if it ends up being Sunday.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Frapper map, and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights And Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com Or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Scott: Just click the link that says "send me an Odeo" on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives, visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.