Rym: It's Tuesday August 13th 2019.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: Super Mario maker to Make it your way play it your way Let's do this.
Rym: So uh in New York you see Brands from around the world that you really don't see in other American cities just in random places like bodegas and gas stations and grocery stores.
Rym: It's just.
Rym: it's one of the nice perks of living here.
Scott: like what?
Rym: Just like random like German candy.
Rym: We're like random Danish crap or like Japanese or Korean grocery stores I thought you're talking about like tempeh.
Scott: Oh, no.
Scott: No you can't get tempeh cream cheese if you don't live in New York.
Rym: I mean if we want to get into that I'll tell you how you can't get Colby cheese in New York.
Rym: Uh-huh some of the grocery store the other day And I saw a brand from a country that I very rarely see stuff from here.
Rym: I saw a Turkish beer.
Rym: all right If this is the type of beer I would have wealthy brand that I would always drink.
Scott: Was it actually made in Turkey was like bottled here or something like cuz?
Scott: you know the Japanese beer they buy.
Scott: Right you go to.
Scott: it says imported.
Scott: It's imported from Canada.
Scott: They have a separate place where they make and bottled some Japanese beers in Canada And they literally just do it in Canada.
Rym: so they can say imported and your stupid brain will Assume it was imported from Japan.
Scott: The law should have make it so they have to say imported from.
Scott: they shouldn't be able to just say Imported.
Rym: I mean they do say that in tiny tiny print that people don't notice.
Scott: yeah They do, but you know are you sure it was so?
Scott: was this actually imported from Turkey?
Scott: Yeah, because no one makes this outside of Turkey all right, so how aren't there like you know trade problems with Turkey?
Rym: No, there are not trade problems with the Turkey.
Rym: the problems with the Turkey right now are around the regime and around them falling increasingly under Sphere of I almost said Soviet, but Russian influence.
Scott: right.
Scott: so wouldn't we not buy beer from heaven?
Rym: no cuz that's not how Economic diplomacy works.
Rym: So what the interesting thing was the brand F is.
Rym: it's just like it You know basically in more like in that part of the world and in Asia You pretty much only find really really light really really weak tasting beer.
Rym: That's just how it is.
Scott: Yeah, I mean Europe is and you know German Belgium.
Rym: That's where the strong beer thing is that you know that's kind of a misconception cuz even in Germany like when it's summer people drink Way light wheat beer and they tend to like I mean I don't drink any beers.
Scott: But I would imagine if it's summertime you would want to drink something more light and refreshing and in the winter you would want to Drink something heavier.
Rym: Yeah, usually, but in Germany like a lot of people like really light beer.
Rym: It's just how it is in most places.
Rym: people don't like real good beer.
Rym: But I digress in Turkey you can really only get like really light pilsners and things and a lot of Asian beer.
Rym: So the brand F is is just one of those beers like.
Rym: it's not actually that good.
Rym: It's just kind of nostalgic, but I noticed something else.
Rym: They only have one kind of F. is the alcohol-free one?
Rym: Because alcohol-free F is is sold in countries where drinking alcohol is not okay like Muslim country yes.
Rym: So I saw it there, but because it was the alcohol-free one.
Rym: I didn't buy it and It sat there.
Rym: There's just one.
Rym: there was no other.
Rym: they're just like this one section that had a few six packs of F is like by itself Mm-hmm and then eventually after like a week I saw the price went down and after another week the price went.
Scott: was it still good?
Rym: I mean beer doesn't really go bad in the fridge.
Rym: So eventually this is only the core over the course of like a month.
Rym: so today I went to get some groceries on the way home And I see that it is now on sale to the point that it was like four dollars for how much for six bottles.
Scott: Okay, so I bought it.
Scott: okay Drinking alcohol-free F is.
Rym: I've never actually had alcohol-free F is and I'm curious to see what it tastes like because I Primarily enjoy beer because of the flavor.
Rym: so if this tastes like regular F is and just happens not have alcohol It's a good.
Scott: so how do they remove the alcohol?
Scott: I'm like you remove the alcohol from bread because you fucking put it in the oven right at a zillion degrees.
Scott: How do you remove the alcohol from beer?
Rym: How does this different kind somehow?
Rym: so they put like an enzyme that eats the alcohol and some of these beers are just low Alcohol like it's 2% like the beer kids would drink and some of these beers.
Rym: They actually remove most if not all the alcohol.
Rym: I'm just curious to see what this tastes like.
Rym: and the funny thing is it even has the weird Pull-tab tops that bottles of beer tend to have in Asia and parts of like Eastern Europe.
Rym: hmm So yeah, I've got some effies in my fridge, which is not something I would be able to say I have not had.
Scott: F is since the last time I was in Turkey Which was right before the coup attempt, but I mean even if it does taste like it like this didn't you just say it's bad?
Rym: It's not that it's not bad.
Rym: It's just not particularly good.
Rym: It's just nostalgic.
Rym: It's kind of like that Dublin doctor pepper.
Rym: I got it a few times.
Rym: when I get that instead I'm thinking about getting some of that again But they won't ship it here in the summer because it might go bad as I got away for the winter.
Rym: I was thinking about getting one shipment of that one last one last glory day of some Western sugar water.
Rym: So uh there's a lot of gaming news.
Rym: We're gonna have to pick and choose because a lot of game news has happened, but simultaneously a bunch of new stuff happened Mm-hmm, so I want to start with this.
Rym: It's only gaming adjacent But it's important to get out there loot crate Which is an exploitative business model like.
Rym: I have basically hated loot crate from the moment I realized this was a legitimate company selling a thing right.
Scott: there are a lot of subscription box services and you know the.
Scott: the subscription box itself isn't necessarily a problematic business model.
Rym: right usually it is though it usually it is.
Scott: but the loot crate one Specifically is one where it's like you buy random shit.
Scott: right at least there are clothing ones.
Scott: Or it's like buy random clothes and back What you don't want right?
Rym: did stitch fix?
Scott: you know a lot of it.
Rym: the ones that sell shirt is from stitch fix this like Weird Henley with the half-length like.
Scott: there are also ones that sell have consumable stuff in a box for example like a blue apron Or whatever.
Scott: right I made the ones that send like regular like.
Scott: I think there's one out there That does like like toilet paper and all that sort of stuff.
Scott: You use it all up right and that's not the worst.
Scott: But loot crate the way it worked.
Scott: if you haven't heard us say this before we have many times.
Scott: They take the junk that nerdy stores couldn't sell.
Scott: all the stuff That's on the shelf at the comic book store and is always there and no one ever buys it like the Funko pop of the D-list character right and all that stuff.
Scott: it's like the store paid money to get it and it sits and takes up shelf space and it costs the store money.
Scott: if The store could get rid of it.
Scott: You know they could throw it out, which is still would be good.
Scott: But you know they can't sell it.
Scott: They if they could get even one penny for it They would make out so and no one wants it.
Rym: So you can't actually just like sell it even at like.
Rym: you can't go to a convention But in the clearance you clearance bin.
Scott: no still no one buys it.
Scott: in the clearance bin It just does not sell.
Scott: so loot crate goes and for almost nothing scoops up tons of inventory not even necessarily from stores But from like you know the warehouses in the wholesale market.
Scott: like we couldn't.
Scott: no stores bought all these figurines.
Scott: We made too many, or you know maybe it's promotional materials.
Scott: It's effectively advertising.
Scott: It's like all right These aren't extras no one wanted.
Scott: I'm making these specifically to shove them in loot crates.
Scott: that way they will effectively be Advertisements because now I've inserted my thing into all these people's houses, and I'll pay loot crate.
Scott: in fact to put this in the box It's like please create put this garbage in your box.
Scott: that way ever.
Scott: all of your customers are being advertised to and now loot crate Makes money on both ends.
Scott: you be will pay to put an ad in the box And then people buy to pay to buy a box with ads in it and then
Rym: even better Once someone's hooked on this because they want their nerd crap then they only need to occasionally have anything even remotely worthwhile.
Scott: There's some consumerist nerds right who are Materialistic and just like getting stuff and then they open the box And it's like surprise, and they really get hooked on.
Scott: surprise is busy gambling.
Rym: no It's not necessarily their fault because this is that variable reward schedule brain hacking stuff.
Rym: Yeah like Remember the sword equation if you ever have money and a desire for swords at the same time your life is over.
Scott: Yeah, so people pay for loot crate.
Scott: loot crate shows up.
Scott: It's a bunch of garbage, but apparently not enough people fell for it because they're going bankrupt.
Scott: Yep
Rym: Well, I think part of why they're going bankrupt is that they were the first one and a lot of people Expected this to be bigger than it was coupled with the fact that Nerds aren't buying it as much of this stuff anymore,
Scott: and
Rym: there's a bunch of other companies competing with loot crate.
Scott: Yeah, it also says that they've got a lot of debt.
Scott: Yeah, and taxes that they haven't paid yeah.
Scott: So they're in trouble.
Rym: it sounds like it was not.
Rym: Despite the fact that the business model was questionable at best the business was run poor.
Rym: the business was run very poorly.
Rym: They've laid off 50 people.
Rym: they filed for chapter 11 bankruptcy Had 50 people.
Scott: Wow doesn't take a lot of it doesn't take 50 people to do that.
Scott: Yeah, so we could outsource most of the business.
Rym: It's got to the point that their credit card processor is withholding customer billings.
Rym: Yeah, they haven't shipped goods tied to 20 million dollars in sales, so I get the impression a ton of nerds Still paying them and aren't gonna get anything.
Rym: When they're not in that money isn't even gonna go to them It's gonna go to the credit card process.
Scott: I guess if you're if you were sad or dumb or foolish enough to pay loot crate cancel that shit now because otherwise you're just Gonna be sending money to some debtor or to some I guess daddy.
Scott: Yeah, lender lender.
Scott: so someone loot crate owes money to and you ain't gonna get shit.
Scott: you even get ads You ain't gonna get.
Rym: oh my god I just felt real old loot crate was founded in 2012. if you go back to 2012 you'll probably find a lot of GeekNights Episodes where we're bitching about this thing.
Rym: probably we were probably really well.
Rym: We were really mad.
Scott: Don't rest in peace.
Scott: I rub my butt on your grave.
Rym: Quote one of the fastest-growing startups loot crates woes began after defaulting on a loan in 2017.
Scott: yep all right that low.
Rym: no this is important.
Rym: that loan was later refinanced and has now been purchased by Money chest LLC.
Scott: that sounds like a great company.
Rym: Money chest that sounds like easy pod Which will provide loot crate with a 10 million dollar?
Rym: Bankruptcy loan and will serve as its stalking horse bidder, so this money chest company is basically buying loot crate out effectively.
Scott: good luck.
Rym: I Do not trust this company - I feel like there's shenanigans going on with this bankruptcy.
Rym: actually the more I read this.
Rym: hmm I'm not an insider.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I'm purely speculating Sue me, but you don't for the lawyer.
Scott: Bye if you weren't gonna buy the stuff Seeing it then it's not something you're willing to pay money for.
Scott: yeah, don't buy Surprise.
Scott: if you want surprise you can just have your friends take stuff and put it in boxes and trade it with your each other.
Scott: I'm telling you guys which of the things I own is this Free surprise.
Rym: should I finally do it I was thinking about.
Rym: we talked about this a while ago.
Rym: You're even kind of on board of adding a tear to the GeekNights patreon of the GeekNights loot crate And if you're at that tear every moment like every couple months We'll just mail you stuff.
Scott: I'll tell you what I'm gonna get.
Rym: you're gonna get a whole bunch of books I'm trying to get rid of for the cost of shipping.
Scott: I will send you random crap from my house that I'm trying to get rid of.
Scott: it will be nerdy stuff of some kind.
Scott: I Will.
Rym: I might actually just make this a tear on the patreon because if someone does it you're.
Scott: I guarantee GeekNights when I go cover the shipping of heavy nerd stuff.
Rym: Yeah But GeekNights will not go bankrupt and you will in fact get packages from.
Scott: anyone wants free nerd stuff Contact me and get yourself to my apartment and I will give you piles of nerd stuff.
Scott: You have no saying what it is.
Rym: It's stuff I'm trying to get rid of and it won't even be bad because we tend to not buy bad stuff.
Scott: It could be just.
Scott: I can't make no claims about the quality or how much you will want it.
Scott: You could maybe sell it on your own, but I don't have time.
Rym: I might just mail you all of dr.
Rym: Slump.
Rym: So in some other news, there's a bunch of news from like Gen Con and all this stuff.
Scott: Yeah, you know, it's Gen Con says a lot of board game news But the biggest board game news is actually digital board game news.
Scott: Yeah the long-awaited Root digital edition now has a trailer that shows what it looks like and it looking good.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: It looks good.
Rym: We have no other content.
Rym: I'm like no other.
Rym: we don't know what this will actually entail other than that.
Rym: It is just root.
Scott: It will let you play root digitally.
Scott: who knows single-player multi who knows we don't have any details but Play root on a digital device of some kind.
Rym: now This isn't probably
Scott: a computer or a phone or a tablet or who knows because root a switch I don't know
Rym: is probably one of the most influential and important tabletop games in recent memory in terms of reach in terms of Expanding interest in the hobby at
Scott: least people who are in the hobby
Rym: Yeah, but of people in.
Scott: you don't see root is not in target as far as I know.
Scott: But
Rym: people who are in the hobby but tend to not play heavier games are Tricked into playing a root and then discover that they actually like these sort of mean war games and things Mmm, like I see a lot of people who would never have played a game like this.
Rym: It was branded differently and then they get vicious.
Rym: But the other thing that's going on here in general is that the tabletop industry is kind of a huge bubble right now.
Scott: Oh, yeah been for I'm sorry.
Scott: I don't understand how it has not popped after so many years.
Scott: What is keeping that bubble inflating?
Rym: well So part of what is keeping that bubble inflating is all these Kickstarter games that are bad But include minis and people buy these games never actually play them and just keep backing these kickstarters.
Rym: Yeah, that's true.
Rym: Like there's a lot of Kickstarter board games.
Scott: That's not keeping like the publishers around right then, you know.
Rym: So the publishers are just consolidating.
Scott: Consolidating because increase there's only one only as mode a seems to be buying up lots of companies.
Scott: I don't see anyone else consolidating really.
Rym: but in terms of like the people who design games are increasingly working for a smaller number of places and independent game designers are having a harder and harder time even getting in front of the publishers because the publishers have Their own game designers like in their stables.
Scott: It's something to do.
Scott: some of them don't and the ones that don't.
Rym: there are so many good game designers out there that you can Basically find the people who are the most desperate and get them to work for a pittance.
Rym: So the industry is definitely moving toward higher production values Toward games that are difficult for smaller publishers to even bring to market games that have gimmicks that are complicated
Scott: or weird and
Rym: having the resources to get someone to make a full digital version of your game is definitely one of those Differentiating factors that smaller publishers and Indies are not going to be able to do.
Scott: Usually it seems like most of the digital tabletop games are made by another set of companies that like specialize yeah in making digital tabletop games and you can sort of tell like ah The same people who made this one made that one and that one and that one because you could all looks pretty similar Interface wise and and such and such.
Rym: so the other thing that I think is gonna happen here Is that I would
Scott: hire the company made the race for the galaxy or my god Hex to this day whatever I'm in my board game race
Rym: for the galaxy is a triumph of Making a UX that works on even a tiny screen for a card game where there are like 50 cards on the table at any given time.
Rym: Yep, like that is one hell of a UX design.
Rym: But what I'm curious about?
Rym: we don't know anything about this root implementation yet.
Rym: So one will it have be?
Rym: will it support VR the way that the settlers one did?
Rym: Probably not.
Scott: it could.
Scott: I don't think that's necessary.
Scott: I That is a very low priority.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: because the Tabletop simulator.
Rym: I've seen some statistics that are dubious So I don't want to really like read into them too much that a huge percentage of the people who play tabletop simulator Play it primarily in VR.
Rym: Uh-huh and having played it in VR It's way easier and better than playing it on a desktop.
Rym: somehow I don't think that that is on the table But the only reason it's that way is because the desktop interface is still pretty garbo and because super good.
Rym: Yeah But I also wonder if this will have PBM play by mail Asynchronous turns that kind of thing because I've already got like five multi-year running Civ games going play by mail.
Rym: I could keep several root games going play by mail take a turn every day before I go to work.
Rym: But there's also this trend that digital implementations of games like this make it easier to get people who refuse to learn the rules To games to actually learn the rules.
Rym: I can't tell you how many people I've run into who love root and play it a lot But don't actually know the rules.
Rym: Yeah, and like need someone to walk them through every single turn
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: like that is a problem
Scott: as well, you know, and there's also Even if you don't know the rules see I think some people What they get a digital edition of a game and it helps them learn the rules and that's good.
Scott: Yep, but there's also people where they get digital edition of the game and because you know The video game provides these rails on which you can't break the rules.
Scott: They just the user interface right.
Scott: they managed to play the game without fully understanding all the rules.
Scott: They just keep making legal moves because they can't not make legal move.
Rym: legit encountered a person who had trouble playing Carcassonne with the tiles on a table because they couldn't figure out Which tiles were allowed to be placed legally where because the app just shows you where it could go and they just use that to Make their decisions.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So, uh This is both a blessing and a curse in terms of the learning but I think it's generally a net positive.
Scott: I mean my fate my.
Scott: the positive I take away I'm happiest about is we may now play route very very quickly Even if we're just sitting around a tablet playing route.
Scott: we can play a route real fast.
Rym: Yeah, like we can bust out a route while we're in line for the omega-thon finale.
Scott: Yep the other announcement yellow and Yangtze a Seems to be the same developer slash publishers.
Scott: Yeah, it's the news is on the same page.
Scott: Yep, and again, it is that similar 3d style to the route implementation.
Scott: So it looks like it's from the same people.
Rym: We've talked about yellow and Yangtze.
Scott: It is what is the name of the company?
Scott: That's making these.
Rym: Ah You're wolf digital.
Scott: Okay, dire wolf digital.
Rym: So yellow Yangtze as we've talked about is the not sequel nor successor But simply companion game to Tigris and Euphrates.
Scott: It is the space almost the same game, but not entirely but as a hex map.
Rym: Yep, it's real good.
Rym: And this is a game that I would play a Lot of weekly basis.
Scott: I played some toilet T&E, you know I'm iPhone and that was okay.
Scott: But if I can play this way, I was not good enough to really do anything.
Rym: Hey eyes cannot be good at games like this.
Scott: Yeah, you can play the team digital T&E with people.
Scott: it works.
Rym: Yeah, it does work.
Rym: Anyway, so in some interesting and strange news if you didn't know the history of system shock 2 Which is a game might have played it.
Scott: You should have played it.
Rym: Yeah, if you might have played it.
Rym: if you haven't now's a good time 90s, like when did it actually come out?
Rym: Early 2000s late 90s as you guys got me out of the system shock train.
Rym: I was not on the system shock train in high school sometime around there.
Scott: Yeah, you don't need to play system shock 1 You just need to play - it's like Megaman.
Rym: Yeah, you just need to play Deus Ex human revolution.
Scott: That games way good.
Rym: So system shock 2 is one of those old games that the developer looking glass went out like went under in 2000 and there was and no one owned the property and no one could play the game because computers changed.
Rym: so 12 years later Someone made an unofficial bootleg patch that made the game work on Modern computers and that patch was great Like it was really well done, which is crazy because to this day No one knows who made that patch.
Rym: the patch is somehow Not secret malware and someone made the patch despite the fact that nobody had the source code to this game.
Rym: Nobody.
Rym: the source code was lost there.
Scott: You just decompile the game.
Rym: No, there was.
Rym: there was a leak of Incomplete source code in 2010 and apparently the best guess is that the person who made this patch Made the patch based on looking at that leaked source code Which was not a complete set of the source code.
Rym: All we know about this person is that they go by their online handle.
Rym: look or boo or the crow Mm-hmm.
Rym: So the plot thickens.
Rym: because a company.
Rym: they continued to make patches to this game.
Rym: they also made patches to thief - same thing and You can play this game on modern computers because of the corbo independently.
Rym: night dive is a company that got the rights to system shock - finally and they Would really like to find out who look or bow is because they would like this person's help because
Scott: they are
Rym: Making a spiritual successor like remake of system shock -
Scott: system shock - is getting the HD remake Right, yeah after Like 20 years or whatever.
Rym: So there's a whole bunch of nonsense going around here.
Rym: That is real fun.
Scott: You just read this article to see the detail and you haven't played system shock - well, that's wait a little bit.
Scott: I'm pretty sure you just get it and like GOG or steam or whatever.
Rym: But at this point I would say wait a little bit and get this remake.
Scott: maybe maybe.
Rym: well, maybe probably it could be bad.
Rym: That can happen But I've never actually played system shock - maybe you should.
Rym: may.
Rym: I think I'm gonna wait.
Rym: I'm gonna wait and see if this remake is good.
Scott: I think you just play right now.
Rym: Why cuz?
Scott: it's like it doesn't need a remake.
Scott: it still holds up.
Rym: Yeah, but is it better than half-life 2?
Rym: because I feel like I should just play that again.
Scott: It's completely different from half-life 2.
Rym: Yeah, but on an Same category better than or worse than from an absolute measure of.
Rym: should I spend time on it?
Scott: I mean you should spend time both.
Rym: I mean you should play Deus Ex human revolution.
Rym: No, why not?
Scott: Play Deus Ex and I was not into it.
Scott: Why not?
Scott: Not did not a fan.
Rym: Why not?
Rym: What's?
Rym: what do you what don't you like about Deus Ex a long time ago?
Scott: I wasn't a fan.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: I remember anything else.
Rym: You can't articulate anything about this.
Scott: I don't remember anything other than I remember.
Scott: I played the game and I went man and I stopped playing it.
Rym: So what about system shock 2 specifically?
Rym: is why I should play it right now with the old janky version instead of waiting for the HD remake.
Scott: well system shock 2 is Maybe the premiere or first or best FPS that had like really sort of like the cinematic horror of loneliness and like a dark space station.
Scott: surreal creepy You know, it's like you're.
Scott: you're sitting there and suddenly like, you know It's like these wild like lab monkeys coming at you and shit also in maybe the first or most best FPS to really incorporate like these RPG elements, right?
Scott: You know, I feel like Bioshock does it right.
Scott: and Bioshock does it in kind of like, you know a more sleek modernized way.
Scott: This does it in more of a you know, the the real old-school RPG kind of way right made more like More like the original fallouts almost You know kind of style in terms of like.
Scott: upgrade your biz and your stats and your items.
Scott: Really really tight inventory management.
Scott: Like you just can't go around shooting things willy-nilly.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: It's like you get hardly any bullets for anything.
Scott: All right, you know, there's a plot is exploring.
Rym: But one last thing about this news at least is that we talk about this a lot.
Rym: when people make Remakes D makes they do something cool that technically violates copyright law in a complicated way.
Rym: And then they get takedowns.
Rym: the pro move is to release stuff anonymously.
Rym: so Le Corbeau my hat is off to you.
Rym: if somehow this Episode of GeekNights finds that you're to you I would love to interview you and we would keep your identity secret.
Rym: Mm-hmm Because I think you have interesting stuff.
Rym: We'll get you in Daft Punk and tell a showdown.
Rym: we'll get Le Corbeau both Daft Punk and teller.
Rym: we'll get all them on the show.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: I feel like I'm gonna use a Mario maker thing of the day because we're talking about Mario maker.
Rym: There's a lot of really impressive and weird crap people are making.
Rym: but this channel is the height of making ridiculous logic inside of Mario maker to make weird levels and This is just one example.
Rym: This is a level where the level will just kill you.
Rym: if you ever look forward You have to be looking backward the entire time and still somehow complete the level and it does not do it in the way You're imagining by having like a boo on a rail.
Rym: That's right next to you.
Rym: It's Complicated and kind of amazing and it really showcases The clever emerging crap you can do with a game like Mario maker.
Rym: Also, the guy who runs this channel is just delightful to listen to and it's real fun.
Rym: And if you like this video you will like literally every video they make and they make a lot of videos All right, so Rym seems to be complaining that Frankfurt Germany is super boring.
Rym: Oh my god It's like the most boring place I've ever visited on the European continent, but Apparently they had a very not boring thing there.
Rym: I think this is literally yet I'm looking at your thing of the day the most interesting thing that has ever happened in the city of Frankfurt.
Scott: They had a concert there known as rockin 1000 right and at this concert the song killing in the name by Rage against the machina Whose play you you may.
Rym: if you hear this song, I think you may recognize if you don't know.
Scott: Yeah It's a familiar popular song.
Scott: I think Anyway, they played this song and it's like, okay.
Scott: What's the big deal?
Scott: Well, the big deal is that rockin 1000 is literally a rockin 1000. what this concert is is There's a band and in the arena The band takes up the entire floor of the arena and everyone else is in the bleachers as if you were watching like an ice Game or something.
Rym: This band is as big as five times bigger than my high school.
Scott: I don't think this band Is hooked up to any sort of sound system or anything?
Scott: It's like there are a field of drummers a field of Guitarists a pile of vocalists a pile like bassists, right?
Scott: It's just like large numbers.
Scott: It's like look how many drummers are there?
Scott: a hundred?
Rym: and it's like I see like 400 symbols, maybe there's so many symbols.
Rym: just right.
Scott: tons and tons of people set up their drum set and all play simultaneously.
Scott: all these guitarists have one little amp next to them.
Scott: each and all their amps combined are loud enough that you can hear them and You don't need to actually have you know, some sort of you know Big sound system that's projecting the one guitarist amp all the way to everyone else.
Rym: So I got to see where this band performs.
Scott: if there's a way to see them in person I don't know if there's a way to see rockin 1000 anywhere or ever again But this is a you know, I think they did play other songs obviously because who would pay to hear one song?
Rym: I mean, they have a YouTube channel with like 400,000 subscribers.
Rym: So I assume they're still active.
Scott: Yeah, but this is I discovered them via this video and it's a good song and a good video.
Scott: So start here and if you are into it, you can check out their other stuff until the novelty wears off.
Rym: I am already into it.
Rym: Yeah in the meta moment the GeekNights book club book is the first novel the tale of Genji, apparently it's about this item that gives you extra attacks.
Scott: No, it's about Yeah kind of.
Rym: well so that's the GeekNights book club.
Rym: the previous one if you were not aware is pages.
Rym: it was pages of pain.
Rym: the first last and only Branded canonical Dungeons & Dragons book that we will ever do on the GeekNights book club.
Scott: Oh, what if I pick another one?
Scott: what you can do back?
Scott: I'll make a liar Eddie.
Rym: I dare you to pick another one.
Rym: I Fucking dare you there is no way you would do that.
Scott: That's like the move in a samurai movie I'll get I'll get a dragon lens Scott.
Rym: That is like the move.
Rym: I've read the fucking legend of humor.
Rym: That is some hot.
Scott: figure out which one was like the first one.
Scott: Well, maybe I can find a Greyhawk pool.
Rym: get like pool of radiance from the Forgotten Realms, that's some dire shit.
Rym: I've read some of those.
Rym: I know all about Strahd.
Scott: Maybe I'll get a forgotten realms book.
Rym: Scott you pick in one of those books is like that move in a samurai movie Where you let the other dude stab you just so you can stab them and you both die.
Scott: I'll get your favorite dude.
Scott: Is it drizzed your favorite dude?
Rym: or?
Scott: Drizzed might be my least favorite Character so that's the one I'll get.
Scott: I'll get the most drizzy book.
Rym: there is One you want to go to get fucking Catherly, okay?
Scott: I'll get a book where Catherly is the main character and it's all about Catherly.
Rym: Oh, there are five books where Catherly the cleric of Deneer is the main character.
Scott: Which one is the worst one okay?
Rym: Those books are written by the same dude who wrote drizzed.
Rym: so imagine drizz But without even it without even having someone cool like Artemis and Traire who is cool in the same way that Reaper and overwatch is cool.
Rym: Not cool, okay?
Rym: Anyway, otherwise uh in not that much time.
Rym: We will be at PAX West 2019.
Scott: it's so soon.
Scott: We are doing we are all summer.
Scott: We're like I'm a convention is so far away.
Scott: It's like well fuck summer is over soon.
Rym: fun Not one, but two panels and those panels are on Friday and then Saturday meaning the rest of this PAX.
Rym: We're just gonna be in tabletop And we're probably only gonna go into the expo hall or even the entire convention center once because packs has added ridiculous Terrible security lines that I am really worried about.
Scott: fYI all of tabletop stuff at PAX West has been moved To a central location at the Hyatt Regency Which is a new venue for back which is also I believe where our panels are.
Scott: no Well, I think the panels are in the Grand Hyatt.
Rym: Oh, yeah, we're one of the Hyatt's good We're in the hippogriff theater.
Scott: there are three Hyatts.
Scott: There's the Grand Hyatt the Hyatt Regency and also the Olive 8 which is a Hyatt.
Rym: Yeah Which is a problem because the way you know every PAX has the rule to figure out where the panel rooms are Based on the names, but PAX West has the most complicated rules because the PAX West is across a bunch of places.
Rym: So the rule was always that's the first letter of the name of the theater is the same first letter as the name of the hotel.
Scott: There are many significant changes to PAX West this year And if you're going you need to look them up on the PAX West.
Rym: Yeah, they they.
Rym: you really need to look them up Otherwise, you're gonna go to the wrong main.
Scott: unless you're not you've never been to PAX before in which case It'll you'll think it was always this way Son I remember when tabletop was in this incomplete Abandoned looking like NX space.
Scott: that is now the annex.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Okay Anyway, let's talk about some Mario maker.
Scott: Alright so Mario maker one came out for the Wii U which obviously didn't buy cuz I don't fucking with you Yeah, and the 3ds and I bought the 3ds one.
Rym: I did not.
Scott: I ended up You know, I the 3ds one was good because the stylus is the perfect tool for creating Mario maker levels But I didn't play it too much just because it wasn't really you know The DS one.
Scott: it just.
Scott: it just lacks some stuff that the full Wii U one had.
Scott: and I even though I was really into the Idea of Mario maker and I played the DS one a bit I just you know because I wasn't on the Wii U I wasn't getting the full deal.
Scott: I have spectating some Mario maker a lot on the internet a bit YouTube and such like that But I missed the boat.
Scott: a Mario maker once.
Scott: now Mario maker 2 comes out on the switch and I'm like All right, all my other games that I was into were sort of falling off, you know, I'm not playing Hearthstone I'm not really playing any the auto chess's anymore.
Scott: I'm going all in on Mario maker.
Rym: Yep I'm not going all-in because I play as my game that I can just keep playing because one overwatch I mean you gave you don't play FPS is anymore Which is part of why you like you don't have some counter-strike to just play every day.
Rym: No, I still got the overwatch.
Scott: Mario maker's got a lot more variety than counter-strike Yeah, but counter-strike so good and your counter-strike is good, but it's not Like just eating sugar cookies all day.
Scott: really what Mario maker is the TLDR.
Scott: if you got a switch Yeah, and you're like Mario and you're the kind of person where you're will because the game is 60 bucks Yeah, where you are content to play 2d Mario a lot Like a whole lot then you should get Mario which I am like.
Rym: I'll still just randomly play Mario 3 sometimes, right?
Scott: However, if you are just the kind of person who just only wants to play Mario a little bit.
Scott: It's not worth $60.
Scott: No, right you're.
Scott: if you're not gonna be Playing this frequently don't play.
Rym: So in terms of that like the kinds of people who should really get this game.
Rym: if you want to break that down a little More if you want to make Mario levels as a hobby hell yeah.
Rym: Oh, yeah This is this.
Rym: is it like?
Rym: I'm working real hard.
Rym: I'm trying to recreate my favorite levels like the the feeling I got for my favorite levels of Mario 2.
Rym: Mario 2 is not the kind of game you can make in this no, but there's in the world.
Scott: meaning are you as a?
Scott: yes?
Scott: You can totally make Mario real.
Rym: Mario 2 levels But for one and for two in the American Mario 2 are some of my favorite levels in Mario games Because it's ice and you got to like Dobbs the enemies.
Rym: I'm trying to make levels that are reminiscent of that in this game right now, and it is.
Rym: it really Drives home how much craft and effort and knowledge and skill it takes to make a good 2d Mario level.
Rym: It is real hard to make a lot of work.
Rym: cuz you make one you feel like it's okay Then you go and play like even just Mario 1 world 1 1 again, and you're like oh I can't make these right,
Scott: but even if you are not interested in making levels at
Rym: all it
Scott: is perfectly worthwhile To get Mario maker just to play levels.
Scott: in fact on the main screen when you turn on the game There are two little you know movie clacky things.
Scott: You know what I'm talking about And one of them says make it.
Scott: one says play.
Scott: And if you just want to make or just want to play you're not interested in both.
Scott: That is perfectly okay.
Scott: There is a sea of content for people who just want to play or just want to make.
Rym: yep There's a story mode like there's a single-player mode.
Scott: so the story mode is really simple.
Scott: It's basically the cast.
Scott: you built the castle.
Scott: Oh, it got the dog hit the reset switch on the castle you to make the castle again.
Rym: I realized almost no kids have any idea like what that reset rocket is.
Rym: Yeah, no no no I appreciate that Nintendo has made the Mario maker games look and feel a lot like Mario paint.
Scott: But that reset rocket was also in Mario maker 1.
Rym: yeah, but that's because Mario maker 1 leaned into the Mario paint aesthetic.
Scott: anyway The point is that the castle got destroyed.
Scott: to build it again need coins.
Scott: So you basically play a bunch of 2d Mario levels that were better included in the game already And talk go around talking to toes in this little area until you have enough coins And you slowly over time eventually rebuild the whole castle and beat all the levels.
Scott: and all these levels that were sort of included with The game in the story mode are levels that were made by some top Mario maker designers as well as people who work at Nintendo.
Scott: So it's that wasn't?
Rym: that's kind of nice And they're worth playing because they actually they teach you things about the mechanics of different Mario games that you might not have Recognized or realize.
Scott: I beat them all.
Scott: yeah You play.
Rym: that is not enough to justify $60 to play a hundred 2d level.
Scott: nope that is $5.
Scott: yeah, that's like to play just like you know.
Scott: as this one package of 2d Mario levels is not a $60 purchase Do not buy it.
Scott: play story mode and then stop playing.
Scott: that was foolish Right.
Scott: what you need to do is you need to look at the other modes, so let's talk about the other modes.
Scott: Yeah, obviously there is making mode right.
Scott: so in making mode you make Mario levels.
Scott: the way It works is you pick Mario 1 like Super Mario 1 not Mario 1. right Mario 3 Mario World Mario.
Scott: you like new Mario Brothers right?
Scott: or 3d Mario 3d with like the cat and all that stuff.
Rym: yeah And this sets the sort of palette of what things Mario is capable of right.
Scott: so mode there They're a lot of them are pretty like Similar right.
Scott: it's like you can do like all of them have boo the ghost.
Scott: yeah All of them have bullet bill.
Scott: all of them have.
Rym: even if those things didn't exist in those games It's more like Mario's.
Rym: physics will be like that game, but the mate right.
Scott: well most well the physics Yeah, detailed physics like if you're a connoisseur are basically new Mario Brothers physics.
Scott: But yeah the rules will change.
Scott: so for example if you pick Mario Mario Mario Brothers You can't pick up shells.
Scott: you pick Mario 3. oh well now you can pick up shells and get a tanooki suit.
Scott: well you pick Mario World you can get a cape and you can spin jump.
Scott: and then you pick new Mario Brothers.
Scott: well now you can wall jump.
Scott: Right yeah, and it's like so.
Scott: the rules change when you choose the different ones.
Scott: you can choose different themes.
Scott: You can do snow world right you can do ghost house.
Scott: you can do right, and it's all the themes are the same across.
Scott: So it's like you could do a Mario Brothers Ghost house which you couldn't do before right.
Scott: you can do ice world in Mario 3 which didn't exist before Snow world.
Scott: ice world existed in level 6.
Rym: I'm basically only making worlds in Mario 3 because that's really what I'm like.
Scott: that's what I'm feeling not into Mario world not as much.
Scott: I mean I think about the world.
Scott: what I'm the level I want to make like I made a level that was.
Scott: the idea of the level was go into the cave Right or the start of the level.
Scott: there's a pipe and you can see the goal on the other side of a wall And it's like oh yeah, I guess go over this wall You could win, and it's like yeah You could but the walls real high.
Scott: So you got to go in the cave in the pipe go all the way and there's a one-way thing.
Scott: So you got to go all the way across the bottom.
Scott: Yeah, and there's a pipe that just spits out cape feathers Hmm, and then you got to go across the top.
Scott: you can't go across the bottom got to go across the top Without losing that cape and get all the way back to the start go in the pipe you came out of and then fly over To the exit.
Scott: people tell a lot of people chose Mario world for that because it made sense.
Rym: Yeah, but a lot of the levels.
Rym: I see are that there and back again.
Rym: pattern like they're back again.
Scott: I haven't seen any other ones doing that.
Rym: I've seen that.
Scott: yeah, but yeah did that.
Scott: and then The most of the levels.
Scott: I see there's lots of kaizo levels.
Scott: There's lots of theme levels.
Rym: Yeah, if you break them down the level I see most are Just bad level.
Scott: bad level is very common like kid just put random stuff on a screen the ends you open the level.
Scott: It's a hundred bosses.
Scott: Aha pick a pipe.
Scott: It's like here's five pipes.
Scott: They all kill you but one.
Scott: Oh, they all kill you.
Scott: that we all eat the level is a hidden thing.
Rym: Then there's the kaizo which uh I'm a fan of watching other people do those, but I'm not actually interested in playing right.
Scott: I'm amazed.
Scott: It's like I could beat those if I right but the thing that keeps me from actually beating them I guess you could say you could argue that I can't based on right.
Scott: It's like I'm.
Rym: I could do that.
Rym: I just don't wanna.
Scott: well.
Scott: I'm physically capable with my hands if I put enough time.
Scott: I'm not capable of putting in the time.
Scott: I don't have the patience and the Memorize and perfect the execute.
Rym: I mean frankly other than the fact that I have some gnosis I don't know if Rym today would be patient enough to beat the star world stuff in Mario world.
Scott: I could do that.
Scott: But as I watch people play these kinds of levels and basically they do have all the patience in the world they play and will Retry and retry and retry for hours and hours and hours until they clear the level and it's like damn.
Rym: There was a time when I was like that.
Scott: They're totally chill the whole time after 10 minutes.
Scott: I'd give up and throw my control.
Scott: Yeah It's like that.
Scott: They'll be four hours in just chillin like whatever.
Scott: Yep This is how I do.
Rym: then you run into levels that are like a very specific gag or gimmick Like someone came up with something clever.
Rym: They want to do something funny like the one we saw that was a 2d like 2d 3d Walking adventure.
Scott: It's a very popular level that one because it was well-crafted even though it was small.
Scott: Yep, but yeah, so You can do is you can go into.
Scott: the first is making mode right.
Scott: the second mode is Basically like course world right?
Scott: So in course world you have a few options, right?
Scott: You can.
Scott: you can just play levels.
Scott: You can like search for levels.
Scott: You can look at the most popular levels.
Scott: You can look at like recently hot levels.
Scott: You can look at there's a queue of the levels that were just uploaded just now that no one's played yet You know, you can get codes for levels.
Scott: like every level has a code.
Scott: So if someone shares a level code with you, you can type it in and play that level.
Rym: Yeah, we've been sharing some in the gig Knights forum.
Scott: I tweeted out some level codes the levels I made right?
Scott: You can also the multiplayer.
Rym: I haven't played yet, but it looks pretty fun.
Scott: The multiplayer is good and bad right.
Scott: the biggest problem with the multiplayer is That I think you need to do Nintendo online.
Scott: First of all, right, which sucks.
Scott: But second of all the mode.
Scott: I had mad lag because it's Nintendo.
Scott: If you want to play the multiplayer and have a good experience either find a way to avoid the lag Which I think means be in Japan or be play it just locally.
Rym: Yeah local is the only way I would ever play a game like this.
Scott: so the multiplayer works is you get a level and everyone is stuck in this little box at the start all four characters like Mario Luigi toad and Toadette.
Scott: you're stuck in this box and it's basically like three two one and the box goes away.
Scott: and now you can escape the box.
Scott: You can move around in the box all you wanted.
Scott: now You can escape and it's whoever gets to the end first and if you die you go back to the start or the check.
Rym: Yeah, well, it actually has two modes.
Rym: You can put it in a versus mode where you're just like fighting or a co-op mode where if anyone makes it you all win Right.
Scott: So the car I don't really see a difference between the modes and the co-op mode is kind of silly.
Scott: I guess you could if you Specifically crafted levels where the cop was necessary But then it's fun or something like that.
Scott: Like you maybe you could craft levels to where the co-op was necessary fun or helpful.
Scott: But co-op is basically just versus but everyone wins isn't the only the ending screen is any different.
Scott: Yeah I don't really notice any other difference between them.
Scott: So it's kind of dumb.
Scott: but the versus mode can be dumb or not dumb a lot of time.
Scott: It's luck based like.
Scott: Sometimes there are good levels designed for versus where it works out But sometimes not.
Scott: and you know, it can be kind of random or it can be kind of good depending on a lot of circumstances.
Scott: Yeah, I think you really want to save the verses for a situation where you can control the circumstances.
Scott: You pick levels that are good for versus.
Scott: you have people With you that are good for versus like you're hanging out at a convention in line for something Right here you play it like random internet online versus is gonna.
Scott: Yeah, great.
Scott: It's like it's definitely not skilled player wins Right, not usually anyway.
Scott: Yep So then you've got what I think is the best mode which is the endless mode.
Scott: Yeah So the endless mode just turn it on and go you turn it on and you can choose easy Normal expert or super expert and it sorts levels based on their clear rates.
Scott: So if a level has been like only cleared once out of like a thousand plays that's probably super expert Right.
Scott: and if a level is as like a 50% clear rate meaning like half the time someone starts the level they beat it.
Scott: That's probably like normal and a level that has like 90%.
Scott: well, that's probably like easy, right?
Scott: Yeah so it gives you some lives.
Scott: the harder the difficulty the more lives they give you to start with.
Scott: and Then it picks a random level from all the levels that have been uploaded into Mario And says here you go play and if you beat if you clear the level you get one point If you die, you lose a life.
Scott: if you lose all your lives game over your score goes back to zero.
Scott: You have to try again and and this is important You can always skip a level.
Scott: right you if you're dead Like if you die You can then skip.
Scott: or if you're standing on the ground you can skip but you can't use skip to like avoid death.
Scott: Like oh god, here comes spike.
Scott: Skip.
Scott: You can't do that.
Scott: That won't work, right?
Scott: You have to skip when you're like standing in a safe spot or if you were already died Then you can see you really use this.
Rym: for oh this level is just random.
Scott: be right You use the skip when a level is complete bullshit.
Scott: Or I've seen a lot of.
Scott: I'm watching people on Twitch who are trying to like win at endless mode and get the high score.
Scott: No Like having the longest streak and they're like concert.
Scott: you can only get to 99 lives and you can only get three one-ups per level.
Scott: So they're really conserving their lives.
Scott: You know trying to beat levels getting all three one-ups if possible.
Scott: Some levels don't have enough one-ups or enough coins and You know trying to beat the level with it dying less than three times and then you can Increase your lives and get farther away from game over, right?
Scott: But what they'll do is because they're trying to get this high score.
Scott: It's good for them to play shorter levels.
Scott: so if they see that the average clear time or the world record clear time for the level is like three minutes or four minutes or Five they're like no I'm just not playing this skip even if it's beatable because they could be beating like Three one minute levels in the same amount of time, right?
Scott: So that's a thing.
Scott: yep, but yeah endless mode on super expert.
Scott: the levels are too hard.
Scott: I think the world record for like the streak on super expert is like hundreds maybe of levels.
Scott: Right easy and normal.
Scott: You could go forever if you put the effort into it, but expert endless is really where it's at Because the levels are gonna be hard enough But not just stupid hard and broken that had to skip almost every level to find a beatable one that you could be in Less than three lives, right?
Scott: It's like you can beat expert levels in less than three lives if you're an expert, right?
Scott: You know, you're gonna have to do some skips now and then but for the most part, you know the people I watch on Twitch.
Scott: It's mostly this nice Irish guy named as Iran who's in second place.
Scott: We can't think fine the Spanish person is in first place.
Scott: They're a mystery.
Rym: Wonder if it's Le Corbeau.
Scott: There's also some a Japanese person who's in like sixth or seventh place who's named like Gigi sevaku.
Scott: That's he's a very funny dude.
Scott: The Irish news just chill.
Scott: but yeah, it's like you watch them play and It's good times, but they're skipping a lot, you know, but they're also really fucking good at Mario.
Rym: So let's talk about the making because the UX is
Scott: pretty
Rym: good And there's a lot of clever things in this interface that actually make it way easier than it could have been Like and it's worth noting that this interface and this tool is way better than anything The NES developers had to make levels.
Rym: Oh, no, no, they were like drawing them on paper and using that to like make levels, right?
Scott: So, I mean it there's some limitations in level making right?
Scott: Yeah, when you make a level you have an area and a sub area and they can have different themes But they have to be the same game.
Scott: You can't be like Mario World up now.
Scott: It's Mario 3.
Scott: You can't do that.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: You can change the length of each area longer or shorter.
Scott: You can also be elevation.
Scott: So if you keep all of your stuff in the bottom half, there will not be any vertical scrolling going on.
Scott: But if you suddenly put stuff in the sky, then when players get Mario up near the top suddenly the camera will move up.
Scott: But if you keep everything in the bottom half It'll be like, you know Mario Brothers 1 Where Mario goes on top of the bricks at the top and the camera doesn't go up there.
Scott: Yeah And you just run across the top so you can sort of control things.
Scott: that way You will always have no matter what a goal is Going to be in your main area.
Rym: And what's cool is depending on the mode you pick.
Rym: like if you pick Mario 3 It's gonna be that black area right behind the scenes with the little square right and the player always starts in the main area.
Scott: So if you're playing a Mario maker level and you're in the main area and you reach like a giant hole and a pipe or something You know, you don't have to go in that pipe.
Scott: You could theoretically if you can go forward.
Scott: You know The goal is in this area and that pipe is taking you to a sub area where there is no goal.
Scott: Just presumably another pipe that takes you closer to the goal in the main area.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: So you have that knowledge.
Scott: so then you got the sub area which is just more room to make Mario.
Scott: shit, right?
Scott: And it's where your pipes go back and forth from but there's no goal there.
Scott: So it's just a way for you to make your level bigger by putting more stuff in this other space.
Scott: So, you know a common level design is level starting area.
Scott: where the pipe pipe goes to the sub area You go through the sub area you go through another exit or door pipe.
Scott: it comes out back in the main area near the goal.
Rym: Yeah, I made one where I just use the sub area to make a bunch of bonus rooms like Mario once that's also a pot Of pot pattern you're in the main area.
Scott: You could just beat the level going through the main area But you put lots of little bonus rooms in the sub area and pipes that go back and forth between them.
Scott: Yep, I made a level like that.
Rym: or people I see a lot where there's a the main areas horizontal But the sub area is a vertical.
Scott: right your main area must be horizontal.
Scott: the sub area can be vertical or horizontal.
Scott: So if you want to make a level where the player has to go up Maybe like a rising lava level or a rising water level or just go up in a tower level or go down Then you could use the sub area for that.
Scott: You can't do that with the main area.
Scott: Alright, so that's the first.
Scott: that's the main Structure of your level.
Rym: it has to have in terms of like the tool like.
Rym: the most important part of this UX is the Mario Trails.
Rym: yep, that is how you make a good level.
Scott: you make a level right.
Scott: you just put stuff terrain blocks Mushrooms enemies just put stuff and you Mario is always there And you move them around and it you can push select at any time and the game will just start playing and with Mario in The spot that he was in so you can test out whatever it is in your level and see how it feels which
Rym: is good.
Rym: It's a lot like in the early days of HTML the first time we had Software where you could literally just like Futs with your code and then just see your website live
Scott: that you can unit test any part of your level with Mario
Rym: Yep,
Scott: and then when you push select again.
Scott: You will see what like the trail of where Mario most recently was.
Scott: So for example, you make a platform you start the game you run and jump then you stop the game.
Scott: You can see the arc of Mario's jump.
Rym: So maybe you want to put like a bonus block at the maximum height of a perfect jump from the beginning.
Scott: Maybe you put the platform Mario has to land on in the spot where he lives you.
Scott: aha That is exactly how far Mario can jump.
Scott: So I'll make Mario jump maximum distance or I'll make the game a little easier.
Scott: I don't want to make a super hard level.
Scott: I'll make sure to put my platform for Mario to land on three four or five blocks closer.
Scott: So that way you can do a small jump.
Scott: Okay, I'll make the small jump.
Scott: All right, that's the distance for the small jump.
Scott: I'll put my coins in the path of where Mario jumped right to encourage you to make this kind of jump here.
Scott: Alright now I'll put my goomba right there where Mario is gonna land to make it a little scary.
Rym: I cannot stress enough.
Rym: use this feature to test out your levels and figure out how things work Because this is how you make a level that has things like flow.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: You got to undo this little undo dog.
Scott: Yeah, I can use As eraser.
Scott: you can erase stuff that you can select and move.
Scott: you can select and copy.
Scott: So like for example You make a pipe then you put a piranha in the pipe.
Scott: if you want to make a whole bunch of piranhas and pipes You're gonna do go pipe pipe pipe piranha piranha piranha.
Scott: It's a pain in the ass.
Scott: you make the pipe you make the piranha you select them both you copy You make you copy it several times Then you select all of them and you copy that several times and now you've got a whole freaking army of piranha pipes.
Scott: All right, that's how you do it.
Scott: So It's a lot of stuff is easier to do with the touch screen on the switch, obviously Yep, but some stuff is easier to do with like gamepad.
Scott: So it's like you're sort of mixing it up.
Rym: This is one thing I wish I could just have this on a PC.
Scott: Well, I wish I could have it back in the 3ds of the stylus.
Rym: I just want a mouse and a keyboard.
Scott: that would work too.
Rym: Mouse and a keyboard would be great Yeah, but yeah.
Scott: So it's like you're kind of mixing it up between the controller And also the touch screen to sort of craft your level stuff.
Scott: and you got it sort of.
Scott: get used to it and learn your Way around.
Rym: you're gonna need to use both.
Rym: like you can play.
Scott: you gotta learn the different button.
Rym: You can play the levels on your TV.
Rym: But if you're making a level sit there with the switch in your hand Learning to use the different what the buttons map to like.
Scott: if you actually want to like, you know Use the touchscreen and you have to reach over to like.
Scott: touch the undo dog.
Scott: It's like no.
Scott: you got to learn that B is undo L is a race, you know, the L Z whatever is, you know Selecting copy.
Scott: Yeah, you gotta learn all these controls to really be efficient at making levels.
Scott: Otherwise, it's gonna be a huge pain in the ass.
Scott: What else is there to say about Mario mate?
Scott: that doesn't really have any other modes, right?
Scott: It's like you miss it.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know, it's just.
Scott: even with those few modes There is just such an insane amount of content like levels constantly being uploaded you making levels constantly, right?
Scott: They're just thousands and thousands and maybe even million.
Scott: who know this game has sold millions of copies?
Scott: So if everyone made a level that's millions of levels and there's a huge active online community.
Scott: Yeah the best thing is like.
Scott: I was talking about watching people play it on Twitch.
Scott: one thing that I've been doing lately is you go Twitch and you look for Mario maker and the Mario maker category is a lot of players and you'll see some people who say viewer Levels and of course that means they're playing.
Scott: you submit levels to them and they play them.
Scott: there's some sort of API or something that they've got that hooks up to Mario maker where you think you can type in your Level code and it will add it.
Scott: There's like an automatic queue these twitch streamers have set up to where it cues your level up for them to play Right, and it actually somehow finds the name of the level and the information about it via some API and Gives that to the twitch streamer and shows it on the screen for them.
Scott: But what I use this for is not because I'm desperate to have people play my level I don't.
Scott: I don't care about that.
Scott: as a user for play testing Nothing will help you make a better level than watching someone play your level.
Scott: So what I do is I make a level I go to twitch, right?
Scott: I said I find a small streamer who doesn't have a big audience.
Scott: But I watch them play Mario a little bit to see how good they are.
Scott: Right because sometimes I want someone who's not good.
Scott: Sometimes I want some real good, right?
Scott: But certain people it's like you don't want them at all because they can't really give you any useful feedback.
Scott: Right, you can sort of tell and then once I find someone good I add I follow them and I add my level to the queue.
Scott: I waited five minutes because they don't have a lot of viewers Like empty queue or whatever and I watch them play my level and I ask him for feedback And then I see how they play my level like I why I've made a level called Damage boost desert and the design of the level was your little area is like Mario 3 Right in the desert and there's you know, the purple pipes, right?
Scott: so the it's sort of zoned in the little separate rooms with the purple pipes and the only way to get to the next room is a Small Mario sized slit that has spikes on it.
Scott: So you have to have a mushroom and you just run onto the spikes get hurt and then run into the next room.
Scott: Right and you damage boost and if you get hit by something else You're not making it into the next room because now you're small Mario and there's exactly one mushroom in every room.
Scott: And at the end of the level I put some spikes underneath this question block with a star in it.
Scott: Yeah, so you have to land you lose you you Right you get hit by those spikes You have to hit the question block and grab the star before you die and then you can run to the end, right?
Scott: And what I watch someone play this level and what I noticed was when they got to a certain area They were approaching it completely differently than I was even though it was a really straightforward area.
Scott: We just jump up onto some platforms to go higher.
Scott: Right, but there was a goomba that I had placed far away from this area very far away.
Scott: But because it was a goomba it walks and then falls off.
Scott: Yeah, right only you got to pay attention to stuff like this like red Koopa and go loomba.
Scott: They will turn around when they get the edge of a platform and stay on it, but green Koopa and goomba they fall off.
Scott: They just keep going.
Scott: so that goomba because the way they had played the level Fell out of the sky and just landed on him.
Scott: It's complete horseshit.
Scott: It's like imagine just going up and suddenly a goomba comes out of nowhere lands on you.
Scott: It's like that's just bullshit bad level, right?
Scott: So when that happened, I was in the chat like oh shit my bad I'm gonna fix that.
Scott: And I never would have known that if not for the ability to submit my level to a twitch streamer.
Scott: watch them play it And then you can't edit your levels.
Scott: So what I did is I just deleted the level and uploaded it again with a different code Right and you know with a better version.
Scott: and I think some people what they do is they keep uploading levels and they just keep Uploading like v2 v3.
Scott: They just keep uploading more and more and more instead of deleting them.
Scott: Yeah, actually increase the limit.
Scott: one player can now upload 64 levels total.
Scott: So if you want to make 65 different levels yet to delete one of your levels They're presuming that over time that level will increase as the game because as the player base shrinks more Right, but as of now the game is still pretty hot.
Scott: So 64 is still quite a bit of level.
Scott: I mean I've still.
Rym: I'm working on one good one, right?
Scott: I so many people make theme levels or quirky levels or all these other.
Scott: I'm trying to make Normal levels that look like they would go in a Mario game.
Scott: Yeah also Have some sort of at least game Mechanic gimmick like they go to the end get the feather and then come back without getting hit use a damage boost to go to Some kind of.
Scott: I made a level that was just shortcuts, right?
Scott: I put the vine cloud shortcut the pipe underneath shortcut, you know The sideways pipe underneath the cliff hole kind of got a slide along the wall to get in there shortcut, right?
Scott: You know all kinds of different shortcut e bits and that was you know, I mean some idea for the level not just walk to the end.
Rym: Yep, the only thing I wish I could do is have a little more control of the enemies.
Scott: Yeah, I mean you put the give the enemy, uh, you know You can you can.
Scott: so you can customize a lot of things.
Scott: you can just about any enemy has a lot of option.
Scott: Any item has a lot of options.
Scott: Yeah, you can give like a even a coin.
Scott: you put a coin You can give the coin wings or I can give the coin a parachute.
Scott: Yeah, you can give the coin wings and a parachute.
Scott: you can do all kinds of weird stuff, right?
Scott: So an enemy a lot of enemies.
Scott: you give a wings a parachute.
Scott: some enemies have more options than that You know, they could.
Scott: you get the thwomps.
Scott: you can do a lot of different things with thwomps different directions Different style of flop big thwomps small thwomps, right?
Scott: You can also put guys on top of each other and arrange them in different ways.
Scott: So like you can do a you know, there's the king Koopa.
Scott: All right, he's got that little.
Scott: you know, Mario world He's got that little vehicle.
Scott: He flies in right.
Scott: you can make a fire version of that vehicle But like you could put something else in the vehicle.
Scott: That's not king Koopa.
Scott: You could put like a boo in there Right.
Rym: I see a lot of people make big mechs and big like robot looking things.
Scott: You can put enemies on top of each other and combine them in different ways.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: You can also effectively make different things just by arranging levels in a certain way.
Rym: I mean people will make a lot of complicated boo logic by having Booze and things all stacked together somewhere.
Rym: the player can't see a little try.
Scott: So the biggest the biggest new thing in Mario maker 2 is the on/off block.
Scott: yeah, basically there will be blocks and you hit them and it switches between red and blue and then you can put in the Level red and blue blocks and when it's in people hit the thing and it switches to blue mode.
Scott: all the blue box becomes solid And the red ones become transparent and vice-versa.
Scott: and the most common thing people do is make a level.
Scott: you run and jump run Jump jump jump and when you jump you hit your head on a switch block and now the platform you're about to land on Becomes solid right?
Scott: It's a blue platform.
Scott: You'd fall through it But you you jumped and hit the switch.
Scott: it becomes solid before you land on it You run a red platforms coming up, but you run and jump and hit the switch and so on.
Scott: That's very popular But lots and lots of people making all kinds of puzzly tricky levels Just with on/off blocks.
Scott: cuz they're new they weren't in Mario maker one.
Scott: I don't believe they weren't in a lot of Mario.
Scott: I can't remember.
Rym: So what's new in Mario maker - what slopes?
Rym: apparently weren't in Mario maker one.
Rym: now You could get slopes that you can slide the Sun but also see saw Swinging claw dry bone shell on/off switch boom boom and parachutes.
Scott: Yeah, boom boom.
Scott: is the boss from Mario 3 the minivan?
Rym: assume?
Rym: the listener knows that.
Scott: I hope so.
Scott: The on/off switch is the big one That people are using the most but the dry bone shell is really interesting.
Scott: It lets you make lava levels.
Scott: You can also play dead with the dry bone shell and like fall through spikes like spinning saw blades.
Scott: You can all through them.
Scott: The seesaw is kind of interesting, right?
Scott: The slope.
Scott: I actually utilize the slope in a clever way.
Scott: the upslope.
Scott: You're right people think about the downslope, but the upslope you can't run very fast up the true You can force.
Scott: you can sort of slow the player down with the upslope and put them in tricky situations.
Scott: But yeah The end is the angry.
Scott: something is also the angry moon.
Scott: actually.
Rym: well that the moon lets you change day to night.
Scott: No, no, no the angry moon.
Scott: if you touch the angry moon, it destroys all enemies on screen.
Rym: Oh I didn't even notice that I even notice that.
Scott: right but the angry Sun is.
Scott: the angry Sun from Mario 3 just kills you.
Scott: Yep That's pretty fun.
Scott: putting the angry Sun in places you normally wouldn't.
Scott: There's also like these low gravity levels you can make.
Rym: those are okay Yeah, or like water levels and you can mix like you can make weird broken crap.
Scott: if you want water levels I don't see a lot of them.
Scott: So if you want to make water levels, please do yeah water levels and like Flow based ice levels.
Rym: I don't.
Scott: I made a flying fish style level sort of like, you know 2 - 3 from my.
Scott: It couldn't exactly make the same kind of flying fish, but I put bridges and fish which is close enough.
Scott: Yep Anyway, if you like Mario and you're gonna actually play a lot of Mario or make Mario pay $60 for Mario maker If you're not gonna be just gonna play story mode or and that's it or you're not gonna play it a ton.
Scott: $60 is too much and the price probably is never gonna go down.
Scott: So then I wouldn't recommend it for you.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand.
Scott: Okay for the logos be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night
Rym: and the patreon patreons for this episode of GeekNights are Craig Oliver Allen Joyce, I mean angle just like a dude gag shirt option to William I see Rose link Iji Graham Finch Jennifer Hitchcock Chris mid give my stadium calm.
Rym: j-band scoot alone Lee Shawn Yeager Nicholas Brando Mr.
Rym: Strong stretch in four to one creations like you on Sebastian Bach rock ominous McIntyre sad man, sir Thunder Shervin Von Harl Rory Superboy Clinton Walton run for New Zealand Ryan parent rope and lander Finn Dread Lily Tana Bray Sean Klein Chris Reimer Thomas Hahn.
Rym: and now this Do you have a song request?
Rym: Thinks he can run me out of town.
Rym: Oh, man.
Rym: I love this song.
Scott: I've been driving all night and it's wet on the wheel Doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo, there's a voice in my head that drives my heel doo-doo-doo-doo-doo.
Scott: It's my baby girl Doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo.
Scott: I got some pizza and I'm bringing it home.
Rym: I've got to stick.
Rym: It's the paradise.
Rym: You My name is Luca.
Rym: I live under second floor.
Scott: Yeah, some call me the gang.
Scott: I feel like makin' love, makin' love to you.
Scott: Can't you song alright?
Scott: You really wrote it?
Scott: Yeah, as a tribute to Princess Di and Dodie, because these days, princesses... I want good for lovin' you, baby You haven't get enough for you, baby These batteries have to power everything in our house.
Rym: No, I'll tell you what I want, what I really, really want, what I want, what I want, I'll tell you what I want, what I want.
Scott: That was totally worth it.
Scott: Sugar, doo-doo-doo-doo-doo.
Scott: Oh, honey, honey, doo-doo-doo-doo-doo.
Scott: You are my... What's his name?
Scott: Herman Munster, motorcade, birthday party, Cheetos, polka sticks and lemonade.
Scott: You symbiotic, stupid jerks, that's right, grand dudes, what are you talkin' about, too?
Scott: Hey, man of fever, whoo, hey What's the world, bam, ba-doo-doo-doo-doo.
Scott: I'm so hot for me, I'm so hot for me.
Scott: I'm so cold, blue.
Scott: There was a little Spanish flea A record star, he thought he'd be.
Scott: He heard of singers like Cheetos, the chipmunks he'd seen on TV.
Scott: Why not a little Spanish flea?
Scott: And so he did Inside a door.
Scott: I wanna dance the night away.