Rym: It's Wednesday August 21st 2019.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight the new anime That is still ongoing.
Rym: Dr..
Scott: Stone Let's do this.
Rym: So I was feeling for a little bland Monday and got kind of a like a low-key cold like not quite even sick level just like low-key a Little flam and I was annoyed on Monday, and I'm like poking around and just doing my life.
Rym: and Then I'm in the living room, and I stepped in some water.
Scott: Okay, water in the house again water in the ceiling.
Rym: we gotta go back not in the ceiling this time.
Rym: so water by the TV.
Scott: Oh, that's a dangerous place where there'd be water with electricity.
Rym: The rug is wet uh-huh, so I'm like I didn't spill anything and I look and I poke around and basically the radiator had just broken.
Scott: not you need The p-tach unit.
Rym: yeah the hvac unit the p-tach that has a radiator in it.
Rym: It's just a radiator in there.
Rym: Yeah, yeah It basically it looks like what happened.
Rym: is the what?
Rym: the thing that takes condensed water out of it?
Rym: We had clogged somewhere And it had completely filled with water.
Rym: the
Scott: water that should have been leaking out the side of the building to be mystery water on Someone's head was slowly
Rym: In the apartment
Scott: was filling in your house
Rym: And it looks like it been doing this for a while and it eventually because it was so humid Only like this like recently as humid consistently long enough that it actually filled that reservoir Entirely and then just started leaking everywhere.
Rym: Luckily because that's a very self-contained thing They just came in and like completely fixed it and like replaced a bunch of parts, and I'm good to go.
Rym: So it wasn't like the ceiling leakage.
Rym: it actually was resolved quickly and did not actually cause any damage.
Rym: I just had to leave the rug out to like dry before I put everything back And it was an opportunity to dust behind the TV.
Rym: I haven't dusted under there in like four or five years All right, so you got any news on this Wednesday.
Scott: I mean, it's not exactly any animation or comic news, but I guess it's close enough.
Scott: So the Hugo Awards happened right?
Scott: And it seems that you know don't they happen it.
Scott: those the ones happen at Worldcon.
Scott: Yes Worldcon in Dublin this time double this time, okay, so you know there was some drama in the past.
Rym: There's always some drama at Worldcon.
Scott: the most drama ish con on earth.
Rym: second most drama ish non anime con on her.
Scott: anyway You know there was always drama involving Hugo Awards But it seems that the terms of Hugo Awards that the the good side has managed to win out And this time they have won even more than in the past The Hugo Award for what best related work, I believe
Rym: yep best related work has
Scott: been given to awarded to Archive of our own which is also known as a o3.
Scott: so if you don't know Archive of our own is basically the number one premier central like hub of fan fiction Ever right?
Scott: it's like all the fan is like the fan fiction community above all others.
Scott: You know it's like.
Scott: you know if it was 1996 this would be the geocities of fanfiction.
Rym: yeah with it does have all of the drama you might expect.
Scott: oh, yeah.
Scott: But you know even despite whatever you may you know think about fan fictions right.
Scott: the point is is that hey a A lot of people that you consider you know to be like quote real writers write a fucking lot of fan fiction.
Scott: Right?
Scott: someone who's like job it is to write say spider-man comics.
Scott: They're just writing fanfiction for a living.
Scott: basically they didn't invent spider-man.
Scott: They're not.
Scott: you know Stanley died right now Although they're writing all spider-man all every Marvel But they're writing canonical fiction.
Scott: sure every Marvel movie that you have seen is basically fan fiction right.
Scott: It's just great.
Scott: It's like this magic wand.
Rym: it is entirely possible that some of the works You've just talked about were made by people who are not in fact fans of the subject matter So they might not be fanfiction.
Scott: But also that you know regardless of the legitimacy of fanfiction which it is super legitimate although not all of it may be high-quality.
Scott: The number of quote real right because everyone who writes is a real writer.
Scott: Number of writers who are even professional or even amateur or whatever Got their start writing a lot of fucking fan fiction Right and wet the Hugo Awards.
Scott: what happened is after they gave the award you know to archive of our own Right they asked anyone in the crowd a room full of basically sci-fi Fantasy authors and such people who care about Hugo Awards or we're going you know nominated for them.
Scott: They were voting on them and stuff like that.
Scott: Please stand up.
Scott: if you know your archive of your own like you know you're a member of the community if you did stuff there If it you know impacted you and cetera and a lot of fucking people stood up Like at the room, so it's basically like this.
Scott: You know the award didn't go to a single You know individual or anything like that, but it acknowledged Fanfiction is legit is not?
Scott: you know something to be looked down upon or yep scraped away.
Rym: I mean we've all Made fun of things like Sailor Moon saves the furries and that kind of thing.
Scott: I think fanfiction people also do yeah, right, but at the end of the day you're writing stories.
Scott: Yeah Just cuz your characters might be characters that someone else thought of and you modified or kept the same or added to or you know You're well.
Rym: I mean what we always say even if you make some to be honest some hot garbage at least you made something.
Scott: Yeah anyone who made even the crappiest fanfiction made more than someone who sat around making nothing and just playing games and Reading and watching yep.
Rym: also I get the impression that a lot of the drama and the fanfiction community is mostly people who don't actually write much fanfiction beefing with people who do write fanfiction Because they want the fiction to go differently and they don't want to write it themselves.
Scott: who knows?
Rym: So in some other news you may have seen all this spider-man stuff and I don't want to talk about it too much because I don't really care that much but basically Disney and Sony.
Rym: Uh Some of the few remaining entertainment companies, right?
Scott: So if you don't know brief briefly, right?
Scott: There's all the projects all the Marvel characters, you know, right?
Scott: Almost all of them belong to Marvel.
Scott: Yeah Disney because that's where they started and no one else ever really bought them away.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: However Fox is making x-men movies.
Scott: They had those rights and they kept making them and as long as they kept x-men movies, which I like none of Do I like any x-men movie?
Rym: Do I like any x-men anything other than the original?
Rym: Oh, well, not the original the cartoon the Fox cartoon.
Scott: There are x-men things I like.
Rym: I like a few of the story arcs in the comics.
Rym: I like individual characters.
Scott: Anyway, the point is that that was Fox but Fox is now Disney.
Scott: Yeah, so that has been rejoined heard right, but someone's fantastic for I don't know what the fuck happened with that garbage.
Scott: And then spider-man.
Scott: spider-man was hanging at Sony But they reached some sort of.
Scott: they reached some sort of agreement at some point that I don't know the details of that allowed Spider-man to appear and I actually saw it wasn't on a plane or was it on TV or someone happened to be near a TV.
Scott: I saw.
Scott: not I don't know what it was.
Scott: It must have been like the end of a Marvel movie I don't even fucking know which one it was and it was like Iron Man and then like Peter Parker was there and he was Really young.
Scott: he was like teenage Peter Parker version and You know Iron Man was like, oh come be an Avenger and spider-man was like nah.
Rym: Oh, yeah, that's I saw that one under there.
Scott: I saw that one scene.
Scott: That's all I saw.
Rym: So in a world where so at some point they reached an agreement that allowed spider-man to be in the same movies in a world Where spider-man into the spider-verse doesn't exist that might be the best spider-man movie.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I didn't see it.
Scott: Anyway, I only saw that one scene.
Scott: the point is that Sony obviously is still under that agreement had the right to make other spider-man movies because they made.
Rym: as you said Spider-man to the spider-verse like I cannot express enough is the best spider-man movie ever made.
Rym: Maybe it's one of the better movies ever made.
Scott: No, no, no, it's one of the better movies Better superhero movies ever.
Rym: It's the best ever.
Scott: I don't know about that.
Scott: It depends Counts as a superhero movie.
Scott: Yeah, is that even a genre?
Scott: Yeah, or is it just like, you know Any sci-fi movie where someone is powerful.
Scott: It's like best spider movie a superhero movie because Maybe Iron Monkey is right.
Scott: It's like what you know, we're not gonna talk about that right now.
Scott: Yeah The point is the news that everyone's yapping about is that there seems to be some breakup of disagreement and spider-man may have to exit Marvel movies and a bunch of fanboys or Non-fan just fan.
Scott: people in general are upset about this and I don't give a shit cuz I Watching his fucking movie.
Rym: Here's a good.
Rym: Here's a pretty good take on this.
Rym: So basically Disney is now a Monopoly on pop culture and needs to be broken up.
Rym: I mean stop.
Scott: that is also true for Several other companies need to be broken up.
Scott: the Google but the Apple Amazon almost of all Yes is merging with like Viacom.
Rym: that should be stopped yeah, but forget about that.
Scott: Disney right now because Disney is on the list List.
Rym: Disney in particular has a lot of just general goodwill among regular people And I believe the company is deeply taking advantage of that to pit Disney fans Against the remaining holdouts to the Disney Empire.
Rym: I feel like Disney is relying on the fact that Their fans will defend their monopoly because they're more excited about Star Wars Potentially being able to cross over with Disney shit and all these like fan stuff They want.
Rym: they care about that way more than they care about a healthy entertainment ecosystem with competition Mm-hmm.
Rym: So I think Disney is kind of actively weaponizing Disney fans.
Scott: Well, it's crazy how you know the fans, right?
Scott: It's like they really want things to happen.
Scott: They'd be like, oh my god Star Wars crossover with the thing.
Scott: Oh my god, please make it happen.
Scott: And then when it happens, they'll be like, whoo Whoo and they'll still spend the money on it and then right and then the next time around Right.
Scott: and I basically I basically never fall for that.
Scott: I'm always like right.
Scott: It's like I think I remember a time where someone was like, hey Scott, you like Megaman you like board games.
Scott: They're making a Megaman board game.
Rym: That game is guaranteed bad.
Scott: And I said immediately that's garbage.
Scott: I don't give a shit.
Scott: I can tell us garbage rat right?
Scott: Whereas I think most fans would be like, oh, yeah That logic would be correct for most fans.
Scott: but yet just like Yesterday, I found myself doing the normal fan thing where they're like, hey, we're making matrix 4 and I'm like, all right Yeah, yeah, just take me with your garbage.
Scott: Second movie Reason you skip two numbers you just take my money.
Rym: He's rigid your wallet.
Rym: You slap down the table like.
Scott: but It's like.
Scott: I'm vulnerable, but I think I'm just less vulnerable than the other fans Frequently vulnerable to be fair.
Rym: The matrix was a phenomenal movie and I look forward to there being a sequel.
Scott: Yes Three times that's in under a minute.
Rym: That's one of my most go-to jokes.
Scott: The point is You know even being less vulnerable, I believe at least about myself perhaps egotistically, you know to this sort of phenomenon.
Scott: I think that you know, I can still occasionally vulnerable.
Scott: so I can understand, you know That feeling I have when I see matrix 4 and I'm like up you got me.
Scott: It must be what people feel like who like superhero movies like every fucking time
Rym: yep, but that the problem here is just that Disney is going to continue to get a huge amount of support and a huge number of people are going to
Scott: Pointedly
Rym: ignore the real dangers of this monopoly to our pop culture and just to the entertainment industry as a whole Because they want these crossover fan things to happen.
Scott: and bringing it back to my first news stick away from the big-time Industry arts and stay in the fanfiction fanzone in the indie arts and you won't have these issues Particularly when it comes to tabletop RPGs.
Rym: That's for a different time.
Rym: This is Wednesday.
Rym: news is related to animation But as you know my little pony which was a pretty phenomenal success all things considered it ended its end like it's over.
Rym: They're gonna milk it forever.
Rym: They'll probably.
Rym: they'll probably do another series someday in the future.
Scott: Like I mean, they're not gonna kill off a successful money-making property, but the TV show That airs on whatever the fuck that channel is called these days the Pirate Bay.
Scott: Yeah, it's not called whatever it was the hub or whatever the fuck it was called when yeah, we talked about.
Scott: I only watch like three to four seasons and maybe three.
Rym: I've seen all but the last two seasons.
Scott: I'll maybe one day go back and watch.
Scott: actually the point is the show's ending.
Scott: Yeah, the show's ending but the property will live on.
Scott: who knows how long the comic will gone.
Rym: Yeah, just like Adventure Time like Adventure Time is not gonna disappear.
Rym: Adventure Time is a cornerstone of like animation Which reminds me?
Scott: I was listening to Guaranteed audio.
Scott: Oh, they reviewed a podcast that almost never has an episode.
Scott: They talked about the recently Netflix released Rocco's modern life movie.
Rym: Oh, I was.
Rym: oh we were.
Rym: we should do it the next Wednesday show on that.
Scott: invaders in movie Yeah, and they talked about how invaders in was on Nickelodeon for like as long as a fart Yeah, and meanwhile they've been selling merch for the thing for like 20.
Rym: that's it my little pony.
Scott: and my little pony is.
Scott: It's like it doesn't have they don't?
Scott: they weighed way more my little pony seasons that it ever deserved no matter how good it was.
Scott: Yeah Cuz you only needed like two and then it's you just get enough to have people interested in the property and then you can just Sell merch forever.
Scott: You don't need to actually make Story shit.
Rym: Yep, but speaking of fan stuff So the fans of my little pony had made BronyCon.
Scott: BronyCon's been around as long as the show's been around pretty much 2011 hundred people attended.
Rym: supposedly the most recent one had 10,000 attendees But the not the site tell all the citations of that are not like they're gone.
Rym: Mm-hmm I don't necessarily trust it but BronyCon is also ending and apparently sense.
Scott: Yeah, it's funny because when's the last one gonna be?
Rym: it already happened.
Rym: Previous one was the last one.
Scott: so it is already done.
Rym: So what's funny is at the last one they basically announced the dates for the next two BronyCon's.
Scott: Oh, and then they changed their mind right after that.
Rym: They're like, oh, yeah, BronyCon's got gone.
Rym: big mistake I'm at the two times ago.
Rym: so they so people knew that the one that was coming up.
Rym: that just happened was the last one and Part of the reason it had been canceled was that starting in 2015 attendance declined at a steady rate Partly because it moved like it moved to Baltimore and then it cuz it was too big to fit anywhere
Scott: else
Rym: and then it moved Dates.
Rym: Baltimore was desperate to get any convention after Otakon left.
Rym: There's a lot going on.
Scott: I have a convention in Baltimore to give me that convention center real cheap, and I'll go right in there.
Scott: Yeah, you got to lower the price a lot.
Rym: I don't know how much construction happened because that convention center had some structural issues.
Rym: I don't know what this.
Scott: I actually do not know what the state I mean it has its issues, but it's still enormous space and it's not big enough for our convention.
Scott: We could use one room.
Rym: Yeah, but also one of those rooms.
Scott: We're good This.
Rym: this was a. this is a moderately unpopular opinion, but when PAX first announced there's gonna be a PAX East I would but The Baltimore Convention Center was literally the best possible place to put it.
Rym: and they put it in Boston.
Rym: I remember being pissed about it.
Rym: I'm still pissed about it.
Rym: But now the BCC is pretty good, but back then it had a lot more problems.
Scott: But the Baltimore first PAX East was in the Heinz.
Rym: Awful, but the Baltimore Convention Center for all of its like problems of age the physical space is Literally one of the best possible spaces for a nerd convention.
Rym: Just the way it was laid out.
Rym: like no other convention center is like that And it's kind of a shame.
Scott: But anyway, you know to kind of left that building a long time ago already.
Rym: so Bronycon was declining in attendance rapidly because as Popular as My Little Pony was.
Rym: it is really hard to dedicate a fan convention of size to not just one Genre, not just one thing.
Scott: Yeah one IP right and usually there are conventions like say BotCon I'm pretty sure is still going.
Scott: I haven't heard that it died.
Scott: Yeah, but just about transformers, but it's not a big convention.
Scott: It's kind of you know, it's medium smallish.
Scott: It's not a big thing.
Rym: and Star Wars Celebration.
Rym: Well, it's just Star Wars Star Wars.
Scott: doesn't that only happen every two years?
Scott: and isn't it also like run by Disney like it's official stuff It's like super official.
Rym: Yeah, so Basically what happened is this con was just declining in attendance and rather than downscaling They were just gonna shut it down.
Rym: But because people knew was the last one I think the last one was the highest attended one ever.
Scott: Oh Okay, not rich.
Scott: They should say this is the last packs and everyone goes up and then just kidding except packs already sells out.
Scott: yeah, and Last news.
Scott: I can see that phenomena actually is happening.
Scott: This year is the 30th and fine.
Scott: It's right.
Scott: the week after packs.
Scott: This year is the 30th and final New York City century, which is not the greatest bike ride in the universe.
Scott: Yep But if it's the last one, but it's like it's the fucking last one.
Scott: So I think people are gonna come out in droves.
Rym: I intend to be able to go to the last packs.
Scott: You Have to survive yeah, I.
Rym: So we actually here's an over/under.
Rym: will we outlive packs or packs outlive us?
Scott: Well, I think it's more of a question of the problem.
Scott: We outlive Mike and Jerry and we'll packs well penny arcade corporation under or outlive them.
Rym: You know five or six years ago just based on their per not I would have assumed we would outlive them but they're both a lot more fit than they used to be and like no one is There is nobody who can.
Scott: there is no more Robert coup to keep Mike from getting a motorcycle.
Rym: that is true.
Rym: Why does he not realize he can just buy a motorcycle?
Scott: don't tell him.
Rym: no Nobody nobody.
Rym: tell my crew like that.
Rym: He can buy a motorcycle.
Rym: Good God That would be the last.
Scott: or do do tell.
Scott: The point is right.
Scott: the penny arcade company the convention culture in general those two jerks us two jerks Right, it's like which of these things will die first.
Rym: so race against.
Scott: none of them.
Scott: None of them are immortal.
Rym: Nothing lasts forever.
Rym: But packs as a convention has done a good job of trying to make a structure that will outlive the people that created it.
Rym: Anime cons in particular.
Scott: it has yet to be tested.
Scott: Oh, yeah, but that's like having a backup plan and you've never done a restore Yep, but they're trying most fan cons don't.
Scott: even I got a bunch of backup tastes.
Scott: Have you looked at him?
Rym: No But most fan cons are like backup tapes.
Rym: our con chairs been the con chair for 40 years he will live forever.
Rym: Why do we need to teach anyone else how to do this job?
Rym: but uh brony con and that kind of con I've we've like pointedly as GeekNights like a lot of these Single-issue cons try to get us to appear.
Rym: I Just cannot make that specific amount of content.
Rym: But more to the point when it comes to fan stuff I see this happen a lot.
Rym: when a particular fandom gets very big a huge ecosystem of fan podcasts and fan video analysis things appear.
Rym: but Too many of the people who make those sorts of things get way too Invested in that thing growing forever.
Rym: and I see them like every time this kind of thing happens.
Rym: You see like a whole swath of podcasters Like not know what to do with themselves and aren't able to like make a show about something else.
Scott: Well, I mean even we have GeekNights where we have so much things that we can podcast about with our wide variety in four Shows we run out of ideas.
Scott: I remember in the earliest days of podcasting I wouldn't listen to them because they didn't care about Harry Potter.
Scott: but I saw a lot of Harry Potter podcasts in the mid 2000s, you know and All of them quote-unquote pod faded because they ran in our fucking material.
Scott: Yep It's like even if they're another book.
Scott: that was before all the books are out, but it's like yeah What do you?
Scott: how many podcasts you gonna make between books?
Scott: It's like you already talked the shit out of that book.
Scott: How many Harry Potter news is there per week per month?
Scott: We need to make one podcast per book.
Scott: It's like we will wait a year for another episode of your podcast.
Rym: It's like I wonder if there are still.
Rym: firefly was the biggest one for that firefly fancraft was coming out.
Rym: Yeah I wonder.
Rym: okay.
Rym: Yeah, I think the last.
Rym: I don't think there are any more Firefly podcast, right?
Scott: You could do a my little pony podcast and you could.
Scott: you know, there are still one season of episodes left, right?
Scott: Yep, right.
Scott: You can talk about those you can talk about, you know, there have been different other you can about some merch stuff.
Scott: There was that card game that came out at one point.
Rym: But you turn into just like comics come out every month pretty consistently turn into what all those firefly things turn into which were literally just scraping the bottom of the barrel of any news like ah, No, no, but at least for something like my little pony.
Scott: there is stuff that comes out, right?
Rym: I mean, I guess the best you could do is do a. I mean look we have even finished.
Rym: GeekNights presents utenna.
Rym: No, so we were doing.
Scott: the other thing that you can do in that situation is you can resort to reporting on the meta.
Rym: Right, so that's what all those firefly podcast turned into and they just turned into like the community meta like.
Scott: so it's like.
Scott: Oh, you know check out someone made this awesome rarity cosplay.
Scott: Oh check this out.
Scott: Someone made this awesome Applejack quill.
Rym: So, you know, it's funny.
Scott: Oh so and so is having a meet-up in this town.
Rym: I looked at photos of the last BronyCon.
Rym: the far majority of the cosplay I saw was just random anime con crap.
Rym: Nothing to do with my little pony.
Scott: No So yeah I guess I haven't seen the too much pony cosplay at other cons that I go to.
Scott: they do have cosplay even though I used to see a bunch.
Rym: I see the most still in magfest but mostly in like the people who are going to like the.
Rym: not because Basically have raves but I see it a lot in the concert areas and I don't see it a lot in the rest of the con.
Scott: That's where there's a lot of room.
Rym: Yeah, so, uh last Many I feel like the anime community just sort of forgot this.
Rym: but it was sort of an open secret a long time ago that Neil Gaiman basically penned the English adaptation of Princess Mononoke.
Scott: See, I didn't even know I didn't know that I mean those, you know manga.
Rym: I feel like we've talked about this on GeekNights.
Scott: You know translations.
Scott: if people don't realize this do have writers, right, you know It's usually the translator does sort of like, you know Just turning it into like what is the meaning?
Scott: and then the writer will sort of edit slash rewrite it and say, okay That means that let me rewrite that sentence in a better way, right?
Scott: And that's what the writers job is when you're doing an adaptation.
Scott: Yeah that right, you know.
Scott: Um Yeah, anyway, so, you know, I knew that somebody did this for pretty much any Anime movie ever.
Scott: that's been translated right, but you never think a famous person would have that job.
Scott: Like name name the English writer of like any manga or other anime like yeah I guess someone someone did it for Naruto.
Scott: who the hell did it?
Rym: But like I feel like there was a person when anime nerds just knew it was one of those things people would talk about like I did not know this.
Rym: Okay, interesting.
Rym: So I Feel like everyone forgot because the news of this broke again recently and I saw a whole bunch of people losing the shit about it Which is really funny, but Neil gave me I didn't know about it before but why would I lose my shit about it?
Rym: So but there is some interesting stuff because one thing that I never knew Because this is one of those things like before the internet was like kind of what it is today You could.
Rym: it was often hard to research these kinds of things to find out the full story.
Rym: There's a lot of like Tribal knowledge in the anime community that like no one can go research.
Rym: Hmm So Neil Gaiman started talking about it like now and revealed some things.
Rym: I didn't know so.
Rym: So now I'm yeah on Twitter.
Rym: Now we know why this wasn't quote open secret and like why it was seen as this like sort of secret knowledge.
Scott: I'm just gonna.
Scott: I mean I did know that when Disney was a debt did have the license and was adapting the Ghibli movies for the US that pretty much for every job Involved they were hiring like top tier famous people all the voice actors they got for those things.
Scott: Super famous people not the regular anime voice actor.
Rym: and it's right it showed because those dubs they had their problems, but they were Light years beyond the best like traditional anime dub in the rest.
Scott: So all those Ghibli's that Disney had adapted as you know, not that G kids do a bad job.
Scott: They do a great job Yeah, but Disney when they did it, they hired the famous just famous people cuz remember back like Disney did this through Miramax.
Rym: They didn't do it directly.
Scott: No, but it's Disney.
Rym: So I'm just gonna read Neil Gaiman's tweet because it's actually fascinating.
Rym: now We know why this was.
Rym: scenes like a weird secret.
Rym: quote my biggest secret Biggest secret.
Rym: Wow studio Ghibli asked for some of not about his biggest secret.
Scott: isn't something that happened if I'm gonna?
Rym: Yeah, I met these two jerks and this guy named Steve.
Rym: Studio Ghibli asked for some of the Miramax execs.
Scott: I forget the guy who fell asleep while I was telling my story.
Scott: How rude.
Rym: Studio Ghibli asked for some of the Miramax execs to be removed from the poster and credits.
Scott: Okay, the execs he's not an exec.
Rym: He was in this purpose.
Rym: Here's the thing the execs looked at.
Rym: all the names Determined that theirs would remain and realize that mine was contractually expendable Mm-hmm.
Rym: So basically the Ghibli wanted to reduce the number of English names and put more Ghibli names on Like the posters and in the front credits and all that stuff.
Rym: So the executives were like I'm not taking my fucking name off of this and they basically removed all the names of people Who did not have contracts.
Rym: that specifically gave them the rights to be in the credits and Neil Gaiman was one of those people.
Rym: They took his name fucking off of it ever like.
Rym: they took it off of everything they could.
Rym: Okay, that's it.
Rym: That's the story.
Scott: It couldn't fit another name on there.
Scott: Is not a room.
Rym: No, they were.
Rym: the Ghibli executives wanted fewer American names.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Like that's just something they wanted.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: Why didn't they just say no American names?
Scott: That's what.
Scott: if I was Studio Ghibli, I'd be like you can't put your fucking name on that.
Scott: We made it.
Scott: You're just adapting it and putting it out there in English.
Scott: You don't get to put any fucking names on it assholes.
Rym: Yeah, this was part of the negotiations.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, uh, so there's a further thing here.
Rym: That is crazy.
Scott: Okay, that doesn't see cuz that part just is normal Hollywood bullshit.
Rym: Neil Gaiman also confirmed that he received the opportunity upon recommendation from Quentin Tarantino.
Scott: Apparently why was even?
Scott: why did he not have anything to do with?
Rym: so the rumor was Miramax went to Quentin Tarantino.
Rym: Okay, who said what?
Rym: No go to Neil Gaiman?
Rym: Okay, so Adam Turley asked Neil Gaiman.
Rym: Is it true that they first asked Quentin Tarantino who then suggested you instead?
Rym: and Neil Gaiman?
Rym: Official Twitter account said yes Okay, so they went to Quentin Tarantino.
Scott: who said What?
Rym: I get the impression that Quentin Tarantino's reaction to this was about the same as yours like.
Rym: Somehow this became news and it became fascinating news but anyway It's time for.
Rym: So things of the day.
Rym: this is a Japanese YouTube channel and Basically, it is a professional pianist performing in her house.
Rym: It looks like Chopin's a - like what is your palms works?
Scott: You'll know like a good show fun.
Rym: Yeah, you'll know which one it is.
Rym: It's the one that everyone knows.
Rym: Yeah, you'll hear it.
Rym: You'll be like, oh that song.
Scott: Okay, so what's special about this thing of the day then?
Rym: so the video doesn't start with the pianist.
Rym: It starts in her house and there's there's another.
Rym: there's someone else in the house and this person's like this.
Rym: they're going around doing stuff and they're slowly moving toward the room where the where the practice session is happening and They interfere with the practice.
Scott: Okay,
Rym: and this happens several times because this is in fact a video of the cat one of her two cats Getting bored and Apparently is pissed that she is practicing the piano instead of playing with him and slowly goes into the room waits for his moment Jumps up on the key
Scott: on the piano
Rym: and messes up the performance over and over and over again.
Scott: This is normal cat shit.
Rym: Yep, it's really really really cute.
Rym: Okay, that's my thing of the day.
Scott: All right, so If you've ever seen anyone play drums There's a very important thing next to drums almost always That people maybe who aren't musicians don't pay enough attention to and those are cymbals.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: Usually think about cymbals.
Scott: you think about like a marching band with a guy banging two cymbals together like Yeah, right.
Rym: So what I can say is when we were in marching band in high school the cymbals that we care that the band would carry.
Rym: Those cost more than any other instrument the school owned except for a handful of silver French horns.
Scott: But also, you know cymbals are like one of the most important instruments There are that I guess I don't get enough credit like I'm like even like, you know Don't that's part.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: That's part is symbols.
Rym: Well percussion in general if you're not a musician it off and it often blends into the background.
Rym: You don't realize how important it is.
Scott: Think about.
Scott: well I think it's just that like if someone's playing guitar you go ah guitar so it's playing bass You're like wicked bass solo, right?
Scott: But it's like if someone plays a drum solo you go You hear a drum set Drum solo, even though there's plenty of and and all kinds of in there.
Rym: Well, depending on the drum set there could be like 14 different instruments that that one person is playing.
Scott: And but no one does a cymbal solo, right?
Scott: So it's not.
Rym: well, it's hard to do a cymbal solo.
Scott: Uh, you could do pretty good stuff.
Scott: Anyway, well and a lot of cymbals aren't even called cymbals.
Scott: like you someone's got a hi-hat.
Scott: That's fucking cymbals, but you know and say, you know, it's don't you don't call it cymbals.
Scott: Go ahead.
Rym: anyway Buddy has done some cymbal solos.
Scott: You could even argue that like a gong is a somehow a cymbal cousin or something.
Scott: Well, yeah fucking know.
Rym: Well gongs, uh, Gongs are actually hard to play.
Scott: Regardless if you've ever it now that you're thinking about cymbals more than you have in the past 10 years.
Rym: You've ever thought about cymbals, right?
Scott: You might think common sense.
Scott: every cymbal you've ever seen almost Almost every cymbal you ever seen says Zildjian on it.
Scott: Yep, right It's super rare to see a cymbal that does not say Zildjian on it.
Rym: It's saving it otherwise, right?
Scott: It's like there's one other company that make like that.
Scott: You may have seen maybe and it maybe looked like a knockoff cymbal.
Scott: Maybe people who really do know about drums are like wait a minute.
Scott: There's more.
Scott: I know them Yeah, but 90% of the cymbals you've seen say Zildjian on them.
Rym: I've seen three kinds the two we just talked about or unlabeled garbage cymbals.
Scott: So my thing of the day is a video from the Zildjian cymbal factory that shows the 100% entire process of making a cymbal out of a lump of fucking metal all the way to a Playable cymbal with Zildjian printed on it.
Scott: It is an incredible video.
Scott: That is amazing How they mass-produced them.
Scott: the highlight of the video is the guy whose job it is as his only job cymbal tester.
Scott: Fuck he's had the job for decades.
Scott: There's one dude as a fucking amazing.
Rym: I want to give this guy on that show of which of these two things is more expensive.
Scott: That's the dude That's the cymbal testing dude.
Rym: Yeah, right That's the guy also That's the face of an expert.
Scott: after you watch the cymbal testing video go and read the Wikipedia page about Zildjian cymbals the company.
Scott: it is fascinating.
Scott: It is one of the oldest companies there is.
Scott: they do make an absurdly large percentage of the world's cymbal supply And the history is somewhat similar to the history of Adidas.
Scott: your do your man Adi Dassler right who made shoes and then his brother was like and his brother went and made Puma, right?
Scott: So Zildjian is a family the Zildjian right and they chose one Person at one point among the generations of Zildjian's right?
Scott: I guess it says who the current ones are.
Scott: There's still Zildjian still family company, but at one point in the history of you know, they're I guess You know, what's it called?
Scott: Arid What's the word for that?
Rym: what the dynasty?
Scott: Yeah, I guess at one generation someone was chosen to take over to be the Zildjian guy and The one who wasn't chosen went and went off and made a different cymbal company, which is something else.
Rym: Yep I mean I was watching that, you know that winter garden guy who's making the crazy marble machine X Right.
Rym: He Recently like not too long ago chose the cymbals for the new machine and he he has very similar opinions.
Rym: He got a bunch of Non name-brand symbols shall we say and they were all shit.
Scott: Yeah But yeah, awesome to see how.
Scott: I remember on Sesame Street back in the day There was like a video they would always show of like a saxophone being made.
Rym: I remember that one.
Rym: I remember I have like kid memories of that one, right?
Scott: And it was fascinating seeing you like get bent right and like.
Scott: It was really fun.
Scott: Yeah But this is this is equally good and they don't hide nothing.
Scott: like you watch this video.
Scott: If you have enough money, you could probably copy that factory from this video.
Scott: They're not hiding nothing.
Scott: They're so confident that you cannot beat them at the same game.
Rym: They're like, yeah here We'll show you everything like a night like watching I don't know a super like watching it one of the best hockey players on earth play.
Rym: It's not like they have to hide their technique So someone doesn't steal right.
Scott: one of the most fun parts of the video also is you know, they're making the symbol.
Scott: They're flattening out this big piece of metal me a perfect circle putting a lump in the middle poking the hole in it.
Rym: All this real important.
Scott: Yeah all this stuff right and then it's at the whole time It looks like it's all filthy and disgusting.
Scott: It's like when are they gonna polish it and then only like very close to the end do they?
Scott: they don't polish it.
Scott: They throw it on the lathe and the dude lathes it by hand.
Scott: How many symbols is a dude lathe?
Scott: That's dangerous as fuck.
Scott: Holy shit.
Scott: He does it really fast.
Scott: Yeah, watch this video.
Rym: I mean one of the comments on the YouTube video is part two is held in symbols retail $400 to $900 each.
Rym: part three my friends not believing me when I tell them that my kit is worth $10,000 and It's only $1,000 if I didn't own symbol right.
Scott: you look at like a few hundred dollars per symbol and in this video there's like Thousands and thousands and thousands of dollars just float and on buys.
Scott: because like symbol symbol symbol symbol symbol.
Scott: But I guess each one was laid by hand.
Scott: That's what you're paying for and tested by hand.
Scott: Yeah, that's what you're paying for.
Rym: cuz a cheap symbol sounds bad like garbage like you have to Mike.
Scott: You're better off you don't take a piece of metal right and hit it and take a hammer Right and maybe a forge and try to make it sound like any fucking thing.
Scott: try to even make like a cast a net.
Scott: good Fucking luck.
Rym: if you want to make if you can't afford to make a tambourine If you can't afford a real sound even a whole tambourine just one part of the tambourine you're better off.
Rym: Just using a drum machine.
Scott: Yeah, you know what's in the drum machine recording is of Zildjian symbols.
Rym: yep In the moment the GeekNights book club book is the tale of Genji.
Scott: I actually started reading tale of Genji.
Scott: all right I really are reading.
Scott: I read the introduction and I'm in the beginning of the first chapter of a very long book.
Scott: So it's still gonna be a while.
Rym: I gotta fly to Seattle soon, and then I gotta fly to London by way of.
Scott: you will read Maybe the introduction and a few chapters.
Scott: Yeah I will read the introduction because usually that gives us a lot of introduction gives a lot of info whenever you're reading these Translated slash old books like when you read the Odyssey.
Scott: so here again is another translated old book and Therefore you need to read the introduction to get all the historical meta info and translation meta info from the translator.
Rym: real soon We'll be at PAX West 2019 the true packs.
Rym: We'll be there doing a panel on Friday morning.
Rym: Well Friday afternoon technically and on Saturday morning and the rest of the time We're gonna be in the tabletop area playing games.
Scott: You should go to PAX and then we'll go to every other part of PAX once.
Rym: each probably at least yep Cuz packs has some nonsense metal detectors.
Rym: now, I feel like At this point magfest is the only con we go to that doesn't have like ridiculous fake security.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: It's the only one yep Alright, let's get into it.
Rym: so one of the anime that we need to do Wednesday show.
Scott: I said what anime do we watch?
Scott: I look kids are all watching dr.
Rym: Stone.
Scott: I went and I looked on crunchyroll.
Scott: I looked at what we judged.
Scott: dr.
Scott: Stone was near the top.
Scott: Let's watch that.
Scott: it sounded like the premise had possibilities.
Scott: everyone earth gets turned to stone.
Scott: That's all I knew.
Scott: so I watched enough episode.
Scott: I watched a set of it.
Scott: I watched three episodes, and I said all right how I usually we watch four But I kind of want to learn exactly this much stuff before I talk about it, and I learned exactly that much stuff I think in episode six, and I think seven episodes were out, but I decided not to watch anymore ever And I'll just read spoilers when the show is done.
Rym: Sim that's my my similar.
Rym: That's how I handled attack on Titan.
Rym: after the first two seasons.
Rym: I was like you know what.
Rym: I'm gonna read the spoilers to find out what the secret of space is.
Rym: I know the secret of space.
Rym: do not watch any more of that show.
Rym: I don't know if you even want to know what the secret of space is.
Rym: yeah But I do want to know what the secret of space is in dr.
Rym: Stone.
Scott: so here's the deal.
Scott: there's a high school kid is in typical Japan high school.
Scott: yeah, he.
Scott: obviously all that.
Scott: most of the other people in the high school are non characters because they don't look cool.
Scott: Yeah, he looks cool.
Scott: It's weird though.
Rym: They character design of these two main characters are like a cross between Yugioh and Jojo's Bizarre Adventure, they're pretty extreme characters like crazy hair Dumb guy the real main guy who isn't the doctor yeah?
Scott: He is the only guy's not a doctor either.
Scott: the stone is the doctor.
Rym: the soap is the doctor.
Scott: well There's another doctor.
Scott: the stone itself is that anyway yeah?
Rym: But there's.
Rym: it's weird because they when I saw his face And he looked weird and I realized that he is a weird amalgamation of the
Scott: most generic
Rym: possible anime high school protagonist
Scott: crossed
Rym: with Basically the golden boy face kinda like he makes the golden boy face a lot like to the point that
Scott: I think it's based on The art style of the manga creator.
Rym: yep as soon as he frowned I was like it's just a golden boy holy crap Yeah Golden boy.
Scott: and then you they briefly introduce cuz he stops in the science lab for like two seconds.
Scott: this clearly other main character Who is like science guy who's a genius yep?
Scott: And then they introduce the girl the main guy is into is obviously also a main character.
Scott: So and then you do this in about a minute.
Rym: Yes, here's the thing.
Rym: I'll break in here.
Rym: as we described this shot This was the first make-or-break moment for what I was gonna say about the show cuz.
Rym: my worry was There's like five episodes of build-up to all the crap and introduce all the people.
Scott: nope one minute.
Scott: And then as soon as he's gonna confess his love to this girl Outside by the tree the girl you just saw for the first time who he's been talking about for the past.
Scott: Maybe minute the whole entire earth everyone every human being on earth some mysterious green wave.
Scott: it comes and turns everyone to stone.
Rym: Yep, but in the co-stars, but then it's just him.
Rym: he's still conscious, and he's just like I can't pass out What if I die and for?
Rym: 3,700 years he's just laying there just trying to stay conscious.
Scott: right he really really really wants to somehow stay conscious.
Scott: Get out of this rock that he's been.
Scott: the people clearly have not been turned to stone.
Scott: like Medusa turns people to stone He there he's like alive inside a stone shell which is already Terrifying now because it also makes no sense because that would be worse than solitary confinement.
Scott: you would just go insane.
Rym: very In a real world the this doctor kid probably would have woken up fine, and everyone else would have woken up insane.
Scott: Dr..
Rym: Kid would also know because the doctor kid with his second counting.
Rym: Not that any of you listening to Wednesday GeekNights have read the prince of nothing But that's some kellis shit right there kind of.
Scott: but I still don't do.
Scott: anyway the point is very unrealistic.
Scott: It's an anime so the one guy concentrates on the girl that he wants to confess to.
Rym: the other guy just For four or five thousand years.
Scott: the other guy literally counts every single second while Simultaneously having thoughts in the other half of his brain see us about the situation whatever and he's science guy.
Scott: and Basically yeah, they wake up thousands of years later, and no one else is awake.
Rym: So my second point when they wait now you've got brains guy and bronze guy Teaming up to rebuild civilization from scratch, and I'll point out up to this point not only is it moving fast And but it's also pretty funny like right away.
Rym: The science guy is like hey.
Rym: I made you a love potion.
Rym: I'm the science guy And he's like I would never use such a thing.
Rym: and he pours it out.
Rym: And then the kids like good thing he poured it out.
Rym: That was just fucking gasoline.
Rym: Yeah, I didn't make a love potion.
Scott: He's like I was like I was 100% sure he wouldn't take it.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: anyway He does that a lot.
Scott: where he does the I'm X percent sure yep, and it's actually pretty like he's a pretty funny character Like it's a little bit of c-3po.
Scott: It is so yeah, so this anime I see it as a combination of aspects of other animes, so the the comedy Aspect right that's sort of the wackiness there that you see right really reminds me of you know Not of like a chromardie, which is sort of like the.
Scott: you know it's.
Scott: it's just like.
Scott: You know it's just sort of like these the.
Scott: you know the extreme not as D Art wise like extreme reactions like.
Scott: you know someone says something and someone's like holy shit.
Rym: It's like the shonen equivalent of like the SD stuff that happens in like for she writing all the characters.
Scott: reactions to things like are Extreme and like when they're emotional.
Scott: It's like you know they cry and like a river of tears come out right you know That kind of thing.
Rym: yep This was the next point.
Rym: now they don't.
Scott: then the set the other anime I think is a combination of right isn't?
Scott: it's not even anime it's still a manga is?
Scott: it has the sort of storytelling structure of Delicious in dungeon where it's like you're there.
Scott: You know this is this this plot.
Scott: That's happening right You know?
Scott: oh the world has turned to stone.
Scott: What do we do?
Scott: or trying to accomplish this or trying right?
Scott: But they pause and explain science things the same way that delicious in dungeon pauses and Explains.
Scott: you know recipes of monsters the same way that any of those.
Scott: you know I guess Mushishi pauses and explains a mushi made-up.
Rym: nonsense of mushishi right.
Rym: But and it's pretty accurate to the point that the show has all these warnings at the end like kids don't fucking eat mushrooms in the wild right.
Scott: The other thing it combines with I think is obviously attack on Titan.
Scott: You know what is this the big secret of this world?
Scott: then obviously attack on Titan isn't the first one to do it But it does it in the you know attack on Titan way like Evangelion also has.
Scott: What is the secret of this world, but it doesn't come across the same way?
Scott: This is overt ham-fisted?
Rym: What is the secret of this world, but in another point one thing that I do enjoy a lot about it is that?
Rym: Like in a Western fandom people like especially fanboys really like the zombie apocalypse like okay Basically all the people are gone.
Rym: You got a small amount of people in there zombies everywhere.
Rym: What do you do like?
Rym: how do you survive, but in this case?
Rym: How do you survive like the enemy is just like the conflict?
Rym: is science like all right?
Rym: We gotta make food We gotta make shelter.
Rym: We gotta make fire We gotta make.
Scott: that is a final anime that I think this is a combination of.
Scott: is that it is a combination of also the MMO Anime, how is this a combination of MMO anime where there's no video games involved?
Scott: well?
Scott: I'll tell you I hit the time.
Scott: they simply have replaced the MMO with a game like don't starve or even minecraft.
Scott: you know any of these games the survival type games you start or You know one hour one life.
Scott: any of these games?
Scott: you start with nothing and you build up from the the only things that you can gather from the environment and Create full things by combining and combining and combining and combining so fast.
Rym: there It's always literally like a video game like they once they start picking mushrooms.
Rym: now They just have mushrooms all the time.
Scott: We never even look at that again, right It's it has that same structure of one of those games And it comes across the same way as when an MMO is adapted to an anime.
Scott: And you know say hack sign it just is one of those different game slightly different game genre Adapted to anime.
Scott: slash manga right and take all those all those elements right the the wacky comedy the pause aside to explain science, you know the big secret of this world and the survival game and Put them all together.
Scott: and that is dr.
Scott: Stone.
Rym: It's got a two-sauce of Fist of the North Star In the sense that it's our some action scenes.
Rym: It's a post-apocalyptic world, but the action scenes when when humans conflict with each other Which I was wondering if that would even happen I was wondering if the show was literally just gonna be we science for 24 episodes?
Scott: no But you know it does move quickly to its credit.
Scott: so like they wake up another person like almost right away Yeah, they do not hesitate and also the girl right.
Scott: so the statue of the girl the guy finds it right away.
Rym: If the statue of the girl had been a statue for more than like five or seven you assume that like.
Scott: oh waking up the Girl is gonna be like the last episode.
Scott: No he wakes her up in episode three Yep, and he was gonna wake her up earlier or something like that like right away.
Rym: But they wake up muscle guy instead.
Scott: and to wake up muscle guy because lions come.
Rym: so that's the fist of the North Star.
Rym: Because muscle guy basically immediately turns into a fist of the North Star villain.
Scott: right well.
Scott: He's not really a villain He's a good.
Rym: He's good, but well He's good.
Rym: He's got one bad good idea, but he's dangerous, and he's making the Society of muscle men.
Scott: Yeah, kinda like right away like I'm stronger than all of you, and he's like.
Scott: he's like row.
Scott: he's bad But he's not yeah.
Rym: He's I said fist of the North Star villain.
Rym: He's not.
Scott: that's why I thought of round, but there are other villains like that.
Rym: yeah But there are.
Rym: he's not one of those like Skeletory fist of the North Star villains more.
Rym: He's a conflicted villain right but This is where the show gets a little.
Rym: he fucking punches a lion to death and then turns its skin into a outfit like Instantly like he can just fight lions.
Scott: Yeah, it's is immune crossbows.
Scott: This guy is all sciency right the science guy And he tries to.
Scott: he's trying to figure out the mystery of you know why everyone turned to stone?
Scott: which and how come only people?
Scott: Sparrows turned to stone?
Scott: yeah, right, and it you know it's like okay.
Scott: You know see everything's cool here.
Scott: Everything's really legit science.
Scott: There's no bullshit going on.
Rym: is nitric acid?
Rym: wake people up right?
Scott: it Bob Emily's.
Scott: at least it's real science for the acid you know.
Scott: But the thing is it's like he doesn't question his own Superpowers the superpowers of his best friend the superpower of the guy they wake up or the apparent lack of superpower so far That's obvious of the girl.
Rym: now That's what I don't know I did because like in a show like you're trying Are this a little bit of Lord of the Flies here right?
Scott: We're each person trying to survive and each person is a specialty, but they're all super powered in that specialty beyond all reality Except the girl who buy has a secret superpower, and they're not questioning these superpowers And it seems they did have the superpowers pre everyone turning the stone.
Scott: yeah, right It's like whoa, so that's what I wonder.
Rym: because in shows like utenna The weird super power crap that happens that you might just write off as anime crap Plot.
Rym: it is explained specifically, but then in some other anime.
Scott: It's also the plot in one punch, man Yeah, but then exactly why?
Rym: what is one punch?
Rym: man's deal that anyway, but in other anime Yeah, this person just randomly has powers because it's an anime.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: There's no explanation.
Scott: That's the only thing that's like.
Scott: not they didn't even try to explain in any way.
Rym: My based on the like six a few episodes I saw.
Rym: cuz not even there aren't even that many episodes out.
Rym: yet There are gonna be 24 episodes total a grand total of seven.
Scott: is that gonna cover the whole thing which I assume is the manga.
Rym: Doubtful because the manga is 13 volumes.
Rym: it started in 2017.
Rym: It's already got 13 volumes.
Rym: It's ongoing.
Rym: okay So the manga is still going and there are 13 volumes of it.
Scott: alright, but yeah.
Scott: So that's that explains what the show is.
Scott: the thing is I don't think I really want to watch more of this show.
Scott: Interesting because it's so.
Scott: the characters are so two-dimensional.
Scott: They may be the most two-dimensional characters have ever seen.
Rym: I was almost inclined to keep watching just because Despite that it was moving so fast.
Scott: the plot moves at a very rapid pace.
Rym: like I said They're already like trying to make gunpowder.
Rym: Yep It's like they move it right fucking along in the same time waiting Despite how fast is moving based on the opener alone.
Rym: They're a shit ton of characters.
Scott: Well, I mean you didn't.
Scott: if you watch two more episodes like I did yeah You'd have seen they meet someone who is not awoken by them.
Scott: There are other people who have already been awake When basically when they set off the gunpowder it makes smoke and then they'll see a smoke signal in the distance.
Scott: and like what?
Scott: Other people oh my god.
Rym: so on one end I'm very happy to see a lot of the things you could normally get out of it like fantasy world isekai or out of a like Zombie apocalypse type thing, but instead it's more like kind of real kind of real science-based like it's a very different like Setting for this kind of story.
Rym: Yeah, but but it's still in the end a shonen show.
Scott: yes The two-dimensional characters.
Scott: to think of the number one thing that turns me off the rapid pace is good because you're not Sit around doing nothing.
Scott: Yeah But just like stop by your rap you're rapidly plowing through a really flimsy kind of meh plot You're not?
Scott: you're not rapidly plowing through a deep meaty plot that gives not to think about.
Rym: it's not like escaflowne Which is just like every episode is a two-hour movie 23 minutes.
Scott: the thing is that I think stands out most about this show is it definitely feels like somebody created this for Japanese children, which is all.
Scott: anime is great for Japanese children almost all of it right, but And there's so much stuff that Blatantly reeks of.
Scott: we are trying this show is trying to teach Japanese children how to be right.
Scott: It's like you know oh that guy who is you know only wants to get rid of the old people.
Scott: He's bad looks.
Scott: you can solve anything with science.
Scott: science is good.
Scott: Oh, you know.
Scott: I'm not amazed with your science.
Scott: I'm amazed with your hard work And how you know you didn't?
Scott: you just patiently kept working until you you know got the job done.
Scott: you see took you hours but you see a lion to death with your own hands.
Rym: and
Scott: It's like the show reeks of like Pausing constantly, and they say things that really sound like things that like would be after like the more you know star
Rym: To their
Scott: credit
Rym: in a lot of shows that teach stuff They tend to like like my Ashima had this problem a little bit.
Rym: They spend a lot of time talking about Very little when they actually explain stuff.
Rym: in this show they explain pretty accurate things very quickly, and then they move on like hey Here's the chemical.
Rym: Here's what it does 30 seconds later.
Rym: They're fighting a lot.
Scott: Did you know you can use seashells for yeah?
Scott: You can make sodium bicarbonate, and you can use that for this.
Scott: you can use it for that and you can you.
Scott: it's like.
Rym: I'm curious where they're really gonna go in the long run with gunpowder though because gunpowder is not hard to make.
Rym: you know It's hard to make a cannon.
Rym: Yeah Explosives are way easier to make than things to harness explosions, right well the show is called dr.
Scott: Stone and the first time they mentioned dr.
Rym: Stone when he makes soap, and he's like this is the only thing that will keep us alive.
Scott: He's like without society we have no medicine if we get sick.
Scott: We're fucked.
Rym: this so is our doctor Dr.. Stone, but I love it when shows say the name of the show.
Scott: in the show They say the name of the show again because as it turns out right When they're covered in stuff you'll notice all the characters of these cracks on their faces.
Scott: Yeah, that's because first you think it's just character design But no it's because the stone was cracked when they were turned to stone.
Scott: and apparently when you get unstoned that Unstoning like heals you in that part that you got unstoned in.
Rym: so wait They're gonna restone someone at some point.
Scott: I don't know maybe but there's actually the girl.
Scott: they unstoned her and like her foot is still stoned and then they unstoned the foot And then like like her foot is like healed Like somehow when I get hurt and then when they and then it got healed by the unstoning.
Scott: so and they're like Maybe this stone that everyone turned into is the doctor stone.
Scott: Maybe what turned the world to stone wasn't malevolent, but was benevolent.
Rym: So these are my working theories having seen a little bit of this show.
Scott: so they already have two meanings for dr Stone if you maybe count the third one and that the science guy.
Scott: he's not a doctor, but it's like.
Scott: you know It's the stone age.
Scott: Maybe you could call him.
Scott: You know because he's a smart science guy doctor stone.
Rym: Maybe kind of see the stone doctor doctor stone anyway.
Rym: So my idea number one is this is a wind of amnesia situation.
Rym: if any of you watch old anime Aliens did this to see if well It's actually.
Scott: I don't know if you saw the scene where the science guy is thinking.
Scott: What are the possibilities?
Scott: number one aliens.
Scott: number two evil mad scientist.
Scott: number three like foreign government?
Scott: Yeah before some sort of in environmental.
Scott: He's like going through the list of all the things that you would think of could be an oryx and Craig Situation.
Scott: he's like.
Scott: he's like could been a virus that did this to that to the humans and only if in the virus Only affected swallows in human or better Explain the light right, but it's like he's trying to.
Scott: he comes up with all the explanations It's that you're thinking of too, and he runs down them all.
Scott: Yeah, he doesn't settle on.
Scott: he doesn't know yet.
Scott: He's still trying to figure it out.
Rym: But my real thinking is either It's a wind of amnesia situation of aliens like testing to see if humans are worthy to the world.
Rym: our actual world is Actually a fantasy world from a long time ago, and this is the world resetting in some way.
Rym: Mm-hmm like I could see that like some weird thing happening with that.
Scott: But everything is not.
Scott: everything is science though.
Scott: yep true there is no is not a fantasy world.
Scott: This is a science world.
Rym: I could see benevolent aliens doing this to protect us from some cosmic event that was going to kill us Like radiation storms coming through and the aliens like do this to save us.
Scott: That's the only thing they could think of.
Scott: yeah Anyway, so if you're the kind of anime fan who likes you know like the most popular You know shonen type animes, then you're probably gonna like this type of show.
Rym: I like this way more than any other shonen show.
Scott: yeah, I guess it's better than like a Naruto or something that goes into a Tournament and drags on.
Scott: yeah, but it's still you know.
Scott: But it's it's better than an attack on Titan because it seems like it might actually be going somewhere But I don't.
Rym: it's going like both Shallow as all fuck.
Rym: bokurano was another show that was a. bokurano was legit though Yeah, but it was characters in a predicament.
Rym: those characters were not two-dimensional true They were not two-dimensional but it was still.
Rym: it was characters in a like very contrived freaking predicament who intelligently worked to solve the problem and Bokerano was going somewhere.
Scott: that would make you cry a lot right by those Characters all had their own deep backstories with things they had to deal with.
Rym: this shows.
Scott: You are science guy you are girl.
Scott: you are you know?
Scott: Brawny guy you are.
Rym: Your fighting guy is literally 40 seconds on screen of.
Rym: a long time ago an adult hit me.
Scott: no No, there actually is a whole like half an episode that shows his backstory, so it's more than that It's litter.
Scott: no It's literally just.
Scott: dad bought him a bunch of science stuff and he always science.
Scott: do you want to go to space?
Rym: because fighting guy?
Rym: His backstory is literally.
Rym: one time an adult hit me when I was a kid, so I'm going to murder all the adults.
Scott: Yes, but that is it is the mug I said is the most maybe even one-dimensional characters.
Scott: Yeah, right They don't have it there Just literally.
Scott: science guy brawny guy fighting guy girl.
Rym: yep at one point that might even just be zero-dimensional.
Rym: There's no dimension.
Scott: It's just also You know super sexist that obviously I don't even need to be mentioned that it's super sexist that the girl Is.
Rym: if the girl characters superpower and she only nurturing healing yeah?
Scott: She only exists as love interest and thing to be protected defended etc.
Rym: Though in the opener there are a lot of other motivation for men.
Rym: there are clearly a bunch of other female care They did.
Scott: the person that they met who is not Who is not you know thousands of years old was a girl.
Rym: so if I were you though like if you're an anime fan at All just watch the first episode because move your anime fan who wants the highbrow animes stay far away.
Scott: But if you're okay with the lowbrow popular animes Then this is the lowbrow popular anime of the season, and it's better than other similarly equally lowbrow anime.
Rym: Oh god on control views are like this also liked log horizon Majin bone taboo tattoo and bleach.
Scott: yeah So that's that's it.
Scott: I'm not gonna watch anymore because I've seen what I got to see.
Rym: I'm gonna read.
Scott: I'm gonna read a spoiler when I really want to know.
Scott: I only want to know the bigs.
Scott: I've learned everything I need to know Except for the one big secret which I can now learn from a spoiler.
Rym: it's of course be careful because I know the fullness of attack on Titan and Kind of wish I didn't.
Scott: well I don't care that if I don't waste my time watching the show that it's not a problem Yeah, but I kind of wish I didn't know what attack on Titans about.
Scott: Also, probably no one the writer might not even know cuz the manga is going on going.
Rym: yeah, and you know serialized manga.
Rym: sometimes I'm waiting for the tournament to enter this show.
Scott: the science tournament could get to one Cuz.
Rym: it's already gearing up to like punching nation.
Scott: It is gearing up to a war between brains and brawn.
Scott: See whether which society will prevail.
Scott: right cuz it's a. it's about that.
Scott: You know.
Scott: sort of dynamic right where it's like.
Scott: okay doesn't matter how smart you are there's a strong person.
Scott: They rule the world Until you have society built and then people who are smart rule the world.
Scott: and being strong doesn't help you gain power.
Rym: It's just part You know fits to the North Star Mad Max.
Rym: in a world where all technology is gone The biggest strongest shittiest dudes end up being in charge of things because they can physically force themselves into power.
Scott: it's an old story.
Rym: alright and That's an anime.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Rym: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night And the GeekNights patreon free to patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Craig Oliver L enjoys hiding McNichol just like a dude guy.
Rym: could you art option?
Rym: William Eisner's think he?
Rym: G Graham Finch Jennifer Hitchcock Chris midkiff Mystate.com j-ban Shawn Yeager Nicholas Brando mr.
Rym: Strong stretching for two one creations like you on Sebastian Bach rock ominous Mac and our side man sir Thunder Shervin van Horre Rory Superboy Clinton Walton run from New Zealand Ryan parent or open letter Finn dread Lily Tenebrae Sean Klein Chris Reimer Thomas Hahn and I shit ton of people who give like a dollar because dollars
Scott: fine.
Scott: Don't worry about it.
Scott: and Anyway, dr.
Rym: Stone was okay.
Rym: Show me shows may be disrupted in a couple weeks because I go to London as I mentioned before for work.
Rym: Maybe I'll record a few patrons specific things while I'm in London because I got to bring some equipment there anyway but now I leave you with Oh The.