Rym: It's Thursday October 24th 2019.
Rym: I'm random Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We are talking about sleep the thing that mammals do to keep their brains from going crazy.
Scott: You saying snakes don't sleep.
Rym: Oh snakes also other things.
Rym: I didn't say other things don't sleep.
Scott: I just said mammals do it Saying that all mammals sleep.
Rym: Oh, yes all mammals sleep.
Rym: I'm confident.
Rym: I'm not wrong there.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So a Thing about if you don't live in New York or a few other places on earth like I'd like.
Rym: when I lived in Michigan I liked fireworks, but I thought I'd seen good firework shows.
Rym: I knew I had seen good firework shows because I was near enough to New York, but then I moved to New York and I saw a firework shows done by like for real professionals, right?
Scott: So if you don't know the best fireworks on earth There are three places that I know of at least that make the best fireworks on earth.
Scott: a number one China.
Scott: Yeah, literally just the Chinese government fireworks.
Rym: I mean, I've seen some videos.
Rym: Yeah, holy shit, right Disney?
Scott: Disney Does fireworks like daily?
Scott: Yep, so they got really fucking good at it, right?
Scott: Yeah, I spent a lot of money on it those Epcot fireworks.
Rym: I had a real good time right in three.
Scott: There's an Italian family the garucci family and they do it a best of firework with the racist Italian accent And a lot of times in New York like when I was growing up right.
Scott: nowadays If you go to like say fireworks at the baseball stadium on July 4th, right?
Scott: Yeah, you see some fucking garbage sponsored by Verizon.
Scott: not even fireworks But back in the day pretty much all the real, you know, fireworks shows in New York are grouchy fireworks.
Scott: Now the only ones I see that are still grouchy are the Astoria ones.
Scott: I don't think the Macy's ones are them you know, but The Astoria ones are now.
Rym: I'm not saying like regular old fireworks Like.
Rym: I still enjoy like.
Rym: I just like fireworks no matter what like even if they're kind of bad.
Scott: I'll set one off right here.
Rym: See what the Depends on what kind of firework.
Rym: firecrackers.
Scott: You know the big guy how big Smiley face.
Rym: good, but like the difference between a regular old firework and the kind of fireworks We're talking about are that like, you know when there's a composer who's kind of naive versus the composer who's just a master?
Rym: It's about the composition and the timing.
Rym: like a good fire.
Rym: really good proper fireworks show will actually surprise you.
Rym: It'll use colors that are difficult to make and use.
Scott: you'll see little cost more money last longer Yeah And better synchronize with music.
Rym: and the best heuristic I can give you.
Rym: if you're not sure if the virus is higher bigger Let me writer like I like cheap one and I like expensive one.
Rym: But with fireworks the way to know if a firework show is more legit Generally cheaper firework shows the the finale tends just be a whole bunch of bullshit all at once and then it stops.
Rym: But a real firework show the whole bunch of bullshit will still seem very Choreographed and have like an ebb and a flow and like it'll rise and rise and rise to a climax like you'll.
Rym: you can notice these differences like watch a bunch of firework shows on YouTube, so There are two factors enjoying fireworks because I saw last weekend the best firework show I've ever seen in my life.
Scott: See the best fireworks ever in October which isn't a hot firework time for anybody Not at Disney World.
Scott: you didn't go to China So you didn't use a time machine, so there's two factors.
Scott: You go to like the fireworks factory, and there was like a demo like they were testing out their shit.
Rym: Oh, we went to the box factory.
Rym: So because there's day like with wine there are two factors in terms of not just our.
Rym: is this the best one or our?
Rym: These the best fireworks, but it's also were these that was this the best wine I ever had the best experience I ever had for like with gaming crystal chronicles.
Rym: Not the best game ever true But the way we played crystal chronicles that experience was one of my best gaming experiences ever Mm-hmm because the experience was really good.
Rym: the game was a big part of that But the game by itself was not like that.
Rym: good on its own mm-hmm.
Scott: I mean, that's the same thing.
Scott: if you eat a delicious food right it might not be The five-star restaurant food.
Scott: it might be three-star restaurant food, but if you are mad hungry
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: and if you were say with some good people, or you know someone cooked it for you
Rym: Yeah, right
Scott: then suddenly that could be even a better experience than five-star food even though if you put it next to five-star food you but yeah the five-star food is tastier.
Rym: a piece of like oh Like Oh maka say like Oh toro sushi from the finest master When I'm just like gonna have some sushi would be equally enjoyable, too.
Rym: Here's a crab stick because Rym you literally haven't eaten in two days right?
Scott: or like you know I could make a steak on the grill in the backyard and that could be as good as At least the experience could be as good as you know.
Scott: the the most expensive wagyu right yep.
Rym: So for a zillion dollar the fireworks show I saw.
Rym: so here's the deal.
Rym: We're at a wedding all weekend like upstate staying at this quaint little hotel and like North Branch.
Rym: It was really fun and a lot of stuff happened to this wedding.
Rym: There was a thing on like the itinerary Like after the dinner before the cake where they're like we're gonna go outside with sparklers and take night photos, okay?
Scott: All right, that's cool.
Scott: You can do.
Scott: you can do a long exposure You can draw with if it's dark enough right out.
Scott: you do a long exposure with the camera And then you draw with the sparkler.
Rym: so this was in fact a trick.
Rym: Uh-huh this was a trap.
Rym: so we go outside, and there's a whole bunch of giant like for real sparklers And there's a path of like blue glow sticks like going off and away.
Rym: So take a sparkler and light it and start walking down this path.
Rym: There's a line of us walking down this path the sparklers run out Just as we get to the end of the path like they were timed Mm-hmm.
Rym: and at the end of the path they turn red and they form a circle mm-hmm.
Rym: So I'm near the front of the line, so I'm like hmm is this?
Rym: knowing the people are getting married the first thing I think is is this a jump scare?
Rym: is that are they gonna?
Rym: is this adjacent gonna pop out?
Rym: cuz that would be amazing.
Scott: How much I spent on this.
Rym: uh so the way?
Rym: I'll put it is there's two ways to have this kind of wedding.
Rym: you either spend a lot of money to have it like in New York where we all live and Do the bare minimum or you spend that same amount of money.
Rym: do it somewhere cheap upstate and for that amount of money you?
Rym: Can do ridiculous shit.
Scott: so they skimped on the venue and spent the money on the fireworks.
Scott: They skimped on the food and spent the money on the fire.
Rym: so the fireworks were Right there like they were so clever that time in a wildwood when a few mortars fell into the crowd Mm-hmm and like exploded all around us man.
Scott: It happens a lot.
Rym: It was a show that was Directly over our heads, but was super professional timed well like choreographed.
Rym: Well the finale was good, and it was really long.
Rym: But they were so close that you could see all the fireworks in 3d and all the debris was just like raining down on Top of us the whole time sounds dangerous.
Rym: It was professionals doing it.
Rym: It was as close as you can be to fireworks where it's still reasonably safe.
Rym: That was a fucking fireworks show.
Scott: mm-hmm wonder how much it cost.
Rym: I don't know, but I imagine that had the wedding men in New York City there would have been no fireworks.
Rym: Of course the fuck.
Rym: You get a permit for that shit, so I heard that you don't have any news today.
Scott: There's not a lot of news going on.
Rym: There's a lot of news going on.
Rym: holding a giant wildfire.
Scott: Yeah, what do we say about it?
Scott: There's a wildfire in California.
Scott: Don't live there.
Rym: How did you not see the sarcophagi?
Scott: I didn't see that or the hidden chamber.
Rym: They found in the Great Pyramid.
Rym: That's not news.
Scott: yet like I said before the show if you find a hidden chamber It's not news until we know what's in the hidden chamber.
Scott: Just like I have Al Capone's vault.
Scott: That's not news now.
Scott: It was Al Capone's vault is empty.
Scott: That's news.
Rym: It was news that they found that door in the Great Pyramid But there was news again when they opened the door.
Rym: It's not news until you open the door now because finding the door is news.
Scott: it could be a mean it could be a worthless door And then it was hype up for nothing, but there's still a door.
Rym: I was obsessed with that fucking door like my entire childhood because there was no info on what was behind that door And I just assumed I cared about the robot.
Scott: I didn't care about the door I cared about.
Rym: I was mad like why can't the robot just open the door?
Scott: That's what I said.
Rym: I cared about the robot.
Rym: Later they did find like robots who could like look behind the door And there was like stuff back there and actually there's like the.
Rym: the Great Pyramid still has many mysteries sure But anyway, I got a few news as we can talk about.
Rym: so there's actually something happening.
Rym: That's kind of a big deal, and you probably wouldn't even notice.
Rym: This is happening unless you go to Smaller movie theaters that show old movies.
Scott: Oh, I read the story.
Rym: Yeah, okay.
Rym: This is real bad.
Scott: so basically The Disney bought Fox a while ago Yep, and which means among other things for example the Disney streaming service is gonna have every Simpsons ever.
Scott: Yep, right because that's Fox.
Scott: you know a lot of things are Fox 20th century Fox You know like the thing that used to be like old movies like Raising, Arizona The thing that fly the thing that used to be at the start of Star Wars movies is not there anymore.
Scott: Yeah, right Disney bought Star Wars and Lucas, and now they bought the other part.
Scott: yep, so Basically which by the way they wouldn't have been allowed to do.
Scott: if there are any sort of antitrust anything.
Rym: Yeah, Disney should be broken up like 100%.
Rym: That's the moral of the story is way too big.
Rym: It was way too big a long time ago, and it just been accelerating its bigness way too much, but yeah I think Disney should have been broken up in the 80s, but I digress.
Rym: yeah, probably so Disney did a thing in the past called the vault which a lot of younger people don't really realize.
Scott: so what happened in the olden Days?
Scott: I'll explain the vault right is?
Scott: you didn't have your Netflixes.
Scott: You didn't have your pie digital internet piracy didn't have any internet, right?
Rym: If you're lucky you want a VHS tape.
Scott: so if you want to see a Disney movie Right it either has to be a. you're really lucky And it's getting on TV And you can record it like my grandma recorded Dumbo off TV so I can watch it over and over.
Scott: right B You bought a VHS at the store.
Scott: right C You saw the newest Disney movie in the theater But you ain't seen any old Disney movies in the theater only the newest newest one right and that was it.
Scott: That was the only way to see a Disney movie.
Scott: were those three ways.
Scott: and what they would do is those VHS.
Scott: is that you?
Scott: Could buy?
Scott: they would only be like they'd be like all right.
Scott: You know Aladdin was out came out like last.
Scott: you know last year a few months ago.
Scott: now Here's the first Aladdin VHS.
Scott: it's right.
Scott: and then what?
Scott: and then after like some months like you know what we're done Selling Aladdin on VHS.
Scott: it's going in the vault.
Scott: and now if you didn't buy Aladdin on VHS And you had the chance you got to wait until they decide.
Scott: you know what we're gonna put Aladdin on VHS out again.
Rym: It would make the news when Disney would be like hey little mermaids gonna be back in stores, right?
Scott: It's like you couldn't?
Scott: you went to the store to the Disney VHS even DVD section I don't know how long it went on for and you wanted to buy Lion King, and it just wasn't fucking there.
Scott: All right, you can maybe get a used one from someone.
Scott: you could maybe rent one at a blockbuster cuz they would keep them You know and especially if you went to a non blockbuster like a small local store.
Scott: Yeah Right they got everything when they were Available and they have the whole lineup because they bought them when they could right and then they rent them out.
Scott: So you could always watch them that way.
Scott: But if you wanted to buy one you had to buy they would cycle them right out of the vault.
Rym: well, so now so that the vault like wasn't as much of a thing anymore partly because Netflix Netflix.
Scott: Yeah, it's like it's not being meaningful.
Rym: so that what's happening now is there's a secondary thing going on.
Rym: There's a whole bunch of movie theaters that do things like hey on Halloween Let's show the movie Halloween or let's show the Rocky Horror Picture Show.
Scott: Yeah, I mean there's.
Scott: you know movie theaters are not getting too many people to come unless it's.
Scott: you know There's mega Marvel movies and shit then filled with in Star Wars and people fill the theater by the way All of those are owned by Disney.
Scott: Yeah So all these other movies that aren't these, you know It's like less people are going to the theater for the not top tier mega blockbusters.
Scott: so movie theaters who want to fill their seats are doing all sorts of things like.
Scott: You know the fathom event stuff really went from being small to being like a huge thing.
Rym: Yeah, right like Nighthawk near us This has like brunch and booze and stuff.
Scott: and I show like old movies like Even theaters out in the burbs not in the cities.
Scott: are you know showing?
Scott: you know, not movies that are current run movies.
Scott: They're showing old movies.
Scott: They're showing special events.
Scott: They're showing like concerts being streamed from wherever the concert is happening live You know, they're showing all kinds of crazy stuff to get people to come in including old movies.
Rym: Yeah And these are old movies that otherwise are making zero dollars like.
Rym: it's just free money for Disney Free money for like the theater.
Scott: It's some movie that is, you know, maybe it's available on DVD somewhere But they're not like printing them and selling them like hotcakes.
Scott: Yeah But like they have the tape might be straight might be streaming on a service who knows it might be available to buy on You know for like a few dollars in iTunes or Amazon or YouTube or something, right?
Scott: But it's not a movie that like, you know is being marketed currently.
Scott: It's just part of the library.
Scott: It's just in a bundle somewhere whatever.
Rym: but these small theaters because it's so cheap to get these movies That's how they kind of make their money to be able to also show Even more independent stuff.
Rym: that gets the smaller audience while still being profitable, right?
Scott: It's like hey No one's gonna come to see.
Scott: you know, we got we got ten screens in here.
Scott: Let's just show fucking Ghostbusters tonight.
Scott: Some Nostalgic people will come more than will come for whatever else the fuck we could put on there.
Rym: and that's a point.
Rym: So increase.
Scott: it's gonna cost us what like, you know If you got to pay the Ghostbusters people a few dollars to get the tape for the real or with the digital whatever because you Don't have film projectors anymore, right?
Scott: So you pay them.
Scott: they send us the thing we screen the movie we send it back.
Scott: It's that's how it works, right?
Rym: Yep, and these old movie screenings to actually draw a lot of people Yeah, like.
Rym: I would rather go see a lot of old movies than a lot of like first-run movies.
Scott: You know people wouldn't be running these things in the theaters if people don't know him Like I go see commando in the theater diehard, especially people do like, you know, they'll do like special things.
Scott: You know, they'll mix it up a little.
Rym: show home alone and home alone - right?
Scott: Or hey the one of the actors in this movie lives in the area.
Scott: Let's have him come and talk before after the movie or you know Hey, we're gonna watch these silly movies and provide everyone with you know, some accoutrement.
Scott: Maybe you know some Rocky horror esque experience.
Scott: Yeah, you know size things up bit by bit.
Rym: a bunch of theaters notice This is everything just recently that all these Fox movies.
Rym: suddenly when they say hey, we'd like to get this film They're told it's not available.
Rym: Disney's basically not letting anyone get these movies anymore.
Rym: They're not letting anyone show them.
Rym: They're going back in the vault.
Scott: Yeah, anyone who's like, hey, I'd really like to show this Fox movie.
Scott: Send me.
Scott: Here's some money.
Scott: Send me the thing.
Scott: It's just like nope now show something else.
Rym: You can read this article again in the details but the suspected reason for this is Disney's always had this really fucked up strategy of they want to control a huge percentage of the number of screens in theaters Even if there no one goes to these those movies because they don't want other people's property to be in those.
Scott: This is their property.
Rym: Yes, but it's not their a-plus property.
Rym: They wonder what property is.
Rym: They want the property that they are currently making and pushing to fill the theaters Screens even if no one sees them.
Rym: Yeah, I don't understand that logic.
Scott: that makes no sense.
Rym: common sense I mean, I don't want to like derail the whole show and get into it but I've read a few articles about it and there's a whole bunch of kind of good in fact by Capitalism.
Rym: they do better by doing that.
Scott: Yeah, maybe I don't know but the point is by saying no You can't show the Fox thing.
Scott: So they'll just go to the remaining movie studio.
Scott: That's not Disney and show something else old.
Scott: Ah They're not gonna show a Disney thing.
Rym: I don't think you understand what you meaning.
Rym: the listener not Scott.
Rym: how many old movies Disney owns now?
Scott: Oh, yeah, they do but there are still plenty that they don't.
Scott: Yeah, but if you're if you're a movie theater and they say no, you can't have the Fox movie I'm just gonna find fucking something else that someone will let me I'm actually gonna read a paragraph from this article because I this is.
Rym: this is a vulture article.
Rym: More than one exhibition professional contacted for this article Speculated that Disney's overall goal is to claim as many screens at a theater as possible for its newer titles Even if some of them are packing the house and others are selling just a handful of tickets.
Rym: a former theater manager for a major Chain who asked not to be identified for this piece said it seems short-sighted, you know, but they do it I think just to keep Sony out To keep a universal out.
Scott: But this is a person who is the person who's in charge of deciding what to show who they're interviewing and that person knows this.
Scott: So wouldn't that person then get a sony and universal thing?
Scott: Hey, it's like they're in charge of what goes on the screens.
Scott: Disney doesn't own the movie theater directly Which you wonder why they don't and that would be odd.
Rym: So there was a lot of speculations.
Scott: Disney Just buy like regal and AMC or whatever.
Scott: It is now.
Rym: There was a lot of Theaters did merge.
Rym: Disney used to go after the theaters.
Rym: Disney wanted to like own the theaters.
Rym: Disney like.
Rym: look at that.
Rym: Remember all the shitstorm around the rules Disney put in place to allow a theater to show Star Wars Disney's play in Monopoly hardball here.
Scott: Then the point is, you know, obviously that's even worse Monopoly if they do own the theater.
Scott: But it's like why not just fucking buy the theater?
Scott: then no one can show us anything.
Scott: I think here's the person who decides what goes on a screen in the theater.
Scott: knows Disney's trying to lock up all the screens.
Scott: Can't that person intentionally just show Sony Universal things?
Scott: Yeah, they can and be like, hey Disney Let me show the Fox stuff or else I'm gonna show Sony Universal instead.
Scott: Fuck you.
Scott: In fact, you're brand new movie.
Scott: I won't even show that.
Rym: fuck you.
Rym: The problem is theaters don't make money.
Rym: No theaters are like that.
Rym: whole industry is on the verge of collapse.
Scott: as far as I can Yeah, yeah, I mean, you know, I could I feel like I could run a theater and make money.
Scott: I would just be good to be very clever and creative and you know, yeah be in a good location.
Rym: Well, yeah, it's definitely being a good location.
Rym: There's definitely a divide like urban feet like theaters in cities are a completely different world from theaters and suburbs.
Scott: Yeah, we can show promare and fill the house.
Scott: Yeah subtitles in a story.
Scott: Right, if you show promare with subtitles in you know a suburb you're getting the 10 anime nerds at the high school.
Scott: Yep, and that's it.
Scott: You're not filling the whole place.
Rym: So in some other news that is accurate, there's a lot of shitty news today But there's some really good news.
Rym: if you're not aware Polio is still around.
Scott: Yeah That's why you still get a polio vaccine and you don't get a smallpox vaccine because smallpox is not still around.
Rym: the only reason Smallpox is gone and polio is mostly gone is because of the massive vaccination effort that continues to happen.
Rym: Mm-hmm The world is actively trying to eradicate polio completely.
Scott: Yeah, we mean it's mostly eradicated in a lot of the world where people have access to vaccines.
Scott: But in a lot of the poor parts of the world where people don't have access to vaccines in great health care There's still quite a bit of polio going around.
Rym: There are multiple strains of polio.
Rym: One of them I think was completely eradicated a long time ago.
Rym: Yeah, uh Just now Another strain was completely eliminated.
Scott: How do you know?
Scott: How do they measure that?
Scott: It's like that person had it and they they died and now no one else has it.
Scott: anybody anybody have the second polio.
Rym: So it comes down to you.
Scott: You got polio 3 anyone got polio 2.
Rym: I'm sure some people are gonna jump on me for being slightly wrong about this but as far as I'm aware the way that works is based on statistical analysis of Based on all the research.
Scott: No one's gotten this in X years.
Scott: Yeah, we're calling it So like we sort of like the elections are like like we're calling it.
Rym: There's enough votes in research sampling and testing and reporting cases have an X percent chance of detecting any given type of illness But we have data on that.
Rym: So that percentage coupled with how long it's been since one was reported, right?
Scott: So it's been a super long time since we've found any case of this and we Yeah, so that means it must be gone because no one's gotten it.
Rym: Yep, and Pakistan is one of only two countries in the world where polio was still endemic.
Rym: So, okay We're in like the final stage of the country.
Scott: I don't know what do we even have data on that though for like the really bad countries like Eritrea or North Korea?
Rym: They're they're part of the UN and a whole bunch of multinational organizations work really hard to make sure that data is accurate.
Scott: I'm just saying, you know, it's like you'd think that like the worst a country is like Pakistan's not the greatest country, right?
Scott: They got issues, but like Eritrea is like the worst country, right?
Scott: It's hard to imagine that that Pakistan would have polio and Eritrea.
Rym: It's complicated because countries that have lower economic activity also have less like travel and You can see how this gets really complicated in a hurry.
Rym: So the perfect storm For misery the perfect store for human misery is a country that is growing rapidly modernizing has a growing economy But still has Yeah, yeah, okay makes sense.
Rym: So now some bad news.
Rym: Just another.
Rym: you know, I cannot stress this enough and I'm not gonna dwell on this too long.
Rym: You're like million details But the United States is in the middle of a literal crisis and might fail as a country and you really should be.
Scott: That's not news.
Scott: That's been true for several years.
Rym: Yep, and you'd think every week What does that?
Rym: how could this week be that much worse than last week?
Scott: This news is really just like a stunt.
Scott: It's not really a big deal.
Rym: It's a stunt except for the fact that it's done.
Rym: basically a whole bunch of American Republican Congressman did something that is like literally illegal.
Rym: Yep, and they're not being punished for it.
Rym: They broke into a secure compartmentalized information.
Rym: Whatever the skiff for the sift depending on what part.
Scott: intelligence community Yeah, but anyway the point it yeah people don't know.
Scott: but basically, you know When you're in the government and you have a security clearance, right and you gotta have a meeting and the meeting involves You know some security detailed stuff that not everyone can listen to.
Scott: you got to be sure That when you talk about it that you're only talking about it with people who are you know?
Scott: Are allowed to know.
Scott: and you got to be sure they say there's no bugs bugging you right from other countries spying.
Scott: Yeah, you got to make sure that you know Nobody's bringing like their phone in there to take photos of documents.
Scott: Just email the documents away.
Scott: No, right, you got him, you know, there's some certain rules, right.
Scott: so they have these rooms ranging from small to large.
Rym: Right like Obama had a tent that he'd bring around that he could set up in hotel rooms if there is an emergency And he needed to like look at and interact with secure information, right?
Scott: He would you know, they set up the tent.
Scott: he goes inside he looks at the stuff.
Scott: everyone else He's not allowed to see it stays outside the tent.
Scott: Yeah, but yeah, it's like, you know and these rooms They have people who are trusted people.
Scott: I assume they have some really intelligent system Where they make sure that there aren't any bugs in the room, yep, like Yeah, and it's like when you go in the room you got to leave your phone outside You got to leave all the shit outside.
Scott: They search your ass.
Scott: You can't just walk in there.
Rym: Cuz like a lot of military people go to the microphone.
Rym: What an officer would tell anyone who's gonna go to one for the first time is if you fucking forget your cell phone and it's In your pocket and it enters that room.
Rym: It's the government's cell phone now and that's gonna suck right.
Scott: and you know There's even it's even a lower level of government like even in like your local government like say I don't know like like a DA or a US Attorney or someone like that.
Scott: We'll have one of these because they have to look at like Documents that are sealed and no one else in the office can see them.
Scott: right stuff like that Maybe like some grand jury type stuff.
Rym: There's all kinds of secret documents all over the place and there's different levels of secure things But this is basically the secure room in the basement of Congress for some of the most Congress.
Scott: they have one of these because you might need to have say a committee interrogate somebody About secret shit and the Congress people obviously are allowed to know.
Rym: not all the Congress people No, not all of them But the people on say the security committee and considering like half our Congress people are basically foreign assets at this point, right?
Scott: Or you know the you know judicial committee or whatever, right?
Scott: Sometimes they got to have you know committee meetings and they got an interview.
Scott: Maybe they got to bring in some top secret military dude and interview him right about top secret shit.
Scott: Maybe some CIA people got to come in and testify to Congress about top secret shit.
Scott: They have a whole big-ass room that they can have a committee meeting in.
Scott: that's you know.
Scott: Lock the door.
Scott: everyone leaves their phone outside the room right in a bag.
Scott: It's a big phone pile.
Scott: Yeah, there's and this little guy stands with a guard of the sack.
Rym: There's like little lockers and things.
Scott: I'm sure they got it handled right?
Scott: But anyway, you know the They had a meeting of this nature.
Scott: Yeah And there are public answer in the meeting.
Scott: legit because it's a committee meeting and all the committees are split like 51 49.
Scott: Yep, regardless of how many elected people there are which is I think a problem Topic for another day.
Rym: Well, it wasn't a problem until the Republicans under when Obama was president.
Scott: No, but I'm saying is like if you're I don't want to go on with this about an hour.
Scott: Pretend party a took 80% of Congress.
Scott: Oh, yeah, maybe they should have 80% of the committee seats on each committee and not 51 49.
Rym: Yeah, the thing is doesn't matter because the committee conveys that the committee will do whatever the majority party wants.
Scott: obviously.
Scott: But like what if we elected 10 people from some third party?
Scott: to Congress right I'm just saying.
Scott: I'm just saying How many seats on the committee's?
Rym: what?
Rym: what if a unicorn got?
Scott: like how many committee seats would kudos get on which committees?
Scott: Even if they got like 20 people they will get zero right exactly.
Scott: So I think that's a problem.
Rym: But anyway, regardless I Know out they should make them a hundred percent Democrat.
Scott: There were Republicans they should and there were Republicans and Democrats in the committee meeting as is normal.
Scott: And then the Republicans pulled a stunt where they like busted into the room.
Scott: Physically, I guess the guards didn't stop them.
Scott: I don't know why I don't.
Scott: I think that I feel like if you try to bust into that room you get shot right regardless of who you are.
Scott: So from what I like if I tried to bust into the room, what would happen?
Scott: What if I was black and I tried to bust into the room?
Rym: I would happen.
Rym: I think at best you'd get tackled right right.
Rym: It don't tease me bro might happen.
Scott: It wouldn't be a good result.
Scott: So they got in the room.
Rym: Why didn't the sergeant of arms hit him with that mace?
Scott: the mace isn't over in that area.
Rym: I want to see Nancy Pelosi like texting him like get the mace.
Scott: the mace doesn't get the mace.
Rym: We need it.
Rym: bring the mace to the basement as soon as possible.
Scott: You're not good enough for the mace.
Rym: Well get you at the butt end of the mace not the top part with the wings.
Scott: I mean the.
Scott: the wing end is probably the one you don't want to hit someone with.
Scott: Mess up the one you'll mess up the bird.
Rym: Yeah, you mess up the bird and the person one hit with the other end.
Rym: so basically one of our political parties a bunch of their members broke a whole bunch of laws and No one knows what's gonna happen now like now I'm sure that room is gonna have to be like swept.
Rym: and the best part was they all a bunch of them tweeted while they were in this fucking room and then in this like hilarious display that That actually is interesting because the door was still open.
Rym: Oh the door was like that point.
Scott: I was like, how could you tweet from the room?
Scott: That shows the rooms got a problem.
Rym: if the door was closed I don't think you could tweet.
Rym: Okay, pretty sure it's a Faraday cage.
Rym: Okay, just check it.
Rym: So you saw a whole bunch of them tweeted from the room and then like ten minutes later They all started tweeting.
Rym: things like by the way that last tweet was sent by a staffer outside the room.
Rym: Try to cover their asses.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: So we can just see who tweeted.
Rym: Yeah Frankly they should all be jailed and removed from Congress.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, I mean or at least jailed.
Scott: Yeah, I mean Do it by a video.
Scott: well, no, you can't.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: well you got to show up to cast your vote.
Scott: Yeah, you're in jail.
Rym: It's Problem sucks for you.
Rym: I guess you won't be voting things of the day.
Rym: so this made it past my feed and Like I saw it and I got it was a funny little joke and I noticed two things.
Rym: I noticed that one most people who saw this tweet did not get it Because I think most people can't actually read music at all.
Scott: Oh, I saw this.
Rym: Yeah, so it's just someone just posted something They're like, I never had such a face after sight reading something in my head alone, right?
Scott: Cuz it's like it's it.
Scott: the lyrics are Mary had a little lamb, but little lamb are all the same.
Scott: note one, two, three.
Scott: Yeah, and here it's like it's three different.
Scott: Oh, it's it's up down up.
Scott: It's like Mary had a little.
Scott: it's like it's wrong.
Scott: Yeah, right Even if you don't have perfect pitch if you just know how to read music and you know that notes that are vertically higher are Higher and music notes that are lower or lower.
Scott: You can see that these notes do not line up with these lyrics.
Rym: So I see all these people like not getting it.
Rym: but the joke was pretty good and I laughed out loud, uh Basically, I'll just ruin it.
Scott: It's so it's super wrong.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, do you know what that song is?
Rym: Oh it is.
Scott: Oh, they took a different song and put Mary had a little bit.
Rym: So if you do you read the notes and sing the.
Rym: It's the Hall of the Mountain.
Scott: I can now see that it is the Hall of the Mountain King.
Scott: I didn't realize it was another song.
Scott: as soon as you told me that I could tell what song.
Rym: Yeah, I looked at it.
Rym: I was like, oh, it's the wrong note.
Rym: Oh God damn it.
Rym: And now every time I hear all of the Mountain King, I'm thinking Mary had a little lamb So the other I can read music.
Scott: Yeah, I just couldn't play that on an instrument unless I went and practiced again.
Rym: So even better.
Rym: you can read the thread on this tweet of half the people getting it Not getting it and a bunch of people posting even more obtuse music Right.
Scott: So you keep posting this one and I keep thinking that like maybe it's a fucking all-star This one this one's not all-star right or is it lost?
Rym: people keep thinking this one.
Scott: I thought it was.
Scott: I thought it was like a four note all-star cuz.
Scott: you can see how I could think that cuz like.
Scott: yeah Cuz it'd be like, you know, it was the star is like some body, right?
Scott: Yeah It's like.
Scott: I thought it was woody woodpecker because it looks like doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo.
Rym: I realize I for whatever reason I got this right away.
Scott: What is it?
Scott: It's a doo-doo-doo-doo.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: It's doo-doo-doo-doo-doo, which you're close.
Scott: I was close, but what it is is it's the dots the diamonds the dots.
Scott: Yeah, I forgot how to read the dots until just now.
Rym: very opening bit to the undertale megalovania fight song.
Scott: Oh, that's of course why I wouldn't know.
Rym: it is not something I know but if you look at undertale people like undertale community People they this is not.
Scott: I thought I would be mad if it was something I knew but there's no way I could get that.
Rym: So this has been a meme for a long time like since undertale came out of.
Rym: people will post this in Reaction to something that they're incensed about.
Scott: you should make one that says so that's I guess.
Rym: I guess That's wrong on purpose to make all right.
Scott: Well the notes for somebody would be like right, so be a half note and then like yeah, right and then I guess put and then put a different lyric on it.
Scott: or To take this and write somebody under it.
Scott: Yeah, right something like that.
Rym: or is this loss?
Rym: Everyone thinks this is lost when I post it.
Rym: It's not lost.
Rym: No, it's did it.
Rym: it did it did it.
Rym: Yeah, I even made it my form avatar.
Scott: So what do you got?
Scott: what do I have?
Scott: Oh, so when I was a kid back in the day you get on a school bus every morning.
Scott: Yeah, and in kindergarten, I got on the school bus and that was Ralph the bus driver.
Scott: Right who route?
Scott: the bus driver was awesome, right?
Scott: I kept seeing him for many moons.
Rym: I wonder why Ralph is right now awesome bus drive kindergarten Why I got driven to school or I walked to school.
Scott: I took the school bus for a very long time.
Rym: Anyway, the point is I basically never took school buses except in middle school because many.
Scott: So on the school bus, they would always play hot 97, which you didn't know you're in Detroit.
Scott: 97 was a New York radio station.
Scott: It was broadcast from the top of the Empire State Building 97.1 and in the early 90s hot 97 switched From being sort of like, you know 80s early 90s dance music to being hip-hop Right, and it was good in both forms, right, but they changed genre right in in the early 90s.
Scott: So the hip-hop hot 97 that's like man.
Scott: There was some good shit going on there.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: it's like legendary right, but the point is here.
Scott: my thing of the day is I don't know how.
Scott: who say who rescued this.
Scott: I don't even know how they have it.
Rym: Haha, right Channel is like 600 subscribers, right?
Scott: Yeah, so before I'll subscribe.
Scott: Yeah, so Romanowski, that's right.
Scott: before it switched away from dance music Jeff legendary DJ Jeff Romanowski.
Scott: Right, we put like these awesome, you know late 80s early 90s dance mixes.
Scott: He even described this was one of my last shows right on Hot 97 and this is one of the lat.
Scott: there's actually more on this channel than just this one But this is one of the last ones.
Scott: he did on a Friday night before the genre of the station changed And I guess he lost his radio show.
Scott: it became a different show Right and you could listen to the whole show.
Scott: and these awesome beats on YouTube hasn't been taken down for some reason?
Scott: Okay, I'll take advantage of it.
Rym: while it's there it's got some.
Rym: it's listing a bunch of songs that are in it.
Rym: I'm sure it's got some copyright thing going on where he's not making money from it.
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: But yeah, if you want to experience the early 90s, you know, New York late night awesome radio.
Scott: Here you go YouTube.
Rym: That's pretty cool in the meta moment.
Rym: The GeekNights book club book is the tale of Genji.
Rym: It's gonna be a while.
Rym: So we might read another short book in the interim and just idly read the tale of Genji over some time and talk about It occasionally as we work toward its stunning may have may have bitten off more than it's doable in one bite.
Scott: Yeah, maybe maybe we can be like tale of Genji first half or something and then come back with second half.
Scott: I'm gonna we'll see.
Rym: We'll see.
Rym: Well, we might do some checkpoint like book club episodes along the way with the tale of Genji But in the area, we might pick a shorter book like in the works.
Rym: Maybe a short story or something.
Rym: Yeah something I'm gonna pick something cuz my choice would be next and we'll read it in the interim.
Rym: Otherwise, we're gonna be live at PAX Unplugged doing two things We'll link to them and everything when the schedule is fully up.
Rym: Paxis badges went on sale today.
Scott: Yep, as did Saturday sold out.
Rym: yet I'm gonna.
Rym: last year It took two hours for Saturday to sell out with the caveat that people were in line to buy that last badge Way before you actually saw that sell out.
Scott: Yes Saturday sold out but every other day Open.
Scott: because Oh four days available - oh, yeah Now that they brought back the four-day badge, by the way.
Scott: So even if Saturday's sold out if you want to go to all of paxis the easy to get a bad four-day badge There it is Not bad.
Rym: All right, so we will be at PAX East.
Rym: also PAX South is coming up and also magfest.
Rym: We'll be at all these places.
Scott: So many people just want to go to PAX East for Saturday only.
Rym: in Russia most people only want to go to cons for one.
Rym: All right, that's like normal people.
Rym: they live in the city.
Rym: They go to the they go to the gaming con their kid gets the signature of the youtuber.
Rym: They like they walk around the expo hall.
Rym: They go to one panel and get the fuck out.
Rym: that's why it's so empty at night.
Rym: hmm, and especially paxis because Part of the reason why paxis doesn't sell out as fast as it used to is that now that it can accommodate a lot more People there are not enough hotels in Boston Like there just are not enough hotels.
Rym: any hotel that's even remotely close to packs is already completely sold out.
Rym: So, uh, I think that is really put the damper on people buying like going multiple days.
Scott: No Anyway,
Rym: cuz like imagine if I was gonna go to PAX West and like Saturday was sold out and I didn't have a way to Get a badge for Saturday I would not fly out to Seattle to go to a few days of packs and not be able to go on one of the Days, I just wouldn't go at all.
Rym: Cuz I'm not gonna fly all the way to Seattle unless I'm going for like the whole con.
Rym: Yeah, I feel like paxis has a similar thing happening.
Rym: Anyway, so sleep.
Scott: Oh Main bit.
Rym: Yeah, let's get right into it.
Rym: Can't believe you never talked about this.
Scott: Yeah, well, you know sleep is a hot topic because people don't get enough of it.
Rym: Yep, my late capitalism has ruined the world and nice you're rich.
Scott: even rich people I think aren't getting a lot of sleep because they're the kind of people who you know.
Scott: It's like they can't afford to sleep all they want but they're the kind of people don't on purpose.
Rym: Yep, it's kind of an aside But I promise you that Scott and I are not like this.
Rym: if I had enough money to where I could live a pretty good Life ever one of the things that I really I would never work again I would just make one of the reasons.
Scott: I want a lot of money.
Scott: You know, I don't need an insane amount of money.
Scott: I just need enough money to not have to go to work.
Scott: I'm only that level of greedy because I want to be able to Every every single day.
Scott: I want to be able to just go to sleep when I'm tired and then wake up whenever my body wakes up With no alarm whatsoever.
Scott: That's that's that's like one of the top things I want in the world.
Scott: But no I have to.
Scott: you know I need to because I waste my whole day at an office doing bullshit looking at the bed screen.
Scott: I need to spend a certain number of hours awake at home taking care of biz.
Scott: Yeah I can't go to sleep as early as I would like and then I have to set an alarm so that I wake up on time To go to that stupid office again.
Rym: So let's go through history because actually I think about my life and all the different stages even from childhood I've never gotten enough sleep my entire life.
Rym: So in elementary school and well elementary school, I don't have that many memories.
Rym: But like I don't know when my parents sent me to bed I just I'd stay up until I went to bed.
Rym: But all what I do remember is that I stayed up way later than anyone I knew like all the kids at school be like, oh like bedtimes 8 o'clock and I was like, what the fuck bedtimes like 11?
Rym: What's wrong with your parents?
Scott: I mean, yeah, I mean at a certain point in my life I definitely went to bed after pretty much everyone else in the house whether it was like I'm downstairs watching the hockey game until it's over and then everyone else is asleep and then I go to bed or Downstairs playing civilization 2 until everyone else is asleep.
Scott: Yeah and then I go to bed.
Rym: high school was the best because my whole family would go to bed and I would be up until Like for like I'd be up until the Sun came up playing sieve - oh not that late.
Rym: No kind I was up until sunrise.
Rym: I stayed up all night.
Rym: I want to say once or twice a week in the summer when I was in high school like all night like I'd be up Summer I went to camp, you know, I didn't go to camp.
Rym: I was just I'd be playing sieve - or I'd be out biking and the Sun would come up and I'd go and get some breakfast Somewhere and then I'd come home and I'd go to bed and wake up again at like 1 p.m Like
Scott: even at summer camp, right?
Scott: It's like they make you go to bed.
Scott: It's like it'll be dinner then the night activity.
Scott: then you go back to your bung and then it's like, all right Now you got to go to bed.
Scott: You're not letting you do anything else.
Scott: And then you had to wake up at a certain time because shit starting and you got to go, right?
Scott: And so even there it's like you got plenty of sleep because you know of the hours that they set.
Scott: but it's like you still Didn't get.
Scott: you know You were woken up in the morning by you know, often their dinner.
Rym: It's funny.
Rym: Like I use the same alarm clock from Third grade until I left RIT and I even used it in Beacon for a long time.
Rym: That sound to this day.
Rym: if I hear that sound I don't want to say I have a panic attack But I suddenly had this moment of oh shit.
Rym: Oh fuck.
Rym: I have to get up.
Rym: I have to wake up.
Rym: Fuck.
Rym: Goddamn it.
Rym: Like that sound is the worst sound on earth to my brain.
Rym: And that's why I don't use that alarm clock anymore.
Scott: Yeah, but you know, it's like.
Scott: but even that considering that, you know, never really got.
Scott: I mean there are certain nights where I get You know, I'm able to do that but not many like on the weekend I can do.
Rym: this was and there's recent stories about this.
Rym: That's why I thought of this episode because studies have been showing forever That kids don't get enough sleep and it actually makes them perform worse at school and like has all these problems.
Scott: I mean, I mean for everybody if you don't get enough sleep, there are several studies that show a it fucks up your digestion.
Scott: Yeah, it probably makes you live less long.
Scott: It makes your brain not as good.
Scott: pretty much everything is bad if you don't get enough sleep But specifically kids.
Rym: and it's began a big part of why kids don't get enough sleep.
Rym: Is that school starts in America?
Scott: The crack ass of dawn.
Rym: and it's been that way forever mostly because Americans like both parents often work and school has to start early enough for parents to get their kids together to go to school Before the parents go to work.
Rym: So if work is at 9 then schools got to start at like 730, right?
Scott: I never understood that because we have no problem having school end at like 2 or 3 and then it's like you.
Rym: look at schools Always have latch key and shit.
Rym: some of them do but some like every school has that except well except schools in poor neighborhoods Because our society is fucked right?
Scott: But I mean some people some often they charge for that, right?
Scott: You know, it's like, okay, you remember even in my
Rym: elementary school I think like half the kids just stayed at the school for like three extra hours until their parents came and picked him up After work,
Scott: I mean I would take the bus home No one would be there but I'd have a key and I went in the house
Rym: in Michigan.
Rym: That was illegal.
Rym: Okay, it was technically illegal for kids under a certain age to be home alone.
Scott: Interesting.
Rym: Yeah, a lot of states have laws like that.
Scott: We did not have that situation.
Rym: Yeah, you might have you just didn't give a shit.
Scott: But the point is is like when I was too young I couldn't do that, right?
Rym: Yeah, but my middle my middle school middle school I remember because it was burned in my brain.
Rym: My alarm was set for six twenty in the morning.
Rym: That's when I had to wake up to get to middle school on time.
Scott: I had to wake up that early.
Rym: Like sixth grade seventh because it started at like 730 was my first class and Jazz band an optional class was in the magic zeroth period before the teachers got to get there even earlier.
Rym: Yeah sucks for them once a week on Fridays.
Rym: I had to get up at 520 in the morning to be able to get to jazz band on time.
Rym: Yeah, so my five dad had like drive me to school every day at like 6 a.m.
Scott: You know, I feel like if you have kids the it should be regardless of whatever the school hours are.
Scott: It's like your work is just should have to just fucking deal with it.
Scott: Yeah, come to work when you're you know, after you take your kids to school whenever the hell that is You know what?
Scott: That's what nice.
Scott: and then you leave work when it's time to pick your kids up.
Scott: Fuck you work.
Scott: You're the one who has to deal with.
Rym: you know What one of the benefits of working for the place I work for is that they're kind of just like that.
Rym: like a lot Of people their schedules are just weird because they do stuff with their kids based on like school schedules and things Like.
Rym: no one has a problem with that.
Rym: It just happens.
Rym: It's totally natural.
Rym: More jobs should be like that, but they're not yep, but in middle school like I'd stay up or whatever.
Rym: But high school like once I had a car and a bike and my parents basically is considered me an adult at that point I basically just would like not go to sleep.
Rym: Like I would just like I'd go to sleep at like 2 I'd wake up at like 6 30 to go to high school.
Rym: I do like high school for a couple hours.
Rym: I'd say fuck it I just leave.
Rym: I'd go to the park and nap for like two hours Go back to school.
Rym: make up some excuse.
Rym: so I I didn't get in trouble like oh I was like.
Rym: I tell the band teacher Oh, I was helping the drama club or something.
Rym: and I tell the drama teacher Oh, actually, I had to go help the band teacher.
Rym: No one ever called me on it.
Rym: Anyway, and then I get home I take another nap and then I'd stay up until 4 a.m.
Rym: And do the same thing.
Rym: I didn't do that.
Scott: Anyway, so actual sleeping, right?
Scott: I'm lucky and that Relatively speaking.
Scott: I don't have too many sleeping problems Lay down I close my eye and then I know if I close my eyes and I want to be asleep I am asleep within 30 seconds, right?
Scott: I know a lot of people I know have like an insomnia of some kind where they can't sleep and a lot of them talk about How basically their brain is constantly thinking of stuff all the time.
Scott: Yeah, and that sort of keeps them up.
Scott: I've experienced that I guess mildly on occasion.
Scott: It usually happens more if the following day is gonna be a weird day.
Rym: Yep a weird day, right?
Scott: Going on a long flight to Australia or tomorrow I'm biking really far or if I got a complicated thing that I have to do the night to wake up at a different time Tomorrow and do something way out of habit.
Scott: I'll be thinking a lot about it the night before that.
Scott: Yeah, also the food I eat.
Scott: we you know, it's not talking about dream situations, but obviously get some some cheese dreams, right?
Scott: Well, I mean, it's like if I eat a bunch of Thanksgiving I'm gonna fall asleep way faster.
Scott: if I eat a bunch of sugar it's gonna be a problem.
Rym: Yep, and cuz I'm in my 30s if I eat like pizza too late at night, I'll get woken up with the heartburn.
Scott: Yeah It's bad to eat Too close to going to sleep and it's also bad to like look at screens too close to go in the snow along those lines.
Rym: Remember at RIT?
Rym: I had like a lot of like heartburn and throat problems.
Scott: Was that from eating before sleeping?
Rym: No was so.
Rym: I'd thought it was that but I finally just went to the doctor Mm-hmm, and I was like, so I have all this wicked heartburn and she looks at me and she doesn't what she says.
Rym: She's like, there's literally nothing wrong with you.
Rym: And then she's like, so how much sleep do you get per night?
Rym: And that was RIT's.
Rym: I was like, I don't know four and a half five hours.
Rym: She was like, that's your fucking problem.
Rym: Hey sleep go to bed.
Rym: Like she literally said the words.
Rym: That's your fucking problems.
Rym: She went on this tired.
Rym: What is it with you?
Rym: kids go to sleep?
Rym: And I started like remember there was a time at RIT Lane colony where I started like going to bed.
Rym: But even when you guys were staying up a little bit suddenly all my heartburn went away like my like everything was a 180 Yeah But yeah, so but you know, I know people have that problem where they can't get to sleep.
Scott: Yeah, that sucks.
Scott: And I also know people who have a problem where you're like narcolepsy.
Scott: It's like yep suddenly that's real dangerous.
Scott: Less people have that.
Scott: it seems like insomnia seems to be super super common.
Scott: So narcolepsy is rarer but still too common.
Rym: There's a difference between narcolepsy and microsleep because if you just if you don't have any other medical conditions But you just did not sleep enough then you'll get so tired that you'll just have like microsleeps, you know where you're like, yeah Yeah, that's that happens.
Rym: Uh, jerk yourself up microsleeps.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I Used to get those a lot because I didn't fucking sleep like ever.
Scott: I only get those on the rare occasions that I don't get enough sleep or if I try to stay up too late I'll start having like.
Scott: there have been occasions where like say I'm reading a super exciting book in bed, right?
Scott: Yeah, I'm like should go to sleep.
Scott: Book too good.
Scott: Keep reading book and then book hits me in the face.
Scott: Literally.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I bet that happened.
Scott: I'd say that's a microsleep right there.
Rym: I have woken up with a book like crumpled on the bed.
Scott: next I hit my head with my iPad too on occasion.
Scott: It's pretty rare, but it's not zero times.
Rym: I dropped the switch on my face a few weeks ago.
Scott: That does not happen cuz I usually play switch in living room.
Rym: Yeah, but I was playing switch laying in a bed in a hotel room.
Rym: Yeah, and I was playing slay the spider.
Scott: I've like woken up with a DS next to me.
Scott: That's on.
Scott: Yeah, that happens.
Rym: But it's interesting how much of that seems to be tied to like routines.
Rym: Like if you have a very strong routine in your life your body just seems to adapt to it.
Rym: So like if you always fall asleep at the same time and wake up at the same time your body will just do that without Alarms or without right.
Scott: that is a problem that I do have.
Scott: is that on occasion It seems like maybe a few times a year.
Scott: I'll have it maybe once twice a year.
Scott: My body just like like wakes up stupid early.
Rym: Never had that right?
Scott: It's like it's.
Scott: it's like I'll have normal sleep.
Scott: I know my sleep is relatively normal.
Scott: Like I said compared to insomnia narcolepsy people have real problems.
Scott: Right is like it's relatively normal.
Scott: I lay down and go to sleep and then I wake up in the morning, right?
Scott: I'm pretty deep.
Scott: It's hard to wake me up.
Scott: a little relative You can wake me up, but it's not it's not.
Scott: honestly I don't wake up at the drop of a hat.
Rym: I would sleep crazy like I know some people will wake up if there's like at the tiniest noise.
Rym: What's that actually asleep?
Rym: It's really hard to wake me up.
Scott: Hey But the point is you have to like shake me.
Scott: there are still times we're like for some reason like like a few months ago I had a problem.
Scott: We're like.
Scott: I Felt like I was waking up like super waking up.
Scott: Like I felt like wow, that was a complete the sleep.
Scott: Let's open my eyes and open my eyes and look at the watt my clock and it would be like 1 a.m.
Scott: And I'm like, I went to bed at like 10 11.
Rym: Oh, that's the best.
Scott: though if I that time when I do I feel like I'm super fully slept after like two three hours Yeah, and then I go back to sleep and then I wake up again and it's like, all right What time the fuck is it now for that three?
Rym: Okay, great One of the best feelings in the world is because usually it's so specific on weekdays I wake up at exactly 7 no matter what I'm just awake.
Scott: mine kind of floats around In the 7 area.
Rym: if I set my alarm for 655, it'll wake me up.
Rym: if I set it for 705 I'll wake up.
Rym: I'll reach over grab my phone.
Scott: It's exactly said they're the majority of the time.
Scott: It's something around like that.
Scott: But there are times we're like I sleep for just some reason.
Scott: we'll get messed up and weird things will happen.
Scott: Usually in the waking up early department this going to sleep I don't have too many problems, but the what, you know, it's only like I said the rare, okay Yeah, I'm thinking too much and I can't sleep.
Scott: but more common Wake up early for who the fuck knows?
Scott: I
Rym: think one thing that happened to me specifically because it messed up my eating schedule to a little bit like kind of permanently is I had that job when I when we lived in Beacon where I had to get an ass early train because I worked seven to Four in Manhattan and I did that for like almost four years.
Rym: So as a result like this and it was Metro North it was if I missed that train I was gonna be an hour late to work.
Rym: I never missed that train in four years But it really ingrained this like hyper specific schedule in my life of wake up.
Rym: at this exact time you have Exactly eight minutes to get to the train station.
Rym: Yeah eat lunch at 1105 leave work at 405 to catch the 411 train home and to this day.
Rym: I think that just like set these schedules in my brain that will never go away.
Rym: Mmm, like I still eat lunch at 11 I can't even if I eat breakfast.
Rym: I just I get hungry at exactly 11.
Rym: Mm-hmm and I get hangry if I don't eat by 1130.
Rym: But the other thing is I used to go on a lot of road trips like a lot of road trips and I was usually the only driver on these road trips and Remember even our IT.
Rym: whenever I went home to like see my family I would always wait till like midnight and then I drive through the Canadian wilderness from midnight until dawn.
Rym: So I had a lot of experience driving when I'm really really really tired.
Scott: That's really really dangerous.
Rym: But as a result, I had this like very hyper specific like cannot fall asleep mode that I can put myself into.
Scott: Yeah, I guess that is.
Scott: that is also a thing is like even though I if I lay down I can and I'm tired I can go to sleep.
Scott: I can probably even do it if I'm not that tired.
Scott: Yeah, but I have a real hard time sleeping in Weird positions like right.
Rym: a lot of people say that like oh, I can't sleep on planes Right sleeping on a plane because I'm sitting up.
Scott: I'm not laying.
Scott: if I was laying down I'd be fine But it's I'm sitting up right?
Scott: It's like I need to lay down flat if I'm or at least mostly for some reason I don't like I've fallen asleep standing up before I mean I have.
Rym: I kind of fell over Super tired.
Scott: I can like I have slept on plane like I could sleep in this chair But it's not.
Scott: I mean I could if I was super tired but like I could be a little bit tired or barely tired and sleep in a bed just For me to sleep in a chair or some other position.
Rym: I need you know to be extra tired doesn't matter What time of day does any plan I get on to.
Rym: I see even if it's like the crappy economy seat on a shitty Airline in the middle of the day soon as I sit on that plane two or three minutes go by I'm tired And I just fall asleep.
Scott: I can only do that if it's like a long flight, and I get way tired if it's.
Scott: if the flights too short I won't actually fall asleep.
Scott: I can like close my eyes and sort of But I won't like really sleep.
Scott: You know unless it's I get extra tired Because I'm not.
Scott: but if I was laying down right I could like immediately Mmm.
Rym: Yeah, I was about to get into dreams, but we already did a show on dreams.
Scott: I mean I think we did a show on mattresses Pillows and blankets.
Scott: we're gonna buy a new mattress, so let's just end it by talking about sleeping positions.
Scott: I mostly sleep on the right side of my body Touching the mattress and I got semi fetal positions, so I can sleep in other positions like I toss and turn at night.
Scott: sometimes I'll just go like you know face down on the on.
Scott: the thing is like my second best position.
Scott: I Partly because you sleep like the month like a vampire.
Rym: I sleep like a vampire like I'm like it's such a flat on back like I I cannot sleep except on my back.
Scott: If I sleep on my side my arms, and you can say you said you can sleep in an airplane though sitting up is fine.
Rym: But if I'm in a bed, I like sitting up is fine.
Rym: I can sleep sitting up if I'm lying down if I lie on my side My arms and legs will fall asleep because I'm so skinny and bony That it just like compresses and like everything instantly falls asleep like in the bad way And my legs are really thick.
Rym: so they'll if I let you sleep on my side unless I'm very careful things get crushed.
Rym: You don't have huge games.
Rym: Okay Do you understand the scale of my games?
Scott: That's in front of your legs.
Rym: Yeah between them, but then if I've been to lay on my side And they're like pushed out in front, but then if I move my legs at all I'll I crush him in my sleep or now my leg will fall asleep Uh-huh.
Rym: so I can only sleep on my back.
Rym: if I'm in a bed And I tend to just naturally pull my arms up in the cross position like over myself like I'm just now And I just I'm silent I'm just laying there not moving.
Scott: also I like to be on the side of the bed where since I'm my the right side of my body is touching the mattress.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I want to be on the side of the bed where I'm basically super close to the edge.
Rym: Oh, we are we alternate every few years which side of the bed.
Rym: We're on.
Scott: okay That's not the worst.
Rym: I say like kind of like with my wallet.
Rym: actually in 2020 It's time to move my wallet from my back left pocket back to my back right pocket while always front right pocket.
Rym: Never never pocket.
Scott: nothing in the back pocket where it can be all in the back pocket.
Scott: nothing in the back pocket.
Rym: always wallet My whole wallet.
Scott: I don't want to sit on nothing up.
Rym: I have jeans where it doesn't.
Scott: I'm not actually sitting on it cuz it's on the side So it's easy for me to just snatch it out while you're sitting.
Rym: no cuz they're really tight jeans I defy you to get my wallet out of my pants.
Rym: YouTube video I'll sit you try to get the wallet out of my pants, and then I'll run right with your wallet.
Rym: But no like.
Rym: if you see like people make fun of me.
Rym: Firstly you see me sleeping, and I'm just a Nosferatu like it's weird.
Scott: Maybe I'll suggest that bed switching hadn't thought of that idea.
Rym: like everything like long cycle is the right way to do it.
Rym: Part of it's because in the morning are like the movie the bunny will Do its funny stuff and whoever seem on one side of the bed gets to watch it mm-hmm and the other person can't really see It.
Rym: so we alternate every now, and then it's about time to alternate again.
Rym: Yeah, top blankets anything else will defer to another show.
Scott: You know if you can afford it.
Scott: king-size bed if you got room for you know It's funny.
Rym: queen-size bed is fine like for two people like I don't have the king-size bed I think.
Rym: ah a king-size bed feels like it's just a stupid waste of whatever.
Rym: no But every time I'm in a hotel where I'm in a king-size bed my body is just like What and I sleep.
Rym: star unless you're a smaller person yeah, but I starfish.
Scott: we're large enough to you know.
Rym: There were at the wedding over the weekend.
Rym: it was a king-size bed.
Rym: I didn't sleep like a Nosferatu.
Rym: I slept like a starfish.
Rym: I woke up literally like the duck like this Every morning.
Rym: I woke up like you know.
Scott: measurement wise is not that much bigger But it's just like.
Scott: for some reason it just looks way bigger and feels way bigger despite only being slightly bigger.
Scott: inch wise.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our Website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, how do you mingle?
Rym: just like a dude?
Rym: gags art obvious and William myson rose linky gee hydrated Gannon boogaloo Jennifer Hitchcock Chris midkiff my state he calm j-ban Shawn Yeager Nicholas Brando Let's see if Rym says Toronto properly for two one creations chilling out max and relaxing.
Rym: all cool Shervin but all Rory Superboy Clinton Walton run from New Zealand Ryan Perrin Dropping lender Finn dread Lily Tenebrae Shawn Klein Chris Reimer Thomas.
Rym: on and here's something Potatoes and molasses.
Rym: There's only one sis if you can't take a fisherman's but when you start seeing stuff, it's More potatoes.
Rym: That's enough father.
Rym: is this what I've been paying for?