Rym: It's Tuesday October 8th 2019.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We are talking about a train game in space 2038 tycoons of the asteroid belt.
Rym: Can you build a financial empire in space?
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: So yesterday I stayed at work a little late because I kind of there's a whole thing going on like a big important project.
Rym: And you know, I'm a product manager and I do a lot of things.
Rym: It's hard to say what a product manager means because it literally has a different definition every company.
Rym: But basically I was asked to make some slides to be able to present something to important people today.
Rym: So yesterday I stayed like an hour late and I made these slides because people have realized that making slides is something I am like fucking pro at like.
Rym: I think the two of us could just have a job making slides me and Scott.
Scott: If anyone wants to hire me as a professional slide maker that job would be way easier than the job I have now and if you pay me more or as much I mean.
Rym: So I stay late and I make these slides because today at like 10 a.m I got to do a really important presentation on these slides.
Rym: So first I gotta figure out what the hell these slides are about.
Rym: I gotta I gotta let do my things.
Rym: I get my thing ready.
Rym: I get up early today.
Rym: I head over to the subway like 8.
Scott: Oh, you have to get up early to get to work it by 10.
Rym: No, I wanted to get to work a little early to like look at these with.
Rym: some of the other.
Rym: people are gonna be in The room and like a sanity check and I had to go to a different office.
Rym: so I wanted but I wanted time.
Rym: so I got up a little early.
Rym: like have a leisurely morning before I do a big thing and I get on the train at like 815 810 and suddenly the train like runs over something and Stops dead and just sits there not moving in the tunnel with no signal.
Rym: Mmm I was trapped on that train for two full hours Mm-hmm.
Rym: the worst part about this for me at that point was simply that a lot of people including my boss were like expecting me to show up at this meeting at 10 and 10 o'clock was actually rapidly approaching and I had no way to tell anyone what happened to
Scott: me.
Scott: Nope So not when you're under the river.
Rym: So as far as literally like all these people are converging on this room Like for this important meeting and bit by bit I imagine it's starting to be like where's Rym.
Rym: Hey, he hasn't even like shown up at work yet.
Rym: It's 945.
Rym: Where is he?
Rym: Did you try calling him?
Rym: Yeah, I tried calling him.
Rym: Can't get through what's going on.
Rym: Oh, no.
Rym: Has anyone seen him?
Rym: Like that is clearly going on.
Rym: so eventually after like 40 minutes they get on and they're like, yeah the emergency brake something something something To trail off crack a shit.
Rym: Yeah, so eventually Someone walks through the train very slowly and people are of course asking them question.
Rym: Well walks through the train is not quite what happened shoves their way through the train because I was stuck for two hours Standing up crushed against the wall on a completely packed subway train.
Scott: Oh, it was a full train completely full.
Rym: so I'm like crushed against the wall like Rereading the same way.
Rym: post story again because I ran out of shit to do on my phone.
Scott: Play reason the galaxy hundred.
Rym: I finished that book I was reading and I hadn't downloaded a new.
Scott: Well, you could never run out of pages into a reading Tale of Genji is not actually on my phone.
Rym: I've been reading that on my kindle stakes are made.
Scott: Yep, I would have been okay with a Kindle app on your phone and sync it.
Rym: Yeah, I should.
Rym: but anyway, I'm gonna do.
Rym: I'm gonna.
Rym: tale of Genji is gonna get on my phone tonight.
Rym: I know that the next time I'm delayed for two hours with no internet I will have a literally Unlimited amount of entertainment because if I get all the way to the end of the tale of Genji It'll have been so long that I could go back to the beginning having forgotten the details of what happened, correct?
Rym: As happens when I watch certain anime over again, so, uh eventually the train Is not gonna move.
Rym: so they announced that rescue trains are coming.
Scott: All right Well, it's a very so people don't know.
Rym: the seven trace the seven train Train is like the second most important subway in New York.
Scott: There are several trains that go underneath the East River.
Scott: They're also trains that go over the East River on bridges Like the J train just goes on a bridge right.
Rym: all of them goes so deep that it has to go Under.
Rym: Roosevelt Island is the deepest subway station.
Scott: Yeah, the F train goes under Roosevelt Island.
Scott: The N and R trains.
Scott: they have a tunnel.
Scott: right now the EC the E train has a tunnel.
Scott: Yeah, but then the Seven the seven train has its own tunnel.
Rym: Well, the seven train has something known as what the Steinway tube the Steinway tube.
Rym: It has fucking iron.
Rym: It's over a hundred years is a cast iron literal tube.
Scott: Also, those are IRT trains.
Scott: So it's they're narrower right track wise and narrower trains.
Scott: then I get the trot track wise but the trains are narrower.
Rym: Yeah, right then the BMT and IND trains Because we're gonna talk about a train game.
Scott: No, this is relevant.
Scott: and those tubes are super narrow.
Scott: They're so narrow that they do not have room to be for a worker to be in the tube working While the train is in the tube.
Scott: It's not like normal tunnels where I give someone a nook to hide in.
Scott: it's like no what they want to work on the tunnel Which they have to do a lot because they're old and busted.
Rym: New tunnels need to be dug, but we can't afford that because of upstate New York, right?
Scott: But anyway, so they have to basically stop seven service between Manhattan and Queens or to work on the tunnel.
Scott: and also The tunnels are just cast-iron tubes that are constantly leaking water into them.
Rym: So there's pumps in there.
Scott: right like think about it Even if there's not a hole in it, which there probably are holes and cracks in it for who right somewhere.
Scott: But you know if you take your cast-iron pot, it's sort of like it can get wet.
Scott: It's like it's not a hundred percent non-porous, right?
Scott: Water is getting in there all the time.
Scott: It's underneath a river and They have to pump that water the fuck out.
Scott: There are pumps running all the time.
Scott: If the pumps of enough pumps fail, yeah, then it will flood and you can't go in there.
Rym: The important thing is the NW train and the seven train between the two of them That is millions and millions and millions of people.
Rym: like that is a hugely important subway System those two train two sets of trains.
Rym: So the city has a protocol where if one of them is down The other one cannot under any circumstances be down or it is a like.
Rym: it is a ridiculous disaster for the city.
Scott: Yeah, man, everyone on each.
Scott: Yeah 100% capacity.
Scott: you have everyone on EF train.
Rym: Yep So the seven being down for like three and a half Like that train being down probably caused tens of millions of dollars in economic damage to New York City.
Rym: Yep, like it was a shit was a big disaster.
Rym: So eventually a rescue train comes in from the front.
Scott: Yeah, they can't come in from the side.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: It's well, it's a Because there are two tracks in this tiny - yeah, and we were kind of near Grand Central like we were approaching Grand Central.
Rym: So they brought a train from the front and they just rolled it up and eventually like they opened doors They made a platform between the two and put up all these tarps and then they made everyone walk from the train.
Rym: We were on forward to this new train and once they got everyone that train they're gonna take us in the Grand Central.
Rym: I don't know if you understand how long New York City subway trains are.
Rym: it took like a half hour to get everyone to walk into this other train.
Scott: Well, you only need half the people to walk into the because you can bring another Half.
Scott: had another half right but you know But you I imagine you were in.
Scott: if you're in the front even in the front car You're in the front car.
Scott: You still have to walk the entire length Of the new rescue train to get to its front front car.
Scott: Yeah, well was rear is now gonna be front car when it moves the other direction.
Rym: Yeah anyway so we walk up eventually and then this this rescue train is gonna go and it starts to move a little bit and then It fucks up and the emergency brake kicks in and it gets stuck like five feet away people.
Rym: I Said my favorite phrase in the world Thank You New York, okay.
Rym: So eventually the train like we get into the station.
Rym: It's like 101.
Rym: So of course my phone goes apeshit now And I call my bosses and everything and they're like, yeah the meetings about to start.
Rym: so I run to my office which is not where the meeting is log into the video conference out of breath and I do the presentation remotely while someone else presents the slides in the room and that was super difficult and stressful.
Rym: I couldn't even hear what any was saying in the room because the microphone in the room was bad.
Rym: So people were asking me questions and I was guessing what they had asked and I guess I answered every question correctly Despite not actually hearing any words.
Rym: They said except a few nouns.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Everything went fine.
Rym: I didn't actually learn until later when I was talking to Scott randomly that what had happened was the train.
Rym: the car I was in Ran somebody over and that thing I felt was the crushing.
Rym: Yep, and those tarps were said.
Rym: no one saw it.
Scott: There were tarps under the train.
Rym: well They put tarps up as we had to walk from one train to the other train and they put like tarps up that They were.
Rym: all the workers were implying it was to make it sure we couldn't like fall out the side when we because we had To jump across the bike from one train to the other there was like a two-foot gap We don't?
Scott: they usually just take a metal sheet and use it as a bridge.
Rym: They didn't have that.
Rym: yet They waited until every.
Scott: those aren't those like included in every train car Like.
Rym: there's just like a secret compartment a metro north and those are for side to side.
Scott: Train rescue could still use it.
Rym: Yeah, they did.
Rym: we had to jump across.
Rym: It's like two-foot gap.
Scott: What if someone couldn't jump?
Rym: everyone who couldn't jump?
Rym: they waited until everyone walked across which was the vast majority of people.
Rym: and then?
Rym: MJP workers like went and Yeah, they individually helped everyone else one by one, okay So that was my Odyssey this morning.
Rym: All right.
Scott: Well, my opening bit is way less exciting And let way less unusual.
Scott: So I've been trying to buy some jean.
Rym: Oh So Uniqlo they don't they don't have the good Uniqlo jeans anymore, but it's like, okay Well, but that's the thing is the Uniqlo jeans.
Scott: I got the last time I got Uniqlo jeans, right?
Scott: They were you know, right size right comfiness level, but they were lacking in the durability and lasting department.
Scott: They literally broke.
Scott: You know, I was like the old Uniqlo jeans.
Rym: I still have one pair of those left.
Scott: I was like Even cheapo Levi's, they're not the comfiest.
Scott: They're not the best fitting but they don't break.
Scott: They're super strong Yeah, so I switched by rectification.
Rym: I gave up all my jeans are just basically spandex and I just replaced them every few years because they wear out.
Scott: Well, I was recommended to go get American Eagle jeans.
Rym: So I did right But they're really durable.
Scott: well so what happened was is I got them and they were way comfy and They're the right size and they're stretchy and they look good.
Scott: But what happened is Some of the ones I got right.
Scott: they were like 32 30 The inseam was 32, which was correct.
Scott: when they were new.
Scott: I go with the 34 because and they they shrunk a little bit and then they became a little high watery.
Rym: Oh, the high water is the worst, right?
Scott: So then I tried some 34 But that was too long.
Rym: So my Strategy I wear 30 34 so 30 inch waist even though it's a little big but it's hard to get 29 34.
Rym: So I get 30 24 or 30 34 and I just roll up the cuffs.
Rym: I do the style of.
Rym: I've rolled up cuffs in all my jeans, right?
Scott: So anyway, so then There's a company called Madewell, which is owned by J crew and in the city all their stores only sell ladies clothes and they specialize in denim.
Scott: They like denim bar.
Rym: So I'll admit straight up some of the G. a lot of my jeans are women's jeans.
Rym: guys fit me better.
Scott: So on their website, however The Madewell website they have man jeans.
Rym: Oh, but not in the store.
Scott: So yeah, right.
Scott: So I ordered their man jeans on their website, which were expensive.
Scott: But Amanda got something was like, oh these are worth all the money's they're so great I'm intrigued now.
Scott: So I ordered them from the website and I right but but the ones I ordered they were way too big.
Rym: Oh, so I went like are the numbers just wrong?
Scott: They were like they were super long and super fat in the butt and like the butt was like I had like a little Parachute, but yeah, that's partly why increasingly I just wear spandex.
Rym: that looks like jeans.
Scott: Oh, so then I apparently the thing was is you can return those at their store.
Scott: So I went to their store and it took two minutes.
Scott: I gave them the jeans that came in the mail and they gave me my money back.
Scott: So then I'm like, you know what I heard about this store, right?
Scott: I work in like Soho.
Scott: It's like the fancy fashion II district.
Scott: we're like ultra high-end shit where you know, rich people buy stuff.
Scott: I'm like, let's just go they're not gonna kick me out.
Scott: I'll just go to the rich people store.
Scott: Try on some rich people jeans and not buy them and see if it's or is it worth it to buy?
Scott: $250 jeans.
Rym: So the last time I did that was gloves.
Rym: I went to the fancy fancy place in Midtown There's like ten years ago and I was like, what are fancy gloves like?
Rym: and I tried on some leather gloves.
Rym: They were like they were like butter.
Rym: and then I thought these are what like $400.
Rym: All right.
Rym: No, they were $4,000 and I walked out of that store.
Scott: So I went to this store at the rag and bone where the jeans are $250 each.
Scott: right expecting not to buy any jeans.
Scott: Oh, I didn't buy any jeans?
Rym: Yeah, not paying $250 for one gene.
Rym: fuck that I would if they were durable and perfect if I can wear them for a decade.
Rym: the play was comfortable.
Scott: place was very much Shiloh warm sirs crack pipe dude wanted to like bring me water while I was in the dressing room.
Scott: Right, it was often glove place.
Rym: they followed me around like they thought it was a shoplifter because I didn't look fancy enough, right?
Scott: So The thing was is for $250.
Scott: It's like all right, maybe what you know, if this gene will last me 15 years, I mean I
Rym: bought a thousand dollar computer chair a long time ago, and I'm still using the right
Scott: Right, so and like if this gene well is the most perfect fitting gene in the universe, right and will last me a super long Time and that's fucking great.
Scott: Then I might consider buying it.
Scott: It was on sale Yeah, and so I go to try on a whole bunch, right and in I got there.
Scott: They don't give you lengths on these.
Scott: they're only with what there's only with and they're all about 34s at least what they say.
Scott: and then if you need shorter then you can tailor them.
Scott: you can you go get them shortened And the guy actually suggested we will shorten them for you for $30, but he's like you should just go somewhere else.
Scott: It will be cheaper and faster.
Scott: All right good on him, right?
Scott: Cuz he says that yeah, it takes us like three weeks to do it and we charge 30 bucks each.
Scott: But basically they just make all their genes Slightly longer than at any average person would need them and then expect you to shorten them.
Rym: See I choose to do the new style of always get 34s and just roll them up, right?
Scott: But yeah, so the I got there was and also their genes run big which I'm like if they're expensive fancy rich people ones.
Scott: Shouldn't they just be exactly right?
Scott: Why are they right?
Rym: But I took for that.
Rym: you need tailored genes.
Rym: where they cut They make them for you.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, I got 32s in two different colors, but basically the same exact gene and one of them was a lot like Different size than the other.
Scott: what it was like I'm like feels like they were not I was expecting like perfect amazing comfort and whatnot.
Rym: No, cuz like when I got I got a few tailored shirts for like fancy occasions and they were expensive but not crazy expensive.
Rym: They were expensive but they fit Perfectly, I mean these were like so perfectly.
Rym: It's weird.
Rym: I'm like Finn's grass sword.
Scott: We were they were nice jeans and if I would have gotten them tailored to the right length, they would have fit all Perfectly as a gene is gonna fit.
Rym: but for you could.
Scott: but they were not Three times as good as a $90 or you know, whatever.
Scott: They were not like with steaks.
Rym: a $10 steak ain't that great.
Rym: a $20 takes pretty good.
Rym: a $40 steak is great.
Rym: A $400 steak is only slightly better than a $40 day, right?
Scott: The $250 gene was not three times better than the $75.
Scott: You find me a steak Better 85, I don't know.
Rym: find me a steak That is ten times better than a $40 steak and I will pay any amount of money for that steak.
Rym: Yeah, cuz it doesn't exist.
Scott: So I do not recommend the $250 gene.
Scott: What I did is I went back to the the Madewell one, right the ladies gene place Yeah, and I just went back to the website after getting my refund And it has ordered a smaller size because I can just return those again, too If they're not any good right
Rym: also for that price.
Scott: that doesn't work out.
Scott: I'll try some other place.
Rym: how much do actually just straight-up tailored jeans cost then compared to these like Multi-hundred-dollar not tailored jeans.
Scott: I mean I could have just bought those $250 jeans and had them shorten them and that would know.
Scott: tailored means they like measure Multiple parts of your body and every other part of the gene was pretty much exactly right as long, you know.
Scott: But not were it wasn't as good as the price.
Rym: I got the problem because I run so much.
Rym: I got really big gams and very few jeans.
Rym: So tiny waist and big game.
Scott: well, so what you got to do if you got that is they have athletic cut jeans, which basically are this like extreme tapering situation Which is good if you're like a hockey player and you have a giant ass and giant thighs and like, you know Normal-sized normal-sized calf.
Scott: Yeah It's actually a relatively recent development.
Scott: it used to just be like skinny slim straight.
Scott: now There's like the athletic cut is a relatively recent thing.
Scott: Yeah, that is for people with gigantic thighs and asses.
Rym: The other problem I have though is for any of you have met me in person.
Rym: I have Freakishly tiny wrists and ankles.
Scott: I have tiny wrists and also long arms.
Scott: Yeah while I was in there was like coats in the store and I was checking him out and the.
Scott: I saw a really nice coat at another store recently and when I looked inside the coat, it was four thousand or two thousand dollars.
Scott: And I looked at a coat in this store and I was like, oh that looks like that $2,000 coat.
Scott: and I was like Oh, it's only one thousand dollars.
Scott: I guess I still won't buy this.
Rym: I saved a thousand dollars, right?
Scott: but I tried it on and Basically the medium my arms came way out the sleeve and the large was like, you know a balloon.
Rym: see that's.
Rym: That's what I don't get when if you're paying that much money for something Better be tailored like.
Rym: if it's off the rack.
Scott: It should be cheap anyway, and then I was in another store.
Scott: I was just passing by and they had a similar coat and it was like, oh only five hundred dollars.
Scott: Not buying this money.
Rym: I Remember when I was a kid, I got a $90 jacket once And I wore that jacket until it was just threads.
Rym: I bought I got a leather integrated around me.
Scott: I got a leather jacket suede leather.
Rym: I love that.
Scott: I got a leather jacket in high school from like this leather good store in the mall.
Scott: That was way good at least at the time and then the zipper got busted and then I had someone fix the zipper But it was still busted.
Scott: and then I just never went and got the zipper fixed again.
Scott: And then by the time I was like, oh, you know I should go and get the zipper fixed on that fucking thing.
Scott: and I went and I put it on and I was like Wow, this jacket from the 90s looks way derpy Fixed.
Scott: it's sort of big and poofy and derpy looking.
Scott: Wow Why did I think this is cool when it was new?
Scott: and then I gave donated it at the coat drive at the holiday season After like 15 to 20 years after I got it.
Rym: So there's a lot of really big news.
Rym: we're really only going to talk about one thing before we get into our space train game review, but briefly if you didn't notice the Professional hockey season has started while the NHL season.
Scott: There's a lot of other professional hockey in the world.
Rym: Yeah But this is the only hockey we're at.
Rym: at the conclusion of the season Some team will have the right to hold Lord Stanley's Cup mmm, and There's no like lockout like all that's like.
Rym: didn't none of that happen?
Rym: We're getting just normal hockey and I continue to be a fan of the undefeated New York Rangers.
Scott: Oh what happened to your and your your Detroit team?
Rym: I've lived in New York.
Scott: You disloyal person.
Scott: I think if I think if I move to Detroit, I would be like go wings.
Rym: You know if I live I moved to Detroit for 10 years.
Scott: I would probably really if I move to Detroit and live there the rest of my life.
Scott: Do you think I would ever Want the Red Wings to win?
Rym: but Scott, what about the people who are born in Buffalo?
Rym: You got to give him an escape.
Scott: you mean my co-worker who is from Rochester and Was like Scott taking me to go see the Sabres and I was like, okay I can see the Red Wings play in New York like at best twice a year.
Scott: or I can mean once Oh, I guess you could see them against the Islanders.
Rym: Yeah That's the level of desperation it would take.
Scott: you can see them playing as the Devils.
Rym: Yeah I'd rather go see them play against the Islanders.
Rym: But or I can see the Rangers play all the time with a half season.
Rym: So mmm I live in New York.
Rym: But anyway the big news and it's all still developing.
Rym: So I want to send some context for this because China has gone after Both Activision Blizzard and the NBA in a very short span of time and These situations are both evolving kind of rapidly.
Rym: So I want to sort of set the stage by explaining something people don't realize.
Rym: you might assume you talk about this on Twitter.
Rym: The video game industry and to a large extent the tabletop board game industry in the entire world Regardless of whether or not they talk about it follow most of the Chinese censorship rules Because the reality is you either sell your games in China if you're a big company or manufacture your games in China if you are most tabletop game publishers or You're done like.
Rym: you can't make money like that's how the world is.
Rym: People whether we like it or not whether we talk about it or not They tend to follow all of China's rules to avoid Having to deal with the Chinese government giving you shit or seizing your games or denying you access to the market.
Rym: Like that's the thing.
Rym: that's why you tend to not see Taiwanese flags in any video games.
Scott: hmm
Rym: other countries pull similar shit like India does the same thing with if you show Kashmir the wrong way on a map, but Because of economic reasons big companies don't really care if they can sell their games in India But they care a lot if they can sell their games in China because most of these companies Might be in trouble if they couldn't sell games in China financially.
Rym: In fact in many cases they might be liable for damages to their shareholders because of ridiculous and possibly out-of-date fiduciary responsibility Rules, I am NOT a lawyer.
Rym: This is not investment advice but That is the context for this.
Rym: Blizzard got called out because China Effectively forced them to do this.
Rym: Well, yeah, I got called out because the NBA I don't know what's gonna happen with the NBA All right.
Scott: So here's so here.
Scott: you didn't talk about what actually happened.
Rym: Here's the details and you read these stories for the like.
Rym: full details cuz we're not news we're commentary right.
Scott: so in the NBA Right.
Scott: I think is the owner of the Rockets I believe the king so right?
Scott: Or is the coach of the owner?
Scott: I forget I don't pay too much attention to the Houston Rockets, right?
Scott: The point is the dude made a pro Hong Kong Comment right.
Scott: and then Houston Rockets are the most popular.
Scott: and not only is basketball super popular in China, right?
Scott: The Houston Rockets are the most popular NBA team in China because that's a team Yao Ming played for a lot of sponsorship deals in China.
Scott: right Yao Ming is a big duty.
Scott: It's like yeah.
Scott: You remember the super tall Chinese dude who came and played basketball for a little bit and then went back to China.
Scott: He basically runs basketball in China.
Scott: Now.
Scott: He's a big deal that guy.
Scott: But yeah.
Scott: But because of this comment China's like well, we're not gonna broadcast any Rockets games.
Scott: In fact now, we're just now gonna broadcast any NBA preseason.
Rym: This is the company that streams NBA in China is ten cents.
Scott: Mm-hmm The same company that's holding seems like the ball seems like ten cent only exists to distribute Western things and make partnerships with Western companies to do Chinese thing.
Scott: pretty.
Scott: it seems like that's all that company does.
Rym: pretty sure ten cent Made that like mobile Call of Duty game to sell in China.
Rym: There is a Like it or not home video game companies.
Rym: Like.
Rym: the only way to really make money is to make mobile versions of your IP and sell that in China through ten cent.
Rym: that's how you make money.
Scott: It's like every time it's like, oh, yeah, we're gonna work with ten cent to do stuff.
Scott: Okay, whatever.
Scott: It's so.
Rym: the Chinese basketball Relationship with the Rockets like Merchandise is no longer allowed to be sold on Alibaba like all sorts of shit went down.
Scott: So now the NBA has to skirt this line.
Scott: It's like, okay Well, we don't want to condemn this guy for saying something that's a right Yeah, but be in America where you have freedom of speech, right?
Scott: But see if we don't do anything about this, we're gonna lose a fuck ton of money.
Rym: Yeah, we were like to the point that it might be a problem for the NBA.
Rym: Right.
Scott: The NBA is long-term.
Scott: plans are basically to like have real NBA teams in China and make it a real thing.
Scott: Oh and before we you know Worldwide League and that this is there's one person making one off-hand comment Can like screw that whole thing like a bill a multi-billion dollar comment.
Rym: The NHL actually has a similar strategy because hockey is getting popular in China.
Scott: There was a. there was a CWHL women's hockey team in China All right.
Rym: There's also you've noticed in a lot of Rangers games and other hockey games You'll actually see various Chinese firms buying ads in the games.
Rym: Oftentimes those ads are even in Chinese.
Rym: Like.
Scott: I don't think hockey's that big in China Yeah, but it's it's really big.
Scott: as far as I can tell if you're a sports league You're trying to make you know, Chinese people care about your thing.
Rym: I'm not an expert but as best I can tell hockey is really big among upper-class people in certain parts of China.
Rym: I mean, I'm sure healthy people like cocky there.
Scott: I mean wealthy people around the world.
Rym: I mean hockey is a very like wealthy person sport for a lot of you have to be healthy to play hockey.
Scott: Yeah, you need an ice rink.
Scott: You need skates and all this other shit.
Scott: It's not like soccer.
Scott: Anyone can play.
Scott: Anyway, so with Hearthstone and Blizzard what happened was this is dude Blitz something.
Scott: What's his name?
Rym: Oh, this dude is my hero.
Scott: Yeah blitz chung, right?
Scott: So this is a Hearthstone guy that I had known.
Scott: I just knew his name.
Scott: I knew he was a Hearthstone player, but I didn't know anything else about him.
Scott: And basically he was at a Hearthstone tournament.
Scott: I think did he win me?
Scott: I think he might have won.
Scott: I'm not sure.
Rym: he won a match in the Grand Masters, right?
Scott: He won a match and then there was a an interview and at the interview He was just like yeah Hong Kong.
Rym: Whoo.
Rym: He said the thing that is like super illegal to say in China Yeah, liberate Hong Kong revolution of our time and he wore goggles and a face mask in solidarity with the protesters, right?
Scott: He's basically like yeah, let's go Hong Kong you know with his which is what I recommend pretty much anyone do.
Scott: if You manage to get put on a stage and you get a mic with enough ears, right?
Scott: Do not take that for granted.
Scott: don't use it what it's intended to be used for right?
Scott: It's like if you win an Oscar don't go up and be like, oh, thanks so-and-so you should do it.
Scott: many other people have done and use your Moments of nationally broadcast television in the most effective way possible.
Rym: Yep, right Their health care.
Scott: if you win an Olympic gold medal, you know, go ahead and raise up your fist.
Scott: You only got one shot.
Scott: Don't wait.
Scott: You got this opportunity.
Scott: Don't fucking waste it.
Scott: and anyone who doesn't waste it you're badass.
Scott: I root for you.
Scott: good job.
Scott: So anyway, this guy wisely did not waste his opportunity while many many people were watching him on Twitch and other places around the world And then as a result blizzard a Denied him all his winnings from hearthstone this year.
Rym: the reef of all the things blizzard did are partly because ten cent owns a chunk of blizzard and Blizzard isn't just blizzard.
Rym: blizzard is Activision blizzard.
Rym: Activision uses ten cent to make money in China.
Scott: Yep, and he's banned from hearthstone.
Scott: and Now what's happening is blizzards between a rock and a hard place.
Scott: because on the one hand, right?
Rym: If they don't do this they're gonna get like all the blizzard games could just get booted out of China like literally half the overwatch league will disappear and Activism blizzard may not even be able to sustain the league anymore, right?
Scott: And also on the other hand If you look at say the blizzard reddit the hearthstone reddit any of the right if they do this They're gonna lose the American team.
Scott: even even blizzard play at blizzard employees were covering up You know the the slogans at the blizzard headquarters.
Scott: Yeah, that say like, you know every.
Scott: you know, what does it say?
Scott: Every voice is to be listened to or something every every voice should be heard something like that.
Scott: Yeah, they were.
Scott: basically it's on the American side.
Scott: Everyone's just like.
Scott: well, I'm done with hearthstone.
Scott: Fuck you.
Scott: Fuck this Fuck blizzard not playing your games anymore deleting my blizzard people are deleting their battle net accounts.
Scott: All right, just like oh fuck that the end.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So, you know on the what you see it even Politicians in America right even bad Republican ones are say I end the Democratic ones.
Scott: I saw at least one Republican and one Democratic senator Commenting on like even blizzard specifically just MBA.
Rym: when the US government says the right thing It's either the Democrats or the Democrats and the Republicans.
Rym: It's never just the Republicans.
Rym: They've never said the right thing.
Rym: They don't say the right thing on their own But but they both agree that this is trouble.
Scott: They're basically like yeah China uses its threat of you know, cutting you off from their market, right?
Scott: to control your behavior.
Rym: And that is not worse because most tabletop games are manufactured in China.
Scott: China has a history.
Scott: Well, we did.
Scott: I don't know if we did a news on it, but there was a call.
Scott: He's that game.
Scott: Yeah, there was a call of Cthulhu Supplement.
Scott: I think that was being printed in China and I think I had the issue with the maps.
Scott: I think we did do news on this.
Scott: It had map issues.
Scott: right with regards to the you know Those islands that China cares about for I don't know fucking reason.
Scott: just get over it.
Scott: Jesus Christ anyway.
Scott: As a result they that RPG was not ever shipped to the u.s.
Scott: And all the copies are just burned in China.
Rym: and I will while I am not at liberty to give specifics.
Rym: I Have been told of specific instances and seen specific Guidelines that were disseminated non publicly given to various publishers at various times over the years not recently This is often like three or four years ago that basically said follow these rules or we will fuck you over.
Rym: Like you can't get around this stuff unless you Completely produce your game outside of China
Scott: and don't sell it to anyone in China
Rym: or at least if people play your game in China you don't rely on that revenue and you do not interact with the Chinese government and you do not care if the Chinese government allows you To continue to sell there or not.
Rym: Mm-hmm honestly, I think that Non Chinese game companies have a moral imperative to not sell their games in China.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I think China does not get to censor the world.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Us has done a lot of shitty things.
Rym: Our government is completely fucked up.
Rym: But the one thing that we've almost got right is that when it comes to creative expression there's freedom to make creative things
Scott: and
Rym: The fact that the entire video game industry of the world has been basically following Chinese censorship laws Without even telling you this is not something new This is just this all being exposed to you now because they can't hide it anymore.
Rym: Esports is a global thing.
Rym: There are Chinese fans.
Rym: There are American fans.
Rym: They're all in the same league.
Rym: One side is gonna give in this.
Rym: there's no compromise possible here.
Rym: I don't think and I don't know how this is gonna play out Mm-hmm.
Rym: I'm gonna keep playing overwatch because I really like overwatch but at the same time I Think blizzard should abandon the Chinese market and if that destroys the overwatch league as much as I love the overwatch league So be it.
Scott: Well, I think you know, there's a. there's a certain thing going on, right?
Rym: I own a lot of blizzard stock.
Rym: I would be harmed myself personally and financially.
Scott: you do something if you do something that China Chinese want.
Scott: China wants and you don't sell it there.
Scott: They just sort of copy you.
Scott: Yeah, right and So it's sort of like.
Scott: well, I can't really threaten them by denying them this thing.
Scott: They'll just copy it.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: It's like yeah, China kicks out the NBA.
Scott: It's like cuz they got their own league right, you know, but it's like.
Scott: But are the people in China isn't there still some element of them being like hey You're denying us the best basketball players on earth, right?
Scott: It's like yeah, I like my Chinese league that I go to I like going to see RIT hockey.
Rym: Yeah, but but I Exist.
Scott: Yeah, if you banned me from seeing the NHL, I'll be fucking pissed.
Scott: It made this KHL teams.
Scott: They make money.
Scott: They have fans.
Scott: this, you know Finnish teams and Swiss Swedish teams.
Scott: is this leagues of hockey around the world?
Scott: You know the soccer leagues around the world, but imagine if like, okay, you know, you're in South America, you can see.
Scott: you know, the American cups all the soccer that happens South America.
Scott: we're not gonna let you watch World Cup or Europa League or Premier League.
Scott: We banned those.
Rym: it's like oh, there's the news.
Rym: Apparently the team's considering firing Daryl Maury over this.
Scott: Yep That's the NBA guy yeah, but anyway.
Scott: So it's like there must be some amount of pressure that can be had from denying China Something that they can't necessarily copy.
Scott: They can't copy LeBron They can have basketball But they can't have the world's best basketball that we that is the United States thing.
Rym: short of a multi-decade Effort to build up a pipeline like all the things that make basketball players in America possible, right?
Scott: That's a long-term investment and it would take a long time for the Chinese Basketball League to produce a team That is better than the NBA all-star, right?
Rym: I mean dreams.
Rym: I think a long long time ago on GeekNights I talked about the the Global Football League.
Rym: that was American football played by literally everyone but the United States and how utterly amazing that league was.
Rym: Yes, Japan was apparently the champion for multiple years in a row.
Scott: Yeah, but anyway, the point is I think that where possible right where there is some leverage like say NBA Right, the NBA has way more leverage than Activision Blizzard does.
Scott: well, yes and no, right?
Scott: So well if the NBA was to say fine China free stop Massacring those who eager people or otherwise no basketball for you, right?
Scott: I feel like they have a moral imperative to do that.
Scott: They aren't gonna but they should.
Scott: I would if I was the Commission or whatever.
Scott: Yeah But think about Blizzard, right?
Scott: There's probably actually more people in China playing and caring about Blizzard games playing Wow store craft overwatch Diablo true, however combined however are People who need NBA.
Scott: imagine if we're just like alright everyone who's ever bought hearthstone cards in guess what?
Scott: We're shutting down all Chinese servers and blocking Anyone in China from accessing any server in any other country and we're kicking you all out of our eSports.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: No, no, no what Chinese people can do any play any Blizzard game You just all cut off until your country is better, you know.
Scott: exert that kind of force instead of just bowing.
Rym: the Trouble is what those people in China get way mad and do something or with the state apparatus of propaganda basically minimize the existence of overwatch in Blizzard.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean if you've been playing World of Warcraft in China for how fucking long and suddenly China is actually very different from World of Warcraft in the US I'm sure it is but it's still you if you're invested in a game.
Scott: You spent a lot of years on it and You're pro, you know, I get this guy's, you know, the guy who quit hearthstone, right?
Scott: He's like, well, I lost four years of my life, but you know, he doesn't seem you know, obviously for him It's more important, right?
Scott: Yeah, but imagine this is imagine if you were pro China, right?
Scott: You're a Chinese person who's pro China But you also, you know play a Blizzard game and suddenly it's just like up.
Scott: We deleted your account because your country sucks.
Scott: fix your shit.
Scott: You may be that person would get mad and do something.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: if they'd get that message though the message from the state Propaganda apparatus would be this this evil capitalist company is denying you this because they hate you.
Scott: I mean, I'm sure also I would also both, you know before I got blocked in China I would disseminate messages to all the players and then go right.
Scott: It's like they would try to open up, you know, their Starcraft and it would say exactly, you know, right?
Scott: I'd sneak that patch in.
Scott: it would be on their computer before it got blocked.
Rym: Yep There's there's a complication here that I don't you know, it involves a lot of you know.
Scott: There's a lot of details and how you exit.
Rym: but I want to get to the main bit.
Rym: But there's a complication here in that Activision Blizzard is a publicly traded company.
Rym: Mm-hmm Denies itself a whole bunch of profits in Situations that I'm not qualified legally to give you any advice.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, but I. but the point is regardless of that duty I would just a ignore that duty right.
Scott: and then it's like I'm a big CEO, right?
Scott: It's like okay the the board take and the shareholders take me to court.
Scott: I would first of all a have lawyers and an argument.
Scott: I'd be like, well, you know, the American players are all leaving.
Scott: I had to do something.
Rym: this is to be richer than you and a better lawyers.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean that's not the point.
Scott: The point is I have an excuse.
Scott: I would go and argue the excuse in court.
Scott: Even if I lose right?
Rym: It's like you did the right thing, right?
Scott: I did the right thing, but here's the thing.
Scott: I can sleep at night.
Scott: And in fact, I would be happy because like well I fuck China good and I fuck these rich asshole bosses double good.
Scott: most American made their shares worth nothing.
Scott: Fuck them.
Rym: Yeah, most American success gamer bros who just want to play their triple-a games.
Rym: The trouble for them, I'm not saying we should give a shit about them, but without the Chinese market I think a good chunk of the American video game industry disappears.
Rym: Oh, yeah probably because we're already in the middle of a huge bubble who played the triple-a games.
Scott: don't realize how much you're being propped up and Subsidized by you know, the Chinese.
Rym: we're thinking about doing a Tuesday show on the price of games.
Rym: That's a topic that we can't get into because it's time for.
Rym: but anyway things Of the day.
Rym: So when I was a kid, I believed in UFOs hundred percent.
Rym: I thought it was for real me.
Scott: It was real.
Scott: I would go to the library and check out UFO books.
Rym: It was mostly because all these stupid shows on TV that I believed Yeah, stupidly and one of those shows the one that I think is primarily responsible for this for me was unsolved mysteries.
Scott: I didn't I mean I only watched that one a little bit.
Scott: It was more for me like these random Every episode of this.
Scott: I watched all these like weird Roswell's special things.
Scott: I even when I learned about the FOA was AOL.
Scott: it was actually a page.
Scott: you could send an FOA request and I sent an FOA request.
Scott: I did something similar on prodigy for Roswell shit, and then they the government sent me this big envelope full of papers I didn't read.
Scott: It was like a huge ass envelope full of a ton of documents and I found that Documents when I cleaned out my mom's house recently and then I recycled it but only like a third of the mysteries.
Rym: that unsolved mysteries were ghosts or aliens.
Rym: the rest were just like murders and financial crimes like real crimes with real people.
Scott: and Yeah, the one I remember though The only unsolved mysteries episode I actually have a clear memory of was like ghost in a hotel that George Washington stated Okay, so I wasn't mr.
Scott: Remember I wasn't making up a memory.
Rym: That's a real episode.
Rym: Okay, good.
Rym: All right The entire show is Legally for free just on YouTube for you to watch on their official channel.
Rym: nice and even better They did the syndication Episodes meaning they have the full commercial breaks.
Rym: Like if you're a nerd it really cares about that.
Rym: No, they really owe.
Rym: but the commercial break the cuts and all that stuff.
Scott: Okay, but not the commercial not the commercial I was gonna say.
Scott: how are they get the rice of the commercial?
Rym: because it's in syndication.
Rym: It's those episodes.
Rym: if they solved it while the show was still going They actually show you the solution.
Rym: So I was watching one last night and it was or watching it and I'm watching this piece of shit.
Rym: husband who?
Rym: 100% murdered his wife.
Rym: Yeah, of course, and it's him.
Rym: It's actually him and like it's real people in this show.
Scott: It's not it's not actors.
Rym: No, most of the people in the show reenactors.
Rym: They were not actors They were the actual people.
Rym: Okay, so which actually is weird watching this like 20 30 years later.
Scott: Those people are older dead Yeah, but uh, we're way older than they were and they're like, we'll never know.
Rym: and I was like that guy did it 100% holy shit, that husband did it like holy shit, and then it cut to the update and it was like Yeah, the husband fucking did it and we sent him to jail.
Rym: and I was like, yes Yeah, the show crazily enough.
Scott: if you killed your wife, why the fuck would you go on TV to prove his innocence?
Rym: I get the impression they work.
Rym: they tricked a lot of murderers into literally being on this show and then they got caught because of the show because the crazy thing is Your case that otherwise could have been a cold.
Scott: This show you don't want attention.
Scott: if you committed a crime you want to be quiet.
Rym: This show was before the internet and they legit solved a lot of crimes because people called these tip lines.
Scott: so a lot of crimes only get solved or investigated or prosecuted by even like even like the DA like the public prosecutors will find out about cases to go and investigate from basically Journalists investigative journalists some journalists and this is basically is investigator journalism, right?
Scott: So I'm independent journalists working for a TV station trying to make a TV show is looking through some records Trying to find cases that weren't solved, right?
Scott: Oh, here was a person who was as a death certificate of murder and no one went to jail for it.
Scott: Let's go get all the info we can and then suddenly it's on TV and then the prosecutor is it brought to their attention And then oh look we solved it because they actually put effort into it because we brought attention to it.
Rym: the funniest thing though, is that Emily never really seen this show.
Rym: So never.
Rym: But the way I described it was like.
Rym: so every episode will have like a UFO a Murdered wife of some kind of some sort of embezzled like.
Rym: I listed like that the cliches of the show.
Rym: Let me turn on the episode and it was literally the cliches someone embezzling a UFO from there.
Rym: So What do you got?
Scott: So this is dude.
Scott: What's his name?
Scott: It's Dan Cordero.
Scott: Dan Cordero is a professional for top wedding photographer as as their job.
Rym: All right Oh, this is so good.
Scott: And if you know a lot of games these days, especially Nintendo games like Breath of the Wild has a little camera.
Rym: Yeah, Jimmy selfies I've taken in front of ridiculous shit in that game and you often forget to use it like cuz when you get it.
Scott: they like Teach you to use it and make you do one quest involving it And then you pretty much hardly have to use it really anymore in the game.
Scott: You can you get benefits from using it, but you don't have to write.
Scott: I barely used the camera at all in Breath of the Wild and then I only used it a couple times like alright I can use it to find items.
Scott: And yeah, I was like I used it for a couple things and that was it.
Scott: But yeah Mario Odyssey also has a camera.
Scott: I think a lot of Nintendo games just look for the camera cuz it's gonna be there, right?
Scott: And he went and says a photographer played Mario Odyssey and also used the fuck out of the camera with their professional photography skills and took all these photos of Mario's Odyssey.
Scott: and It's some really great fucking photography and composition Going on here.
Rym: This is really fun.
Scott: It's really great.
Scott: I don't know how much Photoshop was involved.
Scott: I think he's at least removing.
Scott: You know some various things possibly from scenes or cropping definitely in certain scenes and things like that but in general Still fucking great job Using the camera in Mario Odyssey.
Scott: I Caught you know, I did actually Think about doing this in some way because I know that like Just like general FPS games any game with a camera on Steam.
Scott: You can just use the screenshot button.
Scott: Yep, so there were times I think I took like a photo in Skyrim once.
Scott: that was way good.
Scott: It's a stuff like this.
Scott: I've thought about this in the past, but this person has taken it to the extreme Conclusive level that it deserves.
Rym: These are great and some of it like they're subtle.
Rym: They're just well composed.
Rym: This is really good.
Rym: It's really good because I got the good things today in the moment the GeekNights booklet book is the tale of Genji.
Rym: It's real long.
Rym: We're reading it.
Rym: It's the first novel.
Rym: You should read it, too.
Scott: I'm gonna be done with my apartment biz probably in a week and then probably be reading again.
Rym: We will be live at PAX unplugged, which is coming up.
Rym: Not that long from now.
Rym: No, we will be doing at least one panel.
Rym: We're very likely doing.
Rym: take your damn turn.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: I'm really excited about this one.
Rym: I already started making slides.
Rym: Oh, yeah Because that's my job is making slides and we will also be doing one of our learn and play learn and win Sessions, but we're not just gonna do one game.
Rym: We're gonna do the regame daddy three in the same session.
Rym: you come to some someone else's session.
Rym: They're gonna teach you one game over the course of two hours.
Rym: We're gonna teach you three games in the same two hours.
Rym: Mmm, we're gonna do a cockroach poker.
Scott: Are you gonna spill all the beans?
Rym: I'm just gonna say we're gonna do cockroach poker and two other things.
Rym: I bought the games myself.
Rym: If you follow me on Twitter, you probably saw some pictures of the games We're gonna do.
Scott: we should do ants in the pants a cootie or so Actually wizards.
Rym: one of the games we're gonna do.
Rym: okay, but I couldn't get the American fantasy wizard.
Rym: there weren't enough copies available So I got the German version.
Scott: Yeah, why would you get the American one?
Rym: Uh, cuz the German version was more expensive, but it says over and are you gonna?
Rym: every card has a name and They're all different and they're written on the cards in the German version.
Rym: I know what Scott Johnson is called now.
Rym: Okay, they're all.
Rym: they're all like the king the banner like they'll have names on them All right, and they're way lower quality than the American release.
Rym: All right, like the cards are just like shittier stock and the colors worse.
Rym: Okay, like they're just bad.
Rym: Otherwise, okay, but it's gonna be a fun time.
Rym: PAX Unplugged.
Rym: I think it's my second favorite packs.
Scott: now It's a good.
Scott: pecs.
Rym: PAX West PAX Unplugged pecs.
Rym: off pecs.
Rym: south a long gap pexy's those packs it.
Rym: So as you know, we are a while ago reviewed a game called 1846 race for the Midwest, right?
Scott: So though it's an 18xx game.
Scott: It's a real train game.
Scott: when people say train game That's the game they're talking about.
Scott: Right, they're games that you know often include things such as historic real historical representations of actual trains.
Scott: You got like operating around right stock the basic core idea of all these 18xx games, right?
Scott: I think we reviewed 1846, which if you are gonna play get into these games, that is the first one to play.
Rym: Yeah, do not start with this one.
Rym: I don't even know.
Rym: I want to recommend playing this one.
Scott: We were interviewed we reviewed it in late 2017.
Scott: Now.
Scott: I've played a lot more of these games since 2017 And basically the core of these games is this really they seem complicated and they are complicated for the average person but that's because of reasons.
Scott: but the core thing of all these games is that you invest in companies in One round then you the companies actually do business for two rounds two identical rounds And then you invest or divest in companies again, and you repeat this cycle of invest come work work invest work work and whoever has the most shares in a company at During the work set turns is the person who actually controls that company during the work turn.
Scott: It's like you know, the company isn't you.
Scott: it's separate from you.
Rym: You you have your money you and you run companies that you have a majority share, right?
Scott: So to win you want your money to be the most at the end of the game when the bank runs out of money.
Scott: But you know, so you sometimes you control a company.
Scott: Sometimes you might not control any companies.
Scott: You might buy a company that used to be someone else's.
Rym: you might sell a company now It might end up with three companies in front of you and now your turn takes for fucking ever, right?
Scott: It's like, you know the companies go in order.
Scott: So it's like one company might go then it's someone else's company and then it's your company.
Rym: Yeah, that's how it works.
Scott: Yep investing and then The companies do business and then you investigate and you're controlling basically your investment decisions.
Scott: Which companies do I want to have shares in?
Scott: Along with Trying to make certain companies do well and make some do worse the ones that you have more shares in you want to do better So they spit out more money and the ones you don't have shares in you want them to do worse.
Scott: So that's other people will not make as much money.
Scott: So when the game ends you win.
Scott: That's that's all there really is to it.
Scott: Yes,
Rym: and if you want About like these details like what these games are like on like this higher level I will link to go listen to our old review of 1846 because that's where we talk about a lot of this in detail
Scott: right and that we're
Rym: gonna review This train game in comparison to other train games and in the context of I was about to say normal No, it's just a regular board game.
Scott: If you don't understand the other train games You're not gonna understand this review really?
Scott: Well, cuz I mean I was hard to talk about it and except using words that only people who understand these games will understand.
Scott: and
Rym: the other thing I would say is that This game 2038 tycoons of the asteroid belt If you have never played one of these friend games before and you like the kinds of board games you see the game like packs I Doubt you will enjoy playing this game
Scott: right?
Rym: This game is not easy to play, right?
Scott: There is no reason for me to try to explain this game and simpler You know in terms to someone who doesn't know anything about these games because this shouldn't be your first one.
Scott: and if it you right.
Scott: Only reason to listen to this review is if you already know about train games 18xx games and you want to know about this one, but the reason of that because I like what 1899 1889 89 is the Japanese my favorite one so far.
Rym: 1846 is by like second or third I like in 46. but but the thing the thing I'll say about these games that's relevant here Is that they all have this fundamental problem of I don't want to say naive game design.
Rym: It's not that problem, but they are designed For goals other than elegance and consistency of their mechanic.
Rym: They're eggs.
Rym: They're designed for the historical experience.
Rym: people that people play them tend to like Very fiddly rules that have like.
Rym: there will be more exceptions to a rule than the rule.
Rym: like you really you cannot internalize all the rules to one of these games unless you play them a Lot and you play them a lot.
Rym: They actually break down Pretty poorly.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So the problem with these games for someone who likes to play normal board games Is that you can't just learn the mechanics and then start to play?
Rym: You need to be constantly figuring out all the exceptions and fucking with the rules and unless you have a facilitator Basically, these games only need a game master or an expert to help you play them or a computer.
Rym: Yeah, we'll get to that.
Rym: Then they're very difficult to play.
Rym: but that said I love the shit out of 1846, right?
Scott: Like I said that core concept of investing in companies Controlling some of them right and trying to make the most money is a great game and I still think you could even replace.
Scott: You can and the best part is that simple framework can be expanded contracted and rearranged to make lots and lots of different games.
Scott: You could make the investment part simpler or more complex or even crazy complex.
Scott: You can make the operating part a completely different game.
Scott: There's a game called a Should big city shoulders or something like that.
Scott: I forget the exact name of the game.
Scott: If you go to board game geek and type in shoulders There aren't that many fucking games with the name word shoulders in the title.
Scott: Yeah, you're gonna find it.
Scott: I think it might be city of the big shoulders.
Scott: Anyway, it's an 18xx game with an investment round and operating rounds the big shoulders.
Scott: I got it, right But basically instead of trains it's like a euro game.
Scott: in the operating part It's like you invest and then you play a euro game and then you invest.
Scott: it's the same Right, well then there's games like Chicago Express.
Rym: take the core concepts of a train game and just like Distill distill distill right anyway, our Paris connection.
Scott: So 2038. what it does is it gets rid of the historical part by putting you way into a theoretical space future.
Scott: We know we're probably not gonna have space trains in 2038 at the rate things are going.
Rym: but if we did which already presents a problem from a game design perspective because the fiddly like fucky mechanics of the other historical train games at least are trying to model very real-world history.
Rym: meaning if you want if you know something about the 1840s in the Midwest that historical knowledge will actually help you a little bit better.
Rym: I'm not a lot but like a little bit like you can intuitively play the game By doing the things that make sense as an intelligent human being looking at a complex situation Mm-hmm,
Scott: and in fact if you do things that happened in history Right or you
Rym: tend to play out the way they played out in history,
Scott: right?
Scott: They tend to play out.
Scott: So it's like oh, yeah that that rail line was built there from the Civil War Caused it to be irrelevant right?
Scott: and then they had to dynamite it.
Scott: and that happened around this year and the game starts in this Year, so if I do that at this timing it'll print it kind of work.
Rym: So the games are almost more experiences like if I play an 18xx game and I lose terribly like go bankrupt or something.
Rym: It's still really fun because it's almost like I'm playing this weird Simulations like playing a Civ game just to see how the world ends up.
Scott: I've never won And I've never been upset playing an 18xx game.
Rym: Yep, but with 2038 It has that same level of fiddly shit from a fictional inconsistent world, right?
Rym: And the thing is the fiddly shit is So fiddly that it becomes Onerous the operating round of this game where you run the trains like my train goes here here and here to make this much money.
Rym: It's really fun and makes sense and I liked it.
Rym: But as soon as it scales up even a little bit it is.
Rym: it is a disastrous mechanic.
Rym: Like it is it is own playable.
Scott: So normally the way it works in most most of the 18xx games is when you actually run.
Scott: There's a point at which after everyone's done building tracks and shit We figure out how much each money each train spits out.
Scott: and what you do is you look at the board He's alright.
Scott: my train has to start at one of my spots right and it gets blocked by other people's spots and It can go in pretty much any track right?
Scott: My trains just can't.
Scott: my trains can't overlap each other, but I have to care about what anyone else's trains do.
Scott: I just can't go through any spots.
Scott: They're blocking with their station.
Scott: Yep, right So it's pretty easy to look at a board.
Scott: It might not be easy to a hundred percent perfectly get the best pot most money out of the trains.
Scott: Well, you're close enough, but you can get very close and once you get very close, it's like well What changed since last turn?
Scott: Well, one piece of track was upgraded.
Scott: Well, I guess my route is upgraded by $10.
Scott: then, right?
Scott: I'll just run the same route again with that one upgrade and you don't have tends to balance to where it takes.
Rym: it might take You a little while to figure out but that is downtime for the other players to figure out some shit that they're gonna be doing.
Scott: It's not too bad It's.
Scott: it could be improved.
Scott: a computer should just tell you the optimal routes and spit out the money with no thunking whatsoever.
Scott: But it's not so bad that you're it's a problem that you're like frustrated with.
Scott: Yeah, 2038 the way it works is each train each company operates in order ain't no tracks in space Right going around with their spaceship mining asteroids and collecting or and but the problem Is right when it potentially refueling.
Scott: right when a ship's picks up or Right, it picks up a little piece of cardboard off the board of flips it over and now no Spaceship for the rest of the turn can get that or it's that turn
Rym: might involve like five different companies each running Multiple spaceships, right?
Scott: So use the first person sends their spaceships out and now you see which oars have been flipped over And then the next person goes and sees which oars have been flipped over and basically each person has to Wait for each spaceship every turn Completely rethink and refigure out the exact optimal way to get the most best oars Right with each spaceship.
Scott: now And then you can't even begin to think about your spaceship until everyone before you has picked up resources with their Spaceships.
Rym: this it made the game interminable.
Scott: now in one hand and the early turns is not a big deal because it's like, okay Well, this one picks up the only two oars it can reach and no one else can reach them.
Scott: fine And there are also ways to stake claims on Certain resources and no one can take them.
Scott: and hopefully you would claim the best ones and that way you can quickly just be like Well, this ship takes all the claim spots.
Scott: You know thinking necessary because no one else can take those they're claimed.
Scott: but you still get when you get better ships and more of them and Unclaimed spots or you ran out of claims.
Scott: You don't have enough claims.
Scott: those later turns in the game starting about halfway through Become a big mess plus it gets hard of that.
Rym: might have been that the way we were playing it because we weren't Fully versed in like there's no history to look at.
Rym: Yeah, so we ended up making companies in a way that was a little bit weird.
Rym: Yeah the way the board broke down Totally legal though Yeah but totally legal.
Rym: but It basically means that there is a trap where if the game evolves a certain way the game will take four times longer than it normally Would.
Rym: but even if the game performed optimally optimally.
Rym: this operating around situation would still be a serious problem right and even worse.
Rym: unlike say eclipse which has a very Elegant physical mechanism for representing complex resources this game gives you fuck all for physical bits.
Rym: You could solve this problem not a computer But you can solve like a third of this problem just by having better physical Components and ways to track this stuff better.
Rym: It doesn't give you anything to do this.
Scott: another thing to have.
Scott: Another thing that contributes is also the lack of stability in the game and a lot of other train games.
Scott: There'll be a series of rounds where things pretty much stayed mostly the same.
Scott: like the turn order of the company stays the same mostly, you know the Ownership of the company stays the same.
Scott: mostly.
Scott: everyone just sort of operates and upgrades for a few turns just moving things along.
Scott: here It's like all right.
Scott: well this turn suddenly this company's value went way up, and it's going earlier, so that changes everything.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: Oh and now these all these companies merge into the asteroid league.
Scott: well that fucking changes everything.
Rym: Right we'll get to that.
Rym: We'll get to that.
Rym: I want to talk about that cuz that part's really cool.
Scott: I really like that part.
Scott: That part is really cool.
Rym: Yeah, there's basically you know in these train games.
Scott: Well, I'm just saying it contributes to the instability and that you have to rethink the Gathering a resource part.
Scott: every single time you're starting from scratch again Optimizing which or for each spaceship, and it's just this busy work.
Scott: It's not even like decision-making.
Scott: I guess there's a little bit.
Scott: you could theoretically take a suboptimal route with a ship to pick up resources to deny another ship Resources, but not in a super significant way once the board is full of asteroids everywhere.
Rym: to complicate this There are ways to refuel ships so then that they can move even further if they move a certain way Making it actually a pretty difficult problem to solve and optimize.
Rym: for like I even to give an unlimited time on a complex board It would take me a while to fully optimize.
Scott: Yeah, I think it would actually be hard to write a computer program.
Scott: Yeah, we optimize The search graph would be enormous, and you'll have multiple kinds of ships.
Rym: so when you're buying ships So I want the one that moves further and picks up less or the ones that are like there's way too many Variables for the operating round which should be the least interesting part of a train.
Scott: It's not the part where you're making decisions, and I think that's a fundamental problem with all the train games.
Scott: Is that the Part of the investing part of the game?
Scott: the stock round is what actually most Determines the victory condition which player wins which player loses which shares?
Scott: you have Right.
Scott: the second part of the game the operating rounds are our only sort of Secondary to who wins and loses.
Scott: right they're important because they control how much money each company is spitting out.
Scott: But if everyone's good Anyway, any good gamer can operate a company not optimally, but optimally enough that it's you know right and The actual decisions made during the operating round aren't as crucial to the actual victory condition of the game But they take a disproportionate amount of the time and effort and the stock rounds are usually Oversimplified and don't take long at all.
Scott: so you're just buying and selling shares going in a circle.
Scott: It's real simple
Rym: the really cool part about this game Which is why I really wanted to like it and this is why I want I want to make a computer version of this game and then fix a bunch of stuff, but 2048 2058
Scott: and some
Rym: of the other train games the
Scott: 2057 or 58 different time.
Scott: you understand different different spaceships.
Rym: the Independent companies tend to be pretty simple and disappear pretty quick in this game.
Rym: They're all way different Yeah, and you're running like real companies of privates, and there's this whole complicated mechanic where based on things I don't want to explain in too much depth because you can learn this game if you want to play it.
Rym: They can either join the asteroid league or not join the asteroid league at some point in the future.
Rym: yep And the asteroid league then becomes this company, and there's a whole like system around this that is Really cool, and I really wanted to interact with that by playing the game more times Until I ran into the operating round deadlock.
Rym: that made me never want to play this game again.
Scott: Yeah I actually had the asteroid league.
Scott: I was the asteroid league guy I know which made it pretty cool because like I started the game with one space company Understood that I could withhold or pay out.
Rym: We're like I had the option.
Rym: with these into these privates.
Rym: I would have done something way different right and you can also take a private and like turn it into a company early.
Rym: like.
Rym: There's.
Rym: there's way more ways to form companies and do company stuff in the.
Scott: yeah You could start.
Scott: you can make a growth company which is a company that's worth like nothing at the start of the game and Basically instead of joining asteroid league you'd start this little like I little startup who like ships like one good Basically and sucks ass.
Rym: it starts with no share value, but I bought those shares for nothing right?
Scott: But those shares were worth nothing because the company was like a guy with a like.
Scott: a true space truck is a galaxy trucker.
Rym: But I didn't.
Scott: and then it Theoretically if you start one early enough and work on it and work on it That can work out to end up being like a big-ass awesome company, and that's what I didn't understand.
Rym: I kept paying out because I had our.
Rym: I had ice finder Which was a really like.
Rym: it was making a shit ton of money for a private because the way I'd set it up.
Rym: So I was making all this money, and I was paying out dividends to myself, and it was awesome.
Rym: I didn't realize I could withhold.
Rym: even in these privates I Will.
Rym: if I'd known that I would have withheld and I would have gotten a couple of fewer shares of like the other company.
Scott: We're just having a discussion about how it should be illegal to withhold and companies should have to pay out dividends and the profits You do.
Rym: oh, yeah, but train games are about your evil capitalist Corrupt system.
Scott: understand?
Rym: yeah, no I would do the completely unethical thing.
Rym: yeah I would have withheld I would have turned ice finder into an indoor growth company, and I would have made Bank.
Rym: I played this game way different.
Scott: I had the asteroid league and it was way fun.
Scott: when the asteroid League formed that was way fun.
Scott: But the problem was is now I had to control this giant ass asteroid League and that kind of sucked.
Rym: So Chris in the chat says the asteroid League miners thing comes from a different 18xx game.
Rym: That's more normal, okay?
Rym: Okay, we're gonna.
Rym: I want to play that one whichever one.
Rym: that is our friend Chris.
Rym: You'll see him in the forum, and he if you see a guy hanging out with us like playing train games at Pax's It's that guy.
Rym: alright Chris brings us the train game.
Rym: That's right.
Scott: I don't own any of these fucking things.
Rym: I I would well I would consider owning 1846.
Scott: I wouldn't make one before I bought one.
Rym: I would own it to Start ideating on how I would make one because this game taught me something.
Scott: just reader rolls PDF if I need to.
Rym: yeah I would play 1846 1889 a lot of the other train games again.
Rym: I would never play 2038 again.
Rym: no not not in its default tabletop form but a video game That was designed to feel a lot like this tabletop game.
Rym: But take advantage of the fact that it's a computer and have a little more complexity like these games would be more fun If you could have a little bit more complex stock market like if I could sell Options from a train company to other players.
Rym: or if a player sell futures.
Rym: that would be fucking impossible to do elegantly out in the tabletop And if you made it too complicated it would just turn into sieve.
Scott: or I mean there is a New York one I think that has a Selling short and stock market is a little bit more complicated.
Scott: But yeah like I said before The victory condition of all these games is mostly in the stock round.
Scott: the operating round is like this separate minigame of optimization.
Scott: I would really like to play one where the stock round was more advanced and had more decisions.
Scott: It was more complex and the operating round was simplified and made more elegant and streamlined and abstract.
Scott: And this while the theme and some of the detailed rules and cool Thematic things like the asteroid league and the mining.
Scott: at least the the the theme of the mining make it awesome.
Scott: The reality is this the exact opposite of what I want in a train game.
Scott: it is the a much simpler stock market released a normal level of complexity stock market for these games and a Ridiculously tedious operating rounds.
Scott: that are Have fun aspects, but just too many busy work aspects.
Scott: They take too goddamn long.
Scott: Here's the line to make it worth my while.
Scott: and so it's like 46 in 1889.
Rym: It's like I'll still play those games cuz it's worth my while enough.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: The TDM is not in.
Rym: 2038 is Impossibly tedious in the operating round.
Scott: Yep Alright, so if you want to play it get into these games.
Scott: you can go listen to our old episode of 1846 or go play 1846 or Yeah, you can play that one too sure but do not play this one.
Rym: Do you think that is actually better in a lot of ways?
Scott: some ways do not play this one?
Scott: 2038 as your first one.
Scott: if you're super experienced with these games and you don't mind some tedium and you just want to see what The deal is there's a lot to.
Scott: there's some good stuff to see here in this one.
Scott: So I'd recommend like you play it learn it Maybe not play a whole game of it because it would take too long or maybe you just have a ton of time and think is Even though like our game went on so long.
Rym: We got kicked out of packs and couldn't finish it, right?
Scott: I would not recommend this one though for serious buying playing and replaying.
Rym: Yep, but I realized something fundamental the primary problem with these games Is that because they are tabletop and because they have very fiddly rules everywhere else They end up needing to rely heavily on Start player order and the mechanics to determine that are just terrible.
Rym: Mm-hmm And it matters too much to be a terrible mechanic.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: That is the thing I think you could solve with all of these tabletop games.
Rym: You can make them more elegant without without ruining what makes them unique and different from the euros.
Rym: We tend to like more.
Scott: Yes I'm in favor of a Simultaneous market and not an ordered market because I learned after plant.
Scott: it took me like a year to Scott mule mule mule Right.
Scott: It took me a year or two to learn how important the priority deal is.
Scott: That means you go first in the stock round.
Scott: how that gives you the can basically had you know You're having it at the right time is how you win the game and I've played several games of this and I basically got burned By it over and over that.
Scott: I learned it but got burned by it Even though I saw it and was trying to grab this one.
Rym: I was the start play.
Rym: I basically had the start for the most of the game because it was a three-player game and neither you were willing to like Rust stuff and I did.
Rym: I just like I.
Scott: well now there was a game of 1889.
Scott: I played I think a magfest where I finally understood it and was trying to grab a hold of it.
Scott: And right it's like.
Scott: I understand it now, but I can't Can't get it.
Rym: Yeah, you know what that's like.
Rym: It's like ooh, I understand this raging bull now.
Rym: I will attempt to ride it Right.
Scott: It's like I understand what I have to do in a video game Even though I know when to I have to push the button at that time But I keep pushing it and it's not the right time and I keep dying.
Scott: Anyway, yeah when we played this it was the first time where I finally managed to grab a hold of that priority deal mechanic At the right time move my trains and one company to the other force the shitty company on to Rym.
Scott: Yeah, right get everything in order.
Scott: I didn't do it perfectly.
Scott: I could have done it even better, but that's just because I didn't understand exactly when the trains would rust.
Scott: spaceships would rust.
Rym: But the problem is like Is also so important and also relies on the turn order, right?
Scott: But I could have screwed Rym more.
Scott: but the point is that was the first.
Scott: it, you know It would regardless of which one he played.
Scott: this still would have been the one where I figured it out Finally, because it's the same mechanic and all of them basically.
Scott: So coincidence there.
Rym: So yeah space trains is the only one I've played so far that I would never play again Which is a shame because stylistically a Stylistically a plus it feels very do.
Scott: all the characters and are and you know, everything about space wise is really great.
Scott: So that's a shame.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and make comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night in the patreon.
Rym: patreons for this episode of GeekNights are Craig Oliver Ellen Joyce Heidi McNichol just like a dude guy.
Rym: chart option William Eisneros Linky G Hydrated Ganon Boogaloo Jennifer Hitchcock Chris midkiff my state calm Jay Pence Shawn Yeager Nicholas Brando Let's see if Rym says Tronic properly for two one creations.
Rym: You know how I became the prince of a town called Bel Air Sure Mutharl Rory Superboy Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan parent rope and Lander Finn dread Lily Tenebrae Sean Klein Chris Reimer Thomas Hahn.
Rym: and now I leave you with something very important from my childhood.
Scott: This program is about unsolved mysteries.
Scott: whenever possible the actual family members and police officials have Participated in recreating the events.
Scott: What you were about to see is not a news broadcast tonight on unsolved mysteries.
Rym: the residents of a Florida nudist camp were stunned to discover that one of their most popular members was allegedly a fraud a cheat and a child molester.
Rym: In Ypsilanti, Michigan a small-town realtor was callously gunned down in his office by two unknown killers?
Rym: Was this regular family man the victim of a professional hit?
Rym: In a tiny church in Ambridge, Pennsylvania The congregation are certain they have witnessed a miracle.
Rym: the eyes of Jesus and the carved wooden statue over their altar were once open.
Rym: Now they say the eyes are closed.
Rym: Join me for these fascinating stories, perhaps someone somewhere has that one vital clue that can help solve a mystery.
Scott: Perhaps that someone is watching perhaps.
Scott: It's you.