Rym: It's Monday, October 28th, 2019.
Rym: I'm Rym, and this is GeekNights Tonight.
Rym: Microphones, like the things we're talking into right now.
Rym: Podcasts.
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: All right, so my new apartment.
Scott: Oh, yeah, new apartment.
Scott: Directly across the street from high school.
Scott: That's exciting.
Rym: You can see high school sports.
Scott: I can see a lot of free high school sports.
Scott: High school marching bands.
Scott: It's not really a marching band.
Rym: I mean, marching bands are really more of a Midwest thing.
Scott: There is a tiny amount of band.
Scott: I heard some toot-toot during a football game.
Scott: But yeah, there was a big crowd.
Scott: They closed the road over the weekend.
Rym: Oh, right.
Scott: And I was, and there's mobs of people out there occasionally.
Scott: And it took a while to figure out what the hell was going on.
Scott: So what the hell was going on is this thing that no one outside of New York City will know about.
Rym: I barely knew about it because I don't have kids.
Scott: I know about it.
Scott: It's called the SH.
Scott: SAT.
Scott: Basically now relation to the real SAT, and other than that it is a standardized test.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And what the deal is is New York City, right, you know elementary school, middle school, you sort of go to the ones near you based on where you live.
Scott: Yeah, at least if you go into a public one.
Rym: People who don't live in New York, like the way it works is if you live in a town, the town has a school, there's a school district.
Rym: In a big town, the town and the school district are the same.
Rym: In a really big town, there'll be like multiple school districts within the town.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It's all based on like population.
Scott: But anyway, New York City works differently because it's obviously a special-edge case, right?
Scott: But the point is for high school, you got to take this fucking test.
Scott: And the test is the literally the only criteria used, that way they can say it's a meritocracy, in determining who gets to go to these special New York high schools, right, like Stuyvesant and whatever, like these special high schools that are like better and fancier, at least, you know, and according to some people, they're more prestigious and whatever.
Scott: And yet somehow the, you know, the ethnic diversity of these schools ends up not being so even anyway.
Rym: Yup, somehow.
Scott: There's a lot of issues they're not going to go into.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But what was shocking to me is A, B, why is there this mob of people in the street and a street closing for standardized tests?
Rym: That's what I don't get, because like I took a lot of those kinds of standardized tests and like there was there was hullabaloo, but it was always like in a building somewhere.
Rym: Why aren't these parents like sitting in the gym or something?
Scott: They only administer this test apparently at like a handful of locations around the city.
Rym: Oh, that's fair.
Scott: So people came from all the fuck over.
Rym: That sounds totally fair.
Scott: Why not administer the thing at like every high school?
Scott: Well, like, look.
Scott: Every high school.
Rym: Here's another SAT, the PSAT, every middle school and high school just administers it.
Scott: Our middle, our high school had every.
Scott: it's like everyone.
Scott: isn't every high school in the city administering the test.
Scott: Why do people have to travel?
Scott: Maybe that's maybe that is, you know, contributing to this problem.
Scott: is that, hey, poor people can't afford to take a weekend to travel to some high school far away.
Scott: with the test being administered.
Scott: Maybe if you offered it to every single high school.
Rym: Well, let's back up every single school period.
Rym: The real problem is that for you non-American listeners, this might explain a lot about us as a country.
Rym: For various, mostly racist reasons, schools are funded from the local tax base and there are federal things involved.
Rym: But basically, if you live in a richer town, your schools just have more money.
Rym: And if you live in a poorer town, your schools just have less money because they base it almost exclusively on property taxes.
Rym: And that is a fucking problem.
Rym: But in New York, it's extra special because everyone lives so close together and most people rent that they have to like figure out where to send kids.
Rym: Like you can't send every kid to the school that's closest to them.
Scott: You'll also have like buildings that have several schools in them.
Scott: You'll have people scamming where they like.
Scott: they find a nape because you're not too far away from a different school.
Rym: When I was a kid in the suburbs, people did that.
Rym: Like there was a dividing line.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But you think it's bad in the suburb.
Scott: It's way bad in New York City.
Rym: There was a street in Southeast Michigan near Anchor Bay where literally if you lived on one side of the street, you went to a really good school.
Rym: If you lived on the other side of that street, like in this subdivision, you went to a really shitty school.
Rym: And there was just no way around that.
Scott: Literally, the house I grew up in was in Trumbull, Connecticut.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Which was a somewhat wealthy, you know, affluent, suburb town with, you know, quality schools, according to people, I guess.
Scott: Literally, the other side of the street was Bridgeport, Connecticut.
Scott: The kids who lived on the other side of the street had to go to Bridgeport High School, which is like the worst high school in like, you know, poor urban Bridgeport.
Rym: Now, sometimes they were like where I grew up when I went to high school, we were in Sterling Heights, which basically had a school district for its area.
Rym: And it had four high schools that are all equally good.
Rym: As long as you're in that school district, all the schools were great.
Scott: Anyway, point is, they only administered it in a handful of places.
Scott: What the fuck is up with that?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And of course, as you were just saying, why?
Scott: the fundamental problem is, why are some high schools shouldn't even be better than others?
Scott: Why can't all high schools in New York City be equally good?
Rym: Well, what I couldn't have to care which one you go to, what I could make an argument for is there should be a series of specialized high schools.
Rym: They shouldn't be better, but they should be focused on a particular need, like a certain kind of special education or a certain kind of advanced program.
Rym: But then there should be a fair way to make sure the kids who need that special education get to go to that specialized school.
Rym: Well, I think you can't put that level of specialization in every high school.
Scott: No, but I think, you know, what you should do if you are going to say right that, you know, some people are special and need a special thing.
Scott: It's like, well, OK, the way they do it now, it's like, well, here's this high school.
Scott: It accepts this many people every year.
Scott: And it's like, well, what if the number of special people?
Rym: The rule should be everyone who meets the criteria for special education, literally everyone who meets it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If you it's like, no, no, no, none of this bullshit where you need a test and you have enough seats is literally all these kids got straight A's.
Scott: They're all geniuses.
Scott: Then they all go to equally awesome special high school.
Scott: No limit on number of seats.
Scott: Bullshit.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Now, take this on the national level.
Rym: Like I could do to make sense where, like, if your kid is like a super genius or has a very specific type of learning disability that needs specialized help and you live in like dirtbag Pennsylvania where there's only 40 kids in the high school, then the government should make sure that your kid gets to go to a kind of school wherever it is in the country.
Scott: Well, I mean, there's too many issues going on.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like the kid who is a genius, but is poor.
Rym: So, you know, when I recognize some specific like I went through this as a kid, my parents like threatened to sue the school because there's a Michigan law that basically said if a kid needs special education.
Rym: And the district can't provide it.
Rym: The district has to provide it via alternative means.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But how many kids, you know, they're poor.
Scott: And maybe if that kid had been rich, they'd be genius, too.
Scott: But they weren't.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: It's like, come on.
Scott: You know, now that kid can't pass this test.
Scott: Not because they couldn't.
Scott: They could have if they had been born wealthy.
Rym: There were probably a lot of kids in my middle school that qualified to be like this gifted kid thing, but the school district basically didn't want to deal with that.
Rym: So instead, they just sent a bus to pick me and only me up every day to take me to the high school to take high school classes and then back to the middle school to take my required middle school classes.
Scott: Not everyone has parents who will fight and spend money.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: They didn't spend any money.
Rym: We didn't actually sue.
Scott: Not everyone has parents who will send them the special, you know, training classes for this this one test you have to take and wait outside the school in the rain to get you when you finish the test to bring you back home to a far away where you live.
Rym: Also, one of your kids is just like sick that day and does shit on the test because they're sick.
Scott: Well, it seemed it seemed like the test was going both days and I don't know anything about how the test is actually structured, but it felt like there was based on the flow of people.
Scott: It seemed like there were several sessions per day.
Scott: So I don't know if you had to sign up or you just show up for one of the sessions on either day.
Scott: So you got two days.
Scott: You got probably plenty of advance notice.
Scott: You know, you got a handful of locations.
Rym: Apparently, they do have a little tiny bit of accountability.
Rym: You parents can get a copy of the kids answer sheet and the questions and like they can like review it and make sure, like the questions weren't wrong or something.
Rym: There's there's some good things here, but there's a lot of bad.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, schools are weird.
Scott: The street outside my house was like a shit show all weekend.
Scott: And then it was crazy rain on like a mad rain on Sunday, which was kind of, you know, it was like a big umbrella sea of all these parents.
Scott: And other people just loitering in the closed street, waiting for kids to finish a test.
Scott: And at one point, people like kids came out and there was like clapping.
Scott: But wow, that culture.
Scott: That's bad.
Scott: But here's what I don't understand.
Rym: This is a high school.
Rym: This is a test to get into high schools.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Kids who are at the end of middle school should already just like why does the kid just take the subway to this thing, take the test and go home?
Rym: Like why are the parents there?
Scott: Where does the kid live?
Scott: I might not live in a subway place and take the bus.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You might be bad parents who don't let your kids roam around and go all the way.
Rym: I mean, at least when I had to take I took entrance exams to go to some private schools and I didn't go to any of them, partly because we couldn't afford, even though I passed the test, couldn't afford to go to those schools.
Rym: But I couldn't drive.
Rym: I was like 14.
Rym: Some parents had to drive me to these.
Scott: Anyway, so, you know, this, you know, I, you know, purposefully don't have children's going to deal with this bullshit.
Scott: Just comment on it from afar.
Scott: I feel bad for the people who did choose to have children who have to deal with the shit and didn't realize that.
Rym: Well, I remember when my, when we moved, like as a kid, like we'd move a few times, like we just moved houses.
Rym: Every time we move, my parents spend a shitload of time, like researching the school districts, like, oh, this house looks good.
Rym: And then they'd spend like a week trying to figure out if the schools that that house is associated with are good or not.
Rym: And there were a lot of really good houses we couldn't buy because they were in really bad schools.
Rym: And that seems like a weird thing to have to worry about, especially in, you know, arguably the richest, best country in the world.
Rym: Maybe.
Scott: Yeah, outside my house.
Scott: It was bad times.
Scott: Yeah, I guess that'll happen every year.
Rym: So there's a whole bunch of news going on.
Rym: And the first thing I want to talk about is this feature that Netflix is reportedly testing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So if you have a podcast reader, a feature I know a lot of people haven't used is make it sound like GeekNights.
Scott: Also, people do this with audiobooks.
Scott: also is the speed up feature.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I can understand that feature, especially for like an informational, like daily news podcast or something.
Rym: If you care about the content, not the execution.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You speed up that podcast.
Scott: So that way you it takes less time to ingest more information, because really, in terms of information density per time spent, nothing beats text.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Everyone keeps producing audio and video content.
Scott: If you're just interested in the information only.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like I'm watching YouTube video like how to do X. I want it to go as fast as possible.
Scott: I'd rather have an article.
Scott: I'm watching the video because maybe the imagery will help me because it's like a crafting or something.
Scott: You get the idea.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, I guess I want text.
Rym: I keep finding videos unless there's a technique that I don't know what I want to watch.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Perfect.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But speeding up can help there when you want content.
Scott: But, you know, for audiobooks.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, I guess it kind of makes sense to speed it up because there's two kinds of two aspects.
Scott: The next of the audiobook.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the one aspect, it's like, well, I'm using this audiobook because I can't, won't or otherwise have a reason not to read.
Scott: And, you know, I'm really just trying to get the words from the book.
Scott: So the image I'm painting in my head, I just need the words to deliver the words to me, which I would have gotten if I read the book.
Scott: But some of the image in my head, just as I would have if I was reading the book.
Rym: But some audiobooks are almost like a treatment where like it has like good acting.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Like it's a story.
Scott: If you want to speed up an audiobook where there are like voices and acting and stuff and you speed that up, you are destroying that.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Which is, you know, you're basically doing the equivalent of instead of watching a TV show, literally just reading the script to that TV show.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: That's what you're doing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Perfect.
Scott: So Netflix is adding a feature to speed up Netflix shows.
Rym: So I can see one use for that.
Rym: Well, I can see two uses for it.
Rym: Use number one, which I think is actually pretty good.
Rym: If you're watching a documentary or a nonfiction thing, those things are so information sparse that I think the same rules apply.
Scott: If you're watching like something that is any sort of show that is purely content.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So like a soap opera, soap opera.
Scott: It's not about what you see on the screen.
Scott: It's not about like, you know, it's just about knowing what happens next.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Well, so and so, so and so where the acting is good, but usually not.
Scott: Usually, I mean, it could be good, but it's that's not what it's about, even if it is good.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's just about knowing what happens next.
Scott: You guys say one piece, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You can speed through one piece.
Scott: That makes sense.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's got lots and lots of filler.
Rym: People like to watch that filler because there'll be dramatic moments within it and the animation is really good.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But there is lots of filler.
Scott: You could turn the speed on during the filler.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's unlike a fast forward where you wouldn't get any of the content.
Scott: It's like this part.
Scott: I just need to know what happens.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because it's just filler.
Scott: Here's the actual plot again.
Scott: I'll watch it at normal speed.
Rym: So this is the only other case I can see for using this, but it's specific to people like us who have to review stuff, possibly on a deadline.
Rym: Say I have to review an anime and I haven't had time to watch one and like we were going to review the show on Wednesday.
Rym: I would still watch like the first two or three episodes at normal speed because it's an audio visual media where like timing and things matter.
Rym: I got to make sure I experience it as it was intended to be experienced.
Rym: But then I might watch three or four more episodes sped up just to get enough content to make sure like it's going in the direction I expect it to be.
Scott: Or just like, you know, let's say I need to get.
Scott: I need to know something about a show, but I don't actually intend to watch it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Maybe, you know, it could be like a lot of times.
Scott: it's like you could find yourself like fast forward.
Scott: I guess we can just scrub around.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I don't really need that.
Scott: But, you know, there might be a thing where it's like I need.
Scott: I need to know about a thing, but I don't actually want to watch it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I'm not intending to actually consume this content.
Scott: I just need to extract information out of it, even if it's a work of art.
Scott: Like maybe I don't know.
Scott: I need to.
Scott: I got to remember they're Bojack Horseman, something I can probably don't care about how well-made Bojack Horseman is.
Rym: But if we had to watch it to do something on the show and you like had to know something about it, that'd be a very good way.
Scott: The problem is, is a lot of those things like IMDB just exist.
Scott: But imagine if it's the olden days and I want to know like the names of the characters in Jaws or something, I could just put it on speed mode until I learned the characters names.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: But I feel like this is not aimed at any of the use cases we just brought.
Scott: It is clearly not.
Rym: I feel like I'm going to use a pejorative term here, but I feel like it's appropriate.
Rym: I feel like basic people are going to watch the same crap they're watching now and just watch way more of it and binge even more and it's going to feed into those addictive watch the next episode cycles.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much like I feel like this is a feature that could have good uses that is going to be abused and is going to be used to the detriment of the medium.
Rym: In fact, I imagine shows for a certain demographic might even start assuming people are going to watch it at one point five X and make it that way accordingly.
Rym: Maybe I could see people doing that.
Scott: Yeah, there's a whole, you know, talk to be had.
Scott: We're not going to have about like, you know, the author's intent of the author.
Scott: Do you have a right to, you know, it's your life anyway you want.
Scott: But the way I think of it is like this.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Some chef makes a delicious meal.
Scott: You know, forget about telling the chef no onions or something like that.
Scott: That's not what I'm talking about.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, the chef makes a delicious meal and brings it out to you.
Scott: For you to eat.
Scott: And you lick it, you just look at all over like, like, like, like, like, like, because you're in you're consuming it the way you want to consume it and you don't bite it.
Rym: Now, I think the right response there would be unless you are a reviewer, like doing some sort of like.
Rym: there's some sort of other angle.
Rym: The chef's response would be whatever you paid me for this.
Scott: Right, exactly.
Scott: But at the same time of your preferred way of eat of, you know, buying if you prefer to buy food at a fancy restaurant.
Scott: lick it like crazy and not bite it, I judge you, and I rightly judge you, as a person who is, you know, got problems.
Rym: You know what this actually is a very parallel discussion to?
Rym: The discussion about how EXP share in Pokemon will now be mandatory.
Rym: It's the exact same conversation.
Scott: Well, but EXP share being mandatory is good, and speeding up Netflix is bad, mostly.
Rym: Well, but on one hand, if I'm going to be a true Tim Berners-Lee internet, I say the playback means, like, the thing that's playing back content or letting you interact with content can do whatever it wants with that content.
Scott: Of course, technologically.
Rym: So the Netflix, like, if I'm streaming Netflix...
Scott: I'm just judging someone who chooses to use it in this way.
Rym: Oh, yes, if you just start watching, like, entire 26 episode shows of, like, good anime...
Scott: The same way that I agree, yes, you have freedom of speech to say whatever you want.
Scott: If you say something stupid, I judge you.
Rym: I'm gonna laugh at you.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: You have freedom if to take, to consume, to lick your steak instead of biting it.
Rym: I judge you!
Rym: You are free to watch Carole & Tuesday, a show that is literally about people making music and then performing that music in the show at 1.5x.
Rym: You are welcome to do that, and I will laugh at you until the end of time.
Scott: I will not respect you as a person of high culture.
Rym: But if you're gonna watch a History Channel documentary on Netflix, watch that at, like, 10x.
Scott: Right?
Scott: Or just don't watch it?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I feel like if something is not worth...
Rym: I feel like you learn more.
Scott: If something isn't worth watching at 1x... The way I'm gonna live my life...
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: If it's not worth watching at 1x, I'm just not gonna watch it.
Rym: So...
Scott: Notice I don't watch a lot.
Rym: Because, well, but all the special cases there, the caveats, are, like, if I'm editing a video of me and Scott...
Scott: I have a reason.
Rym: I'm gonna watch that at, like, 2 or 3x while I'm editing because I don't need to know what I said... Yeah.
Rym: ...two days ago on a stage.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: I probably remember that.
Scott: Though sometimes I don't.
Scott: But, yeah, this is a thing.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So, a lot of you, I don't want to get into all the issues around this, or Scott's money laundering scheme.
Scott: Ah, my money laundering scheme.
Rym: No.
Rym: But many people are very misguided about Adobe.
Rym: Like, they're mad that Adobe switched from a "buy our software and have to buy upgrades every few years" to "pay for a subscription and always have the most up-to-date
Rym: software.".
Rym: I still say the substitution model is fine and perfect, and if that rankles you, it's because Adobe is professional software aimed at professionals.
Scott: That's because they're people who are mad about that.
Scott: They care a lot about principle, even when the reality that, you know, it's like, I actually agree.
Scott: In principle, yes, the principle of paying once and just having the thing forever is better.
Scott: But the reality is... But the reality, you know, is that doing it the way with a bad principle results in a better life.
Rym: Here's the example.
Rym: If I bought Adobe Creative Production Premium, whatever, I paid, like, over $2,000 for this.
Scott: I bought Lightroom some version before it was subscriptionable once.
Rym: No, I bought the Production Premium thing for, like, over $2,000 a long time ago.
Rym: It was, like, CS4.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: I theoretically owned that, and I could still install...
Scott: Oh, a license to it.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: CS4 is fucking garbage.
Rym: And if I tried to edit a project in CS4, one, it wouldn't work that well.
Rym: It'd be garbage-y.
Rym: Two, Adobe has no incentive to ever make it better because I'm not paying them anymore.
Rym: There's all these reasons why, if you want software to get better, it really needs to have a subscription model.
Rym: If you don't care if software gets better, that software is not something you're using in, like, a production pipeline.
Rym: That's, like, a video game.
Rym: I don't need a subscription to Mario 1 because I don't need any changes to Mario 1.
Scott: Well, notice there's still software that's developed, so video game people are making effective subscription video games or microtransaction games so they can keep getting money and keep their jobs.
Rym: Which they're doing primarily because...
Scott: It's, like, if you want Adobe to start a giant company, make Photoshop, and then shut down after they collect all the money from selling it, then, yeah, the "pay once" model will work.
Scott: The reality is, if you want it to keep getting better, and, right, it's, like, you might not need it to get better, in which case, okay, Adobe just go out of business.
Scott: then after they make Photoshop just for you and no one else.
Rym: But if you're a hobbyist, use open source stuff.
Rym: Yeah, it sucks, but guess what?
Rym: That's what...
Scott: Yeah, you're not someone who cares about getting constantly improved stuff.
Rym: You're happy using shitty stuff, so use free or low-cost stuff.
Rym: When we couldn't afford to buy, like, Adobe shit, I used that pirated copy of Cool Edit.
Scott: Free or low-cost stuff, and don't complain.
Scott: If you want the best stuff, then it's gonna be expensive, and people are gonna need to continuously work on it all the time, which means they need to continuously be paid.
Scott: So even though you're against, and I'm also against, the principle that I paid for it but now it's somehow it's gone and I can't use it anymore even though I paid, yeah, that principle sucks.
Scott: But the reality is, you get the best possible software.
Scott: that constantly gets better all the time, right, and is amazing, and it's more expensive, but guess what?
Scott: If you just deal with it and pay for it, you get the most amazing softwares.
Rym: Or if you're cheap, like on old GeekNights, I use ReSound on Linux.
Scott: You also get more of a right to complain if it isn't the best, 'cause say, "Hey, I'm fucking paying, like, 50 bucks a month for this shit, it better be fucking
Scott: amazing.".
Rym: So, recently there was an issue where there are sanctions against the Venezuelan government for a lot of reasons.
Rym: Venezuela is a very troubled place right now.
Rym: Many parts of the world are very troubled right now.
Scott: The United States is a very troubled place.
Rym: Yep, but I suggest if you haven't seen it in the news because of the hellscape we live in, check out what's going on in Chile.
Scott: Chile, Venezuela, Lebanon, these are the troubled places.
Scott: Hong Kong, United States, a lot of troubled places.
Rym: Liberate Hong Kong.
Rym: So, people who want to use bad old Adobe software were pointing at the fact that because there are sanctions against Venezuela, Adobe was obligated by law to cut off access to their software in Venezuela.
Rym: That isn't really an argument against the economics of subscription software, that's an argument against oppressive government regimes and the ties between government and economy.
Scott: The borders actually mattering for software.
Rym: Yep, which also gets complicated because economies are different in places.
Rym: If you charge the same thing everywhere in the world, you can't make enough money to make the thing, or you can't sell to anyone except the industrialized world.
Rym: There's a lot of issues, it's really complicated.
Scott: The price that we pay for Adobe whatevers, in Venezuela no one could afford it, so they couldn't have it, which would be fucking them over.
Scott: But if they charged the whole world the Venezuela price, they wouldn't make any fucking money.
Scott: So, it's a tough thing.
Scott: They don't really want to regionalize the prices, but what other choice do you have?
Rym: But I don't think these people realize that if Adobe wasn't subscription software, they would still cut off Venezuela.
Rym: You couldn't buy another license.
Rym: You couldn't download it anymore.
Scott: But the thing is, if you had bought it previously, they couldn't take it away from you.
Rym: But if you're at the point where your government is sanctioned by the world such that it can't trade with anyone else, you should be pirating the weapons to make the memes to fight the battle.
Scott: Exactly!
Scott: If you're in a country that isn't trading with the country that makes the thing you want, then you can just fucking pirate it.
Scott: Well, there's no problem.
Scott: You don't agree to the other country's intellectual property laws.
Scott: Just pirate like crazy.
Rym: So, even better, you were all mad at Adobe for this.
Rym: Adobe was actually pissed.
Rym: Adobe did not want to stop giving software to Venezuelans.
Scott: Of course not.
Scott: They wanted to make money from the Venezuelans.
Rym: So Adobe followed up.
Rym: and now Adobe actually has, this is like a very, very breaking story, like 1030 this morning, Adobe has a specific license to bypass the sanctions and continue to let people in Venezuela use their software.
Scott: Right, so at first Adobe was just going to refund everybody, but now they're like, "Okay, we'll give you a whole bunch of free months because of all the
Scott: trouble.".
Scott: Right?
Rym: Now, this seems like the right call because selling this kind of software, like continuing to let the people of Venezuela use the software, this is the kind of software that can help them make their movement and maybe try to fix their government.
Scott: Right, they can produce all kinds of amazing protest videos.
Rym: And Adobe seems to have done the right thing, like they got the exemption.
Rym: Everyone did the right thing, except the Venezuelan government and most of the US government, but not all of the US government.
Rym: In some other news, new AirPods are coming.
Scott: Right, so Apple made AirPods and AirPods are garbage.
Scott: Apple made headphones, the ones that are Apple branded because Apple owns Beats, I guess, and some of those are okay-ish, not the best.
Rym: I mean, if you buy, in the old days, like you buy an iPod or an iPhone or whatever and it comes with headphones.
Scott: I have a backup pair that I've never opened.
Rym: Yeah, rule one, throw those away and buy real headphones.
Scott: Right, the Apple headphones, the main problem with them has always been A, not comfortable, B, don't really fit nicely in the ear so much.
Scott: But the biggest problem is not noise canceling or isolating in any way.
Scott: So you put them in, all the outside noises still get right in your ear.
Scott: You've got to turn the volume on them way up in order to hear if there's any loud noises around you and then you end up damaging your ear.
Scott: If you keep it quiet and low volume so you don't damage your ear, guess what?
Scott: You can't hear your music or anything.
Rym: What's sad is this isn't new.
Rym: Very few people use isolating headphones.
Rym: Like in the 70s, 80s, 90s, headphones...
Scott: Well, those isolating and noise canceling weren't really a thing then.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, you could get real closed headphones but people didn't wear those in public.
Scott: But they weren't active noise canceling.
Rym: But people just stupidly destroy their hearing because they don't understand these basic principles.
Scott: Anyway, so, people still don't.
Rym: I was on the subway today and someone was wearing earbuds that were so loud.
Rym: It sounded like a speaker.
Scott: So I've always been buying isolating headphones from other companies but they have a host of problems.
Scott: The etymotic ones, which are really amazing and perfect, the wire keeps breaking because it's too fragile.
Rym: The etymotics are more like... And it's not replaceable wire.
Rym: Yeah, don't use those on the go.
Rym: Those are what you use in your home system.
Scott: No, for many years.
Scott: And I had to keep buying and warranting and all kinds of stuff because the wire kept breaking.
Rym: That's why I went with Shure.
Rym: Because Shure is super high quality.
Scott: Then I tried the appley Beats ones.
Scott: The Beats X, recommended by a listener, Luke.
Scott: And those were kind of comfortable.
Scott: They sounded a little heavy on the bass but they still sounded good enough.
Scott: And the wireless connection to the iPhone was great because Beats is owned by Apple.
Scott: So they connected and there's like a special Apple wireless headphone connecty thing that only Apple and Beats headphones do.
Scott: that I know of.
Scott: That made it a little more... It's still Bluetooth.
Scott: It's just the connection process is a little more seamless and a little more fancy.
Scott: And for example, you connect it to your iPhone.
Scott: It's automatically.
Scott: your iPad just knows about it now.
Scott: It does fancy shit like that.
Scott: And usually with Bluetooth, it's still... Bluetooth is still pretty seamless these days but a little bit flaky.
Scott: So it's nice to have that if you are an iOS person.
Scott: So those are okay but then the battery or something on them messed up.
Scott: I had to take them in for service.
Scott: Then I got new ones and the new ones weren't perfect.
Scott: And I was not the most thrilled with them.
Scott: And also, they were more isolating than Apple freaking earbuds.
Scott: They were not really isolating like the etymotic ones where you hear nothing.
Scott: So I got the Shure ones similar to what Rym has and they're isolating like the etymotic ones are and the cable is replaceable.
Scott: Which is really nice because that way I can go wired with a headphone jack or I can go Bluetooth with a separate special Bluetooth cable.
Scott: And the earbuds presumably will never break.
Scott: So that's great.
Scott: The problem is that the Bluetooth cable is not... The Bluetooth is not the best.
Scott: The cable is good but I don't like to have a cable.
Scott: Whether my phone has a headphone jack or not, not having a cable is nice.
Rym: I've used expensive Bluetooth headphones, cheap Bluetooth headphones.
Rym: Bluetooth audio works okay.
Scott: When you're connected and it's working, it's great.
Scott: You have wireless headphones.
Rym: But then you'll get interference.
Scott: There are certain places in the city where like I walk and the headphone goes like... Also the cable that is around from earbud to earbud with the battery and stuff on it is sort of floppy around the neck and kind of annoying.
Scott: And that is the major feature of the Apple AirPod.
Scott: It's just as shitty as every other fucking Apple headphone.
Scott: But it's just two little guys.
Scott: So it's like totally perfect and you don't have the stupid cable around your neck and it has perfect wireless connection.
Scott: So that's the feature you want.
Scott: You just need the isolating.
Scott: So here we go.
Scott: Rumor was true.
Scott: Apple announces AirPods Pro.
Scott: They're AirPods.
Scott: Perfect.
Scott: Two little white guys.
Scott: It's us.
Scott: Perfect wireless connection but also isolation plus active noise cancelling.
Scott: You shove them in your ear.
Scott: The best of everything.
Scott: The only problem with these is they're $200 something.
Rym: For $250 I could get like two super professional quality IEMs.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And also just like the regular AirPods, the battery does not last forever.
Scott: The battery will die in like two to three years.
Scott: And you can't really replace the battery.
Scott: You're just going to have to buy more AirPod Pros.
Scott: So it's like it's bad enough to replace AirPods after two years.
Scott: You're going to replace... Which are not that... They're expensive but not as expensive as AirPod Pro.
Scott: You can spend $200 every... $100 a year.
Scott: Over $100 a year just to have these.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: I've got the same IEMs that I bought seven years ago and they're fine.
Rym: And also they have a wire because I don't actually... On one hand I can see why some people really like the wireless aspect.
Scott: It's really nice not having the wire.
Rym: But on the other hand the wire has literally never been a problem and it also means that...
Scott: It's one of those things...
Rym: But it means the same headphone that I plug into my phone and my Switch... You can't use these iPods with your Switch, can you?
Scott: Probably not, no.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So I have the same headphones one time instead of...
Scott: I don't know why the Switch does not support Bluetooth audio.
Scott: That's a problem.
Scott: That's on Nintendo.
Rym: Yeah, but I'm saying...
Scott: Because there is a Bluetooth radio in there.
Rym: Because I have an Android phone, I plug the same headphones into the phone, the Switch, the tablet, and if I'm on a plane I plug it into the airplane.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: So... That is nice, but it's one of those things where it's like I've never had that wire.
Scott: I've always had a wire.
Scott: It's never been a problem.
Scott: And then you go without the wire for a while and then if you put the wire back in you're like, "Eh, this is an annoying
Scott: wire.".
Rym: But the wire is required for most of the things I plug headphones into, like my Switch or an airplane.
Scott: The only time I have a wired headphone necessary... I don't use the audio on airplanes whenever I'm on airplanes.
Rym: I watch movies on planes kind of often.
Scott: I do not do that.
Scott: I turn the screen off and do not look at that screen full of ads and garbage.
Rym: But if you fly on a nice flight it's just a giant screen that you can watch real movies on.
Scott: I do not watch those movies.
Scott: So I don't have that problem.
Rym: That's how I watch your name.
Scott: I watch it in a theater.
Rym: I also watch it in a theater, but I watched it early because I was on a JL flight and they just showed it.
Scott: Yeah, the only time I plug headphones in with a wire is my home desktop because my headphones are wired.
Scott: I plug them into the top of the computer at work.
Scott: I have Bluetooth connected to the laptop.
Rym: So last news that I just want to point out.
Rym: I'm not going to go into all the details about this story, but this is one of a huge number of examples where basically there's a hospital algorithm or the set of algorithms that's used to determine, given a bunch of people, who to prioritize treatment for, like triage type stuff.
Rym: If there's ten people and you have four doctors...
Scott: Who's in the waiting room and who's going to the doctor?
Rym: If you spend your resources on someone who's not likely to make it versus someone who's likely to make it with treatment, what do you do?
Rym: These are really hard questions to answer.
Scott: Right, but with a shit ton of medical data, even anonymized data, it should be theoretically possible to make better decisions on this than a human would.
Scott: You have a fuck ton of data.
Scott: The doctor can't just know, "Oh yeah, someone who has these symptoms...".
Scott: It's like the doctor can't even diagnose the person until they're in the room and they're looking at them.
Scott: But the computer could maybe be like, "Alright, we've got symptoms and that's all we've
Scott: got.".
Scott: "Alright, well that person is bleeding all over the place.
Scott: This person may be broken on...".
Rym: So the problem is, for a lot of reasons that you can guess at these reasons, talk to an old person or read a book if you're unclear on this, but the data that we're going to use to feed these algorithms and these AI systems is already really racist and biased,
Scott: because the data
Rym: is collected from a pretty racist and biased society.
Rym: So imagine an algorithm that decides whether or not someone you're about to hire for a job is trustworthy.
Rym: That algorithm is going to be based on the data sets collected by people who have been hiring up to this point, which there is a history of racist, biased hiring.
Rym: Therefore, you're just going to train the computer to be as racist as society.
Scott: Well, what you could do is you could have that old data, right, and then instead of telling it, "Hey computer, do like we did in the past...".
Rym: "Hey computer, find the biases and fix
Rym: it.".
Scott: Well, you could be like, "Computer, in the past we fucked the fuck up.
Scott: You make decisions, not according to this
Scott: data.".
Scott: You know, you have this data, use it, but don't do it this way.
Scott: that the old data did it.
Scott: But that's hard to do.
Scott: Of course, but look at that old data and don't do it that way.
Scott: Do it a different way.
Scott: Optimize for this other thing.
Scott: Don't optimize for this, right?
Scott: But people don't do that.
Scott: They just write a real simple program that's like, "Pick who's most likely to
Scott: survive.".
Scott: Well, yeah, when doctors were racist, black people didn't survive.
Scott: So you're going to keep telling the doctors to treat white people.
Scott: Because you're not doing it because they're white, you're doing it because they're more likely to survive.
Scott: Because in the past, they were more likely to survive in racist land.
Rym: The provenance of your data and the way it was collected is very important if you're using it for any real AI application.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So I just saw this tweet come by.
Rym: Apparently there's the Helvetica font, which is an okay font.
Rym: But there are many things that are called Helvetica.
Scott: Yeah, it's just like an obvious, the most softball, easy joke that anyone could think of.
Scott: So it's so bleh that it's not even funny.
Rym: There's like a band called Helvetica.
Rym: I've seen like ten different fonts called Helvetica.
Rym: They're just shitty in some way.
Rym: But they're always like either satanic or like rooty.
Rym: Like they're always something like that.
Rym: I found the true Helvetica.
Rym: It is identical to regular Helvetica except the kerning is broken.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: It's just bad kerning Helvetica.
Rym: And it's really funny to look at.
Scott: Okay, I don't think it's that funny.
Rym: I think it's pretty funny.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: So what do you got?
Scott: So in China, right, there was a mafia boss.
Scott: All right.
Scott: And the mafia boss hired a hitman and said, "Kill my rival mafia boss hitman and I will give you many
Scott: monies.".
Rym: He's only going to pay him $282,000.
Scott: That's a lot of monies.
Rym: Depends.
Scott: I mean, yeah.
Scott: But anyway, I feel like for a hitman.
Scott: that's one hit.
Rym: If you only got to work a week a year to make $282,000 a year, okay.
Rym: Tax-free.
Rym: You're not paying taxes on that.
Rym: At least I hope not.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: IRS, what do you do?
Scott: I am a hitman.
Scott: This hitman figures, "You know what?
Scott: I want this money, but I don't really want to kill this other mafia
Scott: boss.".
Scott: That's A, hard.
Scott: B, dangerous.
Scott: C, it's clear why you would not want to do that.
Scott: But it's also clear why you would want to not tell the first mafia boss, "No, thank you.
Scott: I'm not going to do
Scott: it.".
Scott: Right?
Scott: You want to say, "Yes, I'll do it," and somehow get away with not doing it.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So, genius hitman hires another hitman.
Rym: Subcontracted hitman.
Scott: So, the thing about it, you're getting what?
Scott: $282,000 something?
Scott: So let's just say $300,000.
Rym: Oh, he split it in half.
Rym: I'll keep $141,000.
Rym: I'll give you $141,000.
Scott: The other guy doesn't even know he's getting it split in half.
Scott: He's just like, "Look, I'll give you $140,000 to kill this mafia
Scott: boss.".
Scott: $140,000.
Rym: Still a pretty good salary for a year.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Right?
Scott: And that guy, he's thinking, "Hey, I could hire someone else to do this hit and pay them like
Scott: $70,000.".
Scott: And this exact thing not only is a hilarious story that would make for a great movie, it's a real story that really happened.
Scott: It got all the way down to the fifth hitman.
Rym: But the fifth hitman had such a good idea.
Scott: Was smarter, yet also dumber than all the other hitmen.
Scott: The fifth hitman went to the victim, the person who had the hit, the rival mafia boss.
Rym: Because he's not making that much money at this point anyway.
Scott: Right.
Scott: He's not getting paid enough.
Scott: And he's saying, "Look, bro.
Scott: Somebody paid me to kill
Scott: you.".
Scott: And this person doesn't even know who the original hit person was.
Scott: He can't even rat out the original mafia boss to the rival guy.
Scott: But he can say, "Look, fake your death.
Scott: You fake your death and I'll get money from this fourth hitman, who I don't even know is the fourth hitman.
Scott: And then we'll split that money.
Scott: Just fake your death so we both get
Scott: money.".
Rym: You know, good on him.
Rym: He's the only one who didn't take an action that would lead to another person's death.
Rym: So, I don't know how...
Scott: I assume China's justice system is not that just.
Scott: I mean, ours isn't that just.
Scott: I assume China's is possibly less just.
Scott: But regardless, there's a photo of the courtroom with all of the hitmen lined up.
Scott: And apparently there was more news since I read the story.
Rym: They all look mad and sad, except this guy who seems like, "Eh, you got
Rym: me.".
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, Rym apparently read more details on the story, I guess, that are more recent.
Scott: Oh, so there's even further updates.
Scott: Some of the hitmen got off because I guess the last guy technically didn't commit a crime.
Scott: All he did was...
Rym: Well, he committed a crime, but he didn't commit attempted murder.
Scott: Oh, that's true.
Rym: But it gets more complicated.
Rym: I found even yet more updates.
Scott: He didn't hire a hitman, which is illegal.
Rym: I guess the first trial had some problems.
Rym: They did it again.
Rym: Eventually, they all went to jail.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Regardless, that is a hilarious story that someone's going to make a movie out of.
Rym: But some people were like, "No, this would be the best Guy Ritchie
Rym: movie.".
Rym: Oh my God.
Scott: It just is a Guy Ritchie movie.
Scott: Are you sure it isn't like a Guy Ritchie faked his news story so that he could then make a movie?
Scott: No, Guy Ritchie hired the original mob boss to put the hit out.
Scott: He's like, "Look, I know five cowardly
Scott: hitmen.".
Scott: You have to hire this guy and they all know each other.
Rym: I would just call the movie.
Rym: The movie would literally be called Five Cowardly Hitmen.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: This is such a great story.
Rym: In the meta moment, the GeekNights Book Club book is still the Tale of Genji.
Rym: It's going to be a while.
Rym: We're going to pick an inner Rym book.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: I got to pick it.
Rym: Stay tuned.
Scott: Or we could do several episodes on Tale of Genji.
Scott: There's another I. And just do piece by piece.
Rym: Like chapters.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Good chapter by chapter, maybe.
Scott: That's too many.
Rym: How many chapters are there?
Rym: A lot.
Rym: It's like the tea set thing.
Rym: But the incense thing.
Scott: It's big.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, we'll do it at some interval.
Rym: We'll say how far we got.
Rym: We'll be like, "Hey, we're going to do a book club on the first
Rym: bit.".
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Because then we can speculate on what's going to happen next.
Scott: We'll see.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: We're going to be live at PEX Unplugged doing... I'll post the schedule when I get a chance.
Rym: We're doing one talk.
Rym: A brand new talk called Take Your Fucking Turn.
Scott: Hell yeah.
Rym: And we're going to do another talk that is two hours long.
Rym: We're going to teach you how to play and play with you three different board games.
Rym: All in the same room.
Rym: One, two, three.
Scott: Are we sure we're going to be able to do that in the allotted time?
Rym: Definitely with the games we're doing.
Rym: Plus, we'll do Wizard last.
Rym: Because Wizard can stop after any number of hands because people will have gotten the gist.
Rym: So I think we're good there.
Scott: It'd be kind of lame if it stopped after the first or second hand.
Rym: I feel like we could get further in.
Rym: These games are not hard to teach.
Rym: I think Genshin Clever might take the longest, but we can move it along.
Scott: What else do we got?
Rym: PAX East, PAX Unplugged, PAX West, PAX Fest, PAX East.
Rym: All this is coming.
Rym: Let's get into it.
Rym: Talk about microphones.
Scott: So we got to avoid doing what is a high crime worse than hiring a hitman, which is doing a podcast about podcasting.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: That is a crime.
Rym: I feel like there's a podcast now.
Scott: Enough of those were made, you know, 14, 15 years ago.
Scott: No more shall ever be made, especially not by two white dudes.
Rym: Though what I would say that is kind of fascinating is everything that tells people how to make podcasts tends to be full of terrible goddamn advice.
Rym: that makes bad podcasts.
Scott: The only advice you need to start is to just talk.
Rym: Content is king.
Scott: Talk into a microphone, make an MP3 and upload at the end.
Scott: Content is king.
Scott: So, microphones.
Scott: The number one rule is you must not use a microphone as your logo if you are a podcast.
Scott: Unless your podcast is about microphones.
Scott: Our podcast is about nerdy things, therefore our logo should have nerdy things in it.
Rym: I feel like the only reason.
Scott: Podcast about soccer shouldn't have a microphone in it, it should have a soccer ball.
Rym: You might have noticed we changed our logo and we're currently rebranding because it's kind of bridging from the meta moment into the main bit.
Rym: But I feel like the only reason our logo, the old logo with the microphone gets a pass is that there were like 12 podcasts when we started.
Rym: Like there weren't that many podcasts.
Scott: Anyway, so we're going to talk only about microphones, right?
Scott: The things you talk into and the hardware and the types and such and such.
Rym: Because I've realized in my life that most people know fuck all about microphones even though they use them all the time.
Scott: They don't know how to use them.
Rym: Yeah, like people will use microphones that are designed to work no matter how stupid you are in incredibly stupid ways.
Rym: And I see people, like speakers, they do the same thing.
Rym: You'll see people who have the PC volume set all the way down but then their amplifier, like the external one is set to the max volume and all sorts of just terrible ideas.
Scott: So what was the first ever microphone?
Rym: Oh, I don't know.
Rym: That history?
Rym: That was probably that liquid microphone.
Rym: Let's see.
Rym: In order to speak, the first microphone ever was a megaphone.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: Yeah, well.
Rym: You know what?
Scott: I actually don't know how the fucking megaphone works.
Rym: Really?
Rym: You really don't?
Scott: It's just a big horn.
Rym: A megaphone or a microphone?
Scott: Like a megaphone.
Rym: Resonance.
Scott: Oh, is that it?
Scott: Acoustic amplification.
Rym: It's a whole thing.
Rym: Alright.
Scott: But like if I can talk into a big horn, like a Viking, and just be loud.
Scott: But a megaphone is a lot smaller and has a battery in it.
Rym: So megaphones used to not have batteries or electronics.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: I understand how a horn works.
Scott: But how does like a modern megaphone that I would buy at like the sporting goods store.
Rym: I want to give you a second to not feel dumb about this.
Rym: Because it's really simple.
Scott: How does it work?
Rym: The point you're talking to is a microphone.
Rym: And there's a speaker on the other side.
Scott: With an amp.
Scott: And then a horn.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: And a horn.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: The horn part coming out is just an acoustic amplifier in addition to the electric amplifier inside of the thing.
Scott: So you're just using a smaller horn with a powered amplifier so that you don't need a big horn.
Rym: That's literally all it is.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: That's boring.
Scott: I thought there was something in there.
Rym: I owned one of those megaphones for a while, but I got rid of it because that was a real waste of time.
Rym: I was going to bring it to Connecticut.
Rym: It'd be real annoying.
Scott: They're mostly used on like, you know, these days for like not much.
Rym: There's cops.
Scott: People just use PA systems.
Rym: There's cops in Grand Central every day using them to yell at people to not go up the downstairs.
Scott: I see them mostly use like boats to yell at other boats.
Scott: No.
Scott: Who have like a radio.
Scott: They're just really close.
Rym: So let's talk about first things first.
Rym: What does a microphone do?
Rym: Because there's microphones are actually both electrically and mechanically very, very simple devices on the surface.
Rym: And the details only matter if you are doing things a little more complicated than just talking on a phone.
Scott: So the idea is that someone's talking, right?
Scott: Or you're making noise.
Rym: Sound is happening.
Scott: You want to capture that noise in an electrical form.
Scott: You want to turn noise into electricity, right?
Rym: And then from electricity, turn it into something else later.
Rym: We don't care what you turn it into.
Scott: Well, it just so happens, we're very lucky that noise is an analog signal.
Scott: It is waves in the air.
Scott: Sound waves.
Rym: Vibrations.
Scott: Vibrations.
Scott: The air is shaking.
Scott: If there's no air, you can't make any sound, right?
Scott: Or you need something to vibrate, even if it's not air.
Scott: You need some sort of medium.
Scott: But regardless.
Rym: And we won't just talk about air.
Rym: I've had microphones that are not designed to detect air.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But most of the time with humans talking or noise making with instruments, it's air that's vibrating.
Scott: You want to capture it.
Scott: You want to detect how the air is vibrating.
Scott: What frequency, what amplitude, right?
Scott: And then you want to sort of record that with electricity.
Scott: It just so happens we're lucky.
Rym: Well, it didn't actually have to be electricity.
Rym: There are completely mechanical microphones.
Scott: I'm sure there are.
Scott: That have... But most of the time it's electricity.
Rym: Well, but there are microphones that will detect the vibrating air and stencil it directly into something like a wax cylinder or a record.
Scott: That's cool.
Rym: Yeah, that can exist because it's not even turned into electricity.
Rym: It's just.
Rym: Can you record vibration and store a record of that vibration somewhere?
Scott: Yeah, I mean, we've heard about like archaeologists, like taking old pottery and like dragging needles on it because the vibrations of people talking way, way, way, way back.
Rym: Theoretically be captured there.
Scott: Theoretically had been just been captured because the movements of the air hitting the pottery while it was being made.
Scott: So you heard what the maybe the noises that were being made when the pottery was being made.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: In practice, it seemed like that didn't work out.
Scott: Regardless.
Rym: It's a good idea, but it didn't work out.
Rym: Right.
Scott: You just need to capture the vibration.
Scott: So what you do is you have some sort of thing that is so light.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That it will vibrate.
Rym: Or so big, like it just has to, it has to react.
Scott: The air, the air will push it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then modern times you put a fucking magnet on there.
Rym: Well, actually, that already gets complicated.
Rym: But think of it this way.
Rym: Really, all the microphone is a transducer in the end.
Rym: All it's doing is converting one form of energy to another form of energy, taking vibration and turning it into something else, some kind of signal.
Rym: So really, that's just a transducer.
Rym: There's a lot of ways to make transducers to detect vibrations.
Rym: I'm going to not really talk about all the historic kinds of microphones because they're just so obsolete.
Rym: It doesn't matter.
Rym: Unless you're a nerd who really is interested in this stuff, it is not helpful information.
Rym: But basically, modern microphones are either condenser microphones, electrodes, which are actually condensers.
Rym: They're just a different kind of condenser.
Rym: The details are kind of nuanced.
Rym: Carbon microphones, which are known as cheap as shit, piece of shit microphones.
Rym: There's dynamic mics, which are what a lot of microphones are.
Rym: And then there's kind of crazy, like the more specialized stuff like contact microphones and RF microphones.
Rym: And then the really crazy stuff like laser microphones.
Rym: Don't really need to talk about those that much either.
Rym: But in terms of you, any microphone and any device you have that's like a phone is probably just an electric condenser.
Rym: Fancy microphones tend to be either dynamic or condenser.
Rym: The fancier microphones tend to be condenser.
Rym: But yeah, it doesn't really matter for most people.
Rym: Condenser microphones really aren't better unless signal quality matters a lot to you and other factors we can get into.
Rym: But the way these all basically work, like to talk about all the differences, a dynamic microphone is pretty easy.
Rym: It's basically the magnet thing, like Scott said.
Rym: Have some sort of diaphragm, have some magnetic stuff and just calculate air velocity rather like and use that.
Scott: When the magnets move in relation to each other and metal, right, there is a current.
Scott: It's a really weak current because it's kind of, you know, it's not like a giant magnet.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But that weak current is enough, you know, and it's analog.
Scott: So the vibrate, the movement of the magnet, the change in voltage in the wire is going to mirror the vibration of the air because the air moving is what's pushing the magnet.
Scott: The signal comes out, you amplify the signal with a preamp or just an amp and now you record that in whatever recording medium of choice.
Scott: It could be like a tape or a record.
Scott: Let's talk about that.
Rym: This gets into audio stuff that's going to be on microphones, but there's like mic level and line level.
Rym: And if you have something that's just playing music, it's playing like at line level, meaning like it is loud enough.
Rym: There's a signal that is loud enough to do stuff with, but microphones make extremely weak signals.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Think about how small a microphone is.
Scott: There's little magnets in there and they're so weak ass that the air.
Rym: Well, it's actually a magnetic coil.
Rym: It's an electromagnet.
Rym: There's no like a permanent magnet in there.
Rym: The point is dynamic microphone.
Scott: The point is they're light enough that air is physically pushing them around.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They're moving when I talk.
Scott: My voice is shaking them.
Scott: And that shaking is making a voltage.
Scott: that's obviously not making a big voltage.
Scott: If it was making a big voltage, we could have power plants just by taking people like us who talk too much.
Rym: Which we could.
Scott: We could make a power plant where people like us just talk at a wall and generate electricity.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If microphones were better.
Scott: But no, the voltage that comes out is weak ass.
Rym: So whenever you hear an audio person on a preamplifier or a mic amplifier, that's just an amplifier that takes the weak ass signal from the microphone and gets it up to line level.
Rym: So it's on the same level as something that is like a normal signal.
Rym: And then on the other side, if you're playing stuff out of a speaker, you usually have an amplifier to drive that speaker to make it as loud as you want it to be.
Rym: Because usually you want a speaker like in a stadium to be really loud compared to my voice.
Scott: I want the speaker to be louder than me.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because even a signal that's at line level, right?
Scott: If I got like a normal tiny speaker or some headphones, line level's probably enough to shake the speakers in the headphones.
Scott: Yeah, tiny little speaker.
Scott: If I'm in a stadium or I'm a DJ and I got a giant speaker, I need some, I can't, it might take a line level signal and send it to the speaker.
Scott: That ain't shaking shit.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Right?
Scott: It's not shaking.
Scott: no booties.
Scott: You gotta get big amps and a big stack, right?
Scott: Power that shit up and then you go boom, boom, boom, boom, boom.
Scott: Right?
Scott: You need big electricity.
Scott: Because the speaker, usually speakers aren't powered.
Scott: Right?
Scott: They don't have their own battery.
Scott: They don't plug into the wall.
Scott: They just have speaker wire going into them and all the amplification happens somewhere else.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: So dynamic mics are like basic, like a microphone you see on a stage is probably an SM58.
Scott: The metal like mesh ball on a thing you hold, that's what that is.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: So dynamic mics, a lot of people who are podcasting or something or doing anything, they feel like, "Oh, but I need a condenser because they're much more expensive.
Rym: They must be
Rym: better.".
Rym: Meh.
Rym: And they are better.
Rym: We use condensers now.
Rym: We used to not.
Rym: But dynamic mics actually have a lot of benefits.
Rym: One, the difference in quality probably does not matter to you or most people.
Scott: You probably would never notice.
Rym: Two, dynamic mics are better in situations where the volume, like the actual objective volume of the sound could get crazy loud.
Rym: Dynamic mics basically can't get blown out.
Rym: They're just invincible and their gain before feedback is really high.
Rym: so they can take in a crazy high signal, meaning you wouldn't even need to pre-amplify it that much before they start to fuck up.
Rym: I'm skipping a lot of details because they're not that relevant, but that's basically that normal microphones on like a stage are dynamic microphones.
Rym: Condenser microphones are the so-called fancy ones.
Rym: They're a little different.
Rym: They use a capacitor.
Rym: You want to know why they're called condenser microphones?
Rym: Do you know why?
Scott: It's not condensation from the air.
Scott: Why?
Rym: Capacitors were originally called condensers.
Rym: That's all.
Rym: They're just capacitor microphones.
Rym: So instead of like a coil and a thing moving, which may or may not be a permanent magnet depending on the kind of microphone, like dynamic, there's all different ways to do this, then that'll make the signal.
Rym: Condensers are much more sensitive.
Rym: It's basically tiny elements moving and changing the capacitance of those elements.
Scott: Ah, mmm.
Rym: That's how they work.
Rym: That means you need a power source.
Scott: Yeah, otherwise that capacitor just drains right out.
Rym: Yep, dynamic mic sort of powers itself.
Scott: Yeah, because like I said, there's magnets, right?
Scott: Magnets moving just makes electricity, right?
Scott: The same way that if you crank, if you take a motor and turn it with your hands, right, voltage will come out the other end, and then if you put voltage in, then the motor will spin.
Scott: It works in both directions.
Scott: This is the same thing, right?
Scott: Moving the magnets makes electricity, right?
Scott: Making electricity moves the magnets, but if there are no magnets, you're going to need power to fill up the capacitor because it will just drain on its own.
Scott: So there's a thing called the phantom.
Rym: Phantom power.
Rym: If you see that phantom power button.
Scott: Grab the key and fucking run.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: All that means is that the thing you're plugging the microphone into is sending some voltage out, like it's sending electricity to the microphone, so the microphone can basically power itself.
Rym: There's some nuance to what that power is used for that I really don't want to get into.
Scott: The point is, if you have a microphone that needs the phantom power, because it has a capacitor in it.
Rym: Meaning it's a condenser microphone.
Scott: And you do not have phantom power, the microphone will not work, right?
Rym: It'll either generate no signal, or...
Scott: It'll be so weak, maybe there's some energy left in the capacitor, who knows?
Rym: Or depending on the kind of condenser microphone, it's theoretically possible it might generate a signal that's just so small, nothing could detect it.
Scott: It also might get weaker over time if you start using it, because the capacitor will drain.
Rym: Yeah, it's complicated too, because usually condenser microphones use that voltage both to power themselves and to polarize one of their elements.
Scott: Regardless, the point is, if you do want to plug it in, you need to find something to plug it into that will give it the phantom power.
Rym: And this is why most people would prefer to use the dynamic microphone, because unless you're doing really professional stuff, I don't think you want to have to have the equipment that can send phantom power to your device.
Scott: Right, you can just take a dynamic microphone, if you've got the right cables, you can shove it in the back of your computer, you can shove it into your iPhone, you can shove it into anything, you've got a microphone hole.
Scott: If you've got the right cables and adapters to plug into the bottom of the microphone, you can connect the dynamic microphone.
Scott: It's gonna work, you're gonna talk, the audio's gonna come out.
Scott: If you've got the condenser microphone, you need to find some kind of device, some audio mixer, amp, something that has phantom power.
Scott: I have a thing at home, it's made by Shure, it's called the X2U, literally stands for XLR to USB.
Scott: On one side, it's a little tiny guy, it's just like a little rod, on one side is an XLR connector to connect the microphone, on the other side is USB, the big kind of USB that you use for your printer and stuff.
Scott: And then, in the middle, there's just some volume knobs, there's actually a little headphone hole.
Scott: so you can monitor the microphone on its own separately from your computer.
Scott: But regardless, it takes the USB power, and with a little button, you can say, "Hey, I'm using a condenser mic, take the USB power and use it as phantom power and power the
Scott: microphone.".
Rym: Yep.
Scott: I think that's the smallest, cheapest thing I know of that you can use to get phantom power.
Rym: A lot of people don't understand phantom power, and a lot of people buy microphones that they can't use because they don't understand this.
Scott: It comes down to your microphone either needs it or it doesn't, and if it needs it, it needs it.
Rym: Now, modern microphones, if you put phantom power down the line, but it's actually a dynamic mic, usually it won't break anything.
Scott: Yeah, you won't even notice.
Scott: I've had it happen before, it's like, "Yeah, this microphone doesn't need phantom power, but it's on, oh well, you won't even
Scott: know.".
Rym: That is not true for another type of microphone, the ribbon microphone, which thankfully is just so obsolete, like it doesn't matter anymore.
Scott: That's the old timey radio ones, you see, that no one uses anymore unless they're weird and retro.
Rym: The history of microphones is basically that different technologies came at different times, but some of the technologies, while they were better in many ways, were not easy to produce, or worked, but were shitty, like one we'll get to in a second, the one that's actually in all your phones, like that kind of microphone.
Rym: So ribbon microphones have a little, tiny, tiny, thin ribbon of metal inside of them, and that's the thing that detects the signal, and they have a whole system around them.
Scott: It sounds like
Scott: "wah-wah-wah-wah-wah-wah.".
Rym: Actually, in the olden times, a ribbon microphone was super good compared to all the other types of microphones they could make.
Rym: It was like the high quality one.
Scott: But now it sounds like old timey.
Scott: It wasn't just the recording technology that makes it sound old timey, it was also the microphone.
Rym: But the problem with ribbon microphones is that that piece of metal is way bigger than you think, and is crazy fragile.
Scott: Well, because it has to be so weak that air moves it.
Rym: Even worse, if you turn on phantom power to an old ribbon microphone, it'll also instantly destroy the very expensive microphone.
Rym: A too loud sound can ruin a ribbon microphone.
Rym: Yelling to one that's not designed for yelling?
Rym: You've just broken it.
Scott: Yeah, you just shake that little piece of metal right off.
Scott: The end.
Rym: So, there's a subset of condenser microphones.
Rym: Most people don't seem to realize these are condenser microphones, but they're called electrets.
Rym: They're basically a condenser microphone.
Rym: They were invented in the '60s.
Rym: They're pretty new.
Rym: And they used to be really shitty, because they were very low quality, but over time, the technology got better and better to where this is the kind of microphone that's in everything today.
Rym: Anything that isn't like a studio mic, anything in a phone, in a portable console, if you have a smartwatch that has a microphone in it, it's almost definitely an electret.
Rym: They're basically just condensers where the polarization is like.
Rym: they have a pre-permanently polarized thing in there.
Rym: Like an electrically charged ferroelectric material.
Rym: You can read Wikipedia.
Rym: I don't even understand it that well, because I don't give a shit about electret microphones.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, they're not... Electret microphones are not usually used for sounding great, right?
Rym: They're used because they're tiny.
Scott: Tiny and cheap.
Scott: Tiny, efficient, cheap, right?
Scott: They work.
Scott: Durable.
Scott: Don't think about it.
Scott: They're relatively low.
Rym: quality is kind of why you can't record anything with good audio on your phone.
Rym: As much as you might think you can, you really can't.
Rym: All those other kinds of microphones are really obsolete.
Rym: Most people, when they think about kinds of microphones, it actually comes down to the idea of the pickup pattern.
Rym: Like, how does the microphone pick up sound?
Rym: Because if you weren't aware of this, you can design microphones that basically only pick up sound from one direction.
Scott: Well, the pickup pattern isn't always directly related to the type, right?
Scott: It's completely unrelated.
Scott: You can have different condensers with different patterns, different dynamics with different patterns, a dynamic and a condenser with the same pattern.
Scott: So you can have like a shotgun microphone.
Scott: You think about you put it on your camera because you're walking around town with your camera interviewing people for the local TV station.
Scott: So you have a shotgun mic.
Scott: It's a long stick and you aim it straight at people.
Rym: If you're watching the stream, I'm holding mine up.
Rym: It's like a foot long.
Scott: Right, you aim it at people because you want to hear them talking and you don't want to hear anyone else talking like the crazy hobo who's trying to yell because he sees the news people recording something.
Scott: You aim it and it picks up that person right in front of you along.
Scott: It's like a long stick.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: that's why it's called a shotgun.
Scott: It kind of makes sense.
Scott: And you could have a dynamic shotgun or condenser shotgun or I don't know.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Scott: It's the.
Scott: it's where it's the shape of the microphone and the shape of where does it?
Scott: a part capsule that you part of it that you aim and then how far away does it pick up.
Scott: It's like a three dimensional shape that comes out of the microphone and it's like any noise in that zone.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That is moving in this direction will be picked up by the microphone and air moving outside that zone will not hit the microphone and will not be heard and recorded.
Rym: Now, if you're curious how this works, because this is purely physical, this is using physics and the shape of the thing around the actual microphone element to block sound from a direction.
Rym: Right.
Rym: So that isn't even that complicated.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like it is a microphone I'm using right here.
Scott: If I try to talk into it from the side, you just disappear.
Rym: Right.
Scott: It's like you can probably still hear me, but probably not much.
Rym: And if I come around to the frame all the way around to the back, like 180 degrees more so than if you were back here.
Rym: And the reason for that is because we're these microphones are Beta 87 A's.
Rym: They're condensers.
Rym: They're sure, but they're hypercardioids, which is a tight type of pickup pattern.
Rym: But the math basically comes down to interference patterns.
Rym: So like, you know, if I play a sound and then I play the inverse of that sound, like the exact same sound, but I invert the phase, meaning like if it's a sine wave going up and down and up, like up, down, up, down.
Rym: And I play the exact same sound, but I flip it over.
Rym: So it's down, up, down, up.
Rym: Sound waves interfere with each other in the real world.
Rym: So if two sound waves that are the exact opposite are happening at the same time, they cancel each other out and you hear nothing.
Rym: Right.
Scott: It's like if I'm pulling the tug of war to the right, you pull left, the rope doesn't move.
Rym: But there are still forces.
Scott: If I shake the air with a wave and you shake the air with the exact opposite wave, then when that part of the pool where the waves in the water meet is a still water.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So active sound cancellation, like in fancy headphones, that's what they're doing.
Rym: It's generating sound.
Rym: That's the inverted phase of the background noise.
Scott: Intentionally looking at the waves coming in the pool and intentionally making the opposite wave to force there to be still water.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: That's pretty cool.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Imagine if like you could, you know, it's like you could never do it with your hand, but like splashing the water in the pool so fastly and precisely to force the water to be still.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: That's what's going on.
Rym: So the shape of the microphone determines this.
Rym: And even though I understand them, this is one area of math, I actually do understand it pretty well.
Rym: Without drawing it, it's really hard to explain this.
Scott: It's also three dimensional and all the illustrations everywhere will always be two dimensional.
Scott: Maybe a YouTube video could show you some 3D explanations.
Rym: But a lot of people get confused about when and how to use these different patterns.
Rym: And this is something generally.
Rym: there's two kinds of microphones, directional or omni-directional.
Rym: An omni-microphone means it picks up sound equally in all directions.
Rym: It just works.
Rym: Any time you do something to make a microphone more directional, you also color the sound.
Rym: You're changing the signal that's coming in because you're fucking with it.
Rym: Like you're making the audio go through all these paths.
Rym: You're canceling things out.
Rym: So if a microphone is omni-directional, it'll pick up sound from all directions.
Rym: But sometimes, in fact, most times you want that.
Rym: If you can get away with it, you always want to use an omni-directional microphone because you'll get the purest possible representation of the actual sound at that point in space.
Rym: So an omni-directional microphone that's closer to the sound source will be better than a directional microphone that's further away from the same source.
Scott: The problem with omni-directional is sometimes you're recording sounds.
Scott: And like I said with shotgun microphone, you don't want to record every sound that hits that point in space.
Scott: It's like we've got two people talking.
Scott: We don't want to record anything else except the two people talking.
Scott: We don't want the birds tweeting and the grass blowing.
Rym: This room we're recording nights because I only have two bedrooms is not a full sound stage.
Rym: I don't have acoustic foam covering every surface.
Rym: There's a lot of echo in this room.
Scott: There could be noises coming from outside like the 7 train.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Scott and I are also very loud.
Rym: We're just yelling into microphones for an hour.
Rym: And I need to make sure his mic doesn't pick me up and vice versa.
Rym: so these hyper-cardioids...
Scott: They're not in separate rooms.
Rym: The pickup pattern on these is very specific.
Rym: And if you buy fancy microphones with directional patterns, they come with a template.
Rym: you can put over the microphone to figure out where to put other sound sources.
Rym: Because the sound they pick up the least is like 270 degree angle and the inverse of that out the back.
Rym: Because on a stage you stand on the X and you put the monitor speakers pointed at you so you can hear your band and yourself pointed at the microphone from those angles.
Rym: So the microphone will pick you up and it'll pick the crowd up a tiny bit but it won't pick up those two specific speakers.
Rym: Like that's how cool this shit can get.
Rym: But it colors the sound.
Rym: So you know how people talk about a radio voice?
Rym: That's caused by that pickup pattern.
Rym: The closer you get to a microphone that is directional, the more you'll pick up bass.
Rym: Like bass gets physically amplified.
Rym: My voice will get deeper the closer I get to this thing.
Scott: Also you intentionally talk deeper just then.
Rym: That was not intentional.
Scott: You did it though.
Rym: Even if I talk really high though it'll still be deeper than if I do it back here.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: So radio people, depending on what you're doing, maybe you want to get someone's natural voice.
Rym: Then you want to use an omnidirectional mic.
Rym: Maybe you want to sound like Barry Manilow.
Rym: You get a fucking shotgun mic and you like swallow it and talk into it.
Rym: So shotgun mics are just really really really really directional microphones.
Rym: That long length and all those vents on the side is just to pick up reflections and route audio around to where sound that comes in from the sides, well not from the direct sides but from like any sound you don't want to pick up, is generally going to be reflected internally such that it cancels itself out.
Rym: So because of math and physics you can't actually do that for all sounds.
Rym: So the pickup patterns are actually way more complex than these images I'm showing you because they also are different at every frequency.
Rym: So that's the complication and this is the stuff you have to learn if you use microphones for serious.
Scott: Right well because you might have, you know, if you're doing some audio stuff where it matters, you got a whole set of microphones with all sorts of different ones, you get to pick the right one for the right job.
Scott: But you know you're making a movie or something or recording a band, it's like you got to know that stuff.
Scott: But if you're 99% of people using microphones are just talking.
Rym: And in that case you just want to be as close to that microphone as you can and that's fine.
Rym: And then set your gain like the volume so you're not overloading the thing.
Scott: Yeah I think most people are just using, you know, the ones in their headset or the ones in their phone.
Rym: I have never found a headset that had a microphone that was even like worth talking about.
Scott: They're so bad.
Scott: Right the strategy.
Rym: When I play like Overwatch if I wear this just because that's what I'm talking to like the team with, I'll record my voice with a different microphone if I'm streaming for the rest of you.
Scott: This is my recommendation.
Scott: You know they sell gaming headsets and stuff like that to people.
Scott: They're pretty much all a bad idea.
Rym: You're better off buying headphones and a microphone.
Scott: Yes if you go online and be like what's the best gaming headset?
Scott: Pretty much everyone who knows anything says buy headphones because you can get really good headphones really cheap.
Scott: And then buy a microphone.
Scott: you can get a pretty good microphone pretty cheap.
Scott: And that's cheaper than a gaming headset which is shitty headphones attached to a shitty microphone and a bunch of gaming garbage.
Scott: The only time you should buy like a headset that has the microphone and the ear thing is like let's say you're a salesperson who's on the phone all day.
Scott: Then it's like well the audio quality doesn't really matter.
Scott: The hands-freeness is what matters right?
Scott: You know then the not hassle of having two things is what matters.
Scott: Other than that headsets no bueno.
Rym: So volume wise I think we're not gonna get too deep in this.
Rym: We've gone long enough.
Rym: but in terms of what you do with the audio the last thing we should talk about is dynamic mics.
Rym: You generally don't like.
Rym: you don't get so loud that the microphone distorts you.
Rym: Usually it's the thing you're putting the signal into does not have the ability to capture the signal that you're putting into it.
Rym: That's what clipping is.
Rym: We live in a digital world.
Rym: analog clipping exists but it turns into a different kind of distortion that sucks but doesn't suck as much as digital distortion.
Scott: And we're not a metal band.
Scott: we're not going for intentional distortion right?
Rym: But basically however whatever microphone you're using whatever thing you're putting that signal into.
Rym: You want to make sure that the loudest sound you intend to put into it will not go above whatever red line your software has.
Rym: Because that is clipping and that's where literally the signal will not be processed.
Rym: If you record something and look at it in some software you'll see these like flat tops on the waves.
Scott: Right you think about a wave right?
Scott: The air is moving when I'm talking right?
Scott: It's a wave.
Scott: it's nice and you know regardless of what frequencies are in the wave it is you know up and down.
Scott: It has you know an amplitude.
Rym: But there's no maximum volume.
Scott: No I could get louder and louder and louder and louder until your eardrums break.
Scott: You might not be able to hear all the sounds.
Scott: maybe a dog can hear more of them but they're there.
Rym: In air there is an upper limit.
Rym: there you could have a sound so loud that it causes nuclear fusion.
Scott: That's true too.
Scott: That could theoretically happen.
Scott: You could also just blast all the air away so there's no air left.
Rym: Yep you get one big sound and then nothing.
Scott: Right but regardless of those ideas right there's not a lot of limit to how much and you know to what frequencies and how hard and fast.
Scott: I guess the air molecule can't move faster than the speed of light.
Scott: that's your limit.
Rym: So if you're recording to a physical medium like a record you can only stick the needle so deep into the vinyl before you go through it.
Rym: Yep and if you make your tolerances such that the loudest sound you could possibly record on earth will go as deep as you can go.
Rym: Then most of the sounds you're going to record will be so quiet they won't even scratch the record.
Scott: Right and if you have a computer recording the noise digitally you know you can only have it.
Scott: you know it's like how often am I going to write down onto this data?
Scott: right with bits zeros and ones the amplitude at a given point in time?
Scott: right.
Rym: The frequency is how often and the number of bits is how much?
Rym: how many gradations can you store.
Scott: Right it's only.
Scott: it's like just same things.
Scott: look at a high resolution image.
Scott: it's like I can use 64 bits.
Scott: I can write down a thousand bits.
Scott: 20,000 billion bits per microsecond right is a limit.
Scott: And that number of bits it's like.
Scott: well that's how many amplitudes I can represent.
Scott: if there's a sound that's even louder.
Scott: where I'm already I already wrote down all ones.
Scott: all ones is my loudest possible highest possible amplitude.
Scott: So what happens if a louder sound comes in than all ones?
Scott: A louder sound appears.
Scott: all I can do is write down all ones and you're just gonna hear even though there's a noise happening.
Scott: it's just gonna be the loudest possible.
Scott: constant noise is the flat ones.
Rym: Yep and even worse.
Rym: and the last point because we've gone long enough.
Rym: if you have more than one microphone and you record with all of them at the same time they could all the things you recorded could interfere with each other in a way that it didn't interfere in the real world.
Rym: Because you're well for reasons that we're out of time we've gone way over an hour.
Rym: That was an okay show I think.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon Patrons for this episode of GeekNights are... Ryan from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Dropenlander, Finn, Dread Lily Tenebrae, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, Thomas Hahn.
Rym: And now here's something that thanks to the Comedy Central television station when I was young is burned into my very soul.
Rym: I leave you with...
Scott: My lady.
Rym: she went downtown.
Rym: She bought some broccoli.
Scott: She running home.
Scott: She's jumping broccoli.
Rym: Jumping broccoli.
Scott: Jumping broccoli.
Rym: She jumping broccoli.
Rym: Jumping, she jumping, she jumping, she jumping, she jumping, she jumping, she jumping, she jumping, she jumping, she jumping, she jumping, she jumping, she jumping broccoli.
Scott: Eeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeee.