Rym: It's Wednesday, February 20th, 2019.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Tonight.
Rym: We review Dororo, the anime from 2019.
Rym: Not the one from the 60s.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So I had to do a thing that I got to do every now and then, but I will only have to do a relatively small number of times in my entire life.
Rym: I had to renew my passport.
Rym: No, I don't know.
Rym: We're gonna go--.
Scott: Don't you just go to the post office?
Rym: No.
Rym: Have you ever renewed a passport?
Scott: Yeah, I went to the post office.
Rym: Why?
Rym: You're not supposed-- So they've actually changed the process a bunch of times.
Scott: I did it one time.
Scott: I went to the post office.
Rym: So nowadays, the correct way to do it is to just mail it to them with a form and they'll just mail it back like that's the way you do it.
Scott: All right.
Scott: And the turnaround time-- And then they punch holes in it so you can't use the old one, right?
Scott: Well, yeah, they mail-- But they always give you back the old one.
Rym: Yeah, with a hole punched in it.
Scott: And with holes punched in it so you can't use it.
Scott: And it's like, why don't you just shred the old one?
Rym: Well, because one, people want it back for nostalgia purposes.
Rym: Maybe, but--.
Rym: Two, because the old one will often have unexpired visas in it if you're a world traveler.
Rym: And you can use the unexpired visa for many countries.
Scott: So you take two passports with you and you're like, here's my new passport.
Scott: Here's my old visa and my old passport.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So supposedly, if I want to fly to, say, Brazil tomorrow, I would bring both passports, the old one and the new one, because the old one has my life.
Scott: I mean, it's like, I don't know about most countries, I've seen passports.
Scott: They're like books with actually like, they're not like just stapled.
Scott: There's like a nice binding on there.
Rym: Yeah, my passport is just like a binding.
Scott: Yeah, there's no reason that they, since it's such a somewhat moderately fancy book, they couldn't take those pages of visas out of-- you're sending them the old one.
Scott: You got to have the old one to renew it.
Scott: Take the pages out of the old one and sell them into the new one.
Rym: One, there is actually international law and treaties about the conformance of passports that make that difficult.
Scott: That must be why they're also similar.
Rym: Two, so fun fact, normal passports have a certain number of pages.
Rym: And as you might know, I filled mine like three times.
Rym: So I kept having to get pages added to my passport.
Rym: Adding them is a giant pain in the ass.
Rym: And it basically comes-- They're on special paper.
Rym: Well, it comes back to you with these two sets of pages like sewn into the passport and all these special notes in the passport that are like, yeah, fucking pages were added.
Rym: This is legit.
Rym: These pages are real, dude.
Rym: And it was a pain.
Rym: So luckily when I renewed, I'd been told by my guy that you can't get the thick passport anymore.
Rym: That was a lie.
Rym: I got the thick passport.
Scott: I haven't had to get any stamps because most of the countries I go to are just put your passport in the machine and then walk through.
Rym: Yeah, you know, it's funny.
Rym: Actually, most of the places I go are like that, too.
Rym: But I went to Turkey like ten goddamn times.
Scott: Oh, so you needed ten pages for ten turkeys.
Rym: And it wasn't because technically you're only supposed to get stamps for one country per page, though a lot of places just ignore that.
Rym: I didn't know that.
Scott: I thought I thought they were supposed to go in order, but they always just like go in a random place.
Scott: They just open up to a random page stamp.
Scott: Don't even try to get it in the squares.
Scott: There's like four squares on a page.
Scott: They don't stay in the squares.
Scott: They're just like, man, whatever.
Rym: So some like Germany was like hyper strict about it.
Rym: So Germany, I have a page.
Scott: The German would put the stamp right side up with the perfect amount of ink in the perfectly centered within the box.
Rym: I have a bunch of pages in a row that are all just Germany in Germany out Germany in Germany out.
Rym: That's far on the page.
Rym: Next page, Germany in Germany out.
Rym: But then, like in the middle of one of those is a fucking Canadian stand just like right in the middle.
Rym: Why would you get a Canadian stamp if you go to Canada?
Rym: They don't care.
Scott: I thought you could just like show your passport and you're like, oh, OK, goodbye.
Rym: Well, I flew to Canada and I've flown to Canada several times.
Rym: And they're just like Canada cares.
Rym: They give the least fucks of anyone in terms of where they stamp.
Rym: As far as I don't see any reason.
Scott: I guess even if I was going to go to Vancouver, I feel like I would fly to Seattle and then go to Vancouver.
Rym: So I have one page in my passport that has Japan, Costa Rica, Turkey, Canada, London and Australia, like all just stamped all over the place.
Rym: It's kind of Australia didn't stamp.
Rym: Yeah, they.
Rym: I've been to Australia a bunch more times than you.
Rym: Sometimes they stamp me.
Rym: Sometimes they don't.
Scott: I bought that.
Rym: I got the what our visa, but Turkey was tough because Turkey had to get the stamps, but I also had to keep getting visas because they only lasted like six months.
Rym: I had to keep buying visas and you buy the.
Rym: it was kind of a scam.
Rym: Like for Brazil, like you go to the consulate and be like, I want a Brazilian visa and you do a bunch of crap and they give you what looks like an entire passport inside of your passport just for Brazil.
Rym: And it lasts like 10 years.
Rym: But Turkey, you go in and they will take 20 euros.
Rym: They'll take 20 American dollars.
Rym: They'll take 20 pounds.
Scott: They don't really care when you should give 20 of the shittiest currency, obviously.
Scott: Why would you give 20 pounds?
Scott: You great.
Scott: Well, so pounds might become the shittiest currency.
Scott: Well, yeah.
Rym: So I mean, I don't know.
Rym: All I know is I go your pounds and they'd be like 20 and I'm like, OK, and I give them 20 bucks and with cash and they would literally just put a Turkish visa there, like no questions asked.
Rym: They didn't even look at me.
Rym: It was it was basically just a tax.
Rym: every time I came into the country.
Rym: The one the few times I came back and I already had a visa, they were shocked that I already had a visa.
Rym: And I had to, like, keep explaining, no, I already have a visa.
Rym: It's still good stamp.
Rym: I don't need to give you 20 more dollars.
Rym: But so I got my passport back.
Rym: And if you're worried about the turnaround time, like if I mail it and it comes back, what if I have to travel or something?
Scott: You should be doing the shit way in advance.
Scott: Too many people do it at the last second.
Scott: It's like how often is international travel truly a surprise emergency?
Rym: Well, the situation that often comes up is you literally travel internationally, like every single month.
Scott: So you need so what you have to like, take a break in order to renew.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Or if you pay the little bit of extra money for an expedited process, they said like, oh, it'll reduce the time by a little bit.
Scott: I heard it's bullshit.
Rym: So I actually did it.
Rym: I paid the extra because I had to take four days.
Rym: Oh, I mailed it express because I didn't cost anything.
Rym: It got there the next week.
Rym: The passport just came back like done.
Scott: I mean, when I renewed, it didn't take long at all.
Scott: And I did the normal way.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But if you need it in a hurry and you pay for the express, it had it's like instant like it turned out much as it cost extra like 30 or 40 bucks.
Scott: Oh, that's not bad.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But I guess only do it if you're in a hurry because still 30, 40 bucks you could buy.
Scott: But nice dinner, 30, 40 bucks.
Rym: That's that's what I did.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Depending on where you're eating.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, it depends really outside of New York.
Rym: That's like 10 nice dinners like upstate in Pennsylvania.
Rym: That's like that's like a month's rent and a month's worth of food.
Rym: But so here's the crazy thing where I'm getting to my opening bit and then we'll do the real show.
Rym: So the craziest thing happens.
Rym: I then had to go to this like federal government portal to update my trusted traveler stuff.
Rym: So I keep getting like my skip customs thing to work.
Rym: And because my company paid for it like before.
Rym: So I just have it.
Rym: But every time you're near your passport, you got to go into this thing and tell them your new passport number.
Rym: And I assume if I lie, they'll find out.
Rym: So I put the real passport number in there.
Rym: I didn't want to like come back from a foreign country, try to use try to skip customs and get stopped and have not followed the rules.
Rym: So I did this and I go to this old, you know, it's a federal government site in the United States.
Rym: It's a piece of shit.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Like it like you have to make a password.
Scott: That's like I went to the Secret Service, not Secret Service.
Scott: I was social security.
Rym: I was about to ask you a question to the Social Security website recently.
Scott: Just, you know, check it out because you log in there once in a while.
Rym: Not great.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, it worked, but it's not.
Scott: it's better than a 90s website, but it is not good.
Scott: So I've had similar experiences with the Treasury website.
Rym: So I have no chance.
Scott: A lot of security on it.
Rym: Oh, I had to use the Treasury website in two thousand and I was bonding it up.
Rym: Yeah, I was.
Scott: So I had the only reason a normal person would go there to get bond action.
Rym: So I went there when I had to do something weird.
Scott: Maybe I'll go buy some bonds.
Rym: I had a bunch of class like the good bonds, the double I think the good bond.
Scott: I had the kinds of people gave me as gifts and I wanted to turn them into money.
Rym: Basically, people our age had a certain kind of bond.
Rym: I think it was the double.
Scott: But I don't buy those for kids.
Rym: I assume so.
Rym: But they pretty much suck now.
Scott: I mean, yeah.
Scott: Who wants to invest in the U.S.
Scott: government?
Rym: No, it's not double.
Rym: It's something before that.
Rym: Whatever.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Scott: The point is, Treasury website me.
Rym: Anyway, I had like all these bonds and I cashed them all before I went to RIT to buy a computer.
Rym: All the bonds I got my entire life basically bought me one computer.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Because I spent like four grand on this thing in the year 2000.
Rym: But two of my bonds I could not cash in because I'm not old enough.
Rym: No.
Rym: When they were all mature, they were actually worth it.
Rym: Like they were worth a lot of money.
Scott: Too old?
Rym: Uh, when they were purchased in the 80s, the bank just didn't fucking stamp them the right way.
Rym: Like they were they were stamped wrong.
Rym: So I had to go to the Treasury website and do a ridiculous amount of nonsense.
Rym: It would have been easier to tear them up, throw them away and claim they were lost than to get the bonds I actually had corrected.
Scott: All I had to do is go to the website, type in some numbers.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And I didn't need the piece of paper anymore.
Scott: Those bonds were now digital.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And then I could do whatever.
Rym: So I went to this government portal that I remember being a nightmare.
Rym: And when I go to it, it says, oh, we got rid of that portal.
Rym: You got to go over here to this other way more complicated portal now.
Rym: So I go there and it just worked automatically.
Rym: My account was just there.
Rym: Everything worked.
Rym: And as soon as I made my new account, it was like, Mr.
Rym: Decoster, welcome to the portal.
Rym: Before you continue, you should set up two factor authentication.
Scott: Yeah, they have to.
Scott: Even though the sites are so black, even the crappy Social Security one has, you know, two factor auth of some kind.
Scott: But it wasn't even like the Google kind with some other kind.
Rym: It wasn't the other kind.
Rym: I had the other kind if you sucked.
Rym: But it was like, yo, T.O.T.P.
Rym: I scanned the barcode just work.
Rym: Google auth auth.
Rym: Good to go.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I was shocked that I really need the Google auth app to.
Scott: There's really two features that I need in the Google auth app that it doesn't have.
Rym: Back it up so I could like.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Feature one, I buy a new phone.
Scott: Let me move everything to my new phone.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And feature two, I got way too many sites in there now.
Rym: Let me say favorites.
Scott: Let me like set favorites and search and organize them.
Rym: Yeah, because I got like 12 in there.
Scott: I got way more than that.
Scott: Let me count.
Rym: Well, because I work doesn't use it.
Rym: I'm my own authenticator for work now.
Rym: So the only things I use it for are my own AWS account.
Rym: My Google stuff, three, four, like Amazon regular, like regular Amazon that you buy stuff on.
Rym: Are some of those work?
Rym: The nice forum, I guess I use it for twenty six.
Scott: And yes, some of them are work.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I used to have like eight just for work, but now I work at a place where we roll our own and I have like this fancy hardware three factor thing.
Rym: I don't need my phone.
Scott: I work.
Scott: All the things we use are like cloud services, like, you know, Google and Jira.
Scott: And so I have.
Scott: Yeah, I have a lot of doubles.
Scott: It's like I got like Amazon Web Services, personal Amazon.
Scott: Services work.
Rym: In fact, it was personal work at my old job.
Rym: I had personal Amazon services, Slack, personal Slack work.
Rym: I had work production, Amazon Web Services.
Rym: Then I had work non-production, Amazon Web Services, three accounts.
Rym: OK, but now I work for a company that's so big, like we roll our own everything.
Rym: So anyway.
Rym: So, yeah, that was interesting.
Rym: Anyway, it's anime day, right?
Scott: So in the anime news, there was an anime movie in theaters that you usually say, hey, this anime movie in theaters, go see it.
Rym: So wait a minute, wait a minute, though, I'm going to qualify that.
Rym: We usually say I'm going to paraphrase our own advice.
Rym: If it's an anime movie that is not a sequel to an existing anime movie, like Pokemon Movie 10 or One Piece Movie seven or whatever it is, then and it's not a compilation hundred and is not a compilation movie.
Rym: Always go see it in the theater.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So Mobile Suit Gundam NT narrative.
Scott: narrative is like short for NT is short for narrative, not for Windows.
Scott: NT was in the theaters.
Rym: I'm actually less interested in this.
Scott: already based on this movie supposedly covers the events of like one of the Gundam Unicorn novels.
Scott: And it happens like after the regular Gundam Unicorn series.
Scott: But before the Gundam series.
Scott: Anyway, I don't understand where exactly it takes place.
Rym: It takes place in UC 0096.
Scott: OK, so way after Gundam Unicorn.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, Gundam Unicorn is OK, I guess whatever.
Scott: But yeah, I have not seen this.
Scott: I'm not going to see it, but I've seen a lot of people on Twitter comment on it.
Scott: And normally I wouldn't take such comments as truth.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Usually if people say something's good or bad, I just believe them because everybody's wrong.
Scott: But the opinion is so unanimous and so believable.
Scott: Based on one of my personal experiences, plausibility with other Gundam things that I must relay it to you as if it were true, because I would bet money that it is true.
Scott: and what people are saying is that Gundam NT is a Gundam movie and glowing review.
Rym: And it is incomprehensible, even to people steeped in Gundam lore and tradition, because Gundam F91 makes no goddamn sense unless you know about Gundam.
Scott: The best tweet I saw said Gundam NT was I should.
Scott: they said.
Scott: they said, why would I watch Gundam NT when I can watch Gundam F91?
Scott: And I said, whoa, whoa, is this person about to say something positive about Gundam F91?
Rym: Because you may recall we reviewed Gundam F91 a long time ago when it came out on DVD.
Scott: But anyway, they said, why would I watch Gundam NT when I can watch Gundam F91?
Scott: It's just as incomprehensible, but at least it looks really good.
Scott: So I, Gundam NT, even if I got Gundam, nice try, Gundam nice try.
Scott: But yeah, if you know a lot about Gundam, you might be able to understand something that's happening in this, but it might not still, it still might not be worth it.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And if you don't know anything about Gundam, this movie will mean nothing to you.
Scott: Just go watch a regular Gundam.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Like the original one, or maybe Gundam Seed or Gundam Wing or something.
Rym: I feel like the last Gundam.
Scott: This might even, I don't know.
Scott: I haven't seen it, so I can't say for sure.
Scott: But I mean, it could be worse than G Gundam.
Scott: At least G Gundam is crazy.
Rym: At least the G Gundam is good at being what it is.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, anyway, so yeah.
Scott: Avoid Gundam NT in the movie theater.
Scott: If you must see it, I guess wait till you can watch it for free somewhere.
Rym: I'm curious now, because I feel like there's two classes of Gundams.
Rym: in terms of what was the last, there's a lot of classes of Gundams, in terms of what was the last good one.
Scott: I mean, you know, the class one is there was a Gundam, the origin thing recently ish.
Scott: There was a some blooded orphan thing.
Scott: I don't know what that was about.
Rym: I guess I break them up.
Scott: Gundam Build Diver, which is for a certain group of people.
Rym: What was the last Gundam that was good?
Rym: If you care a lot about Gundam and what is the last Gundam that was good?
Rym: If you are aware of Gundam, but don't care that much about it, I mean, I feel like for the latter, Gundam seed might still be the last.
Scott: That's just the last one you saw and know about and care about.
Rym: I saw a bunch of unicorn and I just didn't.
Rym: I couldn't.
Rym: I didn't care.
Rym: It just was all right.
Scott: It was good.
Rym: It just I didn't care about.
Scott: I don't watch it.
Scott: Good ish.
Rym: I think that my problem with gonna unicorn is it had too much talking about Gundam.
Scott: Isn't that every Gundam?
Rym: Yeah, but like say Gundam seed had a lot of talking about Gundam, but it also had a lot of fire of the low and greens.
Rym: But no, that's not every Gundam.
Rym: Gundam, the OAVs like War in the Pocket is look at this child experiencing the horrors of war.
Rym: Yeah, they don't talk a lot about Gundams and those are not like full Gundam series or movies.
Scott: Yeah, they're like OAVs.
Rym: But I don't know.
Rym: I just I don't feel like there's been a Gundam that people have talked about super positively since unicorn.
Rym: And I feel like a lot of people kind of fell off the Gundam train if they were even getting on that train after seed, maybe because destiny put a bad taste in the medicine.
Scott: If you know, if you if you know a lot about Gundam, you don't need Gundam advice from us.
Scott: If you don't know anything about Gundam, just watch Gundam seed and or the original fucking Gundam.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And then all the other a set of the OAV slash mini series movies.
Rym: If you're that into it, I think we're in the pocket is we're?
Rym: we're in the pocket.
Rym: A.M.S.
Rym: team like that stuff's all worth watching.
Scott: Those are only two things.
Scott: Yeah, those those two just to do two kinds, two kinds.
Rym: Cut it out.
Rym: So in some other news of a movie we have not seen, I assumed from the beginning, from the earliest talk of they're going there being a live action Alita Battle Angel movie, like a non anime remake.
Rym: I assumed it wasn't going to happen because this gets announced for every anime property.
Rym: How many Cowboy Bebop remakes have been announced and not made?
Scott: Well, OK, so first of all, there's a long history of people wanting to optioning, trying to make live action Americanized versions of anime movies.
Scott: They have done it a few times.
Scott: For example, that goes in the show movie.
Scott: that was supposedly awful.
Scott: I didn't see it and I won't.
Scott: But this one is different in that I was a Cameron is not the Terminator guy, I think, right?
Scott: I'm pretty sure that's the guy anyway.
Scott: Famous director guy.
Scott: I think it was a Terminator directing guy, but it might be I'm wrong about you.
Rym: type in James Cameron.
Rym: Alita literally got recommend.
Scott: I was right.
Scott: All right.
Scott: That guy must have read the Alita manga at some point.
Scott: I have it actually digital because you can get a digital way cheap.
Rym: And he got obsessed with it.
Scott: No, I haven't read it yet.
Scott: But not you.
Scott: This guy read it.
Scott: He read it a long time ago when I guess it must have first come out in English, which is actually a long time ago, and became obsessed with it and has wanted to make a movie of it for a long ass time.
Scott: And he has kept trying and it was constantly in the nerd news.
Scott: This guy wants to make this Alita movie.
Scott: This is happening.
Scott: He's trying.
Scott: He's trying real hard.
Scott: He's doing this other thing.
Scott: He's trying hard.
Rym: Listen, James Cameron, I got a manga that you should read called Sanctuary.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I don't think that's his kind of movie.
Rym: Now who we need.
Rym: We need the snatch guy to read sanctuary.
Rym: Oh, gosh.
Scott: It would be rated X, though, I would watch.
Rym: I would I would see that I would watch in the theater.
Scott: It's also the exact opposite of what is what is good in the work.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, you want to show Mr.
Scott: Tokai in twenty nineteen audience.
Rym: I feel like you take a. you make it a spiritual remake, not a line for line.
Scott: I think you would have to definitely erase Mr.
Scott: Tokai's existence.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You changed some of that anyway.
Rym: Anyway.
Scott: But yeah.
Scott: So it's somewhat of a miracle that despite, you know, so few of these actually being made, the ones that are made are awful and I avoid them.
Scott: This one was made.
Scott: It's in theaters now and much the opposite of Gundam NT.
Scott: Everything I see on Twitter is positive, which is freaky.
Rym: Even the fact that when the early shots came out like the earliest, like, wow, it's actually getting made and she had like the anime.
Scott: I guess she has these weird and it's canonical because that's the way the robot's made.
Rym: So apparently, against all expectation, this movie is good on its own.
Scott: I have not seen it.
Scott: It could be those people could be wrong, but I don't entirely believe.
Rym: the people I trust have said that it is both good on its own and good as being an anime like live action remake movie.
Scott: So it was upgraded from never watch like Ghost in the Shell live action.
Rym: You will watch on two.
Scott: We'll watch at some point.
Scott: Probably not going to go to the theater.
Rym: Yeah, but I will see this movie.
Rym: I am.
Scott: Some day I'll be sitting there and I like turn on my, you know, HDBC and open to the Netflix app and the icon will be there.
Scott: This is like I'll be like, oh, nothing to do.
Rym: I'll watch this.
Rym: So in some last news, so we don't go to Katsucon anymore.
Scott: We haven't been there in a long time.
Rym: The last time we went to Katsucon, we were on the staff and helped run and like emcee the arcade that it had before it was in the Gaylord when it was literally an entirely different convention.
Rym: It says Katsucon today is a ship of Theseus from the Katsucon we staffed.
Scott: That is true.
Scott: The arcade at the Katsucons that we went to was similar to the arcade of Magfest at the time.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: Magfest obviously was focused on arcade and gaming and expanded that tremendously.
Rym: But there was a time when Katsucon had an arcade.
Scott: It was in a similar location on Earth, same city, same general area.
Scott: But that wasn't their focus.
Scott: And I don't think they have that anymore.
Rym: Like seriously, this anime con had an arcade that to this back then, back in like 2000, like seven.
Rym: This arcade was better than at this anime con than any PAX arcade has ever been.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I had more fun in that Katsucon arcade for those two times.
Scott: we did it, I think, even though it was sick one time.
Scott: Then in the Magfest arcade at the first Magfest we went to in the shady hotel, I do think that Magfest arcade had more quantity of games, but the quality of games was not as high.
Rym: So Katsucon is a like large, gigantic, well-run anime convention today.
Rym: It's one of the big like cosplay anime cons.
Rym: Like cosplay is a big focus at Katsucon.
Scott: It is the number one focus of Katsucon far and away.
Rym: Like even relative to other major anime conventions.
Scott: They made it.
Scott: That gazebo is famous not because of cosplay photos from Magfest, but because of cosplay photos from Katsucon.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Now we are now in the same building, by the way, these two conventions.
Rym: We don't go just because.
Rym: They were not originally.
Rym: I mean, we stopped going to anime Boston because of the security nonsense.
Rym: The only reason.
Scott: Also, it's just a pain in the ass to go to Boston in the spring for three days to do like two panels.
Rym: The reason we don't go to Katsucon is because Katsucon is in the thick of like our busiest conventions season already.
Rym: Like it would have been this past weekend.
Rym: Like we.
Rym: well, we realized that we go to like four ish, four to five packs a year.
Rym: And they're actually all in a pretty short span of time.
Scott: They're really like, well, it's basically everything is when it's cold and in the summer we don't do nothing.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: We got to go to PAX in September, October, if we go to us, November, January, March and then back around to September.
Rym: So Katsucon is in the same venue as Magfest and Katsucon announced something and did something really interesting and really amazing.
Rym: I am shocked and surprised that they were able to pull this off and Magfest needs to do this.
Scott: You have to hundred percent to understand what's going on.
Scott: You sort of have to look at a floor plan if you haven't been there.
Scott: But basically, you have this big ass hotel, right?
Scott: And then at the cross to the big lobby and there's this huge downstairs area with all this like a little Christmas village, this giant gazebo area, this restaurant area.
Scott: And then once you get to the back of the lobby is like this area where there's like stores that sell like jewelry and clothing and and there's a spa.
Scott: And you go through this tunnel where the stores on the other side of this short tunnel past the hotel elevators is the convention center.
Scott: So there's sort of like this straight line across the building where it's like you're in the hotel side, you're in the convention center side, but it's a really short tunnel.
Scott: And because the lobbies are so huge and there's all these other vast areas where the gazebo is on the hotel side.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And there's actually ballrooms and stuff on the right behind that gazebo.
Scott: Guess what?
Scott: There's like a ballroom where there's all kinds of it's like a main panel room for breakfast.
Rym: Right now, this is a. this is one of those like issues, concerns that only exists for some of the largest of the fan can write.
Scott: paxies doesn't have this problem because what paxies is?
Scott: one giant building.
Scott: Yes, one.
Scott: It's just one big rectangle.
Scott: The end.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Now, there is actually a hotel directly connected to paxies, but it's got this skywalk.
Scott: So you basically are.
Rym: Well, here's the more important part.
Rym: That hotel has no convention programming in it.
Rym: None.
Rym: And is entirely distinct as an entity from the hotel.
Rym: Or from the convention center for purposes of pax.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But this is a common situation where the largest conventions tend to have a hotel convention center combo where significant portions of the convention center space overlap with the hotel or are technically public areas like anime, anime.
Scott: Boston has stuff in the Sheraton.
Scott: Yeah, it's like a mall in between a shopping mall, a public shopping mall between the convention.
Scott: Pax West, the convention center is a mall with like restaurants.
Scott: Here's what this means.
Rym: The convention staff cannot require a badge for someone to be in one of those public areas.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So like if there's some, you know, people who would go to, say, anime Boston and we're just going to do cosplay stuff in, say, the shopping mall or the Sheraton lobby, anime Boston can't really stop them.
Scott: Those are public places.
Scott: If someone goes to Pax West, they don't check your badge like at the entrance to the convention because the convention center is legally public space.
Scott: It's a public mall.
Scott: It's a shopping mall.
Scott: What if you want to go in and wait in a super long line with a bunch of pax goers to buy a Subway sandwich
Rym: so they can only check
Scott: the badges at these glass doors at the top of the escalators that separate that shopping mall zone from the expo hall area?
Rym: So Katsucon has had a problem for a long now.
Rym: Lobby conning, if you've never not familiar with this term, is a perfectly valid fan practice.
Rym: The idea is, say, you go to conventions mostly to hang out with your friends, play games like hotel party, whatever, and maybe only a subset of your friends actually go into the convention to like go to panels and stuff.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Or maybe so only a few of your friends, you know, you want to do things at different times.
Scott: You share some badges, save some money.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, it's like it's a perfectly valid thing to do.
Scott: It's not in itself wrong or should be banned entirely.
Scott: So if I happen to know that even in non nerdy conventions, maybe you go to a tech conference with charges, an arm and a leg, you don't care about the content.
Scott: You're just there to network.
Scott: So you hang out in the hotel bar the whole time networking.
Rym: Here's what I used to do.
Rym: I used to go to trade tech Paris every year.
Rym: It is really fucking expensive to go to trade tech Paris.
Scott: But your company, your company would pay for.
Rym: Well, yeah, but even then, it's really expensive.
Rym: So what we would do is I'd get a badge for like one day to actually go into trade tech Paris.
Rym: But I'd stay in a hotel and hang out around trade tech Paris for like the entire week because all the people I need to talk to are in town at the same time.
Scott: You have private meetings with them in other places.
Rym: Like I know some people who will go to Magfest, not buy a badge, never even go into the Gaylord.
Rym: And they literally just get drunk and hang out and party in their hotel room with all their friends and some of whom are going into Magfest.
Scott: They're going there because a bunch of people are going to be in this area that they want to see.
Scott: So lobby counting is the practice of going to the city and or hotel where a convention is to go near a convention because you want to hang out with the people who are going to that convention.
Scott: But you yourself do not want to go.
Rym: Totally OK to do this.
Rym: However, at the Gaylord, it for various reasons, conventions that are there have a problem in that a lot of people will lobby con and a lot of those people will completely fill the technically public areas of the convention center space and generally be a nuisance, get in the way, cause fire code issues, harass people, et cetera.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's to the point where so many people are doing it, but actually going to the lobby there, a getting convention content without paying.
Scott: You know, they've crossed that line.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They are interfering with the operation of the convention and they're harming the safety of the people who did pay for the convention.
Scott: So if you go to a convention, you expect that convention, you know, there's an expectation these days.
Scott: the convention will provide for your security at the convention.
Scott: You need to feel safe there or you're not going to go.
Scott: The convention.
Scott: really only thing they can do if people don't break the law is take people's badges away and kick them out.
Scott: You can't really do anything to someone who's not breaking the law, maybe just hanging around being a jerk.
Scott: What can you do to them?
Scott: Not much.
Rym: If they don't have a badge, the best you can do is get the venue to trespass them.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But that is hard to do to people who don't have badges or in the hotel.
Scott: There are a wide variety of behaviors that would not get you kicked out of a hotel lobby, but also would not send you to jail and all you can.
Scott: But you're still a bad person.
Rym: You kicked out of packs.
Scott: Right, exactly.
Scott: And those behaviors are exhibited a lot by people going to hotel lobbies, especially nerd cons.
Rym: So Kazukan did something that I didn't know was an option.
Rym: I did not.
Scott: And I've never heard of this before either.
Rym: So I knew about this was happening at Kazukan, but now we saw the result.
Rym: I'm going to read their own press conference.
Rym: Too long.
Scott: Don't read it all.
Rym: No, just the beginning of it.
Rym: Kazukan, in coordination with the Gaylord National, have made the decision for Kazukan to be what is called a "closed profile
Rym: event.".
Rym: This means that for the duration of the convention, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, the hotel and convention center will only be accessible to either people wearing or in the process of obtaining a Kazukan badge or registered guests of the resort itself.
Rym: Full stop.
Scott: Or guests with confirmed restaurant or spa appointment.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: I was I was wondering, I'm like, is the restaurant going to be upset?
Scott: Apparently you can go to the restaurant if you have a reservation.
Scott: You can't just walk in to go try to wait in line at the restaurant.
Rym: So what that means is that now convention staff, Kazukan staff, can be in that area.
Rym: And if someone's pulling some bullshit, they can kick them out of the convention.
Scott: Or at the very least, if it's a hotel guest who doesn't have a badge to Kazukan, they just they just bought a hotel room.
Scott: They can at least report them to the hotel.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: This magfest needs this desperately.
Rym: I'm glad that Kazukan did it.
Rym: And so far, it seems like the only people who are mad about this policy are a huge number of cosplayers who have been used taking photos inside of the convention center in that gazebo area for years without buying badges and the photographers who would follow them in to do this.
Rym: So now all these photographers and all these cosplayers are really, really mad about this and had to buy Kazukan badges.
Scott: Yeah, good.
Scott: Buy some badges.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You're mooching off the convention here.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: This is a step beyond lobby conning.
Rym: This is like con squatting at this point because of the blended public private spaces of the largest events, etc.
Rym: Anyway, you can read more about it.
Rym: Kazukan, I'm glad you did this.
Rym: Magfest, please, for the love of everything.
Scott: I'm curious how much.
Scott: I'm curious how much extra you got to pay to get that service.
Rym: I have a feeling that due to so one, I already ran into a lot of drunk shit ass white boy bros at magfest this past year who were complaining that they couldn't get into the arcade without a badge.
Rym: Yeah, I, based on my own personal anecdotal experience, believe that a huge percentage of the people causing the problem at magfest are only causing the problem in those public spaces and do not have badges.
Scott: If those people, maybe not legit ones.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: If those people could not get into the Gaylord at all, I think magfest would have a lot less of the problem.
Scott: Magfest would be way better in general.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: So it couldn't hurt.
Rym: It could not hurt, but only help.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day, what do you got?
Scott: I was just sitting around today, you know, just thinking about programming.
Scott: Cause that's what I do all fucking day.
Scott: And I, you know, my brain, I forget how it arrived at this thought, but I was thinking about, you know, programming for like old computers or consoles and whatever.
Scott: And if my brain was thinking like, you know, yeah, I know an NES game is generally structured kind of right.
Scott: I know like the limitations of the system, like how an Atari game sort of is programmed.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then my brain was just like, I don't know how the fucking arcade game, not like a new arcade game.
Scott: Well, not new, but like, you know, and how like a dig dug works, like how the hell is a street fighter to work?
Scott: Like what if I wanted to like make a game like a ROM that ran on the same hardware as street fighter to what the fuck does that like?
Scott: So I just Googled, I typed in like street fighters, you source code.
Scott: I'm like, it's probably online somewhere.
Scott: And I didn't find that I found a blog of someone trying to reverse engineer street fighter two.
Scott: And there's a terrific article on this blog about the AI of street fighter two.
Scott: And I was like, that's something I always wanted to know, but didn't think of to look.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Cause like the AIs and dig dug pretty simple Pac-Man pretty simple.
Rym: How does Ryu like get you?
Scott: Right.
Scott: So now I read this and it was fascinating.
Scott: And I have learned more about the AI of street fighter two than I knew I wanted, but I definitely wanted.
Rym: And wow, I can, you can use crappy methods like this to make some pretty good AI, I guess expert systems and basic, like if then trees with pseudo randomizers, not bad solutions to a lot of problems.
Scott: Anyway, it's really fast.
Scott: It's also fast.
Scott: It also answered an age old question of how does guile do that flash kick without ducking?
Scott: He must be cheating.
Scott: Answer.
Scott: He is cheating.
Scott: A human being has to duck for two seconds to do a flash kick, but, uh, you know, guile controlled by the AI does not.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So I've been mad about this for a long time and I was thinking about it the other day and sure enough, our good friend who is not captain disillusion, but looks a little bit like him, depending on the angle you look at him, technology connections, he a great youtube channel.
Rym: I've linked to them every now and then.
Rym: He did a tear down of space heaters called space heater nonsense, where he's mad about the same goddamn thing I'm mad about.
Scott: What are you mad about?
Scott: I thought your favorite thing to be mad about regarding space heaters is why did they just exist?
Scott: Just use a computer.
Scott: It's also 100% efficient at producing heat.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So it's, it's adjacent to that.
Rym: I don't want to get into my like, use your computer as a space heater, but what I would like to get into is Scott.
Rym: What makes you say you want to get a space heater?
Rym: Like you might've bought one at some point in your life.
Rym: What makes one of them better than another one?
Scott: Better than another one.
Rym: How can one space heater possibly be better or different than another space here?
Scott: I guess it could be bigger, right?
Scott: So it could heat up a bigger room.
Rym: So how could a bigger space heater heat up a bigger room?
Scott: Uh, kind of like fans on it and stuff to help distribute the heat around the room.
Rym: How could a fan cause a speed?
Rym: So there is literally no matter how big, no matter how many fans, lack of fans, no matter what you do, all electric space heaters have the exact same amount of heat they can produce and thus can heat any room of any size, the same amount, full stop.
Rym: There's no fucking difference.
Rym: Nothing you do matters.
Scott: You can.
Scott: So let's say that it's, you know, it got a space here in the corner.
Scott: All right.
Scott: It's using, of course it's turning all the electricity that comes out of the holes into heat with a hundred percent efficiency.
Rym: So there's a max on that.
Rym: The amount of BTUs based on American electrical systems, right?
Scott: So now, you know, the, the area around the space heater, if it's just say a hot coil, right?
Scott: The area around the space heater will be quite hot here on the opposite side of the room.
Scott: You will still be quite cold, right?
Scott: Ah, there's only fan to sort of not move the heat, but to you move the air, right?
Scott: So now the room is now heating more evenly, right?
Scott: Instead of being hot in the corner and cold in the opposite corner, you can get that air moving, right?
Scott: Cause the convection won't really happen too much.
Rym: So the room as a whole will not get warmer and added at any at a different rates.
Scott: No.
Scott: And in fact, the opposite side of the room will be warmer sooner potentially, but not in any meaningful way for space heaters because the overall temperature of the room will not rise somehow to a higher temperature at the end.
Rym: Space heaters can't output enough heat for that fandom matter in any reasonably sized room.
Rym: They don't output that much heat.
Rym: There's a pretty low limit on how much heat they can output it.
Scott: I guess you can make a space heater that plugs into more outlets at once.
Scott: That is illegal.
Scott: I'm aware, but you could do it.
Rym: So you could plug in more space heaters.
Rym: A lot of space heaters try to argue that they're designed for a large room versus a small room or they're designed for efficiency.
Rym: That's all made up bullshit.
Rym: They all have a BTU rating.
Rym: That's it full stop.
Rym: And in fact, if you have a fan, you might say, Oh, maybe the fan takes away some of the energy that would go into making heat, but that fan will itself, all the energy, the fan is going to move the air will also generate heat.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: The only possible difference between a space, two space heaters you plug in would be if they're going to heat the air in the room via convection or ran a heating coil, or are they going to generate an infrared spotlight that you're going to point at your own body.
Scott: because infrared heaters, are there ones that do that?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I never heard of that.
Scott: I guess it would totally work.
Rym: Let me find a picture of one red space.
Scott: I mean, why don't not just get like, uh, you know, a lamp.
Rym: They basically are a lamp that you point at yourself.
Rym: All right.
Rym: And they will give you cancer.
Rym: No, they will basically warm you up at the expense of warming up the room.
Rym: They will not warm up the room.
Scott: So if the room is losing, you got to aim it at you.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Aim it at you.
Rym: You will feel warm, even though the room itself is not actually make a transparent slash translucent chair that has lamps all under it.
Rym: That's not a bad idea.
Scott: Just saying, it'll be like, it'll be sort of like heated seats in the car.
Scott: Only, uh, possibly safer because it just lamps and not, you know, I don't know, not the heated seats in a car or a danger.
Scott: I don't even know.
Scott: I've never seen anyone like, Oh my God, my heated car seat set on fire.
Scott: That's never happened.
Rym: That's the only possible argument one could make is that shittier space heaters are more likely to catch on fire and or kill you because they're shittier.
Scott: That is very true.
Rym: Like cheaper components.
Scott: Extremely true.
Rym: So anyway, this video is 20 minutes.
Scott: Like the one that you can plug into two hours at once.
Rym: Well, like my old DOS keyboard that had to plug into two USB ports at once.
Scott: I've had keyboards like that.
Rym: That is bad news.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: That is against the USB spec.
Rym: Anyway, this video is 20 minutes of explaining this in the meta moment.
Rym: We are going to be live at PAX East in like 36 days.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Doing a panel on Friday called the real harm of game.
Scott: I started to outline it.
Rym: I found some Nora citations we can use.
Rym: I found some stories and anecdotes and things.
Scott: Send me that then.
Rym: I will.
Rym: Uh, otherwise we are book club book 2001 A Space Odyssey.
Rym: I am.
Scott: I am due to finish reading this book tomorrow.
Rym: There is a good chance Thursday next week we will do the book club book episode on 2000. after all this time I'm going to start reading.
Scott: It took me like no time to read it.
Scott: Also, I'm gonna.
Scott: my goal is to stick with my kindle train strategy and never stop.
Scott: Like if I read all the books I have in the kindle app, buy more books because you can only raise for so much galaxy to stop playing games on my phone on the train entirely, hopefully.
Scott: But of course, by summer, my reading might go down as I bike instead of subway.
Rym: So let's get it right to our main bit.
Rym: We got.
Rym: there was a manga by the great Osamu Jessica called Dororo.
Scott: I read it when it came out in English, published by vertical.
Scott: That was a while ago.
Scott: I remember too much.
Scott: I only remember the basics from reading it.
Scott: Uh, but this manga was adapted into an anime way back in the day.
Rym: And I want to say 1969.
Scott: It's one of those manga that's sort of like on this like semi fame level where like it's it's known but not super.
Rym: no like manga comic people will know.
Scott: But like average American anime that I'm really curious like what percentage of Japanese people will know it if you just bring it up.
Scott: But they know what you're talking about.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Like how known is it there?
Scott: Yep.
Scott: 1969.
Scott: Obviously not as known as Astro, but not unknown.
Rym: Anyway, the manga was made.
Rym: It was, you know, it was a testicle moderately famous that in 1969 a black and white anime was made.
Rym: Uh, I've never seen it.
Rym: I know almost nothing about it.
Rym: All I can say is that there is, in fact, an anime news network article about it and it has very high ratings among the 15 people who have seen it.
Scott: So anyway, they came out this season.
Scott: We judged anime and I noticed while we were judging anime, by the way, judge anime by its cover next episode, we're going to do.
Scott: The next season starts in early April, PAX East of the last week of March.
Scott: So probably like right after PAX East, either right before or right after PAX East, we're going to judge anime again.
Scott: Antichart.net already seems to be well on its way towards updating.
Scott: Anyway, we noticed last season we were judging anime.
Scott: There's a new Dororo TV series, so a new adaptation of the Dororo manga into anime with, you know, that was made this year right now.
Scott: It's airing currently.
Scott: I think seven episodes have already aired as of this podcast.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I have seen three.
Scott: I think I've seen two or three.
Scott: I don't remember.
Rym: Do you see these three?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Do you saw the, uh, the village with the lady?
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And then the next one is the doctor's back story.
Rym: The guy who made the prosthesis.
Scott: Yes, I saw that.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: We've seen about the same amount.
Rym: We we've seen enough.
Rym: You've read the manga.
Rym: I have not.
Rym: So you know a lot more than me.
Scott: I died, but I have much.
Scott: Do I remember the manga?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's only, it's actually not a very long manga.
Scott: Tezuka wise.
Scott: It's only like a few volumes.
Scott: Uh, but yeah, so basically the story of Doro is kind of a crazy and unique story is that there was this dude, he was some sort of like samurai Lord kind of guy.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: And you know, like those guys that are always trying to increase their social standing and, and such and such.
Rym: So like you do, he goes to the temple at the gates of hell and asked the 12 right near his house is a temple on the mountain.
Scott: And that temple on the mountain is not a temple of nice gods or buddhas.
Scott: It's a temple of horrible evil demon.
Rym: There's basically this one monk there who's like, stay the fuck away from castle lemon grab.
Scott: He's like, I'm basically here because I'm protecting this place.
Scott: He goes in there and he's like, oh, demons help me out and make me fucking awesome.
Scott: Like go down to the crossroads.
Scott: Let me be awesome at guitar.
Scott: This is all, this is like, I'll give you anything awesome demons.
Scott: Meanwhile, his wife is pregnant and the demons are like, I take your baby.
Rym: You said anything.
Scott: He doesn't care.
Scott: He's just fucking evil.
Scott: He's like, I take my baby.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Kills the monk, makes a deal with these demons and the demons are like, let's roll.
Scott: Yeah, sure thing.
Scott: So this baby basically has all of its body parts stolen by demons.
Scott: Yet somehow it's not dead.
Scott: It has like, just, it doesn't even have skin and eyeless, mouthless, like earless, noseless, skinless body.
Scott: It makes no sense that it's alive, but it's an anime and a manga.
Scott: So whatever.
Scott: So it has almost no organs left.
Rym: And the Lord is like, oh, I guess the demons, that's what they wanted.
Rym: All right, whatever.
Rym: I'm going to be King.
Rym: I'll make another baby.
Rym: These are real easy to make.
Scott: This baby pulls a Moses and goes down the river in a boat and somehow it survives.
Scott: And somehow in addition to surviving it, like actually, you know, manages to live some kind of life and eventually it figures out that, hey, if I find these demons and slay them, then it seems like the demons must have like divvied up the body parts.
Scott: Like there is an eyeball for you and a brain for you and a skin for you.
Rym: So it's like a reverse Castlevania two or Dracula's going around killing people to get his body parts back, right?
Scott: It's like you are Dracula trying to get your body parts back except you're good and you're killing demons to get the good body parts back.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: But Doro, the car, I guess the characters, you know, that's not Doro.
Rym: No, it's just this guy.
Scott: Uh, right.
Scott: So that's like the focus is that story of this, of this baby trying to get his body parts back.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And maybe get revenge on dad eventually.
Scott: The other players here are this kid who sort of discovers and make friends with, you know, missing body part person.
Rym: This kid's introduction is basically he just scammed the hell out of a bunch of dudes.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: He's basically just as like wandering drifter scammer.
Rym: kid throws rocks at people.
Scott: There is a doctor who committed war crimes and felt really bad about it and thus began a life of creating prosthetics, which he would then give to, you know, the victims of wars and also the corpses of wars who are missing body parts.
Scott: He's got to the battlefield and put legs on corpses that lost their leg and stuff, uh, to atone for his sins.
Scott: And he also helps out the person who is trying to get their body parts back with giving them some prosthetics that allow them to function prosthetics with swords in them.
Rym: It's not much of a spoiler.
Scott: That's how you get the demons.
Rym: You learned that he is basically a body part missing.
Rym: Good guy.
Rym: You can't see here, talk, smell, touch, feel, taste or anything.
Rym: All they can do is sense demons and sense good people.
Rym: and he knows the difference between the two.
Rym: and he's got swords in all his product, swords everywhere, just sorts in him and there's various other people along the way.
Scott: Like there's actually a brother that was born after the deal with the demons.
Rym: He made his wife pregnant again and that babies are real easy to make the demons.
Scott: did that brother.
Scott: I think I remember is kind of evil.
Rym: Maybe I blame his upbringing eventually.
Scott: I guess a conflict there.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Evil dad, evil son, whatever.
Scott: Anyway, but yeah, it's, it's all about this adventure tale that goes on.
Scott: So the anime is pretty well made.
Scott: You know, the animation is, is decent, is not crazy, good, amazing, but it doesn't have any like horrible problems.
Scott: It's good.
Rym: It feels good.
Rym: It looks good.
Rym: It's serviceable.
Rym: It's better than most anime.
Scott: The story is just as compelling as it was in the manga, except the manga was a Tezuka manga and therefore has lots and lots of ridiculous slapstick comedy nonsense that is completely absent from the anime.
Scott: They pretty much just took only the serious parts of the manga and only turned those into an anime and left the rest of the manga where it was on the page.
Rym: That's where this shines.
Rym: Like if you want to experience the drama of a Tezuka, this is a really good anime to watch three episodes in.
Rym: I'm actually really into it.
Rym: It's it's just, I think what I like the most is that it's just the good part, but also it's not that the comedy is a bad part.
Scott: It's just, it's a really, you know, it feels old.
Rym: The comedy is toned down and makes more sense in the context of the world in this anime than it does in the manga.
Scott: And also, if you've read any Tezuka manga, you know, the kind of comedy that's in there, like, you know, random, weird, kooky characters, all alone.
Rym: None of that dude in ancient times pulls out like a modern telephone for some reason, for one gag, that kind of stuff.
Scott: None of that is in here.
Scott: They took it all out.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But it also, the character designs, because Tezuka character designs, they'll be like the serious ones, but also the kind of like really iconic kind of weird ones.
Rym: It tones that down, but takes the right parts to where, parts to where.
Rym: the character designs and the sets and everything, they evoke Tezuka's style without cleaving too closely to Tezuka and making it look weird.
Rym: It looks good for a modern sensibility.
Scott: It doesn't, like the way the Metropolis movie looks like a Tezuka thing.
Scott: This does not.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: But if you know Tezuka stuff, you'll see the Tezuka in it, but it won't distract a non Tezuka aficionado from the very compelling good story.
Rym: Right.
Scott: So now the thing about the story is that it's structured in such a way, it's like there's episodes for each body part.
Scott: they're trying to get back, there's like an episode.
Rym: Kill a demon, get a body part.
Rym: Right.
Scott: So that structure makes the story actually quite similar to something like Mushishi, where each demon is different, right?
Scott: They're on a journey.
Scott: They stop at places and encounter some situation.
Scott: It's like, oh, what's happening here?
Rym: Oh, this town is beset by a monster and like the lady who runs the town needs them to go kill it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Why is this town so wealthy in the middle of nowhere with no business?
Scott: What's going on here?
Scott: And obviously it's a demon that's holding onto a body part, but they sort of, each episode, you know, you're sort of, they have to like solve the riddle of this demon, figure out what's going on here.
Scott: The same way, you know, Mushishi figures out what's going on or the same way Kitaro figures out what's going on and then solves, you know, the Yokai situation.
Scott: that's happening.
Scott: Or, you know, it's always, it's the same kind of structure.
Scott: Go on a journey.
Scott: Even, even galaxy express the same structure, arrive at a planet, face a moral quandary, deal with it, leave and go to the next place.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So the Dororo is like, well, they go to the next place on their journey around Japan.
Scott: They encounter a demon situation and figure it out.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And meanwhile, the, the non Dororo, the other guy forgot his name.
Rym: I forget all the characters, I think anyway, but he bit by bit as he gets more body parts, becomes more and more of a human.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So it gets more exciting later when, you know, it's like getting some real body parts back.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: He's pissed about demons.
Rym: You don't say if I had to define his character based on what I know so far, hates demons, kind of like star row.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: That's, that's what he said.
Rym: Like swords uses swords.
Scott: So yeah, we judge this completely accurately in our judging anime this season.
Scott: And I can say, if you're looking for an anime to watch this season, you should watch this now because I looked ahead at next season.
Scott: Uh, one bunch, man, second season is coming out.
Rym: Oh, the second punch.
Scott: So you better watch Dororo now because when you're watching one bunch of man, you're not going to have time for any Doro.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion, news, and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, gaming Tuesdays, anime comic Wednesdays, and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution.
Scott: 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Rym: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night and the patron patrons for this Doro related episode of GeekNights in order of money.
Rym: Here we go.
Rym: I have to catch my breath there.
Rym: I'm yelling.
Rym: Craig Oliver, Alan Joyce, hiding McNichol, just like a dude guy.
Rym: Kishore adoption.
Rym: Link Eiji, Jennifer Hitchcock, Chris midkiff, M Y S T A D Y.com J band scooter lonely Roberto Kingsley, Sean Yeager, Matthew Smith, Nicholas Brenda, mr.
Rym: Strong stretch and four to one creations.
Rym: Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn, Sharvin von Harlow, Rory, Rochelle, Monta, Nona, super boy, sailor Vista, Don, Schleich, Joshua, Joe Starr, Clinton, Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan, parent drew open.
Rym: Lander, Finn, Daniel, Redmond, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, Thomas Hahn.
Rym: I will see you both at PAX East where we are doing a panel and it's Zenk icon where I am doing a bunch of panels and otherwise I'll just be rip roaring drunk wandering around Lancaster.
Rym: And now I leave you with.