Rym: It's Thursday August 1st 2019.
Rym: I'm Rym guy and this is the GeekNights' cheese episode.
Rym: I am pretty confident.
Rym: We have never talked about cheese as a topic.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: In fact all I could find was a GeekNights' episode from a long time ago.
Rym: Where I'm.
Rym: the show node say something to the effect of Rym got ahold of some Christmas cheese And it's a link to a tweet and the tweet is just a picture I took on my phone of Emily standing somewhere holding in her hands like two pounds of wrapped Vermont cheddar With no other context no replies no thread no follow-up.
Rym: I have no way to know what this Christmas cheese is except to go listen to this old episode of GeekNights.
Rym: Uh-huh, so I'm gonna link to that and I hope one of you will listen to this episode or maybe you're insane And you remember this old episode and you can tell me what the deal is with my Christmas cheese.
Scott: Yeah, I feel like you just deleted our cheese episode.
Rym: I mean it took you a while to get here, so that's definitely what I did.
Scott: Everybody's got no episode ideas.
Scott: he finds an old episode deletes it and then it's like oh, we never did a cheese show.
Scott: It's like someone out there has an archive of that cheese show.
Rym: yeah Well, we'll see.
Rym: so I got a bunch of travel you know, but I had my old job.
Rym: You may remember pretty often GeekNights should be derailed for a week or two at a time because I would just I had to.
Rym: And when I took the new job one of the nice things was as much as I enjoyed all that travel.
Rym: It was nice to just not have to travel when I wasn't a hundred percent feeling it.
Scott: well I mean, that's the thing is like.
Scott: you know traveling going on vacation is like great.
Scott: Not a lot of people get to do it at all right.
Scott: most people like stuck where they are and can't move around too far.
Scott: Yeah in general regardless of whether they want to or not like if
Rym: you have a job That doesn't travel and your company like sends you to London for a week
Scott: But
Rym: Every month or in London well,
Scott: it's like if you keep going into the same place Then it's sort of like well, you're kind of living in a different place.
Scott: You're not really tourists in there.
Rym: Yeah, you're part-time living there Which is not as great like for all the time I spent in London this year or like it last year when Emily I went on a vacation there.
Rym: It was the first time I'd ever been to London in my life as a tourist.
Scott: right It's like if you go somewhere, and you're not even if you don't do touristy things.
Scott: when you're a tourist you're smarter than that.
Scott: You're still having free time there where you can do whatever check out stuff during the day.
Scott: if you're sent to a place to Work and they actually have a lot of work for you to do there And not a lot of bullshit
Rym: that you're working all
Scott: day Then it's just a fucking different office in a different time zone with it Maybe a different language or different accents or different food or something like that.
Scott: It's.
Scott: it's slightly novel maybe the first time because of the you know those kinds of differences But it's like the first few times just doing we're gonna dig in a different office.
Scott: it might.
Scott: it's as novel as it's almost.
Scott: It's not too different just working a different office across the street.
Rym: Yeah, well the first few times you do it though one thing That's fun is that you're in a place like when you get out of work You don't like.
Rym: what are you gonna do?
Rym: go back to the hotel?
Scott: right you go like check out the city But it depends how much time you got if you're working too much.
Scott: It's like okay.
Scott: Well, it's like I've worked eight hours in this other city And then I ate a dinner at a new restaurant and I went to it.
Scott: I checked one thing out, and then I went to bed because I got to work tomorrow in the same place.
Scott: You know it's like come on But if you're sent on business travel with lots of bullshit time like go to this conference give a talk and you're there for three Days yeah, it's like oh well Then I guess I'll be spending day two looking at the tempestries.
Rym: yep And or like a lot of my travel was not work all day It was you have to meet with these important people in this city go there for like n days.
Rym: and or like go to all These European cities and you have one meeting in each one of them And I didn't really have like work that had to be done during those trips other than those meetings and the follow-up to those meetings.
Scott: Yeah, so that's good travel.
Rym: and more importantly like you got like do a trip to Paris and you're working the whole time But your work is go visit people like all over the city.
Rym: It's almost like a scavenger hunt.
Scott: Another thing that can happen is you know so there's the bullshit business travel where you don't get to do anything.
Rym: You've got a different office or the travel to the travel to a low tier American city.
Rym: If you're like we're gonna go traveling in the same country as me Yeah, like I've done business trips in the past where it's like go to Chicago for a week that sucks, right?
Scott: Business travel where you actually get to do to have time that's good.
Scott: But sometimes the business travel either has you away from home for a consecutively long time or even if it's not consecutive It's home back home back home back, and it's just the number of date.
Scott: You're not home enough, and it's like why I'm even paying for this home.
Scott: You know it's like even if I went on vacation.
Scott: just come vacation.
Scott: It's like if I went to the tropical island, and it wasn't my home, and I was there for like a month.
Scott: I'd be like this is too long.
Scott: I want to go home.
Scott: Yeah, my home was here.
Scott: That would be amazing, but it's not.
Scott: yeah.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: you know you're not home sick necessarily like a child who misses their home.
Scott: It's just like you got shit at home.
Scott: You kind of want to do.
Scott: you don't want to be away too much.
Scott: you want to be home and away with the right proportions?
Scott: Otherwise it's like I can't see my people.
Scott: I can't take care of my biz.
Rym: But now due to the nature of my job.
Scott: I don't got my stuff with me.
Scott: I need I want to use some of my stuff.
Scott: I don't got it.
Rym: So it looks like I'll be traveling again, but for a very different company, and that will see how that all goes.
Rym: But it's gonna be mostly London which I've spent so much time in London.
Rym: like I know.
Scott: I still don't understand what the modern Technologies of video conferencing and such and such like.
Scott: why is there this real?
Scott: There are cases where you need to send a person somewhere But like if you're just a business II person who talks and discusses and things like routine work.
Rym: There's no reason for that kind of try.
Scott: as opposed if you just meeting with people if you have a business if you're doing something Like I'm a Formula One engineer, and the race is in Germany I need to go to Germany to work on the car.
Rym: It's also like saying a new team And you're gonna let you want to like meet the team in person and get to know them And then you don't really travel back there that often.
Scott: Yeah, maybe something like that.
Rym: That's the kind of travel I'm doing.
Rym: or like meeting clients or something.
Rym: I'm not.
Rym: it's not like meeting clients.
Scott: I'll just meet you on the fucking phone.
Scott: Do you know what?
Rym: For whatever reason almost every interaction I've ever had in commercial like stuff over all these years meeting people in person just ends up being way more effective than using Utterly perfect video conferencing technology, and that's just how it is.
Scott: Oh, you're you're.
Scott: the damage to the environment I think outweighs the effectiveness of all the extra travel that's going up.
Rym: But do the nature of my job.
Rym: Not to mention the other costs.
Rym: I gotta do like carbon offsets and stuff Like.
Rym: I actually got this report of how much carbon I'm wasting by doing the strip and I gotta like offset it.
Rym: There's all this stuff.
Scott: Uh-huh Well, you could be eating lettuce then on the trip.
Rym: Yeah, but the problem is.
Rym: well, not the problem But I'm going to London, which whatever I like London like.
Rym: going to London for a week is always fun because I know a lot of people in London.
Rym: There's stuff to do in London.
Rym: It's like being in a slightly different, New York.
Rym: People talk a little funny, but then I gotta go to Nothing against Frankfurt, but I've been to a lot of German cities and Frankfurt.
Rym: visiting Frankfurt is like that is the least German city I want to visit.
Scott: Are you gonna get some great Frankfurters though?
Scott: I like the best the original Frankfurt's known for having an airport.
Scott: I know that like.
Scott: that's what I know it for the airport and its name.
Rym: Yeah hot dog like if I had to rank German airport if I had to rank German cities that I've spent a lot of time in in terms Of how much I like them like Munich is number one.
Rym: by far.
Rym: Hamburg is like a close.
Rym: the Hamburg is like a distant second.
Rym: Berlin's like close like pretty close to Hamburg.
Rym: I think I like Hamburg more than Berlin, but I haven't spent a lot of time in Berlin.
Rym: list almost every other major German city and then Frankfurt at the bottom was just an Airport and a bunch of meetings that are within walking distance of said airport.
Scott: Oh, it's that the airport's like downtown the airport's like right there.
Rym: Wow.
Scott: That's pretty good.
Rym: So yeah Sometime at basically after PAX there'll be a week of no GeekNights and then we'll be back to our regular schedule.
Scott: No, that's good for me.
Scott: I got free Rym goes on trips.
Scott: I got time to do shit.
Rym: Yeah, so you got any news.
Scott: Maybe I'll do shit related to my news.
Scott: So Ninja who I guess is still maybe like not if not the number one like one of the top video game streaming people on the Earth.
Scott: Yeah, and doesn't I mean, I don't know.
Scott: I guess he's still popular and he hasn't Fucked up majorly like some other streamers have.
Scott: he hasn't PewDiePie himself.
Scott: So I guess I'm not gonna call him.
Scott: I'm not gonna call him good.
Scott: But I know he isn't.
Scott: he's not evil?
Scott: I guess not yet.
Rym: We are we are reasonably is plus only watching.
Scott: then I've watched one ninja stream for five minutes and he was like, yeah a guy that the kids would like I guess Yeah Not someone I need like.
Rym: I'd watch his stuff and I can see like you're watching one of his dreams and you can imagine Exactly the kind of kid who's into that anyway.
Scott: So he has decided to move from twitch to exclusively mixers.
Scott: If you don't know mixer is another site.
Scott: maybe does what twitch?
Scott: does you stream yourself playing games?
Scott: But it's obviously much less popular than twitch much less.
Scott: Well known.
Scott: It's not owned by Amazon or some giant company?
Scott: I don't.
Scott: I think it's probably some startup that's losing money hand over fist.
Scott: I'm not sure about that I don't but that's what I guess.
Scott: it's probably correct.
Scott: But it has a ton of features that twitch doesn't have like built right in and plugins and I like share your controller like let Your listeners fuck with your controller, right?
Scott: you can do quizzes and all kinds of crazy interactive stuff with your audience.
Scott: and Whereas on twitch you would have to like do development work to get a lot of these features.
Scott: Yeah mixer makes it a lot easier and they provide a lot of them out of the box.
Scott: You don't get to do anything really other than use mixer now.
Rym: Mixer like.
Rym: I don't care about mixer at all yet But I'm glad it exists and it's getting some traction because it's forcing Twitch and YouTube to up their game a little bit Right.
Scott: So YouTube's competition.
Scott: YouTube shut down YouTube gaming which was really just a different UI for YouTube and a different home page That would filter out just gaming content Filter to just gaming content and they shut that.
Scott: dad You can still live stream on YouTube But I don't think a lot of people do really.
Rym: what seems like most people do is they live stream a live stream on Twitch And then they put up the polished VOD on YouTube.
Scott: They and if they're a big streamer They have someone who edits for them like the the best clips of the day of their day-long Stream and makes YouTube videos out of them.
Scott: and they get.
Scott: they get to revenue streams.
Scott: Yeah, some people are and you follow them on YouTube some follow on Twitch some do both, whatever.
Scott: Apparently I was.
Scott: I wasn't fully aware of this.
Scott: I knew Facebook had live streaming right, but I figured it was mostly used for things For example, like, you know mayor press conference is usually streamed on Facebook.
Scott: Yeah Apparently that Facebook gaming booth.
Scott: It's always at PAX.
Scott: I thought that was about things like oculus because twitch owns oculus.
Scott: I mean Facebook owns oculus, right?
Scott: and I thought it was about things like games you can play on Facebook or you know games that like link to Facebook or That Facebook developers are developing.
Rym: I thought that that's what that booth was about and you might say but room is God Aren't you journalists one?
Rym: No and two.
Scott: Anymore that's a booth that I walk past and glance and that's about it.
Scott: I know I'm useless.
Rym: I've been to a lot of PAX is if I look at a booth for more than a second that already means I am deeply Invested in whatever it is.
Scott: They got yeah So that booth apparently was actually about people who?
Scott: Use Facebook to stream themselves gaming instead of or in addition to twitch and I didn't realize anyone did that.
Scott: But apparently people do and have some number of viewers.
Scott: Facebook is like a competitor in that arena, I guess.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: All right Yes, I guess I don't think the kinds of streams I watch would be popular I suppose.
Scott: but it seems like YouTube failed to compete with twitch.
Scott: Facebook is trying but I guess it hasn't succeeded.
Scott: But mixer actually seems to be doing better than YouTube or Facebook at least just by my feeling.
Rym: But it seems like it's competing with twitch.
Rym: I think it's just because of two simple factors one They added some features that twitch is probably just gonna also implement eventually.
Scott: and two Until now YouTube would be wise to get.
Rym: until now most of the people I've seen moving to mixer seem to be people who aren't that popular and Going to a platform that's like kind of popular at least doing okay.
Rym: You'll be a much bigger fish.
Scott: That's I mean, that's always the dilemma here right?
Rym: is an ad gives you that algorithm boost.
Scott: you might think so But think about this, right?
Scott: Let's say you're uh, you know above zero on twitch, right?
Scott: You have a small following.
Scott: you go to mixer on mixer like you're on front page of mixer.
Scott: So literally everyone on mixer you're getting there.
Rym: I think you're better off getting front pages on mixer than having like under five thousand subscribers.
Scott: a lot of it depends on numbers.
Scott: first of all exact numbers, but also it's like That mixer pond is so small.
Scott: Are you real like you're not getting additional viewers because no one's on there button.
Scott: twitch for example, right?
Scott: I've been watching a lot of Mario maker streaming cuz it's.
Scott: it's really.
Scott: first of all If you want to watch a game streamed Mario maker is the best because it's always something different.
Scott: Yeah keeps changing constantly.
Scott: But also I found this Irish dude who's in second place for endless mode and he's just like this quiet cool Irish, dude Who just casually plays Mario maker 12 to 16 hours a day like that, but it's totally chill And he is in second place in endless mode Always trying to catch the crazy Spanish person in first place who apparently doesn't stream or at least you haven't found their stream.
Scott: We don't know who they are And his stream is totally Jill.
Scott: But I found him because what I did is I went to twitch and I clicked on Mario maker Which showed me all the Mario maker streams on twitch and I scrolled up and down and I looked at them all and I saw One that said like second place endless blah blah streak and I clicked on that one right on mixer.
Scott: There's a lot less people doing that.
Scott: so true if you are in like not on front page of twitch You're on middle page.
Scott: You might pick this just so much more people there.
Scott: You might pick up some.
Scott: you know, I guess what we would call it Street traffic.
Rym: Yeah, it's hard to say though because discover traffic eyeballs Really low.
Rym: in this space you have to already be big to be big Right, so in this case ninja who's enormous?
Rym: well You say he's enormous, but this article actually says something specific.
Rym: He reportedly has 14,900 ish subscribers.
Rym: Okay down from his peak of 285,000 last year.
Rym: So that's an order of magnitude and if you look at twitch tracker, you see him.
Scott: He's all living off it.
Rym: Yeah, but you see him peak in a March of 2018 and just a constant steady decline.
Scott: Dove just since then like he's losing I mean a lot of the people were probably watching him when he was the hottest shit.
Scott: Right and like in those days when he was at his peak He was getting celebrities on there like fortnight was new but his number of active subscribers has dropped.
Scott: It's really to maintain that is just so, you know untenable, right?
Scott: You would have to constantly be like the hottest shit all the time constantly doing something new grabbing attention.
Scott: People get bored of watching the same guy do this, you know, yeah And the thing is it's like, okay people are getting bored.
Scott: I'm just keep doing what I'm doing So I mix it up and then you lose people who are into you for the thing you were doing.
Scott: Yeah, so you you can't really win isn't?
Scott: it's unsustainable to just when your content is a person sitting there playing game Right.
Scott: This is why you know, if you're a TV network, you can sustain by having new programming and new Yeah, there's more than one television show on a net, right?
Scott: You can do you doing things to like sustain constantly if you're if you're for if your entire network Hours and hours and hours a day is your face and a video game and you can't sustain the high counts They're gonna be fluctuations and variations.
Rym: Maybe I will say though.
Rym: This article says something that he's Still very large.
Scott: So moving to another platform his he has a significant portion of his following.
Scott: people Go to wherever he goes.
Scott: So once you're big enough, you don't need the platform anymore.
Scott: You have an audience.
Scott: you can go wherever you want to go and bring them with you.
Scott: I wonder if mixer paid him to go there to help them or if he's just going because of the features and it won't hurt Him to leave.
Rym: or maybe he's going because if he's like he's losing popularity and he's trying to consolidate or make a movie.
Scott: I mean, you know, there are definitely people who if they left twitch would lose a ton right of their following.
Rym: Yeah, but this article also says something interesting.
Rym: It says that a lot of you basically says that mixer is also said to have a much more friendly community than twitch.
Scott: Smaller.
Rym: yeah, that's a ridiculous thing to say.
Rym: all small platforms have better communities than big platforms except like a Chan and Gab and all those Nazi platforms.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if you know it gets big then it'll get worse.
Rym: Yeah It'll get just as bad as twitch.
Rym: twitch is not bad because of much of the design of twitch.
Rym: I can argue that twitch could design its plan its interactions to be less time.
Scott: It's just.
Scott: it's not even a social network or platform thing.
Scott: That's just a human society thing.
Rym: Way way back if you have a small there was live-streaming Scott and I did a live stream of GeekNights one night.
Rym: Remember that on what you stream?
Scott: Yeah, and there were like is you stream still exist?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: There were like a dozen people watching because it was a live stream.
Rym: like people didn't have bandwidth to watch stuff like that back then.
Scott: So yeah, it's like we had you know Like ten of our listeners watching that one live stream and they had like ten was enough to hit the front page.
Rym: Halogen lamps on us cuz LEDs weren't really like like it was.
Rym: it was a long time ago really non HD webcam.
Rym: But for whatever reason you stream like about a third of the way through the stream Just put us on the front page.
Scott: cuz we had like ten people watching.
Scott: so then we had like 100 people.
Rym: Maybe we have many hundreds.
Rym: and then what happened was the chat filled with just garbo rage and bullshit and Racism and Nazi shit like instantly.
Scott: Yeah, not all kinds of just random typing.
Rym: Yeah, just random shit posting, right?
Scott: So like the guy I was saying the Irish guy playing Mario maker He's got tens of people watching him at any given moment.
Rym: The average number of viewer views per channel is 10 on mixer, right?
Scott: But his twitch chat It's like you can talk in it, but you even someone who just has like hundreds or thousands of people in their twitch chat.
Scott: It's a useless twitch chat.
Scott: It's just a emoji flood.
Scott: It's useless.
Rym: Yep so speaking of following someone.
Rym: so I will not link to this story because I do not want to give this Probably questionable dude any Google juice, right?
Scott: So there was this dude that I had heard.
Scott: his name sounded familiar Colin Moriarty, so I had his name sounded like.
Scott: Basically when I heard the name I was like.
Scott: that reminds me of name of bad YouTube shouty, man.
Rym: So you look at his you his Twitter?
Rym: Yeah, he seems like a bad.
Scott: Nothing about him.
Rym: I couldn't pick him out of a lineup But his Twitter icon is like the Gadsden flag and his name is like no tax.
Rym: something Appears to be a bad person.
Scott: Anyway, so this person was on some sort of panel that was accepted at PAX West this year Which we have panels at surprise.
Scott: Yeah, and he got an acceptance email.
Rym: I think the panel was pretty much his podcast or the podcast He was on which fun fact panel packs asked us for like five years running to do a GeekNights panel And we refused because we didn't want to do anything.
Scott: brandy in 2025.
Scott: We could do 20 years of GeekNights the panel.
Rym: Yeah, the listener it'll be a pride a luxury experience for you anyway.
Scott: But yeah, there was a panel that seems to be effectively their podcast the panel.
Scott: It was accepted Before the schedule is not out yet.
Scott: There's no public.
Scott: but they did send out acceptance emails.
Scott: They sent them then another email that said sorry you're canceled But you're still getting free badges free special guest badges just like all the other panelists now
Rym: before we're taking
Scott: your panel off the schedule now
Rym: before we go on at Professional conferences at fan conferences like that happens all the time that
Scott: it happened for an insane number of reasons.
Rym: How many times I have canceled someone's panel at the last minute for just random reason even the last minute.
Rym: It's a month away Yeah, but I've canceled people's panels like the day before they arrived.
Scott: There are so many reasons.
Scott: it could be it could be they had to schedule another panel in that specific time for some reason.
Rym: Maybe that's the only time that the company held the representative had Clicked and he got and he got the like acceptance email by accident.
Rym: like the CMS is that we all use to manage this kind Of stuff for conventions are not great.
Scott: Yeah, there's so many reasons It could have been canceled, but we are pretty sure it's because he's bad person.
Rym: So it's even better cuz he's flipping out now and getting his fans to like flip out at pack, right?
Scott: So clearly his reaction is proof.
Scott: Oh, yeah, you were a bad person.
Scott: Yep, a good person who received that email would not react this way.
Scott: So the fact that you received the email and reacted in this way is only proof that you were.
Scott: it was good that you received The email in the first place, but it's extra funny like I'm not gonna like.
Rym: I'm just gonna tear down some of the points you might see around this because You're this is gonna be a big enough like shit show on the internet to where you're gonna run into people who care about this.
Rym: Yeah, I think this will go away as soon as I think it'll get like a good Whatever I don't like all of them to my block.
Scott: It's only noticeable for us because we're so close to packs panels.
Scott: I think most people don't even know.
Scott: this is whatever.
Rym: Yeah, but so point number one this dude is like but that's bullshit.
Rym: People are like they bought plane tickets and packs badges to see me there.
Rym: well now first of all there is but there is no universe where that is true because They packs didn't even send acceptance emails out for the panels until after the badges were on sale and the badges sold out like Instantly.
Scott: that is true, but also Even if he was the one who said I have a packs panel guys come to packs to see me.
Scott: Right and people bought badges.
Scott: that was him.
Scott: Advertising packs did not advertise that he was coming yet They did not put the schedule alive yet.
Scott: So to sue packs for that would be false.
Scott: packs didn't say come buy tickets.
Scott: This guy is coming.
Scott: you said buy tickets to facts.
Scott: I'm coming which clearly was a lie on your part.
Scott: It's on you.
Rym: so
Scott: - if anything you should have to pay those people back for telling them you were gonna Have a do a panel and you're
Rym: not now - this dude is like Emailing back and forth with packs, and he's posting the emails and he is using words Like promissory estoppel.
Scott: yes He is clearly.
Rym: those are the words that crazy dangerous people say right now.
Rym: that is sovereign citizen adjacent shit.
Scott: Yeah, it is not the sovereign citizen language, but it is very adjacent to it.
Scott: very very.
Scott: It's like right next to it in this next lane on the highway sovereign citizen in the right lane.
Scott: He's in the second to right lane.
Scott: Yeah looking out that he looks to his right He sees a sovereign citizen in a rusty old car with fringe on it.
Rym: Yep, so three He made a big deal about how I even had access to the back-end system to like Confirm the details of my panel and update my like.
Rym: yeah fucking everyone has access to that.
Rym: Yeah, like anyone can submit a panel.
Rym: Yep, anyone.
Rym: Yeah, it just works.
Rym: You can you listening right now.
Scott: You can do it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: How do you think we started doing shows at PAX one day?
Rym: I went to the PAX website, and I clicked on a button and I made an account and then I typed in hey I want to do this panel.
Rym: that was it.
Rym: so this is This is something to avoid and anyone who is mad about this and is mad at PAX about it is a person To avoid
Scott: the only criticism that I have right of PAX's side Which is actually a larger criticism I have of wells in general
Rym: where the caveat that we don't actually know the reason.
Scott: Yeah, we don't know the reason.
Rym: if the reason is that is because this dude is a bad person.
Scott: is I hope that's the reason.
Rym: We're just guessing we have no inside.
Scott: But wait, I feel that even if it's because the person's a shithead and they are a shithead right that if you kick ban Evict Suspend punish another person in any way for any reason under any system whether it's private public whatever That you should just tell the reason at least to the person right.
Scott: Magna Carta.
Scott: What am I being arrested?
Scott: Yeah, right?
Scott: It's like they should have at least told the guy your panel is cancelled because and you can you know Hide some of the details if necessary.
Rym: I have told people when I ran ConnectiCon for a decade like the panel stuff like, you know I scheduled because every scheduling conflict because yep, uh, you know because we determined that We had too much content of your type.
Rym: We would love you to submit this next year, right?
Rym: But with too much content of their type was basically code for I accidentally accepted a homestuck panel.
Scott: So you get banned from the night's forum, which is super super rare.
Scott: We tell you why.
Scott: yeah, right?
Scott: You're a Nazi get out of here.
Scott: Yeah, we don't just say you're banned and then you're like why?
Scott: why was I bad?
Scott: It's like because you're a Nazi.
Scott: Yeah, because you you you're spelling is bad.
Scott: It wasn't because English is you're not first language and you didn't try to fix it.
Rym: now I will say that Every con I've worked with including packs or a panel that might have been scheduled got cancelled or rescheduled or something.
Rym: They have told me why.
Rym: mm-hmm the fact that no one told this guy why probably means is a bad person.
Rym: But again, we don't know we don't know but we probably know he's probably a bad person.
Scott: the only other Criticism I have and this is this is the one that's only true if like if he was kicked off if this panel was kicked out of the schedule because Him or other people on it were bad and therefore they don't want those people on panels at packs.
Scott: if that was the reason Why are you giving them the free badges?
Rym: You should hand them from packs.
Rym: when I scheduled ConnectiCon You know, that was I said I was hundreds of panels.
Rym: I like googled and searched social media and poked around the wall.
Scott: for the to be fair You were familiar with the vast majority of the people submitting those panels.
Scott: Yeah, if you're hey, you're managing anyone.
Rym: I didn't know like if I saw a panel like huh?
Rym: That one looks interesting, but that's the majority of them.
Scott: You did know.
Scott: Yeah, or they had been panelists But not the vast majority.
Rym: more like 60% tops majority.
Scott: The point is if you're doing it for the vast majority for packs You don't know none of those people, but you know what I would say - that's gonna be a research project.
Rym: Oh, hey does not have that many panels.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: I Like research.
Scott: a lot of them are industry also.
Rym: Yeah, like you don't need like.
Rym: is Square Enix evil like?
Rym: well not in the way that would affect us.
Scott: Yeah, right but you know.
Scott: Yeah, if someone is a problem to where you're not going to allow them to have a panel at packs because of who they are.
Scott: You should not allow them to be at packs period if they're a problematic human being.
Rym: Yep Or in the very least you should say this the P this kind of content is not welcome at our show or this kind of Person is not welcome to present at our show
Scott: Content because it seems like as far as I can tell the panel was literally just their podcast the panel.
Scott: now That may have been a problematic podcast.
Scott: I never have and never will listen to it.
Rym: Yeah, but I mean your podcast.
Scott: the panel is not in and of itself a problematic panel Especially when we have specifically been asked to do GeekNights.
Scott: the panel.
Rym: Yep, but looking at this dude's Twitter If I were scheduling a convention like when I was at Connecticut and I saw this Twitter I wouldn't die.
Rym: This guy would be on my secret blacklist forever.
Rym: Yeah, I did have a secret blacklist.
Rym: Yeah there are a lot of people who were.
Rym: Who are?
Rym: I made sure they would never get a panel scheduled in case I got hit by a buzz and someone finished the schedule.
Scott: But yeah, if you're a bad person who's not?
Scott: if you know You should have the same list for attendee and panelists.
Scott: who who is a person such that you're bad?
Scott: We're not gonna let you speak at this con, but we'll let you come.
Scott: It's like that doesn't line up girl.
Rym: Yeah, well I feel like usually when that happens It's because someone made a mistake and accepting something in the first place and they're trying to just Back out as quietly and drama free as possible, but if the person actually is a problem Well, they're making themselves a problem.
Rym: Yeah but that's just evidence that they are the way this dude is reacting.
Rym: if I were the in charge of a like if GeekNights started The convention which kind of working on?
Scott: stay tuned Kind I kind of one we said we would have in this year.
Rym: Yeah I'm putting more effort into it now that we're finishing up another project.
Rym: We were working on.
Scott: we are the Branding stuff.
Rym: Oh, yeah now that that is progressed.
Rym: Well, I'm actually poking at this again, but Anyway Stay away from this bad, dude.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: This is an old thing that you may not have seen.
Rym: The something awful forums are not gonna get into the things about those forums, but there's an important part about them In that they were very important to the formation of modern internet culture.
Scott: Yeah, good and bad a lot of people, you know It's like it was a very inside group that had an outside influence on Just web culture and a lot of people don't realize the things that spawned from it.
Scott: And but it is.
Scott: you did as many things.
Scott: there are
Rym: two very famous stories that are related to each other From something awful and this is a Twitter thread of someone Who basically went into these archives pulled the like an oral history of One of the epic threads from something awful and explain the deal with photos and stuff on Twitter.
Scott: This is actually a thing that you can just do in general for fun.
Scott: Just find online communities that have archives like I don't know GeekNights forum Which is archived back to 2005 and go find like a drama thread find a thread of stuff.
Rym: That is like an interesting Incident like we did with one of our most popular panels of all time the ballad of dude, bro.
Scott: But that was a recent incident at the time, but now it's historic incident.
Scott: Yep, and you know dig it up do some like our fact We are still doing digital archaeology.
Scott: in most places people talk about the story of what happened.
Rym: We are cited as a like primary source.
Scott: I'm just we're not.
Scott: we're a secondary.
Rym: Yeah We're a secondary but we're like cited as the source of the data.
Scott: I went to the actual forum where the thing happened and then did a thing about it.
Scott: I'm a secondary source.
Scott: Yeah Anyway, but the point is digital archaeology.
Scott: Cool.
Rym: So this is the story of Something that is affectionately referred to as the machine to kill children.
Rym: All right, or the rest in peace line Aka the rip line.
Rym: Okay, the story is like a zipline that's broken.
Scott: So is it an action park?
Rym: I'm gonna quote this tweet tomorrow.
Rym: I'll record recount the story of a dude who built a zipline for a summer camp.
Rym: Okay with a 143 foot vertical drop tower to tower bringing a test sandbag up to around 55 to 65 miles an hour How do you stop at the other end?
Scott: Uh
Rym: the story is this dude had got a bunch of like a big budget to make a fun thing at his summer camp like a bunch of money and He and a bunch of people who knew a lot about construction and knew fuck all about engineering or safety Built a zipline that they thought would be cool.
Rym: Having imagined someone making a roller coaster who didn't know how roller coasters actually work He made a zipline that if any human being used it in any capacity would kill them All right.
Scott: Did anyone actually use it and die?
Rym: No, so he basically got he posted in the forum and he was like yo guys I need some got any suggestions on how to make this work.
Rym: The kids would come in too fast and the people in something awful Responded basically saying you dumb shit.
Rym: This could never work, right?
Scott: You are an idiot who will kill children as someone who is at a summer camp.
Scott: several summer camps with ziplines.
Scott: They were lame-o ziplines.
Scott: You don't have a fancy zipline at a summer camp.
Scott: It wasn't the kind where you go across the top of the rainforest.
Scott: It was the kind we've done.
Rym: that it's real fun.
Scott: It was the kind where you just go we and then get off.
Rym: It's the kind it's the South Park guys, right?
Scott: And the way that they worked was you went into the woods.
Scott: you climbed a tree at the top of the tree.
Scott: You tied yourself safely to the rope, right?
Scott: You they let you go And you would go down But then there was a whole bunch of rope after you hit the bottom that was going up.
Scott: It was like a sagging rope.
Scott: Yeah, and you didn't end at the other end of the rope, right?
Scott: You would sort of hit the bottom of the curve go up a little bit and then come backwards.
Scott: So yeah Eventually you'd rest in the middle and then they would let the main rope down with like a pulley system and then they'd unhook.
Scott: Yeah, this is and they would pull the zipline back up and it was a saggy rope, right and you would land in the middle.
Scott: It's not a straight rope from high to low where you end at the other end and crash into the opposite post and die.
Rym: Well, so this is very similar to an adjacent story called Grover house, which is about a dude who Effectively posted a bunch of photos like hey, I'm renovating my house cuz I'm so cool Check this out.
Rym: and something awful people responded saying things like wasn't that a load-bearing wall?
Rym: It's a similar situation.
Rym: It did so.
Rym: well, you can read about Grover house.
Scott: I'm not going to read over.
Scott: house is Amazing I'm sure it is.
Scott: I will amazingly stay away from.
Rym: yeah, so this is an oral history of the rip line.
Rym: So what do you got?
Scott: Oh, yeah, this is a really simple thing of the day.
Scott: It's just a little tiny video on Twitter.
Scott: The caption is Street Fighter is getting a new fan creative with its merch.
Rym: I was gonna say Street Fighters got a new fan.
Scott: But yeah, I don't know if this is fan merch.
Scott: I don't know if this is actual merch or just something someone made and it doesn't matter what it is.
Scott: is You know imagine a stick fan right?
Scott: Yeah, you know an old-school one the kind I have in my bedroom.
Scott: It's a stick at the top of the stick as a circular fan.
Scott: Yeah, but the fan oscillates.
Rym: So it turns left and right and she's got that little nub in in the back to control the oscillation like fans head.
Scott: So what they have done is at the top of the fan They have put a little thing that is Blanca and he looks like he's getting hit.
Scott: and right next to him They've got Ken doing a hurricane kick on a stick and the stick is in the part of the fan a little nub the little Nub that spins to control the oscillation.
Scott: So Ken is actually doing a hurricane kick next to the Blanca.
Scott: and then really the delicious icing on the cake is the e Honda Attached to the front of the fan.
Rym: the first reply to this tweet that e Honda is fucking dope.
Scott: right the wind from the fan Right is blowing into the Honda.
Scott: He's attached to the front grill.
Scott: His wind is hitting his back.
Scott: They've cut his hand off and attached it with some kind of spring or a pipe cleaner.
Scott: It might be a pipe cleaner, but a pipe cleaner has got to be strong or anyway paper.
Rym: I used to be papercraft.
Scott: maybe it because of the wind?
Scott: his hey, it might actually be three separate hands.
Rym: It looks like it's three separate hands flapping back and forth in the wind.
Scott: But yeah, he's doing a hundred hand.
Scott: slap there Thanks to the wind from the fan.
Scott: It is impressive and they added Street Fighter music to the little video.
Scott: I create a masterpiece work of art.
Scott: Enjoy it for it's like 30 seconds and then push rewind and watch it again in the moment.
Rym: Book is the first novel the tale of Genji.
Rym: We'll be live at PAX West with not one but two panels one on Friday on one on Saturday.
Scott: You're really getting through this meta moment quickly.
Rym: Yeah, cuz I got stuff to do.
Scott: It's a real moment.
Scott: I'm going somewhere not even a minute.
Rym: It's a minute moment and we are not going to talk about the Democratic primary debates.
Rym: No, but I will just remind you that GeekNights did formally endorse back in May Elizabeth Warren.
Scott: I have not changed my mind after watching the debate only reinforced my decision.
Rym: I did watch the debates and I am now even more solidly in Warren's game.
Rym: Well, there we go.
Rym: So that's it.
Rym: Let's talk about cheese.
Scott: All right, so I think we've done a cheese already.
Scott: Let's go home.
Rym: I don't think we've done a cheese show.
Scott: him deleted the cheese show so we'll have to make a replacement cheese.
Rym: So if I had to rank the classes of food that are my favorite foods like broad categories number one is breads And number two is cheeses and then like other stuff is after that like Bread and cheese are some of my favorite things.
Scott: and combining the two I mean, I can't rank like what you got me a rank bread cheese Sugars meat.
Rym: so you think about in terms of what if you had to give one up?
Rym: Like I would give up meat before I'd give up cheese.
Rym: Yes, I would give up meat before I'd give up bread.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Yeah, that's that's my ring.
Rym: Okay That's how I rank this.
Rym: like there is almost nothing.
Scott: I would be willing to Give up first cheese or ice cream.
Rym: I would give up ice cream first cheese or cookies.
Rym: I would give up cookies first.
Rym: Oh, I fucking love cheese.
Scott: You love cookies.
Scott: I do.
Rym: It's a regular Sophie's choice here Not that so So Cheese.
Rym: I am very thankful that I am NOT lactose intolerant And if I was I would I would just like drink shots of lactate.
Scott: Yeah I don't understand why people who are lactose intolerant Maybe like I've heard.
Scott: maybe doesn't work that well now we're getting off topic.
Scott: But like I would just the streamer the stream.
Rym: someone just said how we went from cheese to this.
Scott: Anyway, I would take I would just take the lactate pill then eat the cheese.
Scott: I wouldn't give up the cheese ever.
Rym: Yep Never you know like that guy right listen to an NPR show a long time ago with the talk to this dude Who is deathly allergic to shellfish.
Rym: and once a year?
Rym: He basically eats a bunch of shrimp and then goes to the hospital.
Rym: That's how much he loves shrimp.
Scott: That's a guy.
Rym: I feel like I would be that way with cheese.
Scott: Why do you need to go to the hospital?
Scott: Then?
Scott: Why don't eat it at the hospital?
Rym: Oh, yeah, just go to the hospital and be like.
Rym: so listen I'm about to eat all that because the hospital might stop you from eating the shrimp.
Scott: Do eat it in the waiting room.
Rym: So what's your favorite kind of cheese?
Scott: can't pick just one kind of cheese.
Rym: We'll treat this more like movies cuz I don't like.
Rym: what are your top five movies is a question But I do like name some of your favorite movies.
Scott: Oh, I like a gorgonzola cheese because it is a stinky cheese But it is not one of those stinky cheese that is so ridiculously stinky.
Scott: Like you're just trying to prove how ballsy you are by eating the stinkiest cheese.
Rym: Well, it's not that like rancid stinky or that ammonia stick exactly and it's not that fungus II blue thing.
Rym: It's like take a little bit because like straight blue cheese, which I love it's good.
Scott: But like I guess gorgonzola is like a subset of blue cheese.
Scott: That's just like superior, right?
Scott: So I was like when someone says like a little spicier, right?
Scott: So when I see something that's like blue cheese dressing or blue cheese on a burger, I'm kind of mad.
Scott: But when it says gorgonzola, I'm like, I'm in.
Scott: yep I love.
Rym: so I'll just cut up gorgonzola and put it on crackers sometimes.
Scott: That's okay Yeah, but that's the thing is even though it is a stinky cheese and it's stinkiness is not ridiculously powerful You know that needs to be like, you know, whatever I do mostly I think maybe 100% of the time I don't eat gorgonzola straight.
Scott: It's got to be in a salad.
Scott: salad is like the best Salad.
Scott: we used to get those two letters Right, that's like the best but you got it.
Scott: It has to have some sort of vehicle.
Scott: Yeah for it, right?
Scott: You just eat like but with the spoon.
Rym: I'm sure someone does make a French onion soup, but melt gorgonzola instead of mozzarella over the top.
Rym: Oh that is that is a powerful soup.
Scott: That is literally hot shit.
Rym: Well, not shit though, literally hot But good shit, yep, or or you make a grilled cheese with another more like mild gennaro cheese But then you put a little bit of gorgonzola in that you can't just have gorgonzola sandwich gorgonzola cheese with just gorgonzola.
Rym: I don't think that's a good idea.
Scott: No, no No, if you did make like a big sub right with say likes You know some deli meats and some maybe some even some other cheeses maybe lettuce tomato onion something like that.
Scott: You could Sprinkle gorgonzola bits down the middle of the sandwich.
Scott: Yeah, that's good - and that would work.
Rym: Also, I like gorgonzola on a burger a lot.
Scott: It's okay as long as not more so than blue cheese.
Scott: Oh, yeah, but I mean like I just said if I saw blue cheese burger I would pass but if I saw a gorgonzola burger, I would order.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I'm trying to find lists of cheeses.
Rym: There's just too many cheeses, right?
Scott: I mean, so I know right let's talk about the elephant in the room, right?
Scott: Obviously fake cheese, we're not even gonna go to fake cheese.
Scott: Fuck your easy cheese.
Scott: Fuck your Velveeta's get that shit out of here.
Scott: I don't even eat that stuff.
Scott: It's garbage.
Scott: So I also hate anything Like Cheetos or cheese puffs where it's like this nasty cheese powder that's on there.
Rym: I was cheese.
Rym: It's cheese.
Scott: It's our real cheese.
Scott: They taste actually like cheddar.
Scott: It's real cheddar.
Scott: same thing with cheddar goldfish.
Scott: I can eat those two.
Scott: Yep, it's not.
Scott: those aren't a matter of like a cheese poof where it's like this powder.
Scott: that's like blasted on.
Scott: It's a matter of like.
Scott: no the cheese is integrated into the cheese at cracker.
Scott: is real cheese.
Scott: It tastes like real cheese.
Scott: It's good.
Rym: So I basically won't.
Scott: it's not a cheeto or dorito where it's like orange fire of poison.
Rym: I will never seek out on purpose or eat by design American cheese.
Scott: Okay, so this is just too bland.
Scott: Well, okay.
Scott: So here's the thing with America.
Scott: I got some American cheese.
Rym: You can always do better in any situation.
Scott: Most people Have experienced only Kraft singles American cheese, which tastes like nothing.
Scott: Yeah, they don't taste bad They just taste like nothing.
Rym: even a good American cheese is no.
Rym: Kraft single is not as good as literally any other cheese.
Scott: There are good better American cheeses.
Rym: If you want a generic American cheese Just get like a Colby Jack or a Jack cheese instead.
Scott: if you were to buy like Lando lakes or Boar's Head American cheese Which I guess are normal higher-end brands that are available at every deli counter in America It's still not worth it.
Rym: There's no reason to eat that shit.
Scott: They are not the same.
Rym: Trying to defend American cheese.
Rym: You really tried to set this up.
Scott: I know why you're trying to attack American cheese.
Rym: not an elephant in the room to understand that American cheese.
Rym: It's just not worth eating any circumstances.
Scott: It is not an exciting fancy cheese by any stretch of the imagination.
Rym: Monterey Jack the like most flavorless generic cheese.
Scott: It is not a strong flavor that these good American cheeses have.
Rym: but what are you?
Rym: Gonna wrap a hot dog in American cheese.
Rym: Like is that we're gonna eat that your meal now?
Scott: That's not we use it for.
Rym: but that good not All right Crap, you use American cheese for other than a Philly cheesesteak, which is the only acceptable place.
Rym: because that's what a Philly cheesesteak A lot of things with it because why would you waste bread on a grilled cheese?
Scott: It is not a strong flavor, but it is a flavor.
Rym: I'm only gonna not disagree that it is a flavor.
Scott: That is not a flavor that you will find with other cheese.
Scott: American cheese does have a distinct.
Scott: you gave me a real not craft Singles, I mean, I guess I could tell a craft single just by the texture because it has like this plastic enos to it.
Rym: You gave me an American cheese and I was blindfolded.
Rym: I would say this tastes like Nothing, this must be American cheese.
Scott: No If you gave me an American cheese Right, it has a distinct flavor a real American cheese.
Scott: That is not the same as say a quite adjacent Munster cheese, right?
Scott: Even though they're pretty close in their power levels, right and it is a sometimes useful cheese.
Scott: I will not often choose it But I will also not you know Put it down as much as Rym.
Scott: who wants to just wipe it off the face of the earth?
Rym: So in the I found a mental floss article about American cheese, okay in the old days, you know, though, however First white is complete bullshit.
Scott: They taste the same.
Scott: It's just food coloring.
Scott: You should order the yellow cuz.
Scott: it's cheaper cuz.
Scott: for some reason.
Scott: stupid Americans Just are want the white color and not the yellow color.
Scott: Just save money.
Scott: It tastes exactly the same get yellow American if you're gonna get American.
Rym: so pretty much almost all American cheese is just cheese food.
Rym: It's not actually cheese.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: Like it like even the fancy stuff is processed.
Rym: It's not.
Rym: actually they can't call it.
Scott: I mean, I mean what's your team?
Scott: All these other cheese at the telecounter are also processed.
Rym: Yeah, but Munster has a flavor and is in American cheese.
Rym: Yeah, nothing.
Scott: No, it has a flavor.
Scott: So I'm gonna quote you just hate American cheese so much you avoid it.
Scott: So you don't even know.
Scott: it's late.
Rym: classically before Factory processed stuff at the market American cheese was actually just a blend of cheddar and Colby.
Rym: Okay If if you give me a blend of cheddar and Colby sure that is fine I dare you to find an American cheese that is called American cheese.
Rym: That is actually just a blend of cheddar and Colby.
Rym: Also, what's with outside of the Midwest?
Rym: No one has Colby cheese.
Rym: Like I rarely find Colby cheese anywhere.
Rym: That's true.
Scott: It is not a thing here in the north in New York area.
Rym: as a kid I guess go to the deli and buy like a brick of Colby.
Scott: Colby is not a frequently used cheese.
Scott: I don't really see it on restaurant menus.
Scott: I don't see it on burgers.
Scott: You can get Colby Jack.
Scott: I don't see it at the grocery.
Scott: I think that the Italian cheeses are sort of like have most of the the market share here in the New York zone.
Scott: Your parmesans your provolone.
Rym: pure Colby cheese is not that good for a lot of applications Like it's good on a salad maybe or something, but it's kind of crumbly.
Scott: I think it's the kind of cheese you'll see a lot of times and like maybe like a Cobb salad Which is not my favorite.
Rym: Cobb salad is one of my favorite kinds of salads.
Scott: not into it.
Rym: But that's the reason why if you find Colby cheese in most of the coastal cities in America It's always Colby Jack.
Rym: It's Colby cheese and Jack sort of mixed together because Jack makes it more meltable and like usable like it makes it more generic and easy to cook with.
Scott: yeah, Jack is like the number one cheese you see on the Plate to put cheese on crackers because it's like the generic cheese.
Scott: right that will not.
Scott: that will not offend.
Scott: They'll be right everybody.
Rym: It's no one's sensibility, right?
Scott: It doesn't taste like nothing Right, it doesn't.
Rym: it tastes close to nothing.
Rym: Jack is only a step above American cheese.
Scott: also.
Scott: people usually would use like a pepper jack for that that has peppery stuff in it.
Rym: Well, yeah, cuz you got to add something to it.
Rym: cuz the cheese by itself is not that good.
Rym: It's actually kind of springy and a little rubbery like it's not good doesn't know?
Scott: it's a little tough.
Scott: Yeah Fight into it or like, you know to get the knife through is a little bit of a little bit effort.
Rym: Yep, and a Janae Jap your jack cheese grilled cheese sandwich not really better.
Scott: It's not a cheese for grilling it's just the cheese you're putting on a cracker.
Scott: Yeah, no, so it's like you have that and it's like people who would avoid your powerful stinky cheese.
Scott: Right and you know don't want to eat a cheese.
Scott: It's a weird color.
Scott: That's what that Jack cheese is for.
Rym: Jack cheese is for boring.
Scott: It goes on the cheese plate to be eaten by the boring people.
Scott: It has a flavor, right?
Scott: It's a stronger flavor than an American cheese, but it's not.
Scott: you know, I'm not Buying at the store really.
Rym: so in terms of a cheese.
Rym: I like to just eat by itself.
Rym: I'm pretty much if I. actually while I do like some stinky cheeses the cheeses I like to eat the most are like a port salut a Cheddar like just straight-up cheddar.
Rym: I will just eat on crackers cheddar.
Scott: I feel like I got a like, you know, I use it to like melt onto something.
Scott: Usually I like cheddars when there's some kind of barbecue sauce involved.
Scott: Oh, yeah I can see that like if you're making a burger or it's like a chicken sandwich and you're getting some barbecue sauce on it and Maybe some onion and it's like the cheese that's got to get.
Scott: the only cheddar cheese goes in that mix.
Rym: No other cheese fits in that like the cheese by itself I like just like a white goat cheese, but a cheddar cheese doesn't work on like a sub sandwich But like a port salut.
Rym: or I also like manchego and like that class of cheese is a lot.
Scott: Mm-hmm I mean if I'm not going down the barbecue road.
Scott: Alright, if I'm melting a cheese onto a thing It's got to be the best possible cheese is something.
Scott: and like the Gruyere family.
Rym: Oh, all right That means we got to talk about grilled cheeses.
Rym: The best grilled cheese is Gruyere plus a different cheese Anything.
Scott: there are other cheeses that are like in the Gruyere family.
Rym: Take a Gruyere or a Gruyere adjacent because they put one other cheese.
Rym: It's not only their flavor that works So well, they melt is so good.
Scott: It's the way they melt makes it perfect for the function.
Scott: Yeah It's like there are a lot of cheeses that might actually taste great if you were to say grilled cheese them.
Scott: But you they don't melt nicely and they make a mess.
Rym: or they get too messy or maybe they don't melt enough Or they take a lot of effort like you could make a grilled cheese with them But it takes a lot of effort.
Rym: with like a Gruyere like Gruyere Swiss together works really well.
Scott: It was like designed for melting.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So, uh in terms this is more of a cold sandwich cheese.
Rym: Yeah, if I make a lot of time or a burger cheese, yeah, sometimes Swiss is good on a burger by the mushroom.
Rym: I like Emma Emmental better than Swiss for that.
Scott: Yeah, what I tend to use Swiss for is like a lot of times what I'll do when I'm Lazy is for dinner.
Scott: I'll make a cheese sandwich.
Scott: I'll buy a bread Yeah, and I'll just not.
Scott: not a hot sandwich a cold sandwich.
Scott: I'll put on you know, no meats, right?
Scott: I'll just put on like cheese cheese cheese cheese lettuce tomato onion Maybe not even lettuce peppers salt and pepper maybe a dressing right?
Scott: It's basically a salad on a bread But that I like a salad on a bread and that's where I bust out my Swiss.
Scott: I'll bust out provolone.
Scott: Yeah bust out Munster.
Scott: Those are the kinds of cheeses that go on the cold sandwich.
Scott: Also, if I am getting a sandwich even with meats Yeah, right and I do do and it's it's kind of sandwich where I am gonna put cheese with the meat together.
Scott: Those are the same cheeses that I will go to right, you know.
Scott: provolone plus, you know, some kind of Italian meats together.
Scott: This is how it works.
Rym: Yep in turn.
Rym: I'm a big fan of Like the breeze and all the like fungusy cheeses, but I actually do not like the rind like.
Rym: that's just a thing I don't know.
Scott: I do not eat the rind either.
Rym: I love brie, but I'm this dude.
Scott: I gotta eat the mushy part.
Scott: That's like you can good part.
Rym: You can spoon it.
Scott: It's so mushy right that inside the rind.
Scott: Yeah, but like the rind itself It's like it's all hard and it tastes too strong and weird.
Rym: Well, it tastes too Fungusy and like musty.
Scott: Yeah, it's not.
Rym: I mean, I don't like people can like that like I can see the appeal.
Rym: I just don't personally enjoy that.
Rym: that's partly why as much as I like brie I tend to go with port salut because it's similar to the brie in terms of like how you would eat it and like why You'd like it, but there's like an inedible rind.
Rym: You just don't eat You just get the good port salut in the middle and you get a lot more of it.
Rym: I'm also a fan of like Huntsman cheeses and like all the sort of like really strong flavored cheeses that aren't that stinky But they have a really strong flavor like or like Stilton.
Rym: Love me a still.
Rym: the Stilton is like the dreaming cheese Arguably probably just because it causes significant indigestion.
Rym: It may or may not have chemicals.
Rym: that mess with dreams.
Rym: It's jury's still out.
Rym: I do like it.
Scott: Oh, I think wasn't like Comte.
Scott: I think that was the Gruyere adjacent cheese.
Rym: I think so.
Rym: Yeah, that was good for me.
Rym: I'm not a cheese expert.
Rym: Our friend Natalie is way.
Scott: Yeah Shop in New York Murray's cheese.
Rym: Not only can know they're opening one right next like right down the street.
Rym: Oh like right there.
Scott: It's a chain.
Scott: I've only seen it in New York City, but it is a chain and their outlet is Oh, yeah over by the rail yard in this neighborhood.
Rym: You can go there and buy like they're defected a whole wheel.
Rym: You can buy a whole wheel that's defective because it got dented for like 10% of the normal price.
Scott: But yeah, it's it's a chain.
Scott: I've only seen in New York City.
Scott: It might be elsewhere.
Scott: They have such a crazy variety of cheeses there like it's amazing top-flight cheeses down to the cheapy cheeses.
Scott: Right, you know, it's just a cheese shop.
Scott: It's amazing and Natalie goes there and like that's like her favorite stuff.
Scott: She's all into the cheese as I go and I'm just like let's try that cheese.
Scott: I never heard of whatever.
Rym: Yeah, I do like the smoked cheese is like the Gouda.
Scott: Yeah, that's a good one.
Scott: It's a good.
Scott: It's a good one.
Rym: I tend to only like Gouda like by itself though.
Rym: Like I don't really cook with it I don't really like try to make things out of it.
Rym: I just eat it Like I do separate cheeses and do the cheese they put on salads the ones I put on sandwiches the ones I'll just eat As a primary thing and the ones I will cook with Mmm like mozzarella.
Rym: Actually, I will cook with and I'll just eat because I love mozzarella Mmm, especially like a good and I like.
Rym: I really like cheese curds like just gennaro cheese curd, but I think the mozzarella right is like growing up.
Scott: that was when like the the String cheese was invented.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: So it's like first of all, you're in love with mozzarella cuz on pizza, right?
Scott: It's like you can't really.
Scott: you mean you can you can and maybe mix some other cheeses onto the pizza But mozzarella has got to be there.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: It's just like that wet cheese, you know It melts on to the pizza at the high temperature.
Scott: Right, you don't let it go so far that it gets burnt and crusty.
Scott: Yeah, right It's like, you know, but when it's more dried out you you know You can you can pull it into the strings you can tear apart with your hands, right?
Scott: It's like that's.
Scott: it's you know, but definitely I'm all about buying the the raw mozzarella.
Scott: It's still in some kind of liquid or a ball or something like that the fresh mozzarella.
Scott: I don't buy, you know, the shredded stuff anymore.
Scott: Really?
Scott: Yeah, it's all dried out.
Scott: It's not as you know, not as good like that.
Rym: I usually get a big block of feta usually Greek but sometimes French or Bulgarian like they're fine.
Scott: I mean, I'm in the.
Scott: I live in Greek land so like every grocery store has like several different feta.
Scott: so
Rym: I'm not gonna lie I Enjoy Bulgarian feta more than Greek feta and I'll make Greek and Turkish salads with Bulgarian feta primarily
Scott: For me, I mean it is a situation for me where Sometimes I'll get feta cheese like, you know Like you'll get a salad a Greek salad and they'll be the feta wrapped in the leaves in there.
Scott: Yeah, and like.
Scott: sometimes it's like, oh, this is so great.
Scott: this feta cheese, you know, it's working great crumbled up in this salad it's you know, but sometimes I get it and he's just like, uh, and I'm since it's always been the case the more expensive feta is just Better right?
Scott: It's like I wasn't the one who chose the feta But there were like times where I eat it and it's like ew and times I eat it where it's like.
Rym: So this is one of those.
Scott: pretty sure it's a. I only like expensive feta.
Rym: And yeah, cheese is one of those things where except for like these basic cheeses that are very ubiquitous in America Most cheeses the more money you pay up to a point.
Rym: It is just better.
Rym: Yeah, like way better and that sucks.
Rym: But that's the reality.
Scott: I think there's that series of videos with like food expert.
Scott: I think they'd one just went up today with mustard expert.
Scott: Whoo, but Yeah, I think we made it thing of the day when we discovered it because there was cheese.
Scott: expert was like one of their first videos.
Scott: So watch that.
Rym: Yeah, so on that note I think we're gonna stop here cuz I gotta go eat some cheese is happier before.
Scott: I talk about some Parmesan and sprinkly cheese.
Rym: All right, we'll do one last bit.
Rym: So these are the the accent cheeses that you sprinkle on to another dish, right?
Scott: You get your parmesan.
Scott: It's usually Italian, right?
Scott: It's parmesan pecorino slash romano.
Rym: I tend to do this lately with Manchego.
Rym: I'll just read Manchego over stuff.
Scott: Yeah, if you get the microplane you can do it with a lot of cheeses that you normally couldn't do it.
Scott: We know it as long as the cheese is hard enough.
Rym: Yeah, which Secret?
Rym: if you got a cheese that isn't hard enough just put it in the freezer for like a minute Yep, and then you can shred it right.
Scott: sometimes though you shred it and then like if your dish is hot it melts and Disappears and sort of mixes into the dish Like with the chili.
Scott: you want that sometimes with the chili, but sometimes you want the coating.
Rym: no I wanted to mix in usually anyway, but yeah the Parmesan cheese You definitely I never get it grated anymore.
Scott: I will grate it at definitely have to watch out for the ones with the sawdust filler and stuff like that.
Scott: It's not gonna hurt you.
Scott: but it's like yeah the already grated Parmesan even if it's fancy brand It's like no there's filler and stuff in there.
Scott: It's not the best cheese and it goes bad quicker, right?
Scott: You want to get the solid piece of Parmesan even if it's just a little sliver triangle.
Scott: You can grate it yourself if there's mold on there.
Scott: You can scrape it off and start shredding underneath, right?
Scott: That's the way you go.
Scott: And if you got the monies, it's like actually yes be like special product.
Scott: Parmesan o reggiano is just better.
Scott: Yeah, it's like just go for it Buy like a tiny slivery triangle of it cuz a lot of money and shred it yourself.
Scott: It's worth it.
Scott: So one thing
Rym: I like about living in New York is that it's very easy to just on my way home Like if I want a fancy cheese for something I will buy like a Tiny bit of that cheese at a cheese shop and have it home and I eat it all in that meal And there's no chance of it going to waste just no chance of it going bad.
Rym: I'm not gonna try to explain to you how to not let your cheese go bad.
Scott: Just like Google it Right, and I guess we're not gonna talk about any sort of creamed cheeses here, right?
Rym: No, we can't.
Rym: that's a whole topic.
Rym: I feel like we talked about that.
Rym: We have to do a whole show about it.
Scott: This is the bagel show just on cream cheese the bagels.
Rym: I could do a whole other creamy cheeses like mascarpone.
Rym: I could do a whole show just on that.
Rym: Okay, GeekNights is now cheese nights.
Scott: cheese nights.
Scott: We just live stream ourselves, we don't but we're running out of cheese knowledge.
Scott: you'd have to actually get cheese experts on the show.
Rym: Oh, yeah, we know because we are color and commentary.
Scott: I'm sure there's a cheese podcast out there somewhere.
Rym: Yeah, go find that if you want to know more about cheese.
Rym: I just.
Rym: my primary interest in cheese is eating it.
Rym: Yeah, that's right with wine with port.
Scott: I'm gonna eat some for dinner from I'm a - I'm gonna get some.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night
Rym: and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Greg Oliver, Alan Joyce, Heidi Mayne Dickel, Just Like a Dude, Guy Kishore, Tavishan, Linki, Gee, Graham, Finn, Jennifer, Hitchcock, Chris, Midgiff, MyStady.com, Jay Bench, Scootalonely, Shawn Yeager, Nicholas, Brando, Mr.
Rym: Strong, Strachan, 4-2-1, Creations, Like, Johannes, Sebastian, Bacharach, Ominous, McIntyre, Cyan, Mancer, Thunder, Shervin, Van Horl, Rory, Superboy, Clinton, Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Durope, and Lander, Finn,
Scott: Dread,
Rym: Lenny, Tenebrae, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, Thomas Hahn, and I leave you with a song to which I Honestly know all the lyrics
Scott: You.