Rym: It's Wednesday December 11th 2019 I'm Rym and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We are talking about manga dis Manga distribution in the United States, let's do this All right, so we were at a little PAX Unplugged over the weekend.
Rym: Yeah, a little back some plug right before a bunch of other packs is yeah, which is in my least favorite city.
Rym: Well, I like how you tried to start a fight with the people in the crowd.
Scott: I know that's my plan.
Scott: The good news is Philadelphia and back props to them for not throwing anything at me, which is what they're usually do.
Rym: Oh, yeah, cuz I had all the batteries on city.
Scott: It's even really close to Christmas time.
Scott: their favorite time to throw shit.
Rym: It was uh, my favorite moment was when Scott was like fuck Philadelphia and half the crowd's like fuck you Instantly and I'm just like, all right.
Scott: Well, that's how it's gotta be.
Rym: Well, cuz my point there was.
Rym: I like a city I can fight with more than it's like DC Like I have this grudging respect for and they're like, I guess you're a real city different towards respect depending but Philly I can just have a fight with.
Scott: Yeah, at least DC right.
Scott: most of the population, you know, regardless of your feelings toward there, you know They're racist sports team or other things.
Scott: Are you know?
Scott: honorable public servants, you know, the elected ones are usually a problem.
Scott: But yeah, the appointed and you know federal employees are usually bureaucrats hard-working good people's bureaucrats.
Rym: They're mostly okay, right?
Scott: Yeah, they got the contractors of lobbyists.
Scott: Those are the bad people too, right?
Rym: But whatever Oh, I do have some batteries.
Rym: I could huck one at you if you're missed out on getting a battery.
Rym: huck that yeah I'm pretty good.
Scott: No, so while we were there right, you know, I Rym decided to pay a zillion dollars and take Amtrak $58.
Rym: Yeah, like not that much more.
Scott: I paid like ten dollars.
Scott: Yeah, say little bus, but we say the bus and the train land at the spell the land.
Scott: They come out of the sky.
Scott: No, they stop at the same place because the bus just the bus stop is literally in front of the Amtrak train station All right in New York.
Rym: Where is?
Rym: it is over by the tick-tock diner stuff.
Scott: No, it's near Javits.
Scott: You take the seven.
Scott: Oh, I mean actually there's more than one but that's the one we went to.
Rym: Yeah Anyway, cuz we took the we took a late train like the 9 40 p.m Train cuz we went to a long dinner with everybody after packs.
Scott: Anyway, so On the way in right it's like I don't know where the hell any thing fucking is in Philadelphia Which is weird to me and what I know or anything is there.
Rym: I was making funny afford at the con partly cuz.
Rym: like I don't know a lot about like every city on earth But any place I go I have a vague idea of the geography.
Rym: Like I know generally what I know the local West I know uptown and down.
Scott: I know the local geography of Where like the area around where I was like even at Boston, right?
Scott: It's like I know the geography of.
Scott: if I walk in a place then I know where I was when I walked, right?
Rym: So I know around no I'm talking like Philly There's Center City like to order away from Center City.
Rym: Like you don't like.
Rym: I know the not know anything about that like Boston.
Rym: I know where Southie is Like.
Rym: I know like I imagine it's.
Scott: I imagine it's south.
Rym: That's actually where PAX East is.
Scott: Okay Well, anyway, I you know, I know where I walk rights like in Seattle.
Scott: I walked over like most of Seattle.
Scott: That's why I know my way her and I've done it so many times.
Scott: I haven't gone up that hill right and I've ridden the light rail Which I can see out the window and that sort of.
Scott: let me know right know the general relation of some things.
Scott: Yeah, right in Seattle, but like Philly, you know, it's like alright.
Scott: Well, I know there's the train station and I know where things are around the convention center But I don't know.
Scott: in between is like black empty space It's like it's like a RTS and it's all black right train station always out of town I don't know.
Scott: Anyway, all I know is where I've walked and removed the fog of war.
Rym: How do you I don't know how you go to a city and not know like basic things about that city.
Scott: But anyway, so yeah like Rym was saying he made fun of me because I used a cab to go from the train to the Con when there is both to navigate the fog of war zone when there is but one quickly and with low effort.
Rym: There is a subway line that goes from the train station to the convention Connected to our hotel and there's a trolley line that runs like every three minutes that also goes between those two places.
Scott: He made fun of me for that.
Scott: So on the way home We go down into the subway or trolley or whatever the hell down into whatever.
Scott: we used it to get to the train station that Night, all right, and we looking around and I'm like, all right.
Scott: I would try to figure it out.
Rym: All right, you buy a ticket.
Scott: so we go to the ticket machine.
Scott: Yeah, you take a machine has two options.
Scott: Yeah, we push the option on the left.
Scott: It does not none of these choices out.
Scott: there were three choices.
Scott: after pushing that one None of them were to buy an individual ride.
Scott: The cheapest one was a full day pass for $6 and I'm like that is not right.
Scott: So I chose the one on the right one.
Scott: that was for refilling some kind of other pass.
Rym: just get a pass.
Rym: That's like a metro card.
Rym: It just works.
Rym: The screen were to get a single ride pass.
Scott: They were all more than the two.
Scott: so one.
Rym: There are different machines that are aimed at tourists that sell the single ride like magnetic stripe.
Scott: There's only one kind of machine in that Back.
Rym: that is not true.
Scott: Well in the why had this first one there were only one kind of machine.
Rym: I have bought single rides there.
Scott: in the spot that we were there was only one kind of.
Rym: Same went into Grand Central went to a random like Metro card only machine and couldn't figure out how to buy a ticket.
Scott: then Went to right.
Scott: Amanda had the same problem, too.
Scott: we could not figure out.
Rym: just bought the Philly equivalent of a metro card and put like a Dollar or two on it and would have been good to go.
Scott: That is that was not clear how to do this and not without buying a. the only option I could find that was not a zillion Way too expensive using six dollar day.
Rym: But you are never allowed to make fun of tourists having trouble with the metro.
Scott: Figure it out either.
Scott: Why are you making fun of me?
Scott: Like I'm stupid.
Scott: I'm pointing I'm saying is I'm saying this was not hard?
Scott: And I know I'm saying we are not stupid.
Scott: I'm saying the Philly system is as awful as I said, it was.
Scott: I'm right.
Rym: I'm saying I use those same machines.
Scott: are you saying a man is stupid also, she couldn't figure it out?
Rym: You two definitely have a problem with.
Scott: you couldn't figure out how to buy a single ride ticket.
Scott: We could not figure out which side of the map was on.
Scott: the wall was like some partial map.
Scott: that didn't show like a map Of the city.
Scott: it just showed like a line and some dots and it didn't say which one we were at or we couldn't tell Which one's got all over.
Scott: that we couldn't show which direction was east or west we couldn't.
Scott: it says on the platform We looked on the platform.
Scott: We couldn't tell which side of the platform was going east or west or whether we should be going east or west or what kind?
Scott: Of train was coming to that guy.
Rym: All I'm saying is you sound like a tourist and I don't know why you had all these problems.
Scott: I'm saying that the system was garbage.
Rym: We used the subway to get it to get back and forth.
Rym: We also use the subway to go to the restaurant which was east in the other side of the city.
Rym: Well, and then we took it from there back to the hotel and then back to the train station.
Scott: the Philly Public transit is great garbage and has awful design.
Rym: All right, uh, I Don't understand how you had these problems because I use the exact.
Scott: Amanda had also had these problems.
Scott: So when there are also other people coming in who also couldn't figure out what the fuck to do and they had a booth with No one in it to ask for help
Rym: Okay, so I you are never allowed to make fun of people in New York having trouble with the Metro cards machine That
Scott: your card is very well designed and has no problems.
Rym: I think they're equal.
Rym: And in fact, actually the Philly system is pretty easier to use.
Scott: Yeah, okay I'll go next time I go down there.
Scott: I'll take a video.
Scott: I'll make a video comparison of the Metro card machine versus whatever fucking machine they had down there.
Scott: Okay, Metro card machine It's like by Metro card.
Scott: one ride boom done.
Scott: There was no one Got.
Rym: you realize New York is phasing out the one Ride and they charge a premium for that.
Rym: it cost more than buying a normal Metro card and filling up.
Scott: I was taking one ride for the whole year.
Scott: I want to pay 275.
Scott: There was no to seven.
Scott: That was what was promised.
Scott: one ride 275 there was no option on that screen.
Scott: got for a single 275 ride.
Rym: You realize New York.
Scott: anyway, I navigated every menu on the device.
Rym: not you realize in New York You have to pay an extra dollar to get a Metro card.
Scott: Yeah, well, that's a different thing.
Scott: But the point is there was the same way in Philly.
Rym: You could have just spent the extra.
Rym: it's like a dollar 20.
Rym: There is no time the equivalent of a measure.
Scott: No, I navigated every menu.
Scott: There was not option.
Rym: My wallet that I bought from one of those machines.
Rym: like three years ago.
Scott: There was no option on that men in any menu on that machine to buy one ride and Scott.
Rym: Well, like I said the one ride.
Rym: machines that sell a paper ticket.
Rym: Those are only used by tourists.
Rym: That's an item part of the station.
Rym: I've used them.
Rym: They're.
Scott: there's also no option to buy a card with one ride on it.
Rym: Uh, yeah, there is.
Scott: I did so and also see that you have the card.
Scott: But I'm telling you two intelligent people tried to use this machine.
Scott: even if it was possible to get that card from the machine the Design of the machine and the design of the system was to blame.
Scott: we could not figure it out.
Rym: I think that's really funny.
Rym: I don't understand what your problem was.
Scott: I think it is an awful garbage public transit system.
Scott: So we had plenty of time so we walked.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I think the Philly transit system is great.
Scott: I think it's I think it's trash and their whole city's trash burn it down.
Scott: But they seem to do that on purpose so I don't have to really encourage them.
Rym: I would say that Philly probably has the third best transit system in America.
Scott: I mean that's like saying oh the third least smelly tire.
Scott: I would also say that Philly's Even the New York subway, which is great is garbage compared to actual transit in other countries.
Scott: But I'm saying so if you're third best that's like wow, you're worse than the garbage.
Scott: That's tolerable.
Rym: I'm also saying that Philly's is better than Boston's and it's way better than DC says equal to Boston's Probably.
Rym: what if you ever use?
Scott: Boston sucks ass it does and Philly also sucks ass.
Rym: Well, maybe if you couldn't figure it out for some reason I can't figure out fucking the tea either.
Scott: you go down there try to buy a Charlie card and it's like the machines.
Scott: don't spit.
Scott: You can't even find me.
Rym: I've never had a problem like that.
Scott: I've had the same problems in Boston.
Scott: You like try to get a charlie card stations.
Scott: Don't have a machine Scott.
Rym: I've used the tea a bunch of times.
Rym: That's not a problem.
Scott: I have used it.
Rym: I've used it with you Yeah, and I've had no problems with it.
Scott: It's bad sucks.
Rym: The only problems with the Boston tea is that doesn't go anywhere that I want to go and that transferring between lines is Usually like a 40 mile walk in an underground tunnel.
Rym: But other than those two problems the machines the ticketing that all works fine.
Scott: It also doesn't run late.
Rym: Yeah, Philly's does so again.
Rym: Philly better I don't?
Scott: you said the thing comes every three minutes the whole time.
Scott: with this Scott many minutes.
Scott: We were down there trying to figure it out.
Scott: That sounds like you came.
Rym: that's because you went to the fucking subway that runs every 11 minutes as opposed to the trolley.
Rym: That's on another track right there that runs every three or four minutes.
Scott: We could not tell where the difference between a trolley or a subway.
Rym: We could have looked at one of the many maps.
Scott: the labeling of the system and the maps were so awful.
Scott: They were incomprehensible.
Rym: I'd say they're actually easier to read than the New York ones there were.
Rym: and we're just blinded by the fact that you've studied the New York one a lot.
Rym: I guess you can't use a subway.
Scott: What is much more?
Scott: Comprehensible and well-designed in its typography and maps.
Scott: You never see like a map in the New York City subway that just shows a yellow line For the end and doesn't actually have a picture of New York behind it.
Rym: Yeah, Scott That's what's in the actual subway cars that strip at the top.
Rym: that just shows the last.
Scott: I'm saying before I even get on.
Scott: imagine if that's all you saw.
Rym: Yeah Scott.
Rym: There are just normal maps.
Scott: It's usually not already on the trains got.
Rym: there's normal maps.
Rym: No design anyone.
Scott: Well again, I know for a fact they're there and I think we saw did not even indicate which station we were at.
Rym: Okay, that was on like every sign when you go in.
Rym: All right.
Scott: Well next time we go there Well, let's go in for a next unplug.
Scott: We'll go down into a little subway and you can explain it to me.
Rym: Okay?
Rym: I was not too intelligent.
Rym: adults could not figure it out.
Rym: It is not me.
Rym: I will gladly teach you how to ride subways.
Rym: That is what you're asking me to do.
Scott: I know how to ride subways.
Scott: I just don't know where the fuck I'm going or how the hell the Philly subway is designed because it's designed By a crazy person.
Rym: All I'm gonna say is one I think you just only know how to ride the New York transit system and literally can't deal with it anywhere else on earth.
Scott: I think that other places on earth are just really shitty - I think I blame the system.
Scott: I don't blame the rider.
Rym: I Can't wait to see you try to ride the Tokyo subway I'm sure it'll show or the Paris underground.
Rym: I've seen the London underground.
Scott: I've seen signs in Tokyo and I know that the train also has words in English, so I should be able to ride it.
Rym: Yeah I don't think you're gonna be able to buy a ticket because the Tokyo system is not as well documented in like outside.
Rym: It kind of assumes, you know more about it.
Rym: The Philly one has a whole bunch of signs and things to help you everywhere.
Scott: Everyone did not have helpful signs.
Rym: Feel like I need to go down there and make like a POV video of like.
Rym: Oh, look another map of the subway station.
Rym: Let's walk.
Rym:  oh look another map of the subway station.
Rym: Also, you could have just asked Google if you'd put in Google.
Scott: We looked at Google and it was not helpful because Google told us, you know It was like.
Scott: oh take any of these green numbers.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Rym: They all stop it with the same platform.
Rym: That was early.
Rym: no numbers.
Scott: They're at the platform to tell us that these numbers are showing up in this place or which direction I'm going.
Scott: We were in a green place.
Scott: It's like, okay.
Scott: No you guys.
Rym: No You weren't because what you fucking said that you said you waited that long.
Rym: you were waiting for the MFL.
Rym: You are not waiting for the trolley.
Rym: You were in a different part of the subway station.
Scott: There was no explanation of how are you supposed to know what we were waiting for?
Scott: Google Maps said MFL on it.
Scott: the letters MFL did not appear in the station We were in.
Scott: that is why we could not match up.
Scott: Well Google Maps said with what the fuck was going on because the things that were labeled on Google Maps were not labels that Appeared anywhere in the station.
Rym: as Google Maps says like go to this platform get on the train that says it's going here.
Rym: It arrives at this time.
Rym: Does your Apple Google Maps not do that?
Scott: That is not what we saw on Google Maps.
Rym: Is your does your?
Scott: Google Maps had a list of a strip with several numbers and it said yeah One of these numbers there were.
Scott: none of those numbers appeared in the station.
Rym: Scott, New York.
Rym: The four five and six all go to crazy fucking different place.
Scott: Yeah, but if you go in the station the station says four five six on it.
Scott: This is like if I looked at Google Maps and it said four five six and I went up to the station and all it Said was Lexington Avenue and didn't actually say four five or six on the station.
Scott: Well, how do I fucking know if a four five or six station?
Rym: I think you just hate mass transit in her bed.
Scott: Imagine if I removed all of the colored numbers and letters from the M from Metro from the subway Only I. But yet on Google Maps there were.
Rym: yeah when you search for things that would be the colored circles I'm all I'm saying is I was able to and for three years in a row go to Philly Go down into that subway buy a ticket.
Scott: Congratulations.
Scott: We were not right.
Scott: We are not stupid.
Scott: The system is garbage.
Scott: just cuz you can successfully navigate a garbage system doesn't make it not a garbage system.
Rym: I think you can't navigate subways.
Rym: I think you can only navigate the New York City subway.
Rym: Yeah, okay Okay, I you have said things that are objectively not true about that station.
Scott: They are extremely Station.
Scott: that how come Amanda couldn't do it either.
Scott: Are you calling Amanda stupid as me?
Rym: You both had a problem with.
Scott: are you saying that she is stupid?
Rym: I didn't say anyone's stupid.
Rym: I'm saying uh-huh.
Scott: That seems to be what you're saying.
Scott: Oh, you know, we must be stupid.
Scott: if either were stupid or the system is broken.
Scott: You can't be on one of the other.
Rym: I think you had some problem.
Rym: That is not coming to everyone else.
Scott: That.
Scott: meanwhile other people in the station were all equally confused.
Rym: I just tourists cuz I see Many people come.
Scott: anyone else in that station was also confusing couldn't figure out how to use that machine.
Rym: They were probably all tourists like you.
Rym: I see thousands of confused people in the New York subway every day.
Rym: They're all tourists Mm-hmm.
Rym: I think you were just a tourist and you couldn't use the subway.
Scott: Yeah, if they removed all the letters and numbers from the stations.
Scott: But those letters and numbers appeared on Google Maps.
Scott: How the fuck would you know if you're in a six station?
Rym: Because it says all over the place what the station is, right?
Scott: But imagine if it all didn't.
Scott: you looked at Google Maps and said take the six and when you go to the station There are no sixes anywhere.
Scott: How do you know that you're in the fucking six station?
Scott: I mean, yes I know the six is coming here Yes in a made-up situation where there weren't exactly what happened in the Philly subway where Google said all these numbers on it.
Scott: take one Of these numbered trains and none of those numbers are on the station anywhere.
Scott: So, I don't know if I'm in the fucking right station All right and Google Maps didn't say to go east or west.
Scott: so I couldn't tell.
Scott: and I couldn't tell if I was in the east or West side of the track because it was so mislabeled Scott.
Rym: You didn't know which direction was east or west down there.
Rym: It was on labeled.
Scott: It did not say this.
Scott: it like in New York City subway you go down.
Scott: It says this is uptown track.
Scott: other side is downtown track.
Scott: There was no such label in the station telling you which side of the track was upward downtown.
Rym: god or Easter I'm gonna say is those signs are definitely there signs.
Scott: We're not there.
Scott: I looked all over.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Anyway in anime news So studio trigger is Coming out.
Rym: They've announced like right away right on the heels of promare.
Rym: We don't know a lot of details yet.
Rym: I think they did the initial announcement anime Expo, but there's gonna be a new trigger anime called BNA.
Scott: I mean they pretty much as continuously make shows one after the other right?
Scott: It feels like almost they've got like a parallel processing going on.
Scott: We're like they make a movie and they got like a team on a movie and a team on a show and when when the shows Coming out they're working on the next thing and like this is like a constant production going on Which is I guess how you have to overwork people to make money.
Scott: in anime He's just constantly things out.
Scott: if you have a gap where you're not putting anything out You're not making any money to pay anyone during that time, right?
Rym: So here's what we know.
Rym: it is called BNA which stands for a brand new animal.
Rym: It is straight up.
Rym: It's a furry show.
Scott: He stars thing is hot.
Scott: I haven't checked it out yet.
Rym: Yeah, it looks like there's a cute.
Rym: Maybe she's a raccoon girl.
Rym: I can't quite tell.
Rym: there's some sort of wolf guy.
Rym: Looks like they're putting their good people on it.
Scott: I mean all their people are good people.
Scott: so they have bad people.
Rym: So, let's see They list a whole bunch of people who are any bad people that trigger.
Rym: I'm sure there are others.
Scott: What did they put out?
Scott: That's no good.
Rym: There's got to be like a beat.
Scott: I mean some of its better than others, right?
Scott: But like have they put out anything bad?
Rym: No, they definitely have not.
Rym: Okay, so So I'm pretty excited about this.
Scott: when's it actually gonna be out?
Rym: Uh, let's see.
Rym: It's not clear yet.
Rym: Actually, they've just announced that it exists.
Rym: It's gonna be on Fuji TV plus ultra in 2020.
Rym: Okay, so you got a while.
Rym: That's all we know.
Scott: No rush.
Rym: Uh, so we'll see how this goes.
Rym: I'm just assuming it's gonna be great It's not.
Scott: is it based on anything existing or is it completely original?
Rym: I have no idea.
Scott: Like is there already a brand new animal manga?
Rym: There are one, two, three, four, five paragraphs on this article two of which are just like one sentence.
Scott: I imagine it is then not based on an existing thing because they would have mentioned that existing thing and linked to it.
Rym: Yep, it looks like it's just its own thing.
Rym: They have a script writer.
Rym: It's the Kellok Hill strip script writer.
Scott: Mm-hmm All right.
Scott: So this is sort of it's not really a news org.
Scott: I guess kind of a geek But I don't know if I can know how to describe what I'm about to talk about.
Rym: So you're talking about something.
Scott: Yeah, so there's some nerds in New York City, right?
Scott: Who are like, you know, one of them's even like a like a profess like.
Scott: the main person is like a professory Like a manga professor a person who like teaches somewhere.
Scott: I don't even know somewhere in the city Like classes like about manga like studying, you know, there's always that professor at college who's teaching all the weird stuff, right?
Scott: Yeah, small class somewhere the thing that they're they're just really interested in it personally and since they're professor they can do classes on it.
Scott: Right, you know what.
Scott: you know that everyone who's been to college knows about that professor, right?
Scott: So They run this club that I found out about called the manga reading and research network, right?
Scott: So I went.
Scott: some of its meetings were literally a block away from here.
Scott: There's this place or a recording, right?
Scott: So I went to those meetings in 2017 two years ago.
Scott: They then had a meet a couple meetings in downtown Manhattan.
Scott: So I didn't go to those because those are far away.
Scott: But then they had another meeting a block away from here suddenly in 2019.
Scott: So a club that started in 20 May of 2017 had its last meeting in November 2018.
Scott: So it hasn't met for a year.
Scott: suddenly had a meeting a block away from here again in 2019.
Scott: I thought it was dead, but then I got an email and the reason I went Emily went also is They had.
Scott: it was a special meeting.
Scott: Usually most of the other meetings were like Rita manga You know show up and then talk about the manga.
Scott: right this meeting They had an actual editor of actual manga whose current job is editor of manga at weekly young magazine, which is not.
Scott: it's not like a You know, it's not a show a show to jump level, but it's like that's the magazine of Kara was in right?
Rym: Yeah, I miss this.
Rym: It sounds like it was fun.
Scott: It's a big-time, you know.
Scott: Editor of real current mangas to come and talk to us.
Scott: The dude was in New York.
Scott: We had.
Scott: we submitted questions.
Scott: they asked him the questions he asked us questions.
Scott: It was a good time.
Scott: I learned a lot of interesting stuff.
Scott: We saw some interesting mangas.
Scott: We didn't know about that are in that magazine.
Scott: I read there was a sampler for this one called starving anonymous, which is sort of in that horror terrible secret of a space genre.
Scott: And then he talked about one that he's editing also which is it's like witch and beast I think is what it's called and it's sort of like a beauty and beast reversal.
Scott: where is this girl who's the beast?
Scott: and she's trying to Kill all the witches and each which has like a different magic power of some kind You know, but I guess it's it's probably still has some fighting tournament aspects to it, right?
Scott: You know go to the next witch kind of deal.
Scott: Yeah, right but yeah, it was interesting time.
Scott: and So if you're in New York, you should you know, see if this thing ever meets again, maybe next year It'll have a meeting.
Scott: who knows right?
Scott: You never know.
Scott: And show up to it.
Scott: Oh, yes, you know this.
Rym: I mean if I wasn't like in Asia on this like big work trip I definitely would have got.
Scott: you know, a bunch of weebs will show up and you can learn about some mangas.
Rym: I actually was in London during this.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I was somewhere.
Scott: I don't know if this ever happens again.
Scott: Show up come on show up.
Scott: And Otherwise it gave us the show idea for today because the guy was asking about you know how to distribute mangas digitally, so
Rym: Yep, the well, we'll get you to the main bit because the alternative was I wanted to review Beavis and Butthead But Scott doesn't remember it that well
Scott: I haven't seen a Beavis and Butthead since.
Scott: I mean, I can't remember when I saw that's how long ago.
Rym: I feel like we will need to Watch more Beavis and I'm pretty sure you've seen all of it repeatedly.
Rym: I watched it like on TV from the beginning.
Rym: I was probably too young.
Scott: I've watched episodes here and there definitely not even all of it.
Rym: Like the family would sit around and watch Beavis and Butthead.
Scott: Yeah, no, we did not do that.
Rym: I saw the Beavis and Butthead movie in the theater.
Rym: That movie is phenomenal.
Scott: I did not do that.
Rym: I feel like we should at least you should watch the movie at some point like this year next year because I got better movies.
Rym: Beavis and Butthead movie is an underrated film.
Rym: It is really funny.
Scott: It's a solid poop and not a diary.
Rym: Oh, it's.
Rym: no I would say that it is a standout solid movie.
Scott: It's a godfather.
Scott: Watch out my godfather Beavis and Butthead movies coming.
Rym: It's the godfather of Beavis and Butthead movie.
Rym: like if you take all the content of Beavis and Butthead.
Rym: the Beavis and Butthead movie is like the height of what that could be and It is laugh out loud Hilarious, uh-huh.
Rym: Also that quote that never gonna score thing that we play to the hockey game.
Scott: I know that that is from them.
Rym: It is from that movie.
Scott: I am aware.
Rym: So, uh in some other brief news at anime cons you know have their artist alleys and I saw a Kind of interesting internet kerfuffle.
Rym: because the problem with artist alleys at anime cons as time goes on is that a lot of people make it a Like professional like necessary part of their lives and treat it very seriously.
Scott: Well, I think even if it's not a necessary part of your life, right?
Rym: There's so many conflicting things going on in an artist alley Originally mostly in comic cons for like like in America like that like a comic-con would have like the person working on spider-man Will like sit there and like sign things for money, right?
Scott: It was and it was also for independent comic creators or people who are just ill it right?
Scott: It's like you could sell your art.
Scott: You're an artist right?
Scott: Your name is on comic books or whatever, right?
Scott: but you're not at a you know, Exhibitor booth right, you know that like at a comic-con the the expo floor Wouldn't be where artists would sit right, you know and do you know commissions and that sort of thing.
Scott: It would be where people were selling comics, right?
Scott: It was like mostly merch booths collector booths, right?
Scott: That sort of thing right.
Scott: and then the actual artist was sitting the artists alley So anime cons which spawned from comic cons had artists alley, but it wasn't full of actual anime artists.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: It was full of fan artists.
Scott: So you got the fan art issue going on, right?
Scott: But you've also got the issue these days and that The there's so many fan artists and the anime cons, you know, even though they're past their highest of heydays They're still huge.
Scott: and if you have a table in an artist alley whether you do You know are you know depending on your income level you make depend on this money or not?
Scott: You can if your art is good.
Scott: You can make a lot of money on an artist alley table.
Scott: Yeah, it doesn't cost a lot to get the table and you can sell a lot of merch if you have a table but Most of that merch is technically violating copyrights, right?
Scott: Right.
Scott: So there's that's that issue.
Scott: There's tax.
Rym: people are not paying taxes.
Scott: You could do times we could.
Scott: there's so many topics.
Scott: You could do a podcast like.
Scott: I think there are artist alley Podcasts that talk about artists alley issues and you can make an episode a week for like ever and never run out of things To talk about.
Scott: yeah, and you like in your news part you could talk about like the next con coming up and what they're doing.
Scott: you know, you could just go forever.
Rym: but so I saw on Twitter like randomly like I saw a bunch of Controversy like oh, but people were referring to pretty much anytime any artist alley does something does right opens or does something weird or changes?
Scott: Anything.
Scott: the people who are going in that artist alley, you know go crazy about it Positively or negatively because it's a big deal because you know for the people going to the con They don't even know this is happening.
Scott: Yeah, but for the people who are in that alley a lot of money is at stake.
Scott: Yeah Whether they get or don't get a table and the rules around what they can sell and all those yelps
Rym: But meanwhile huge
Scott: deals for those people
Rym: companies like real vendors like like the people who are like selling like legit Goods that aren't in an artist alley They don't have any of these hassles because they just like have a contract relationship with the convention.
Scott: The difference is is that you know The if you're if you want to be a dealer at an anime con you just pay.
Scott: just buy a dealer booth.
Scott: you buy Expo space by the foot from their grid of space and they're happy to sell it to you.
Rym: Yeah or depending on the gun like I won't share the details of how packs works.
Rym: and also it might have changed because I haven't.
Rym: I Haven't tried to buy Expo Hall space at a PAX in a while But the like.
Rym: oftentimes you'll like have a rep who like works with you to fit you in the right spot.
Scott: But I mean the point is that doesn't usually sell out.
Scott: and if it does sell out the con raises their rates.
Scott: Right in that area the artist alley to keep it viable.
Scott: Right as a thing because it's definitely a draw for fans.
Scott: You don't want to get rid of it.
Scott: It brings Pete by it sells badges.
Scott: All right, people would be very upset and not come to your con if you didn't have one
Rym: Yep,
Scott: or if it wasn't any good though
Rym: counterpoint having run conventions and seen like the stuff like Not for nothing and I'm not gonna name the con that I'm referring to and it's not the one you might all be thinking of uh Shutting down the artist alley at that con would probably have solved a lot of the problems.
Rym: the kind of head maybe.
Scott: but anyway, the point is You're running the con right the artist alley.
Scott: You need to charge a low flat rate for the tables and no one can buy more than one or two tape, right?
Scott: There's like a little right.
Scott: you're either buying a one tabler or a two tabler, right?
Scott: You're not.
Scott: you can't like.
Scott: let someone make a mega booth in there.
Scott: Otherwise, it's just more expo space, right?
Scott: You have to have a flat rate and you need some other system of decide if the demand to go to those tables is high.
Scott: You need some sort of system to distribute the limited supply just like you do it.
Scott: badges at a sold-out con.
Scott: Right, you have so many people who want artist alley tables because it's basically you're handing out thousands of dollars but hundreds or thousands of dollars to people.
Scott: Yep, right and exchange for like.
Scott: I don't know what an artist alley table cost these days hundreds Time.
Rym: I paid for one.
Rym: it was 70 bucks, right?
Scott: That's pretty cheap.
Scott: I think yeah.
Scott: But the point is you're selling these extremely cheap tickets each of which if someone gets one if they have art and merch to Sell which they probably do will you know net them a hot a great profit and more people want them.
Scott: then You're right to your choice.
Rym: It's just like badges They're.
Scott: the supply is way lower than the demand and if you raise the price Well, then people are gonna be super pissed and not buy them because they'll be suit, right?
Scott: It's like yeah, we're not it's just.
Scott: they'll just be more expo Hall.
Scott: then it won't be an artist alley, right?
Scott: So rather than raise the price you got to do a lottery or you got to do a first-come first-serve.
Scott: You got to do something right and none of its fair.
Scott: and as the con Arguably the random like f5 system is as fair as it's gonna get unless you raise the prices somewhat fair Right, but like the con just wants it to be easy right and to work and to fill their artist alley.
Rym: There's a fundamental point.
Scott: but the artist people they all want them to get a table funded.
Rym: This is the problem.
Rym: same with badges.
Rym: no tells at cons artists That was the same thing.
Rym: There is no way to make the artist happy because there is no solution.
Rym: You cannot make enough space for all of them.
Rym: if you did make enough space So everyone who wants the table got one there'd be so many artists that the artist themselves wouldn't make money.
Rym: I have data from another con again Not the one you might be thinking of where I looked at dealer space and it turned out that When they expanded the dealer room the individual dealers all made a lot less money.
Rym: So they actually shrunk the dealer hall kicked out half the dealers and then the dealers who got in made two to three times More money, right?
Scott: Cuz even if everyone's selling I mean you could have left you could have had the bigger one and lowered the prices Right, and that would have still netted the convention about the same money.
Rym: It's like all right.
Scott: Well, we'll sell more we'll sell more tables for cheaper, right but it's like no.
Scott: the dealer needs to make a certain You know, it's like okay.
Scott: Well, the dealers profit margin is the same as like no they need a certain amount of money to cover their flat costs of.
Scott: you Know shipping right?
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Yeah travel, you know lodging etc.
Rym: So I so all you know all these clustering issues not to turn this in the whole show I I basically saw a bunch of people on Twitter referring to the Otakon artist alley Controversy and I expected it to be one of these.
Scott: isn't that something that happens just every year?
Rym: Yeah So I expected this there.
Rym: I expected something along the lines of all the things we just talked about headlight gone down.
Rym: but then I went and looked into it and The controversy was simply that Otakon made a little puzzle like a flash game And they put it out there and if you solve the puzzle it told you what day the artist alley table like Registration link was going to open and that was it.
Rym: That was literally the extent of the controversy.
Scott: So they just they just made an announcement in a cute way Yep, in a way that they thought was cute and fun.
Rym: Good fucking God are people outraged about this on the Internet?
Rym: Okay, because it trivialized the artist alley.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Yep at that that tells reeks to me of someone who just wants to be mad and is looking for a reason to be mad.
Rym: I Looked around Twitter like I searched for like Otakon AA and I was looking at the threads and the discourse and I Realized that that that level of reaction seems to be the same literally no matter what happens.
Rym: I feel like that's the same amount of discourse that happens just when the date gets announced.
Rym: Anyway, except people are mad about the puzzle.
Rym: But if they didn't do the puzzle people would have been mad about the date and then the system and then the announcement and then We didn't get a table.
Rym: I feel like the the amount of drama remains constant regardless of all other factors, right?
Scott: And it's like even if you were to choose, you know, make all your decisions to make one person perfectly happy Someone else would be super angry.
Rym: Yeah, so this is the same reason why it's so hard to get a hotel at like magfest or paxies Like.
Rym: it's all the same problem.
Rym: Yep So I think we've got really long on the news.
Rym: So I think we should probably just get into The eggs of the day what he got for me, so we're well into hockey season, right?
Scott: Actually pretty scarily deep in hockey.
Rym: See you asked me a few weeks ago I had a more positive opinion of the current hockey season than I do right now anyway.
Scott: So here is a really great video.
Scott: Somebody posted like when did they post this?
Scott: whether even if they posted it?
Scott: No, I think it reads very recently like a few days ago.
Scott: But yeah, this is a video of something that doesn't happen very often in hockey.
Scott: It's so rare that they were able to compile Every instance of this ever happening in the NHL history on video, I guess every time it was recorded.
Scott: I'm pretty sure it's every time it's ever happened.
Rym: It hasn't happened that many times.
Scott: This is right really hard.
Scott: It's only like a six-minute video and it's a recording of Every single time a goalie has scored a goal most of the time by shooting for the empty net when the other team pulls the goal.
Rym: There's only two ways this can happen because it is Effectively impossible for the goalie to score a goal against another goalie Directly partly because they changed the rules in the NHL to say and this is a while ago that Goalies are not allowed to cross the center line.
Rym: That used to not be a rule.
Rym: They made a rule not for the reasons you'd think they made the rule because goalies actually did it a lot and one dude in Particular did it a lot.
Rym: He just like skate to the other side and like try to help a play and he kept getting hurt.
Rym: Goalies got hurt and NHL really does not want there to be a game where there aren't enough goalies to continue the game For reasons we've talked about before.
Rym: so the only way to get a goal as a goalie is to shoot for the empty net which is a huge risk because if you miss it's an icing usually or Get a technicality where you are technically the last one to touch the puck and then the other team scored an own goal.
Scott: I get an assist.
Scott: as a goalie is pretty easy.
Scott: You make a long pass to someone who then goes in for the shot, right?
Scott: Or, you know, you pass to someone who passes to someone who scores right.
Scott: that happened.
Scott: goalies get assists now and then I've seen it In person getting a goal.
Scott: It's got to be some crazy fluke or something for that to happen.
Scott: So, but yeah Here's a video showing every time an NHL goalie in a regular in a real NHL game has scored a goal.
Rym: I remember Chris.
Rym: I was good doing it.
Rym: He's also notable for charging out of the goal and fucking drilling somebody one time and taking a penalty for it.
Rym: So my thing today speaking of Beavis and butthead.
Rym: Most of the time you try to find like episodes of Beavis and butthead or things like you'll just find the cartoon.
Rym: But that wasn't really the best part of Beavis and butthead.
Rym: the whole point of Beavis and butthead was that the little cartoons were Just these really simple short framing stories by Mike Judd, but most of the show was basically the Beavis and butthead characters MST3K-ing music videos because it was on MTV.
Rym: You know the station that ostensibly for a little while showed music videos.
Rym: So I found on YouTube this is probably super like bootleg.
Rym: I surely get taken down to some point.
Rym: This is just an episode of Beavis and butthead.
Rym: I want to say it was from like 93 or 94 But and I remember this episode because we watched it like a live on TV This was the Beavis and butthead Christmas special and it has the music videos intact Which is kind of like Muppet Babies.
Scott: How is it not taken down?
Rym: I assume it'll get taken down to some point.
Rym: it was uploaded like Less than three weeks ago So watch it while you can.
Rym: This will tell you if Beavis and butthead is the kind of humor you would enjoy or not.
Rym: And you're gonna see a side of Beavis and butthead that most younger people have never seen.
Rym: they've never seen Them just like reacting to music videos kind of like how most kids have never seen Muppet Babies Just reenacting Star Wars with clips of Star Wars interspersed Mmm in the meta moment the GeekNights book club book.
Rym: We're probably gonna do the first chapter at some point pretty early next year.
Rym: bar Not the first chapter, but like the first third the first bit.
Rym: pick a stopping point Tale of Genji.
Rym: We're still reading it.
Rym: I'm almost done with that World War one book that I started reading instead and got really into but I'm almost done with it.
Rym: now I'm gonna go back to this.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: We were just a PAX Unplugged.
Rym: We did two panels.
Rym: I'm gonna edit the video together and try to get him on YouTube like by this weekend.
Scott: We're about to go to mag fed where we are doing a bunch of panels.
Scott: They sent me the draft schedule I gotta like confirm sent me a link and I clicked on it and it went to an error.
Rym: Well, the problem is we're doing panel panels and mages panels and I might be doing a third thing for a different group and our Panels are split between two through.
Rym: It's it's complicated.
Scott: The point is I clicked on a link and I got an error.
Scott: So, I don't know what the fuck I'm doing.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well as long as you get your badge, that's all that matters I will get the bad as that.
Rym: You know Scott we split our duties.
Rym: since I am the producer of GeekNights one of my jobs Like Scott actually makes sure the website keeps working like barely.
Rym: Yeah, barely.
Rym: We're stay tuned on that.
Rym: We're.
Rym: there's changes coming to the website in the forum But basically Scott's the one who has to deal with me.
Rym: if I message him at 1159 and I'm like Scott the post didn't fucking Work cuz.
Rym: yeah, I'm not gonna deal with that and I have to deal with all the convention logistics.
Rym: So I am sorting out our schedule for mag fest.
Rym: We also do know our schedule.
Rym: We're doing at least one panel of PAX South the 41 tabletop games You should play which is 41 different games that we've never talked about in a panel.
Scott: He's not doing this panel every time.
Rym: It's really popular and I think it's a really good important panel.
Rym: There's too many tabletop games.
Rym: Do you want to be the producer of GeekNights and I'll take over the sysadmin?
Scott: I think I could just not do a clickbait panel.
Scott: We got plenty other panel ideas.
Rym: Yeah, I submit a lot of panels but at the same time I have to balance with each convention and the rep I work with in the convention what they think will Draw a crowd like what they need that year where the gaps are in their programming.
Rym: It's a whole thing.
Rym: This isn't just submit panels get responses.
Rym: I have a lot of conversations with convention people that you do not have to do.
Scott: I could talk to them be like hey I really don't want to do clickbait.
Scott: Let me do something erudite.
Rym: I've had those conversations.
Rym: That's why we kind of alter you notice like it.
Rym: packs is like sometimes we go to packs and we do like.
Scott: I decided look It's packs.
Scott: You're selling the same.
Scott: You're not selling it.
Scott: We're not selling you any badges, right?
Scott: You know, we're just to.
Scott: you know, fill in some seats.
Rym: Yeah but there's like.
Rym: one example is sometimes the con needs programming to another popular thing as I got to figure out like what could draw a crowd away from that other thing that's gonna fill up.
Scott: Anyway, well, I'll just tell me what that other thing is and I will talk about something That is a different topic.
Scott: So that way so it PAX Unplugged.
Rym: It was an acting thing All right.
Scott: So I won't.
Scott: so I can either do something.
Scott: I could either Target acting right and try to do RPG stuff that will bring those people over Right or I could try to do something completely opposite of RPG people So that no non RPG people will go and try to get acting seats.
Rym: But anyway, stay tuned for us at PAX South at magfest at PAX East and then I think we actually have a bros Thank icon and I think we actually have a break.
Rym: Scott might not go to zinc icon because I guess he won't be able to figure out how to take the Amtrak.
Scott: I mean I can take the Amtrak but Penn Station is also garbage But for other reasons, but station now.
Scott: God's not the reason I won't go to Philadelphia like.
Rym: I respect you more than Scott, but I live in New York's.
Rym: I only can respect you so much.
Rym: but I Will agree as a New Yorker Penn Station is a fucking shithole.
Rym: Of course it our Penn Station.
Rym: God, the only thing sadder than the New York City Penn Station It's where the New York City Port Authority bus station is all shitty because that's where the New Jersey leaks in Path.
Rym: I would say that about path more path is also bad.
Rym: Yeah path is bad for other reasons.
Rym: So Manga Distribution right.
Scott: so this manga editor and he comes over, you know, and you know, he's asking us like hey Yeah, if we're gonna do manga digital distribution, right?
Scott: What are you guys willing to pay?
Scott: What would that look like?
Scott: Right, you know, we couldn't give such detailed answers.
Scott: There's only so much time.
Scott: There are a lot of people there.
Scott: there was it was like ten times as many people.
Scott: is that all the previous meetings?
Scott: It's only had like five people.
Scott: Yeah But you know, let's just talk about it in general, right?
Scott: So in Japan right manga goes in these magazines.
Scott: the magazine is like two dollars.
Scott: It's like four dollars.
Scott: Maybe it's super cheap.
Scott: It's huge.
Scott: It's like computer shopper was back in the day.
Scott: There's one chapter each of many many many many mangas in there like 20 plus different mangas.
Scott: It would be like if you went to the comic book store and you got every single Marvel comic book.
Scott: They came out in a whole month but bound together into a single volume for $4 Whereas instead you're getting one floppy.
Rym: well and to a point kind of disposable, right?
Scott: It's also a much shittier paper and black and white and has ads in it.
Scott: But I guess you know you pay four dollars for a spider-man copy.
Scott: You're getting 20 pages of spider-man with ads in it in color on fancy paper, right?
Scott: so take that spider-man put it on shitty paper in black and white keep the ads in and Combine it with all the x-men comics and the Avengers comics and the Iron Man comics and the friend is more comics and all them Together in one bound volume for the price of one floppy.
Scott: and that's what they do in Japan.
Scott: But then they combine all the chapters of each manga together into the tanka van Which is what we read in the US.
Scott: and you go to Barnes & Noble or whatever or Amazon and you buy a volume for?
Scott: 10 bucks.
Scott: you're actually getting like, you know, eight ten chapters worth all together.
Rym: I remember as a kid like figuring some of this out like I remember, you know Manga was not really available in the US when I was really into anime.
Rym: So like I was able to get some fan subs and I could get like some anime.
Rym: but manga like was not in stores.
Rym: there were not good ways to get it.
Rym: and I remember the first time I finally found some manga and it was a big book and I was trying to figure out which like Vault like issues of this manga were in the book because there weren't really internet resources to figure that out either.
Scott: bad hell no Right, so, you know in Japan, that's how they do it in the US.
Scott: We just do tankavans only.
Scott: Yeah, there have been attempts to do the magazine.
Scott: I think you can get some sort of shonen jump subscription.
Scott: You can get some right.
Rym: It's interesting because I know a lot of like American anime fans really said Oh if they just sold shonen jump in the US, I would definitely pay for it.
Rym: kind of like Oh if New Type was in the US.
Scott: Well the thing is even when they did or if they still do right It was not the same.
Scott: It wasn't right.
Scott: the full shonen jump It wasn't the huge fat magazine with a shit ton of manga in it for four dollars.
Scott: Meanwhile the opposite problem right, there was like an America at one point and it was like and you know, it was a. It was a smaller magazine that had fewer titles in it and didn't come out weekly and wasn't four dollars.
Scott: It was more expensive for less content.
Rym: Well it's the opposite of when New Type came out It was exactly the same as in Japan and people realized once they could read it that it's stupid.
Scott: Yes, that was a different story entirely.
Scott: Yeah, right, but I mean if they really did sell the full Frickin magazine a big fat boy.
Scott: Yeah, it's the low ass price in English that might draw some Turn some heads.
Scott: Yeah, but no one has done that like.
Rym: I think part of the problem Is that there's a. there is definitely still like a bigger collector mentality among a lot of anime fans in the US.
Scott: Well, I don't think there is at all.
Scott: I think what's happening is that they're not.
Scott: they don't care about collecting and they don't care about collecting so much that they don't want To even have anything right.
Scott: they don't want to spend any money.
Rym: Well, they don't want to spend any money, but they still want stuff and they just want to read.
Scott: You know, they're setting their computer or their phone.
Scott: They don't want to have a book Read digitally.
Rym: Yeah, but also one thing like with anime.
Rym: What I noticed is that once anime was just like like we're in a golden age I can just see like almost any anime I want online real cheap and There's still a significant subset of nerds in the US who like make up excuses to continue to not pay for it when it costs Almost nothing.
Scott: Well, there is a little bit of fragmentation going on in terms of different streaming services and whatever.
Scott: Yeah, but manga has an even worse problem.
Rym: You go ask me what where to go to read any given manga.
Rym: fuck if I know I'm gonna like research.
Scott: well There's so many mangas.
Scott: Yeah, right and then there's so many Untranslated ones.
Scott: right and be it's like most animes that you're gonna want to watch.
Scott: have you know This the ones that are you want to watch that haven't been brought over or licensed or it's like are fewer and fewer Percentage.
Scott: wise right, you know, even some old-school ones are like fully subbed and licensed and released right like every episode of Galaxy Express 39 TV series you can get.
Scott: it's like whoa, right?
Scott: Yeah manga There's so many they will never never will a significant portion and they're produced so quickly.
Scott: and there's so many of them.
Scott: There will never be a significant portion that are translated to English until a computer can just do all of it at once Yep, which that day will come.
Scott: Yeah, maybe in our lives who knows.
Scott: but that means that there is still some real justification for Scanslation of mangas that will never be in English, right?
Scott: Yeah Right.
Scott: I still even to this day support if you have a piece of artwork or media or anything book movie Whatever and nobody is legally translating it from its original language into your language Whatever that language is.
Scott: I feel it is not only morally accepted but sort of almost not you know Comparative but like.
Scott: it is not only okay to do but it is good to Just do it as long as you're not like selling it.
Rym: So here's here's a problem too.
Rym: There are pirate sites that sell a lot of this stuff.
Rym: Oh, yeah cheaper than official channels or like.
Rym: even if they're not available in official channels They're still selling it.
Scott: right and if you go to Google and you type in a manga you want to read The pirate sites usually show up first and a lot of kids don't even know they're pirates on it because they don't.
Scott: they're not.
Scott: I don't like that.
Rym: Is that one of the legal ones of one of the illegal?
Scott: pretty sure that's illegal.
Rym: cuz sanctuary is here.
Rym: This seems like it's the only place to reach.
Rym: I think I can read sanctuary right now.
Scott: Yes, you can for free.
Rym: Oh, yeah Oh, yeah, here we go.
Rym: Oh shit.
Rym: It's just sanctuary.
Scott: Yep, and nobody's doing anything to take it.
Rym: Are you sure?
Rym: This is illegal.
Scott: I'm 99% sure that's an illegal.
Scott: So here's the thing 100% without doing research.
Rym: I don't know if I don't know some 14 year old.
Rym: we definitely doesn't.
Rym: if you go to Google and you search, right?
Rym: Oh, man, I just want to read sanctuary again, right?
Scott: It's like you go if you go to Pirate Bay, right?
Rym: You know what you do, you know what you're doing.
Scott: You realize you're buying any legal thing if you go to Amazon and you type in the name of a product and you buy it and a bootleg board game shows up at your door Which is a real thing.
Scott: You don't know that you just bought a bootleg.
Scott: if you're not an expert Yeah.
Scott: So if you go to Google and you type in the name of a manga you want to read and there's a site that looks Legit works.
Scott: lets you read the manga for free is right there It's like and looks like a real site.
Scott: doesn't look like some site that's trying to hide something or makes you do any shenanigans Right.
Scott: It feels like this is a legal and legit thing you're doing.
Scott: Most people have no idea that they're doing that.
Scott: So I don't really I don't blame them at all.
Scott: Right, you know, I know a lot of people who are anti-scandalization blame the people reading them But like I don't they know the vast majority of those people have no idea.
Scott: They think that that's just how it is.
Rym: Yep, right.
Scott: They don't know that this is some illegal thing or the
Rym: problem is unlike with anime stuff like because manga is still a much more fractured experience and digit like Digital reading of things other than just books with text has definitely lagged behind Watching video of things in terms of devices and like good support and good UX and all those things.
Rym: There was this space that existed for manga to have a huge and thriving pirate industry that has Significantly displaced the legitimate industry in the u.s.
Scott: Right?
Scott: Well, I mean also part of it is that even if you know, it's illegal if you don't have a lot of money, right?
Scott: Yeah, and you want to read?
Scott: One-piece how many fucking volumes is one piece have?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: You know, I a bunch of line even $10.
Scott: Like even if you buy one-piece omnibus editions that they put out which are like several volumes in one, right?
Scott: How much is one of those?
Scott: how much is a one-piece omnibus edition cost?
Rym: looking up right now one-piece omnibus 28 books They are 11 bucks each, right?
Scott: So 11 times 28.
Scott: That's for a kid.
Rym: There's a lot of money right.
Scott: kids can't afford it But if they go if it's free Right that kid can read a litter.
Scott: if you're a kid with free time on your hands cuz you're a kid You can read with one piece.
Scott: You can read all of it.
Scott: You can read all of it several times over, right?
Scott: But you could never afford to buy all of it right ever, right?
Scott: So you're not losing.
Scott: you're losing some money because that kid could afford to buy some one-piece.
Scott: But right the kid cannot afford to buy all the one piece he can read and that is just one.
Scott: Manga, but that gets that card can read several one pieces.
Rym: that's the other thing that happened in the manga space.
Rym: is that the proliferation of and Digital entertainment made it such that manga now competes with a lot of other things like for example Free to view video and free to play YouTube.
Scott: you're competing with YouTube, which is free.
Scott: Yep I can go to YouTube actually free.
Rym: I can go to YouTube and watch like an hour long Perfectly cut screams compilation and for a like 12 year old kid that is equally entertaining to one piece.
Rym: They're just looking for something right.
Rym: so the kill time.
Scott: Japanese businesses, right have you know, I always do the same comparison every time.
Scott: But that's because it's true right you look at you know, say Korea a very tiny country But they put a lot of money into their music industry, which has a lot of problems.
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: but one problem It doesn't have is becoming popular because they freely Spread their TV and their music and their movies all over the world on purpose however, YouTube channel that literally is an official channel of KBS like the national TV channel of Korea and they intentionally take their TV shows put them up for free on YouTube with subtitles on purpose.
Scott: So each K in Japan would never do something like that.
Scott: They take that shit down Everywhere.
Rym: long term though.
Rym: Even that former model is unsustainable in a late capitalist world without Government subsidy of the arts to create the works.
Scott: Yes Well, but that's the thing is.
Scott: I think I think Japan does have government subsidy of the arts.
Scott: They have their whole cool Japan government program But that program still is not enough to get them to do the thing They need to do which is to allow their art to spread around the world in bulk and at low price.
Rym: I get me with freedom.
Rym: I suspect partly that that like those initiatives are held back a little bit by the Another goal of helping to monetize and protect the monetization of the internal healthy industry around this media.
Rym: Yes, you can definitely those are two mutually exclusive things in capitalism exactly.
Scott: You can see.
Scott: you know This same business pattern in all sorts of Japanese companies behavior from Nintendo to music companies Nintendo taking down live streams right all this sort of.
Scott: you see that same mentality across, you know Japanese businesses Related to the arts especially right all over right?
Scott: They have this sort of dual thing where they want the rest of the world to care about their art and think it's cool and be interested in Japan.
Scott: so They can make a lot of money by selling their culture.
Scott: But they also do not want to widely and cheaply distribute.
Rym: But there is another thing a subtle thing that can happen because we see the same thing with movies and TV.
Rym: If you have a big enough back catalogue of things you own that you can distribute and you distribute that cheaply.
Rym: Those things are often new to people of a current generation.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and that actually can take the monetization away from anything new being made.
Rym: Yep, like it makes a really difficult situation.
Scott: Why would I buy a new right?
Scott: It's like the thousands of manga that you've written over the past 30 years.
Scott: you put you know if you make those available.
Scott: That's enough manga for me to read in my whole life.
Rym: I've got all of dr.
Rym: Slump up there.
Rym: I only made it like five volumes in right.
Scott: I don't need to read any new manga you make right?
Scott: If you're in Japan and you can read Japanese, it's like why go back and read old stuff I can just read weekly.
Scott: I can buy the giant magazine, but that is a problem.
Rym: That's just generic to a modern world where there's a lot of reasons Why it's difficult to monetize or even to support the creation of new art, right?
Scott: So I think what they should do and never will do right is they should make a Netflix like service Right.
Scott: that provides either free trial or some manga is free some not some subscription Right something like that, but it had regardless of the details of it in order for it to succeed right it has to have large Quantity.
Rym: well crunchy roll is a lot of manga.
Rym: I can read it for free for 14 days Yes, but the crunchy roll not know.
Scott: the quantity of manga on crunchy roll is not many titles It is.
Rym: those are the popular ones.
Rym: there's a decent number here.
Scott: There's a decent number, but it is not like you know vast.
Scott: so it compared to the right here That's all of them.
Scott: that is not a large number.
Scott: I mean yep, right I'm talking like even just the young man.
Rym: well, so this is another problem this there's a difference between discoverability Versus like interest.
Scott: coverability is a separate problem Yeah, but the point is regardless of discoverability in the system.
Rym: But I'm saying interest most people in America like anime fans other than like super fans who pay a lot of attention.
Rym: They seem to want to read manga That they are told to.
Rym: they like.
Rym: they find out about it because an anime was made about it.
Rym: Maybe then they want to read the manga like attack on Titan.
Scott: sure But if you're going to chart you're gonna need to charge someone dollars per month or per year for the to access to the service.
Scott: Right even if you have say you had a service that was literally all the popular mangas that anime But no other mangas right.
Scott: maybe some people would pay for that kind of service.
Scott: right, but that's not gonna get people subscribing Forever because they'll read all the kids.
Scott: they would be able to read all those manga.
Scott: and yeah Right in order to get someone to pay you need quantity, right?
Scott: You need to have you know hundreds or perhaps even thousands of titles in that library like hey Pay us you know five bucks a month, and you'll have access.
Scott: you'll have a library of thousands of manga every volume all transit.
Rym: It's like a reader dotnet safe and legal.
Rym: No it is not legal.
Rym: No.
Rym: I looked it up.
Scott: There you go.
Scott: obviously not What you need right.
Scott: you need the low price even if it's month right relatively low.
Scott: it has to be cheaper than Netflix I think net right.
Scott: and Because people value comics and manga less than they value like movies.
Scott: Yeah as a thing.
Rym: well I mean that the the relative valuation is a weird situation Especially in the US right now because people will flip the fuck out if you want them to pay like $10 for a video game that they play for a hundred hours.
Rym: yet They'll happily pay $20 to see an hour and ten minute movie in a theater.
Scott: I think that's even.
Scott: what's even crazier is people are happy to spend 15 to 20 dollars to see a movie in a theater.
Scott: that's that.
Scott: maybe even if it's a three hour movie right they'll pay $15 to see Star Wars, but an app that they will use every day of their lives on their phone.
Scott: They will not pay a dollar only free apps for me.
Scott: I won't pay a dollar for now But they'll go to a movie for $15 which is partly the cancer of late capitalism coupled with the cancer of free-to-play.
Rym: Having skewed prices coupled with Media has not raised its prices in America at the same rate as inflation.
Scott: wages Also have not risen.
Rym: to my trip a triple-a game in 2019 still cost seventy eighty dollars a triple-a game.
Scott: People can't afford more than that at once because their wages haven't risen.
Rym: but a triple-a game in 1986 cost 70 to 80 1986 dollars people.
Scott: but you can trick people Like 300 bucks right.
Scott: you have to trick people into spending more than they can afford.
Scott: you can't do that by charging the giant price Up front.
Scott: you need to do shit against like gambling right which again You could charge a higher price if you raised wages.
Rym: well I'm so well.
Scott: and also what we would say I can't afford a hundred dollar video game.
Rym: There's that there's an even further undercurrent here the manga industry.
Rym: You know the the anime industry is pretty exploitative.
Rym: people don't make it.
Rym: Manga is a fucked-up situation in Japan.
Scott: Oh, yeah you if you're a manga artist you work in crazy hours.
Scott: You're getting paid like nothing right.
Scott: It's not good times.
Scott: It is not a glamorous life whatsoever.
Scott: So on top of that they're charging $4 for a magazine And I guess splitting that $4 up between everybody in the magazine which is a lot of bat manga artists.
Rym: I mean you see this with like Spotify.
Rym: how much money better?
Scott: Hope your tonka bond sell like crazy and your manga is super popular or you're gonna be eating you know like Not-very-good food yep and living in a tiny tiny cold place.
Rym: and the last time I saw so any numbers about this stuff like like In the pre digital like the DVD days.
Rym: I remember when I got some inside information When we're at RIT anime like we were working with some of the anime companies And we found out how many copies of certain anime were actually sold to people in America And what was considered a success.
Rym: and all I'm gonna say is that those numbers were?
Rym: Way lower than you would expect even if you were pessimistic.
Rym: well those are in different.
Scott: those are in certain times.
Rym: Yeah, I'm saying even in that time I remember I saw this number for a recent popular anime And they were like this is the best-selling anime of the year.
Rym: and all I thought was what the fuck.
Scott: oh Yeah, funny even comic books in the US those $4 spider-man's.
Scott: yeah, right It's like.
Scott: it's like okay like if Batman is set like is hot It'll maybe sell like tens of thousands of copies You know in a week if Batman comes out And that's that's like a good.
Scott: that's like real good.
Scott: tens of thousands in a country of hundreds of millions of people.
Rym: I'll tell you what I want all right I would just like there be an app that works on tablet mangas to sell.
Rym: you know Way way way more than that if they're an app that just worked on tablets generally like Android tablets and like there's all kinds of tablets and had a desktop version because I'm like on my laptop or Whatever should work on every device.
Scott: I've got yeah, and it should synchronize between every device I've got so I can pick up where I left off like your Kindle does but don't tie it to Amazon and also don't buy Amazon tablets.
Rym: they kind of they're kind of shitty yeah, so and I don't even need new manga I actually would just want like a wide collection of Classic old manga like a wide selection and that would do me.
Rym: I would pay for that probably forever as long as it's a manga that is my style right.
Rym: you know It's like I go back and read like a whole bunch of ridiculous lengthy nonsense.
Scott: He told us about a manga He worked on that failed about some girl who solves problem with solves problems with her advanced knowledge of physics.
Rym: I thought you're gonna say something very different cuz I was thinking about suki kimusume.
Scott: I know he talked about this manga.
Scott: that was like a failure of his.
Scott: And I was like I want to read that manga that sounds like the best manga.
Scott: I've ever heard.
Scott: yeah, right I want to read that right now.
Scott: And it's like that's the kind of obscure o manga that like started ran a few chapters Dot was cancelled right that you would find in a truly vast library.
Scott: You would never will.
Scott: no one would ever pay for that.
Scott: I would pay wouldn't even pay a dollar to read that but I really want to read.
Scott: well I would pay a dollar to read it.
Scott: as long as it came with a zillion other manga to read The other way it could go.
Rym: that I would be okay with is The same reason why I balk so much at using other game stores than steam even though there's problems with monopolies.
Rym: if Because there's just one app where I can just like see and buy a bunch of stuff and that app is consistent.
Rym: if there Was an app where I could just buy almost any manga you never had to pay each time I wanted a different as
Scott: long as the price was like a few cents or something even
Rym: if it was a few dollars
Scott: Right or even if it was like an audible token system like I think audible is like.
Scott: that's like the audio.
Scott: Oh, yeah, book on the audio.
Scott: What if it was like where you pay for this ad?
Rym: you'll get like you can read up to 10 volumes of manga a month And you can pay for more.
Rym: sure right.
Scott: It's like all right you get 20 volumes a month.
Scott: It's like I can only really read 20 volumes a month, so that sounds great.
Rym: But then you hook people by.
Rym: anything you've read stays in your catalog forever unless you stop paying the big yep.
Rym: sure I guess the subscription service that wouldn't be a vague because this is a legitimate business, but I digress.
Scott: right.
Scott: you know It's it's whatever it is right.
Scott: You know.
Scott: It's it's.
Scott: that's what they need.
Rym: they need quantity They need reach and we need to destroy capitalism so we can support artists actually making stuff, right?
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our Website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights for trying to get in as many episodes as we can While we have time to do episodes between all these conventions gives me a lot of video hitting the YouTube channel.
Rym: It does take a lot more total time to make a video From a convention of a brand new panel than it does to do a podcast.
Rym: so you'll see fewer GeekNights But you'll see more YouTube content at least for the time being.
Rym: but anyway Here we go.
Rym: Craig Oliver Allen Joyce Heidi McNichol just like a dude guy.
Rym: chart obviously and William ice and Roselyn kiji.
Rym: hydrated Gannon supports Hong Kong.
Rym: Chris mid give my state e.com.
Rym: Jay bench Sean Yeager Nicholas Brando Let's see if Rym says Toronto properly for two.
Rym: one creations started making trouble in my neighborhood.
Rym: Sure but all Superboy Clinton Walton run from New Zealand Ryan parent rope and lender Finn dread Lily Tenderberry Sean Klein Chris Reimer Thomas Han and now I leave you with Deep in my soul.
Rym: He's leaving for you.
Rym: Yeah, you just won't let go.
Scott: He's laying around He's got a mean bite.
Scott: Now he's ready to Stand up for what he knows.
Rym: I don't need your trophy So you go.
Rym: I just want to tell you all go.