Rym: It's Thursday June 20th 2019.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is the GeekNights book club tonight.
Rym: We are assuming that you read pages of pain by Troy Denning the Dungeons & Dragons Planescape branded canonical novel.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So I feel like it's a very basic thing to just talk about the weather like we kind of like a home today But don't really talk about the weather like not usually.
Rym: it rained today, but normally I wouldn't say anything about it.
Scott: It's been raining all fucking week.
Scott: I can't bike to work cuz it just keeps raining constantly.
Rym: Yep And I was hoping maybe cuz I'm gonna pick my bike up tomorrow from the shop.
Rym: So I was hoping I could get on a city bike tonight to go to that Screening the animation thing and then I'd have the city bike for 24 hours.
Rym: I would use it tomorrow to go to work and then to go to Chelsea to pick up my bike and then drive my real Bike home, but I don't think that's gonna happen cuz it ain't just raining it is fucking rain.
Scott: Well, it stopped but yeah It was.
Scott: uh, I was sitting in a meeting at work and then it starts like super raining like boom boom boom Like I very rarely in my life seen rain this persistent and hard in the United States.
Rym: the
Scott: time it rained The most is in between freshman and sophomore year of college when I was working in a summer camp And at one time I was driving to or from the camp Alone on the highway in Massachusetts like in the Berkshires somewhere Yeah And it rained so hard that with the wipers on the maximum setting and they were good wipers and there's nothing, you know, whatever I Couldn't see shit.
Scott: It was just a blur like I had Rym's eyeballs.
Scott: I couldn't see nothing.
Scott: I just pulled over to the side of the road and put the lights on and waited till I could see again.
Rym: So I think see I've experienced like you a few times in my life in the u.s.
Rym: But I spent a lot of time in like Singapore and Hong Kong and parts of Asia.
Rym: This is Singapore rain.
Rym: Like this is what it rains like during the rainy season in Singapore.
Scott: It's a lot of fun if you you know don't get caught in it and you're inside and you get caught You know and you don't want a bike to work.
Rym: I mean I was out in it when it started raining really hard again.
Scott: I luckily came from work to here in between to rain.
Rym: I stopped at the grocery store.
Rym: So I'm walking back from the grocery store and eggs are made.
Rym: I don't have my umbrella out and It's just like on my back and I feel like one or two drops of rain in my head.
Rym: I think well might as well open up this umbrella.
Rym: Just let me open up the umbrella and then just as I get it open.
Rym: It was like a wall of water Simultaneously hit the ground.
Rym: It was amazing.
Rym: I watched two cars hit each other like right outside the apartment in the rain on the way in.
Rym: don't drive Yeah, and a T and a taxi driver tried to turn illegally onto the bridge.
Scott: Okay, why I was crossing?
Rym: so I just stood there.
Scott: only bus can turn they there.
Rym: and so I was crossing.
Rym: So I just stood there and he couldn't get past me and he rolled down his window to try to yell at me.
Rym: And then the rain started going into his window and he like rolled it up and then he rolled it down a little bit to Try to yell at me and then I was bored.
Rym: So I left.
Rym: that was the end of that.
Rym: But anyway, there's no news cuz we're not gonna talk about the coming hopefully not actual war with Iran that we shouldn't be doing.
Rym: It's too depressing.
Rym: We're gonna talk about something similarly depressing painful pages, but first it's time for Things of the day.
Rym: So, you know, you watch a speedrun of like especially Zelda games.
Scott: Well, you know, there's a SGD Q. is this Sunday?
Rym: Yeah, I'm hyped for this.
Rym: Hi, but This channel terminal montage, one of the things that they seem to do is they make little cute animations You know like that car bot level of animation like those old Starcraft animations.
Rym: It's like that kind of like simple animation.
Scott: I don't know what you're talking about, but okay.
Rym: Remember the little like the cute zergs?
Rym: Yeah, and like the little lumpy spanny?
Rym: Wow, really?
Scott: I mean I might have you showed it to me.
Rym: Yeah, I'll show it to you later.
Rym: So it's similar like cute little ink doing his thing But basically they animate in a jokey way.
Rym: What a breath of the wild speedrun like a real one actually looks like.
Rym: so it has all the things that happen in a real Speedrun, but animated in a pretty funny way.
Rym: Okay, it's a better way to watch a Zelda speedrun than actually watching the speedrun.
Rym: Okay, so what do you got?
Scott: I have for you a man named Jimmy Smith?
Scott: Jimmy Smith is an amateur boxer.
Scott: his record as an amateur boxer is three, you know, he's a bad.
Scott: he's up against another gentleman.
Scott: I don't know the name of it would be glass Joe.
Rym: He beat the Kaiser, right?
Scott: You know, whatever He's up against another gentleman in this heavyweight bout.
Scott: The ring has an advertisement on it for a Schlitz malt liquor.
Scott: Which is me?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Rym says probably one of the worst forties you can drink.
Rym: Schlitz is one of those beers that well quote-unquote.
Scott: It's a 40.
Rym: It's one of those beverages that came out of the fact America had to rebuild its beverage industry from Scratch after prohibition.
Scott: Anyway, the title of the video is Jimmy Smith the worst boxer ever.
Scott: So Jimmy Smith goes up against this other boxer who is not the champion or anything But clearly has had professional bouts and lived to box again.
Scott: And here they are in a heavyweight bout.
Scott: keep in mind Jimmy Smith weighs like 16 something pounds less than the other guy and is like a few inches shorter and has less reach.
Rym: But he's undefeated.
Scott: Yeah But none of that matters because you once you see Jimmy Smith fight you will know everything you need to know.
Scott: It's one of those things that really fascinates me.
Scott: I wish there was like a word.
Scott: there probably is a German word for it where it has to be where it's like you don't Know shit about something right?
Scott: It's like I don't know any.
Scott: I could not be a graphic designer.
Scott: For example, no way I can't even draw but if I look at graphic design Right, I can still tell for the most part right?
Scott: Obviously I wouldn't get details, right?
Scott: Right, but there's no accounting for taste right but for the most part I can tell that's good.
Scott: That's comic sans, right?
Scott: I don't need to know anything to know that's good.
Scott: That's bad, right?
Scott: It's like in the same way if you know nothing about boxing you never watched a boxing match in your life.
Scott: Maybe those people would despise this boxing for mostly rightfully.
Scott: So but you know, it's okay to watch old boxing.
Scott: I just think we should stop having any more boxing now that we know better.
Rym: see also hockey fights Like.
Rym: I get excited watching a 90s hockey fight But I don't ever want to actually see a fight like that in a modern hockey game right regardless We have this old.
Rym: Well, the problem is I kind of do but I also don't.
Scott: anyway happens I get excited when you watch this fight, even if you know nothing about boxing, you know Even if it wasn't the title of the video you can tell if you are not is the worst boxer ever.
Scott: if you were not Human technically a professional because he was in this professional fight being paid to fight.
Rym: if you are not a human and you stumbled Upon this video with Jimmy Smith win his three amateur bouts I would love to see what those look like.
Rym: is the other guy doing the same elbow thing that he's doing?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: The point is watch this and it is amazing.
Rym: You watch it.
Rym: She's like buddy.
Rym: That's not where your elbows go.
Scott: when you're very funny You're about to get punched in the elbow and therefore it is thing of the day level.
Rym: It's It's only a minute and 36 seconds long.
Rym: Mm-hmm All right.
Rym: So the context of this as we've talked about a bunch is that there was an.
Rym: when I was a kid I Played Dungeons & Dragons and in Dungeons & Dragons.
Scott: I don't know if it was ever a first edition thing.
Scott: I'm pretty sure was the second edition thing mostly right.
Scott: there was a. there was a play setting for D&D That was official called Planescape and the idea of the setting was one in which the players Would have lots of access to portals that go between different planes to have a wild and crazy Experience and all sorts of different universes really easily.
Scott: and there was one central base of operations Which was a city that we argue over.
Scott: the pronunciation
Rym: of the canonical pronunciation, which is stupid is Sigil,
Scott: but it is written exactly what the way you would write the word Sigil as in the word Sigil, you know,
Rym: it's funny because when I was playing Dungeons & Dragons
Scott: Sigil
Rym: like in the 90s
Scott: No
Rym: one actually knew how any of these things were pronounced because you just pronounced it.
Rym: However, everyone around you pronounced it.
Rym: So when I like D&D was a topic on the radio or the TV you would only read about it in Dragon magazine or books Right or you'd meet something like you'd only say the words from Dungeons & Dragons out loud if you were playing Dungeons & Dragons.
Scott: But it kind of makes sense for the word Sigil to be the name of the city, right?
Scott: It's like I inscribed my Sigil upon the wall or something, you know, it's like, you know, you have a Sigil.
Rym: I don't think that really makes sense.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Sigil is like.
Rym: it's like a symbol right arcane symbol Yeah, but what would that have to do with the city a city in like some planes somewhere?
Scott: It's it's a roughly fantasy ish word.
Scott: You wouldn't use the word Sigil in everyday life.
Scott: Nah, you don't use it in a D&D fantasy book, but it's a fantasy ish word You mean in real life.
Scott: you might use the word rune maybe but even that's a fantasy word.
Rym: But case in point I pronounced it dro and I pronounced it so I said drow.
Rym: Yeah, it was random whether or not you knew the right pronunciation unless you like meant just cuz.
Scott: dro sounds stupid.
Rym: I think dro sounds better than drow drow drow drow.
Rym: But it's the way it's spelled phonics kid D R O W drow drow drow drow anyway Sigil Sigil.
Rym: So the difference in experience between me and Scott is that I had read all the planescape source material before this novel.
Scott: I have never read any planescape material even to this day except this book.
Rym: So Scott before we get into what I'm curious about is what do you like?
Rym: What do you think or what did you think like that sword lady was before you read this book?
Scott: Before I only knew things about D&D Right about these settings that I learned from osmosis hanging around nerds.
Scott: Yeah Who talked about these things or taught me about these things or told me about their character like this is how I know Dark Sun cuz.
Rym: I never played Dark Sun games until way later.
Rym: So in middle school, I would hear about Dark Sun from the cool kids me play like one Dark Sun session.
Rym: I played a couple of Dark Sun Sun sessions in high school.
Scott: I mean I never even heard of it till we got to RIT and I think we played it once and
Rym: played it because you were the
Scott: Play like one session and I think all I heard is other people talk about it and say yeah This is what Dark Sun is all about.
Scott: I didn't ever read a Dark Sun book.
Rym: pretty sure Dark Sun is not canonically connected to planescape.
Rym: Like you can't get there from here regardless.
Scott: I did play planescape torment, but it was such.
Scott: a. People love that game.
Scott: I know but it was such a annoying game for me to play.
Scott: just like, you know I met the gold box games.
Scott: Yeah, but I so I ended up.
Scott: actually when I was younger There was some other PC games I played on DOS and they would before while the games were loading or installing they would show you like a video trailer for planescape Torment because it was like made by the same publisher company or whatever.
Scott: Anyway, I actually played the game later in life And I didn't really absorb too much of the lore because I was just sort of reading a fact to get through it.
Scott: Yeah, I never would have gotten like Baldur's Gate.
Scott: I got through like to the town and that was it.
Scott: I can't really get very far in those games.
Scott: So the only reason I even beat it was from cheating and I didn't learn too much from cheating.
Scott: I didn't read a lot of the lores and stuff.
Scott: Yeah, so the deal is I only know what I absorbed from other people talking Like yeah, there's a city.
Scott: It's got a bunch of portals to other planes.
Scott: It's the center of the multiverse.
Scott: There's some lady there who's made of swords.
Scott: You've seen pictures of her everywhere because you've been in a game store before.
Scott: Yeah She comes if she's mad at you in the city and kills you.
Scott: She's the lady of pain.
Scott: She runs the show there.
Scott: She's all mysterious and shit.
Scott: She's a terrible seeker to space.
Scott: So here's something about God's not coming there.
Scott: and yeah If you pray to her she gets mad because then she would become a god and that would be bad.
Rym: because the context it's bad To be a god there the context you wouldn't have.
Rym: that came up a lot in the book is a few specific Planescape things.
Rym: number one is that in Planescape like it's different from the prime material planes.
Rym: Like people there are just different.
Rym: like if you're on a prime material plane like I got it around and you just die Your soul just goes straight to the plane of whatever God you worship.
Rym: Planescape fuck you now what like gods aren't gonna help you you're out.
Rym: It's like being in a city versus being in like the provinces.
Rym: number two.
Rym: The other weird thing is that there are these factions.
Rym: It's like a big part of the original Planescape setting.
Rym: I got a vague hint of that in Planescape 2 because every character except the Thrasin were Earthration or however the amnesian hero Theseus maybe.
Rym: Every one of them is basically in one of these factions like Tesali the elf the Barrier like the goat centaur who believes that he's the center of the universe.
Rym: Every one of them is like in one of these factions and in the game world The factions are like something characters join and it's part of the plot and they're all very simplistic Philosophy nonsense things like.
Rym: one of them is a faction of hedonists and the leader is of course Yeah, exactly The leader that's for me.
Scott: give me the grapes.
Rym: the leader of that faction Is a my lounging chair.
Rym: It's a woman who is a werecat because cat girl.
Scott: Oh, baby.
Scott: Yeah, sign me up I already chose.
Scott: I don't need to hear the other options.
Rym: You are objectively correct because you've the ones you encountered in this fucking book that you're all garbage compared to the one you just described.
Rym: Let's see this one awesome cat girl pleasure forever.
Rym: Awesome, the dustman everything sucks and we're all gonna die.
Rym: Yeah I am literally the center of the universe next.
Scott: next.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: They're all dumb like that.
Rym: Yeah, those guards in the big those are another faction.
Scott: Nope, not better than cat lady.
Rym: None of them are good news.
Scott: No, the cat lady's the only good one.
Rym: Uh, yeah, there's literally the only good one.
Scott: So that brings up.
Scott: the first point about this book that I want to make is that you don't need To know any D&D stuff to read this book.
Scott: But it really sure helps because they basically just assume you know a lot of things Right proper noun wise which you know other fantasy novels with the proper nouns right like say Prince of Nothing.
Rym: We love the Prince of Nothing.
Scott: two words in it's all right But you know They lead you in and through Context and through reading you sort of begin to understand what the proper nouns mean and what's going on without having just being told to You right?
Scott: However There is a lot of things that just go straight over your head because the book isn't that long and doesn't have that much Context.
Scott: so you learn enough to understand what's happening in the book, but there is a greater context.
Scott: I feel that's not necessary to understand the main story and its main characters But that will be missed if you are not steeped in the planescape lore and I probably missed more than half of
Rym: it Yep, and the other part of that the context that's important is that Pages of Pain was kind of as far as I can tell was kind of written to try to introduce people to the setting because the setting had Only been out a couple of years.
Scott: Okay Another thing is that even stuff that you could understand what was going on for example right at the beginning of the book he goes To wait in this line Yeah to go talk to someone at a window and you get the idea that like there's this bureaucracy in the city Right and has a thing going on and like I understood the deal basically Yeah,
Rym: but I
Scott: felt like if I was a planescape nerd I would be reading this right now
Rym: like oh that's so-and-so Bullshit, right like oh, baby Because
Scott: I hadn't read any planescape stuff.
Scott: It was all right.
Scott: I get it.
Scott: There's some bureaucracy thing.
Scott: you wait in a line and talk to someone and you can get stuff from because there's no government.
Scott: That's like a real government or it's definitely not democracy.
Rym: Yeah, it's a bureaucracy.
Rym: Generally the people we people play and run planescape at least in my experience is they tend to set it in Sigil as opposed to doing a lot of planes hopping.
Scott: well I mean when you set it in Sigil you can planes hop easily.
Scott: yep as we see in the book and Sigil is sort of like A mishmash.
Scott: It's like if you started it and say I don't know the plane of fire, and you're immune to fire.
Scott: I guess yeah Usually you'd be playing a fire is just like you make a portal to throw someone into fire.
Scott: right right You can you set a game in some other plane.
Scott: the idea would be it's like all right.
Scott: well You had to leave the plane somehow which might not be so easy, but when you're in Sigil You can hop around a lot of playing.
Rym: well That's what I'm getting.
Scott: so it's like start your New York game in Grand Central.
Scott: don't start your New York game in distant Brooklyn.
Rym: Sigil is basically New York City of the multiverse because it's the center of the like Multiverses economy.
Scott: right you start your New York game out in Long Island and there's one LIR station, and it's on a weekend.
Scott: It's like the player characters getting to Manhattan is gonna be rough.
Scott: you start in Grand Central.
Scott: It's like yeah You could get out to Long Island pretty easily.
Rym: Your analogy is better than you realize.
Rym: remember all those bits about the people falling in the river through the portal and the wine and All that in the beginning.
Rym: kinda There's an idea of play of uh portal keys Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Scott: Well they got into that a little bit when they were in the tavern.
Rym: that's a big deal in the planescape setting.
Rym: What was that?
Rym: You gotta have the key or the portal doesn't do shit.
Scott: that was actually one of the scenes that made the most sense.
Scott: was Tavern and basically the police equivalent is coming after them.
Rym: I guess.
Rym: well because the tavern is it serves illegal human meat.
Scott: yes They need to hide so they go through a door in the back of the tavern which is and they do a special key thing.
Scott: So actually when they go back there They actually go through a portal to some other like room somewhere a warehouse where they actually store this expensive wine and stuff, right?
Scott: it's like it's like a portal to a warehouse in another plane and When the police come they go through the door in the back to the back room and they're just in a back room Because they didn't do the special thing to activate the portal the other plane.
Scott: So that was pretty clever and fun.
Scott: But then things develop from there.
Rym: So what I remember?
Scott: reading his book that was a very D&D thing like aha I escaped the guys by doing a clever You know, that's it.
Rym: I remembered reading his book and it was Standard D&D book for like the first fifth and then it went way off the rails and got surreal.
Rym: and that's why I remembered it Why I liked it why I felt this weird need to read it again.
Rym: And that first bit was very typical D&D nonsense like every Forgotten Realms book has that kind of clever shit.
Scott: Well, it also had some kind of core.
Scott: The character's name is Jake the snake.
Scott: It's like oh my god I'll totally watch a dumb guy in your party names their character, but that's kind of on brand for the faction She's in.
Rym: okay, they're all.
Scott: I guess.
Scott: then that is.
Scott: I guess you couldn't blame the author of this book But instead the author of the setting for D&D.
Scott: shit in.
Rym: yeah, like imagine that faction is literally just reaper from overwatch.
Rym: They're all just like edgelord pieces of shit.
Scott: So your edgelord friend who you let in the game and didn't kick out for whatever reason is always gonna pick that Always gonna pick that.
Scott: why aren't they picking the cat lady faction?
Scott: That's how you know.
Scott: if basically here's what you do Planescape game.
Scott: you were you list all the factions list the cat lady one last.
Scott: anyone who doesn't pick the cat lady one Just kick him out of the game.
Rym: Yeah, they're no good because you know if they ever get into a real multiverse situation They're gonna make poor decisions.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: So but yeah like normal D&D stuff like that just happens with really stereotypical plot and everything and then it goes way off the rails.
Scott: The characters act like PCs act in a D&D game of Teenage Nerd sitting around a table.
Rym: Yep I look around the corner.
Rym: former make our formation.
Rym: We're doing a trick like let's do a thing, right?
Rym: But before we get into the crazy stuff that beginning bit one thing I noticed is that when I played Planescape and when most people Would run Planescape they tend to run.
Rym: Sigil is like a Perdido Street station kind of like really dirty Dismal like people are knifed in the back alley.
Scott: looks like in Planescape Dormant.
Rym: Yeah And that's how people tend to play it.
Rym: But this book takes it to like and this book does not at any point give you a view Into any part of Sigil that's even remotely livable or nice.
Rym: No, it's just awful awful awful.
Scott: every single person you talk to on the street is like Violence.
Scott: you yeah.
Scott: Oh you're talking to me.
Scott: I assume you would like some violence or some thieving.
Scott: at least he bumps into that one guy.
Rym: It's like pulls out a knife instantly.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, but is it?
Rym: I don't want to give Troy Denning that much credit here But is it that they described Sigil in this like horrific way?
Rym: Because this book kind of has a lot of horrific themes?
Rym: or that's how they viewed Sigil as opposed to like someone who read the setting book and might take a more nuanced approach to it?
Rym: Or is that what Sigil looks like to the narrator the lady of pain herself?
Rym: Who cannot perceive anything but pain?
Rym: Because she only experiences the painful parts of Sigil Mm-hmm And that's like.
Rym: that's that like that allegorical storytelling is there and I feel like it was on purpose Coupled with the fact that the other way to look at it is the Thrasin.
Rym: He comes from a nice place upstate So he gets into this dirty city and is afraid of it and everything's not nearly as bad as he is acting like it is Because he just doesn't understand.
Rym: like you it smells like pee and people have knives.
Rym: They're trying to see he's also.
Scott: really It's sort of a thing where on the one hand the story is about the Thrasin.
Scott: Who is he?
Scott: What's his deal?
Scott: How'd he get here all this mystery?
Rym: as a nerd as a kid I didn't give a shit.
Rym: I just wanted to know is this gonna tell me what the lady of pain is, right?
Scott: That was also.
Scott: that's the real secret of space kind of does sort of.
Scott: But on the same time by having this main character be it's sort of a trope right where the main character has amnesia They're learning everything just like you are reader, right, you know about Sigil in the war.
Scott: They've never been here.
Scott: They don't know what's up.
Scott: You're learning along with them.
Scott: So by combining that trope with also the story being about the character recovering the memory it sort of Overcomes the cliche in a way.
Rym: Yeah Right to a degree it works and I like how because basically there is a plane that is just ancient Greece with Greek gods Of course.
Scott: So it just makes sense.
Rym: and he is clearly just like a Theseus like figure like he's just a Greek hero and Zeus.
Rym: Zeus and Poseidon were like literally there.
Rym: Yeah, Poseidon literally gave him a mission and If you don't know anything about Greek mythology, he remembers that.
Rym: yeah only thing you remember that we'll get into that.
Rym: That's.
Rym: that's a very important point about this book.
Rym: What is a memory?
Rym: but which is it like?
Rym: it treats memories the way a lot of good sci-fi books treat memories a free market Almost literally.
Rym: but Imagine we're like.
Rym: we already talked about reading this book.
Rym: If you don't know anything about Planescape imagine some basic person who likes D&D and reads this book, but doesn't know anything about Greek mythology Like it kind of is important to understand Poseidon's deal.
Scott: You at least need to know the main.
Scott: you at least need to know basic characters and like, you know Poseidon Yeah is kind of a dick.
Rym: He's a Don't drown me, right?
Scott: You need to know at least that much.
Scott: maybe a little more.
Rym: don't worship Poseidon, but you gotta respect Poseidon.
Rym: Also Egyptian gods cuz I guess sure that's how Planescape works.
Scott: Greek and Egypt pretty tight Yeah, Poseidon.
Rym: and I guess set just make a deal to sell off a woman into slavery And or marriage maybe the same thing.
Rym: So, yeah that that all starts like standard D&D plot.
Rym: and then the Dabu's which you know about if you read the source books.
Scott: So this is the part where I think the book's biggest flaw is but also maybe Intentional but still in my opinion bad.
Scott: Is that as As you read the book even in the beginning parts, but especially once the Dabus show up, right?
Scott: That's where it goes off the rails.
Scott: Yep in many ways, but any individual scene you can understand what's happening.
Rym: Right, like like he is waiting in line and arguing and that breaks that guy's arm.
Scott: the transitions from literally every Scene to every other scene are basically instantaneous Like a Complete jump cut in some movie from one place to another place across the universe.
Rym: at one point evening It's lampshaded like he runs away with Jake the snake and then it has a little paragraph.
Rym: That's like After a whole bunch of bullshit.
Rym: they ended up in this alley, right?
Scott: It's like Sentence almost doesn't even exist, right?
Scott: It's like one sentence.
Scott: They leave that the tavern I was just talking about, right?
Scott: They were dudes that deal with the portal in the back and writing right and then suddenly they're like outside.
Scott: I don't know how the hell they got outside, but I guess the deal was over there.
Scott: outside There was some Dabus building a wall for a maze nearby on the street.
Scott: Some other stuff happens and then they're just in the maze.
Scott: It's like what what the fuck?
Scott: It's like how the fuck did that, you know.
Rym: now that's another.
Rym: if you knew how Dabus work They're basically like the minions of the Lady of Pain.
Scott: I understood that much.
Scott: They
Rym: don't talk out loud
Scott: really
Rym: make like rebuses and symbols appear around them and You can interpret what they're trying to tell you by looking at all these symbols floating around their heads and all they do is if you fuck with them they kill you and Otherwise, they just build walls around you and if they build a wall around you you're in the mazes,
Scott: right?
Scott: but it's like the the the.
Scott: the text was written in such a way that it's not like The rocks were encircling them and they tried to climb over and the Dabu pushed them.
Scott: Yeah, they were.
Scott: it was just like oh, there's some Dabus.
Scott: We're in a maze.
Scott: What?
Scott: It's like there was no smooth transition showing how Things got from this scene to the next scene.
Scott: So on one hand anywhere any scene change in the whole book was just instant until they're in the very and basically So you spent the first portion of any scene trying to figure out what the fuck just happened.
Scott: Where are they now?
Scott: What is going on?
Scott: Because like you could tell like what we're not in this past scene anymore.
Scott: We're somewhere else.
Scott: now What is happening?
Scott: as I was constantly?
Scott: Reorienting myself which in a way is thematic like if I was getting pushed through a bunch of portals to different planes constantly But they're not.
Scott: this is almost entirely in sigil.
Rym: Yeah But in terms of that bit like I feel like some of those missing scenes might have been Missing.
Scott: it's not.
Scott: missing scenes is just well, there are no transitions.
Rym: There's a bunch of missing scenes that are sort of like skipped over where I wonder if he had written a longer book and they Dude Dude,
Scott: I also wonder how much of this corny stuff is
Rym: the right
Scott: author's fault or the fault of sticking to the source material Of the settings like you just talked about Jake the snake.
Rym: Well, I get one point and it it matters a lot for such a weird Dungeons and Dragons.
Rym: He's seen he's in a random ass alley and he tries to jump over that puddle of mud.
Rym: Then it tries to pull him in and turn him into goo.
Scott: Yeah, that's very D&D.
Rym: Yeah, that is so.
Rym: there's.
Rym: there's the four elemental planes fire water earth air.
Rym: There's also two other planes the positive energy plane and the negative energy plane.
Scott: Well slime princess and hotdog princess.
Rym: Yeah, it's that exact kind of like specific cosmology but like if you guessed a healing spell in regular D&D you're channeling energy from the positive plane and Necromancers channel from the negative plane.
Rym: So where those four elemental planes intersect with each other They make these like para elemental planes like water and earth together form the para elemental plane of ooze.
Rym: It's the border between the two Water and they're all next to each other.
Rym: They're all next to each other in this multi-dimensional thing.
Rym: I know more about this than I should feel like air Next to the positive elemental or the positive energy plane.
Rym: I think it makes like the plane of lightning.
Rym: Ooh, if I recall correctly and next to the negative plane the negative energy plane makes the plane of vacuum which is not the same vacuum that spell jammers fly through.
Rym: Spell jammers don't really fit into this kind of cosmology directly.
Rym: You can make it work.
Rym: So that is such D&D like Bullshit.
Rym: Yep, but and it would have just been a throwaway scene except it matters like deeply for the rest of the book Yep, and it's it was weird that that was one of the transformative moments for this character.
Rym: like it just stood out to me as being a strange way to make the Allegorical transformation of the character become a literal transformation of the character.
Rym: and you can see how that.
Rym: and then when they cut the foot Off and they replace it with the hand and then to Solly's hands get cut off It's sort of making this meta point around how like when you're injured Physically you have a wound that you and everyone else can see.
Rym: but when you're injured Spiritually or mentally you carry that pain and it's invisible.
Scott: Anyone but you except for the lady of pain and the threats and eventually can see it.
Rym: Yeah, the lady can see those husks.
Scott: It's a bunch of colored husk pustules on your body and they can get popped I guess somehow.
Scott: so there really hurts.
Rym: there is consistency in the color of those pustules.
Scott: I figured that out.
Rym: Yeah I did not care enough to try to remember figure out.
Scott: no I didn't figure out which ones were which but I did figure out that person has those colors.
Scott: this person is those colors.
Scott: They're kinds of pain.
Scott: They're all flavors of pain.
Scott: Yep, right It's like your pain comes from I don't know self-loathing and yours comes from fear of death fear of sun, right?
Rym: Or you know existential crisis doubt anguish loss, etc.
Rym: Whatever I did like how even car Fudd who is like the most badass.
Rym: I am a demon I give no fucks.
Scott: That's another example of a. I just want to bring that up as a sudden scene change.
Scott: Yeah, it's.
Scott: it wasn't just the fact that it was a sudden scene change.
Scott: It was just like there's a demon guy here now.
Scott: There was no foreshadowing of this demon guy It's just the threats.
Scott: and went somewhere and there was a demon and he met him and said hi and now the demons.
Scott: a major character who's there for the rest of the book.
Scott: and it's just like No intro.
Scott: No No, nothing to tell you that this is right.
Scott: It's just you see someone meets and it's such a D&D thing walk into a tavern.
Scott: There's an NPC.
Scott: I'm looking for an NPC.
Scott: There's one.
Scott: talk to him now.
Scott: They're in the party now.
Rym: They're part of your plot, right, but it doesn't really make for great novel Yeah, but it works in a sense because he's like the only person who is in the mazes on purpose that's true, like he locked himself in there.
Rym: and There's sort of this meta plot that ties so much into just like planescape nonsense that there's this idea in planescape that gods are basically collections of people who had similar ideas that formed into like a bigger being that has that same idea and mass.
Rym: and Sigil is at the center of the multiverse on top of an infinitely tall spire and No gods can get there.
Rym: and there's one God who's been climbing up that tower for billions of years trying to get to the top and he can't because it's infinitely tall.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: and If it truly is the godless center of the multiverse could be.
Rym: but if it truly is the godless center of the multiverse and All meaning springs from belief then you get the impression that this demon guy Went there to try and figure out the meaning of the universe and/or take over the universe.
Scott: He's making maps of everything.
Rym: He's trying to map the center of the universe.
Scott: He's very protective of his maps.
Scott: Yep Like he's a lot of work until almost comically.
Rym: so when he just skins the barrier later.
Scott: And yeah, well, he says he didn't but he totally did.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, it's a chaotic evil demon like Even more.
Rym: what do you want?
Scott: It's like you can't forget.
Rym: He's an evil demon yet somehow he is like Literally the only character in this party making rational decisions at any point.
Scott: He's kind of competent and powerful and has goals and while he lies has lost his memory.
Rym: while he lies That's what demons do.
Rym: He doesn't renege on his deals.
Scott: He's.
Scott: he made it like a blood pact I think he.
Scott: I think he physically can't renege.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: That's all deal He's not.
Scott: I mean, maybe if he just said the deal he could renege easily.
Scott: But it's another.
Rym: one of those things were like if you know if you know D&D shit You know what a tanari is.
Rym: and then he's like, ah, I smell a marilith like yeah, that's the snake ladies He wanted to quote-unquote.
Rym: enter the frenzy.
Rym: It's a steven pon far empty the granaries That was that was very D&D that.
Rym: But Yeah, he's there trying to think where I was going with all that just these characters.
Rym: He's the only competent interesting character.
Rym: The main character is competent but makes stupid decisions because of the wine woman.
Rym: Jake makes terrible decisions.
Rym: Yep, that's why Jake was going to be locked up.
Rym: She was probably locked up for good cause.
Scott: Yeah Tassali actually is pretty reasonable like the elf guy is a reasonable intelligent You know person is just sort of on the wrong side of things a little bit.
Rym: Well, he runs the asylum.
Rym: Yeah, and from his perspective Jake is crazy.
Scott: I mean at first you sort of feel at the beginning of the book you feel like he's just wrong and it's like an Evil guy who locks people up for no reason.
Scott: Yeah, but then as the book goes on it's like oh that guy's rational.
Scott: Yeah, Jake is crazy.
Rym: Jake has clearly been going around just murdering people.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you totally should listen to that guy.
Rym: I feel like he might have been a little overzealous and trying to lock up the threson.
Scott: Right.
Scott: the threson clearly isn't crazy because you but we know the threson hasn't lost memory But it's obvious from their perspective.
Scott: Yeah, the threson is crazy.
Scott: Yeah, for knowing what Dane, you know because at the start of the book I didn't know what they knew.
Scott: but then once you know what they know Yeah, as you learn more about what you know It's like if I knew what I knew at the beginning of the book I would also think this guy was crazy.
Rym: like imagine if some someone from upstate New York came to New York City and Wandered around the street asking random people.
Rym: I need to see the mayor.
Rym: Take me to the mayor.
Rym: in a universe where the mayor kills anyone who talks to them Right.
Rym: I saw a dragon.
Rym: And this is known.
Rym: Yep Like literally everyone knows.
Rym: Oh, yeah, if you run into de Blasio, he fucking stabs you like that.
Rym: That's just common knowledge.
Rym: Like it's on the news every night.
Rym: How many people did de Blasio stab today?
Rym: Yeah So that also kind of works.
Scott: so to say his name three times he appears And he's pissed.
Scott: Yeah, be quiet bro.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: Go away from this guy.
Rym: And then you got this jerk comes to town.
Rym: He's like yo dog.
Scott: I'm gonna keep saying his name like in your house like oh good god Run away, please arrest this nut job.
Scott: Put him somewhere.
Scott: We're safe.
Rym: Yep, so Is he really Theseus?
Scott: I don't think it matters.
Scott: What I think does matter is that they suggest that he's Theseus and his body Memories and physical body are the ship of Theseus.
Rym: I see what you did there that that works.
Scott: That's all that matters right because he could be just a dude for all you know, it doesn't fucking matter.
Scott: There's no way to know.
Rym: he replaces his memories with new memories bit by bit and then to drive the point home.
Rym: It's easy body parts bit by bit, right?
Scott: He replaces his memories with the memories of Theseus.
Scott: Does that make him Theseus?
Scott: He replaces his Leg with a but I guess does that is he still Theseus?
Scott: doesn't have these?
Rym: is he still the amnesian hero?
Rym: Is he still the Thrasin which it almost like it excuses the fact that the book keeps calling him by different names?
Rym: Depending on the perspective even within the same paragraph, but then at the end like that actually really does make allegorical sense.
Scott: Yeah, but the writing wise prose wise.
Scott: it was on purpose prose wise.
Scott: It was annoying that there was just this pattern of.
Scott: you got two names for him.
Scott: alternate between the two All right.
Scott: Now we got three names for him.
Scott: zoom B. We're gonna alternate between the three names right just to mix up the text a little bit right and did not just keep saying Thrasin Thrasin Thrasin Thrasin Thrasin Thrasin Thrasin Thrasin Thrasin Thrasin Thrasin right, they just made more names for him and kept cycling through them like, you know Like a like a like a pattern on the American flag red white red white red.
Rym: I'll admit the writing of that could have been a lot more elegant But I think it was on purpose and the craft was Okay in the sense that the name used because it's not just the name he used for himself was the you know Amnesian hero.
Rym: I am the amnesian hero because that was the identity made from set for himself from his own memories.
Rym: but then every other character he interacts with has their own memories of him and has their own perception of him and Give it a different name because those are all very different people.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: But that theme is explored in a lot especially the barrier.
Rym: Yeah That barrier is just like dude.
Rym: really yeah, he deserved to get.
Scott: yeah, not really he wasn't bad he was just dumb.
Rym: Yeah, well that faction is dumb.
Rym: no, yeah, cuz it's not the cat lady fact, yeah Can't have more than one person in that faction in the same party.
Rym: guys, that's true.
Rym: He was alone to their credit, yeah, I probably because his friends were like listen and just threw him over the wall.
Rym: Also, I love how not only was he kind of dumb, but he really fucked everything up by picking up the other end of that Thread.
Scott: Yeah, really?
Rym: Yeah But Otherwise like the naming of the character really does fit the theme and I think you're right.
Rym: It doesn't matter if he's Theseus But I will say that a lot of sci-fi books have handled the concept of what is a person?
Rym: What is a memory?
Rym: do memories make you much better than this with much more elegance?
Rym: Yeah, but it does handle him in a pretty good way.
Rym: And if you'd never read one of those other books, this is that's a. it's kind of like people who?
Rym: Encountered philosophy from the matrix for the first time.
Rym: Mmm, like yeah like welcome to the party But I'm glad you have at least come to the table now With you.
Rym: you've learned about shadows on the wall.
Rym: Congratulations.
Scott: It's always hilarious just to see like in all aspects of you know, I guess intellectual philosophical thought especially on the internet, right?
Scott: I saw like I see these threads posted like on like board game reddit or something.
Scott: Yeah, where someone's like, ah Something something something.
Scott: it's like they just discovered babies first and it's like all right.
Scott: on the one hand It's like I want to say to them bro.
Rym: That's babies first, bro You should have learned that in middle school, right?
Scott: But on the other hand, it's like ah This person has just found the small door to the larger world of thinking about how games work.
Rym: Welcome yep, right and I can think like.
Rym: The reasons book stuck with me is that I had read good science fiction and good fantasy And I also read a lot of garbage Dungeons & Dragons fuck items fantasy.
Rym: but this book stood out because it addressed all those kinds of things that a like freshman in high school Rym would think a lot about.
Rym: so the book would feel like the book would introduce or Expand on those kinds of concepts.
Rym: and when I was older I read a lot more and learned a lot more about philosophy.
Rym: and if I read this book today Without having this previous experience no new concept was introduced to adult Rym in this book.
Scott: Well, but what?
Scott: maybe if you had never read this book there would have been right because you read this book previous.
Scott: Yeah true, but that it being said I hadn't.
Scott: and no new concept was introduced to adult Scott's.
Rym: Yeah, because even 1996 Rym had the idea of what is a memory and does that make a person?
Rym: Yeah, like I had already encountered that core concept.
Rym: Yes But I had never encountered it in a Dungeons & Dragons book before right never even encountered it in a fantasy setting before Always sci-fi hmm, at least in my youth.
Rym: Mm-hmm but it I'm impressed that this book deals with those concepts and Read like what do you see?
Rym: a branded Dungeons & Dragons kind of book?
Rym: You don't expect it to take a like a pretty heavy concept like that and push it all the way into surreal Nonsense, that is not what happens with.
Rym: like popular culture works Like the good place is a really good show But it's not.
Rym: I don't think it's gonna get full-on secret of space like end of Evangeline.
Rym: I think it's gonna be a few steps away from that.
Scott: You know Netflix real soon.
Scott: Yeah, see what happens.
Rym: but this book goes like full-on into like crazy crazy crazy like the world like everything gets abstract and weird and Like the ending is so abrupt.
Rym: It gets away with the kind of stuff that I would never expect a light officially licensed anything to get away with.
Rym: And that really stands out in my mind.
Rym: Like it is notable that this book was allowed to be published with the content It has in it considering its target audience.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and I I'm impressed with that.
Rym: Mm-hmm Are you glad you read it?
Scott: Yeah, yeah I mean basically the way I see it is like, you know, I read those Timothy Zahn Star Wars novels which everyone said were the best.
Rym: I feel like this is better than those.
Scott: right and If people say those are the best Star Wars novels and my opinion of them was Thrawn is a cool character But otherwise maybe Mara Jade or whatever her name is there's a character, but I can barely remember the story.
Scott: It's kind of and whatever right.
Scott: if that's the best you got I ain't reading anymore.
Scott: So I mean it basically is like sort of along the same token or is like, all right If this is the best D&D novel, you don't read any other D&D books.
Scott: I'm not reading anymore right But I can see how a it's like.
Scott: yes it is like.
Scott: Rym said.
Scott: it's notable that you know some.
Scott: it was a licensed You know an official, you know IP license on your book.
Scott: you managed to go off the rails a bit Right in just instead of just you know telling a straightforward, you know, pulp adventure story.
Rym: That's notable and it goes pretty far off the rails like the monster in the maze, which is Sufficiently horrifying.
Rym: Yeah tears its own skin Fluffy and getting in the way and that is not even the most group.
Scott: like gruesome thing that happens that that we're eating the dude's hand.
Rym: Yeah, that was just funny.
Scott: Also, right it is.
Scott: Was I gonna say I forget.
Scott: You started talking about the about the pop culture like some parts like it did got away with this stuff Just by as you know for the audience right for this book being like tea, you know Young teen D&D whatever.
Scott: this book is probably way good for someone like that.
Rym: Yeah, right for sure Right, especially because it almost like just like there are.
Scott: I'm not right.
Scott: There are a lot of like young adult novels that are actually good just for all ages even though they're you know Branded as young adult novels, right?
Scott: They're just good for everybody.
Scott: Regard like the Hunger Games is is young adult novel and I mean it's perfectly fine for everyone.
Scott: It's like some great novel but it's it's better than this Right, it's fine for all ages reading right, but You know I think this is definitely a young adult novel that is good for the teen preteen and for the adult less.
Rym: Oh, yep What about one aspect I really liked about it because I remember the ending being abrupt and reading it again.
Scott: that really read Ending is abrupt.
Rym: I love how like it just accelerates and accelerates to this feverish pace and the end is literally like a series of burning wheels wheel Style like.
Rym: are you going to abandon Jake or the mission?
Rym: Are you gonna abandon the like abandon this or the mission or the mid?
Rym: But but but but but and then in the end It's just this fever page and then he's lost his limbs and everyone's gruesomely deformed.
Rym: and then look they just wake up on the street Like nothing had happened.
Rym: Mm-hmm, except they carry all these wounds both physical and mental Like you get the impression.
Scott: It's sort of like a loop situation maybe which is a little cliche.
Rym: Well, he even says out like he says to himself looking at the River Styx how many times have I done this?
Rym: fuck right.
Scott: Oh, I can't remember the name of the river.
Rym: Yeah, and then he's calling it something else The River Styx or the river lead?
Rym: Yeah, let me you know, it's all like if you drink from it.
Rym: You know it by a different name like that's kind of a thing and it right you lose your memory when you drink from it.
Rym: Yep, and the lady of pain like it just like with him.
Rym: It doesn't matter if she is that woman from his memories or not.
Rym: most likely I think Poseidon like canonically in this is just a piece of shit.
Rym: who's trying to take over sigil and put these memories in a Giant amphora and tried to trick the lady of pain into remembering stuff that may or may not have been true just to destroy her Like that tracks with the kind of shit Poseidon would do.
Scott: Yeah Or is it?
Scott: you know a thing where it's like, you know the memories are for.
Scott: You know the thoracic guy.
Scott: somehow if he opens it when the lady of pain is there Armed with those memories.
Scott: He'll be able to like mess with her or something.
Scott: Yeah, right I mean, I couldn't really tell but there was like a net in there also or something.
Scott: Yeah Poseidon Maybe the net would catch her.
Scott: he would regain his memory and then be able to take her out or something like that.
Rym: Yep, something like that Poseidon had a plan and he had other great gods on board like the wine woman.
Scott: Yep Like that's all just sort of explained actually in a pretty succinct way Yeah, and then so the only thing let's talk about is like the real big picture is like what's the lady of pains deal?
Scott: Right.
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: so cuz it's definitely
Rym: D&D books like they like to do this thing of Concepts elemental concepts like air or fire or pain or love have physical embodiments and like the Necessity of good and evil like you can't have good without evil to justify having all the evil shit in the world for you to fight.
Rym: And it does that with pain without her.
Scott: all the things that are like all the parts of the book that are narrated by the lady Of pain from her perspective They always have like these weird things going on Like my feet was my feet touch the ground that I appear or the feet come off the ground and yeah There's something like that.
Scott: So you get the impression like she's invisible going around Extremely self-aware like ah, this is a trap for Poseidon, but I'm gonna fall for it Right.
Rym: I can't help it or pain sucks But if I don't keep making pain out there Then the world will fall apart.
Rym: cuz without pain people cannot know.
Rym: joy right could also be read as the lady of pain is deluded and that's the rationalization for the Ridiculous painful bullshit.
Scott: She's up to yeah It's like you can sort of see what the lady of pain is thinking and like sort of understand how she works like she goes around invisibly and then appears in places but Sort of just maybe isn't in complete control of her own stuff.
Scott: it's just sort of thinking and sort of doing what she has to do.
Scott: or is, you know, like Like there's a consciousness that is In this body that does all this pain shit, but doesn't control the pain shit Almost watches it happen.
Rym: a lot of almost fiction.
Rym: I've read both D&D and like good.
Rym: Often when they portray the way a deity thinks or an all-knowing being thinks they tend to portray it very similarly.
Scott: It almost feels like the narrator is a lady of pain But is also out of the lady of pains body and is like, you know watching the you know It's yeah, it's like it's having an out-of-body experience Narrating while watching itself do stuff.
Rym: But I've seen that like writing pattern in a lot of fiction involving gods and omnipotent or omniscient beings, right?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's like oh I see myself, you know touch the ground and appear and do these things to the people and you know.
Scott: So it's like.
Scott: is it even in that it always says me but it's like, you know, it's a lady of pain.
Scott: It's not like who else could be.
Scott: yeah, especially, you know, if you had any question about it There's a part where it's like, ah, then I appear and everyone's like, oh shit lady of pain It's like duh, bro.
Rym: I like the little tiny bit at the end where it it Repeatedly points out Jake the snakes eyes and how you can read her moods based on that.
Rym: and Carfa the demons eyes Because they blaze maroon, which is like a demon thing and like his eyes were like betray him.
Scott: It's all setting stuff, right?
Rym: But then in the very end when the threson is looking into the river sticks and deciding where they're not drink from it It makes a point of that.
Rym: He sees his eyes flash purple.
Rym: No, I didn't see any says something to the effect of.
Rym: I'll never turn my back on a tannery again almost implying that the path to becoming a demon like that is to do the horrible things that he keeps doing because he keeps Forgetting his like.
Rym: he keeps drinking from this river forgetting himself and making the same horrible mistakes over and over again Like making demon packs.
Rym: Yeah, like may almost turning into a people's hands off and putting them on his feet.
Rym: Well, like to be fair.
Rym: He was not on board with that plan.
Rym: He still did it and to be fair cart like car foods plan they're Probably the best possible plan considering the circumstances which is an interesting point.
Rym: I would say that but it is yeah Yeah, but that's it bit by all.
Rym: the decisions they make once they meet the demon are Rational in the context of what they're doing, but they're also tiny steps toward being evil Tiny steps toward being a demon.
Rym: at what point do you say?
Rym: No, fuck this.
Rym: I'd rather just die than continue this quest.
Rym: But at the same time it's very easy to justify those steps he takes and car foot is right in a way About everything except maybe the core concept of maybe you just shouldn't have put yourself in this maze in the first place And they didn't put him in.
Scott: the guys came and like shoved him in So I didn't know how they got in.
Scott: there was just net there and then they're in it.
Rym: Yep Anyway, so yeah, this book is memorable.
Rym: I think it is the best D&D branded book.
Rym: having read it again.
Rym: I Would recommend if you're an edgelord teen who is into D&D read this book.
Scott: Sure, like yeah for sure if you're in high school I guess if you have to read a D&D branded officially licensed book, I guess this.
Scott: not knowing any other ones I guess this is the fucking one.
Scott: But if you're an adult, I think there's other books you could be.
Scott: really you don't need to read this.
Rym: But I feel like to people who have read this book versus people who have not Run planescape games very differently.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: If you're gonna run a planescape game, you probably should read this book.
Scott: Yeah, or if you're into planescape, you should probably read this book.
Scott: if you've seen other planescape stuff and haven't read this book Maybe you should.
Scott: this is probably like the core planescape deal.
Scott: maybe if you're gonna play a planescape video game like planescape torment and you actually want to play it properly and not just Sort of skim through it.
Scott: This will give you a lot more context make the game a better experience for you.
Rym: Of course, the other thing you could do is just read all right or vice versa.
Rym: I have it over there.
Rym: You can just read the planescape book.
Rym: that just explains everything about the setting.
Scott: if you're a super RPG nerd I feel like that's the necessity to read, you know, the core.
Rym: it ain't bad reading.
Rym: It's interesting reading that book.
Rym: It's not long.
Scott: I feel like that's the necessity if you're you know, a super nerd like dude.
Rym: It's like half as thick as the Forgotten Realms book probably Probably more interesting to yeah.
Rym: Yeah Forgotten Realms is Not actually that interesting It's just fantasy world.
Rym: Yeah elves dwarves Whatever like Forgotten Realms is on the same level of fantasy world is like the Wheel of Time war two planescapes credit.
Scott: It's a fantasy world.
Scott: Yeah, it's the multiverse is a cliche, but there's no other multiverse that's messed up like this one.
Rym: Yeah Right and the planescape setting does a really good job of making all the pieces like make sense in context of each other In a way that other settings like this tend not to.
Rym: the only problem with the planescape setting Is that no edition of Dungeons & Dragons is good at telling that kind of story?
Rym: You know a story where belief makes power like will to power is a real thing.
Rym: Like I feel like you would need a completely novel like Mechanical engine to roleplay a good planescape game.
Rym: Hmm.
Rym: All right, so I think we're done here.
Scott: You want to talk about the next book?
Scott: What are you gonna pick?
Rym: It's your pick.
Scott: Oh, so I had a few books that were potential selections, right a little list going on.
Rym: I'm ready to type this into Amazon in case I've never heard of it.
Scott: You heard of it.
Scott: Okay You know, they were you know, heaven and home going back and forth had justifications for all of them, right?
Scott: You know my justifications like book on the shelf that I already own and haven't read something that's an Odyssey a Sci-fi book about a post-apocalypse something.
Scott: Oh, you know the kind of things that we would choose as a book club book.
Rym: Right what I'm thinking about for my next one.
Scott: Hmm a movement role book Comics though, usually you can read it in like five minutes.
Rym: other books.
Scott: They're also expensive anyway, so You know.
Scott: suddenly though.
Scott: I think it was was it Sunday.
Scott: It wasn't Sunday.
Scott: I woke up in a reading Twitter early in the morning and I see some tweets and one of the tweets is like hey Scott You know one of those books you're considering for the book club.
Scott: that was sort of like pretty high up on the list.
Scott: Yeah, there's like an exhibit about it at the Met and it's closing today.
Scott: It is the last day to go see this exhibit.
Scott: So I went over to the Met.
Scott: I was like, well, I guess it's fucking raining might as well just go over there.
Scott: It cost me zero dollars to go in there.
Scott: I actually paid one dollar for two people Went in there I checked out there the fashion thing that's going on and some other stuff and I went to the exhibit about this book.
Scott: and Yeah, so I knew as soon as I saw that tweet, I'm like, well, I guess that's the fucking book, isn't it?
Scott: And then the exhibit only even more Reaffirmed my decision.
Scott: so Rym, you know most of our book club selections.
Scott: I think we've done maybe one or two non-fictions, but they're almost all novels.
Scott: Yeah, so I figure we're reading all these novels.
Rym: Wait, if you're gonna pick non-fiction, I have avoided non-fiction only because I didn't want to hear you bitch about it.
Scott: If we're doing all these novels Shouldn't we do?
Scott: The first novel that was ever written by any human being ever Get a mesh.
Scott: No, that is not enough.
Scott: Okay, that is like an epic poem or some shit.
Rym: All right, don't say Canterbury Tales.
Scott: That is not.
Scott: the Fred is waiting.
Rym: Oh, it's making sure because I do not like the Canterbury Tales I do not ever want to read them again.
Scott: The first novel that was ever written by any human being ever is the tale of Genji by Murasaki Shikibu, I read a translation of that in High school so I have done extensive research on the many translations.
Rym: sadly There is no amazing love lets you attack six times.
Scott: There is no amazing new translation written by some genius woman for us to read.
Rym: god damn it.
Rym: No, Emily Wilson.
Scott: There is no Emily Wilson equivalent tale of Genji for us to read.
Scott: Otherwise, that would have been the obvious choice.
Scott: So apparently the Looking around and apparently the best translation according to many sources on internet is the royale Tyler Translation which you will find in the penguin classics deluxe edition.
Scott: Don't get the not deluxe edition That's abridged or some bullshit.
Scott: Okay, you got to get penguin classics deluxe edition And that will give you the right translation with no abridged ness.
Rym: All right, I'm into it.
Scott: And also so the thing of the exhibit that I got talked about right is that This is the first novel ever.
Scott: and what the exhibit was about it was you actually get the book from the exhibit.
Scott: I just saw it on Amazon.
Scott: It's called the Illustrated tale of Genji because the exhibit was all sorts of ancient works of art, you know Well, not ancient but centuries old works of art, right?
Scott: About the book right like Scrolls wall Scrolls folding screens all sorts of crazy stuff like that.
Scott: Is that first of all first novel ever.
Scott: there are people who are insane about this book right like crazed fans The same kind of crazed fans we see going over like TV shows today or whatever sounds right bands, right?
Scott: I saw this exhibit a loads of fan art Not just of the character in the book Genji and scenes from the book But also the art it be the author of the book right Murasaki Shikibu.
Scott: There was tons of art of people like imagining her like drawing pictures of her writing the book, huh?
Scott: Alright, she had crazed fans like stalker fans Like, you know like the Beatles do it whatever or kpop boy groups do.
Scott: there were not.
Scott: there were several Scrolls depicting imaginary poetry battles Between Shikibu and other great poets who did not live at the same time that she did.
Rym: this just proves once again that humans fundamentally have not changed.
Scott: So this is a human being who was such a fan of this author that they Drew and wrote a poetry battle that is that it was made up by them But is imagined to be a battle of poetry battle between this person and another person.
Scott: So it'd be like if I animated a fight between Mike Tyson and Muhammad Ali.
Scott: right.
Scott: Then I could draw Right, and I I couldn't box but I instead I boxing Jimmy Smith, right?
Scott: It's like who would win in a fight.
Scott: Superman was whatever.
Scott: right go ahead and right.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: this is some crazy shit that's going on and this is the first novel ever Which means this has literally been going on as long as books have existed.
Scott: So it's good, but I just have to see in that shit.
Scott: How could we not read this book?
Scott: That is you know, probably what I imagine when I read this book I'm gonna see like oh my god, all these things have been referencing this for my whole life and I didn't notice.
Scott: Yeah, and that's I figured that reason alone was enough to bring it high on the list.
Rym: before even knowing there was an exhibit over In high school, I didn't read the whole thing, but I read several long excerpts from it as part of a class.
Scott: Oh, yeah, get ready adults cuz this motherfucker is 1224 pages.
Rym: so we'll do this on the next Thursday.
Rym: Get ready, we'll probably finish it faster than we did.
Rym: pages of pain Cuz.
Rym: we didn't actually read pages of pain until like right before we did the page.
Scott: Yeah, but actually I'm reading in other books.
Scott: I won't start this until I finish the other book.
Scott: Okay, you got some time But you gotta you have a lot of time for this one and you're gonna need it for twelve hundred and twenty six unabridged Translated pages.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: Heat nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Rym: It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this GeekNights book club episode are Craig Oliver Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol just like a dude guy.
Rym: kashar topshin linky G Jennifer Hitchcock Chris midkiff my state calm.
Rym: Jay bench scoot alone Lee Roberto Kingsley Shawn Yeager Nicholas Brando, mr Strong stretch and four to one creations.
Rym: and there may be other secret names You do not even know sure about horrible.
Rym: Rory Rochelle Montano - super boy sailor Vista Clinton Walton written from New Zealand Ryan parent or open letter Finn dread Lily Tenebra Sean Klein Chris Reimer Thomas Hahn and I'll leave you with something somewhat less painful today.
Scott: By now I don't believe that anybody feels the way I do Back beat I'm sure I don't believe anybody.
Scott: And all the roads we have to walk The light.
Rym: .
Scott: There are many things that I would like to say to you but I don't know how.
Rym:   Because maybe you're gonna be the one that saves me   And after all, you're my one .