Rym: It's Wednesday, August 7th, 2019.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: Una se yatsura, the manga.
Scott: Isn't it urasa iyatsa?
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: I don't know why you're finding it so hard to get Yuzu pissed.
Scott: No, I found it.
Scott: You finally found something?
Scott: I came in an enormous fucking jar.
Scott: Holy shit.
Rym: You'll use it.
Rym: It's good.
Rym: It also keeps for like, ever.
Scott: Well, because we were at the, uh, yeah, I don't think it'll go bad.
Scott: We were at the night market.
Scott: The night market where Rym had never been, but I've been several times.
Scott: But the first time this year.
Scott: And, you know, I wanted to get a beverage and I don't drink anything carbonated or anything poison or any, you know.
Rym: I don't drink a lot of- Scott Beasley won't drink anything but water and certain kinds of juice.
Scott: It has to be actual fruit that was squeezed.
Rym: Not like- And certain kinds of milk.
Scott: Not some Kool-Aid corn syrup shit.
Rym: Yeah, you'll drink certain kinds of milk and certain kinds of juice.
Rym: And water.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Rym: But not carbonated water.
Rym: No.
Scott: So, one of the booths has some lemonade and it had three flavors.
Scott: They have blueberry lemonade.
Scott: It has strawberry lemonade.
Scott: And they had yuzu lemonade.
Rym: Now, it's funny when Emily and I showed up, because we biked there.
Scott: Yuzu, if you don't know, is basically just like Asian super lemon.
Rym: It's, uh, delicious.
Rym: I love me some yuzu.
Scott: Yeah, it's just like a super lemon.
Scott: I guess it's close to a citron, but it's not a citron, right?
Scott: It's like a different lemon thing, right?
Rym: What's the second one?
Rym: The ergot?
Rym: Ergot?
Rym: Whatever it's called.
Scott: Oh, the etrog.
Scott: The lulove and the etrog.
Scott: The etrog is just a citron.
Scott: And most people just use a lemon.
Scott: But anyway.
Scott: So, right.
Scott: So, I had this yuzu lemonade.
Scott: I had the yuzu lemonade.
Rym: It was funny because when we went in, the first thing we noticed was, "Oh, yuzu lemonade.
Rym: We should come back and get
Rym: that.".
Rym: When I ran into you, you were like, "I'm gonna go get me some yuzu
Rym: lemonade.".
Scott: That's right.
Scott: So, the yuzu lemonade, all they really did is a cup of ice, right?
Scott: And they put some yuzu mush in the bottom.
Scott: And I think they put an actual half a lemon slice in there also.
Scott: And then they filled the cup that already was mostly full of ice with some goop at the bottom with, I guess, lemonade or watered down lemonade or really cold water or something like that.
Scott: And then they made me stir it up a whole bunch myself.
Scott: And basically what resulted is a lemonade that is just...
Rym: Too good for this earth?
Scott: It's really good because it's not...
Rym: Well, it has a very citrus flavor and it's sweet, but it doesn't just taste like sugar water.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It doesn't taste like sugar water.
Scott: A lot of lemonades these days are just like soda with a slightly lemon flavor, right?
Scott: But this is like, it's sour, but it doesn't make your mouth squeeze if you were actually to buy lemon, right?
Scott: So it's like, you know, it's very refreshing and citrusy.
Rym: I mean, yuzu is good just in general.
Scott: It's almost like when you eat a hot food and it tastes hot, but there is no... It doesn't reach the point of hurting you.
Rym: Oh, speaking of which, Takamen is a new menu.
Rym: They got a cold Szechuan noodle dish.
Rym: It is the exact perfect amount of Szechuan spice.
Scott: Anyway, so anyway, it was way good.
Scott: So I said, man, I could just like make this.
Scott: Why am I paying $4 for one glass?
Rym: Yup, you can get a tub of yuzu paste.
Scott: And while I was like, well, I'll just buy some yuzus and apparently that's heart easier said than done.
Scott: So everyone I know was like, yo, just get the yuzu paste that they use.
Scott: And I'm like, oh, that is what they used.
Scott: I guess they didn't use yuzus.
Scott: So I guess I should get that.
Scott: So I tried to go shopping for it.
Scott: So I go to the South American river and South American rivers got it for like $16.
Scott: And also I started out being confused because a lot of the jars selling it didn't say yuzu paste.
Scott: They said citron, which I guess is the, you know, they're just mislabeling it.
Scott: They don't have a difference in the naming and, you know, in Korea or Japan or wherever they make it.
Rym: It's not good enough for a second.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: It's yuzus in there, even if it says citron on the jar.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I go to the Sunrise Mart, which is a Japanese market near my work.
Scott: And I go there and they didn't have any.
Scott: And I looked around and they found tree stumps.
Scott: They were selling tree stumps for like $2.90.
Scott: And I'm like, no, I'm not paying $3 for a package of tree stumps.
Rym: Tree stumps cost maybe a cent to make.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, what do tree stumps cost in Japan?
Scott: 50 cent?
Scott: 100 yen or something?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Anyway, so then I go to a Chinese market.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because I'm in Chinatown area.
Scott: And the Chinese market, they also didn't have any.
Scott: I was like, what the fuck?
Scott: No one has any.
Scott: So today I took the train to go to the H Mart, which is like a bigger, more real.
Rym: You were very dedicated to this.
Scott: Well, you know, because someone, one of my friends sent me a link.
Scott: They found a place online cheaper than South American River, but it was still like, I ended up with shipping being like $12 for a jar.
Rym: But that jar will make like 40 melanades.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But you know, the lemonade, hopefully it's still a better deal than the $4 per lemonade at the market.
Scott: But I still don't want to pay $12 for a jar of anything.
Scott: So I went to the H Mart and they had several brands to choose from and they were $8.
Scott: And I was like, yes.
Rym: Your cup overflowing.
Scott: I'm good.
Scott: Yuzu pays for like, ever.
Scott: Because they didn't have, I was looking for the smallest one they had.
Scott: because I've been all about, you know, I used to think back in the day for actually many, many years, get the best unit price on everything you buy.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, well, this is a dollar an ounce and that's 50 cents an ounce.
Scott: Get the bigger one, pay less per ounce.
Scott: You're just saving money that way.
Rym: But now I live in New York, right?
Rym: I don't have space for anything.
Scott: But I learned that, A, I don't have a lot of space.
Rym: And two, stuff goes bad.
Scott: Stuff goes bad.
Scott: So really what happens is unless you use all of it before it expires or goes back, truly expires, not just date passes, right?
Scott: You're losing money.
Scott: If I spend 50 cents an ounce, right, for 20 ounces and I only use half of it.
Rym: All right.
Rym: What you're saying is a very old person conversation.
Rym: That's all I'm saying here.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the other one was 75 cents an ounce.
Scott: But I buy twice, but the total price that I pay is less and I use all of it.
Scott: I'm still paying total less money.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I've been buying smaller things lately.
Scott: So I tried to buy the smallest Yuzu paste.
Scott: They didn't have a small one.
Scott: The one I got is like, it's larger than any jar of jelly that you will see.
Scott: It's larger.
Scott: It was in the honey section.
Scott: It was larger than any honey.
Rym: You'll use it up.
Rym: Just mix it with water.
Rym: Like whenever you feel like it.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, I figure I can, you know, considering that the lemonade that I would buy, which is simply brand lemonade, not promoting them, which is real good, is like three to four dollars for a half gallon.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And this is eight dollars.
Scott: So I guess a gallon's worth of lemonade.
Scott: It's like gallon lemonade.
Rym: Now you could buy the simply and just mix Yuzu into it.
Scott: I could do that, too.
Rym: That might be too powerful, though.
Scott: I'll try it.
Scott: But yeah, per gallon, if I just do water, the eight dollars for the jar is like a tremendous value.
Scott: Right.
Rym: So in some actual animation news, Aggretsuko, which was...
Scott: I still got to watch season two.
Scott: Season two is pretty good.
Scott: I imagine.
Rym: However, I'm not going to spoil anything, but I think our main character made a terrible mistake.
Scott: I'm sure that is what would happen.
Rym: And chose a life that will not be as good.
Scott: Well, is that why your news is happening?
Rym: So my news is Aggretsuko is getting a third season, which is interesting because apparently the director has already said that, quote, he squeezed everything.
Rym: He squeezed out everything he could into the first two seasons to the point that he insisted there's nothing left to say.
Rym: So basically, Netflix is making is getting a third season of Aggretsuko made, even though no one on the production team is really ready to make a third season.
Rym: So they're just going to phone it in?
Rym: Well, no.
Rym: I mean, he said, we look forward to working on it.
Rym: They're excited.
Rym: They're eager.
Rym: I mean, you got to say that.
Rym: But what's extra interesting is that we've seen some recent data showing that Netflix really only benefits from two seasons of anything.
Rym: Like one season of something will drive subscriptions.
Rym: Two seasons shows commitment and also drive subscriptions.
Rym: More seasons of shows have no effect.
Rym: Like might as well not even bother.
Rym: So the fact that...
Scott: Well, does it keep people who like if...
Rym: No, the evidence, the stuff I read said that two seasons is all you need from any intellectual property.
Scott: Season one got someone to subscribe to watch that show.
Rym: Season two kept him.
Scott: Season two kept him.
Scott: And then after season two, if you don't make a season three, isn't that person going to unsub unless you have something else to watch?
Rym: No, apparently like third seasons don't seem to have any statistical impact on subscribers, but the second season has a big impact.
Rym: So there's a bunch of people talking about this.
Scott: I'm probably going to unsub from Netflix soon because I'm not watching anything.
Rym: I'm watching a lot of Netflix.
Rym: And actually, you might not want to unsub because Megumi Hajibara has just joined the cast of Carol and Tuesday.
Scott: Oh, right.
Scott: That was the show I wanted to watch.
Rym: Yeah, the Watson Abe show.
Scott: I don't care about her being on the show, but... Netflix... I was waiting for that show to appear on Netflix.
Rym: And Netflix is the international distributor.
Rym: The show drops on Netflix for us on August 30th.
Scott: That's real soon.
Scott: I'll watch it after PAX.
Rym: After PAX.
Rym: Maybe I'll watch one episode on the plane to PAX.
Scott: That is one thing.
Scott: I don't really care which streaming place gets a show, but if Crunchyroll gets it, you're getting that simulcast biz most of the time.
Scott: And Netflix waits till the whole thing's over and takes their sweet ass time.
Rym: Carol and Tuesday is a show we mentioned in Judging Anime.
Rym: We are like, this show has all the harbingers of being great.
Rym: It's a Watson Abe show.
Rym: It's got good character design.
Rym: The plot is very much up our alley.
Rym: And it's very interesting that Mugumi Hajibara is joining.
Rym: And in the 16th episode, she will appear as a singer who has been knocked out of singing as a career due to the AIs.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So she's playing a singer.
Rym: That's the kind of role she has always done.
Rym: This will be fun.
Rym: So maybe you're going to keep your Netflix a little longer.
Scott: Maybe I will keep my Netflix.
Scott: And related news is that Disney, they announced that for like 12 or 13 bucks, which is cheaper than Netflix, right, you're going to get Disney and Hulu and something else.
Scott: Disney owns Hulu.
Rym: Because I would never watch ESPN and I would never watch Hulu.
Scott: Well, it depends what's on there.
Scott: But the point is, is that this is a typical loss leader to try to take the market situation, right?
Scott: It's like a lot of people who want this anyway so they can watch Marvel stuff and Disney stuff.
Scott: Because Disney owns everything these days.
Scott: So people want it anyway.
Scott: They'll have a lower price than Netflix.
Scott: People will cancel Netflix, get this.
Scott: I probably will at some point, right?
Scott: And then as soon as they get tons and tons of subscribers, then they'll jack the price up.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: So enjoy it while it's cheap.
Rym: Yup, I will enjoy it because as you may have seen, Emily and I have been doing a show where we are going through the entire Disney theatrical animated canon.
Scott: You think they're going to have that on the service?
Rym: I mean, I think they're going to have every Disney movie on it.
Rym: Pretty sure that's the direction they're going to go.
Rym: And if they don't, I mean, I already have means to acquire every Disney animated movie if I so need, as I may have done for Snow White.
Scott: Yar.
Rym: Yar.
Rym: Yar indeed.
Rym: So you had some animation news.
Scott: Oh, I mean, this isn't a very big news, but I guess Rym's News was also a season three.
Scott: So my news is a season two.
Scott: Bananya is getting season two.
Rym: We've talked about Bananya.
Scott: So if you don't know, Bananya is just one of those like cute nothing shows.
Rym: Pusheen adjacent.
Scott: And basically it's just a really short episodes of this banana with a cat in it.
Scott: And there's a few different bananas with cats in them living in a house.
Rym: You could say there is a bunch of bananas with cats in them.
Scott: It's closer to Mamishiba, the bean dogs.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: This is banana cats.
Scott: It's a food plus animal situation.
Scott: So there was a season of it.
Scott: And that season, the English dub, the narrator, who's pretty much the only voice in the show, the part was played by our friend Mike Tool.
Scott: And he did a great job.
Scott: And there's basically since that one season of Bananya, Bananya has stayed alive via merch.
Scott: There's just lots of Bananya merch.
Scott: The Crunchyroll booth at various conventions has set up a Bananya like swimming pool where they fill it with Bananya plushies.
Rym: Every time there's a con, I see certain people tweeting about that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: To see that there's actually more Bananya coming is like, wow, really?
Scott: And judging by the poster, they're making a lot more Bananya to make merch of.
Scott: And they just need to make the show, I guess, for whatever reason.
Scott: So speaking of multiple seasons, She-Ra season- Is that all the news we got?
Scott: Is new seasons of everything.
Rym: So She-Ra season three drops.
Scott: What else has gotten a new season?
Rym: And what I will say about that is one, She-Ra is a fantastic kid's show, but it is a kid's show.
Rym: Like you watch season one and it's enjoyable, but it is clearly a kid's show.
Rym: The animation is not great, even though the character designs are.
Rym: The voice acting is fantastic.
Rym: But as of season three, the show has actually really stepped up its game.
Rym: The plot's gotten a lot more complex.
Rym: The plot's gotten a lot more focused on precursor technology.
Scott: That's what happens in kid's shows, because think about it.
Scott: When did season one of this come out?
Scott: How many years ago?
Rym: Not a lot.
Rym: One year ago, two.
Scott: Not long.
Scott: Oh, okay, really?
Rym: This is not like Adventure Time, where the character grew at the age of its fans.
Scott: I'm just saying the fans are a year older, which in kids being one year older does make a big difference.
Scott: A six year old is different than a five year old by a lot, right?
Rym: But season three has introduced a lot of interesting romantic pairings between characters, a lot of characters switching sides, a surprising amount of nuance, and based on where it's gone, She-Ra's turning into a pretty good show.
Rym: So if you are not on the She-Ra train, there aren't that many episodes.
Rym: It's all just on Netflix.
Rym: You can just watch it.
Rym: And in season three, you will see some characters paired up in a romantic way that you never would have expected.
Rym: Also, the show's covering a lot of ground, like season three.
Scott: Y'all turn human.
Scott: Getting the bone on.
Rym: So I just want to point out that based on where She-Ra has gone, Skeletor is definitely canonically connected to this universe.
Scott: I mean, yes.
Rym: The one time Skeletor and Hordak worked together.
Rym: The one time.
Scott: I just want to see some, if you're going to get sexy action in the Masters of the Universe universe, I want to see some Modulock involved.
Rym: That's my guy.
Rym: That is the second best answer to that, because the best answer is, as always, Fisto.
Scott: Mossman.
Rym: Stinkor and Fisto together at last.
Scott: Now, if you don't know what Modulock is, Google it.
Scott: M-O-D-U-L-O-C-K-K?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Do you know, I have a Modulock that I played with when I was a kid that I had.
Rym: I had battle damage He-Man and battle damage Skeletor.
Scott: One time I was at Scott Johnson's house and I found in a closet somewhere an unopened Modulock and I was like, what the fuck is this doing here?
Scott: I'm just going to steal this and play with it.
Rym: Of course, now we learn from that guy in Millerton that those toys, if you play with them, will just shatter.
Scott: Well, Modulock was a very sturdy toy.
Scott: He's not going to shatter.
Scott: But Modulock mint in vox, Scott Johnson, hook me up.
Rym: I mean, Stinkor still stinks.
Scott: Oh, man.
Scott: Does that Stinkor smell?
Scott: Like, whenever I smell it on something else?
Rym: All I think is, wow, that Stinkor.
Scott: All I think of is that fuzzy green He-Man figure.
Rym: God, Stinkor was disgusting.
Rym: What a terrible idea.
Rym: But anyway, so things of the day.
Rym: One thing we can't say has more seasons is Adventure Time.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, there was the Adventure Time trying to continue with the next season in comic book form.
Rym: And they put the kibosh on that.
Scott: They kiboshed it before they even finished one season of it.
Scott: But they are publishing a trade of that, what they did.
Scott: And I'm waiting for it to show up.
Rym: But Adventure Time is still a very important cultural touchstone.
Rym: It's probably one of the more important animated television shows in history.
Rym: I think Time will definitely be on my side with that.
Rym: And the comedy is still like, they're going to milk this franchise for as much as it's worth.
Rym: Like, merch will continue to come out.
Rym: There's definitely a strategy of keeping it alive, even if they're not making more original content.
Scott: I mean, there's plenty of stuff like that, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, everything that we want.
Scott: Is there a G.I.
Scott: Joe TV show right now?
Rym: I don't think so.
Rym: Evangelion 4.444.4.4.
Rym: This will never end.
Rym: You cannot not merchandise.
Scott: I mean, IDW, right, publishes comic books every month of like, My Little Pony, Ghostbusters, Star Trek, G.I.
Scott: Joe, Transformers, right?
Scott: It's like, all those properties all have comic books every single month, right?
Rym: But I didn't notice until a little while ago what Cartoon Network has been doing.
Rym: And they're only up to season seven on this.
Rym: So they're gonna keep making these.
Rym: But every month, they've released a short YouTube video.
Rym: It's like two or three minutes.
Rym: And it's a song.
Rym: And it literally just summarizes in production release order every single episode of Adventure Time, season by season.
Rym: It was, one, remember way back when we talked about the end of Adventure Time and how you watched it again?
Rym: And how season one really gets right into the thick of it.
Rym: Like, way sooner than you might remember.
Scott: Right, people keep saying like, "Oh no, season one's
Scott: different.".
Scott: No, it's not.
Rym: Season one, it's like four episodes in.
Rym: It is Adventure Time all the way.
Rym: So, watching this really drives it home.
Rym: And these videos are great.
Rym: And you should just watch them all.
Rym: You're gonna have to wait a little bit because they're doing one per month.
Rym: They just did season seven, which is basically Hall of Egress, steaks, all that biz.
Rym: There are several more seasons that gotta make this for us.
Rym: There'll be several more months.
Rym: I'm gonna link to the playlist so you can remind yourself how utterly great Adventure Time is.
Rym: And there were episodes I forgot.
Scott: I watched all recently, so there aren't episodes I forgot.
Rym: So, what do you got?
Scott: So, usually I try to avoid doing K-pop things of the day because if you don't know, basically K-pop groups are coming.
Scott: You know, the big ones come back once a month or so, but you know, every month there'll be one or two big ones coming out.
Scott: But there are lots and lots of medium and small ones.
Scott: Like, every single week there's new K-pop shit, new music videos.
Scott: This is like how I don't use... Every week there are five major, not even counting the minor ones, major music shows on TV in Korea and all the K-pop groups perform on most of them.
Scott: So, imagine if, like, you put out a song, right?
Scott: You're a band and you put out a song and you have to go on five TV shows a week for X weeks promoting your song.
Rym: So, Scott, basically has to have a rule like I do where I can't make Techamoon my thing of the day every week.
Scott: Right, I could make K-pop my thing of the day every single episode and never run out of material.
Scott: Can that just be "Gig Nuts Fridays," just K-pop?
Scott: So, I had to limit it to special cases when some K-pop thing really stands out or is really out of the ordinary or has appeal to people who don't give a shit about K-pop.
Scott: That's usually the main criteria.
Rym: I clicked on Scott's link, I heard some drums, and my brain knew exactly what was going on with no other context.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: So, my favorite K-pops are actually the ones where things are sort of wacky and stupid and sort of... But still high production value.
Rym: It's still good, but it's weird.
Scott: There are groups like Waluwari, who did the Kuna Matata, and Crayon Pop.
Scott: We haven't heard from them in a long time.
Scott: Orange Caramel, remember they did the sushi with the Catalina.
Scott: Right, Norazo is very hot right now with their shower.
Scott: Have you seen that?
Scott: Did I show you that?
Rym: Yeah, you showed us that.
Scott: The shower, yeah.
Scott: So, groups like that who are just doing things that are really insane.
Scott: Like, a lot of people know Psy because he was just sort of silly and wacky.
Scott: It's like, no, no, these are... Way to the closer to wackiness than Psy is.
Scott: Psy is kind of normal compared to these groups.
Scott: Anyway, I didn't know about this group until like this week basically because I was watching all... I just went... One of the music shows, I just watched all the performances, not 100% of them.
Scott: I just went on YouTube and clicked on each one for a second, right?
Scott: To see who they were.
Scott: Like, who are these groups?
Scott: What are they about?
Scott: I don't know them.
Scott: And there's this group called Donkeys, which I don't know.
Scott: what the fuck is it supposed to be.
Scott: It's like a pun on the English word of donkeys, but it's like D-O-N-G-K-I-Z.
Scott: I don't fucking know what it means.
Scott: Anyway, it's this boy group.
Scott: I guess these are like high school, early college boys.
Scott: Who knows how old they are?
Scott: I don't fucking know.
Scott: And their new song is called Blockbuster.
Scott: It's like, all right, whatever.
Scott: And I watch their stage on the show.
Scott: They're on.
Scott: one of the music shows is Inky Gyo.
Scott: I watch their stage on Inky Gyo, and I see some ghosts floating around on the video screens.
Scott: And then I hear some very familiar music, and they got some very homage stage costumes.
Scott: And then there's a surprise towards the end of their performance that I didn't see coming at all.
Scott: So yeah, you can see that.
Scott: And then their music video, it's like, yeah, this isn't even, this isn't like some special parody stage or something like that.
Scott: This is the actual song.
Scott: that is like the title track on their new release.
Scott: It is their actual song.
Scott: Check it out.
Rym: I mean, I thought my cup runneth over with Bustin, and now I've got this.
Scott: Oh, send this to Neil.
Scott: See what he thinks.
Rym: In the meta moment, the GeekNights Book Club book is no longer the painful pages, but it is in fact the first novel, The Tale of Genji.
Scott: First novel ever.
Scott: Yeah, it's about this guy named Genji.
Rym: Might take us a while to get to this, not because-- It's a long book.
Scott: Today's well-read it.
Scott: I'm 60% done with this other book I'm reading once I finish, and that's a long book also.
Rym: I'm still reading the book about Kentucky Bluegrass versus Bermuda Grass.
Scott: Ooh, so once I'm done with that book, I'll start reading about Genji and see what their deal is.
Scott: And also, we're reading the Penguin Deluxe unabridged Longo version of Tale of Genji, so that might make it take a while longer.
Scott: But at least, you know, I've been sticking with the Read on Kindle app instead of playing games on phone strategy for quite a while.
Rym: It's a good strategy.
Scott: I think it is stuck now.
Scott: No more playing phone games.
Scott: So that means once I do Read Tale of Genji, I will keep-- probably read it at a steady clip.
Scott: It's just gonna take a while.
Rym: Yep, and otherwise, coming up at the end of the month, actually, the day that that anime we were talking about, Carolyn Tuesday, drops on Netflix, is the day we will do our first of two panels, at PAX West.
Rym: It's on Friday, 1230
Rym: p.m.,
Rym: then on Saturday, 11
Rym: a.m.,
Rym: and then we're just gonna be playing games and hanging out in Seattle.
Rym: It's gonna be awesome.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: PAX South is coming up.
Rym: I hope you bought your badges.
Rym: PAX Unplugged is coming up.
Rym: I hope you're ready for this.
Rym: And it's basically gonna be convention season all the way up until PAX East again, which ends our convention season.
Scott: At least there's a big gap between PAX South and PAX East.
Rym: That's our biggest gap before the summer.
Scott: But they say that PAX East is coming early, which actually just means that off-season will be super long between East and West next year.
Rym: Maybe we should go to, like, a con we normally wouldn't go to in that gap.
Rym: Do, like, anime next or something.
Rym: Haven't done an anime con in a long time.
Scott: Maybe we could pick a different one than that.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anime Boston is just too cold and I don't wanna go to Boston again.
Scott: Well said.
Rym: So, many of you who have been anime fans and manga fans for a long time may have had the original American release of the Urusayatsura manga.
Rym: It was these big, big books that the binding just fell apart.
Rym: Like, that's whatever, like, literally just disintegrated.
Scott: It was released in the United States.
Scott: So was the anime.
Scott: AnimeEgo put out all the DVDs, including the movies, except for one movie.
Scott: Except for one.
Scott: That was put out by someone else.
Rym: Beautiful Dreamer, which I have, like, eight copies of.
Scott: So, you may recognize that anime girl with, like, the yellow, black, leopard kind of bikini.
Rym: Leopard, tiger stripe.
Scott: Whatever it is.
Rym: It's not a leopard.
Rym: What do you even think a leopard looks like?
Scott: Cat stripe, whatever.
Scott: Tiger.
Scott: Clothing, whatever.
Rym: The point is- The girl in the tiger bikini with the tiny horns and the electricity and the lecherous boyfriend and the cast of idiots.
Scott: It's like, you've seen that chara- A lot of people have seen that character and recognize it as like, "Oh, yeah, anime bikini girl with the horn,
Scott: whatever.".
Scott: And they might know the character's name is Lum.
Rym: Kind of like how people knew, uh, saw Mettalu, but didn't really know anything about Leiji Matsumoto.
Rym: Right.
Scott: And if you recognize that character, maybe if you're higher level, you'll know that it's from a manga slash anime called Urusayatsura.
Scott: And if you know that, you'll know that it was the original manga, was made by Rubiko Takahashi, who made Ranma One-Head.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Inuyasha.
Rym: I still think this is her best work.
Scott: Is this her earliest?
Scott: This came before the other ones, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If I'm not mistaken, I could be wrong.
Scott: I think it came before Ranma, definitely before Inuyasha.
Rym: Oh, Inuyasha was way later.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: It might've come after Mermaid whatever.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: I always forget about that one.
Scott: It might've also come after, um...
Rym: I tried to read that, but it got kind of weird and boring.
Scott: What's the one that starts with M?
Rym: Mezani Goku?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: I think it comes after Mezani Goku.
Scott: I'm not sure.
Rym: Mezani Goku is very nostalgic for me because that is a manga.
Rym: I read the entirety of.
Rym: In bookstores.
Rym: In Walden books.
Scott: Without buying a single volume.
Rym: I never owned any of that manga.
Scott: So anyway, if you weren't able to read those old-ass additions that Viz put out in late 90s, early 2000s...
Rym: Yeah, it was her first serial.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: In Shonen Sunday.
Scott: If you didn't read Urase Asura then, you didn't pirate it or anything like that...
Rym: And you didn't get a hold of one of these disintegrating books, which are kind of hard to find.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They are now, somewhat recently, a few months ago, republishing it, Viz-Sig.
Rym: We talked about this news less than a month ago.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Viz-Signature.
Scott: They're putting out these mega volumes.
Scott: I got the first one here.
Scott: I ordered it.
Scott: I'm probably not going to buy any more because it's too big.
Scott: But I guess this one mega volume contains, I think, maybe two or three regular volumes combined into one book.
Scott: So I don't know how many of these there are going to be total.
Scott: How long is the manga?
Rym: Really long.
Scott: Really long.
Scott: That's why I'm not going to start...
Rym: I have not actually read all of it, though I do hope to someday.
Scott: That's why I think I'm not going to read all of it unless it's digital or something.
Rym: Yeah, there are thirty-four volumes from the original.
Scott: Thirty-four divided by maybe three, so ten to eleven-ish books that are this big.
Rym: So the thing is, I've read so much of the manga over the years that I don't actually know where this book you have leaves off.
Scott: This book leaves off when... With the bird girl?
Scott: Yes, a few chapters into the, like, Goblin Crow girl.
Rym: Okay, it pretty much lines up with the original book, then, I think.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But anyway...
Rym: Well, the original volume won.
Scott: So I hadn't actually read it before, even though I had seen, like, one episode of anime and a movie and a half, maybe.
Scott: Wow.
Rym: I thought you'd seen more of the show.
Scott: I have more of what I've seen.
Scott: When have I read them?
Rym: All I will say is that I have read this multiple times over the years.
Rym: This is one of my favorite manga.
Scott: So I read this full volume just now.
Rym: We are just talking about the manga.
Scott: Mm-hmm, that's right.
Rym: Because when you talk about the anime, you've got to talk about some more.
Rym: You've got to talk about Oshii.
Rym: Like, there's a lot of...
Scott: Right, Mamoru Oshii comes in the anime.
Scott: He has nothing to do with the manga.
Rym: Yeah, there's a lot of interesting stories and context around the manga, or, sorry, the anime and the movies.
Rym: We're just talking about the manga, the thing that started it all.
Scott: So obviously, the first most interesting thing is that when you think of Araseatsuru, you look at this book, it's like the cover just has Lum on it, right?
Scott: All merchandise, almost all of it has Lum on it, right?
Scott: Almost any time the thing is mentioned, it's all about this character Lum.
Rym: But the main character...
Scott: But the actual manga... Is this... She is not the main character.
Scott: She is a supporting character.
Scott: It's this...
Rym: I wouldn't say he's that shitty of a dude, because he's actually not really a bad person.
Rym: He's just a little dumb, pretty lecherous, and he is basically the most unlucky human being on Earth.
Scott: Right, that's the...
Rym: Ataru Muramoshi.
Scott: The real story is the dude Ataru, and the main plot is not... I mean, Lum is there.
Scott: That's a main plot, right?
Scott: But the main plot is just.
Scott: he is the unluckiest person alive, and everything bad happens to him.
Scott: And in fact, some of the early chapters don't even involve Lum.
Rym: No, it's just him being an unlucky piece of shit.
Scott: Right, and the character that no one... It's not in any merch, right?
Scott: The priest dude.
Scott: What's his name?
Rym: Oh, Sakurambo?
Rym: I forget.
Scott: They call him something in the manga.
Scott: I don't know if it's an accurate translation, what they call him, right?
Rym: Yeah, Sakurambo.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I don't know what they call him.
Scott: In the manga, I think they call him something different.
Rym: Well, Cherry?
Scott: Yeah, that's it, right?
Rym: Yeah, the manga translates a lot of the characters' names.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Scott: But yeah, this Cherry Priest guy, basically he comes around all the time and is like, "Ataru, this bad shit is going to happen to you
Scott: today.".
Scott: And he's like... It's like you sort of get the feeling that this old man is causing the bad shit, like cursing him.
Rym: But no, this old man is just... He's right.
Scott: Right, but yeah, the old man is like... On the one hand, it's like a don't shoot the messenger situation, but the old man is also a villain in that he is the messenger of all this bad, unlucky news.
Rym: Also, the old man is pretty lecherous and also kind of a piece of shit.
Scott: Yeah, no, he's not good.
Scott: Well, here's the important thing.
Scott: He sort of gains pleasure in torturing Ataru, telling him about all the bad things that are going to happen.
Scott: He's like...
Rym: Almost no one in this manga is a particularly good person.
Scott: The girl, what's her name?
Rym: Sakura?
Scott: No.
Rym: The priest girl?
Scott: Shinobu.
Rym: Shinobu's got problems, though.
Scott: All right, but she's mostly a good person.
Scott: Compared to the other people, she's a saint.
Rym: True.
Scott: Also, like Ataru's mom, maybe.
Rym: Oh, Ataru's mom is actually pretty neglectful of her son and is not that...
Scott: She's not... But a lot of the other characters... She's not as bad as his dad.
Scott: A lot of the other characters, though, are bad.
Scott: They're like, you know, actively evil or lecherous or violent.
Rym: Megane and all those idiots.
Rym: You know, the capering idiots that follow Lum around that are kind of Ataru's friends, but not really.
Scott: No, they're the three guys wearing blue from Mutana.
Scott: That's who they are.
Rym: No, they're way more prominent in later manga.
Scott: All right.
Rym: And they're like... I could talk a lot about their characters.
Rym: Megane's the ringleader, the one with the glasses.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: The one who's really into Nazi stuff.
Scott: Not in volume one, at least.
Rym: Yeah, that comes up a lot later.
Rym: I mean, he's the architect of the Third Reich Decadent Coffee Shop.
Rym: He's just like a hyper-Japanese high school fanboy.
Scott: Anyway...
Rym: So the plot of the manga is... This story is basically... This dude is super unlucky.
Rym: He's friends with a bunch of idiots.
Rym: He has a girlfriend, and they have an okay relationship.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's sort of like, you know, she is into him, right?
Scott: But she also gets really mad at him because he's so lecherous and will totally become infatuated with other ladies at the drop of a hat.
Scott: It's sort of like... But at this other time, it's weird because on the one hand... I just read the last chapter in this one.
Scott: There was some, like, you know, goblin... You know, there's a lot of supernatural stuff, right?
Scott: Lum's an alien, right?
Scott: And there's the unlucky curses and shit.
Scott: But he gets infatuated with, like, this goblin-like bird lady that he... He gets infatuated with... He kisses and wakes her up like Sleeping Beauty, right?
Scott: And he's all into her, abandoning his girlfriend.
Scott: But meanwhile, super hot Lum in chapter one, who's into him, and is like, "Oh, darling," you know, and wants him.
Scott: He's not interested.
Scott: He's, like, trying to get away from her.
Scott: And it's like, "Dude, if you're, like, just a lecherous dude, why don't you just get with Lum, who wants you, and just be done with
Scott: it?".
Scott: I don't understand that.
Scott: It's like...
Rym: That's kind of the plot of the entire manga.
Scott: Right, that is.
Scott: It's like, he's...
Rym: That's why the movies, like, the story arc of the movies is basically is like, "Yeah, Ataru, she's the one for you.
Rym: Just admit
Rym: it.".
Scott: Right, on the one hand, he's trying to always get away from Lum to get with Shinobu.
Scott: But he'll abandon Shinobu for other third or fourth ladies.
Rym: But before Lum is in the picture, he is trying to get away from Shinobu sometimes to get with other random girls in the school.
Rym: But really, he always comes back home to Shinobu.
Rym: Like, he's just a lecherous dude.
Scott: But he'll run away from Lum, no matter what, to get to Shinobu.
Scott: He's like, "No, Shinobu, Lum is just trying to...".
Scott: You know, like, Lum will come in and, like, forcibly kiss him or whatever.
Scott: So that, like, you know, and then, you know, when Shinobu can see, and then Shinobu will be like, "Ah, stop that.
Scott: You're cheating on me.
Scott: You're
Scott: bad.".
Scott: And he's like, "No, I was being forced into
Scott: it.".
Scott: And he was.
Rym: What I really love about this manga is that over time, because it's a long manga and a lot happens, but all of the main characters actually do really evolve and change.
Rym: Like, Lum becomes a lot more reasonable over time.
Rym: Like, Lum and Ataru's relationship slowly grows and becomes more nuanced and complex.
Rym: Lum and Shinobu kind of become friends and, like, they're resigned to the fate of their situation.
Rym: A lot of stuff happens.
Rym: Like, a lot.
Scott: Yeah, it's weird, because, like, he's just reading this first, I guess, several volumes.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Covers a lot of ground.
Scott: It's, like, each chapter is just a really episodic thing where, like, there's a specific thing that's happening.
Scott: that's, like, a conflict involving, you know, school or the town or... -It's always something... -...unlucky curses or a holiday... -The ludicrous.
Scott: ...or a new character comes in and the chapter is about the conflict with that new character.
Rym: Like, they accidentally call a space cab and then they have to pay the cab.
Scott: Right, or the transforming dude.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: You know, the dude, he doesn't talk.
Scott: He just shows up and transforms like a giant bear, beast, whatever.
Rym: That dude, his deal is that he is dumb as a brick.
Scott: He is not yet, right.
Rym: That is his character.
Scott: But, you know, it's, like, each chapter is, like, an episodic thing, but at the same time, it's still developing.
Scott: The overall character plot situation keeps going forward little by little, chapter by chapter, right?
Scott: It's like, "Oh, he managed to exercise
Scott: something.".
Scott: Or, you know...
Rym: Well, I guess...
Scott: "Lum was in space, oh, but now she's back, and now she's
Scott: back.".
Scott: And then, you know, all that kind of stuff.
Rym: The Rumiko Takahashi works that I liked the most were the ones that basically, she'd have, like, a good cast of characters.
Rym: Like, this manga, anything else you could say about it, this is a really good set of characters.
Rym: It's a good ensemble cast.
Rym: And you just take random ones, any given volume, throw them in a box, throw a weird situation, shake the box, -and just see what happens.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I love that kind of story.
Scott: Also, there's, you know, a surprising amount of, like, -world-building kind of stuff going on.
Scott: Yeah!
Scott: 'Cause, like, you know, an individual chapter will have something, -like, you just mentioned the space cab, right?
Scott: Yep.
Scott: But it's, like, what's the deal with what's going on in outer space?
Rym: Well, 'cause it's sort of a story of Earth gets introduced to the rest of the universe because of this.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah, so if you don't realize, so chapter one, just summary, the very beginning, right, the ogre aliens show up, -the several kinds of aliens.
Rym: They're basically Oni, because Oni are actually just from space.
Scott: Right, it seems like there's two sources of supernatural things.
Scott: There's space, outer space, aliens, right, which apparently are way more advanced than Earth, and they come to Earth, finally.
Scott: But there's also, basically, you know, Japanese folklore-type things, and, you know, Shinto spiritual-type things that are also real.
Scott: And that's where, like, Cherry the priest comes in, right?
Scott: So it's, like, both of those sources of supernatural, not real-world stuff enter the picture into most of the chapters, right?
Scott: But anyway, so the ogre aliens show up, and they're like, "Yeah, we're gonna destroy your Earth unless you beat us in a
Scott: challenge.".
Scott: Same old story, right?
Scott: And the challenge is, you know, someone has to play tag with Lum and-- -Touch your horns.
Scott: Right, touch your horns.
Scott: And Ataru gets chosen because he's the unluckiest dude.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: He wants nothing to do with this.
Scott: He doesn't want to have the fate of Earth on his shoulders.
Scott: But, you know, he's determined to win, and somehow he doesn't like Lum, even though everyone else is way into her, and he's, like, the only hot girl he's not into.
Rym: To be fair, Lum is a dangerous and annoying person in the early parts of the manga.
Scott: Right, the main joke is that she keeps electrically shocking him, and somehow he survives.
Scott: There's even, like, a little side note that talks about, like, how many times he's shocked, and how, like, he doesn't get hurt from that or something.
Scott: It's, like, it's very strange.
Rym: But it's just, it's a good balance of really funny, really weird, sometimes some, like, actually interesting sci-fi stuff, and often it's very heartwarming and charming.
Scott: So, it's, like, if you need, like, an everything manga, right, you can go for this.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Also, it's got one of my favorite tropes, like, the same thing I like in, like, Patlabor.
Rym: All the background side characters are just, like, capering and doing their ridiculous bullshit in the background all the time.
Rym: I love, like, random scene of all the, like, the cat, the idiots are all having lunch together, complaining about Ataru.
Rym: Like, those are some of my favorite bits.
Scott: Yeah, it's, like, you get your, you know, you get romance, both, you know, comedy romance and real romance, right?
Scott: You get comedy sort of like in, you get sort of like the wacky comedy, like, you get in, you know, City, Nichijou, right?
Scott: We talked about that, right?
Scott: You get your adventury stuff a little bit, right?
Rym: Does this volume include when he has to go meet, like, actually, like, have dinner with Lum's parents?
Scott: Uh, maybe?
Scott: I forget.
Rym: I forget what's in which volume.
Rym: I've read so much of this.
Scott: Yeah, you know, it's got adventury stuff, right?
Scott: It's got, you know, some amount of school type stuff a little bit, right?
Scott: It's got, you know, it's like, it's like literally everything, but it almost makes sense because it's focused on the characters and in human life, there's everything, right?
Scott: And so rather than, you know, a lot of, you know, manga anime that focus on, say, adventure only, it's like you're getting all the aspects of the life of the supernaturally unluckiest person to ever live.
Rym: And I cannot stress enough, it is just, it is really funny.
Rym: Like, I laugh out loud reading this comic.
Rym: I always have.
Rym: I have this weird urge to read it again even though I've read that first volume.
Rym: Here you go.
Rym: Many times.
Scott: I can free up some space in my apartment.
Scott: I'm not going to buy more volumes just because they're big.
Scott: Not because I don't want to read it.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon Patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Craig, Oliver, Alan, Joyce, Haddick, Nickel, JustLikeADude, Gaij, Artopishin, William, Eisen, Rose, Link, Eiji, Graham, Finch, Jennifer, Hinchcock, Chris, Midgiff, MyStait, Jaypant, Scootalonely, Sean, Yeager, Nicholas, Brando, Mr.
Rym: Strong, Strachan, 421 Creations, like Johan, Sebastian, Bach, Rock, Ominous, Mac, and Dire, Cyan, Manchester, Thunder, Servant, Shervin, Ron, Harl, Rory, Superboy, Clinton, Walton, Run for New Zealand, Brian, Para, Drew, Openliner, Finn, Dred, Lily, Tana, Barry, Sean, Klein, Chris, Rhymer, Thomas, Han, and now I leave you with some Bustin'.
Scott: Bray Parker Jr.
Rym: Here we go with Ghostbusters.
Scott: Feel good.
Rym: Feel good.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, yeah.