Rym: It's Monday June 10th 2019.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight breaking up all those Silicon Valley tech companies.
Rym: Let's do this so we both had a Bridge related injury over this past weekend.
Scott: Just blow up all the bridges.
Rym: Yeah Mine is way less exciting.
Rym: But also so cuz being injured is exciting.
Rym: Well in the sense that Mine I was not injured that badly.
Rym: However, it said a president that badly I was set for a precedent of something that I didn't really Worry about.
Rym: and now the next time I'm biking over the RFK or running over the RFK.
Rym: I'm gonna worry about it.
Scott: I'm always worried about the area with no fence cuz you could just fall right over into the East River.
Scott: And yeah, even if you survive that which you won't god damn you're in the fucking East River You don't want to survive.
Rym: So, uh, I looked into that.
Rym: No one has ever Fallen off of that.
Rym: good It the center of gravity.
Rym: or if you're on a bike, you're not going to fall off the RFK.
Rym: That is not the problem.
Rym: good.
Scott: But so I was running still really weird because I think it's the only bridge that like doesn't have a big fence on the side.
Rym: I like it that way.
Rym: Like.
Rym: that's why I really like like the dangerous bridge.
Scott: No, I like the beautiful view And I don't jump off easily.
Rym: I don't think it's that dangerous.
Scott: Well, clearly it isn't cuz no one's fallen.
Rym: I'm sure people have jumped people have jumped off of it But no one.
Rym: I could not find any record of someone Accidentally falling off of that bridge at any point.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So I'm running a half marathon and basically the first third gets me to Randall's Island through Manhattan.
Rym: The second third takes me.
Scott: use the use the little tiny.
Rym: Yep Use the tiny bridge tiny bridge.
Rym: the second third of this run takes me all the way around Randall's Island.
Rym: I do a complete loop including where like the governor's ball is The top part even and he's like I turn left over that bridge and go all the way around the full outside of it.
Rym: If you don't go to the bottom, yeah, I go all the way around it big circle.
Scott: So all the way back to the tiny bridge again nearly.
Rym: But instead of going all the way to the tiny bridge then I get on the RFK.
Scott: So you didn't go in a complete loop because you go the bottom.
Rym: I mean I could go a little further but then it would the total run to be more than 13 miles.
Rym: So and then the last third of it is I go over the RFK and back down in Queens.
Rym: So I'm running on the RFK and I'm in that last stretch where you're all you're like right next to the highway with a big cement wall.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Yep, so I'm just running and suddenly I a rock flies out of nowhere from the highway and hits me in the shoulder Really hard like to the point that I stumble like backward and stagger and almost fall over.
Rym: And it takes me a minute to figure out what the fuck just happened.
Rym: Yep I'm just like what what?
Rym: and I'd like I pull off my shirt.
Rym: I've got this giant bruise on my shoulder.
Rym: It's healed more now, but it hurt.
Scott: and then I yes a flying rocks.
Scott: Yeah, you may look owned.
Scott: Yeah, I look down It's no.
Scott: no you didn't get stoned cuz if it'd be dead.
Rym: there's a rock.
Scott: just got partial stone.
Rym: There's a big hunk of rock.
Rym: That's like three centimeters in diameter like this big honking rock.
Scott: That's not a big honking rock.
Scott: That's a rock.
Rym: It's a rock at speed though.
Rym: That rock hit me at speed enough to stagger I'm sure if I threw it at you.
Scott: So that's me throwing it at you with my weak ass arm.
Rym: Yeah, I do not want you to throw a rock of that size at me.
Scott: No, there's a reason people don't like it when they get rocks.
Rym: if it was made out of pumice.
Rym: I might allow it Get hit with that balsa wood baseball bat.
Rym: But what I was thinking now?
Rym: after you know after I recovered like fuck there and I started running again I realized When I'm biking over that bridge, I'm going like three times faster than I run.
Rym: I run at about 7 to 10 miles an hour when I'm doing one of these long runs and I bike 12 to 25 miles an hour.
Rym: if I'd been biking and I rock hit me.
Rym: I definitely would have wiped out probably.
Rym: So, I don't know how common it is that rocks get flung onto this path But now I'm gonna be thinking about it every time I'm over there.
Scott: That's how it is.
Scott: Yeah, it's like I think about a Tram-track every time there is one in the street.
Scott: Yup Yeah, so I was biking.
Scott: I woke up to.
Scott: my original plan was to go to the beach on the ferry and but since it's Too cold in the water just bike instead.
Scott: Yeah, there's a. there's a boardwalk called Jenkins boardwalk.
Scott: I don't know if it's any good as a boardwalk, but is that Point something in New Jersey.
Scott: I don't fuck.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: I don't even know if it's a good boardwalk.
Scott: I just found it on Google Maps and I said there's a boardwalk.
Scott: It has boardwalk shit as an arcade and it probably has like a hot dog.
Scott: So that's why I could theoretically bike to it eat the hot dog and come back.
Rym: So you're doing the typical bike thing of pick an arbitrary waypoint as an excuse just to bike out there, right?
Scott: But then I woke up too late so I can get in the ferry.
Scott: cuz you get in the ferry.
Scott: if you're not getting On the ferry date, you're not getting on the ferry.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: It's not worth it.
Scott: So I just said I'll take it easy.
Scott: I'll leave later.
Scott: I'll just go to the regular beach.
Scott: that doesn't require any boating over the Abadobado bridge.
Rym: Yeah The one.
Scott: Anyway, so, you know, I barely left the house.
Scott: I'm only like 10 15 minutes not even 15 minutes away from the house and going over the Pulaski bridge Which has a nice new like two lanes separated bikeway, right?
Scott: So there's someone biking in the right hand side and they're going mad slow and I'm feeling real good.
Scott: So I go in the I see that no one's coming the other direction.
Scott: I just like no one at all coming the other direction.
Scott: So I go in the.
Scott: you know, the raw the Left lane Passing lane right good, which is also the going the opposite direction.
Rym: I mean like most two-lane highways.
Scott: That's right That's fine, you know.
Scott: and I start passing the two the two slow people and you know, I'm just going and then suddenly Like I didn't even like know what happened.
Scott: It was like this rapid see like, you know, cuz like I didn't couldn't even tell what was going on.
Scott: It was like a rapid series of still frames like a fraction of a second and then I was on the ground and And I was like, basically there was some sort of flappy Cloth or like a sign or a banner of some.
Rym: it was definitely Probably there illegally.
Scott: I don't know it was.
Scott: it was tied to the railing between the bike The bike path and the road path, okay I think you may have been some sort of sign that drivers were supposed to see as they were driving past.
Scott: Yeah, but it was super old and tattered and had been destroyed over time and was going flappa flappa and but it was still attached with some amount of rope or something to the to the rail.
Scott: and You know, obviously if it had caught my attention, I would not have like just bike past it.
Scott: I would have you know, right but I guess the wind came at the exact evil moment.
Rym: It's probably been there for a long time Who knows probably bike past this thing forever.
Scott: the wind came at the exact moment and went flappa flappa And I don't know exactly what happened.
Scott: I only have the evidence of the Aftermath, which is that I was hit my right side of my body on the ground but my left Shifter was like torn when it was torn and completely broken inwards towards the inside of the bike.
Scott: But it was the left shifter.
Scott: so maybe what happened was caught that it grabbed it and then my Handlebar must have turned left But then I was.
Scott: that that doesn't make sense.
Scott: I don't know how it broke in the direction it broke and how I fell in the direction I fell.
Rym: Yeah, but whatever Only had a GoPro he gets one.
Scott: I didn't have to go for it wasn't on though I don't want a film biking over this bridge for we could have done a nice frame by frame of that And it would have been just a shot of like the front of.
Scott: you know, you wouldn't have seen enough with that angle.
Scott: You know the two cyclists who I passed were like, oh are you okay?
Scott: You know and I stood up almost immediately but my arm was all road rash or whatever near my elbow zone.
Rym: Yep I am thankful.
Rym: I have not had real road rash since I was in middle school I don't know, but I have multiple times scraped all the skin off both my knees like all of it.
Scott: Yeah, so I mean if my bike was still not broken like devastatingly broken I would have fixed my arm and then biked.
Scott: Yeah But I needed to go to now I need like doctor.
Scott: instead of going to the beach I had to go to the human doctor followed by.
Scott: So I googled for human You know urgent cares and there was one literally right on the queen side of the Pulaski like right fucking there.
Scott: It was open at four point something stars.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I know which one you're talking about.
Scott: It was like forest something.
Scott: Yeah, I went in there.
Scott: That was like the best doctor I ever been to in the United States in my life the private urgent cares in New York.
Scott: I mean it cost $75, but that's not their fault.
Scott: That's the.
Scott: my insurance is copay for them.
Scott: I just I walked in.
Scott: I'm like you take my insurance.
Scott: They're like, yes, I'm like, okay, I will sit here until you clean this wound.
Rym: So actually funnily enough I went to the doctor today.
Scott: I went to the bike doctor and the bike doctor was like, yeah, you're gonna have to leave this here.
Scott: Yeah I call you and they didn't call me yet.
Rym: I was gonna take my bike to the bike doctor today because I just never to place all the cassettes and everything.
Rym: I haven't done that yet, but it's raining and I don't want to deal with that in the rain.
Rym: Mm-hmm I gotta replace it though.
Rym: I can't use my upper gears.
Rym: I have stripped that cassette Mm-hmm.
Rym: But I also went to the regular doctor to do something.
Rym: that now that I'm old and I bring this up only because a lot Of you've been listening GeekNights for a long time.
Rym: We're pretty old at this point relative to most of you Like we're in our upper 30s.
Rym: so I went and got a Skin cancer screening where they take a picture of your whole body and then they keep track of hey did that mole move?
Rym: Did it get bigger?
Rym: Uh-huh the things that you can't notice on your own.
Rym: Uh-huh, and that my company's just doing it for free So I can just do it at work.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think I need.
Scott: that's something I need to do like on my own.
Rym: Yeah, well basically from what I've gathered you're supposed to get it maybe every four or five years just from your regular doctor Not even a dermatologist.
Scott: Oh, well, I mean, I just went to my regular doctor coincidentally like a couple weeks ago Yeah, and it say nothing about it.
Rym: So Yeah, there is a history of melanoma in my family.
Rym: Oh, so I have extra reason to do it like earlier than most people would.
Rym: but she looked and she was like, yeah There's nothing my biggest mole.
Rym: She was like, that's not a big mole That's all she.
Rym: I was like, this is my biggest mole.
Rym: She's like that's not a big mole.
Scott: I've had this big mole over here for like my whole life and it hasn't grown.
Scott: I think there's one on my back somewhere also hasn't grown.
Scott: Yeah, but the one time I had they're not big compared to the ones I've seen.
Rym: but the one time I had a bike issue like yours where something grabbed my bike and stopped it Causing me to have an accident was one time mountain biking.
Rym: I was coming around a corner on a hardtail.
Rym: So I did like a sort of a drift around the corner where I locked up my rear deal and spun it around and then Started going again.
Rym: and when I spun it around I bumped into a log and the log Had like some sticks sticking out of it and the sticks locked into my rear wheel.
Rym: So I spun around the corner bounced off the log tried to go forward and the bike said nope I'm staying here and I just flew right over the handlebars like instantly.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: It's like, you know, people are always worried about getting hit by a car and you probably should be because you will be dead.
Scott: Yeah, it's like every time I've hurt myself on my bike in my whole life child and adult is Because I just fell on my own damn self.
Scott: Yep Just falling down from some stupid shit.
Scott: and you know people talk about helmets like yeah, you hit by a car What's the helmet gonna do?
Scott: your whole body's mangled even if you avoid head injury and you know what you're right.
Scott: But you know what helmets real good when you're just falling down on your own damn self.
Scott: Yep I didn't.
Scott: I luckily didn't hit my head at all this time.
Scott: I just landed on the right side of my body.
Rym: The fall happens like especially if you clip in.
Rym: like sometimes clip messes up.
Scott: Well, it's.
Scott: I think it's if you if you get anyone who gets clips every single person falls a few times and then they're good.
Rym: Yeah, that's how you learn to do clip right?
Scott: Yeah, you should have a helmet.
Scott: helmets real good.
Scott: Yeah When you just fall because your own damn stupid self or because something reaches out and grabs you some inanimate object or a flying rock comes at you I'll be thinking about those rocks now.
Rym: So anyway, we got some new helmet when you run.
Rym: Yeah Face mask.
Rym: Yeah elbow pads.
Rym: I'm thinking so.
Rym: I'm rollerblading again and Previously all I use when I rollerblade is to like minimalist wrist guards and nothing else.
Rym: I'll wear a helmet because you know, I'm in my 30s, but I don't wear like elbow pads or any of that nonsense.
Rym: thinking about getting knee pads just because old man knee.
Rym: yeah old man knee and also Road rash when you're in your early 20s knee pads, even if you're not, you know gonna land on your knee or fall down They're just useful.
Scott: It's real nice.
Rym: You want to kneel on something if you got a kneel down.
Scott: Yeah, you don't want to kneel down in the street with your knee, even if you're not moving at all.
Scott: Yeah, it just hurts.
Scott: streets are not soft.
Rym: Yeah, but I feel like now that it's like oh I can kneel down and do something like time I shoot rather than 100% rely on my personal ability to catch myself with wrist guards and spin to a stop Without my knees touching the ground.
Rym: I think I should actually wear safety equipment Partly cuz.
Rym: bike rollerblading in New York is a terrifying prospect until you get to like the westside bike path or Central Park.
Rym: So there's a bunch of news.
Rym: the one we'll part talk about first is Apple Day happened.
Rym: There was a bunch of announcements.
Scott: So this is the WWDC Apple Day, which is the developer focused Apple announcements.
Scott: right things for nerds You know programming shit stuff like that.
Scott: Yep So the thing that they announced that we want to talk about the most yeah most of the stuff they talk about is like You know updates to the OS is right, you know.
Scott: Yeah I think new features new things that developers gonna want to include in their apps and that sort of thing.
Rym: But they announced and I was surprised they announced this a new Mac Pro.
Rym: Yeah, you may recall desktop tower Mac PC.
Scott: That is not a stupid trash can that can't be upgraded?
Rym: Yeah, so you may recall back in 2013 Apple released a Mac Pro.
Rym: That's just this black garbage can that was Underpowered and cost twice what it should have and was literally worthless.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So When this came out, I saw the announcement didn't even read the specs didn't even watch the announcement.
Rym: I just saw people on Twitter talking about it.
Rym: So I go to our forum and I say what I always say I can build whatever that is as a PC for half the cost.
Rym: Yeah, and you can and easily yeah, so I got some pushback in the forum people saying oh no It does a lot more you can't do it.
Rym: And for a second.
Rym: I thought what if I'm wrong?
Rym: I didn't look at the specs.
Rym: Maybe they actually built a powerful computer.
Rym: and They did another thing Apple has done in the past.
Rym: They made a Groundbreaking amazing monitor and then they made a kind of crappy computer to plug into it.
Rym: Mm-hmm That seems to be their go-to.
Scott: the monitor they made is amazing is maybe the best monitor That has ever existed in the history of Earth.
Rym: I mean back when like there weren't really for a lot of money, but what else are you gonna buy?
Scott: Yeah, like what else is?
Scott: that's it.
Rym: That's the only one in the CRT area You could get like really high-res CRT is but they had their own problems.
Rym: But Apple has multiple times made like the next big leap in like a real LCD or OLED or whatever monitors.
Scott: if you look at like the absolute best most expensive Dell monitor It like doesn't hold a candle to the Apple.
Scott: yeah, it's like.
Scott: well, I guess they're okay charge.
Scott: But here's the thing.
Scott: They made the best monitor ever and then they're like, okay You want to mount it to like your fancy arm like I have in my desk, right?
Rym: Oh doesn't just have a VESA mount on the back.
Scott: You have to buy a $200 VESA mount adapter.
Scott: All right, if you want to put it on a stand it has its own.
Scott: I guess you could get a VESA stand on your own.
Scott: but they Have a stand that hooks into its custom.
Scott: You know mount thing and that stand which is you know a fancy stand.
Scott: But it has all the same features of the stands that I threw out that were attached to my Dell monitors.
Scott: Yeah They are charging $1,000 for this stand and that is the joke of the century.
Scott: That is the most Apple thing ever.
Rym: So I'll ignore the monitor because there isn't anything to compare it to yet, but the actual Mac Pro.
Rym: Looking at we don't know the prices yet.
Rym: Well, we do know.
Rym: not really we don't know the full prices.
Scott: The cheapest possible one is gonna be like six thousand dollars or something.
Rym: The indication was that the baseline one will be six thousand.
Rym: That's like the default cost without the monitor.
Scott: Yeah, so monitor is also gonna be like six thousand.
Rym: as a result my Argument that I could build this as a PC twice as powerful half the cost Probably pretty accurate.
Rym: even better.
Rym: the guy who does like that the guy who does all the production stuff for where's the article?
Rym: I was gonna link to.
Rym: I found an article on the verge and it has this pro guy who is like, oh, yeah Why would I switch to this?
Rym: I could build something twice as powerful as a PC.
Rym: Like he said exactly what I said.
Scott: That's pretty much, you know Apple's thing is like yeah, they charge like this, you know High-margin premium thing, right?
Scott: It's like and that sort of works when it comes to some of their lower end products because even though they're charging Say a little bit more than the competition.
Scott: It's like, okay, I pay.
Scott: what for the Mac laptop, right?
Scott: I pay an extra $500 but look what I get.
Scott: Yeah, that hardware is great But when you look at them high as you go higher and higher end, right?
Scott: I guess they must be keeping their margin percentages the same.
Scott: I don't know what logic they use to do pricing But yeah, it's like it's like oh to upgrade the RAM from 32 gigs to 64 gigs will cost you $400.
Scott: for $400 I can buy like a 1080 dude for $400 I could buy how much total RAM in a PC like 128 one.
Rym: So I did some breakdowns because they haven't really saw the pricing yet.
Rym: But I looked at the baseline because everyone's talking about this.
Rym: looking at the high-end specs because if you get the maxed out one It's got a 28 core Xeon running in a pretty low clock speed by the way.
Rym: Hmm like they'd like.
Rym: more cores means slower clocks.
Rym: You can turbo it, but I don't want to get into that That's there's a lot going on there.
Rym: But the 28 core server thing.
Rym: That's not gonna be $6,000.
Rym: No.
Rym: And the bottom one the baseline one in this $6,000 PC is an 8 core Xeon That runs at a significantly slower clock speed than the 4 core that I got in my computer.
Rym: So it's 8 cores.
Rym: you could buy that exact chip.
Rym: Actually, you can buy that chip slightly faster than the one that's in the Mac for 1200 bucks.
Rym: Mm-hmm The RAM 32 gigs of ECC.
Scott: right Apple is always a crazy about always using ECC RAM.
Rym: expensive anymore $160 bucks 32 gigs one module.
Scott: number one place that Apple overcharges is the RAM zone.
Scott: Yeah, they always overcharge for RAM and storage and all that stuff.
Rym: Oh the words are the worst part and I don't even know what they're doing here.
Scott: But my point is is that yes Apple overcharges, but when it comes to the high-end like this They're the overcharge ends up being many many thousands of dollars extra.
Scott: It's not like Oh $500 extra But you get a nice Apple laptop with a really nice screen in it.
Scott: or oh you paid $50 more than the Android phone, but you got an iPhone.
Scott: It's like no if you want this, you know instead of the equivalent PC that has an Nvidia, you know board in it That's better.
Scott: You're going to have to pay $5,000 extra $6,000 extra right?
Scott: So even though maybe the margin percentages are might be the same because you know The really fast PC is still two or three thousand.
Scott: It's like you're paying the sum.
Scott: total premium dollars You are paying is absolutely insane and unreasonable and pointless.
Rym: How's it notice something?
Rym: the storage is SSDs and the baseline is 256 gigs, which is nothing nothing.
Rym: Uh, they say that it says quote up to 2.6 gigabit per second sequential read.
Rym: That sounds like SATA - that doesn't sound like PCIe or SATA 3.
Scott: Yeah, it's not Like.
Scott: why does it?
Scott: it's even says it's like two two terabyte for you know SSDs.
Scott: to make a four terabyte SSD shouldn't you be using like, you know, m2 drives like MVNO, whatever?
Rym: Well, m2.
Rym: so m2 is actually just the form factor.
Scott: m2 could be a SATA 3 Whatever the hell that thing is called.
Scott: I forgot since I built my PC.
Rym: basically You want your heart.
Rym: you want your fast hard drives to basically be PCI Express cards that happen to have hard drives on.
Rym: That's really what you want.
Rym: This does not look like that.
Scott: No And you think it's so crazy Pro in every other category.
Scott: wouldn't the storage also be crazy Pro?
Scott: shouldn't it be like two?
Scott: Like eight terabyte, you know.
Scott: and VMEs Something really.
Rym: I assume that they're going for the idea that no one's actually working from local files in an environment Where you'd use this that you're using the shared Thunderbolt, whatever, you know, that's the thing is like.
Scott: Apple loves External attached things but it's like no, this is the stupid.
Scott: This is the case.
Scott: This is the tower PC that you're allowing.
Scott: You're actually allowing people to open it.
Scott: They don't want shit on the desk.
Scott: Yeah, we don't want an external pile of hard drives.
Scott: We want to put like 10 hard drives in this box, but I don't think there's room in that box for any hard drives.
Rym: No, it's got a lot of Pro features, but until they release the actual Expansion they're letting you do is PCI slot.
Scott: This is really reminiscent of the Apple to GS.
Scott: So this so one of our people are making seem like they're letting you do expansion in any other areas.
Rym: They do have the.
Rym: the thing this thing is going for it Is that it has a lot of PCIe lanes and it has a lot of support for.
Rym: like custom Supercharged rendering chips are making special stuff.
Scott: So they made this special card you can get that will do transcoding for you.
Scott: So if you're editing video it you won't have to make proxy files.
Scott: You could like have two or three or some number of 8k files and play them in real time No problem without having to make proxies first.
Scott: because there's such a like a super fast dedicated Transcoder, I don't know.
Scott: I'm sure a similar product must exist for the PC that you can stick in and it well.
Scott: You could probably still get a PC fast enough.
Rym: So to give you so give her a reference point Obviously the I my pipeline is simpler than a Hollywood pipeline Yeah, but when I'm editing 4k video, I usually have two 4k sources at very high bit rates and I can play them simultaneously Even four of them together in a multi-camera view without using proxies.
Rym: Mm-hmm And I get that includes the 1080 and yeah one 1080 and that includes no special transcoding thing.
Rym: That includes no pre-rendered color correction.
Rym: No multiple ATI includes color correction and stabilization.
Rym: what is and all sorts of transforms.
Rym: what it does not include to be fair is Color grading or anything like that.
Rym: that stuff I would do in post or I would do Destructively later or I do it in the render pass at the end.
Rym: But I'm not saying my PC is the equivalent of this thing.
Scott: clearly not.
Scott: but but this thing Dollar as usual.
Scott: It's it's weird to say this is news.
Scott: It's just this business as usual right the dollar per performance ratio of the Apple computer is Absolutely ridiculous.
Scott: You're like getting almost no computing power per dollar Whereas with a PC you get a lot of computing power per dollar.
Scott: this unless you're just like don't give a shit about money There's no reason to buy.
Scott: or you just really really really need OS X and yet afford it.
Rym: Like if somehow you're on like an Apple centric pipeline, I don't know Numbers of people who would need this.
Rym: they're probably probably studios and pipelines where this hardware would be really nice to use in that pipeline.
Rym: But there's a lot of pipelines that rely on software that's really only written to work with Nvidia high-end cards.
Scott: Well, that's mostly when you're not talking about like.
Scott: most of their demos were like art related right rendering, you know And it's like for those things.
Scott: I guess it doesn't matter too much.
Rym: if you have Nvidia or ATI Yeah, but if you're doing like 3d right?
Scott: No, I think it's mostly the Nvidia.
Scott: situation is people are doing CUDA stuff Not just CUDA.
Rym: Nvidia has a higher end chips that are not the 1080 type stuff.
Scott: We right but the point is the CUDA people cannot go with the AMD at all.
Scott: It's like a deal breaker.
Rym: Yeah, right.
Scott: So if you're doing any CUDA based thing, it's like well not doing it.
Scott: on this.
Scott: you're going to buy an Nvidia So Apple can play.
Rym: they say that some of the companies like Let's see, blah blah blah.
Rym: Yeah, a bunch of the companies that have Nvidia only stuff have said they will rewrite those apps to work with AMD.
Scott: Many people are skeptical of that claim because how many customers are you doing this for?
Rym: I mean I remember a long time ago when a bunch of Game companies went way out of their way to make sure their games worked on both Windows and Macs because Macs finally had video cards and none of those games work anymore and no one supports Macs.
Scott: and go back and Watch the Steve Jobs.
Scott: John Carmack, you know doom 3 keynote everybody.
Scott: Oh, yeah, go back and watch it.
Rym: I remember that.
Rym: So, uh got some other news.
Scott: We do have another news.
Scott: So Basically what's happening here is Chrome is changing itself in such a way that ad block Extensions will no longer be able to add block to the extent that they previously ad blocked.
Scott: And thus if you use Chrome Even if you're using all the best ad block biz unless you're like a special business client who is paying for like a special Chrome for your company or some ridiculous.
Scott: I didn't even know that was a thing until recently That you know.
Scott: Let's remove a lot of the limits on the kinds of extensions you can make because if you're a company you presumably have like custom Chrome extensions that you know, whatever.
Scott: It's amazing everyone listening to this.
Scott: Yeah, your ad block is not gonna work too well in Chrome.
Scott: So switch to Firefox, which I've been using Firefox for a long time.
Scott: Yeah, I've been using Pretty much only use Chrome at work for work.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I'm Just I've been using Chrome for a long time and I haven't had this problem yet.
Rym: My ad block is still working effectively.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I have pie hole and stuff that also does ad block by other techniques.
Rym: Yeah But it's part of this news just shows that no browser will last forever and win the so-called browser war Because the people who run these browsers will always fuck it up somehow and just a rotation of who fucks it up.
Rym: So right now the landscape is shifted.
Rym: There was a while where Chrome was the super fast browser and everything else had problems.
Rym: now we're getting back into an era where Firefox is probably the browser that has the best interest of the actual user of the browser at heart as opposed to Google Which is conflicted because Google relies on ad revenue.
Rym: This will get into our main topic for the show.
Scott: Well, that's the reason, you know, why did Google make Chrome in the first place?
Scott: It's like because they can't you know, their business is the web.
Scott: They can't let someone else right be controlling Right.
Scott: Imagine if there was no Chrome and those only Firefox.
Scott: the entire business of Google would like be dependent on.
Scott: like things Mozilla does Mozilla would have them over a barrel.
Scott: Yeah, everyone's using Firefox, right?
Scott: So Google or Microsoft would have them over a barrel because they're controlling, you know the web.
Scott: So Google was doing the right thing to have control there.
Scott: Otherwise their business is just boned.
Rym: Yeah, they were doing the right thing.
Rym: There's got to be competition like multiple browsers.
Rym: No one has a monopoly on the most important app on your computer.
Rym: But at the same time all these companies need to make money and have various interests and various monetary streams that they have to protect and Google is gonna start protecting their stream more and more and they're gonna probably prevent us from blocking ads in the long run.
Rym: Hmm, so we gotta search Firefox.
Rym: Firefox seems to have gotten ahead of this in that Firefox has really been branding themselves more and more as the secure Private browser.
Scott: a lot of their stuff is like all their iOS apps are like privacy related apps and stuff.
Rym: Yep, cuz you don't want to trust any of those like weird browsers made by the crazy people.
Rym: No yeah, so I feel like in our foreseeable future Smart people will all be switching to Firefox and Firefox will have the most please in it.
Scott: Yeah, I only went to Chrome for a limited time.
Rym: Yep I haven't moved yet because like I said my head my Firefox since you know, it was Phoenix.
Rym: I remember using Phoenix and Firebird for a brief time.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: So keep an eye out if you start seeing ads in Chrome.
Rym: Ah That's your signal to go move to Firefox.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Also, the correct ad block extension is you micro block origin.
Scott: It's it's you know, it's not the word micro It's the little you know, it's all.
Rym: you lower lowercase you with or without the little thing lowercase mu.
Rym: Yeah Do not download random ad blocker because ad blockers can inspect your content.
Rym: You better trust that could be people who made that ad blocker.
Rym: You're in trouble.
Scott: You can also set a pie hole on your home network and you can even VPN into your home network to get behind your pie Hole when you're not home.
Rym: Yeah, the most important thing is however you do it you gotta block ads.
Rym: ads are a security threat and they're also a Violence against your brain shall we say?
Scott: block all ads everywhere always.
Scott: if I know exceptions No such thing as a good ad.
Scott: I got to support someone.
Scott: no Fuck you.
Scott: block all ads everywhere always.
Rym: if I could install an extension in my glasses that just blanked out any Advertisements I saw in the real world.
Rym: I would do it.
Scott: I would pay for that.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: so when I first got a PC and I started getting PC games.
Rym: I did not know Piracy was a thing people in school.
Rym: I didn't really me floppy.
Rym: this be like, oh you got a computer here.
Rym: Check out this racing game.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't really you know, it's like.
Scott: I didn't quite understand the concept.
Scott: Like it's like oh you do have software.
Scott: you can copy it and you give it to someone else.
Scott: It's like this is what software?
Scott: just the thing.
Scott: I didn't really even understand.
Scott: all the shareware and then like typing codes like using the star control chart to get the game.
Scott: And then that I finally understood.
Scott: Oh, I see what's going on here.
Scott: Someone made this game.
Scott: They want to charge me for it.
Scott: Yeah, I get it.
Rym: And but I learned pretty quick and then I got involved in the where scene because I Have no fucking money when I'm a little kid.
Scott: Yeah, it was no steam.
Rym: So I had a crack copy.
Scott: Was it even hard to go to the game store?
Rym: I had stunts 40 racing cracked by kill fit.
Rym: most of my games had Screens in the beginning that showed the cracking group that cracked the games that you could play it without needing the manual.
Scott: Oh, I just did other means.
Scott: Yeah, I I knew people like hey give me the doom wad file so I don't have to use the shareware one.
Rym: Yep, it's crazy Like the internet was so different back then.
Rym: that was an era when I would literally go to someone's BBS download an exe file Trust it run it and it didn't have any malware.
Scott: Well, but yeah, but also it's like what was there on your computer - yeah.
Scott: Oh, no, you got my school paper.
Rym: Yeah, most malware.
Scott: back then You got my stone but you stole my copy of chips.
Rym: challenge, oh you deleted my hard drive.
Rym: I guess I lost 500 megabytes of data and have to reinstall Windows 3 1 1.
Rym: So, uh There was copy protection on a lot of these games but one game in particular This game called dungeon master.
Rym: If you look at this video, you'll you'll know what game this is.
Rym: You've seen this game.
Rym: It was even ported to the NES And in fact how it was ported to the NES which is talked about in my thing of the day.
Rym: video is pretty crazy because It has raster images, which is not how the NES renders video.
Rym: So there's this crazy chip on.
Rym: it was hard to emulate but this video goes into detail on how?
Rym: Some of the most effective copy protection to prevent pirates from stealing games in the floppy era worked and usually it would work In such a way to where people who pirated the game and cracked it would think they had succeeded.
Rym: But after you played the game for a certain amount of time the game would just stop working.
Rym: All right.
Scott: For example in a dungeon II game like this Sometimes you'd guess like caught and amazed that what there was no escape from yeah, or like doors just stop working.
Rym: You can't open doors anymore.
Rym: Now the game's broken Yeah, and basically the company would wait for people to open queries and be like Hey the game crashed and I got this error and then the company could say yeah Cuz you fucking pirated our game you piece of shit.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: so You can watch the video.
Scott: I think is a lot of people pirated not even realizing piracy was a thing, right?
Rym: Yeah, but then they'd learn People.
Rym: but I'll link to the actual like detailed technical technical documentation do because this shit is fascinating.
Rym: What the way this copy protection worked is that the discs the floppy discs that they?
Rym: Manufactured.
Rym: some of the bits were fuzzy and they would return a one or a zero Randomly mm-hmm.
Rym: There was no way to copy that Mm-hmm, and the game would periodically check to see what's the value of this one bit?
Rym: And if it doesn't ever change then they know it's a pirated copy of the game Uh-huh.
Scott: What if you just get unlucky and the fuzziness stays static for a little bit?
Rym: It checks over time.
Rym: It was a slow burn.
Rym: Okay, and the video and the article go into a lot of detail.
Rym: It's uh, it's fascinating.
Rym: never had a false positive not that I could see.
Scott: Okay, so what do you got?
Scott: What do I have?
Scott: I forget you have all right like Urges Cup.
Scott: So this guy is some kind of historian or archaeologist or some kind of genius, dude.
Scott: And he's given his lecture and it's a real disappointing thing of the day because this is a clearly a long ass lecture And the video is only three minutes.
Scott: I don't know where to hell to get the rest of the lecture.
Scott: Please y'all find it and send it to me urgently.
Scott: Sorry for the disappointing thing of the day But what he talks about they used to be news.
Scott: lecture is like Urges Cup, which is some cup from Sparta or something.
Scott: But the cup has some sort of amazing property where like in the when you it's like it changes color.
Scott: It's like in the different light or heat condition.
Scott: It's like it's like holy shit And for a long time people basically didn't believe that like this was like all the ancient people didn't have technology for that.
Scott: You know, no, no way.
Scott: But no as it turns out they totally did and we lost that technology for like centuries Before we figured out how they did it and then we're able to do it ourselves.
Scott: It's pretty crazy.
Scott: So yeah, check this out and I'm I want to check out.
Scott: What's the guy's name?
Scott: Does it say his name there?
Rym: Ah Couldn't be.
Scott: no, isn't that his name right there?
Scott: and samobergia?
Rym: I guess it's his channel.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It's samobergia.
Rym: Yeah So this whatever he is samobergia this sociologist and the founder of Bismarck analysis a firm that analyzes institutions and something something Whatever.
Scott: this dude is like the most amazing like he could replace every history professor on earth.
Scott: It's like in three less than the three minutes.
Scott: He already captivated me with his lecture.
Scott: I just want to go and subscribe to his podcast and YouTube channel, which I already did subscribe to that.
Rym: So so in the meta moment the GeekNights book club book pages of pain and full pages by Troy Denny.
Scott: I have endured all the pain of the pages.
Rym: Yeah No, I was able to fully express the extent of this novel with simply four images from King of the Hill And we're gonna do a show on it next Thursday.
Rym: Stay tuned.
Rym: We're gonna talk about this book.
Rym: We're gonna assume you read it and I think it might be the best written Officially licensed Dungeons & Dragons novel.
Scott: I mean so they say throng is the best written officially licensed Star Wars novels.
Rym: I feel like this is the best one.
Scott: It doesn't mean it's a good No, it's the least smelly poop.
Rym: All I'm saying is that this one feels like it did something different compared to every other garbage D&D.
Scott: That is true.
Scott: The other ones are probably all just like yeah, we beat the evil was there.
Rym: I'm an elf and I'm doing elf stuff and plot happens and look there's Elminster and Kelvin Blackstaff Driss Dorden Meanwhile, this one's like this guy's on an adventure and then two minutes later.
Rym: It's like well I swapped a foot for a hand and I'm turning to goop and we're in trouble here.
Scott: He turned to goop game first.
Rym: Yeah, that came first.
Scott: that led to anyway.
Rym: then the amount of times limbs get swapped in this book is Several more than you would expect.
Rym: Yeah, like you think oh that was a thing and then it happens again And you think oh, I guess that happened twice that and then it keeps happening.
Rym: You're just like what?
Rym: So, yeah, we're gonna talk about that book.
Rym: Otherwise, we have no convention still PAX West.
Scott: It's on Labor Day weekend in Seattle.
Scott: tickets already went on sale.
Scott: I booked flights to there got hotels.
Scott: There are some tickets left on sale.
Rym: Well, there are tickets for every day, but Saturday on sale.
Scott: You checked us now.
Rym: No, I checked a while ago.
Rym: Okay, maybe there's fewer days now.
Scott: It's West up.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Oh Friday, oh, yeah.
Rym: No, we're good.
Rym: Sunday is almost so loud.
Scott: Okay, but Friday Friday or Monday?
Scott: No problem.
Scott: Friday is actually a really good deal.
Scott: unlike Monday It's a full day of packs.
Scott: Monday is a shortened day of packs and you get the keynote you get to you and a note on Friday and Q&A Monday.
Scott: you also get an omega-thon finale even though packs is shorter.
Rym: so you don't get like a concert or anything.
Scott: No, but I don't think you get a concert on Friday either.
Rym: Yeah, also If you were trying to submit panels to packs they are online now.
Rym: the panel submission site was actually down for a while.
Scott: It is up again.
Rym: It was just like giving an error.
Rym: It was weird, but they fixed it Whatever the problem was.
Rym: so go out submit your panels to packs And I think we should get right into it.
Rym: So this problem is only getting worse and we got to do something about it.
Scott: Well, this all started really back in the day with the Microsoft and I trust you right and that suit was all about.
Scott: hey Microsoft you have a monopoly on computer operating systems.
Scott: Windows is dominated and you are including Internet Explorer with Windows right and you are using your monopoly power of operating systems to Stranglehold the market out of web browsers.
Scott: These are the days when you can still go to the store and like buy Netscape Navigator on disc or something.
Scott: Yep, right And you know that is against antitrust law.
Scott: and the Justice Department went after Microsoft and there's all kinds of business going on There.
Scott: but since then even though tech companies and even worse telcos like NBC Comcast universal whatever the fuck it is now how many companies are in there?
Scott: and Disney buy everything in the universe Disney own all of media entertainment.
Rym: I mean just say the words AOL Time Warner just rolls off the tongue.
Scott: right all these mega mergers going on.
Scott: But the tech companies, you know, Google Amazon Facebook To some extent Netflix.
Rym: Yeah Netflix is plenty of competition.
Scott: Yeah, kind of.
Scott: but anyway, the point is these mega mega companies Right are controlling huge aspects of society Right in a very few entities much like it's really not too different from the old train companies and oil companies well started in antitrust law in the first thing.
Rym: that's very different though in that a lot of the traditional trust busting was around a company that controls a sector absolutely either vertically or horizontally if any you're looking at it as Opposed to here where we have this mega corpse that do a large number of completely unrelated things And they wield power by the fact that they control these vastly disparate areas.
Rym: I mean the same company I just bought some new deodorant from online also hosts a bunch of my web infrastructure.
Rym: Well, like that's weird and we've normalized it.
Scott: Yeah, you know you have it.
Scott: It's and it's like the Microsoft situation was like hey You that's the reason I brought it up is because it's like hey you own this monopoly on Operating systems and you're using it to weasel your way into web browsers, which we don't think of as being too far away.
Scott: They're both computer software right but it's like you have a monopoly on book selling and you're using it to weasel your way into a monopoly on grocery selling and clothing selling and selling everything and also hosting everything and also shipping and receiving a Logistics and
Rym: like I guess these companies are becoming the literal mega corpse from all cyberpunk dystopia book
Scott: readers.
Rym: It's like and on one hand What's really interesting is that one of the measures of antitrust stuff back in the day was not just that they're monopoly But that they are abusing their status as monopoly and harming like the consumers.
Rym: but Actually like Amazon is an example, they've mostly been helping consumers and they've been harming the rest of society.
Scott: Yeah, that's the thing.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's like, you know, it's like like.
Rym: as a person I don't want to have to go to any store but Amazon.
Rym: I just want to go to Amazon.
Rym: I don't want to have to look at ten different sites to buy things, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, I can go without uber, you know, because I hate the uber just as I hate the Amazon I can't really go without the Amazon even though I'd like to.
Scott: But I can go without the uber because I you know, I know it's even worse.
Scott: I put it's like If you go with the uber, it's like yeah, it's real cheap to get around way cheaper than the other.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's really good for the user.
Scott: It's really good for the company.
Scott: It's really bad for an uber's case the driver and Amazon's place all the third-party sellers and everyone else in the whole society.
Rym: Yep, but look at even something simple like video games.
Rym: on one hand We want there to be multiple storefronts for games known as a monopoly.
Rym: on the other hand There are some multiple storefronts, but I still only buy games on Steam and if I can't buy it on Steam I think about it and decide if I even bother buying it because I don't want to have to deal with multiple stores.
Scott: Well, this is a thing that's you know, when if you're looking at just companies, it's like yeah We don't want to have you know, few large companies and have lots of small companies.
Scott: That's just better.
Scott: but it with technology just the nature of computers there is benefit to Conglomeration aggregation Unification right all these things.
Scott: there are real benefits to those things, right?
Scott: It's like Google.
Scott: Google makes Gmail They also may Google Docs.
Scott: They also make your Android phone.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So if Google makes all those three things and then they integrates them all really nicely That provides the fact that they're all provided by the same person made by the same person company Whatever provides a benefit to the end user.
Scott: if you had to get like Choose a phone from like five different phone operating systems.
Scott: And even if all of them were good, it's like, well, okay.
Scott: Well now you got to choose your email provider.
Scott: So I got to choose what I want to choose the one that works best on my phone.
Scott: It's like there's 20 of them.
Scott: You know 20 things just like Gmail.
Scott: and then there's 30 different web browsers And then you're a developer trying to make a web page and that people are using 30 different web browsers.
Scott: It's like it becomes from a technological standpoint.
Scott: Just like this sort of hellscape of too many choices.
Scott: This is why Linux on the desktop couldn't grab on.
Scott: there's too many distros.
Rym: Yep, right?
Scott: It's why Android is.
Scott: is you know has people not updating?
Scott: is too many Android versions going around right?
Scott: with iOS?
Scott: It's just like yeah, everyone updates and has the newest one.
Scott: There's one version mostly.
Rym: So what exactly do we do about this?
Rym: Do we just break them up?
Rym: And if so, how?
Rym: like?
Rym: this is a Really thorny issue for a lot of reasons because on one hand these monopolies or these pseudo monopolies wield undue power but on the other hand many of them have wielded that power for neutral or slightly positive Outcomes on occasion.
Scott: Yeah, right just cuz you know a bad evil serial killer saves one baby and then kills ten people.
Rym: What if he saves ten people and kills one person to do that?
Scott: I'm just saying where's the line?
Scott: Which trolley should not be a not a saint just because you did some good stuff is my point?
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: but so one thing I think we can do is Basically, everything comes down to the government has to do something about it because no nothing else is gonna do it.
Scott: Yes, because because the right look at like the you know, stupid Zuckerberg owns most of Facebook So no one can tell them what to do.
Scott: but like what?
Scott: what it was like some ridiculous percent of the Investors not a percent of the shares because obviously then something would have happened if it was yeah more than 50% of the shares Voted.
Scott: but like some ridiculous percentage of the investors who didn't own a majority of the shares Voted to kick Zuckerberg's ass out on the street, you know and stop doing evil privacy violating garbage.
Scott: But they didn't have enough shares.
Scott: So nothing happened, right?
Scott: But yeah, so the in the absence of shareholders being able to do anything the government has to do something.
Scott: What should the government do?
Scott: Well, the easy things I think they should do is Enforce some sort of interoperability Situations, right?
Scott: So if you look back in the day Microsoft had like a monopoly unlike, you know office But now there's like other things can read and write doc files.
Scott: So it's like yeah you.
Rym: so how about like for gaming you can use your game.
Rym: the launchers should have some sort of cross-launch interoperability.
Scott: if they're about With OS X you can use the I work pages app.
Scott: or you know You can open up PowerPoints in what?
Scott: what do they call it?
Scott: keynote right keynote and PowerPoint.
Scott: pretty good interoperability wise right.
Scott: It's like by you know, and it's like once you know the inner that wasn't done by the government That was just Matt OS X working with Apple working really hard to get PowerPoints to load nicely in keynote And then once they do people can start using keynote.
Scott: and now you know The Microsoft PowerPoint needs to sort of make you know not break.
Scott: that right.
Rym: We need something more complex and subtle with the caveat that I think there's a danger here as well.
Rym: But I think we more need to break them up based on One company should not be in too many sectors, right?
Scott: Yes, I think that's the next thing right, but I think the Amazon storefront should not be the same company as Amazon web services.
Scott: Yep, that one company.
Scott: I think there's just be a lot.
Scott: I don't know how to word the law because I'm not a lawyer Right, but clearly it's a concept that people conceive of in their brain.
Scott: Therefore it should be possible to make a law out of it.
Scott: Here's the complication though is that you should be able to make a law that says One company must do one and only one thing you cannot even have.
Scott: I think it should and I'm okay.
Scott: Even you would bring up that the like example of like, ah, you have the the subway and Carvel and the same little building.
Scott: I think you shouldn't even allow that.
Scott: fuck that.
Scott: Yeah get for your subway and your Carvel next to each other But not the same company got a register them separately.
Scott: They go out of business separately.
Scott: You can sell them separately, right?
Scott: I'm okay with even being picky about that.
Scott: if it means we can get a law that says one company does one fucking thing.
Rym: Yeah, I feel like it'd be a little broader than that.
Scott: I think everyone's ever to your cracker barrel with your restaurant your gift shop.
Scott: No.
Rym: Yeah, I think that's a gift shop and restaurant.
Rym: I'm not.
Rym: I'm not looking that drastic.
Rym: The thing I worry about more is that one of the benefits of these structures of it being in multiple sectors is that a company can Whether a downturn in sector a with the profits from sector B and continue doing research and development in things that aren't directly profitable because Due to fiduciary duty and the fact that these companies are beholden to the shareholders.
Rym: They're not allowed to like lose money.
Rym: They're not allowed to do sometimes strategic long-term thinking things but by having money from multiple sectors.
Rym: There's a lot more flexibility there.
Rym: That is we don't have a solution for that unless we also change the nature of the relationship between Shareholders and company.
Scott: that's what I'm saying.
Scott: If you have one company can only do one thing right if Netflix wants to start doing I don't know groceries groceries.
Scott: if they're forced to make an actual Completely separate company with a separate board and separate everything and the grocery business doesn't do well Then that has to go out of business.
Scott: They can't prop it up with their Netflix money.
Rym: Mmm, right, you know That's a big part of the problem.
Rym: Like look at uber.
Rym: uber crack is just Subsidizing these drivers with to keep the prices low with their venture capital money.
Rym: They're not profitable.
Rym: Nope They never will be.
Rym: probably nope, and frankly the only thing uber Alec.
Scott: I don't even care that.
Scott: Well, that's the thing is because when people do startups, they're not trying to be profitable.
Scott: They're just trying to make a product that gets enough users that someone else will buy them.
Scott: Mostly the people buying them are those big tech companies the Google Microsoft Apple right.
Rym: Apple buys companies like Constantly, right and there's just a big like mold like 13 billion dollar merger of some like integration companies a while ago.
Scott: But I'm saying is if you had antitrust it would be like, you know Every single one of those purchases of companies.
Scott: you'd be like no your giant Apple.
Scott: You can't buy that.
Scott: It's like don't allow this buying to happen.
Scott: Don't allow the merging.
Scott: It's like you're enormous.
Scott: No, you cannot take over another fucking thing.
Scott: No, you can't buy that Maps company Google.
Scott: It's competing with your Google Maps.
Scott: That's not allowed.
Scott: Stop it.
Scott: and then what would happen is a. There would some companies that are profitable would stick around and compete.
Scott: and all these tiny startups, right?
Scott: They wouldn't be able to have this business plan of burn virtual venture capital money make an unprofitable business Just trying to get users so that someone will buy you because the government won't allow anyone to buy you.
Scott: You're gonna have to make a you either make a profitable company or you make no company.
Scott: and if all those companies basically suddenly Have to actually be profitable They probably won't even exist in the first place because you won't get those venture capital beyond investing in them.
Rym: I think these sectors can be pretty broad.
Rym: Like I feel like Amazon's web services should be split from Amazon's selling business.
Rym: Yes I'm not that clear on whether or not Amazon's movies and video like.
Rym: I feel like that does fit within the purview of IMA storefronts, you know, it's really.
Rym: I feel like this is like where's the line should Amazon be allowed to have its own Primary production studio to make movies and TV shows to sell on their storefront platform?
Scott: I mean there are some blurry lines like that But like that one you could debate them into your but web services and storefronts a little earlier.
Rym: Like there is a pretty clear line there.
Scott: But I have no problem just erring on the side of split it even if you're not sure.
Scott: split it Right, because it's like.
Scott: what's the harm in splitting it?
Scott: if there's this harm in letting it stay together Right, if you let things stay together and you're not sure it's like someone could be nefarious.
Scott: But if you split it and you weren't sure what's the worst case one of the halves goes out of business?
Scott: All right, no harm done.
Scott: Sounds good to me.
Rym: Where do we split Apple up?
Rym: Like what are the?
Rym: what are the companies that come out of an apples play?
Rym: Cuz I don't think apples monopoly.
Rym: I don't think apples even like I'm not like there's not.
Rym: there's no good line to split them up.
Rym: This player right.
Rym: so Apple isn't necessarily a Monopoly, they're a powerful and wealthy company.
Scott: that well, they're the number they're the most biggest company on earth.
Rym: Well, that's why it's not necessarily antitrust.
Rym: There's a Apple's problem is that they have too much cash.
Scott: Well, that's that's a separate issue, right?
Scott: But so personal with Apple right you have this situation where there are Certain parts of the business Right, they don't directly make money.
Scott: OS X is free.
Scott: basically, yep, right so it's like you're getting out Story.
Scott: if you simply if you split them off software and hardware It's like.
Scott: well if there's like a company that only made Apple Hardware, it's like.
Scott: well they would Window, you know, they would.
Scott: I guess I try I have to get.
Scott: they would work hard to make sure Windows right on that hard Cuz there else no one would buy it.
Rym: Well, like.
Rym: here's another example Microsoft.
Rym: I'm actually glad Microsoft is making like their own surface computers because I don't trust Third-parties to not put malware and garbage on Windows computers.
Scott: Microsoft could which you know would probably be the opposite of antitrust.
Scott: those back to my point about you know, the benefit of technology specifically of Unification and fewer players is you know and having strong people right and monopolists is because Microsoft could you know having a OS monopoly could say you want to pre-install Windows on your PC Dell HP Sony whoever then you Lenovo then you are not allowed to install anything else.
Scott: You must install pure windows.
Scott: I don't know why they've never done this.
Scott: Just don't allow these third parties to install garbage pre-installed bet.
Rym: The reason they haven't done it is because there are a lot of people who would go after them for antitrust if they did that.
Scott: Yeah, but but antitrust has not been enforced basically since you know 20 years.
Scott: It's in a completely ignored law.
Scott: So why wouldn't you push it?
Scott: It's not so much Or the last.
Rym: it's that like American antitrust law is complex enough to where?
Rym: Everyone's kind of following the rules because it mostly focused on now.
Rym: I'm just paraphrasing a lawyer.
Rym: I was talking to a while ago.
Rym: I'm not a lawyer and I'm not an expert on this and I'm trying to skim this Wikipedia article.
Scott: It is too complicated a thing of like when it's like it's one of those things where it's like they.
Scott: I'm not technically a monopoly, you know that company has an army of lawyers and they're not technically a not monopoly.
Scott: but there's still a company that is too large and too powerful.
Scott: that is perhaps more powerful in the government in some ways and If they are not technically a monopoly by the current antitrust law Then the antitrust law should be updated so that they are but basically it covers.
Rym: are they doing harm?
Rym: Are they restricting the market?
Rym: Like there's all these things that make you qualify for these antitrust rules and none of these big tech companies are doing any of these Things and in fact some of the things that are disallowed from doing would probably be to the net benefit of society.
Rym: So it gets really complex.
Rym: It's not really antitrust It's a new thing because fundamentally the real problem is just that no single entity should have that much power, right?
Rym: It's like septic government.
Scott: way back We talked about too big to fail with like the banks which should also be broken up probably Yeah, much smaller banks and they talk about too big to fail, right?
Scott: It's like oh no if these fail then our society has failed.
Scott: Well, it's like then that too big to fail is too big to exist.
Rym: Well, no too big to fail It doesn't matter.
Rym: I got a better.
Scott: This is or how many rules you're following.
Scott: if you know company should be allowed to be that big Period even if you're only doing one thing, you're just a bank Scott.
Rym: Here's the bank.
Scott: It's too big.
Scott: Sorry, now you're two banks too big.
Rym: to fail doesn't necessarily mean now you're smaller.
Rym: too big to fail means That's something the government should be doing for the benefit of society as opposed to a private company doing it for profit.
Scott: Right, and that goes back to right.
Rym: Yeah, I talked about, you know, having you know, tell I'm kind of getting sick of capitalism.
Scott: It's a type of interoperability as the one as one of the possible solutions.
Scott: Right force the tech companies like force Apple to let anyone make you know apps without having the app.
Scott: Another thing we could do is for the government to take some of the technological things Right that these companies do and turn them into utilities.
Rym: You know what my guy that's exactly what I was gonna suggest cuz my example I was instead of Facebook being some company like private ass companies like no as a social network.
Scott: That's the utility the end.
Scott: Well, you know anyone can make a social network app that connects to the government photo stream Whatever.
Rym: now, maybe you can make your own but they can't get above a certain And it might not even you know.
Scott: And people are worried about government censorship and government spying and those things.
Scott: and you're right The government doesn't have to actually run the utility just like that's to enforce an interoperability, right?
Scott: It's like the government doesn't run the phone network or the power grid.
Scott: I think they should they should but you know, they could just be like.
Scott: hey Here are the rules for power grid Facebook.
Scott: You are now no different than like, you know, Con Edison, basically Here's a better example cuz social networks get tricky in a hurry.
Rym: But the example I was going to use I was leading you to this was say we had to break up Apple or die Apple.
Rym: Google.
Rym: Google does a lot of really critical things for modern society Like for example, so changing the main thing Google Maps.
Rym: Google Maps could not make money.
Rym: Google Maps cannot make money except by advertising and nonsense.
Rym: Yeah, Google Maps by itself could not succeed.
Scott: Google Maps became a guy like maps gov.
Rym: But you want to know the only thing worse than Google Maps Have restaurant reviews and ads on it.
Scott: It would just be great maps with great directions.
Rym: Do you remember what it was like back when you had to go to MapQuest or nothing?
Scott: Yeah, it sucks.
Rym: Yeah, well, but yeah, Google Maps is the kind of thing that I think should be a service provided by the federal governments Mm-hmm, like that.
Scott: I think that should actually not even be something provided by the federal government.
Scott: I think that should be like a Cooperation between all world governments.
Rym: But that's not a world
Scott: map service Right, of course the probably only problem there that you would get into
Rym: well The only problem only you're the only is gonna be a real big problem
Scott: would be that many of the borders drawn Perhaps around Kashmir or China on this world map.
Rym: Yep, right there are disputes about what the world Some countries wouldn't want to display gay bars.
Rym: Like there'd be shit like that would happen.
Rym: You can't global dig.
Rym: let's stay away from making this global.
Rym: just saying the one thing.
Rym: I Right answer in principle in a yeah.
Rym: But the reality is and even in this era of the rise of fascism and the fucked up Trump world that were like this hellscape I still think that the only thing worse than the United States being the primary regulator of the internet is Literally any other country getting that power?
Rym: That is that is why I'm kind of looking at a u.s.
Rym: Focused Initiative here because if the u.s.
Rym: Does something or the EU does something all the mega corps have to play ball.
Rym: They cannot leave those markets.
Rym: Mmm.
Rym: You could I'd only yeah China There are Chinese there's a Chinese market that could rival that.
Rym: there really aren't other markets that are big enough.
Scott: I don't think Mmm, don't be big then be small.
Rym: Yeah, but yeah, what do you want?
Rym: You want to have Google Maps that only works in the US and then go to Japan.
Rym: you got to get the like Japanese government app.
Rym: that sucks and is different.
Scott: Mmm.
Rym: I don't think that's gonna work Google.
Rym: But I guess I want there to be an ecosystem where something like something as good as Google Maps can exist and is funded Not through consumers paying for it and not through advertising and not their data mining.
Rym: The only other option.
Rym: there is a government service or a government subsidized service Provided with rules and regulations by private companies.
Scott: Or, you know, I mean the other thing is like, you know people don't really think out of the box, right?
Rym: It's like I think we're thinking out of the box.
Rym: I just said the government should take over Google Maps.
Scott: No, he's right.
Scott: For example, right?
Rym: How about this?
Scott: The government goes and takes all the source code and all the you know Google Maps, right and then just like fucking hands it out.
Scott: So now anyone can run a Google Maps now now this Google Maps is all over the fucking place.
Rym: I don't think that would work.
Rym: Which one do you which one are you using?
Scott: No, I'm just saying like just fucking.
Scott: you know It's like if suddenly these things that are the only thing that is keeping us The only thing that's keeping that data accurate.
Rym: is Google having a massive engine that's going out and collecting.
Rym: I'm aware of that.
Rym: but I'm saying is that the a static snapshot of Google Maps data is worthless within a week.
Scott: I'm not saying you're thinking too, right?
Scott: I'm no reason that we can't force these things to be open, right?
Rym: It's like only it could.
Scott: just you know, right we could take OS X and be like, you know what Apple?
Scott: Not only do you have to keep developing this but also why should they unless we're paying them to do it We just force them.
Rym: What do you mean?
Rym: force them?
Scott: can write any law?
Scott: The law can say almost anything.
Scott: the government cannot write laws that force people into conscripted labor How well conscripted later if we require if it's just saying if you want your company To continue to engage in commerce.
Scott: We are the Congress who has the unlimited ability to regulate commerce.
Scott: Anyone who makes an operating system must open source it completely at all times.
Scott: How about that law?
Scott: anyone who makes a mapping system must make all their map data completely public at all times?
Scott: Anyone who makes a search engine must keep their entire search index and its algorithm and everything open source at all times.
Rym: So Scott you can't.
Scott: you want to make any sort of computer protocol or API must have it fully documented Available to public at all times.
Rym: fuck you so you could make a law like that.
Rym: I can write literally anything.
Rym: if I had a small company that made like mapping software and that law existed I would just shut the company down.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: Go ahead I think every company would shut down.
Scott: if you have a bookstore if you have a store online You know where you allow, right?
Scott: You can just be like boom any kind of crazy thing you can come up with.
Scott: just force all these companies, you know if you See, well, how could we destroy Oz with a crazy law?
Rym: Hmm see the point is you gotta get creative but it's got.
Scott: my point is the goal isn't just if you if you make If you make a hardware device of any kind You must provide all customers with the unlimited ability to have any replacement parts full schematics to repair it on their own full documentation of all software included right.
Scott: full documentation on all protocols radio signals How to make so that people can make their own accessories with no limit whatsoever.
Rym: What if I'm making highly specialized medical stuff for one particular realm and even more reason and provide full documentation to all patients doctors All right?
Rym: so what is what if that's that tiny weird niche ecosystem is Already on such a thin margin that if you were required to do the extra work to open-source it and document it You'd might as well just go out of business instead.
Rym: and now there's nothing.
Scott: I think that's a bunch of bullshit.
Rym: I think things like that will happen.
Scott: They're making plenty money.
Scott: Also, if you're talking about medical stuff met no medical business should be able to be for-profit.
Rym: I agree with that right, so therefore just fucking do it, but I'm saying that Some of the ideas you came up with around say Google Maps would just cause companies to stop making maps full stop.
Scott: No deal with it.
Rym: So I think a better solution is to either you don't have capitalism then there's an incentives.
Rym: besides Middle ground would be.
Rym: imagine if the government said there's gonna be a government map.
Rym: We are going to Basically eminent domain Google Maps.
Rym: Google has to keep maintaining it, but the government will pay.
Scott: That's the thing keeping your capitalism around with your paying.
Rym: What is paying?
Rym: who said capital paying is just effectively?
Rym: Providing the materials to make the thing.
Scott: I don't think government money.
Scott: should we go to some private Google company?
Scott: I think we just take it.
Rym: I feel like there is a balance between the two because If the government just takes it you had your chance to be not evil and then you got ready.
Scott: You don't be evil rule because you're evil we can fuck you.
Rym: The problem is you were good who wouldn't have to fuck?
Rym: you got to live in the reality of government Which means that the government well the way it's currently structured unless we've completely restructured the government Which I know we both have thoughts on that too Not really the topic of this show There is no way to hire the kinds of people you would need to continue to make that software good.
Scott: Another thing is you know just the government could use someone like me the government.
Rym: in fact I make more money than I'm I would legally be allowed to make pretty much anywhere in the federal government.
Rym: So unless you destroy the entire private sector people like me would never work for a government.
Scott: You also you know the other evil things the big tech companies do like privacy invading.
Scott: I think they're like CEOs.
Scott: you just go to jail for that Scott.
Rym: That's actually if you read GDPR.
Scott: Well that has the non enforced like what it are.
Rym: what do you mean?
Scott: not enforced it's it is enforced fairly well No, so what I was reading about the GDPR in Europe is that Ireland is in charge of enforcing it.
Scott: Yeah, and they basically have taken no actions basically against any big tech companies because oh, they're all I keeping there.
Scott: You know using Ireland as their tax haven is big scam.
Rym: There's a little more to it than that and they're all.
Scott: there's a lot of G There's a lot of GDPR Violations going on in the big tech companies and no one's doing anything about it.
Rym: Yeah, but for now since Ireland's
Scott: job to do it all
Rym: I would say is stay tuned on that because there was sort of a again, I'm not a lawyer, but there's sort of an an agreement that there would be a slow ramp-up of enforcement because the actual fines and punishments described in the law are Terrifying in how extreme they are good like if they're based.
Rym: They're actually pretty cool.
Rym: They're based on the gross like revenue of the company that does the violation.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: So a little company.
Rym: It's iron monkey style if Google messes up they owe billions.
Rym: where if GeekNights messes up We owe what I'd owe like 20% of our gross revenue, which would come down to like under a thousand dollars Right.
Scott: I basically think you know, it's like the the.
Scott: if you're that big If you're that big and you have that much money you have no excuse not to fuck up, right?
Scott: So if you do fuck up, you shouldn't even get like three strikes.
Rym: You should just be punished in a devastating manner, but I'm saying the way the approach to this.
Rym: I think what we need like the practical way to solve this problem is to have the United States Senate Back and once it's under the control of the Democratic Party again, when will that happen?
Rym: You're alive either in 2020 or I'm probably leaving the country.
Rym: So but We need to actually pass a few laws.
Scott: You know, the numbers are there for 2020.
Rym: We only need to get to 50.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: That's literally all you need because if you get the presidency Then you also have the tie-breaking vote.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: It's pretty close there Mm-hmm But anyway We need to pass some basic laws to reign in the extreme power of a handful of existing tech companies And I feel like that is achievable in the next decade.
Rym: Amazon Google Facebook There's a really short list of companies that need to be very broadly broken up into broad sector companies.
Rym: Yeah, even that would buy us a lot another way to go and this is sort of like the crazy talk.
Rym: alternative if we're looking out of the box is those companies should pick a side and use their billions to fix society and Solve the problems that are being caused by these monopolies such that the government leaves them alone because they actually funded the solution.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know, that's the thing is like monopolies are tolerated if they serve the public.
Rym: good.
Rym: look at the sports exemptions.
Rym: All major league sports are exempted from all antitrust laws.
Scott: Yeah, because having more than one sports league is stupid.
Scott: Yes, so in some technology one search engine is sort of similarly stupid.
Rym: Yes, so in some technology areas, there are definitely spaces where it makes sense to have one company that is monopoly.
Rym: But we need heavy rules and regulations regulating that industry and that company and We need the government to pass those laws.
Rym: I feel like the big tech companies the best thing to do would be to lobby and Take over the government enough to force those changes so they can maintain their monopoly status But get appropriate regulations on top of themselves before we just bust them up because they we hit Mad Max post capitalism.
Rym: Hmm anyway We're not lawyers or politicians It's still.
Scott: it's interesting how this was like.
Scott: this kind of talk was like non exist.
Rym: You know like non existent talk, why do you think we've officially endorsed Elizabeth Warren for the US presidency?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: only among the craziest of nerds like us was this talk and now lately it's become like the.
Scott: the amount of this Talk is like increasing.
Scott: It's still not huge right?
Scott: You're still not seeing this like, you know All people talking about this all over the place, right?
Scott: It's not like at the level of say.
Scott: also it's a level of like gun control where everyone talks about it.
Rym: Still am very much against a lot of the things that the EU is trying to do to Microsoft.
Rym: I didn't think it was.
Scott: A lot of times they're doing stuff be just because they're trying to attack.
Rym: you can't bundle your web browser anymore.
Rym: You don't see the right jackass.
Rym: How do I download Chrome if I don't have a web browser?
Scott: We're in attacking European companies, right?
Scott: Yes, just you know, sort of, you know, a commercial war kind of situation.
Scott: Yep Economic warfare.
Rym: It's a very complex situation but the fundamental problem remains.
Rym: there is a small number of companies that have terrifying amounts of money and terrifying amounts of power over the global infrastructure and Few and they are too big and therefore they must be destroyed or forced to not be too big.
Rym: Yeah, but the details of how we do that are very complex and probably involve drastically reorienting not just these companies But the US federal government as a whole our entire society.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, but it's it's funny We're like, you know all the sci-fi cyberpunk books were like, you know, oh, yeah snow crash the world.
Scott: We're just corporations everywhere that run everything.
Scott: It's like guys.
Scott: How many times when someone writes a sci-fi book?
Scott: You're not supposed to try to make it come true.
Scott: I should write a sci-fi book.
Scott: Yeah, and then hopefully people will try to make that come true.
Scott: instead I'll write one where it's like Or the fifth element or it's like.
Scott: when they wrote 1984 they wrote all these books.
Scott: They were trying to make those things not happen and everyone's all like, oh look how all the things everyone wrote is happening.
Scott: It's cuz you're trying to make it happen dumbass see at least shadowrun.
Rym: Well, yes, we have the Shadowrun is not happening.
Scott: at least shadowrun one.
Rym: Yeah, you have a megacorp dystopia.
Scott: We have dragons and elves and magic and president would fix this shit so fast.
Rym: Yeah, you know what?
Rym: That's why they assassinated him like right away before he could do anything.
Scott: Yeah He was gonna fix it all.
Rym: gotta be a spirit.
Rym: You can't be no ghosts.
Rym: All right, I think we've talked long enough about this, okay This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and make comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights.
Rym: Ah Craig Albrecht enjoys having a nickel just like a dude guy.
Rym: kajar tovish and linky G Jennifer Hitchcock Chris midgiff mystady.com Jay bad scoot alone Lee Roberto Kingsley Shawn Yeager Nicholas Brando, mr Strong distraction for to one creations and there may be other secret names.
Rym: You do not even know.
Rym: Chirping about our.
Rym: or Rory Rochelle, Montana Superboy sailor Vista cleanse Walton from New Zealand Ryan parent.
Rym: You're open letter.
Rym: Finn dread lily tenebrae Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: We both survived our various bridge incidents.
Rym: and now I leave you with something from even more ancient past Nakama, okay That can't almost a man.
Scott: yeah Give me that don't know that I was in blue chance.
Scott: Oh boy It's a good day.
Rym: Ah, that's a Tomo.
Rym: Ah, that's whatever it was later.
Scott: Oh You know.