Rym: It's Tuesday March 12th 2019.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: the newest hottest hotness Autochess a mod in dota 2 that has nothing to do with chess.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So there's a thing I knew about for a while.
Rym: It's happened in New York in several waves.
Scott: I was hoping to me actually mostly last year.
Scott: It never happened to me.
Scott: Oh I had for like about a week.
Scott: I was getting them constantly and I blocked them all.
Scott: but basically it's a. it's a scam call But it's a scam call that targets Chinese people who live in the United States Tells them probably I think a scam about immigration to try to get them to send money to someone.
Scott: Yeah, and since you live in New York City where there's a lots and lots of Chinese people that call was hitting us Because I guess of our area code they were targeting Whereas other parts of the country with less Chinese population probably weren't getting this particular evil scam call.
Rym: Well part of the reason why I never got it is that I have two phone numbers.
Rym: One of them is in an area code in the mid Hudson Valley where I don't live.
Rym: So I just blocked any phone call from that area code because no one who lives there would ever call me.
Rym: And if somehow I know someone who lives there that sucks.
Rym: You just can't call me.
Rym: I'm not willing to deal with it.
Rym: And then my other phone number is a New York City phone number, but it's on Google Voice that has spam filtering.
Scott: Yeah, I just have an app on my phone that spam filters.
Scott: It actually has been working betterly or either there's less spam calls or the app is improved lately.
Rym: So I was at work today and My phone at my desk rings, which doesn't.
Scott: oh you have a office phone.
Scott: Yeah, but I always refuse to have an office phone and it has been very good for me.
Rym: I don't even know what the phone number is to call that phone.
Scott: I haven't had an office phone since I worked at the company that sent me to the middle of nowhere.
Rym: I had an office phone when I was at that broker-dealer So long ago.
Scott: companies are saving so much money just not having my last company.
Rym: They were like you want a phone and I was like, why would I want a phone?
Rym: Hell no Yep, and I was.
Rym: and they were like, well, how should people call you?
Rym: And I was like, why would I ever want anyone to call me at the office?
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Do not call ever.
Rym: Yep And then I set up like a Google Voice for myself at work and like I set up Google Voice for everybody It just worked.
Rym: It was great.
Scott: email me Those are the work approved communications.
Rym: anyway this phone rings and I'm just like what.
Rym: what's that sound?
Rym: What the hell is going on?
Rym: And because it's a fancy company everything's integrated.
Rym: So then it pops up on my screen and it's like phone call from the outside world.
Rym: because I guess your VoIP system with the software Yeah, cuz I guess if someone called me internally like I'd see their picture.
Rym: Yep We're big on video chat like.
Rym: yeah, if I want to talk to someone at work I literally just click a button and a video chat opens like at their desk and we see each other and just talk.
Rym: It's awesome.
Rym: So, uh, I Answer this call because I'm just like what.
Rym: why would anyone?
Rym: and immediately that music starts and I hear the Chinese game.
Rym: so I hang up and then I noticed that a Phone a few deaths down for me rings and they pick it up and they these and they mutter under the breath What the fuck?
Rym: Oh and then they hang up and then another phone on the floor rings it.
Rym: it called every goddamn phone number in My company one by one.
Rym: All right, and the reactions range from I have a phone To.
Rym: why is someone calling this phone who even knows this phone number?
Scott: Robot who's just iterating through phone numbers?
Rym: yep, and then I got home and I noticed that the spam filter on my New York number had picked up a spam call to Voicemail and it gave me the notification like by the way, there's the spam voicemail just in case you care.
Rym: So I looked at it.
Rym: I clicked on it just now and it was the from the music and then the Chinese spam.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So there we go.
Rym: That's my story.
Scott: Okay, yeah, that's what that's that's not like.
Rym: that's my opening bit.
Rym: great I can't talk about the water in the ceiling.
Rym: is we're saving that for our next Thursday show?
Scott: That is going to be called.
Rym: so this coming Thursday We're gonna talk about the book club book.
Rym: The next gig nights Thursday episode will be called water in the ceiling.
Rym: great.
Rym: So we got any gaming news.
Scott: We do have a gaming.
Rym: There's actually a lot of gaming news.
Scott: So I we might have talked about it on the show before but you've definitely talked about this Again.
Rym: so there's
Scott: a If you follow the speedrunning biz other than a GDQ as GDQ on their twitch channel They have they host other speedrunning things like quick fixes and whatnot and one of the things they host is the mystery race, which is a speedrunning race where People sign up.
Scott: you can even do it yourself.
Scott: You don't have to like be as pro to join in.
Scott: you can try to win And they surprise everybody by sending them a game they've never played before and Everyone has to race it sight unseen just using your raw video game skills and see who finishes the fastest.
Scott: And I was watching one of these mystery fun races and I saw a game.
Scott: it was a game made it a game jam a nice cute little puzzle game called Baba is you?
Scott: and Then I went and I said, oh my god, I want to play this game.
Scott: So I got the game free game jam version, but it's a very short game.
Scott: Why you know was in this little speedrun race.
Scott: And then I said are they ever gonna turn this in like a big real game?
Scott: and I went and I saw some imitators people Stealing the idea for this game making ripoffs, but now for reals.
Scott: officially tomorrow Baba is you the not game jam.
Scott: real deal game is gonna come out on Steam I think and switch and I don't know what platforms but whatever it is.
Rym: I'm conflicted again.
Rym: I guess it's not online so I might as well just get it on the switch.
Scott: March 13th 2019 Which might be today for some people.
Scott: Get this game.
Scott: This game is amazing.
Scott: Here's how it works.
Scott: There's a grid and you walk around and push stuff like Lolo Watching it makes like the trailer tells you everything you need to know right and you at the start of the game You know, you are sheep.
Scott: You are Baba and then as you push stuff around You are pushing objects and when you push them into configurations the rules of the world Change.
Scott: as you push you can always reset I think and it is best in most innovative puzzle game I've seen in many moons like this game.
Scott: get this game.
Rym: the concept of this game alone is Utterly fucking brilliant.
Scott: It is a work of genius.
Scott: possibly game of year 2019 like this is a Unmissable gaming experience.
Rym: This is this is on the level of when portal came out.
Rym: Everyone's like wait this puzzle FPS What's going on?
Rym: And then they played it.
Scott: They're like, oh, yeah, it's just a cute little 2d game.
Rym: Yep, and now it's legit It's out.
Rym: It's on Steam in some other news.
Rym: Uh, I Just kind of assumed this has already happened, but I guess it didn't because it's only now happening.
Rym: So in March of this year, so very soon, you know Nvidia has their driver updates like game ready drivers If you don't know.
Scott: so when you install the Nvidia driver, right you can during installation It will prompt you.
Scott: yo, you want geforce experience.
Scott: Yes No now geforce experience does some stuff you might want and also does some stuff you might not.
Scott: Well, I do use geforce experience.
Scott: I did use it now.
Scott: I don't use it anymore.
Rym: So Because actually there's on my previous computer the shadow cast it does was way good performance compared to OBS back then.
Scott: Anyway, so the thing is the main feature of geforce experience that you do want.
Rym: Oh shit.
Scott: There's a driver Automatic notifications of new driver updates.
Rym: Are you gonna plug your Twitter?
Scott: Yeah, I am.
Scott: I made a Twitter bot.
Scott: It's called Driver Envy, I think twitter.com.
Scott: driver Underscore Envy.
Rym: I was good doesn't have enough Google juice.
Scott: No, no one knows about it.
Scott: That's what I think.
Scott: It's driver underscore Envy I believe.
Scott: Verify that anyway what it does my I mean little bot that basically checks the Nvidia website to see if new Drivers come out.
Scott: It only checks for the windows 64-bit driver.
Scott: It doesn't check for any other OS is or versions or bits a 32-bit drivers or anything like that.
Scott: But anytime the driver gets updated it tweets and then you can click and manually get the driver and then install by hand And avoid the geforce experience and just have the Nvidia driver.
Scott: Just make sure when you're installing a driver don't click the geforce experience box Unless you know what it does and want it because it's not bad.
Scott: It's not great.
Rym: What's what's what's not great about it?
Scott: So that shadow play that you love so much Messed up my sim 5 for quite a while and I had to until I figured out that that was the thing that was messing It up.
Rym: Yeah, I do remember when that was a problem, but I reckon I found out that was a problem right away.
Scott: Anyway, that's just one example.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: What is there?
Scott: another example clogs up my system tray with more shit.
Rym: It's not in my system train as I tell it to be.
Rym: yeah.
Scott: Anyway anyway follow my follow my bot on Twitter to find out about Nvidia driver updates and avoid the geforce experience.
Rym: So the last version of driver 418 will be released in April of 2019 and 418 will be the last driver ever to support something.
Rym: You've probably never heard of called 3d vision, right?
Scott: So people might not remember because it was such a brief flash in the pan.
Scott: as I said it was at the time.
Rym: I mean it was before 2016 and it's been a thousand years since 2016.
Scott: So before 4k TVs, but after 1080p TVs the TV and monitor manufacturers like shit.
Scott: We got to upgrade somehow to make people buy new TVs.
Scott: Everyone's got a 1080p TV and they're cheap.
Scott: We're not making any money.
Scott: Yeah, so they invented a 3d TV Which is basically just 120 Hertz TV that alternates between left and right eyeball.
Scott: They were kind of bad and really expensive and no one made any content for them.
Scott: yep, but if I were a nerd and you had an Nvidia graphics card and you could buy a 3d monitor and certain games would Basically play the game at 120 Hertz and make the game itself 3d.
Scott: So you can play an FPS and it would be 3d like when you go to the movies.
Rym: It was a total gimmick Yeah But I think YouTube might have even supported it at one point like a bunch of more things supported it than you might realize There was a lens for the GF tube camera.
Scott: I bought that could take 3d photo.
Scott: Yeah Anyway, not videos.
Scott: But anyway, uh, and maybe could do video.
Scott: I don't remember.
Scott: Anyway, the point is it was a fad flash in the pan 3d in your home.
Scott: No one bought it.
Scott: It went away.
Scott: Well someone pointed out Driver still has a special module so that you can that it works so that those 3d games You can still play.
Rym: is it needs hardware acceleration for that?
Scott: I remember we would go to PAX and like Nvidia had a thing at the booth and there were glasses and a. you know There was the thing.
Scott: I think the main reason why this and then it was only at Pax's for like one or two years and then it was gone.
Rym: The main reason why this died is one No one bought 3d TVs.
Scott: No one was wearing these glasses.
Rym: But - if you're gonna wear glasses If you're gonna wear glasses to play a game might as well just do VR.
Rym: because well Pro sumer VR did not exist in a usable form when this was a thing But now 4k didn't either.
Rym: yeah pro sumer VR Exists and is fine.
Rym: Like if you're if you're willing to be a like one step past early adopter one step before expanded market VR user.
Rym: VR is way less of a pain in the ass than this ever was and is probably better than this For that kind of experience.
Rym: or if you want a really good TV, just buy a 4k TV.
Rym: Yeah, buy 4k.
Scott: so Nvidia.
Scott: obviously no one's using this shit except a few really dedicated crazy people.
Scott: So they're removing the feet.
Scott: I got hiccups.
Scott: They're moving the feature from their driver.
Scott: All right, Scott and the few people who care about this you probably get out.
Scott: They're probably this.
Scott: you know it's a very small number of people who are very loud because they bought a 3d monitor and they got a 3d game and they got these glasses and they actually use this.
Scott: And now there's gonna be so mad because they invested in something that is now worthless.
Rym: I think there's a secondary class of people who bought very cheap 3d TVs after that whole thing failed.
Rym: Who are then using this for funsies?
Scott: I think that if you are one of the people who's mad about this what you should do?
Rym: Have a dedicated PC.
Scott: I just never update the driver that old Nvidia driver.
Scott: You got the software for that game that has 3d support.
Scott: You got a computer.
Scott: It works on.
Scott: don't update it.
Scott: No, you put it in a virtual machine or something like that.
Rym: And then you know, I mean you're good until like DOS box and everything like really worked.
Rym: There was a time when I still had this old PC that I just ran DOS on to play DOS games.
Rym: You know in it at RIT remember it sat under my desk.
Rym: Eventually, we we tried to install a counter-strike server on it, but wasn't powerful enough Hmm.
Rym: Anyway in some final news.
Rym: I got a little gigabyte update.
Rym: Okay, so war group.
Rym: we reviewed it on February 26th.
Rym: We had both played like Less than 10 missions in the game and like one Set of two versus matches when we did the review.
Rym: I have now played the entire game.
Rym: I've beaten everything except the entire puzzle mode and it's great.
Rym: The endgame is fine.
Scott: The I have not played any war groups since we did the show I have.
Rym: I have unlocked everything that I care to unlock.
Rym: I have not s ranked every map because s ranking some of the maps.
Rym: I see what to do.
Rym: It's not fun and I'm not willing to do it.
Rym: I said that a long time ago about the first GBA Advance Wars But I eventually in a fit of rage boredom went back and did it anyway.
Rym: So maybe I will do this to war groove, but I can say my full final thoughts were war groove Holy shit.
Rym: If you even had a passing interest in Advance Wars Just buy war groove and play it.
Rym: the endgame is great.
Scott: the last if you do a passing interest in Advance Wars and haven't played It play Advance Wars.
Rym: There's not that many.
Scott: you can just get advanced.
Rym: start with the GBA one.
Rym: Don't bother with the ones that weren't released in the US.
Rym: They're only worth it.
Rym: If you are full of rage Mmm, if you're desperate like that is that is going back.
Scott: I really want the real experience.
Scott: don't want to emulate.
Scott: go on eBay.
Scott: buy like a GBA a DS light or GBA SP.
Scott: buy the cartridges used you'll be all good.
Rym: Yep Emulating a GBA works fine.
Rym: Yep, emulating a DS works fine in this at this time.
Scott: And you don't get no touchscreen or that you can with a mouse.
Rym: So the thing is my previous computer could run Advance Wars days of ruin on the D on the thread the DS Emulator just fine.
Rym: if I disabled sound it could not also emulate the sound in real time.
Rym: It used a hundred percent of my CPU all the cars.
Rym: now my computer can handle that All right, but even then it actually uses a lot of resources.
Rym: See our work group final thoughts.
Rym: It is the best you're gonna get and I greatly look forward to Advance Wars 2. and also I Predicted who the square boss would be and I was fucking wrong.
Rym: Oh, the square boss was not who I expected.
Rym: Okay, it had the twist I expected and then it had a twist I didn't expect and I was very pleased by that.
Scott: the same thing does seem good from what I played.
Rym: Yeah, it was.
Rym: it was good it.
Rym: the story it revealed was actually more interesting than I expected.
Scott: Compared to Advance Wars story it is.
Rym: it is a step up from an event.
Rym: It's a step up from the first Story.
Scott: visitors is characters, but in character does.
Scott: it doesn't really carry his character designs Yeah, but it doesn't have anything else.
Rym: the characters in Wargroove have more character than anything that ever happened in Advance Wars.
Rym: But there's still and the game's good.
Rym: It's great.
Rym: Just play it.
Rym: I've played it completely to fruition.
Scott: You get all s-rank.
Rym: No, that's the only thing that there's some maps I did not get an s-rank on and I looked at it and decided it is not worth human effort to get it because the Ranking is to you because you can't do.
Scott: I could.
Rym: I am I could.
Scott: here's the problem.
Scott: Yeah, I could do.
Rym: now Here's the problem compared to Advance Wars.
Rym: S-ranking certain missions is heavily RNG.
Rym: So it's a full web situation Advance Wars.
Rym: there is no full web situation to s-rank anything except maybe in the earliest Advance Wars.
Rym: But actually even then no APC trick you're good.
Rym: So you have the full web situation for s-ranking.
Rym: some of these Coupled with the fact that the algorithm to determine an s-rank is much more simplistic than the algorithm in later Advance Wars.
Rym: So it's not interesting to s-rank those maps because those maps are scripted story mode maps with just RNGs is coming out to ruin you.
Rym: If anyone wants to play this game online, I am 100% up for that.
Rym: You just have to consent to me streaming your pitiful defeat.
Rym: but anyway things Of the day.
Rym: so I got something really dumb and simple.
Rym: I found this a long time ago and I laughed a lot that I forgot about it.
Rym: I found it again recently kind of randomly.
Rym: it's just titled Simpsons blue Swede hooked on a feeling and If you watch it It is basically a mash-up of a scene from the Simpsons with the song Hooked on a feeling made famous by a number of movies.
Rym: It's pretty well known in pop culture.
Rym: as soon as you hear this song if you don't know what song I'm talking about you'll think oh that song.
Rym: and This is an interesting result of a previous meme that was not widely spread on the internet.
Rym: It lasted like two weeks where people were remixing this scene from the Simpsons a million different ways.
Rym: That entire meme came and went in the span of like two and a half weeks and this was its triumph.
Rym: This was what rose to the top in the very end.
Scott: So what do you got so long ago?
Scott: GeekNights.
Scott: one of my things of the day was the Minnesota State High School Turned hockey tournament because they have a tradition at this hockey tournament of all the players good or bad for all the teams getting the most amazing hockey hair they can grow on their heads and then During player introductions skating up to the blue line showing off their hair to the camera that is right in their face.
Scott: And this because been a thing for quite a few years And you know back when I did it as a thing of the day, you know, it was those I think we're still living a beacon.
Scott: Yeah, I think so and this year the internet took notice of it more than it has in recent years.
Scott: So, you know but One thing interesting happened this year and that is on one of the particular teams.
Scott: I guess the yellow team High school.
Scott: that is The kid squiddy skated up to the blue line for his moment his time to shine And show off the hair that he worked so hard on.
Scott: Something funny happened and is a funny video that is thing of the day worthy.
Rym: It is definitely thing of the day worthy In the meta moment the GeekNights book club book, which we will be doing on Thursday in two days.
Scott: read the whole book.
Scott: Yeah, oh, he finally read it.
Scott: It's not a long book and the time it took you to read that I have almost finished.
Scott: I've read one and like a half Larger shattered earth books.
Rym: Ooh Yeah, you've hit some stuff.
Rym: You're getting closer to Evangelion and the shattered earth looks to me overseen.
Rym: Yeah, smoke twos gonna be over soon, right?
Rym: Yeah Oh, you're on three.
Scott: Yeah, I read one long ago.
Scott: Yeah, I already finished - okay.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: Okay That's what I'm saying is I'm you're reading away.
Scott: So Use my subway reading strategy has a suddenly in space.
Rym: Try gun moment happened yet I mean There is a moment many almost identical to that moment in try gun It's quite a few of them where it just cuts to a space station and some people have a conversation about a thing.
Rym: That's when it from that point on it just such moments.
Rym: Yeah There are several.
Rym: one of my favorite moments is in that geode where everybody goes into that control room and is looking at stuff And that's way back already.
Rym: Yeah, that's one of my favorite moments though when they start to figure out the deal with that place And somebody touches something they shouldn't fucking touched Even I know reading the books like don't touch it.
Scott: It's gonna be a bad time Technology, let me mess with it.
Rym: Yep, except 2001 is face outie.
Rym: Odyssey is literally hey precursor technology Let me mess with this.
Scott: Well, it was put there to mess with you.
Rym: Yeah, you don't know that and The only thing I want to say before we get into the book club on Thursday is that 2001 having a matter that you don't know is so well designed.
Rym: having read this and Having seen the movie a long time ago The only thing the only new information I have is the like mind state like what a lot of people were Thinking in the world of a space Odyssey that was not directly conveyed in the movie.
Rym: Otherwise, it's pretty much the movie.
Rym: Talk about that in depth, but Thursday we will do that.
Rym: Otherwise, it's time to talk about Auto chess PAX East.
Rym: Oh, yeah We're gonna be at PAX East doing a panel the real harm of games.
Scott: I'm gonna start making that panel like right now.
Rym: You'd better this is all you Plus pen in the cuttlefish theater than Rym's panel.
Rym: Oh my panels really popular people like my panel.
Rym: Uh-huh We'll see how.
Rym: uh, I thought problem is all our panels lately have good titles That'll get a ton of people in the room regardless of the content.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: But yeah, this would be a good panel and I'll be a zenk icon.
Rym: I still haven't looked at what panels I'm doing.
Rym: I gotta go sort that out.
Rym: But I'm doing a bunch of panels and zenk icon not this weekend but next weekend and then the following weekend packs and then I think we got nothing until PAX West Which means we can start making videos again about things Mm-hmm.
Rym: All right Auto chess.
Rym: Auto chess came out of nowhere.
Scott: Well, so here's what happened.
Scott: right is hearthstone which has an expansion coming out soon and you know has sort of faded a bit.
Scott: And there's a community of streamers that are like all nice people not bad streamers Like you usually see who played mostly played hearthstone, but if you some have veered off into other areas, right?
Scott: And that general streaming community.
Scott: quite a few of those players moved to Auto chess and I was at first.
Scott: I saw them streaming Dota 2 and I was like so sad.
Scott: I'm like, oh no, but then I clicked just to see and I was like What the hell is this.
Scott: and then I realized it's a free mod for Dota 2 and it's like and it's nothing like Dota 2.
Scott: And I learned how the concept of it.
Scott: and then I played it and then I kept playing it and then I made Rym play it.
Rym: yep, I'm gonna say like just like my highest level hottest take is that It is not that good nor is it actually that fun really.
Rym: but the concept of what it is is a Goddamn plus and even though the whole time I was the whole time I was playing it I had this like very ambivalent feeling.
Rym: not ambivalent in that I don't care and that I'm being pulled in equal opposite directions.
Rym: on one hand I hate the UX and I see all these deep flaws in the game.
Scott: There's so many flaws because it is a Dota 2 mod.
Scott: They couldn't they didn't just make a brand new game.
Scott: Well, it also has deep flaws in the sense of not like knowledge requirements And all the requirement is really mostly in the UX because once you learn the UX all the knowledge is just there.
Scott: It's like just on it just there.
Rym: Yeah, but at the same time the concept is so good that it's like you're scratching an itch and Like you it doesn't stop itching.
Rym: I can feel like you're so close to scratching it.
Scott: So the UX right?
Scott: so imagine if you're playing Magic the Gathering right and someone threw a bunch of magic cards at you and The magic cards had no text and you're just like how the hell am I supposed to play?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: if these cards do I have to learn them, right?
Scott: Yep But if you just you don't have to actually learn what the cards do the text is there.
Scott: you just have to learn that if You blink with your right eye twice and then with your left eye three times the text will appear and then it will be obvious What to do?
Rym: Yep, right and then you got to move a miniature around the table.
Rym: And if you put the miniature on top of a card, it'll automatically go somewhere else All right.
Scott: so here's what auto chess is right and it it's funny that the name so the name of the game is auto chess because You can see how they came out.
Scott: that name the way it works is a little a little.
Scott: It's a big Dota 2 map and it splits it up into eight boards and they look like little chess boards and you can only control what's happening on one of the boards, but you can see what's happening on all of the boards where your opponents are playing and You recruit with money Dota 2 heroes
Rym: called chess's
Scott: called chess's in this game, but they're all just Dota 2 heroes.
Scott: Yeah, and you put them into your chess field and you have 30 seconds to do this and then they automatically fight.
Scott: Sometimes they fight NPCs.
Scott: Sometimes they fight copies of opponents Armies of chess's.
Rym: right you have no control or interaction with this fighting at all.
Scott: It's automatic.
Scott: This is great.
Scott: It's like an RTS but everything is automatic.
Scott: I have no control over it.
Rym: There's no micro and it takes like 30 seconds.
Rym: It just happens.
Scott: Yeah, they just fight and you want to win but maybe sometimes you also want to lose.
Rym: I wish I could skip the fighting entirely and just see the outcome instantly.
Scott: I also wish that but the the reason that they show you the fighting is is because it's Dota 2 and If you if you see what's happening the fighting you might be able to and you understand it You might be able to strategize.
Rym: Well, actually that's on your positioning because the game is It's got a lot of like.
Scott: you see that you're losing to the Kunka alt.
Scott: You might want to see that and then you spread your dudes out.
Rym: So it's interesting watching the fighting is boring to me.
Rym: Like I hate it.
Rym: I just have no interest in it at all Except you can sell your dudes during the fight and buy new dudes.
Rym: But the fighting does provide time to shop yep, but the fighting does provide a reasonably natural heuristic to figure out how pieces work and the Attributes that are not told to you by the game.
Rym: because the game assumes, you know how Dota works.
Scott: Yep, so The way I see Dota auto chess is not as chess, but as poker.
Scott: Imagine you're playing poker But After you, you know what happens in draw poker right?
Scott: Not not other pokers draw poker.
Scott: Yeah, you draw a hand and then you discard and draw new cards in an attempt to improve that hand Right.
Scott: yet in draw poker They only let you draw like once and then it's over and then you throw out everything and you play again.
Scott: Imagine if you're playing draw poker But you keep drawing and discarding and drawing and discarding over and over to make up better and then a better hand You're making a better.
Scott: and this and not obviously the the ranks in poker would make no sense because everyone would.
Scott: Four people would reach royal flush Eventually, right, but that imagine is every time you get three aces You can turn them into one like super ace and then if you get three super aces, they become a mega Right.
Rym: So you got eight clubs out.
Rym: clubs make clubs more powerful.
Scott: Yep So it's like, you know There's a different way of ranking the hands based on The synergies like bunch of trolls bunch of elves bunch of Knights and this is a lot of synergies and they're moderately complex.
Scott: They're not that complex.
Scott: Well, they're.
Rym: they're simple on one level.
Rym: But on the other hand you got to keep them all in your head.
Scott: No, you don't because they're right on the screen.
Scott: They actually made it better recently.
Scott: I can show you.
Rym: Oh, yeah I saw that has little circles now that tell you how many synergies you've got for each thing.
Rym: if you hover over them It says what that synergy you click on a do it, dude.
Scott: It shows you all the things that that dude synergizes with and then you can go and hover over that and it tells you The full documentation as long as you got time.
Rym: He's only got 30 seconds to click on that shit.
Scott: It's really not hard anyway.
Scott: But yeah you.
Scott: and the thing is if you just play the game for like two days, you'll learn all the dudes.
Scott: Yeah, that many dudes that you can't learn them all.
Rym: basically the UX and like trying to play the game is just this Undocumented nightmare.
Scott: Yes, because it is a Dota 2 mod.
Rym: But even though Scott had figured it out and like played it and figured a bunch of stuff out.
Rym: I'm still awful I've made.
Rym: I tried to get the experience from scratch.
Rym: I joined a game knowing nothing other than what Scott had told me as a nightmare scenario and I was able to Fight because I couldn't figure out how to get my dude onto the board.
Rym: Yeah But then I figured it out and then I figured out every other thing.
Rym: like over the course of two or three plays Didn't figure everything out.
Rym: I figured everything out that mattered.
Rym: I started getting very close to winning very quickly.
Scott: Well winning isn't hard.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Well because the game is pretty rare, especially once you first start out you're getting paired.
Scott: There's a ranking system.
Rym: Oh my ranking.
Rym: I was paired almost entirely against people with like bishop and knight rank No pawns and no one ranked.
Scott: There's not a lot of people playing as pawns.
Rym: Yeah, it was me and like all bishops and knights It doesn't pair you against people but it will.
Scott: what will happen is like it doesn't match you up against people with similar rank But it adjusts your rank based on the rank of the people you played against.
Rym: Yeah But I play it against people who are all pretty good.
Scott: Come in like fourth.
Scott: if you have people under you are all like night and the people above you are all like Queen.
Scott: It's like you're gonna rank up probably if you're under night.
Rym: Yeah thing is even when it was all nights like I didn't come in last play the only game I came in last place.
Scott: game is Also, it's so RNG.
Scott: as long as you're playing competently, right?
Scott: You're going to.
Rym: on average You'll make it like 20 25 turn.
Scott: You'll only be down ranked if like you really just don't know what you're doing.
Scott: If you know what you're doing, you're going to rank up Over time.
Scott: in aggregate you're gonna make it was of RNG.
Rym: You're gonna make it 20 30 rounds in.
Scott: it was supposed to be an RNG game.
Scott: There was an AMA with the developers and a lot of people are like are you gonna fix item RNG?
Scott: They're like, it's an RNG game.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: They're like.
Scott: they are like.
Scott: this is a game of randomness on purpose.
Rym: There are already degenerate strategies.
Scott: They're already like definitely some dudes that are stronger than other dudes.
Scott: early mech goblin Sell them all get something later on that's stronger like yeah night or early early druid rush if you can get the later ones is pretty powerful.
Scott: Enchantress.
Scott: you can upgrade druids with only two guys and three dudes and then that lets you you know upgrade them to max quickly.
Scott: But they're not the strongest units towards the end except for the lone druid who's pretty good.
Scott: Yep, the other ones are me unless you need the elves.
Scott: Anyway, yeah.
Scott: So that's how I think about.
Scott: I think about it as a game of poker.
Scott: You're leveling up your hand slowly over time and eventually, you know You get matched up against people and all these fights and then when you lose a fight you lose some HP.
Scott: And when you win a fight you gain some HP, but there's war you don't gain HP You just don't lose.
Rym: well, but there's more.
Scott: you can get completely eliminated and the last person standing is the winner.
Rym: It's not just like if it was just that whatever.
Rym: What makes this kind of like in extra interesting in magic is that the way you're making your poker hand of dudes?
Rym: is via a Communal pool draft.
Scott: Yeah, it's not quite.
Scott: it's not a draft like seven wonders.
Scott: you pass it around right?
Scott: The way it works is based on your current level.
Rym: is a communal draft from a shared pool, right?
Scott: You have.
Scott: you draw five dudes at a time, right?
Scott: You have a level.
Scott: you get one XP every turn and the first few levels you just fly up Because it's like to get from level one to two is one XP.
Scott: to get the level two to three is one XP.
Scott: to get A little three to four is two XP.
Scott: But to get levels six seven eight nine is a lot more XP.
Scott: you have to spend five gold.
Scott: You can spend five gold anytime.
Scott: you want to get four XP and that's how you have to get the higher levels.
Scott: There's no.
Scott: if you you're not gonna play like 30 rounds the game will be over by then.
Scott: You won't get to level.
Scott: Yeah, so level 10 is max level.
Rym: most of the games I've played made it around 28 to 30 like every time.
Scott: like it always He's right, but to get I'm saying to get from level like eight to nine.
Scott: You need 30 XP.
Scott: You're not gonna get 30 more levels.
Scott: Oh, yeah gold you get.
Rym: don't use the gold to buy pieces But you can also spend gold to just buy more experience, right?
Scott: So you draw five dudes.
Scott: the five dudes you draw are based on your current level, right?
Rym: So The link to read it From the dota from the autochess website is flagged by steam as being I think malformed the URL.
Scott: Anyway, so if you're level like five you have an X percent chance of drawing guys from this first pool an X percent chance of Drawing guys from the better pool an X percent chance of drawing guys from the even better pool of dudes.
Rym: Oh, there's a big bug that just got introduced like yesterday.
Rym: Great.
Rym: Yeah, fractional gold breaks everything.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: So anyway, the game is buggy as shit.
Scott: It is super buggy as hell.
Rym: I joined one match and all the couriers were invisible and no one could start the game and then it told us all we lost.
Scott: Yep, it happens so you Draw some five dudes and it caused gold to put dudes in your hand.
Scott: Which are the pens?
Scott: you have a limited hand size?
Scott: It's always like what?
Scott: eight or nine something like that.
Rym: one, two, three, four, five, six, seven eight eight dudes.
Scott: Then you can put dudes in the field.
Scott: You can put as many in the field as you want But if you got more than your level they come back to the pens based on your level.
Scott: Your level is the number of dudes you can keep in the field once the battle starts.
Scott: So you could buy like the whole shop if you got enough gold and put everyone in the field But then it'll put everyone back in your hand.
Scott: And if it's still like there's still too many dudes out in the field and your hand is full It just sells dudes that lose if that happens to you.
Rym: You're just out.
Rym: You've just you're done.
Rym: Well, it depends because I'd sell some garbage thing, but it might sell your one leveled up, dude, right?
Scott: So when you sell a dude though, you basically lose.
Scott: no gold.
Scott: you get the full Refund back.
Scott: you can actually make gold by combining druids and selling them.
Scott: Yeah, they sell for the cost of three, but you can upgrade for just two depending if you have enough druids anyway.
Scott: So yeah That's that's in.
Scott: basically you can spend I think two gold to draw a new hand and when you draw a new hand all the Dudes that were in the hand go back into the pool that everyone else is drawing from.
Scott: so if I buy all the mechs There's less mechs in the pool for everyone else to draw and if someone loses the game to get eliminated All their dudes go back in the pool.
Rym: Yep I was playing one game where I was actually I was actually doing a very heavy goblin mech strategy those working out pretty well.
Scott: It works early, but then they're not strong enough for the late game.
Scott: So you got to switch to something else by selling them all and buying something different.
Rym: But a dude who had way more mechs than me died.
Rym: and then I got the mechs upgraded sold everything and then bought new stuff.
Scott: Yep, but yeah, that's how that's how that works.
Scott: So it's it's sort of like seven wonders and everyone has 30 seconds to Push cards around as fast as they can.
Scott: it only works.
Rym: It's a video game and you know push cards around by doing dota 2 crap in the game like with key bindings and everything.
Rym: Yeah, cuz you're still playing dota 2.
Scott: Yeah, it's.
Scott: it's a dota 2 mod.
Scott: It has to.
Scott: it does.
Scott: if you made this as a it's standalone game.
Scott: It would probably just be a card game.
Scott: It would be a great tabletop game.
Scott: I think you just need to figure out a way in Tabletop to evaluate the combat.
Scott: so sort of hand ranking system like poker Just reveal your dudes look at the other person's dudes and know immediately who won.
Rym: but a hand ranking system would mean that players could memorize Statistics and break the game with likely degenerate strategies very quickly.
Scott: Yeah, you'd have to make some other changes.
Scott: I don't think you're gonna have the infinite hand redrawing.
Rym: Yeah, this would be better as a phone app than a great phone at play solo, right?
Scott: Also, I think it would be great if the combat was more like Final Fantasy.
Scott: Yeah, then like dota Yeah, I just I.
Rym: part of the problem part of what I don't like about the game Is that the meta of it like you can figure out like the synergies the mechanics just by reading all this documentation.
Rym: But it really assumes that you play dota already and know all these characters.
Scott: I don't know the characters.
Scott: I learned them in like two days.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I did mostly - hmm It's also items.
Scott: So the item RNG is just sort of like a sideshow.
Scott: so in the certain levels like the first few levels you fight NPCs and then Every fifth level, you know all the 10 15 20. you fight certain NPCs and it's always the same ones.
Scott: So, you know how to handle them, right?
Scott: You know, they're coming.
Rym: Yeah, like the wolves or whatever coming with that one round every time 15 is the wolf guys.
Rym: Anyway, they jump right to the back.
Rym: You gotta jump to the back.
Scott: So you got to rearrange your positioning after level 14 and then switch it back after level 15 anyway.
Scott: so When you fight the NPCs if you destroy any they randomly drop Presents.
Scott: you walk over with your guy to pick up the presents.
Scott: There could be either items in there and it's completely random.
Scott: some games you get like no items.
Scott: some games You get a bunch of items.
Scott: you can then give the items to your dudes to hold and it boosts them up basically.
Scott: and Then the only way to get those items back.
Scott: You can't reassign the items to a different, dude.
Rym: You have to sell the dude you gave the items to and then they fall onto the map and then you got to go get Him again, right?
Scott: But that's the only way to get the items back.
Scott: So you got a really carefully consider who you give the items to like early in the game.
Scott: I'll give the items to a guy.
Scott: that's good now But I know I'm gonna sell and then later in the game I can give the items to my strong late-game guy who's gonna carry who I know is gonna make good use of those items.
Rym: Yep So all this combined makes this frantic real-time drafting Eight player game that is really fun except the UX is so bad.
Rym: It's very hard to learn to play it and very hard to continue to enjoy it.
Rym: Yeah, I think the like the people I played with like.
Scott: there's a lot of degenerate strategies the game super not really degenerate strategy so much as People know which combinations are stronger.
Scott: Everyone knows right?
Rym: Well cheating is rampant.
Scott: I didn't see any.
Scott: I haven't seen cheating, but I've seen a lot of talk of cheating.
Scott: I don't I don't disbelieve it obviously.
Scott: Yeah, right But it's you know, which guys are the strongest.
Scott: So sometimes it just comes down to Who drew the strong guys?
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Sometimes someone just start, you know, I've started three.
Rym: You might just have like three of the same guy just right there to buy.
Scott: I started I started games and it's just like oh you just gave me three.
Scott: I literally I played one yesterday where I bought a dragon knight and then the next round the shop pops up and there's two dragon Knights and I'm like, well dragon knight, even though just got nerfed is the strongest dude, basically and I've got all the dragons.
Scott: Let's go.
Rym: The meta seems to change a lot based on patches.
Scott: when they rebound they patch the game a lot.
Scott: They're working hard on it trying to fix all the bugs and make it as good as they can.
Scott: It's frequently frequently updated.
Scott: so when they make a balance change that you know, it's like Stuff like mages were worthless.
Scott: now mages are hot.
Scott: No, right trolls used to be the bomb.
Scott: now trolls are I?
Scott: They're not the greatest they were before.
Scott: they were like a bomb.
Rym: I have some luck with early game like big synergy warrior combos But I had to get rid of them.
Scott: Warriors and mechs are way good late game.
Scott: You need a lot of warriors and you have to have the good warriors.
Scott: Oh mechs aren't so great late game But you can switch over to the the good mechs like the.
Scott: if you get the super late game ones the gyro and the the tinker Those are good tinker.
Rym: Yeah, I had a good timber.
Scott: your timber saw might be good super late game if it's level three But otherwise like, you know your clockwork and you're you're not not the Tinker techies.
Scott: techies is the super late game one tinker clockwork.
Scott: You got to sell those.
Scott: They're not doing nothing in the late game even if they're level three.
Rym: so That this game is just unique in that no one's really made anything like this before.
Scott: No, it's like a brand new idea.
Scott: I've already seen one garbage clone on iOS.
Scott: that don't isn't worth.
Scott: it is obviously awful But I really want to turn this into a tabletop game or a streamlined video game.
Scott: Yeah, and it would be someone multiple companies.
Scott: This is going to be the next battle royale situation where everyone's gonna try to clone This core concept like PUBG made a thing and then fortnight came along and it's like aha Some auto chess is the PUBG.
Scott: someone else is gonna come along and make the fortnight to Dota chess is PUBG.
Scott: What's interesting though is that the bomb and I'm gonna play it.
Rym: some of the elements of this game are definitely like specific even though they serve these heuristic purposes that we talked about like they have this other.
Rym: like they're there for reasons or at least they serve a purpose.
Rym: a lot of the things in this game seem to have actually just been done because it apes the things that people who play MOBAs like like Rent like automatic play battling creeps like the fact that you have these Standard encounters and you literally sit there for 30 seconds just watching dudes kind of just swing.
Scott: That's You could shop during that time but also be that's the time I used to look at my opponents.
Scott: Yeah, cuz you've got the shared pool going on.
Scott: I want to know is like, alright, what are other people going for?
Scott: Oh, that guy's going mages that guy's going mages that guys I guess I'll go warriors players Because of the history and legacy and everything like.
Rym: it seems like one of the main things they like about MOBAs is just standing there last hitting and watching like creeps just die.
Rym: leveling up in a Progression like this game is all about leveling up in a progression, you know competitive idle game sort of right?
Scott: Yeah, that basically is no it's like competitive progress quest action Which is partly why I'm gonna.
Scott: I think is the board game.
Scott: part of it the the drafting Yeah And the strategizing of which guys to get which guys not to get which who to go for?
Scott: Right that competitive drafting aspect and you know different matchups against different opponents, right that sort of thing.
Scott: It's like, you know, you might think that's the strongest dude, but your opponent gets a disruptor right now You're not you got.
Scott: if you want you wish you had different dudes.
Rym: I will continue to play it partly because I want to make sure I fully understand.
Scott: I will show you things for like five minutes like I didn't know.
Rym: you combine items.
Scott: Yeah, I'm gonna show you five minutes after the show and then I'll go home.
Rym: But I'm not going to continue to play this game.
Rym: I'm gonna play whatever better version of this game comes out.
Rym: I play.
Scott: I'm still playing auto chess, you know, but I don't play.
Scott: here's my man Probably one or two games a day and you know if I really got nothing else to do.
Scott: And then that's it.
Rym: a game of auto chess takes like 30 to 40 minutes.
Scott: well it is true It does take in that time.
Rym: I can play like 12 over Matt overwatch matches.
Scott: the game does Still way more fun.
Scott: It's a it's the thing that is that even though it takes that long It's like a board game that forces everyone to take their turn.
Scott: real bad.
Scott: I'm invested So it's constantly engaging the whole time as long as you're still alive.
Rym: Like I increasingly want to play board games with chess timers.
Scott: It's like you have 30 seconds to get your shit in order and then it's like well fight time even settlers of Catan.
Rym: Imagine what settlers would be like if you had a chess timer and you had four minutes of total thinking time for the entire game.
Scott: It would be exciting though If the fight like you said was instant and it would be 30 seconds.
Scott: and then all right five seconds to think.
Scott: All right, 30 seconds.
Scott: Yeah, you know, that'd be great.
Rym: I also think like to your point Final Fantasy style combat final fantasy style combat.
Scott: Also, I think Pokemon would be great for this.
Scott: I got three pikachu's.
Scott: They become a Raichu.
Scott: I got three dratini.
Rym: My.
Rym: my sole goal in life right now would be to get the Pokemon license and have a studio make the auto chess for Pokemon.
Scott: Auto chess for Pokemon would be the greatest.
Scott: that is the perfect thing for this.
Rym: I would play the ever they have that they have.
Scott: they already have abilities.
Scott: Oh, it's like it's.
Scott: everything is already lined up.
Scott: Oh Pokemon would be the greatest guarantee if I wouldn't get sued.
Rym: Yep If I was in a position to get someone to make it, but that is so far beyond my abilities.
Scott: Nope I'm just gonna let someone else carry this one.
Rym: if anyone out there has the air the people who could make that happen I will invest in you.
Scott: and let's say I did talk to someone who's working on a thesis project based on overwatch and what they're Doing.
Scott: who is they're using?
Scott: this is genius, by the way They're making a tabletop digital hybrid and their idea was to use drop mix controllers.
Scott: You put your car your dudes onto your drop mix controller and they limited is just for but for technical reasons.
Scott: But you would put your dudes out on the for on your personal drop mix board.
Scott: get four of them together and then you look at the tablet and then you see the results of the fight Based on the dudes that you put and then you draft the card.
Rym: I feel like drop mix controllers are gonna be the Q cats of 2019.
Rym: Yes But I was that that'll both anger people who like drop mix and tell some people how old we are.
Scott: My idea is to just have this game where you use jackbox technology and you draft dudes on your little phone And then it's like times up and everyone looks at the TV to see what happens.
Rym: Yeah, and then you could like it could cut around with like pseudo commentary of like.
Rym: let's look at what's going on this match for 30 seconds.
Scott: Well, you could retheme it in such a way.
Scott: to where instead of having all these individual battles where
Rym: you want big mega battle
Scott: royale Well, you're instead of drafting dudes for an army You're drafting like parts for a robot and then all the robots go in and in About like a royal rumble and with one man like one robot standing and you basically rank the robots each battle.
Rym: This raises a meta point.
Scott: think about everything we just said, but basically the core concept of auto chess is genius.
Scott: The history is incorporated into tabletop and other video games.
Rym: I feel like not everyone recognizes this especially people who are newer to gaming younger people Or older people who like didn't play all these games.
Rym: One of the truest and most important aspects of PC gaming is that every major?
Rym: Revolution in like new kinds of game design comes from someone just fucking making a mod Even if it's garbage just thrown it together and saying hey I made an FPS where if you get shot you just died.
Scott: It's because people who usually have the most creative game design ideas don't work in a giant studio.
Scott: They do not have the technological knowledge.
Scott: They're not a video game.
Scott: So the only ways that they can get those new interesting game ideas into the world is via tabletop Which is why you see lots of stuff happening in tabletop.
Scott: That's why the tabletop indie scene is so fire or by mods because mods require much less technical knowledge and skill.
Scott: someone would just game ideas and Willpower will power and dedication to make.
Scott: the mod can get that out there to see if it sticks.
Rym: Like if I were working at a larger studio I would do almost anything to hire the team that made auto chess and give them the support Valve has a history of absorbing.
Scott: How.
Rym: what do you think happen to Counter-Strike?
Rym: Counter-Strike was just a fucking mod for Half-Life 1.
Scott: Valve hopefully will absorb auto chess and also people.
Scott: are you know bringing artifact into the into the equation?
Scott: There's only hundreds of people playing artifact still so it's like man.
Scott: It's like should valve just refund every all the artifact?
Scott: You know it cost them a lot of money to make that.
Rym: meanwhile Auto chess is made of enough of a splash that it appears that streamer viewership of hearthstone is just collapsing.
Scott: It's not collapsing But it's down.
Rym: It's down and auto chess is up and the amount it's down seems to be nearly equal to the amount that auto chess is.
Scott: a lot Of the biggest are.
Scott: so streamers went to auto chess like I said, and that's how I discovered it from the industry information I know.
Rym: Generally any time someone says something like that the reality is no the streaming audience just grew.
Rym: Everything is up.
Rym: But here it seems like this is one of the rare instances of game.
Rym: a just straight-up stole the viewership.
Scott: Auto chess appeals to someone who like it's an RNG game like hearthstone low investment RNG game.
Scott: It's similar.
Scott: It's basically a card game even though.
Scott: There's no cards.
Rym: Yep right a lot of emergent ridiculous behavior.
Scott: This is a meta right.
Rym: it patches frequently Which is really feels good if you're coming from hearthstone which patches rare But also creates a streaming feedback loop where a patch comes out and everyone rushes to watch the streams to see what holy hell breaks loose.
Scott: Auto chess is also a terrific game to stream because People can like in your chat can say like go that do this do that and during the fighting time you can talk to your Chat.
Scott: there's something for the chat to see because there's a big fight going on.
Rym: I'm waiting for.
Scott: twitch plays auto chess, but it's slow enough that they can give input.
Scott: It's not like a real-time game like overwatch.
Rym: Twitch plays auto chess.
Scott: People can't really help you or talk to you about what's going on.
Scott: Auto chess salty bet Auto auto chess.
Rym: I'm waiting for someone to make a bot that plays auto chess.
Scott: You could have an auto chess salty bet.
Scott: combo real easy That's.
Rym: you make auto chess to the game and you have another game that is literally just salty betting on the live auto chess.
Scott: Well, I think it would be like it would be sort of like The board game downforce right where you own a car, but you also bet on the cars.
Scott: Then it shows you all the other auto chesses and you play auto chess and you're.
Scott: you want your guys to win but you also bet on who's going to win.
Scott: and unlike Unlike downforce which has one race and is kind of meh Imagine if downforce is like multiple races with multiple winners and multiple bets over time.
Scott: It would you know become more interesting, you
Rym: know, this game did something amazing when You know Scott and I are pretty jaded like we've played every goddamn game Like we get you chose any game and we're like, oh, that's just a combination of and we rattle off like four obscure games.
Scott: No, now this game is now an ingredient.
Scott: It is not a combination of.
Scott: it is a combination of other ingredients, but it has now reached the level of.
Scott: it is its own Ingredients.
Rym: it it got us excited and we how many game ideas did we like just rattle off all excitedly just now?
Scott: It's like when I talk about other games, I'll be like, oh that game is just rock-paper-scissors plus Yahtzee, right?
Scott: But it's here.
Scott: I'm gonna I'm not.
Scott: I don't say.
Scott: I mean I could say auto chess is like seven wonders like poker like seven Wonders crossed with dota crossed with rummy and poker.
Scott: but it's like now.
Scott: but no But it is another game that I'll say.
Scott: that game is auto chess plus something else.
Scott: Yep, right that it's hard Just you know for your game to be an ingredient as opposed to a salad.
Rym: It's this.
Rym: it's been a while like PUBG was the last one and now this one.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Rym: cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night
Rym: and the patreon patrons for this particular episode of GeekNights are Craig Oliver Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol just like a dude guy chart a vision linky G Jennifer Hitchcock Chris midkiff my state calm.
Rym: J Bants scoot alone Lee Roberto Kingsley Shawn Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando, mr.
Rym: Strong Strachan for two one creations.
Rym: Chris Thomas primer honey My head is off to you.
Rym: Chris Thomas Reimer Han and Sherman not horror.
Rym: Rory Rochelle, Montana Superboys sailor Vista Joe Shiro Joe star Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan parent rope and lander Finn Daniel Redmond Shawn Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas on.
Rym: I bought a new microphone boom Because the previous microphone boom I bought was literally the cheapest microphone boom boom on Amazon and it Completely fell apart.
Rym: So now I am the proud owner of the second cheapest microphone boom on Amazon.
Rym: So stay tuned.
Rym: after PAX East We're gonna get a couple more panels up and then we're gonna resume judge anime bites cover and GeekNights presents utenna.
Rym: I did a little bit of pre-production.
Rym: We're gonna try to crank out the rest of those episodes.
Rym: Stay tuned, but now I leave you with Wait.
Media: why?
Media: Well, yeah, if you're in the meeting room, but what?
Media: who said she needed to have a new username?
Media: well she got married.
Media: Okay, I just had three people tell me what to do in the last three seconds.
Media: I had just hold on.
Scott: I'm telling you to do this now.
Media: We got a demo in like eight minutes.
Media: So can you get this?
Media: she's a bit a ticket for this change?
Rym: Hey Mike, yeah She got married, okay chance with and relax Shit, but it's not a process thing.
Media: So I'm gonna have to laugh.
Media: There's something going on down there.
Media: Yeah, oh that.
Media: no, listen before you do anything.
Media: I need you to get her VPN up and running.
Media: We have a presentation today.
Media: I'm trying to figure out this ticket.
Media: She's trying to change her name from Johnson to Johnson.
Media: What.
Media: You married somebody whose name was Johnson and your name is now Johnson Johnson.
Media: Why did you do that?
Media: God crazy mrs.
Media: Johnson Johnson your brats have arrived.
Media: Just sign here.
Media: Oh, it'll take ten minutes because I have to write 1,200 letters.
Scott: What's up dumbass?
Media: Hey lads, you guys got anything going on down there?
Media: I should know about because we got three boxes running like total crap.
Media: No, what do you mean?
Media: No, I mean, we don't have anything going on down here that you need to know about.
Media: Where are you?
Media: I can actually hear you.
Rym: Yeah, it's quiet, huh?
Rym: I thought you guys forgot to come into work today.
Media: You know what?
Media: Damn it.
Media: The power caps at 10%.
Media: did you guys change this?
Rym: our cap.
Media: That sound like physical air to you, you know, it's that hippie hippie Cory the night shift.
Media: hippie did this.
Rym: I bet You know what?
Rym: I just realized What.
Rym: this is not my fucking problem.
Rym: Okay, sorry been brought in stitches.
Media: Fucking data center gangster.
Media: What the fuck?