Rym: It's Wednesday, May 15th, 2019.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight fruits basket cuz it's back.
Rym: Let's do this So after like five days of hell weather, otherwise known as Seattle weather.
Rym: It's actually nice out again.
Rym: I like to work for today.
Scott: Yeah, I biked Home from work kind of because I had to go get a bike and then bike it to here.
Rym: I gotta say though your new bike looking pretty good.
Scott: Well, the other bike was all broken.
Scott: Oh, yeah And he didn't want to spend L talk about that on the show.
Rym: Oh Yeah, we talked about that.
Rym: What was broken on it?
Rym: Yeah, it's about $100 worth of unbreaking.
Scott: Yeah, we're not worth ten year old cheap bike to fix yeah, but for someone else it probably is because to them It'll be a new bike that only costs almost nothing.
Rym: Yep Meanwhile, I gotta replace the cassette the chain the rear wheel and some other stuff on my bike.
Scott: Just get the bike I have.
Scott: you can get it in white and make it look dirty like the one you have.
Rym: No, the thing is my bike is way light.
Rym: It's basically it's a. it's as close to a road bike as you can get while still having a terrible hybrid Confirmation.
Scott: I just know you should go pick up this bike.
Scott: That is actually a hundred percent made of steel and you'll be surprised really that bikes hundred percent steel.
Rym: My frame is 100% steel cuz mine the frame is aluminum.
Scott: and then yeah, aluminum is uncomfortable as fuck Yeah, but it's lighter.
Rym: Uh-huh lighter and faster.
Scott: go pick up that steel frame those fat tires.
Rym: Comfy is real comfy.
Scott: steel is also real comfy.
Rym: Yeah, my hybrid has road bike tires.
Rym: Well, the front is a road bike tire and the back is a slightly fatter tire.
Rym: because as much as I'm like pop up Up go go go.
Rym: the fatter tire on my rear butt was uh was the right one.
Scott: I have a hundred percent carbon road bike, so I don't need.
Rym: Yeah, see the problem is aluminum is way lighter and it's real strong, but it is stiff.
Rym: So and if you roll over like the tiniest little pebble that goes straight into the butt bone, yep, like boop.
Rym: Yep So yeah, guess we'll get right into it.
Scott: on anime day I feel like I had another opening bit, but I can't remember what it was right now.
Rym: You even said like oh, yeah I got some opening stuff to talk about.
Rym: I forget whatever.
Rym: All right whoop, I Didn't have any audio going to the stream because I forgot to turn on the compressor because there's an analog pipeline going there.
Rym: So now there will be audio.
Scott: Excellent, yes, sir guys.
Rym: Anyway got any news.
Scott: Do I have a news?
Scott: It's not really a news It's more of like a fat an information that was discovered and is quite fascinating, right?
Scott: So Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles the American TV show from I don't know did it start in the late 80s or was just early 90s.
Rym: I want to say it was late 80s But kid because I remember the era when I was really into TMNT exact year.
Scott: It started was definitely in that zone.
Scott: Anyway, so the very the pilot episode was like a five-part like epic kind of thing That I remember being worth watching even for an adult.
Scott: Of course, that's kid brain remembering with adult analyzation.
Scott: regardless there was an interview with one of the writers for that pilot and He said yeah, you know the usually when they would you know, all the comic was 1984.
Scott: Well, I know that yeah, but the Usually a lot of those shows from that era like a Thundercats not not Not Voltron.
Scott: Voltron in all right Voltron was originally go lion, right?
Scott: So it wasn't Voltron but you know the the ones that were clearly American shows like Thundercats and Ninja Turtles.
Scott: But they were animated by Japanese studios because they outsourced it right the animation to them.
Scott: But the writing and all the other stuff was done in the US, right?
Scott: So still an American show.
Scott: They just didn't use American animators, right?
Scott: So Ninja Turtles is one of those.
Scott: Toei animated it and usually when this happened because you know It was for TV.
Scott: It was a lot a lot of episodes.
Scott: It was for syndication the.
Scott: they wouldn't put the a-team and the Japanese studio, right?
Scott: They wouldn't have the same people who are animating like what was a really big anime like from the early 90s like utenna.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: They wouldn't have the not that that was that animated that well, well, it was animated really well considering its budget.
Scott: Yeah, but the point is they wouldn't put the people animating that who get the best animators on the American Ninja Turtle show.
Scott: They put the B team on it.
Scott: Yeah, apparently for some reason According to this interview with the writer the only the pilot episodes the five episode You know series of the Ninja Turtles cartoon was animated by the a-team at Toei and he could not remember The animators name the director of it, but he remembered that the person moved to LA In the early 2000s, they went to dinner with them and that the person directed a bunch of Sailor Moon after season.
Scott: one description only describe one infamous person Kuri.
Scott: Now I really want to go back and see how many naked cars y'all are in the first five episodes of Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles.
Rym: It's kind of like when you go back and watch the pilot of B Taz and you're like wait This just looks like anime like hundred percent.
Scott: Big O and Batman both start with B.
Rym: This is kind of crazy actually just like it's interesting.
Scott: It's like a fascinating trivia that no one knew except this one guy and now everyone who cares knows Which is almost nobody.
Rym: What's funny is I imagine this one guy is one of those situations where they're like, oh, yeah I worked with this guy once and they don't really quite Realize that.
Rym: to a limited number of people in the rest of the world The name of that person is a really goddamn big deal and no end is one nut job.
Rym: Yeah We got to watch the kappa show so we can talk about it.
Rym: Oh I watched a little bit.
Scott: Are you hold on to your butt?
Rym: Hold on to your butts literally?
Rym: Allegorically literally and literally in a different way because it's Ikuhara.
Rym: The butts are also cars and the prostate is an adolescent's metaphor and also literally the prostate.
Rym: So in some other news if you might have not noticed Pokemon detective Pikachu did come out and the initial reviews from the people I would trust.
Rym: I saw the trailer when the trailer was before Something yeah, it looked like it had a potential to be really good.
Scott: I go to the theater for the head the trailer for this Whatever I saw in the theater before us, but uh, oh I think it was one that we went to see like either Night Night on the what.
Scott: no no no no no night is long walk on girl.
Scott: one of the one of the.
Rym: I don't think it Was that it was what was the only other one we saw.
Rym: that wasn't as good I mean, we just went and saw some other anime.
Rym: You don't remember.
Rym: Well, that doesn't matter.
Rym: anyway, the trailer look good and while some people Weirdly don't like the direction that this franchise was gonna go I was really into it and our friends who like Pokemon to the appropriate level of liking Pokemon have said that it is in fact Fantastic and definitely worth watching.
Scott: I mean the trailer seemed like it wasn't one of those trailers where I went like And it wasn't like.
Scott: by the way my reaction to most trailers is yeah, and it wasn't like Sonic.
Scott: My reaction to the trailer was like huh?
Scott: I see what you did there.
Scott: Maybe I'll watch it on Netflix.
Scott: Yeah, and that's I guess still my reaction.
Rym: Like.
Rym: I don't know if I'll go bother going to see in the theater, but I will definitely see it.
Scott: to be honest I was considering going to the theater to see it during all these rainy days We had.
Scott: yeah, the main deterrent was nothing about the movie itself.
Scott: It was simply that I knew if I went to the theater, it would be full of annoying kids.
Scott: Yeah, true if I could.
Rym: that's why I feel like I'm gonna see it in the theater After like near the end of the run.
Scott: if I knew that going to the theater There would only be 30 year old nerds there who had played Pokemon in the 90s.
Scott: Then I would have just gone probably on one of those rainy days.
Rym: all I want to say I'm gonna read a quote from Wikipedia because it did.
Rym: this is why I want to see the movie quote Tim and Pikachu Interrogated mr.
Rym: Mime who directs them to an illegal underground fighting arena.
Rym: That is all.
Rym: that is the kind of sentence that I want to hear before I go see a movie like that.
Scott: I mean also I got to say the fact that forget the Pokemon part.
Scott: right.
Scott: the fact that it is a live-action Animation combination plus detective story Yeah Roger is one of the greatest movies ever feels like it's.
Scott: it's like at least 50% of this movie is just Roger rabbit homage Where the Pokemon skin on it instead.
Rym: Roger rabbit I could watch any time You could like.
Scott: they could have just taken some script from Roger rabbit to replace all the characters of the Pokemon and you wouldn't even Fucking know.
Rym: Yep, and you know what I'd be fine with that, right?
Scott: I guess it's I have not having seen the movie But I mean definitely it seems like there's too many major factors in common for it to be merely coincidence Yep.
Rym: So in another news you may have seen this and I really got it.
Rym: It's related to animation because it seems like the instigating incident was specifically the Adobe animate software.
Rym: So you might have.
Scott: I thought it's just Photoshop.
Rym: people's know those two separate things.
Rym: The people the Photoshop people are mad that the price to subscribe to just Photoshop went up.
Scott: So the lowest price was the for the photo package which includes only Lightroom and Photoshop, but nothing else.
Scott: Yeah, and what I read it could be wrong But what I read is that the price didn't actually go up.
Scott: just the storage on the default package was increased So that if you go to the website It'll say $20 a month instead of 10.
Scott: Yeah, but you could still have the option of choosing less cloud storage and still get it for the old price.
Scott: Yeah, is that true or not true?
Rym: I'm not sure because why would I?
Rym: why would anyone pay for?
Rym: Just Photoshop?
Scott: when for a little bit more money you get the entire Adobe world I still I mean a hundred, you know If you're paying for just Photoshop and Lightroom because all you do is photos you don't true?
Scott: The only reason I actually pay the 50 instead of the 20 is cuz I use Premiere.
Scott: Yeah, I never made a video.
Scott: I would pay the 20 I use because I use Lightroom the most and Photoshop the second most.
Scott: I use the third most.
Scott: I use regularly Adobe Media Encoder awesome.
Rym: I use Photoshop Lightroom Premiere After Effects InDesign Adobe PDF.
Scott: I'll use the mobile stuff in the cloud storage.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: I have an iPad Pro So there's a lot of stuff I can do there, but I did so.
Rym: yeah, there may be a misunderstanding there But this one's even funnier.
Rym: So the story going around is that Adobe is threatening to sue you.
Scott: This is a separate simultaneous story.
Rym: Yes But this is the one that's making the most rounds that people are the most mad about and people Clearly did not fucking read this article.
Rym: Yeah, any of the articles about it?
Rym: The story is Adobe's going around threatening to sue you if you run the old versions of the software.
Scott: not true?
Scott: Yeah, so one is there a Snopes?
Scott: It's like not true.
Rym: No, so here's the deal There.
Rym: this has nothing to do with.
Rym: if you licensed Pre-creative cloud software like I have a license to cs4 like production premium.
Rym: I can fucking install that on computers if I want to.
Rym: that's totally fine Mm-hmm, if you have the old software that you licensed in fact I have a bunch of audition licenses - you can just use it.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: That's the old shitty soft.
Scott: I actually have an Adobe Premiere Elements license from the early 2000s.
Rym: You know, I have the CD-ROM somewhere - Premiere Elements is the kind of thing you would punish someone with by forcing them to use it.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't make too many videos with it.
Rym: Premiere Elements was such a good thing.
Scott: It was cheap because otherwise I would regret buying unusable garbage.
Scott: It was bad.
Scott: Even when it was new I bought it when it was brand new.
Rym: that is not true.
Rym: You can continue to use your old software.
Rym: This only applies to creative cloud Adobe software and the deal is Adobe will force you to use and has for a long time Either the current version of whatever software like.
Rym: if you're on Photoshop You can either have the current version running or the previous version running.
Scott: Yeah, a lot of times for like when Adobe releases new creative cloud versions.
Scott: sometimes when I open up creative cloud It's just like yeah updating Lightroom now, but sometimes it'll be like Lightroom CC 2018 and guess what?
Scott: Here's Lightroom CC 2019 with an install button next to it And your options are either.
Scott: Right, so you can switch but 2017 will be gone, right?
Scott: And then you install 2019 and switch over eventually at some point and then at some point 2018 goes away and the 2020 shows up.
Scott: and you know Sometimes they do it like that to where you could because it's such a big upgrade.
Scott: you switch on your own Yeah, and sometimes it just updates like Chrome updates.
Scott: You don't even notice.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So that's fine like that's really reasonable and that's what I would expect.
Rym: a Bunch of people who for probably dumb reasons want to use Really old versions of creative cloud software have been like not letting the software update.
Rym: So they're various means.
Scott: Right, so they're paying the monthly cost, but they're just using like but they're never clicking the update button.
Scott: They're just keeping the version that they have of whatever it is and never clicking on the free update that they're paying for.
Scott: Not only Neglecting to get new features, right?
Scott: They're all.
Scott: I mean.
Scott: They're probably mostly concerned about the user interface changing which it will probably.
Scott: yeah, right and think other things like that.
Scott: But they're also neglecting to get new features and neglecting to get new bug fixes and neglecting to get new Security updates that they are paying for and would get effectively for free just by clicking Okay,
Rym: because
Scott: I guess most of my assumption is they don't want the user interface to change slightly in some way and I've learned something.
Rym: So Yes, they're not like changing the things that everyone thinks they're changing and - they're not threatening to sue anyone for using the old Versions.
Rym: they're.
Rym: all they did is send an email out saying look you're using like animate 15 Which is from like 2015.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So anime now is not like version 19.
Rym: So these are people.
Scott: so animate used to be flash by the way.
Rym: Yes, so and these people are using animate 15 or animate 16 from a long-ass time ago and Dolby is apparently suing Adobe because of some licensing issue where Dolby thinks Adobe isn't paying their fair share.
Rym: So Adobe in response one just remove that shit from newer versions of their software.
Rym: So it won't be a problem Yeah, and two they warned all the people using this old software refusing to update that.
Rym: yo Technically Adobe could sue you for using this software because of a licensing dispute.
Rym: You should upgrade to the current version of animate.
Rym: We will help you do it.
Rym: It's free.
Scott: Just click.
Scott: Okay It's young sitting there in your system tray yelling at you probably for four years and you just never clicked.
Scott: Okay, or you turn it off somehow.
Rym: Yeah, but even the bottom is like if you have any difficulties Adobe's customer support is here to answer.
Scott: you're paying for it.
Scott: It's like people hate the subscription service.
Scott: that deal right?
Scott: But look you get what you pay for if you pay 50 bucks a month.
Scott: You get real customer service.
Scott: you get free.
Scott: you get all this shit when you pay that that you don't get when you pay a flat thousand dollars.
Rym: So the story of Adobe is threatening to sue me for using my old software that I paid for is complete bullshit.
Rym: The actual story is a handful of specific Adobe applications Put you in danger of being sued by Dolby Unless you upgrade to a version that doesn't have this problem and Adobe is bending over backwards to help you do this.
Rym: So you don't get fucked.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: It's not even every creative cloud software.
Scott: Yeah, so I mean this just goes back to the point.
Scott: I mean assuming that the people are mad because they don't want user interface changes, which one is dumb, too.
Rym: Those people did not even read this email, right?
Scott: But the thing is it just goes back to the point I always make and that for some reason a lot of people Would rather do immense amounts of work and labor than learn.
Rym: You know hard it would be to be for me to prevent audition from updating as opposed to just using it when it updates.
Scott: It's like people would rather copy and paste something a hundred times then learn a regular expression, right people would.
Rym: They say about regular expression.
Scott: I know people would rather create no JS than have to learn a different language other than JavaScript, right people would rather Do tons and tons of work to make sure this old ass Photoshop keeps running on their new computer.
Scott: Then just learn the user interface changes or shortcut changes in the newer better vastly superior Photoshop with this new features.
Scott: Alright, it's like I see this happen over and over and over again.
Scott: people just for some reason.
Scott: the human brain and a lot Of people not all people cuz not me It's just so averse to like education and learning.
Scott: it just doesn't want to have to learn it.
Scott: it just views Learning even the smallest thing.
Scott: I don't want to learn how to switch gears on my bike.
Scott: I'd rather stomp on this heavy gear all the way up the hill, right?
Scott: Why is some human brains so averse to learning that they measure?
Scott: somehow the effort of learning even a small thing or putting any thought into something as greater than This immense amount of labor?
Scott: how this happened?
Rym: one of the issues that play might be that Newer versions of software don't work that well on Windows 7 and these are the same.
Rym: people are still running Windows 7.
Rym: I well, which again same problem.
Scott: I think Microsoft does still support Windows 7 to some degree.
Rym: It's not dead Yeah, but no one else does.
Rym: Windows 7 don't run Windows 7.
Rym: Of course, it's 2019.
Rym: Of course now Windows 7 is ancient.
Scott: Well, I'd be better to run Windows 7 than in those eight.
Rym: Yeah, Windows 8 was a mistake.
Scott: we all agree just like Windows seems to get it wrong.
Scott: every other deal right Windows 98 Windows me Windows 2000.
Scott: I guess Windows XP was okay.
Rym: Okay, when I was 2000, I remember when it was 2000 came out.
Scott: I thought it was Windows Vista and then it was Good after that.
Scott: I went out.
Rym: I remember hot windows 2000 because it was that good.
Rym: I was like, I'm fucking buying this new operating system.
Rym: Yeah, cuz I was previously running Windows 95.
Rym: Yeah, I didn't even have 98.
Scott: I think I bought Vista ultimate which wasn't as bad as they said.
Scott: Yeah, it wasn't.
Scott: it wasn't me or eight bad.
Rym: But guys Windows 10 is great.
Scott: Fine You just gotta remove all the garbage which is still removable.
Scott: Yeah, if it wasn't removable.
Scott: I wouldn't use Windows 10.
Rym: Yeah, but what would you use Linux on the desktop?
Scott: I have the WSL to which we talked about on Monday.
Rym: Yeah, but then how you gonna play any game?
Rym: Oh man.
Rym: Anyway, anyway, it's time for Things of the day.
Rym: So you probably saw some art on Twitter a while ago.
Rym: That was like Creepypasta or like horror interpretations of Garfield.
Scott: I've seen lots and lots of remixes of Garfield and it's I just still continue to find it fascinating that Garfield is like in this weird unique space separate from all other like.
Scott: there's nothing else like it.
Scott: where it is it is Some people.
Scott: it is reviled.
Scott: It's unfunny, but it is funny, but it's funny in this When it's remixed, it's like this amazing like masterpiece of art like Garfield.
Rym: without Garfield abstract.
Rym: It's your field without our.
Rym: Garfield is like a height of comic art.
Scott: You know, it's Dali.
Scott: It's Picasso.
Scott: it's like everything at once.
Rym: and You know, it's our field is like this perfect deconstruction of late capitalism.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It's just so much going on with Garfield that is not going on with literally any other comic ever.
Scott: So what I'm gonna link you to like I swear to God one day We're gonna go to like the Met and there's gonna be Garfield just on the wall and we're gonna be like, yep And kids will be like what the hell is that?
Scott: and they'll be look at it the way we look at like Van Gogh or something.
Rym: Yup, so what I'm gonna link to you is probably the height of the expression of the remixing of Garfield that exists today And it is a.
Scott: I didn't see this before just now but I can see how elaborate this is.
Rym: This is a YouTube video that takes all this concept art of like.
Rym: what if Garfield was a horror?
Rym: adventure game like five nights at Freddy's and or a horror movie like alien one and It turns it into a fake video game that is 13 minutes long.
Scott: that was that is on the Gameboy But the Gameboy has a 16 by 9 screen and shows more colors than just green but has the same range of colors.
Rym: I cannot express what the fuck cuz normal works for the government.
Rym: Arlene is being held captive in the basement.
Rym: Okay, like keep your scent level that this is some.
Rym: this is fucking amazing.
Rym: This is So much like what any image from this YouTube video by itself would be like.
Rym: enough for me.
Rym: this I cannot.
Rym: this is up my alley.
Scott: who made this and one touch 1.5 million views.
Scott: How is it?
Scott: Not Neil Siseraig?
Rym: This is very.
Rym: this is the.
Rym: this is similar creative expression to Neil Siseraig.
Scott: I don't think he's.
Scott: Neil is like a great pixel art artist.
Rym: those know Neil is.
Scott: Neil has a Neil my son but he could but I would believe it if you told me.
Scott: he wrote this.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I would say I would believe it if someone said that we looked at Neil Siseraig his brain and he has the largest fusiform Gyrus anyone has ever found.
Scott: the point is a lumpy touch.
Scott: you are.
Scott: if you can do one more great thing You will be elevated to an internet legend.
Rym: Yeah, this is too good.
Scott: Maybe they will be.
Scott: touch has done something else great We don't know about.
Rym: let me judge has got only lumpy touch only has a hundred and forty four thousand subscribers on YouTube.
Rym: That's a lot but it's also a travesty.
Scott: That's quite a lot.
Scott: I'm gonna subscribe to lumpy touch.
Rym: Oh my god, like the first comment here is okay Honestly, when I saw this I thought you actually made a game I would play.
Scott: I'd hire them to do the art for my game, dude I would hire them to make this into a game anyway.
Rym: Anyway, what do you got?
Scott: So here is a gentleman from the fine state of Tennessee.
Rym: sounds like he's from Tennessee.
Scott: If you don't know anybody if you don't know anything about the United States, Tennessee is not a fine state.
Scott: But well, Tennessee is kind of it's not the worst state.
Scott: like Nashville is actually on the up.
Rym: Yeah So like Alabama is probably Alabama and Mississippi are tied for the worst state because Mississippi sucks But Alabama just passed like just banned abortion like just now.
Scott: Yeah Georgia's trying Georgia.
Rym: Georgia's bad pretty much.
Scott: if you you go to Florida right and you go to the bottom of the Florida and you go up and up and up and up and things get dark and About halfway through Florida then they get basically pitch black at the top of Florida right when you get to the northernmost part of Florida and then you just go north to the top of Georgia and West and draw a Big ol rectangle and that's like the place you don't want to go.
Rym: weirdly though of all things South Carolina is doing better than North Carolina on a lot of things which is weird.
Scott: that is weird.
Scott: South Carolina has been way worse than North Carolina has been.
Rym: North Carolina's politics are way more corrupt and fucked up.
Rym: Anyway, anyway, Tennessee is like one of those states.
Rym: It's got a lot of good going on and a lot of bad.
Scott: all the good happens to be is mostly going on in Nashville, yeah, which is like super a-plus upswing.
Scott: also, I mean, it's not all positive.
Scott: It's a lot of gentrification going on there also bachelor parties.
Scott: Yeah, but Nashville is pretty great Relatively speaking as far as American cities go but rest of Tennessee, yeah, and here's it fine gentleman from Tennessee.
Scott: and This gentleman needed some work done on the tires on his vehicle because it's a place where you have to drive.
Scott: Yeah, I tend to see of course and you know, he finds out a place that's offering a free tire.
Rym: So he calls, you know Todd discount tire I've been a discount tire and I've gotten a free tire from them.
Scott: calls him up and you know He says yeah, you know, so it's.
Scott: I guess it must be some kind of deal.
Scott: We're like buy three get one or something like that, you know Yeah, and he calls him and he says and they tell him like yeah, we're next to a Taco Bell We're on this road.
Scott: So he goes he drives down the road he goes, you know, he finds finds the tire place and something happens there at the tire place next to the Taco Bell and This is this very fine vertical video with his phone Explaining the hullabaloo that happens at the discount tire next to the Taco Bell.
Rym: Yep, the discount tire next to the Taco Bell This is this is pretty good.
Scott: This is this is a plus video.
Rym: What really helps.
Rym: is that his delit?
Rym: he sounds like a stand-up comedian like his delivery of Just his explanation of this situation.
Scott: He's definitely using stand-up comedian voice.
Scott: Yeah, it's like a Seinfeld voice like The Tennessee accent.
Rym: Can you explain to me sir y x and y?
Rym: anyway In the meta moment GeekNights is a podcast and we do a bunch of stuff.
Rym: if you go to our website You can find out things like did you know we're doing a book club in the book club?
Rym: We're reading the most painful book we have ever read pages of pain.
Scott: I just read some painful pages.
Rym: I just I just met carfudd.
Scott: I Just the demon I was.
Scott: I just read a whole chapter about limbs getting chopped off flying every which way.
Rym: Yeah, then I forgot how many attached and reattached.
Rym: Ah, yeah the reattachment.
Rym: I remember that explicitly.
Scott: That's some fucked up biz.
Rym: the reattachment area is where this book the.
Rym: what I can say is that it's really going on.
Scott: It was already off the rails now.
Scott: It's like you can't even see the rails anymore.
Rym: I think you can see though cuz I remember the thing that I remembered about this book the most is that most like Dungeons & Dragons branded novels are just here is a Dungeons & Dragons kind of story.
Scott: Now it's talking now about like exploding pustules and everyone's body and I'm like, whoa that hasn't been mentioned since chapter one.
Rym: Yep, so you take a typical shitty like Star Wars book and it's like a then B then C then D. This is a nerd fantasy book.
Rym: That's kind of badly written.
Rym: This book starts as like yeah typical fantasy book.
Rym: a then B Then trippy shit then off the rails then it's just allegory.
Rym: What even happened?
Rym: That is why I remember this book being different from all the other Dungeons & Dragons books because it turns into some surreal Nonsense at the end.
Scott: his or it has been nonsense for a while.
Scott: It's just even more nonsense.
Rym: I want to see this made into a movie.
Scott: I don't think you could.
Rym: It's kind of like trying to make a culture book into a movie.
Rym: you read the beginning.
Scott: You're like.
Scott: I can make a culture book in a movie as long as I pick the right one player of games and maybe Consider Phlebas are the only ones that could.
Scott: you could even be the only ones.
Scott: I've read any portion of those are the only ones where anyone Consider Phlebas you can have a sexy pirate and then you can make an angry earth Trilogy of movies with the same actor doing the sexy pirate Scott.
Rym: if you if you ever read use of weapons or surface detail.
Rym: if You can't make a movie out of those you know who might be able to or might have been able to come out like Dune Movie Jodorowsky is the only one who could have made a movie like that.
Rym: Yeah, anyway.
Rym: also gig nights has officially endorsed in the Democratic primary Elizabeth Warren.
Rym: okay?
Rym: Cuz she's the only one who has a plan.
Rym: Also because times are dire right now I just want to remind you because a Bunch of people are talking about how there is evidence that if an online community has an explicit Upfront like rules of engagement and terms like here is how you should use our community.
Rym: These are the rules.
Rym: people actually do behave better and the gig nights forum has very good Rules about how our community functions and the rules basically boil down to no fucking Nazis Full stop.
Rym: you cannot be a Nazi here, so if you want a Nazi free online social community That's chill.
Rym: the gig nights forum is there and you should join it.
Rym: so Fruits basket I gotta take you back to when I ran the RIT anime club from around 2001 to around 2005 because when we were at the RIT anime club an Anime came out.
Rym: there was an adaptation of a manga and that anime was called fruits basket.
Scott: So I knew first basket at the time was a a shoujo manga.
Scott: yep B was ridiculously popular.
Rym: like like who.
Scott: it is actually it.
Scott: from what I heard It was like one of the best-selling bongos.
Scott: Maybe the best-selling manga at least at some point, maybe still that in the u.s.. Ever.
Scott: You look that up.
Scott: I guess.
Scott: and the anime Adaptation of it.
Scott: I knew at the time was somehow flawed or something.
Scott: now I have learned a little bit more information about it And that is yes the fruits basket manga is still.
Scott: you know that what it was?
Rym: It was like a late 90s to early 2000s manga right and the way exactly people were mad about with the original Anime, which I never watched even one episode of me either.
Scott: I never watched the anime any art of the anime or read any of the manga.
Scott: all I knew about the story was it involves some Girl and some zodiac stuff, and it was so popular.
Rym: Well also I knew that there's non-threatening boys who turn into animals if they get hugged.
Scott: I didn't know that.
Scott: I knew that till just now and I had to.
Scott: often it's all just now when I watch it.
Rym: I had to know enough about it because running RIT anime.
Rym: I had like Say like if the punch line to a joke was fruits basket something something The anime club would lose their shit because it was so popular anyway.
Scott: So what was wrong with the original anime from what I've heard from people is that it ended too soon And did not cover the full like it was faithful to the manga up to a point Yep, and then I guess they got ahead of things or something you know and they had to end it too soon.
Scott: but not only.
Rym: Manga ran from 98 to 2006 and that anime ran from 2001 to 2001. right the not only anime end too soon and not cover everything
Scott: But also because the anime itself had to have an ending when they wrapped it up or whatever They changed something in the story that was significant involving certain characters Such that even if they did pick up with more seasons It would have been literally impossible for them to continue with the manga's plot because they diverted.
Scott: They basically took like a 90-degree turn at some point right.
Scott: so that was that.
Rym: that's something I didn't know because that's what I have been told.
Scott: so fruits basket got a new anime that this season literally Just now they made a new fruits basket anime, I assume for some anniversary of fruits basket.
Scott: It is a remastering re HD remake of the old anime.
Scott: only it is supposedly going to stick to the manga and Possibly go through the entire plot of the manga all the way to the end.
Scott: Maybe yep Which they could cancel at any time right, but who knows yeah?
Rym: But that's interesting because having not known about that swerve and having not realized how long fruits basket was The what I'd heard so far is that the new anime is just the old anime like Exactly
Scott: well because the old anime up to the point that we've seen I've seen I think three or four episodes maybe four because that was all that was on when I watched.
Scott: that was all that was out when I watched.
Scott: it is Basically the.
Scott: we didn't hit the sort of point yet Yep.
Scott: So the new anime is the old anime because the old anime was the manga.
Scott: the new anime is also the manga and the old And we're not at the point with the old anime swerves.
Scott: so at this only few episodes in All of them are identical.
Scott: the new one is just obviously 16 by 9 and better drawn.
Rym: So what I don't understand based on what I've watched so far.
Rym: I mean there's only one like No.
Rym: What I don't understand is why is it called fruits basket?
Rym: at what point is there a fruit?
Rym: at what point is there a basket?
Scott: I as the same thing cuz I like fruits, and I'm okay with baskets Especially if they're cornucopias, I love cornucopias, but I don't know if that counts as a basket.
Scott: really.
Scott: It doesn't have a handle doesn't need a handle to be a basket.
Scott: Anyway, I love fruit.
Scott: Yeah, there's no fruits or baskets whatsoever anywhere.
Scott: fruit I don't even know if it's like an analogy or a metaphor for something.
Rym: I don't think it is.
Rym: I think you just gave it a fucking random name.
Scott: I think it was just a cool sounding English name.
Scott: That's what it is.
Rym: What's it about?
Rym: so it is about A girl and I thought so before I watch this.
Rym: all I knew is it's about a girl who is homeless and going to school.
Scott: I didn't know that till I watched it.
Rym: living in a tent Accidentally meets a bunch of non-threatening boys who turn into zodiac animals if she hugs them if anyone Them.
Rym: that kind of is the plot.
Scott: Yes that literally is the plot.
Rym: yep, so this girl basically like family circumstances.
Rym: Cuz her mom died and she's living with grandpa and grandma because basically her family died.
Scott: in some it was accident car accident or something.
Rym: So dad died of like an illness and then mom raised her on her own.
Rym: get the impression mom Meant well and was a good person, but was not educated and might have been a delinquent.
Rym: Maybe I don't know, but anyway mom dies has to live with grandpa.
Scott: grandpa at the funeral They decide who's gonna take her.
Scott: grandpa's pretty something that happens in bunny drop Yeah, where they decide who's gonna take which you know the family gets together and decides who's gonna take the orphaned child.
Rym: Yeah, grandpa like has to leave his house cuz some renovations are going on.
Rym: She made a vow to like take care of herself right.
Scott: so grandpa Grandpa's like hey, I'm renovating the house.
Scott: We're living in.
Scott: Can you like go find a friend to live with?
Scott: you know I have to go live in a tiny place.
Scott: I can't afford a big place right, but I own the house.
Scott: so once the renovations are done We can move back.
Scott: so she doesn't find a friend to go live with.
Rym: she just lives in a tent in the woods Yep, and somehow makes it work kind of well She's only been living in the tent a little while yeah, then a landslide immediately destroys the tent.
Rym: yep Cuz she's just like she doesn't know what she's doing.
Rym: no So she ends up accidentally moving.
Rym: is pretty good considering the landslide But I know we got fancy tents like I could live out of that tent Though that's cool.
Rym: I assume I guess so.
Scott: uh she accidentally moves in with all these boys and discovers Unbeknownst to her the land she put the tent on belongs to this family and So she encounters them in the woods, and they're like what is that person doing in our woods?
Rym: She's like.
Rym: I live nearby.
Rym: one of them like like.
Scott: we own all these woods, and there's no houses in it right.
Rym: They're like what she's like.
Scott: one of them is a classmate and knows who she is and he's the hot boy in school.
Scott: Yeah So that sort of like.
Scott: you know that Connection there and they end up being nice and saying we live in this giant old Style Japanese house that has sliding doors like a samurai lives here because we're an ancient mystical family.
Scott: Yeah Why don't you come live with us?
Scott: and then that's the setup and then not too much happens after that in the episodes I've seen.
Rym: yep, so the one thing I will say I'll say the things that I like about the show before we get into how.
Rym: I don't really think I need to watch any more Of it is that one the truth the secret.
Rym: she figures it out instantly.
Scott: That's good.
Rym: And there's like oh shit.
Rym: I guess she knows they're all magical.
Rym: well You keep our secret cool.
Rym: like all the magic stuff just starts happening immediately right?
Scott: well This is hosted is?
Scott: it's a lot like.
Scott: utana has the story of like.
Scott: you know the prince and um what's it called?
Scott: What the duels you know princess tutu.
Scott: Oh, yeah, princess tutu also has like a fantasy a fairy tale that sort of you know.
Rym: But I like it when a show is like right away like okay everything's set up.
Rym: now the plots gonna.
Scott: Basket has the fairy tale story of why is the cat not a member of the zodiac?
Rym: no true?
Rym: Yeah, that's the.
Rym: that's the long-term mystery right.
Scott: and there's the one character who transforms into a cat a really angry, dude.
Scott: Yeah, right who's sort of like.
Scott: he's in the family, but he's not.
Scott: he's like You know he's like not part of the zodiac, but he still transforms into a cat if he's hugged and it's the conflict between him and The rest of the family.
Scott: well him and the rest of the family mostly the rat guy mostly the rat main guy.
Scott: Right who is right?
Scott: and then the girls.
Scott: you have this triangle situation going on right?
Scott: Because the girl I likes the main guy more not the super annoying cat guy
Rym: But she wants my friends with a cat right,
Scott: but fairy tale wise she's all about the cat right And she has some sort of connection to the cat in the terms of the fairy tale, but these two people who are somehow cursed You know it seems like they're backwards.
Scott: which animal is which?
Scott: so I guess there's some tension.
Scott: of which one is she gonna end up With?
Scott: if any are they gay here?
Scott: they're gonna get with each other right.
Rym: there's a lot to chew on for the fanfic writers Yep, so The other thing I appreciate is that once it once you learn character knows many ships will say if you hug what?
Rym: if a Member of the quote opposite sex hugs any of these boys they instantly turn in.
Scott: So there are girls in the family, and if they get hugged by boy by men presumably They would turn into the animal that they are from.
Scott: yep, and we've only we're only a few episodes in.
Rym: we've only met A few characters like the dog the rat the cat.
Scott: so we know there's a whole zodiac which has how many animals?
Scott: 12.
Scott: Yeah, there's gonna be way more characters in this family.
Scott: Who's the dragon to accommodate all the you know?
Scott: I think that the mysterious one who is behind you don't see them.
Scott: Yeah, it was like behind a sheet or something behind a door.
Scott: They're like oh we have to go consult the person for fit for rulings right and there's like a head member of the family And they talk to them like through a door.
Scott: you hear the voice, but you don't see the character And then you know they're like giving out the orders.
Scott: I presume that that's the dragon head of family person and they can't disobey them.
Rym: yep But what I appreciate is that once she learns she can do this.
Rym: they get transformed constantly Like she'd like she even does it on purpose to stop a fight like I like it when a current character Discovers a magic thing and just uses it all the time whenever it's practical.
Scott: Yeah, there's a little bit of the Superman thing going on because they're trying to hide it at school and the boy got a bad Reputation at school cuz girls asked him out, and then he wouldn't let them hug him.
Scott: He would like run away, and it's not because he is a jerk It's just cuz he couldn't be hugged.
Scott: cuz they find out they did try to hide it right like Superman Trying to hide with a secret identity.
Scott: and sometimes You know there's that tension of.
Scott: is it gonna get leaked?
Scott: and there's a few times they had to transform at school because they got hugged and By some luck sometimes unbelievable luck nobody saw or whatever Right.
Rym: so so here's the problems with the show.
Scott: see if that gets that gets out.
Rym: the problem with the show is That it is not the year 2001 and it is in fact the year 2019 Because if this was a fruit fast again never existed before and this anime just came out.
Rym: What I would say about it is this is the most generic like Basic ass trope shoujo with non-threatening boys the world has ever seen.
Rym: it is just take Generic Jojo tropes like the mysterious like everything stick them all together into a show and just follow the formula.
Rym: So far at least yeah so far at least.
Scott: I heard from people that later in the show it gets dark.
Rym: Yeah It's definitely something at dark secrets in the family because the show is not like.
Scott: it's not one of those cases.
Scott: We're like it's bad.
Scott: wait till it's good gets good.
Scott: Yeah, it's sort of like it's I and it supposedly gets real good.
Scott: It's like maybe if I you know like it's not off the queue now.
Rym: I would watch more.
Rym: I enjoy watching.
Scott: I'm not gonna run out to watch it But I'm also not gonna run away from it because I'm not as curious as I am about fancy lala's dinosaurs.
Scott: Yeah, it's like right under that.
Scott: in terms of curiosity about what the darkness is.
Rym: That's a good place to put it like.
Rym: I do want to know more about the deal and I do like the characters But it is just so Definitely more interesting than the characters and a lot of other anime where I don't care about them at all.
Scott: Yep, and I imagine as I do care about like the drama of the the cat guy.
Scott: Yeah, getting living in not being in the family.
Rym: I hope but I also I like the two delinquent girls.
Scott: She's friends with and I also do The serial killer.
Scott: Those are the best characters.
Scott: Yeah, right side characters always the best.
Scott: the like dark knife wielding one I like no question the best like you could watch the show just for them.
Scott: She has two friends at school And we're like these super powered awesome like outcast I guess they would be if it was an American show.
Scott: they would be like two goth girls or something.
Scott: Yeah, but they're in Japanese school.
Scott: So they're all wearing uniforms.
Scott: But yeah, they're.
Scott: they're like dark serious powerful.
Scott: They get picked on but then they get revenge and the mean popular girls run away.
Rym: Yeah, the mean popular girls are literally just in the Nami squad like straight up.
Scott: Yes, they are clearly.
Scott: You could just putting it on me right in there.
Rym: But yeah, like.
Rym: I think I might watch some more episodes.
Rym: not kind.
Rym: I might just like watch it at some point Like it's a good show.
Rym: I might watch as a secondary show like whenever I'm bored.
Scott: Yeah, I think what it comes down to really is is how far is it gonna go if it's gonna cover?
Rym: 23 volumes of manga that ran from 1998 to 2006, right?
Scott: That makes me a more likely to watch because I know I'll get the whole deal But also I know it ends but also less likely to watch because there's so many episodes.
Rym: It depends on If it cuts short.
Scott: Then I'm more likely to watch because less episodes but less likely to watch because so as you got this sort of thing going on?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Yeah, it's tricky there because I've generally been not watching things like Game of Thrones.
Rym: I probably won't even watch any more of until it's done done.
Scott: I never watched any Game of Thrones and it probably never will.
Rym: I really liked the first season like.
Rym: it was really good Really good And then the end of the first season killed the only character one of the only characters I liked and then season two was Which one?
Rym: It's it's kind of surprising.
Rym: who dies actually, okay the main guy basically Yeah, it's like up making magic comic evap.
Rym: episode four spikes dead and then episode fives.
Rym: Yeah, but it is more characters though, but then episode five is just like the rest.
Scott: It's basically a really good way to run a TV show cuz.
Scott: then yeah, you can just like, you know Get rid of actors get new ones, you know, they're constantly going in and out.
Scott: You don't have to give someone like a big long ass contract.
Scott: Yeah, you'd like soap opera situation, right?
Scott: So, I mean that's a great story for TV But not for a movie where you have to pay the fancy actor a zillion dollars and they're in the movie for ten minutes.
Rym: Yep, but I jet like especially like I would not have even read the first book of the wheel of time if it hadn't been done For a long time that's true, so I wouldn't have picked it if it hadn't been done.
Rym: Yeah So the fact that the manga is done gives me hope that this might be a show I watch.
Rym: it depends on how Many episodes it will take to tell that story.
Rym: and is that story thick and meaty enough to where all those Episodes will be worth watching.
Scott: Yeah, it also depends.
Scott: I'm gonna try to find out how many episodes it takes to get to the dark stuff.
Scott: if it's a long number of episodes Then I might not go.
Scott: it's fine.
Scott: If it starts getting dark and like episode 15 or less I might be like, ooh, yep But if it's gonna be 20 more episodes of just the school drama and the house drama No, maybe there's a way to like summarize that and skip.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So yeah It's a serviceable show and now that we know the story of like why the old Anime needed to be remade and they couldn't just like continue it it does make sense that the show is being remade and it is definitely like a very direct look at Late 90s early 2000s shoujo fandom.
Scott: Yeah, if you are a fruits basket fan You're probably gonna say we're wrong about a bunch of stuff.
Scott: But also, oh, yeah probably excited about fruits basket and I imagine you haven't read it or watched it in quite a while.
Scott: Now you can go back into it.
Scott: good.
Scott: This is great for you Yeah, and if you're not a fruits basket fan, you never read it or watch it.
Scott: It was a significant thing.
Scott: This is your chance to see what the deal was.
Scott: You can watch some number of episodes even if you don't watch all the episodes.
Rym: Yep This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Rym: Geeknights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Craig Oliver, I'll enjoy Saturday McNichol just like a dude guy.
Rym: Jartavish and Linky G Jennifer Hitchcock Chris mid give my state e.com.
Rym: Jay bench scooter lonely Roberto Kingsley Shawn Yeager Nicholas Branham is strong stretch in 4 to 1 creations and there may be other secret names.
Rym: You do not even know.
Rym: Shervin von Horrell Rory Rochelle, Monta Nona super boys Taylor Vista Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin Drew open Lander Finn dread Lily Tenebrae Sean Klein Chris Reimer Thomas Hahn.
Rym: and now I leave you with something.
Rym: It is I author son of also pen dragon from the castle of Camelot king of the Britain defeater of the Saxons sovereign of all England Pull the other one.
Rym: I am and this is my trusty servant Patsy.
Rym: We have ridden the lengths and breadth of the land in search of Knights who will join me in my court at Camelot.
Scott: I must speak with your lord and master.
Scott: What ridden on a horse?
Rym: Yes, you're using coconuts.
Rym: what you've got?
Rym: two empty arms of coconut and you're banging them together.
Scott: So we have ridden since the snows of winter cover this land through the kingdom of mercy.
Rym: After why'd you get the coconuts?
Rym: We found them found them in Mercier the coconuts tropical.
Rym: What do you mean?
Rym: Well, this is a temperate zone.
Rym: The swallow may fly south with the Sun or the house Martin or the plover may seek warmer climes in winter.
Scott: Yet these are not strangers to our land.
Scott: Are you suggesting coconuts migrate?
Scott: not at all?
Rym: They could be carried.
Rym: what a swallow carrying a coconut.