Rym: It's Wednesday October 16th 2019.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: It's the great pumpkin Charlie Brown.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: Talk about a blast from the past.
Scott: play the GeekNights' theme with a piano.
Rym: So fun fact.
Rym: The first CD like compact disc I ever bought whoa Ever even had because I remember this day.
Rym: This was like a big day.
Rym: this will tell you how old I am.
Rym: it's I'm cuz.
Rym: this is not relevant really to the main bit.
Rym: good, but it's adjacent, so We are the family.
Rym: one day like my parents were like we're going to go buy a compact Disc player to put into the hi-fi system.
Rym: Holy shit were we excited.
Rym: so we got this.
Scott: the main feature at the time by the way was Yeah, audio quality.
Scott: Yeah, whatever.
Scott: the main feature was the ability to play any song you wanted.
Scott: Yeah, just by choosing it.
Scott: not having to rewind fast-forward not having to guess with the needle not having to have a very Very expensive turntable to that.
Scott: would a song to replay a song.
Rym: We had a turntable that would actually you could tell it to advance tracks.
Rym: I would lift up figure out where the next track was and try to find it.
Scott: Yeah, the laser can yeah Yeah, so I'm not as good as a CD.
Rym: so we went and we got this giant Rackmount CD player.
Scott: was it a CD changer or just one?
Scott: see one CD.
Rym: This is a long time ago that we put into the hi-fi system along with all the other things.
Scott: He looks like an HD PC with a CD-ROM.
Rym: Yeah, it looks like that giant compressor up there.
Rym: Yeah, so for the CD-ROM in it.
Rym: so uh and each of us got to buy one Compact disc.
Rym: my mom my dad my brother and me is meatloaf.
Rym: No, I did not choose meatloaf because my dad bought a meatloaf.
Rym: Okay good I bought a collection of Vince Guaraldi piano music.
Scott: Okay, the peanuts music.
Rym: There you go.
Rym: The second CD I ever bought was a Michael Jackson CD.
Scott: The third one I ever bought was mental Metallica and justice for all there is no first CD that I bought because as soon as I had the ability to play CDs and Get money and buy my own stuff, right?
Rym: Didn't you do the six CDs?
Scott: I went to Columbia house 10 CDs.
Rym: My dad was like, yeah, it's kind of a scam.
Scott: it actually was not a scam.
Scott: I worked out the math super hard on it before during and constantly because I was like cancel anytime, right?
Scott: So I was always constantly working on the math and basically the way it worked.
Scott: Is it in order to maintain membership you had to buy a certain amount, right?
Scott: And they would charge you like 20 bucks for a CD which was slightly more than like 17 or 18.
Scott: You'd buy it like FYE in the mall, right?
Scott: But every you know, first of all, you got the 10 at the beginning.
Scott: you to pay nothing for right?
Scott: So you're amortizing those right and then every once in a while when they sent you your monthly, you know envelope There'd be a little piece of paper in there.
Scott: They'd be like hey write a CD code on this and we'll send you a free CD.
Scott: and I got so many just like free CDs the number that I had.
Scott: I basically had to buy Like six CDs a year for 120 bucks something like that, right?
Rym: Which was back then actually not like.
Rym: that's what CDs cost.
Scott: and then you got the ten CDs at the beginning and you got Maybe three to four more free a year.
Rym: now what I did to make money on the side is I Would take CDs that I had access to and because we had this really expensive high-fi system with like dubbing bits and like multi Tape copy.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, I would make tapes and sell them Right.
Scott: The other thing is that the the seek the real secret of Columbia house back in the day the 90s was box sets Box sets at the mall.
Rym: Oh, yeah, like a zeppelin box set, right?
Scott: Well, gee, well specifically if you went to that that box set Circles on it right.
Scott: if you bought that shit at the mall like every other kid It was like 120 bucks - I was it was exactly 120 dollars.
Scott: I remember wanting it desperately.
Scott: Yeah, Columbia house the box sets were like just dirt as cheap.
Scott: I think I got that thing for like $30.
Rym: The worst part was that box set cost the same as record of lotus war when it came out on DVD Mm-hmm, and uh, you mean the first DVD of record of Not all of record Actually the box set.
Rym: Yeah Okay, but that was way later.
Rym: Anyway, so I have been scrawly, but actually I'm a big fan of that music independent of peanuts.
Scott: Yeah It's like people think it's the peanuts music but no.
Scott: Yeah, there's other music.
Scott: Yeah, that all sounds like that.
Rym: Yeah, it was a band for real normal band.
Rym: Anyway Also, it's raining and the powers rain a lot.
Rym: Yeah, the power is supposed to go out in my building today for like five minutes.
Rym: So like this morning I was like, oh shit, so I actually like power down the NAS cuz I got a UPS.
Rym: I'm good I don't have a UPS cuz the power has never gone out ever in a decade.
Scott: It's still good to have UPS.
Rym: No, fuck it I'm not gonna waste money and time on that.
Rym: my old UPS the Atlanta has the battery died and I just said fuck it I threw it away.
Scott: Yeah, I got that old UPS I did get rid of but I got a newer one.
Scott: that's been super great for many years.
Rym: Yeah, but I've literally never had a power outage.
Scott: It's it's.
Scott: I think it's activated twice in all the time I've had it.
Rym: So, uh, yeah The power is supposed to go out today for five minutes cuz I guess the building's getting smart readers Will have no impact on my life in any way, but it did not in fact happen because the kitchen is not blinking 12.
Rym: So now I'm worried.
Rym: today was the last day they could do it.
Rym: So either they're gonna do it while we're recording GeekNights Or they're not gonna do.
Scott: it only had a UPS.
Scott: We could record units for five minutes while the power is out.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, I don't think a UPS could actually power this.
Scott: this mixer actually takes a oh, yeah, okay Yeah, I thought mine just powers the computer and one monitor.
Rym: and yeah Yeah, the Marantz could run.
Scott: actually doesn't power the monitors.
Scott: it powers the computer only it doesn't.
Scott: even it doesn't power the routers.
Rym: Yeah My files has its own battery backup required by law because I might use it as a phone system and I could call 911 on it.
Rym: I have not wired it up.
Rym: the battery died and it was a pain in the ass to get Verizon to like Give me a new battery.
Rym: Like I didn't want to do with the hassle So I just disconnected the battery and turned off the alarm because I don't care that much.
Scott: So you got some news.
Scott: I do have some news.
Scott: so Makoto Shinkai your boy my boy.
Scott: Yeah Your name was like big smash hit and since then he came up with another one.
Scott: He just went all-in on cloud.
Scott: I don't know if we talked about this again as before this newer movie newest movie weathering with you.
Scott: But he just went all-in on cloud.
Scott: He's like, you know what?
Scott: Fuck it.
Scott: I'm the cloud guy.
Scott: Movie weathering with you.
Scott: literal weather all-in.
Scott: I was already all-in on cloud.
Scott: Guess what?
Scott: I'm double all-in on class.
Rym: I'm looking at two images here these posters.
Rym: One of them is a guy and a girl who obviously are going to be lovers separated by space and time.
Rym: yep, there are clouds and Sunrays and umbrellas and rain.
Rym: and then the other image is what looks like a girl flying over What I can only describe of as take clouds and make them way more cloud And then make him even more cloud and then put Lapita like on top of the clouds, right?
Scott: anyway, so The movies coming out in English in the US January 17th 2020.
Scott: We're gonna be at Pac South then.
Rym: Yep, that's actually the day before my birthday.
Scott: We're gonna have to watch it after Pac South.
Rym: god damn it.
Scott: If you're in a hurry, though You can see it much sooner at the New York City anime convention anime NYC, which is not the New York anime festival.
Rym: Yep, New York anime festival bad anime NYC good.
Rym: That's how you tell the difference.
Scott: We still haven't been to anime NYC but from what we know of it It is good and better at least actually in the stream.
Rym: the other day multiple people asked if we were gonna be at it this Year, okay No, cuz I forgot Haven't gone to it even though it's been several years already cuz I just keep forgetting to like arrange it.
Scott: Anyway at anime NYC, which is soon much sooner.
Scott: When is it exactly like?
Rym: November 15th to 17 actually, you know, what super thing we're not doing anything at it.
Rym: Cuz I think I'm gonna be in Bangkok.
Scott: Anyway, anime NYC is gonna show this movie way before January.
Scott: So if you don't want to wait a whole month and you're in the area and you're going to anime NYC Anyway, you're anime fan.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There you go.
Scott: First chance to see it in the United States.
Scott: Otherwise just wait till January.
Scott: I don't think in January It's gonna be one of those things that shows just like once and that's it the way like Promare was.
Rym: I think it's gonna get a more general.
Scott: I think it's gonna get a few show.
Scott: you like your name had a few showings.
Scott: Yeah, we were able to have our pick of a few different nights.
Scott: So I assume the same thing for weathering with you.
Scott: We'll probably see it the week after as soon as we get back from Pac South.
Scott: We'll see it that week Yep, and then we'll do a show on it.
Rym: So in some other news, I had a little bit of a geek bite.
Rym: So If you're not aware of disenchantment, it's on Netflix.
Rym: It's basically Futurama esque like Matt Groening thing in a fantasy world.
Scott: It was okay It's just Futurama in a fantasy world.
Rym: as far as I know it's pretty clear that it is canonically.
Rym: You know that.
Rym: you know the in Futurama where fries frozen.
Rym: you see the background like aliens destroy the world and castles get built And then aliens destroy the castles and then like civilization goes back again pretty clear that it's set during that castle period right?
Scott: I mean, that's a thing.
Scott: I've seen happen a lot lately.
Scott: is People taking different, you know fictional universes Canonically saying they are actually the same universe But it's actually the the using time to separate them so much like for example Star Wars right and a long time ago in a galaxy far far away, right?
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: well Star Wars is canonically the same universe as like you could take fucking anything.
Scott: Yeah, you could just be like.
Scott: yeah Star Wars is canonically in the same universe as Prince of Nothing.
Scott: Pretty well and the Prince of Nothing.
Scott: and Futurama and yelp entangled and Buggin, so fine Lucy.
Scott: and it was like in the cult.
Scott: No one can argue with you.
Rym: You didn't read them all in the culture series.
Rym: earth is Canonically like present-day earth is canonically in that universe directly and they even visit our earth at one point in the future or past In the 80s.
Scott: Wow, so so as the culture ships are floating around but earth is in the 80s Yes, and Reagan's walking around the earth is and they're just the culture is just avoiding earth and not the culture basically actually Canonically fucks with earth.
Rym: now the culture's idea is earth is relatively backward compared to the rest of the hominids.
Rym: So let's just leave it alone and use it as the reference point for how hominids progress because we were watching them Before they spaced.
Rym: Let's see if they actually space and how they do it.
Scott: Well, if they're looking in the 80s you spaced.
Rym: Yeah, we spaced a little a little bit.
Scott: Go cute space cut.
Scott: Check out my space.
Rym: It's funny though because the culture Asian is like wow their eyes suck and they can't see for shit And they're all slow and they're all kind of dumb.
Rym: Hmm Anyway, so disenchantment.
Rym: if I had to say rank season one of disenchantment, it's Funnier than the entire run of Futurama on average, but it is not as funny as well.
Rym: That's not very original run of Futurama before they brought it back with those increasingly dire movies.
Scott: I was gonna say like You know Futurama is just averaging out.
Scott: The whole thing is kind of not use Simpsons you gotta separate right?
Scott: It's like a really not useful yardstick.
Scott: is some parts are way better than other.
Rym: I would say disenchantment is 75% as funny as the original Futurama.
Rym: run like take that That funny.
Rym: It's okay.
Rym: It's not great.
Rym: Not bad.
Rym: I enjoyed it.
Rym: wouldn't particularly seek it out.
Rym: However At the end of the season it kind of did something crazy in it on a cliffhanger And season two was actually really good pretty serious surprisingly heartwarming and I'm actually very invested in Third and final season.
Rym: Yeah after it like season two was Weirdly good and I did not expect to give a shit about these characters or give a shit about this universe.
Scott: And now why did you watch season two?
Scott: Yeah now that I've watched season two Why did you watch season two if you didn't give a shit?
Rym: Well because We finished another show and then it was on Netflix like oh Let's see where this was going because season one had ended on a cliffhanger.
Rym: Mmm, and honestly in terms of an animated comedy show 75% as funny as the original Futurama still above the line of like worth watching at some point.
Rym: But not I'm not above the line of go.
Rym: seek it out as soon as possible.
Rym: Uh The problem is you got kind of gotta know what happened in season one to really follow season two and that's sort of how these things work, but Season two has a recap that pretty much tells you everything you need to know.
Rym: Okay, you don't need to know about anything else else.
Rym: Just watch it.
Rym: And if you've seen the show what I'll say is that How do I suddenly have an emotional attachment to King fucking Zog?
Rym: like for real.
Rym: so Disenchantment if you avoided it because of mediocre middling reviews of season one.
Rym: Watch this trailer for season two kind of like how I used to tell people who weren't into antenna based on the first few episodes to watch a random episode from black rose.
Rym: Watch this trailer.
Rym: if this trailer intrigues you at all.
Rym: This show is worth watching.
Rym: if you still don't care after watching this trailer.
Rym: Just don't bother.
Rym: Mmm.
Rym: So, uh, yeah, let's get right on into Things of the day you got for me.
Scott: So here's somebody you know, this is a lot of people out there.
Scott: They can do Fancy card tricks not magic tricks where they're like pick a card and they magically make your card go through like a pane of glass.
Scott: Not that kind of card trick.
Scott: Yeah tricks where they're just handling the cards in a fancy way doing like, you know, smooshing them out smoothly Yeah, you know flipping them through the air right throwing cards.
Rym: in middle school I really wanted to learn how to do card close-up sleight of hand and I tried to practice.
Scott: now watch This isn't like necessarily sleight of hand.
Rym: It's more like, you know Cool thing I want to do like the one-handed shuffle and like the fan out fan back and all that kind of stuff.
Scott: That stuff's really hard.
Rym: and I gave up that forget the word.
Scott: There's a word for it.
Rym: Yeah, whatever really hard to do I gave up immediately.
Scott: So this person they made this video using You know stop-motion animation.
Scott: Yep, and basically to video Increasingly unrealistic and impossible tricks of that nature.
Scott: But it looks like they're really happening.
Scott: cuz stop-motion animation.
Scott: It's it's really slick, right?
Scott: So it's like when you start watching it you can sort of get this feeling like whoa Is there is someone really doing this trick and they're just sort of you know videoed it and then slowly You know just cut a lot of frames of video out to make it look like, you know, stop-motion animation.
Scott: It's like no, no one can do this.
Scott: It's like it's all stop-motion animation tricks, but it's really impressive.
Scott: and mostly I think what makes this video great?
Scott: the creativity and Things they thought to do right?
Scott: It's a how many ideas can you have for how to do stop-motion with a deck of cards?
Scott: That would look cool and be fun and visually interesting.
Scott: And it's like every time you think you're they ran out of ideas They got more ideas, even though it's only less than three minutes of ideas.
Scott: so fun to watch one time.
Rym: So I was poking around on YouTube and I saw something that is that is the kind of thing that me and Scott would be Like who and want to watch a YouTube channel that has animated Hungarian folk tales.
Scott: I mean we had good success with the Japanese folk tales, even though they were pretty repetitive a lot of times.
Rym: Yes, so Hungarian folk tales and the one I'm gonna link to is the one that we've that Emily and I watch the Fox Princess.
Scott: No, that's definitely one I would choose.
Rym: Yeah, and based on title alone it The way I will describe this is that it swerves and you might be thinking of course Why would you make it to think of?
Rym: David didn't do something weird?
Rym: every time you think okay, that was the swerve just keep watching it because This is a trip over the course of ten minutes.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I haven't watched it.
Scott: I've only looked over Rym shoulder.
Scott: This is worth watching on the one hand.
Scott: It gives me good yellow submarine vibes.
Rym: It definitely feels like yellow submarine animation.
Scott: on the other hand It gives me bad Zelda Phillips CDI vibes.
Rym: It's also got that.
Rym: and the worst part about it But also the best part is that it has a narrator in English like it's just in English that a dub.
Scott: I guess the original one was Hungarian.
Scott: I'm not sure.
Scott: or was it originally Hungarian folk tales for an english-speaking audience.
Rym: I'm not sure I could have looked into like where this came from and I started to research Description say I decided I didn't care that made by the what it was, right?
Rym: Yeah, I know I'm saying I didn't care that much.
Rym: It was made looks like by some Hungarian people and I guess they got someone to do this voiceover.
Rym: Pretty sure they got the lowest possible bidder because the voiceover is like someone reading a storybook to you, which is fine.
Rym: the pacing of the narration at no point changes Sentences.
Rym: just roll into other sentences in this straight line of inflection regardless of who's talking or what's happening.
Rym: Like it is weird But it's also definitely worth watching Because it's also weird.
Rym: and that's all I'm gonna say.
Rym: you gotta see where this goes.
Rym: I defy you To predict where this will end based on anything that happens in the course of it.
Scott: Please send us folk tales from all countries that are not the United States Japan or Hungary.
Rym: I do like that.
Rym: the good characters all have this really rye smile.
Rym: They all look like they're fucking up to something.
Rym: cuz they are.
Rym: Oh, yeah Like the princess is up to something the Fox is something.
Rym: the good guy is up to something.
Rym: The bad guys are smiling in a different way.
Rym: Everybody's up to something.
Scott: the point is send me all your folk tales.
Rym: Yeah, but this one just watch this.
Scott: Which country has best folk tales?
Rym: Well best and best.
Scott: Argentinian folk tale Nigerian folk tale.
Scott: Bring it on.
Rym: Yeah In the meta moment you guys book club book is still the tale of Genji, I feel like the tale of Genji.
Scott: I don't know if we should actually do this crazy idea.
Rym: I just had really two seconds ago want to break it up and like chapter by chapter do a little mini show.
Scott: No, that would be too many shows Is so big Giving up.
Rym: Did you bail?
Scott: No, okay, not bailing it.
Scott: Never.
Scott: Why would I do that?
Scott: That would be the worst.
Scott: I feel like we should do another book club not delay tale of Genji Right, but I feel like I could.
Scott: it's gonna take me so long to read this.
Scott: I could read other books at the same time.
Rym: I could see that like we could in.
Scott: so we could do another book club within Right, we'd be like, alright, we're doing tale of Genji.
Scott: The book club episode is going to be so long from now, but we'll have a rest just to have book club episodes.
Scott: We're gonna read this other shorter book in the meantime.
Scott: All right Cuz I actually do that and so that will have a book club episode like a few a month or two from now.
Rym: I did make that promise that my next book club choice cuz it's my choice next was gonna be pretty short.
Scott: So maybe I'm talking like a tiny book like one of the ones is like this.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, like this is that this would be like like flat land short.
Rym: Yeah, I'm not.
Rym: no Dumas.
Scott: Don't pick flatland.
Rym: I Don't need to read flatland again.
Rym: I read flatland.
Scott: That's a short book that comes to mind.
Scott: Yes, really tiny.
Rym: I got plenty of books that are about that.
Rym: I
Scott: feel like we should do a tiny ass book that we can you know and Tale of Genji is still the book club book But just have other tiny books that we can do real quick Just to have episodes while we read this massive Tale of Genji that is literally changing while we're reading.
Rym: Also coming up soon.
Rym: as I said many times recently and I'm gonna post up our schedule soon We will be at PAX unplugged in December doing not one but two events.
Rym: They're gonna be awesome.
Scott: Go to both of them.
Scott: I think if you have the PAX app that you can know this that schedules up.
Scott: I think there's like some amount of schedule for PAX Unplugged that is already up and I know the date time and room of our Panel, I just like yeah I think there is public availability of some portion of the PAX Unplugged schedule.
Scott: seek it out.
Scott: if you are going to pack some.
Rym: Yeah, but our panel is take your fucking turn.
Rym: That's right Because I'm real excited about this one.
Rym: Also, if you didn't notice Emily and I are doing a sideshow.
Scott: we are Discussing sideshow, is it a?
Scott: is it a bearded lady a fire eater?
Rym: It's more.
Rym: it's more melonless Bob.
Rym: Okay, so we are watching every single Disney theatrical feature animation in chronological order of release and doing a full podcast on each one.
Rym: we just recorded peachy Oh and Having watched Benichi means adaptation.
Rym: There's actually a really good Obsessive pop-culture disorder that crack show that was on a while ago about how fucked up Pinocchio Pinocchio is.
Rym: Okay, and anyway Having I had not seen Pinocchio since I was a really little kid watching it again.
Rym: There's some things I did not notice.
Rym: They were actually pretty funny and I remember only portions.
Scott: mostly most of the stuff remembers.
Scott: from the beginning and from the ocean.
Rym: I was impressed.
Scott: I don't remember too much.
Rym: That is the part.
Rym: I didn't remember About the horny fish that tries to see Jiminy Cricket's dick.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much unless it's from the beginning like in the workshop or in the ocean I don't remember it.
Rym: But as a kid Jiminy Cricket was just think I remember visit.
Rym: remember Jiminy Cricket is hilarious cuz he's just a hobo.
Scott: Yeah, I vaguely remember like some seedy part of town near the ocean, but that's it.
Rym: You're thinking of Pleasure Island.
Scott: Okay, I guess that was false memory.
Rym: But yeah, I remember the ocean and now the beginning Nothing else I was pleasantly surprised by is that old Disney movies have a lot of racism in them.
Rym: Oh, yeah There's really only two racist things in Pinocchio only two Ones in the background and one's pretty front and center, but only one only a couple of scenes.
Rym: Stromboli is pretty racist But the weird thing is you'd think is it also racist against Italians, but while it's ostensibly said in Italy Everything feels German like Austrian.
Rym: Yep, like the way everything's drawn the way all the characters talk everything feels Austrian, which is just weird.
Rym: But anyway, I will link to that.
Rym: We're gonna put it.
Rym: the episode will appear Imminently and there's a whole playlist on even though it's posted to the Ignites page around.
Rym: you do not do need not give us Even a single dollar.
Rym: they are all public.
Rym: You can just listen to them.
Rym: Mm-hmm They're just posted on the page around because that's an easy place to put them.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Otherwise we should get right into this.
Rym: So Scott hasn't seen Carolyn Tuesday yet, so we can't do a show on it.
Scott: Well, I have time to watch it right now and I was like, hey, it's Halloween month D nights anniversary What we used to do like full month-long spooky shit.
Scott: Well, I was like what Halloween thing can we talk about this?
Scott: animated?
Rym: Let's not take the x-train, right?
Scott: Let's do Nightmare, you know never before Christmas we could do that sometime.
Rym: Yeah, I didn't watch it again.
Scott: then I was like, wait a minute That's you know, that's like 90 minutes long.
Rym: I guess right and we're busy right?
Scott: Why don't we do a Great pumpkin like I try to think of Halloween specials.
Scott: That's like the first one except your fields this heck on.
Rym: I remember Yeah, the the Halloween specials.
Rym: I remember the things that as a kid.
Rym: I remember watching on Halloween Specifically are it's the great pumpkin Charlie Brown that terrifying Garfield thing where the ghost pirates literally tried to murder Garfield.
Scott: for real Love that one.
Rym: I do love that.
Scott: Well, my favorite part is where he goes up to the house.
Scott: He's like, gimme.
Scott: Yep No trick-or-treat just like gimme and The actual movie Halloween.
Rym: Mm-hmm, which is just a slasher film, but I would often see that just on Halloween.
Scott: So I haven't seen this thing.
Scott: So to give it some background, right?
Scott: So first of all 1966.
Rym: it's a 25-minute TV special, right?
Rym: So the second Charlie Brown animated special ever, right?
Scott: So first of all, I thought was the third one ever double-checking here.
Rym: Oh, it was the second holiday themed one, right?
Scott: It's the third.
Scott: So this is a thing that my parents saw when it was brand new when they were like You know 10 11 12 something like that somewhere around there.
Scott: And so for them it was like a huge deal.
Scott: So them having children watch it every year was like us trying to make our children watch whatever.
Rym: Yep, anime that yep, so we will be like, all right kid It's time to watch take the x-ray and they know dad now Right.
Scott: and this thing was literally on broadcast television every year every year And we everyone would sit like we would all watch it the night games like an event.
Rym: We don't be talking about it.
Rym: Right?
Scott: You didn't see this again Until next year there was not.
Rym: really we would see it with your VCR.
Rym: Yes, because one thing I've talked to this for one thing my family did my whole thing is the VCR too much.
Rym: Yes, well the rule was we had ed blocking in the 80s because no one wants to watch commercials.
Rym: So the rule was anything that was on TV that anyone wanted to watch.
Rym: One of the chores someone in the family afternoon.
Rym: We rotated it just like picking up the dog poop or taking the garbage out or mowing the lawn Was record the thing everyone wants to watch on VHS tapes, but pause it when the commercials come on So the rest of the family does not have to see the commercials.
Rym: We did that for fucking everything.
Rym: We have every single episode of like every major TV show for my entire life up until high school on VHS tapes.
Scott: Anyway, pretty sure we threw them all away, but point is This is like an event right because there weren't ways to see things back then easily.
Scott: Yeah I wasn't sold on VHS until I think way late in the 90s and we lent our tape to other families Sometimes except you unless you're a rims family, right?
Scott: It's like it was.
Scott: it was like oh, it's on everyone went to watch it Right.
Scott: Yeah, so also, you know peanuts at the time Was still really big.
Scott: Well, I mean, it's still kind of big but it's like it was this thing Where it's like.
Scott: I didn't know too many people who were like huge peanuts true but everybody knew who.
Rym: Charlie everybody knew it and they knew like the deal with Peppermint Patty and Lucy and Linus and everyone.
Scott: it's like you didn't.
Scott: there weren't like haters.
Scott: there might be haters of it somewhere but like their warrant It's felt like it was a thing that everyone knew and liked, you know It's like you'd be watching the the Thanksgiving Parade.
Scott: you'd be like a snoopy balloon.
Scott: Yeah, or you'd have like, you know.
Rym: So we had the original books like when they're basically the trade paper bags of every peanuts.
Scott: I got those from my school Elementary school library had those.
Rym: Oh, my parents just had like the original printings.
Scott: Yeah, these were those at the school.
Rym: They were so yellow and so crackly.
Rym: Yep, and they smelled like mildew is from elementary school library.
Rym: I think I read every single peanuts comic that was published up until like the late 80s.
Scott: Anyway, so but it was like this thing.
Scott: It was just like, you know everywhere everyone kind of liked it.
Scott: But no, you know, it wasn't in nor.
Rym: so I have a suspicion.
Rym: I can't prove this I don't know.
Rym: I don't think younger people today actually know much about peanuts.
Rym: I think they just know that peanuts is the Charlie Brown thing.
Rym: recognize Snoop, you know Snoopy And Charlie Brown, but I think they will literally not recognize any other character.
Scott: Well, I mean they might recognize that as a Snoopy character.
Rym: Yeah, but those kids don't fucking know who Pigpen is.
Scott: No, they probably don't know anything right or early lesbian representation in comics, right?
Scott: I think also is that I sorta in my life I sort of went through a phase of on the.
Scott: at the beginning It was sort of that feeling right.
Scott: everyone like Snoopy.
Scott: It's Snoopy.
Scott: Yay, but not mega.
Scott: Yay, right?
Scott: And then later when I was like older it was sort of like man.
Scott: What's you know?
Scott: What's the deal with Snoopy's the board?
Scott: It's a boring.
Scott: the boring newspaper comic It's no.
Scott: Calvin and Hobbes is no far side.
Rym: The reason I got man, it was specifically that I would see peanuts in the newspaper and it was garbage pablum.
Rym: But I had the original books and I really liked the old peanuts comics a lot anyway.
Rym: So I remember I had this impression as a young kid that it was something that used to be great and is terrible now.
Scott: I mean I just had the impression that the quality of it it hadn't changed.
Scott: That simply I had changed and realized that it was just sort of you know This mad boring.
Rym: the only reason I knew the difference was that because I had all those old books I didn't keep them.
Scott: I checked my library.
Rym: Oh, we own them because the family Oh anyway, Charlie Brown looked so different.
Rym: in the old car Felt this very clear distinction between old peanuts and new peanuts, but now being even older right?
Scott: I have a completely different view of it Which is like wow that when I was less intelligent, but thought I was smarter than I was I thought that this you know peanuts thing was just sort of like this mad Boring milquetoast deal and I had just liked it when I was a kid because I didn't know because I was you know a kid.
Scott: But now it's like oh now I can see what this actually is saying.
Scott: Yeah, now that I'm way old and I can see the genius of it and how great it is.
Rym: But it's tricky because on one end there's some genius to it, but there is also some milquetoast.
Rym: Yeah, we'll get to that.
Rym: but this Also has an aspect of and I'm gonna compare it to the sanctuary anime OAV In the sense that there you know those 90s anime OAVs where there was a really popular Manga a comic yeah, and then they wouldn't just take the entire comic and make a cartoon
Scott: no
Rym: But they would take like a set of scenes from the comic and make like a special that you could watch.
Rym: That would just let you see some fun stuff assuming that you've already read the comic and know these people are and This has a lot of that in it in the sense Oh, yeah, you don't know anything about peanuts.
Scott: this like you got it This animation makes all not a lot of sense.
Rym: like you literally have to know Linus's full deal and peppermint patties full like it's no peppermint patties and even there is no character development or introduction whatsoever.
Rym: Oh, there's one tiny piece of character development because a character Suckered into this made-up religion and then realizes it's a scam and goes home early, right?
Rym: Okay, so your development, right?
Scott: So there was so the setup right?
Scott: This is Christmas one.
Scott: Then there was some baseball one and these things were airing every year.
Scott: the baseball one they stopped but the Christmas one in the Halloween They continue to air on television every year non-stop until this day and into the future.
Scott: It's so American.
Scott: I don't even know people outside America ever seen these things or heard of them Maybe the English-speaking world, but I don't like.
Scott: I can't imagine that like yeah There's any of these.
Scott: even hat places don't even have Halloween.
Scott: Maybe the Christmas one airs in other places.
Scott: I don't even fucking know.
Scott: But and then my parents we watch it every year because it was their thing from when they were kids Right,
Rym: and now
Scott: I haven't seen it in forever and I go back to take a look at the Halloween one because it's Halloween month
Rym: And the first thing I noticed was as a kid I felt like this was like an hour and a lot.
Scott: Now the first thing is I go download it and I look and it's 20-something minutes.
Scott: I'm like, why is this show short?
Rym: and I looked up.
Rym: I double-checked to make sure I didn't get a bad file.
Scott: No, yeah, I thought I might have got a bad file.
Scott: Nope, what at the come there were so many commercials on it when we were kids Because it did get like an hour time slot Time slot with big ads because it was a TV event back in the day.
Scott: It was a big deal and they stretched it the fuck out.
Scott: Yeah over a whole hour We watched 30 minutes ads and 30 minutes of Charlie Brown.
Scott: I just watched a Charlie Brown.
Scott: It's short as hell.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So What's interesting is I don't know if kids today should really watch it because without the context of the characters I don't think they would even see the fairly complex like interesting meta-narrative, right?
Rym: but what they should definitely watch without even watching the whole thing is the Snoopy side story because that is really good like atmospheric storytelling and we're gonna get today.
Rym: Holy shit That's the part.
Rym: I remember the most.
Rym: as a kid that part was scary to me.
Rym: Oh, yeah I was really terrified for Snoopy.
Rym: Oh, yeah Partly because I was kind of also into World War one and like that like really resonated up with was yes I did.
Rym: I knew the Red Baron was.
Rym: I actually knew a lot about World War one.
Scott: Charlie Brown says the word stop with like.
Rym: yeah, I've times Like the bit where Snoopy is like getting starting up is stop.
Rym: That's kind of how it was to start those fucking.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right, so is a deal, right?
Scott: So they This thing is animated Surprisingly well for 60s television.
Scott: It's better Even better than 70s 70s and 80s cartoons.
Scott: that was cheap.
Rym: Yeah It's still very badly but not.
Scott: but like you gotta think Looney Tunes are way older this and way better animated.
Rym: Yeah by miles and miles a lot of Looney Tunes were intended to be shown in the theater.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: That's not a TV special, right?
Scott: So for television animation, this is way above par.
Scott: but for animation as a whole it's way below par.
Rym: but kind of like we talked about averaging out Futurama the Snoopy part is Really well animated and with a very minimalist palette tells a pretty terrifying and complex story Right.
Scott: So what you have here in this 20 minutes is really let's see one Two.
Scott: you have like three or four different storylines That don't individually get a lot of screen time and they're all sort of tied together by the main Great pumpkin storyline, which is the beginning and the end and all sort of throughout.
Rym: So let's talk about them all in order cuz Snoopy's is the easiest Snoopy.
Scott: So Snoopy is a dog.
Scott: Yeah, right heat for Halloween He's gonna dress up as a World War one fighting ace.
Rym: and that if you haven't read the comics There's this is a whole.
Scott: it's a whole thing.
Scott: It's a whole thing that Snoopy always does.
Scott: All right, so Basically Snoopy just appears.
Scott: he doesn't really appear in it until he's dressed up as the flying ace as his costume.
Scott: Everyone else is a ghost or a witch or something.
Rym: Yep, right and then well, they're either ghosts or ghost witches.
Rym: Those are the two costumes.
Scott: and then Snoopy goes like often as complete tangent.
Scott: You know, that's not like Charlie Brown narrates.
Scott: cuz they're like, where is Snoopy?
Scott: and Charlie Brown narrates?
Rym: Well, he only narrates a little bit adventure that Snoopy is on as the fighting ace But he only narrates a tiny bit of it and the rest of it is just told by Snoopy pantomiming Being shot down behind enemy lines in World War one in France.
Scott: right and the animation of this whole Scene that has nothing to do with Halloween except for the fact that Snoopy's in a costume.
Scott: Yep, right Is a. it's animated in sort of a. it gives me almost like a tiny bit of like a Ralph Bakshi kind of.
Rym: I feel that it's kind of surreal And dark But in and scary.
Rym: and yet it tells a very specific story like the way Snoopy's Reacting and it's clear like when he's shooting at someone When he's in trouble when someone's shooting it when you get shot down like all these you also got to keep in mind that when?
Scott: This is made in the 60s, right?
Scott: Yeah, this animation itself is Now as old as about as old as World War one was when the animation was new.
Scott: Yep, so you could think of this.
Scott: animation is almost a pretty close midpoint between today and World War one.
Scott: Yep and like I think a World War one when this is a new animation was as Good in the memory of people as this animation is.
Scott: but look at Snoopy story as distant history.
Rym: So Snoopy basically has there's two parts of his story.
Rym: okay, he has this whole fantasy where he gets shot down behind enemy lines and has to make his way back through this war-torn world and Then he makes it home.
Rym: He makes it back to the party.
Scott: Well, he's not home.
Scott: He's at this Halloween party suddenly well but in the apple bombing water.
Rym: This is where it's kind of subtle and interesting.
Rym: because then the second part of his story is there's a joke where he kisses Lucy Whatever.
Rym: Mm-hmm, but then there's this really melancholy bit where he sits down with the brush rotor in the piano and Just like is basically having these PTSD flashbacks as the music shifts between light-hearted music and sad music both evoking World War one era music mm-hmm and That.
Rym: that arc is really compelling and it's surprising that that is just this little.
Scott: and somehow they fit that whole Thing in in the 20 minutes where all this other stuff is even though the pacing feels real slow.
Scott: People are walking slow talking slow doing stuff slow, right and they managed to cram all that in there.
Rym: And yet Snoopy does not say a word and Charlie Brown does not even narrate anything other than the very very very beginning.
Scott: It feels like this extended, you know side sequence right and the piano thing goes on for what feels like a while.
Rym: Yeah, and it's right just really melancholy and scary.
Scott: and what the hell is that?
Scott: Why is this in a Halloween special?
Scott: Yeah, it's like they you know, they just use the Halloween.
Scott: The only connection to Halloween is the fact that Snoopy's in a costume Yeah, even though he does that on non Halloween occasions frequently in other Peanuts things Yeah, but that alone makes this work.
Scott: That is the highlight of the entire thing.
Scott: That's like the reason to watch this.
Rym: I would consider that an extremely important piece of animation.
Scott: Yes, indeed All right.
Scott: So the actual the main story, okay, right is That Linus for some reason believes in this great pumpkin, which is basically Santa Claus in pumpkin form.
Scott: Yep And he believes that if you stay on the pumpkin patch all Halloween night and are the most sincere The great pumpkin will come to your pumpkin patch and not some other pumpkin pad.
Rym: What I like is that it is very clear.
Scott: he writes a letter to the great pumpkin just like Santa.
Rym: it's very clear.
Rym: He's done this his entire life.
Rym: It has never come to pass.
Rym: His faith is unshaken and Literally everyone else on earth thinks he is a moron.
Rym: Yep, except Sally who doesn't know that this is a thing yet, right?
Scott: Well Sally Charlie Brown's little sister right in love with him doesn't believe in the great pumpkin.
Scott: She's skeptical, right?
Scott: She's in love with Linus and trust him.
Scott: So she's like, you know what?
Scott: I'm gonna go for this great pumpkin thing one time.
Scott: I'll see.
Scott: Yeah, you know just to be with Linus in the pumpkin patch all night And you get this whole like literally everyone's like Linus.
Rym: What the fuck?
Rym: Stop it.
Rym: Sally.
Rym: Don't he's crazy.
Scott: Don't go with him.
Scott: Yeah, trust us.
Rym: Yeah, and in the very end the moral is religion is fake.
Rym: Don't waste your time.
Rym: Yep Dude, you missed out on real life.
Scott: Yeah, she missed out on trick-or-treating.
Scott: She missed out on the party.
Scott: She gets away mad right and you know tells him off.
Scott: and it also even the fact that she you know Would you know wanted to hang with him or and get close to him?
Scott: No, that wasn't you know?
Scott: That didn't make up for the fact that her Halloween is completely ruined.
Rym: and meanwhile Linus immediately just says well It'll definitely happen next year.
Rym: Like that's the end.
Rym: like Linus did not learn his lesson Probably got sick.
Rym: Yep, right and then there's this little not aside part where Lucy is sick of his shit But clearly has set her alarm for 4 a.m Knowing that this will happen every year and takes care of him.
Rym: Anyway, despite the fact that this is a hundred percent his fault.
Rym: Mm-hmm And that's that's heartwarming but also kind of sad and it's that's a pretty complex Story.
Scott: Well, the real ending is the next day Right.
Scott: the true ending right is?
Scott: you know Linus and Charlie Brown are both talking about how shitty their Halloween's were right?
Rym: Charlie?
Rym: well, we'll get to Charlie Brown.
Rym: last Charlie Brown's Halloween was shitty because everyone's shitty to him for no reason.
Rym: That's right But it's like all there is everyone shitty to Charlie Brown.
Rym: the end, right?
Scott: So Charlie Brown is doing you know, the normal Halloween, right?
Scott: He you know has to kick a football falls for the trick again.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Rym: His friends are all just pieces of shit.
Scott: Yeah, well, especially, you know, yeah Everyone no one helps them.
Rym: Everyone's making fun of him.
Scott: They're either.
Scott: they're either Directly, but Lucy's the only one who's like directly bullying him and I guess violet and maybe right.
Scott: Yeah, everyone else is just sort of chilling and going along but they don't come to his aid.
Scott: Yeah, right They don't like defend Charlie Brown They just sort of stand there and look and laugh and don't do anything.
Rym: All the other parents in the neighborhood are in on this bullying.
Scott: Well notably.
Scott: Well, that's true.
Scott: But notably I got there is there is no.
Rym: Yeah, I say that a lot whenever we're playing a game or anything it's like what'd you get?
Rym: I got 15 victory points.
Rym: I got nine victory points.
Rym: I got a rock.
Rym: This is what I'm quoting.
Rym: Yeah, this is what I've been quoting my whole life.
Rym: The moral is everybody hates Charlie Brown for no good reason.
Rym: the end, right?
Scott: So Charlie Brown they go trick-or-treating Right, and of course at every house some people get cookies some people get candy.
Scott: They have three houses in a row to give them a rock.
Scott: There was actually I read online.
Scott: They discussed this.
Scott: at first they only wanted him to get a rock at one house.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And then they were like no there was like Aria and apparently he ended up getting the rock at all three houses.
Scott: And then people sent candy to the production company like candy for Charlie Brown because they felt so bad.
Scott: Real life.
Scott: people sent real candy.
Scott: Yep, right for Charlie Brown anyway.
Scott: And then he was.
Scott: he was so happy that he got invited to the Halloween party.
Scott: He's only invited to the Halloween party, right?
Scott: It's implied.
Scott: He wouldn't have been invited except for the fact that they could use his head as The perfect drawing surface because he's got a big brown bald head.
Scott: Yeah come up with jack-o'-lantern ideas Right and he wasn't having a big bald round head.
Scott: He probably wouldn't have gotten invited.
Rym: Yeah, which is well It's hard to say because what we don't actually know our violence motivations is probably violent.
Rym: Actually just invited him and everyone else is just being shitty to him.
Scott: maybe the only thing that Charlie Brown has it's his fault is he Fucks up cutting the holes in his ghost costume because again, no one will help him.
Scott: Well, he's also right, but it's like.
Scott: it's true that you know, most of his problems are caused by other people, right?
Rym: But he does also have his.
Scott: there were two self-inflicted problems, right?
Scott: It's a victim blaming to say that he fell for the football kicking thing.
Scott: You're right because he was skeptical of it at first, but I guess he believed in the paper.
Scott: Yeah But you know the cutting.
Scott: he couldn't cut holes in his own got a ghost costume.
Scott: So he is you know, kind of kind of doofy on his own, right?
Scott: Yeah, everyone else was able to cut holes in the ghost costume.
Rym: just fine, but then the final scene.
Rym: So Charlie Brown's like yeah at a shitty Halloween like I always do and then like a bunch of rocks had a shitty costume.
Rym: They drew on my head and Linus is like great pumpkins coming next year.
Scott: Well, he was like yeah at a shitty Halloween - I was freezing cold all night.
Scott: Yeah, you know your sister got mad at me remember.
Scott: and then you know, Charlie Brown is like, you know At least you got a great pumpkin.
Scott: Yeah, I got religion.
Scott: Yeah, he's like no It's a great bumpkin still.
Scott: Charlie Brown thought that Linus had finally come to set his senses But he had not.
Scott: he still was confident.
Rym: He does what woo people do.
Rym: where Linus his whole arc is doubly doubles down.
Scott: Yeah, he doubles down and finds Oh, you thought the world was gonna end and it didn't.
Rym: but specific In even to the point of making specific excuses like oh, I was an if instead of way wasn't sincere enough Yep, it was my fault.
Rym: So really this is just three like parables That all of which have the same moral welcome to the cruel realities of an evil world Like the end yet presented as this Halloween special.
Scott: that's barely Halloween, right?
Scott: Yeah, not the Garfield once full hollow.
Scott: This one's like partially just happens to be during Halloween.
Rym: So on one end, I'm very pleased that this kind of thing was made and released.
Rym: But on the other hand, it's hard to recommend that Younger people today watch it because if you don't know these characters are it just feels a little bit capricious.
Scott: Well, it's also.
Scott: I just think that it's like like I said when I was a kid, it clearly just went over my head.
Scott: Yeah when I was Older it went under my head because I only saw the surface level of it.
Scott: And now that I see like the high brownness of it like it's secret high brow Right now.
Scott: I feel like it's wasted.
Rym: I mean, we've got a person who tries to make you wouldn't understand the great the great pumpkin.
Rym: We've got Charlie Brown a person who tries to make the best in light of the cruel realities of an evil world because that's just that.
Rym: That's what this is about.
Rym: You've got the war veteran who can't enjoy the good parts of the real world like this Halloween party Because he's having PTSD and flashbacks to the horrors of war.
Rym: and then you've got the religious fanatic who?
Rym: Drags other people down with him and cannot be reasoned with and then it ends.
Scott: Yeah, so it's like what first appears to just be a secular generic Milk-toast, you know how commercial?
Scott: Commercialized holiday special to sell Snoopy crap.
Scott: right?
Scott: is actually this like three Aesop's fables Some gravels right that probably go over the heads of most people right and is actually has really something going on here.
Scott: But also is It's not.
Scott: it's like it's still timeless as long as Halloween is a holiday.
Scott: Yeah, there is nothing That's not timeless about this except for maybe the World War one, but I guess that is not is also timeless.
Scott: Yeah, I mean war is war.
Scott: I still remember World War one.
Rym: Yeah But I feel like people know what it's up with camel is - maybe but people not knowing enough about peanuts is Exactly There's long segments.
Rym: We're like Linus uses the blue blanket to get the to mail the letter.
Scott: I guess like.
Scott: I guess you could Introduce this could introduce you to peanuts, but then it might not be that effective.
Scott: Yeah So like there's a joke like everyone knows is you pig pen?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: well if you don't already know pig pen, you didn't see pig pen outside the ghost costume.
Scott: Yep, I guess you know, the name is pig pen.
Scott: So that gives you something cuz they say it Don't know about Charlie Brown in the football.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's like they hit you with that football joke.
Rym: course If you don't know it still works because that introduces the fact that Lucy is a piece of shit.
Scott: It does but it's early.
Scott: Brown is not Presented as if you already know the football joke and that you've seen Charlie Brown not kick a football before.
Scott: and he's like I'll get it this time.
Rym: Yep, and so you could still infer that The only one thing that really doesn't make sense is Linus and the blue Blanket because that and that is not explained to you at any point.
Rym: That's just there anyway, everything else you could infer It's only 20 something minutes.
Scott: So maybe You know put it on instance.
Scott: There's no television anymore.
Scott: It's pretty easy to find on your calendar every Halloween to just set aside 20 something minutes.
Rym: Yeah, if you've never seen it, I do recommend you go watch it.
Scott: Yeah, if nothing.
Scott: but for if you only if you don't know anything about it can't just skip everything with the Snoopy parts And you'll still get something.
Scott: the other parts on a pure animation level The Snoopy part is like legendary and worth the five minutes it takes or whatever.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Rym: It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, how do you mean uncle?
Rym: just like a dude guy?
Rym: Sure, Thomas and William Eisner's linkage you hydrated.
Rym: Gannon boogaloo Jennifer Hitchcock Christmas give my state calm.
Rym: J Band Shawn Yeager Nicholas Brando.
Rym: Let's see if Rym's does Toronto properly for two one creations chilling out max and relaxing.
Rym: all cool Shervin on all Rory superboy Clinton Walton run from New Zealand Ron parent rope and liner fin red lily Tenebrae Sean Klein Chris Reimer Thomas Hahn.
Rym: and now I leave you with Today's Marty's birthday.
Scott: I'm gonna tell her in my own little way that the top of Phoenix Mountain The bat Mario's in will come out and it's called the red Phoenix and I must say it's the smartest thing that I thought of Today.
Scott: what Mario sees when she's above the trees is gonna bring her to a pretty little knees.
Rym: That's right, y'all?
Scott: I bought every rose in Japan.
Scott: just a little girl that I'm her man.
Scott: Oh, yeah This is it my good friends, it's the message I wanted to send Roses.
Rym: all it's her wake-up call so we can quit play left pretend.
Rym: Huh?
Scott: I'm so cool I'm so smart.
Scott: I'm so cool.
Scott: I'm so smart.