Rym: It's Thursday October 10th 2019.
Rym: I'm Rym Scott and this is a sleepy GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We are talking about the logistics of moving.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: We actually struggled to have a sort of you know, this format of GeekNights.
Rym: We do an open ebit that makes us human like oh, yeah Here's some anecdote from my life.
Rym: and then we talk about the news.
Rym: then we do main.
Scott: Built up during our minor hiatus we all forgotten all forgotten as predicted.
Rym: I feel like every day.
Scott: I actually did a lot of you know, not had.
Scott: my recent days have been not normal days.
Scott: I wasn't like, you know going to the office going to work coming home.
Scott: I was home one day getting a furniture delivery putting furniture.
Scott: I built like four IKEA things in a day.
Scott: Yeah, and today that my hanging guy came.
Rym: the other weekend We went out and did a really really grueling difficult hike upstate.
Scott: He hung up much of shit on the walls as I paid him to.
Scott: Just as awesome dude as last time did a great job.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: what is there to say about that?
Scott: We just I already said everything about it.
Rym: Yep, and nothing.
Scott: if there were no unusual events during those, you know Things right to tell a story about and
Rym: I already talked about the more recent unusual events but no one usual event has happened to me in the net in the last like 27 ish hours that I can think of.
Scott: so I guess the only minor thing I can mention is that my new apartment directly outside the window of my apartment is The height is like directly across the street.
Scott: like look out the window.
Scott: there it is, you can look into the window of the hot the high school like the fancy Long Island City High School and Basically, I figure out a class that's there and post relevant things for kids to cheat with.
Scott: I don't think they can see into our apartment and I could put stuff on the balcony.
Scott: But anyway, but of a big banner, that's just like Barely, I'm sort of at the edge of the building.
Scott: what I can see the entirety of is The field.
Scott: so basically I have my balcony is like like a like a a plus like first Mezzanine seat to see the entire sports field.
Scott: watch every high school sport for free Without paying any money to the kids of the donation bucket at the fence as if you'd want to watch any of those sports.
Rym: Let's see when I was in high school.
Scott: I've been seeing a lot of free high school sports.
Scott: It's not a football game.
Scott: There was soccer today when I was coming over.
Scott: So despite being really annoying the negative part.
Scott: Is that Already twice early in the morning Relatively early.
Rym: We've been woken up by football practice going like You just should thank Satan that this isn't the Midwest because you'd be woken up this season every morning by a marching band The mark.
Scott: there is a band.
Scott: it was not large.
Scott: you would you would say that it was minuscule.
Rym: I mean by your measurement, it's got to be over a hundred kids or it's not a much of a marching band.
Scott: I'd say this what this wasn't even tens of kids.
Rym: Ah, that's so that's during the football game.
Scott: I did here like, you know, do Oh, yeah, that sounds like a cadence.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know, there was some kind of some kind of banding happening.
Rym: So I think back now as a kid despite know my high school had a hockey team.
Rym: But because they played like off-site because even though this was a really like wealthy high school Even the wealthy high school cannot afford its own ice rink.
Scott: So no our highs know there was a in In Connecticut where I lived.
Scott: the ice rink was called Wonderland device and that's where pretty much all ice related things in the area Happened.
Rym: Yep, so I never once saw our hockey team play because I just didn't.
Scott: oh, I didn't know.
Scott: I didn't see our high school team hockey hockey team.
Rym: I went to HL games.
Rym: I never went to a basketball game the school had.
Rym: I never went to any sports.
Rym: the school did accept football because since I was in the marching band I was forced to like.
Rym: I was not optional.
Rym: I would be in trouble if I didn't.
Scott: I never went to any of my high School sporting events ever.
Rym: and I'm when I was a senior I started going to basketball games only because the pep band had started to kind of collapse.
Rym: So I kind of took over the pep band and ran it which meant I had to go to every stupid game and because we Couldn't get any percussionist to join the pep band.
Rym: I Basically played drums for this band.
Scott: I did go to see.
Scott: I wasn't in high school.
Scott: Yeah, I think I might have been in middle school But at the high school that I went to there was a charity game.
Scott: I forget if it was Harlem Wizards or Harlem Globetrotters versus New York Football Giants.
Rym: Wow, that's actually pretty funny.
Scott: that actually happened at my high school actually went to it.
Scott: I remember I think Lawrence Baker the touchdown maker was there.
Scott: Whoa The Giants got crushed.
Scott: Yeah, they're playing basketball.
Scott: They were playing football.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: So it was like five New York Giants maybe a couple like let's watch the New York Rangers play Overwatch against the couple.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Rym: That's exactly Z bad like his tracer and he just keeps jumping off the edge.
Scott: You have a good time and the money goes to some kind of charity thing.
Scott: You wait in line to get autographs from.
Scott: you know All the play.
Rym: so I'm both teams in the entirety of my time at high school despite being obligated To go to every fucking home football game for the entirety of my time in high school I never saw the second half of any football game because we after that halftime performance.
Scott: You're like see ya.
Rym: Yeah, literally, so what's funny though?
Scott: I talked to the long time perform at the end if you won.
Rym: No, okay, cuz we were in a pep band.
Rym: We were the marching band.
Rym: so we'd we do the.
Rym: we'd play the the national anthem in the beginning at halftime.
Scott: You should have just spelled out like fuck right on the field.
Scott: We are.
Scott: we pulled a few pranks like go other team.
Rym: We uh, we did pranks.
Scott: right you were Detroit.
Scott: You should have been like go Chicago.
Rym: but The the two things that were notable and weird about that was that we had a full football field On our school like multiple football fields.
Rym: We had one real one and a whole bunch of practice fields.
Rym: But the real field with bleachers like full-on everything lights Was too close to the m53 a highway.
Rym: So the state for I don't know if the state of the county they basically banned us from ever having the lights turned on So meaning we can never have a night game.
Scott: So why have the lights?
Rym: because the lights were there before the highway was like upgraded or something Did get used at one point.
Rym: yeah long before I got to the ice.
Scott: So our high school switched from being Pepsi school to a coke school at some point during while I was in high school.
Rym: We had neither we banned it we banned it all while I was in high school.
Scott: They switched from a Pepsi school to a coke school to get money to get new lights Oh or to get lights to begin with I forget.
Rym: So basically you scoreboard and this crazy football field with a full-on bleachers and everything could only be used by the marching band Cuz.
Rym: we were the only people who would use it during the day Mmm, but that meant every home.
Rym: so there were four high schools in our area.
Rym: Stevenson was one of was the crappiest of them and it was like our rival because we chose our rival to be the crappiest of them obviously and We were the biggest.
Rym: they uh, we had to have all our home football games at their school.
Rym: So when we played them There would be home games and away games, but they're always there and they.
Scott: it's called MetLife Stadiums, right?
Scott: The New Jersey football teams play there and it sucked cuz.
Rym: it meant every time there's a football game There were a lot of them.
Rym: We had to go to our high school and then the whole marching band would be put on like 20s like yellow school buses and be taken to this other school to do the thing and Either you could try to get on one of the ten buses that would leave from that school and take you back to where you left your car at our high school or You had to stay to the end of the game and then the other half of the buses would leave.
Rym: the other half of the buses are always empty because everyone just got a Home because nobody wanted to see football.
Rym: and the funniest part was All the people who came to see the game other than the parents of the kids who played football also left at halftime.
Rym: So it was basically empty.
Scott: There weren't too many spectators at the football game.
Scott: I watched they were Long Island City, I think lost.
Scott: Yeah, they were just winning a gold soccer though three nothing just now.
Rym: So there's a bunch of news going on and I think I said this in the forum.
Rym: But this the Hong Kong issues and the Chinese censorship in the u.s.
Rym: Is actually kind of exploding like Exploding across all fronts.
Rym: Yep, and it's not that nothing's different.
Scott: The NBA front is probably the top front.
Rym: Yeah, the Blizzard front similarly big front
Scott: was the second front But now the Apple front has come in and pushed it into pushed itself in the second place
Rym: Yep, and I think people are starting to realize that like I said on Twitter instead on the show This is every front because every American company in every industry tries to avoid pissing China off and This is all gonna get pushed to a head in a hurry Because I I the cave as soon as all these domestic American.
Scott: you just have to be a company that does something that is so Safe such as there is like for example, if you make I don't know fucking Children's board games.
Scott: It's like nothing you do is offensive to anyone on earth Unless you also don't manufacture it in China.
Rym: just in case.
Scott: I'm just saying it's like, you know You're not printing anything with a map of China on it.
Scott: Yeah, there's nothing polite, right?
Rym: It is easy to mess up though.
Rym: Do you know many things I've seen?
Rym: we're like an incidental background image in a video game is a stock image of a classroom That happens to have a map that happens to not show China owning one specific fucking island in the middle of the Pacific.
Scott: I'm just saying like that happens, right?
Scott: but I'm saying like if you you know if the company unless you're a company does something that is so mundane like You make bagels Then it's like there's nothing.
Scott: a fan, you know, unless there's some bagel-hating country It's like there's nothing offensive to anyone about what you do any reasonable person.
Scott: I wonder if I come if you do any China, right, but if you do anything, you know a sport it's like oh we play basketball.
Scott: What's offensive?
Scott: nothing.
Scott: but the fact is if you do something that big.
Scott: then you have all these parts, you know public famous Participants and now you're open to anything that they say and do right.
Scott: so that involves all sports anything Streaming anything media based right and of course anything Entertainment or content based where you might be creating artwork.
Scott: That is Offensive to someone somewhere right.
Scott: music movies books, you know anything like that.
Scott: Get you know games that aren't just simple like Mario anything, you know Mario's like okay for the whole world, but you know Anything else?
Rym: Oh So we are not blocked in China yet.
Scott: No, why would we ever know we're so small.
Scott: They wouldn't notice us.
Scott: Yep, it's a manual blocking process challenge accepted.
Scott: in order for us to be blocked in China We would need like people in China and to like start spreading us around like oh my god Check out these two podcasting dudes in China.
Scott: Yeah You know talking shit.
Rym: So the one thing I will disclose those because in the course of that report like I'm very much against Blizzard on this But as you all know, I also own kind of a lot of stock in Blizzard.
Rym: So One to avoid a conflict of interest in being able to cover this fairly and two cuz.
Rym: I Don't know how this is all gonna end.
Rym: So also it's just enlightened self-interest.
Rym: I divested myself of all of my investments in Blizzard.
Rym: I sold all my stock.
Scott: How much could you possibly have?
Rym: Uh, I Don't know if I actually want to say how much I had but it was mainly Many many shares few thousands of dollars.
Rym: No, no more like Many tens of thousands of dollars.
Scott: Yeah, well buy me something.
Rym: then I'm gonna buy some other stock.
Scott: buy me a car.
Scott: put it in the garage in my building.
Rym: Why would I buy you a car?
Rym: Do you want to split a car?
Scott: No, I want a free car.
Rym: No, I'm not gonna give you a free car.
Scott: However, that's the only kind of car I'll accept I would split a car that we could both use.
Rym: I know half of parking in your stupid building.
Rym: No, fuck is my building like.
Rym: no buildings here are allowed to have parking garages fuck Huh, which I'm glad for.
Rym: I'm glad that nobody here has a place to park.
Scott: Yeah in my building They're desperate to have people by the parking spots that are in the garage underneath the building But the biking bike parking ahead to get another rack.
Rym: I've been down in that garage in your building.
Rym: fuck cars.
Scott: The only car I want is one that caused me nothing cuz that's how much I'm willing to pay thing.
Rym: It's the only times I need a car is to go skiing in the winter.
Rym: That's right.
Scott: So and I thought I looked into BMW zip cars in that garage because I guess they couldn't sell the spots.
Scott: But zip car is so expensive, but I had to pay the annual fee.
Scott: So fuck that.
Rym: No, the annual fee is trivial.
Rym: The problem was zip cars that it ends up costing like over a hundred dollars a day to actually use the cars.
Scott: Oh fuck that too.
Rym: to use one of those zip cars over a weekend is terrifyingly expensive because they Their business model assumed you'd use it like in the city like using it to do stuff in the city.
Rym: But no one uses them for that.
Rym: They use them to go out of town on the weekends, of course, so Anyway, the Blizzard like the China Blizzard stuff is going to continue to escalate and it's a rapidly moving space.
Rym: So I'm assuming by the time we do our next Tuesday episode of GeekNights.
Rym: There's gonna be a lot to say about it.
Rym: Hmm in other news we cannot avoid this.
Rym: as you know America's been in the throes of a constitutional crisis since January 21st 2016 basically and it's only been escalating since then and you might think But Rym if it's been escalating that whole time how much more could it escalate?
Rym: Well, let me tell you it escalated more in the last three hours than it did in the last week.
Scott: I mean, I gotta say the one thing that really Raised my eyebrow Right is I have heard people who are usually the kind of people that I get mad at for being far too reasonable.
Scott: Right, you know those people.
Scott: Yeah, please come testify and then well You know, I mean like, you know public figures who are like on the news or whatever, right?
Scott: You know the kind of people who are usually like, you know rule of law this and that Reasonable reasonable.
Scott: They're not people who are like Revolution burn down shoot everybody, you know crazy talk, right?
Scott: But those people right.
Scott: we're suggesting one particular crazy thing Which is the cut right the most reason.
Rym: this is Scott kind of thing, right?
Rym: Normally the kind of thing that Scott would say.
Scott: Yeah, right as a crazy not entirely serious thing like oh do this thing obvious, right?
Scott: Very deep people who are far too reasonable.
Scott: We're suggesting right that the House of Representatives To enforce its subpoena power should send out the entirely ceremonial Person the sergeant-at-arms.
Rym: Oh to go arrest them.
Scott: to go and arrest people.
Scott: and I'm like That is a ceremonial dude who holds a mace and There's not someone who goes there.
Rym: I wanted to be Chekhov's mace.
Scott: go use it.
Scott: The mace is a fashe's first of all, which is not cool.
Rym: Yeah But it's tricky because that predates.
Scott: it does.
Rym: but any of the point is that I feel like we should still change it.
Scott: that dude is Entirely ceremonial.
Scott: there is that's like crown jewel ceremonial.
Scott: There is nothing Actual enforcement about it.
Scott: if that dude went to arrest someone with a gun Right.
Scott: I don't even know who it is.
Scott: Is it is it even someone who's like Physically powerful?
Scott: or is it like an old ceremonial dude?
Scott: is even a dude?
Scott: see it could be anybody as much as I love Like the most ridiculous for super reasonable people were suggesting that and me crazy person Saying know what that person isn't doing jack shit.
Scott: They're just there to death.
Scott: They're just there to like, you know do a well thing.
Rym: So here's the thing in reality, but what that person represents is a power that the house has yes Symbolic power.
Rym: Well, no literal power that just happens to have not been exercised.
Scott: Yes, but it is also entirely symbolic.
Scott: I don't think in the history of the United States that person the sergeant-at-arms has ever had to do anything Except like maybe kick a drunken person out of the house or something, right?
Rym: Now I'm looking to see if there's got to be some crazy story of them doing.
Scott: I'm sure there is but they've never I don't Think gone out and gotten someone else to drag them in with you know as a subpoena All right, well Theoretically they could get other people.
Scott: who is the person?
Rym: it's this guy right now named Paul Irving.
Scott: what's up Paul Paul?
Scott: What's?
Scott: what's Paul all about?
Rym: Paul is I don't know.
Rym: He's all about being the sergeant-at-arms, I guess.
Scott: Yeah, what is the cheese?
Rym: All right, our GeekNights is now devolved into reading Wikipedia.
Rym: So as one of its first resolution you heard this about this, right?
Scott: Yeah people suggesting this.
Rym: Yeah Oh Billy believe me.
Rym: Where do I hang out politically?
Rym: Bark is where I hang out.
Scott: Okay, then people definitely were talking about this day.
Rym: So basically all one of the very first things the first Congress did after the Constitution Which for those of you who don't know was way after the revolution.
Rym: We actually fucked up and made a whole different government and it didn't work at all And we gave up on it and we started over.
Scott: they teach it in school, but people sleep through that and don't remember it.
Scott: Yeah, they don't fully understand what was being said.
Scott: In fact when it was the Confederate the Articles of Confederation were taught to me in school.
Scott: It took me like two days into that sector realize.
Rym: I wasn't the Civil War.
Scott: No to realize like what the fuck are they talking about?
Scott: It's like wait, wait, wait Revolution and then we did something else and then oh, I'm like.
Scott: the Constitution wasn't from 1776 also.
Rym: Yeah, we had government one.
Scott: I did white government one.
Scott: Why didn't you say this like repeatedly on the first day of this section?
Rym: I can explain this to modern modern listeners of GeekNights.
Rym: So the public beta of the US government didn't go so well, that's right.
Rym: So this is basically one of the first things we ever did as a nation, okay Establish this role.
Rym: They are the chief law enforcement officer of the house, correct?
Rym: They're responsible for security of the physical building.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: It's like a bailiff in a in a court.
Scott: It's not like a you know a cop who can arrest people Under the direction of the speaker.
Rym: they are Maintain.
Rym: they are responsible for maintaining order in decorum.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Like I said, I'd kick out a drunken dude.
Rym: Yeah, uh, the house could basically decide whatever they.
Rym: the house can decide what this person's duties are.
Rym: Of course the house could say erratically house gonna point an army under this dude if they wanted to Enforce the rules of the house.
Scott: Yes, of course on paper that will never happen.
Scott: That's crazy.
Scott: Talk.
Scott: Why are reasonable people making crazy talk?
Rym: Because it's not that crazy because we're in the middle of a crisis in the sense that if the White House Refuses to follow the Constitution which they've literally like The White House literally sent a letter to the House of Representatives Like this is not a joke saying we do not recognize your authority to impeach the president.
Scott: Like that is fucked up shit, right?
Rym: That is that is not even the craziest thing that's happened this week.
Rym: But that is the level of craziness.
Rym: the Senate which is responsible for removing the president refuses to take action And the entire justice system is under the control of the White House.
Rym: So they can't do anything and the Supreme Court was compromised by two illegally appointed justices, so they can't do anything.
Rym: So we're just stuck right now.
Scott: Well, I mean it.
Scott: the guest question is if they did the crazy thing and sent the sergeant-at-arms to go and arrest people.
Rym: But there's the crazy thing.
Rym: who would they arrest?
Rym: Rick Perry and Rudy Giuliani Arrest people.
Scott: then what would the Supreme Court say?
Scott: That's okay.
Rym: Yeah, and then what do we do?
Rym: Is this the house say?
Rym: well no because the Supreme Court is broken like what we don't did.
Rym: We're in weird territory and it's only getting weirder.
Scott: So the crazy shit that just I want to say is that's great It's never gonna happen.
Scott: But if it happens any video of the sergeant-at-arms going hitting someone.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: Yes, gotta be on video.
Scott: Yeah, right hit him with the mace.
Scott: So hit him with.
Scott: basically it's big by the way, you don't want to get hit with that.
Rym: So the house just subpoenaed.
Scott: don't look for a picture of it.
Scott: It's scary.
Rym: Rick Perry who is basically an idiot who got appointed to a position where he couldn't do much harm.
Scott: So everyone in the election.
Rym: Yeah The problem was the position that they thought he wouldn't do much harm in is the Department of Energy Which if you don't know anything about the US that is one of energy covers a ton of shit.
Scott: Well, not just power-making.
Rym: well, it actually doesn't really cover nuclear weapons.
Rym: Energy energy is basically euphemism for fucking nukes.
Scott: It's like that's the number one thing they do.
Scott: Yeah, they do a lot of other stuff too that is surprisingly unrelated to nukes.
Rym: But they basically put this befuddled idiot in charge of it for political reasons and our president Basically just said oh the crime.
Rym: I did.
Rym: I did it because that guy told me to Well, that's never an excuse yeah.
Rym: But that's the kind of excuse I made when like I pulled a prank on my brother and I got caught I would lie and tell my mom and my brother told me to do it.
Rym: Like that's literally what's going on.
Rym: So He got subpoenaed over that Rudy Giuliani the former mayor of New York who is also really crazy.
Rym: if you didn't know Well, he was slightly crazy now.
Scott: He became more crazy.
Rym: So as far as I have learned he's actually always been this crazy.
Rym: Just no one noticed.
Scott: How could he not notice?
Rym: They just didn't because no one no one ever put him on TV long enough to let his crazy out.
Rym: it's kind of like Well, there's a lot of people like that.
Rym: where you put him on TV Rym.
Rym: My crazy is usually well contained.
Rym: But the craziness that just happened is Rudy Giuliani who was already being subpoenaed by the house and is already guilty of like every fucking treason And I always wanted to talk about hitting someone with the fashees.
Rym: I'm really no no, but basically he was doing business with these two dudes who are Ukrainian and appear to be former like Soviet people and They just got arrested at the airport trying to flee the country.
Rym: Mm-hmm for this stuff.
Rym: Mm-hmm by New York Because the New York Attorney General is going after him and apparently that's because the feds Ignored this at despite knowing about it.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So Crisis is happening amid crisis amid crisis.
Scott: I don't think New York has a fashees to go anyone.
Scott: Yeah Is there a mace at the at the New York like assembly?
Rym: What I will tell all of you is that what New York has the mace that New York State and California as a state have In all of this mostly New York because a lot of the stuff happened to have happened in New York.
Rym: So the New York like the New York government is actually very important to the federal government for these reasons Because it's very hard to do anything in the u.s.
Rym: Without in some point involving, New York City meaning you involve the apparatus of New York State.
Rym: so Basically, the reason that's important is that the US president can pardon anyone for anything For federal crimes can't do shit for state crimes.
Rym: That's why this is.
Rym: that's why New York keeps coming up.
Rym: if you were curious the New York Assembly does have a sergeant-at-arms.
Scott: It's Wayne who.
Scott: it's Wayne P. Jackson, I don't know if Wayne P. Jackson has a mace.
Rym: I wonder if we could interview Wayne P. Jackson on GeekNights and Looks like a cool person.
Rym: I I will.
Scott: this is Jackson's LinkedIn page.
Rym: I'm gonna try to interview the depart the sergeant-at-arms of the New York Assembly on GeekNights like He has been the sergeant-at-arms at the New York State Assembly Since.
Scott: but when do you think oh my god, when do you think Wayne P. Jackson became?
Scott: This without looking it up of the New York State is a listener can see my screen.
Rym: They can say I can't look in this up.
Rym: You wouldn't ask unless it was really good.
Scott: I'm gonna say since 1968 you're way too early 1979 40 years.
Scott: Whoa in that job.
Rym: I really want to talk to this guy now.
Rym: That's the kind of person no one interviews connected them on LinkedIn.
Rym: I will I will.
Rym: I will try to talk to this person.
Rym: That would be because we haven't interviewed anyone in GeekNights and for fucking acted assembly sergeant-at-arms.
Scott: It's 40 years in chamber daily news.
Rym: Wow.
Scott: All right Person didn't even know a Vietnam vet.
Rym: So in some other news, that's also terrifying and actually really important and people don't seem to realize what's happening here.
Rym: I'm gonna broadly summarize because I want to get down to like our actual main bed, but here's the deal.
Rym: There's this power company in California.
Rym: They caused the one of the day I heard.
Scott: all I heard was that there's power outages in California And I know that the power company in California is called PG&E which stands for Pacific Gas and Electric, right?
Scott: Yeah Yeah, that's all I knew.
Scott: I didn't know anything and then Rym went off on it.
Rym: Yeah, the holy shit.
Rym: So remember that giant wildfire that killed like 90 people destroyed an entire town.
Scott: I thought that's always from like some dirt derpy derp in the woods.
Scott: No smokey the bear.
Rym: No, this was the deadliest wildfire in the history of the state, right?
Scott: I know that those are always caused by no derpy.
Rym: No, this one was caused by PG&E has the most dilapidated piece of shit power infrastructure in America.
Scott: Well, California is pretty big.
Scott: It's hard to you know, this is like this company is like so negligent Allegedly allegedly allegedly, I'm not a lawyer, you know, isn't this why you always have like those helicopters the chainsaws on the bottom Cutting down the trees and bridges near the power line.
Rym: Rather than open myself up to any possible definite I'm just gonna read this BuzzFeed article this paragraph here PG&E Filed for bankruptcy in January in the face of legal claims.
Scott: How could the power company be bankrupt?
Scott: Are they like not charging enough on the electric bills?
Rym: They're bankrupt because to continue reading in the face of legal claims running into billions of dollars after they got sued for the Fire because their power lines were found were triggered.
Rym: the November 2018 campfire Which destroyed the town of Paradise killed 85 people destroyed almost 20,000 buildings the deadliest wildfire in New York State history, New York I keep saying New York, California State history.
Scott: So that liability and losing the lawsuit is.
Rym: and because they're a private company They were like we're bankrupt.
Rym: You can't do shit to us now.
Rym: Okay, because that's how that works because they're a private company is bankrupt.
Rym: The power companies bankrupt because they killed a lot of people and destroyed a town.
Rym: right because they're negligent to an extreme degree.
Rym: So they still are the entity providing power during all this.
Scott: Yeah, I mean bankrupt companies continue to operate depending on the chapter.
Rym: yeah, and basically what's happening is they have said because of.
Rym: Well because of climate change and the fact that there's this huge drought really hot weather and Really strong winds in California was over a while ago.
Rym: No, there's still drought stuff going on.
Rym: Okay, that the state is at a huge huge risk of like way worse wildfires.
Scott: Well, I don't live there.
Scott: one of the reasons, uh Earthquake fall into the sea.
Rym: this power company their power lines bears would if a wildfire happened There's a good chance is because these power lines caused it because they're so old and shitty because they've already caused wildfires.
Rym: so the only way to prevent these wildfires right now because this company is such a piece of shit is for this company to Cut off power to everyone.
Rym: They're just turning off the power for maybe weeks We don't know.
Scott: it seems like maybe the problem is even like we're even.
Scott: obviously if you had Mel maintain power lines It would be less of an issue.
Rym: This would not be an issue with well-maintained power.
Scott: But also it seems like another solution might be just to like not run power lines through the fucking woods.
Scott: No, it's have more power plants that no every town.
Rym: no No, I do.
Rym: I do not even have the energy to get into you with this.
Scott: This can hold fucking trees, right?
Scott: Uh, and and burn down.
Rym: guys Why do you think we use high-tension power lines in the first place?
Scott: Cuz you don't have too many power plants are expensive.
Rym: Uh, why do you think we have a national power grid?
Scott: Because you got a lot of electricity you got a you know, you got to use it all.
Rym: The problem here is that these power lines are necessary and should be well maintained.
Rym: because they are so poorly maintained They are likely to start wildfires due to these extreme weather conditions.
Rym: So the only way to prevent those wildfires right now is To cut off power to potentially millions of people.
Scott: I guess it'll be really easy to maintain them if they're not powered up.
Rym: They're not going to.
Rym: they're just gonna leave the power off until the wildfire conditions aren't that bad?
Rym: Yeah The only actually yeah, so here's what I'm getting at.
Scott: you're blaming But yeah You don't live in.
Rym: if you want to read the stories to find out all these details because we're not journalists here I'm just.
Rym: my point is much more simple.
Rym: There should not be private power companies anywhere in the United States.
Scott: I'll be a private utility anyway.
Rym: power water Internet should be utilities provided by the government housing health care mail Transportation I'm getting there all those.
Scott: And then I think that's all of them.
Rym: Housing.
Rym: I I think there is okay to have a private housing market with the caveat that in dense places like New York City There should not be private ownership of residential properties.
Scott: I think there should also.
Scott: there should be sufficient public housing that no one should be without a house.
Scott: There can also be private housing.
Rym: Yeah, but I'm but it depends on the area like in New York City.
Rym: I do not think there should be private ownership of any residential property.
Rym: But in like bumblefuck sure you can own some little land with a house on it.
Scott: the point is no.
Scott: Every anyone who needs a house.
Rym: Here's the broader point.
Rym: people who like to point at countries like Venezuela Or they used to point at the Soviet Union be like, oh look their power infrastructure is failing.
Rym: Look at the fucking United States.
Rym: This is a ridiculous disaster of a story that is now being talked about as much as it should be.
Rym: this should be well.
Rym: This would be front page in every newspaper if it weren't for the fact that we're in the middle of our ninth constitutional crisis.
Rym: Yeah, so pay attention to the story.
Scott: New York doesn't have these problems.
Rym: yeah, meanwhile Scott actually has a non depressing news.
Scott: Okay, I mean so if you want to impress somebody this week and you live somewhere, that's not New York City That's not covered in light pollution.
Scott: You can actually see the other habitable planets in this universe and gal Galaxy that are not the earth Someplace or her.
Scott: maybe maybe bad things aren't happening.
Scott: Maybe worse things are happening who knows?
Rym: yeah They're not.
Rym: just might be genocidal warfare and butlerian jahads and a eyes and what's going on out there.
Scott: But if you were live somewhere where you can see that there is gonna be Fuck the fuck crazy amounts of fucking meteor showers and shooting stars real soon I think there's like the Draconid meteor or whatever.
Rym: they're gonna be Back-to-back nights.
Scott: yeah the southern torrid one It's like basically all these meteor showers are gonna be like at peak meteor shower activity Same time all up in yep, so the Draconid is already peak.
Scott: So I'm someone who doesn't know that's gonna happen and be like Scott You're a magician or that you're gonna.
Scott: You know be like oh, man.
Rym: Whatever shooting star shows up The Draconids peaked two nights ago, that's already passed.
Scott: well there you go.
Rym: the southern torrid peaked last night.
Rym: that also already passed.
Scott: well It's still pretty high activity though.
Rym: Yeah, but the Pete with the peaks already happened in both of these stories old.
Scott: Oh, no I Mean I can't blame me.
Scott: I was moving and I can't see the sky.
Rym: This is literally the second paragraph of the article.
Scott: I didn't read the dates one two.
Scott: it was on Google News as like a new story.
Rym: I don't think you read the fourth or fifth sentence of this article.
Scott: When was the article posted though?
Rym: I don't know, but it was updated yesterday 730 p.m.. Yeah, see so anyway Okay, so I hope you saw those meteor showers.
Scott: I mean that was only the peak though You'll probably still see some crazy meteor action.
Rym: Maybe I don't know that much about him.
Scott: I mean you know it's like.
Scott: I assume if it peaks that it's not just like what you know.
Scott: there's still lots of you know.
Scott: It's just not at the peak activity.
Scott: It's that slightly less.
Rym: I'm sure the listener will tell us more about that.
Scott: I think it also depends.
Scott: you got to be in the right place on earth to see them right.
Scott: I think if you're like maybe in the Arizona area you might see them better.
Rym: Yeah, well the tricky part too is living in New York City the sky see shit like it does not get dark here.
Rym: No Like to the point that the the park near a house like the lights are a nice power outage would help us out.
Rym: Like right now the lights are all broken.
Scott: go start a wildfire upstate.
Scott: So they'll turn off the power and we can see the sky.
Rym: because I'm actually kind of okay because New York City is so Relatively dense and small that I'm kind of okay with the fact that it just kind of always lit here Because it's such a tiny geographic area.
Rym: That's always lit.
Rym: hmm You can't.
Rym: there's no way to avoid that with a city like this.
Scott: Turn off the fucking lights.
Rym: What do you mean?
Rym: turn off the lights at night then?
Rym: no then no one could see.
Rym: yeah stay fucking Side I go outside at night all the time.
Scott: Don't go to bed.
Scott: See this guy.
Scott: I'm always shocked though.
Scott: I do see like on the High Line and other places There are like you know Astronomy clubs like in New York that do like sky watching like what the fuck are you looking at the moon?
Scott: And that's it.
Scott: you can occasionally see some stuff here like it's like moon Venus Jupiter They're looking at.
Rym: all you got to do is go a little bit upstate and you can see every goddamn star.
Scott: That's right, but why are they on the High Line Nancy and Jack?
Rym: Yeah?
Rym: I do not know.
Scott: maybe there's looking at the moon I Maybe they're looking in some windows seems people shooting rooms But anyway things of the day.
Rym: so check this out.
Rym: Borax is actually a really important thing.
Rym: I use borax now.
Rym: people use borax for a long stretch of human history.
Scott: I only ever used borax in not even school but in Like summer program where I was doing science II stuff, and we made play-doh of the borax and that's good play-doh The good way to use borax.
Scott: also you got to be careful when you do it.
Rym: No borax is like super safe.
Scott: No, no, no, I mean like you know I'm making the play-doh.
Rym: Yeah, I gotta be careful.
Rym: I made that play-doh there that play-doh.
Rym: if you fuck up you can hurt yourself a little bit, but borax is a cool thing.
Rym: that's really really useful and It's really heavy and to use it like in an industrial capacity.
Rym: You need a lot of it.
Rym: so Borax has been collected and transported for a long long time.
Rym: and To make a long story short because I don't want to get into the history of borax Now, but I will get into it to the future because it's a topic that I'm actually Weirdly interested in and know more about than I should.
Rym: but anyway this video shows how the old wagons That had to each be able to carry like a thousand pounds of borax in an era when you made wagons out of wood.
Rym: This is people making 600 pound tires With 300 pound hubs to put on these gigantic wooden wagons.
Rym: And it is really cool and fascinating to see how with relatively simple tools You can make these insane wheels well tires technically mm-hmm.
Rym: It's a really good video.
Rym: It's like a half hour long cuz it's.
Rym: uh You know people talk about like machine porn or manufacturing porn.
Rym: This is woodworking porn.
Scott: It's really good Was my thing today.
Scott: Oh, yeah, so we all know.
Scott: I hope you know about the.
Scott: you know the the history of The gender reveal party basically the story straight.
Rym: people had a terrible idea.
Scott: One person came up with this idea and like articles are written about it And they basically had a party and at the part if you don't know maybe it's not a thing outside America But I hope it's not a thing outside of America.
Scott: They had a little party because they had a baby and they wanted to like sort of be like surprise.
Scott: It's a boy slash girl right by You know cutting a cake or something and like the inside of the cake is pink or blue.
Scott: Or you pop a balloon and pink or blue confetti comes out like you have some interesting way Some mechanism by which you you know surprise reveal what the whether the baby is you know?
Scott: Has a penis or not?
Rym: yeah now obviously there's already a problem here because that only determines biological sex within a spectrum something that only You know.
Scott: straight bad people who are old way thinking would think to do and obviously all Right thinking people like us realize how stupid and bad this is etc.
Scott: It's ironic that the first baby who was revealed at that first gender reveal party is Like a girl who wears suits.
Scott: I guess is not a not a straight person at all.
Scott: And also the person who had that first party kind of regrets it and wish it didn't become a thing.
Rym: Yeah, this trend has gotten weird.
Rym: in fact There's a big story about a huge wildfire caused by a gender reveal gone wrong.
Rym: right a lot.
Rym: a lot of Hicks are using guns And explosives in their gender reveals anyway, so there was a really great Gender.
Scott: whenever gender reveals go wrong or it hilarious stuff gets posted on the internet.
Scott: So here are people they got a black balloon because obviously it's opaque.
Scott: you can't see what's inside must be from Toronto.
Scott: Maybe they're trying to smash you know pinata the giant black balloon.
Scott: Supposedly something will come out of the balloon revealing the gender of the or the the sex of the baby.
Rym: But apparently instead the baby's gender or sex was revealed to be the sex of the baby, but they're saying gender.
Scott: They're wrong.
Scott: Yeah and It's awesome video because they totally fail.
Rym: they fail so badly And the response to it is wonderful because either the baby's sex is the sky or the black balloon or has escaped the gender binary.
Scott: right yeah this the comments and there the Retweets with quote on this.
Scott: not the video is excellent on its own But the videos like a Renaissance.
Rym: you know that video where the the golf cart on the football field like runs away And you like you watch this like drama unfold.
Rym: It's similar in scale to that in terms of how badly it goes for them.
Scott: Yep, and then an additional.
Scott: I have a second Addendum thing of the day, it's sort of.
Scott: it's not from the onion But it's from an onion II kind of site with a fake story, and it's basically like oh, yeah Adventurers have alignment reveal.
Rym: He's chaotic evil.
Scott: It's chaotic evil.
Scott: yeah, it's not a sex reveal party.
Rym: is yeah alignment only In The meta moment the GeekNights booklet book remains the tale of Genji.
Rym: as the weather gets worse and worse We're more likely a new.
Scott: There was a discovery.
Rym: I was gonna bring this up, and you beat me to it.
Rym: So do we have to include that now?
Rym:  no, okay, okay?
Scott: We are going to read the The penguin deluxe unabridged tale of Genji once got linked to on the website.
Scott: Yes, the one that is linked on the website.
Scott: That's the addition.
Scott: We are going to be discussing.
Scott: I'm sure you probably won't be lost in the discussion.
Scott: you read some other version, but regardless that's the version We're gonna read, but yeah, they found another like Section of the book that was written different members all written by hand.
Scott: It's not like they had printing press copy machines And it had different wordings of a section.
Scott: and no you know I got to translate that biz.
Scott: so yeah They discovered some more tale of Genji.
Rym: yep You do not have to read that additional tale of Genji to do our book club.
Scott: Don't worry We'll see how significant it is.
Rym: I'm sure soon yep, and otherwise we will be live at PAX Unplugged doing not one But two events.
Rym: one of those events is actually three mini events meaning We're doing four things that PAX Unplugged other than playing tabletop games for the entire time never stopping That's right, so we will be doing a brand new panel that I'm really excited about.
Rym: We've been wanting to do this one at a packs for a while But PAX Unplugged is like the perfect place to do it.
Rym: We're doing a panel called take your fucking turn.
Scott: is it called take your fucking?
Rym: well It's it's called take your a bunch of characters turn.
Rym: Okay Because the panel is we're going to talk about Why people don't take their turn in board games how to take.
Rym: we're gonna teach you how to take your turn fast.
Rym: We're gonna talk about game design and sociology and all the things that cause people to not take their turns fast.
Scott: Also games being slow games yelling.
Scott: sometimes some games slower faster than others.
Rym: Yeah, I'd like to give you a preview.
Rym: some tires faster slow and others sometimes.
Rym: It's the players fault.
Rym: sometimes It's the game's fault.
Scott: It's the game's fault more often than you think.
Scott: yep Not to say it's never the players fault.
Rym: some games could be fast But if a certain player is a certain way the game will be ruined and be extra slow.
Scott: some games All right are fast or slow depending on details like oh we played Dominion.
Scott: it took two seconds Again curses or everybody.
Scott: well takes forever.
Rym: Yeah, I've been down down that road before yep Or even our space train game.
Rym: that game might have actually gone a lot faster if we had rusted those spaceships earlier.
Rym: Yep, so some games have time traps in them.
Rym: so brand brand new.
Rym: talk first time ever.
Rym: so be fun to see how this one Goes.
Rym: and then we'll be doing a. learn to play and win where we're gonna teach you how to learn and win.
Rym: Cockroach poker Play learn.
Rym: we're gonna teach you the game.
Rym: We're gonna teach you how to win the game, and then we're going to all play the game together cockroach poker Ganshan clever and Wizard.
Scott: we can only teach people how to win the first one in the third one.
Scott: I don't know how to win Ganshan clever.
Scott: I I can't even get to.
Scott: that's pretty clever I think.
Rym: actually what I'm gonna teach people how to win in Ganshan clever is Learn how to win Yahtzee and just apply those skills as best you can.
Scott: yeah I think I don't think we were qualified to help you how to win that game.
Scott: Yeah, it's too hard.
Rym: We were gonna give some previews of our current early Heuristics of how to play that game that we have not vetted thoroughly.
Scott: why don't we find an expert and get their advice?
Rym: Why don't we just play the game like a hundred times before packs unplug?
Rym: We got a lot?
Rym: We got some time.
Scott: come on over.
Rym: I'm game.
Scott: So
Rym: uh stay tuned PAX Unplugged is coming and not too long after that is packs Uh South and before PAX South is magfest Which is also mag year because it's over New Year's and then not too long after that is PAX East And then before you know it PAX West again.
Rym: We go to a lot of packs is also I think pack sauce is this weekend.
Rym: Yeah, obviously we didn't make it.
Rym: We will return to a pack sauce someday Mm-hmm.
Rym: I'm vaguely planning on returning to pack sauce.
Rym: I don't know if you want to come not next year because I'm going to Japan But if not the year after next year then almost definitely the year after the year after the next year meaning the following year.
Scott: Did you know that the in?
Scott: for there are many enforcers at packs us who are GeekNights listeners.
Scott: Oh, I'm well I'm wearing one of whom is in charge of the entire Panels department at packs us.
Scott: if you are at packs us and you find the enforcer who is in charge of the entire panels department They listen to this show so you can connect with them socially.
Rym: in fact.
Rym: actually I will say a lot of enforcers at pack sauce Listen to this show and the enforcers at pack sauce are fucking awesome.
Scott: group of people Not gonna hear the show cuz they're busy.
Scott: packs awesome probably right now.
Scott: Yes in Australia.
Scott: It's already tomorrow, right?
Rym: Yeah, it is in New York.
Rym: It is Thursday night.
Scott: So in Australia, it must be Friday right expects us.
Rym: is type time in Australia into Google the better.
Rym: You don't use the world time buddy.
Scott: No just go to Google and type time in Australia.
Rym: No, I'm gonna the world time buddy.
Rym: Okay fine cuz I'm gonna put in a bunch of time zones here.
Rym: We can put every packs here and make the packs dashboard.
Scott: We don't need them.
Scott: Anyway, actually I use this site a lot because what the fuck day and time is it in Melbourne?
Rym: Yeah, oh right now right now in Melbourne is it writing 652 p.m.
Rym: On Thursday October.
Rym: oh, I died I put in I changed the time.
Scott: This is why I just said go to Google and type time in Australia.
Rym: I will link to world time buddy though because I've noticed if you are the kind of person who is like I said It's 10 a.m.
Scott: On Friday.
Scott: in fact packs awesome is gonna start in eight minutes from right now when I'm recording this I guess anyone watching live on YouTube is getting waiting in line to get into the pack saws.
Rym: Yep, all I gotta say is if you were there liberate Hong Kong revolution of our time.
Rym: So let's get into this moving.
Scott: we did a show about moving when we 2006 right cuz we moved to beacon in 2004 five ish and started GeekNights not too long after in October.
Scott: oh five it's currently October 19 so GeekNights is 14 years old which is terrifying in its own right.
Rym: in fact We are coming up because GeekNights started on October 31st 2005. that was the first published public episode of GeekNights.
Rym: We're coming up on our 15th fucking year
Scott: 15th year okay,
Rym: yeah,
Scott: anyway the point is We did a show around then about moving because we had recently moved from Rochester to beacon
Rym: and that was in fact the first like Full move of a house or apartment that I had ever done where it wasn't like my family moving.
Scott: It was on you.
Rym: It was on me.
Scott: It was really on me.
Rym: Yeah, well I had a lot of shit I had to move to.
Scott: my parents only helped me the tiniest bit when I moved stuff out of colony and into a storage box.
Rym: Yep, and I just I didn't.
Rym: I just packed all my shit in a car and drove it to Poughkeepsie.
Scott: at one point You had a lot less shit.
Scott: I guess I don't know.
Scott: yeah all that furniture There's no didn't you drive it all to the beach first.
Rym: I drove everything I owned except my furniture to Wild World.
Rym: I drove it to Lansing, Michigan.
Rym: actually all right Right right.
Rym: then I drove it a few days later from Lansing, Michigan to Wildwood Left it in my car in Wildwood for like a month, and then I drove it anyway.
Scott: Be on that show.
Rym: to that point when I drove that car I couldn't see out any windows But the front and my left window and I had a monitor that was precariously balanced.
Scott: next to the point is I did that show.
Scott: We only talked about that move specifically.
Scott: We did not talk about moving as a general topic and also we were young.
Rym: we probably did an episode about moving in general But Rym probably deleted it yep But we were also young and dumb so we had some ideas about moving and the way we handled the move was definitely colored by The fact that we didn't know a lot about it.
Rym: We wanted to do it all ourselves because we're stupid.
Rym: a lot of money Yeah, we did.
Rym: we still spent a lot of money despite not wanting to spend a lot of money nearly as much money As much as now yep, but that truck was not cheap No, and also that truck was way too big and I was not qualified to drive a truck.
Scott: that big right all right.
Scott: So uh so I'm moving.
Scott: so you live in one place You want to live in another place.
Scott: my first piece of advice to you is don't own so much shit like I do.
Scott: Yes, if you don't have a lot of shit You can just fucking get your ass up and go the fuck anywhere and life is great if you have an excuse.
Rym: if you were Moving because you're forced to you're because you want to it doesn't matter.
Rym: Consider moving an excuse to look at everything you own and try to get rid of as much of it as possible.
Rym: That's right.
Scott: Don't be like me and have too much nerdy shit.
Scott: You can't let go of.
Scott: I'm not at the hoarder level Right like some people, but I do have enough shit to where it is a burden.
Scott: But I cannot part with most of it.
Scott: I just started with a nice hefty piles, but I still have.
Rym: I just looked up And I have a. I have a shelf for all the like batteries for all the like video GeekNights stuff And I just noticed I have a battery for a camera.
Rym: I have not owned in years.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: That's the kind of thing.
Scott: It's the kind of thing you would throw out if you moved.
Rym: I'm gonna give this to you.
Rym: You could use this battery for that camera I gave you.
Scott: when you're just living in a place you don't notice a thing like that.
Scott: And maybe you do notice and you say I'll take care of that later.
Rym: But if you have to get all your shit out of every place you've squirreled it away for a decade and put it into boxes You immediately realize that you own way too much shit, right?
Scott: So if you follow that advice, you don't own too much shit.
Scott: moving is like a fucking piece of cake, right?
Scott: You just take the little shit you have rent like one the smallest.
Scott: you haul at most Right and you put everything in.
Scott: you go to the new place you end one lease you start another lease you sign a mortgage.
Scott: That's not part of this episode Right and you put all the shit in it.
Scott: It'll take you a day or maybe some transportation time.
Scott: Not a big deal.
Scott: You don't need to hire help.
Scott: You don't need to really do much.
Scott: life is grand, right?
Scott: So moving is really only a topic we're discussing for people who got too much stuff.
Rym: Yep No, even if you don't have too much stuff moving is still kind of a pain in the ass.
Rym: Cuz even if I do not have too much is the less stuff you have?
Scott: moving becomes Exponentially easier and yell more stuff you have.
Scott: it becomes exponentially more difficult with each added stuff.
Rym: yep, the other very important thing that I learned from all these moves that I didn't quite internalize until I was older is Every time you move you pretty much just throw away any IKEA furniture you have Survive.
Scott: I saved the bookcases.
Rym: Oh nice And a lot of my IKEA furniture.
Scott: What IKEA furniture survived?
Scott: none other than the book other than Billy bookcases I saved.
Scott: I think.
Scott: no IKEA furniture that comes to mind.
Scott: Yeah I my bed I had.
Scott: My junk collectors came and smashed up the bed and took it.
Scott: the dresser also taken away by junk collectors.
Scott: the desk gone.
Scott: Oh the the wheelie a file cabinet that came with the desk was actually still is in great condition But I bought a Newer better IKEA file a cabinet thing That's just superior.
Scott: and now the old one is rolling around my new apartment empty and will be disposed of soon.
Rym: So what's interesting is I was once one.
Rym: Let me know I have all these memories because as a kid like you've lived in pretty much the same house your whole childhood.
Rym: But we actually move my house The.
Scott: I lived in three places But only one of them was a place I lived in from like the ages of like 2 to 18.
Scott: So my memories of the other two places are zero and minuscule.
Rym: See I was born in.
Rym: I was born in Detroit like the house on Berkshire.
Rym: I'm trying to run.
Rym: so I was born in this house in Berkshire, which I remember Barely, but I have these vague memories of this house.
Rym: Then we moved to a rental house like really temporarily during another move And then we moved to the house on Harvard also in Detroit.
Rym: Then we moved to Anchor Bay like New Baltimore for a while, then we moved to sterling heights And in sterling heights, we're actually looking at buying a different house in the same town and moving to that house But we didn't actually do it.
Rym: Then I moved to RIT and that was when I brought way too much shit with me.
Rym: Then we moved to the apartment in colony and then after living there for a while They kicked us out for a summer and we had to move back into that place.
Rym: That was a pain in the ass.
Rym: Then we moved to Beacon.
Rym: then we both split into the apartments in New York and then you moved to a new apartment in New York.
Rym: so I moved a bunch of times in my life as a kid.
Rym: Doesn't matter moving is just awesome when you're a kid.
Rym: the adults were super stressed every time Like movers were coming and packing stuff up and strangers were in the house and we're like taking things apart And I just remember enjoying every second of it and reveling in the chaos.
Scott: Yeah There's a lot of things that go on moving as a kid, right?
Scott: It's like new school.
Scott: Yeah, so as I can it can up end all that stuff, but I've never experienced that.
Scott: I've experienced it through the media and through other people.
Rym: What was really interesting is that just by chance my brother got a lot more of that disruption.
Rym: But based on my age I every time we moved was at a clear like separation point between one type of school and another.
Rym: we moved Right at the end of elementary school as I was going into middle school.
Rym: We moved at the end of middle school as I was going into high school.
Rym: So it made it like really really easy.
Scott: I mean, I did semi experience it right like, you know times were like I changed like even when I change schools It's still in the same town, but it was like a lot of new people.
Scott: It was almost like, you know, oh, we were like really new towns every time I even though I was in the same house at home.
Scott: that didn't move right?
Scott: It's still.
Scott: you know I still had that social upheaval by switching a school or like switching a summer camp stuff like that.
Scott: No, you know experiencing the new people thing.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I could just imagine moving being sort of like that with the school situation.
Rym: Yep, and I have all these just vague kid memories of like the adults packing and everyone point I was carrying around a two-liter bottle of cream soda and just drinking from it.
Rym: And I don't think my parents knew I had this bottle.
Rym: and then I was drinking the whole thing.
Rym: And I just remember like watching these movers having a really hard time trying to get this really giant piece of antique furniture Into the rental house that we're only gonna be in for like a month and I just remember standing there watching them Just like this very crystal-clear kid memory.
Rym: But anyway, that's no that's really relevant And you're the stressed-out person who's got a move.
Rym: yeah, that's what we're all gonna be.
Scott: so option one Spend a fuck ton of money.
Rym: I'm gonna say this somebody take care of every goddamn thing if you can afford that Even if it's a stretch.
Scott: afford that your life is already easy.
Rym: Yeah But like that is expensive even for us.
Scott: there are people who you can pay who will come.
Scott: Pack up all your things you have to do.
Scott: live lift no finger whatsoever.
Scott: They'll pack up all your shit at your instruction.
Scott: Take it to where you are moving to Unpack it and place it where it belongs in the new place according to your instruction Like to the level of they will put your clothes in the right closets, right?
Scott: You will leave the place.
Scott: Look it look.
Scott: you will just get up and walk out of your house Like you're going to the mall or whatever or going out to dinner like go on vacation for the weekend.
Scott: You'll go on vacation or go to a hotel or go wherever you're gonna go and then they'll tell you they're done and you will Or they'll schedule and you'll know when they'll be done and you arrive and at the new place every.
Scott: Your silverware is already in the drawer your clothes are in the closet Your TV is plugged in into the entertainment center Which is fully set up and ready to use.
Scott: if you can't afford this do it.
Scott: Also.
Rym: Fuck you.
Rym: Yeah Dynamite a rich person I would say it.
Rym: I don't actually know how much that would cost But I would try would save up to try to do it depending on where I was moving.
Scott: It depends on how far you're moving and how much stuff you have, right?
Rym: Yeah But yeah That's that kind of service is actually pretty reasonable price if you were moving from Relatively small apartment to other relatively small apartment in the same city Yeah, but if you're moving like a house to a house that would cost like more than a car Right.
Scott: So the net I mean, you know, you could.
Scott: so basically that service that is the top tier moving service.
Scott: You can moving companies allow you to scale that service down to basically almost nothing.
Scott: Yep And everywhere in between what I would recommend dream granularity, right?
Scott: It's like well, I want you to unpack my stuff But not pack it.
Scott: I want you to pack some stuff, but not everything.
Scott: I want you to at every level.
Scott: if I want you to take it this far But don't take it all the way.
Scott: take move this stuff, but not that stuff.
Scott: You can literally with every measure of granularity the moving companies the good ones will service and price you Accordingly,
Rym: yep, right the the sweet spot in terms of like even if your money sensitive Which you should be because then the the sweet spot is pretty much get a moving company.
Rym: That is a real company That is that has insurance and is bonded.
Scott: Yep A lot of buildings will check or you know to make sure not use non insured moving companies.
Scott: because like if you live in a certain kind of building as opposed right they then they'll want to make sure that the They'll want proof that they're insured.
Scott: Otherwise, they won't let him in.
Scott: because yeah That's the thing that means that if those movers bust something up in the building like say the elevator Then who's gonna pay for that?
Scott: well when we move insurance would pay for that if they had insurance.
Rym: so the last time we moved before we came for like When we were moving to New York City out of our house and beacon use three Russian dudes in a truck.
Rym: No, we use three Georgian dudes in the trucks.
Rym: Okay, right, but With they caused a surprising amount of damage to the house on the way out.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: In fact almost immediately they put a giant hole in the ceiling.
Rym: Yep, so We were just.
Rym: we were just on the hook for that.
Rym: Yeah, that was just awesome.
Rym: Yep So, uh, make sure they've got insurance and actually check to see that that's not just fake.
Rym: If there are a lot of moving companies that are scams the moving company is super pro like the one I just hired.
Scott: They're like, oh by the way, if any buildings ask for insurance mama, it's like they they're upfront about the insurance.
Scott: Yep, right They took care of everything.
Rym: find a real moving company and get a real quote from them.
Scott: and the sweet spot Yeah, real quotes from several real moving come.
Rym: Yes Because moving companies don't just post prices.
Rym: Anyone who says a flat rate is probably a scam and it's probably gonna fuck you over.
Scott: No the way that the way the moving company they wanted to know they had to give them an estimate and then a quote.
Scott: Right and the estimate.
Scott: they wanted to know exactly what I was moving the exact amount of stuff like one bed 10 small boxes 20 medium boxes five large box Oh and along those lines one if you want to estimate couch to bookcase one TV.
Scott: It's like they want to know an exact list of what you're moving and then they give you a price based on that.
Rym: However, many boxes you think you need you probably need a literally a third more than that.
Scott: Well, the thing is my move actually would have been pretty easy.
Scott: The only thing that ruined me was the Books, I have so many.
Scott: And the thing with books is they're heavy as hell.
Rym: So you have to use the small box.
Scott: You have to use small.
Scott: right you think oh, I'll just get a few big boxes and put all my stuff in it.
Scott: Well, then you can't lift that box dumbass.
Scott: Yeah, right you have to get.
Scott: for heavy things You need small boxes and lots of them and for light fluffy things You can get big boxes, right all the other very important books fit in 40 small boxes.
Scott: Well, it sounds about right and the price it cost to move the boxes.
Scott: now You got to do some calculations like well What if I just get rid of this shit and just buy it again?
Scott: if I actually that's usually cheaper If I actually need it, I'll buy it again.
Scott: if I get rid of it and never need that want to read that book again Then it wasn't a loss that I got rid of it and I saved money by not moving.
Scott: Yeah, right you to make these kinds of calculation.
Rym: There's a subtle point here about those boxes.
Rym: Buy new boxes.
Rym: Hopefully they're made from recycled material, but buying new boxes Yeah buy new boxes that are all the same sizes and shapes like if you need three kinds of boxes by 50 of each kind of box.
Scott: I bought all boxes that were made by the same company.
Rym: Yeah, and try to avoid you line because there's like conservative shit that goes on with that company.
Scott: The other.
Scott: I bought bankers box.
Scott: I don't know if they're better or worse.
Scott: I'm not endorsing whatever.
Scott: The reason I chose them was good.
Scott: They had lids.
Rym: Yeah, you line is like super partisan and bad like do not Don't do any business any.
Rym: you line anything even though they have them like a stranglehold on this stuff.
Scott: But anyway, the point is the boxes I got had lids which makes it great for moving because you don't have to like seal the Box of tape and then well that's sealed.
Scott: you can keep rearranging and cramming more stuff in the boxes You know to hopefully reduce your costs and opening and closing them and rearranging Tetris thing, right?
Scott: Yep, but yeah, so it took me in order to save money.
Scott: I packed my own shit.
Rym: Yep, sweet spot Here's the deal.
Rym: pack your own shit except for All your furniture.
Rym: have the movers pack that.
Rym: take it apart all that nonsense, right?
Rym: Cuz they're gonna have a bunch of stuff You don't own that you don't want to buy and rent Like all the moving pads and the bubble wrap and all the stuff to like.
Rym: make that happen Unless you are a professional and you know what you're doing.
Rym: You're gonna fuck that up, right?
Rym: You think you've wrapped it securely that you're gonna break shit.
Rym: you're gonna break way more things than you realize.
Scott: It's also gonna take all fucking day, right?
Scott: It's like how long did it take us to get right in the old the last moving episode?
Scott: We talked about getting that fucking couch.
Rym: Oh my god into the apartment.
Rym: Oh, it took us over an hour to get one a one thing into our apartment.
Scott: But meanwhile when we got when we moved out a beacon Right that the junk collecting donating people picked it up and walked out in like a minute even those Georgian dudes Even though they were not bonded and not insured.
Rym: They knew their shit.
Rym: So they emptied over all the furniture Every piece of furniture that was still in that house in less time than it took us to get that fucking couch right from the truck To the porch.
Scott: It took me weeks to put all my shit into boxes And even then a lot of shit didn't actually make it into a box.
Scott: It was kind of a little bit haphazard.
Scott: Yeah, a lot of leftovers and knickknacks here and there.
Scott: those movers came in.
Scott: It took them an hour to empty the apartment like BAM Like in all the furniture all the boxes all the stuff that was poorly packed.
Scott: Yeah, I'll bet everything and that included, you know, Oh getting new boxes and packing more shit.
Rym: pay for that.
Rym: Do not just try to put it all in the truck yourself.
Scott: unless you try to have a minimalist life That's a lot of money But that's partially because they made two stops before then arriving at the destination right to pick up someone else's stuff, right?
Scott: But yeah, it was like the it's like if I hadn't had paid that money.
Scott: I would have been so burned if I had to do that some other way Especially because there's a big.
Rym: there's one thing that goes on here with houses and moving.
Scott: I would have basically my alternative y'all like would have done is either a completely fuck up.
Scott: Yep, or be suffer a great deal.
Rym: Moving.
Scott: see all of the above moving to get rid of all my shit.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: moving from a house to a house is easier in one sense in that you have a whole house to like stage.
Rym: Yeah, I do the overlap period like.
Rym: I'm not gonna explain to you how mortgages work But usually you'll have like a 30 60 or 90 day residency and all this stuff meaning You will still have your house and have like between one and three months of having the new house.
Rym: So you have time to move stuff with apartments and leases and like the way we all at least Ended on a day and the new lease.
Rym: I had a 15-day overlap and even though we got money We can't afford to pay to New York rent suck.
Rym: now For longer than like a day or two my money went so way down.
Scott: I lost right between moving paying more rents paying security deposits trying to get security buzzes back Paying all these other services besides movies buying new furnitures.
Scott: If you move into your lost a large portion of my money's moving in New York.
Rym: Like if you have a week overlap, like that's as good as you're gonna get.
Rym: that means you like time this perfectly.
Scott: Yeah, I had 15 days and I made it.
Scott: and then even after I've got all this stuff out I had to like keep going back to the old apartment to hire like a cleaning service
Rym: Oh and
Scott: like junk collecting to clean out old stuff and the old place to make it, you know, perfectly empty Again,
Rym: yep,
Scott: and but yeah.
Scott: then when they be the moving company They did great at doing the final bits of packing not all the packing.
Scott: I did most of y'all right getting everything out in a truck bringing it to the new place Putting it all in the new place.
Scott: They put you know The large pieces of furniture where they were directed to but mostly the boxes were just like alright, here's your boxes Unpackings on you.
Scott: Yep, and I'm still not completely unpacked.
Rym: Yeah Oh, it took us a month to unpack.
Scott: when we moved into this We finally have all the furniture and other think.
Scott: the hanging guy came today.
Scott: He hung the shelves and he hung the TV on the wall.
Rym: now in houses when people in the houses I've often heard this strategy that I think is brilliant and we even did it when we were when we moved as kids You only unpack boxes as you need the things in
Scott: them Yep, and if a box never gets unpacked, it means nothing.
Scott: You don't need anything in there.
Scott: Just throw it out Yep, or donate it or whatever Yep.
Rym: So you put all the box.
Rym: after you do the initial unpacking all the boxes that still have stuff in him.
Rym: You just put them in the basement and wait.
Rym: see what happens.
Rym: but in an apartment there's nowhere to put those boxes.
Scott: No my basically All my stuff that in an apartment was efficiently stored in closets in various places Right to save space and clear out room had to get brought out into the open and put in a box.
Scott: There was no room to move around my apartment as I was moving out of it.
Rym: Well, I should post a picture I have when we moved into this apartment because the boxes were taking up all the room.
Scott: I couldn't even get to my desk or anything.
Rym: Our living room is just completely full of boxes and disassembled furniture.
Rym: Yeah, like it's a nightmare picture and I remember.
Rym: I remember this moment.
Rym: I was standing in the living room.
Rym: It was dark because we didn't have the lights unpacked yet.
Rym: I was by myself.
Rym: I was looking at this giant pile of shit Despairing at the world.
Rym: Yep, and I just closed my eyes and I imagined to myself there will be a day Maybe not now maybe not next week But there will be a day where all of this has Transformed into.
Rym: there is a couch and a TV and I'm gonna sit on that couch and turn on that TV and play a video Game.
Rym: Yep, and a month later.
Rym: I achieved that dream.
Scott: I'm gonna be at that day like within a week Yeah, and then you will start resuming your life.
Rym: Yep You still have time to join our burning wheel game.
Rym: I haven't even uploaded my character yet.
Scott: Maybe I'm more concerned with other things.
Scott: I got to take care of.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, we also got some GeekNights stuff We got to do and we've got on for over an hour.
Rym: So I think we're just done.
Rym: Okay?
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Rym: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Greg Oliver, I'll enjoy setting a nickel just like a dude guy.
Rym: kajar topish and William Eisen rose link eg hydrated ganon boogaloo Jennifer Hitchcock Chrisman give my steady calm.
Rym: Jay pants Shawn Yeager Nicholas Brando Let's see if Rym says Toronto properly for two.
Rym: on creations in West Philadelphia.
Rym: born and raised Shervin Von Harl Rory Superboy Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin drew open letter Finn dread Lily Tenebrae Sean Klein Chris Reimer Thomas Hahn.
Rym: liberate Hong Kong.
Rym: revolution of our age and now I leave you with Always right.