Rym: It's Tuesday, April 9th, 2019.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: We are back from convention season and now we're on our regularly scheduled nonsense for the foreseeable future.
Rym: and tonight we are talking about Baba is you.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So I'm coming home to do the show.
Rym: Scott's already here.
Scott: And the seven train is broken?
Rym: Yeah, that's not my ad.
Rym: The seven train being broken would not be worthy.
Scott: I was gonna say that better not be your lame-o opening.
Rym: Unless I broke it.
Rym: Okay, then it would be if I broke the seven train I think it would be worthy.
Scott: Or you saw someone break it at least.
Rym: If I knew, like if I witnessed its breakage even then it would have to be a noteworthy breakage, but I don't know.
Rym: So I'm in Grand Central.
Rym: I'm getting ready to go down to the seven train and deal with all that and there's usually people in Grand Central like playing music and busking and like there's a permit system where like anyone can do it.
Scott: Well, there's official ones and non-official ones.
Rym: Yeah, but the non-official ones are very well tolerated and usually in the morning there's a sad old guy playing a melodica and he's clearly trying to learn how to play the melodica and he's getting better and better every day over the last like six months.
Scott: Oh, he's actually trying.
Scott: He's not one of those toot toot toot.
Rym: He was playing the Godfather theme like over and over and over again but then he moved on to another song and now he's got like five or six things he can play.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So I'm kind of like.
Rym: I'm proud of that dude.
Rym: Like I'm glad he's progressing.
Scott: Yeah, those are.
Scott: there's some certain songs.
Scott: Godfather theme is one of them.
Scott: that like New York, New York it's like that.
Scott: that's you know not good buskers will try to learn like the main part of and play on repeat to get tourist money.
Rym: Yeah, because it needs to be have a long enough refrain that someone will recognize but won't be there or won't stand around long enough to hear you repeat the same thing over and over again because you never learn the rest of the song.
Rym: Like you learn that first bit of stairway.
Scott: And you can play it slowly and emotionally.
Rym: Yeah, but there's certain genres of music that you tend to hear in the New York City subway.
Rym: It's usually some sort of Showtime thing like an individual person singing really loudly over some like boombox.
Rym: Like there's certain kinds of music you expect to hear.
Scott: Yeah, there's certain genres you don't hear.
Scott: You don't hear my favorite genres like EDM, metal.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You don't hear any of those in the subway.
Rym: So I heard a genre of music on the way home today in the subway.
Rym: I have never encountered down there before.
Scott: What, John?
Scott: Your favorite electro swing in the subway now?
Rym: So you know in like an old Scooby-Doo thing.
Rym: So first off, you know pipe organ music.
Rym: But then there's the variant of pipe organ music that's done with kind of crappy Hammond sounding synths in like the 70s.
Rym: that's often used as the background music in like a Scooby-Doo episode.
Rym: Like scary organ music with like a weird beat like that kind of thing.
Rym: Someone was just fucking playing that.
Scott: They just had Hammond organ in the subway or an electric keyboard?
Rym: It was an electric keyboard set up to sound like that and they had like a backbeat and a drummer and it was basically like a remixed version of scary Scooby-Doo organ music with a beat.
Rym: and I had never heard anything like it before in the New York City subway.
Rym: And I actually stopped to listen to it for four seconds.
Rym: Well, yeah.
Rym: I stood there for four seconds and be like, wait, that's just spooky organ music.
Rym: Who plays spooky organ music in the subway?
Rym: Whatever.
Rym: I gotta go.
Rym: So that was interesting.
Rym: If that ever happens again, I will stop and get a cell phone video.
Rym: So we just dive right in.
Rym: We're back.
Rym: Do gig nights again?
Scott: Yeah, I want to go eat food at my house.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: So we were, as you know, at PAX East and PAX East is the end of our convention season.
Scott: Until PAX West in Labor Day.
Scott: So all summer we're gonna enjoy weather and not enjoy being inside with nerds.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Now in the earliest earliest days of gig nights, we would spend entire episodes reviewing conventions, but it's 2019.
Rym: You know what PAX is.
Rym: So all I want to do is highlight the like the things that were different or notable about this PAX East because PAX East is pretty much the biggest PAX.
Scott: It's the same as it was last time mostly.
Rym: Yeah, though a problem.
Rym: we noticed that we were positing before this PAX that we're like we're worried that this is going to be a trend and I don't know what to do about it.
Rym: And it did continue.
Rym: PAX is, particularly PAX East, not so much PAX West, but PAX East have an interesting problem now where when the Expo Hall closes, the majority of the people in the building just leave.
Rym: So it gets really quiet at night, which used to not be the case at PAX East.
Scott: Tabletop at night, which is always full because that's the place to go when the Expo Hall closes.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But basically I get this impression that all the people who buy single day badges are the kinds of people who tend to come primarily for the Expo Hall.
Rym: And I definitely saw an uptick in people, despite PAX trying to like tell them that there is stuff happening after 6 p.m.
Rym: and that this whole building is theirs, people still seem to primarily leave.
Scott: I mean, if you look on, you know, like PAX communities online, which are there's no single one, there's a bunch of disparate ones.
Rym: The Reddit has like no traffic.
Scott: Yeah, well, it has some, but it doesn't have a ton.
Scott: As always, people coming in talking about like PAX vaporizers for their weed.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There's a brand of vaporizers, PAX, I guess.
Scott: I don't know if the Firefly is a better one.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Anyway, the point is, people in there are, you know, there seem to be like camps in there.
Scott: And the biggest, there's always threads like PAX swag hunters.
Scott: And it's like this people, they're going to PAX specifically for swag.
Scott: When I say what's wrong with you, you materialist, consumerist, shallow human being, they're like, you know, don't hate.
Scott: I'm allowed to like collecting useless swag.
Scott: And that's what I like.
Scott: And I'm saying, yeah, but I'm just still going to hate on you for it anyway, because you're a consumerist, shallow, materialist person.
Scott: And that's bad.
Scott: That's not a good thing to aspire to be.
Rym: There was a time in my life when I wanted two things out of the world.
Rym: I wanted swords and I wanted plastic anime things.
Rym: And the only reason I do not have a lot of those things is because I didn't have money at that time.
Rym: So I don't fault people that joy.
Rym: The only problem it causes is that there are a lot of people who want to go to things like PAX for the entire weekend to experience PAX like we do, like playing tabletop and go to console gaming and like do stuff.
Rym: They're not going to go unless they can go for the whole weekend.
Rym: But there's a limited number of people who can get into the building.
Rym: And now that PAX is all have only single day badges, Saturday sells out.
Rym: And people who would otherwise be those people who go to PAX every year and do what we do, if they can't get Saturday, they just won't go.
Scott: The main problem I'm seeing is just a more general thing in that people come, PAX is really big and people come for a lot of disparate reasons.
Rym: Which should be good.
Rym: It's a merging of all these gaming cultures.
Scott: You know, at other big conventions, that's also the case, right?
Scott: There are people who go to, say, San Diego Comic-Con just to see like preview trailers for movies that aren't out yet or people go to manifest just to get ripped.
Scott: There are people who go to Gen Con just to play like this one.
Scott: They play like one competitive game, say like X-Wing, and they're going just to play a whole bunch of X-Wing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But the problem is when those people go to those other conventions, you know, that guy goes to Gen Con just to play Warhammer.
Scott: Better example, right?
Scott: They get their fill of just Warhammer at Gen Con.
Scott: They don't have any complaints.
Scott: They can fill their whole weekend with Warhammer and they're good.
Scott: They don't care if the rest of Gen Con is servicing someone else.
Scott: That's how it works, right?
Scott: Even though Gen Con has issues, I'm not talking about those right now.
Scott: When you come to PAX, I think the problem is that PAX serves all these different audiences to varying degrees.
Scott: I think that whichever audience you are part of, whichever community you're part of.
Scott: that comes to PAX for a reason.
Scott: It is not necessarily fully servicing, even though it's providing service to all the communities, it's not providing full service.
Scott: So every single different community that comes to PAX from every different angle has at least one thing to complain about.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The swag people complain about something that they don't like, you know, it's like I was waiting in a line.
Scott: You know, I love waiting in lines, you know, to play games even before they're out.
Scott: They just love it.
Scott: They're like, it was bullshit because the exhibitor let a streamer cut everyone in line.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They're mad about something, right?
Scott: The, you know, it's like no matter which part of PAX is yours, there's something that everyone's complaining about, you know, in each different place.
Scott: And they got to fix all those things in each different place to make all the different communities happy.
Rym: Or choose not to fix them and not worry about that community because PAX will sell out regardless.
Scott: I think a bigger problem.
Scott: But it didn't.
Scott: It didn't sell out Thursday or Sunday, only Friday and Saturday.
Rym: So, yeah, the real problem is like the things we'll complain about.
Rym: But this is an opposite complaint or a negative complaint in the sense that it's great for me, but it sucks for PAX and it sucks for the exhibitors.
Rym: People don't really go to PAX East on Thursday.
Rym: No, there was like no one there.
Scott: The logic was, you know, the original logic was like, hey, PAX three days, we have three days of PAX.
Scott: They all sell out.
Scott: We want more people to be able to go and enjoy PAX.
Scott: So we'll sell single day badges and we will add another day.
Scott: Yeah, but the kinds of more total human, different, unique human beings can come and experience PAX.
Scott: And I guess they've achieved that goal because every, you know, unique human being who can get to PAX and wants to experience it can get a ticket because it didn't sell out.
Rym: But they can get a Saturday ticket and the kind of person who wants to go to PAX for one day probably does not want to take Thursday off work.
Scott: Well, that's the thing.
Scott: It worked at PAX West because the fourth day it was, you could take the, you know, you take off work Friday one day, but then the rest of PAX is Saturday, Sunday, Labor Day.
Scott: That fourth day works at East.
Scott: The fourth day does not work.
Scott: It'd be better swapping East if they can't do this probably because they're locked in for quite a while.
Scott: Swap East with South's dates because South has Martin Luther King Day on the Monday.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The South isn't even using that fourth day on the Monday.
Scott: It's just a travel home from San Antonio.
Rym: I think South, you can still get three day badges.
Scott: Yeah, maybe you can.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But yeah, East that fourth day is a Thursday.
Rym: It's like, you know, I feel like there's a Thursday is a problem just because it's a call.
Rym: It probably cost PAX more than they make back from it.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I mean, you know, the exhibitors are not, you know, the big exhibitors don't care.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The extra day doesn't cost them that much extra.
Scott: But the small exhibitors I know have I've heard more than one small exhibitor has complained to me that they don't like the PAX.
Scott: East has Thursday because they now have to pay, you know, 33 whatever percent more money to be there that fourth day.
Scott: And there's no one there on Thursday who's not there on Friday, Saturday or Sunday.
Scott: It's all community people mostly.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Or the lifers, the people who would buy a four day badge like us.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like they're not getting really any extra eyeballs or sales.
Scott: They just lose money on that Thursday and hope to make it up Friday, Saturday, Sunday.
Scott: I think the solution to that specific problem is to do something more like what San Diego Comic-Con does.
Scott: And it's pretty rare that I would use them as a good example.
Scott: But their first day is actually Wednesday night and they call it preview night.
Scott: And it's like you can own.
Scott: they sell a limited number of badges and only some things are open on that night.
Scott: And it's like a special time.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And that's what I think PAX East should do with Thursday is they should open PAX.
Scott: Thursday late, like maybe five p.m.
Scott: or something like four or something like that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And only have it go until like nine or ten, maybe like a five or six hour deal.
Scott: And only sell a limited number of Thursday badges, maybe equal to the number they sold that are still in the green.
Scott: Right.
Scott: A few thousand or so.
Scott: And then it's like you come in, only certain things are on.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There's only certain expo booths that are open, only the big ones, maybe.
Scott: And it's like, look, you can come in, you know, you get a special Thursday badge.
Scott: There hopefully won't be crazy lines.
Scott: You can do some things like maybe go to the Nintendo booth that had a long line and then not have to do it Friday, Saturday.
Rym: So I like the other idea you had of have an area of the expo hall that's not open during the day.
Scott: Well, that's a different idea.
Scott: That's not an idea to solve this problem.
Scott: No, that's just another.
Scott: that's just a cool idea.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, it gets to the broader issue of I feel like there's just.
Scott: this is an adding new cool ideas enough.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Tabletop is innovating with its first look and such, but other areas, not so much.
Rym: So on one hand, there's people like us and the kinds of people who tend to go to tabletop and like console areas.
Rym: And actually, like their main goal at PAX is to play games.
Rym: They want PAX to be as many days as possible.
Rym: They want to just buy a badge to all of the days and they want to just go to the same PAX every year.
Rym: But then you have this opposite need where the exhibitors would they want as many human beings to walk by their booth as possible.
Rym: Anyone who's at PAX more than one day wasted a spot that they could have made more money or gotten more views from.
Rym: And then this third tug of war are the people who only want to go to PAX for one community thing or one specific aspect of PAX.
Rym: Like that year where there was the that there was a sports tournament at PAX and a lot of people got badges just to go.
Scott: There were several sports things at PAX this year.
Scott: Top level is the Smash Brothers North American World Championship.
Scott: There was a huge.
Scott: the biggest one, I think, was the Magic Arena thing.
Scott: There were lots of top.
Scott: it was for the Magic Online Arena thing.
Scott: And they revealed a new expansion for that.
Scott: And there were top level streamers and players all competing in that.
Scott: A streamer I know came in like third place or something.
Scott: It was like, you know, it was way, way big deal.
Scott: That thing was huge.
Rym: All that aside, there's I think the worst aspect of PAX.
Rym: They're like, this was the biggest problem we had this year was that in one of the e-sport tournaments areas, there was a brief moment where some people were playing ice hockey and yes, ice hockey.
Rym: And it was very unfortunate.
Rym: I mean, a little facetious here that the person who was the official emcee, like announcing this thing, apparently had never heard of this sport of hockey and literally had no idea what was going on and proceeded to embarrass himself on stage.
Scott: He embarrassed himself only to us.
Rym: Yeah, no one in the crowd seemed to notice either.
Scott: He didn't seem embarrassed.
Rym: Yeah, he wasn't embarrassed.
Rym: He didn't know.
Rym: most of the crowd didn't know.
Scott: Should have been embarrassed.
Rym: As he kept talking about halftime and was confused about how hockey worked.
Rym: And the poor players didn't really know how the game worked either.
Scott: Yeah, you got to tell the people how it works before you make them play it.
Rym: Or just make them play it, but know how the game works.
Rym: Like, know one thing about hockey.
Rym: Yeah, anyway, I guess they knew one thing.
Rym: It's called hockey.
Rym: You didn't know anything else about hockey.
Scott: He's illiterate.
Rym: But yeah, don't don't get us wrong.
Scott: Read the name of the game on the game.
Rym: This was my favorite PAX East ever.
Scott: Oh, OK.
Rym: I think mostly because it was warm out.
Scott: That was that helped.
Rym: That helped a lot.
Rym: And I only we only did one panels.
Rym: We had a really light schedule.
Rym: So I spent a lot of time just playing games.
Rym: But the real problem with PAX is that the security theater is getting way out of control.
Scott: We won't talk about it.
Scott: It's not news.
Scott: We've been talking about every PAX.
Rym: I will.
Rym: It was way worse this year.
Rym: The security lines were bad.
Rym: Because they were actually checking bags most of the time.
Scott: Well, I think that's just a matter of it's not you know, it's like who you hire to work at the bag thing.
Scott: It's like some people who work at it.
Scott: take it to.
Scott: there's two kinds of people who work, you know, bag check security at a private place like a convention center.
Scott: The kind of person who's just getting a job and they just doing the bare minimum to keep the job and get the money.
Scott: It doesn't actually care.
Scott: And then the person who's on like some kind of power trip and believes they're keeping everyone safe is going to root through every possible thing.
Scott: It doesn't care about how slow the line is.
Rym: I would.
Scott: But it's got to the point to where if you're going to have security theater and you know it's theater, you shouldn't hire the second kind of person.
Rym: If I was not able to use the exhibitor entrances to PAX East, I would not go to PAX East.
Scott: I agree.
Rym: I would literally skip going to PAX East if I couldn't continue to use the exhibitor entrance because that line you can't get in.
Rym: There were panels people were doing at the beginning near the beginning of PAX where no one could get in to see them.
Scott: So that magic thing I was talking about, the big the big magic arena e-sport thing.
Scott: So the actual reveal of the expansion and the finale of the tournament was on Sunday morning because someone had asked me about it the previous day.
Scott: Like, when is it?
Scott: I'm like, oh, it's because they had like their own mega booth, which is like one of the biggest booths.
Scott: And they use that for their tournament the whole weekend.
Scott: But then on Sunday, they moved to the PAX arena for the finale and the reveal.
Scott: So it was in the PAX arena, like at 10, 10, 30.
Scott: As soon as basically as soon as PAX started, they started that thing and the whole seating area of the PAX arena was full.
Scott: But the rest of the convention was pretty much empty.
Scott: People were outside struggling to get into the building.
Scott: Dude, I had every other area was quiet when I was there looking at that full arena area.
Scott: So it's like people were desperate to go to that, lined up early, got and filled in while most of the people were still not in the building.
Rym: Yeah, I remember tabletop opened and there was no one in tabletop playing games because no one could get there.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: But it was a good PAX.
Rym: So we'll talk about a lot of the stuff we saw at PAX over the next few weeks.
Rym: One thing that was announced at PAX East, it's big news.
Rym: Borderlands 3 is coming.
Scott: I didn't even play Borderlands 2 and I didn't finish Borderlands 1.
Rym: I think the Borderlands 3 announcement thing was the only thing that filled the main theater.
Scott: Like as much as people talk about... People were hoping for swag, right?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And I think there was swag.
Rym: But I actually heard that, like, the presenters messed up and like couldn't actually present much of anything.
Scott: Oh yeah, I heard that it was actually like a disaster that could even show their trailer or anything.
Rym: Yeah, but I get the impression that PAX was in no way at fault with these problems.
Scott: I still do not understand the desire to physically be in the room during, basically, an advertisement or a press... It's like, you know, even if I had the option to like go to the press conferences of like my favorite sports teams, why would I go?
Scott: I was more... I could just watch them on Twitter.
Rym: I was more hyped about Civ 5 than I'd been about any game in like my modern life since maybe Team Fortress 2.
Rym: And when I got to PAX, there was the big panel about it and there was the like the multi-hour line to play it.
Rym: And I saw both of those things and said, you know what, I already preordered this game.
Rym: I will just get it.
Scott: I do not understand.
Scott: It's like, yeah, OK, you enjoy that.
Scott: But why?
Scott: Why do you enjoy being physically in the room?
Scott: It's not like it's a concert where hearing music live is a different experience than hearing music on Spotify.
Rym: I mean, sometimes the swag is worth it.
Rym: Like sometimes the swag is everybody gets a copy of the game.
Rym: Like stuff like that does happen.
Scott: Yeah, maybe.
Rym: I mean, if I didn't have money, like that would be great.
Scott: But usually the swag is one.
Scott: Rando gets a video card and everyone else gets nothing.
Rym: But yeah, like even Act Inc didn't completely fill the room, as far as I can tell.
Scott: It's a big room.
Rym: Yeah, it is a pretty big room.
Rym: It's like thirty four ish thousand, depending on the configuration.
Scott: Not thirty thousand.
Rym: No, three, four thousand thirty.
Scott: I was like, hell no.
Rym: Well, I was about to say it's not a stadium.
Rym: I was actually about to say thirty three hundred.
Rym: And then I backed it up because the number is different because full disclosure, not only do we exhibit, but we enforce.
Rym: And I enforce main theater and the number is different depending on how the room is configured.
Rym: And I got to know that number for every event that's in that room while I am an enforcer for that room.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So another thing that happened recently, this is not the hugest news, but, you know, Nintendo has their Nintendo Switch online program, which I think is complete bullshit.
Scott: You pay twenty bucks a year, which is a low, low price for most services.
Scott: I would be happy to pay twenty bucks a year, but I would.
Rym: But it's Nintendo.
Scott: Here's what you get for your twenty bucks a year.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I think it's twenty bucks a year.
Scott: Anyway, this is what you get.
Scott: You get to play your switch games online.
Scott: So like you could you can't play Smash Brothers online unless you pay twenty bucks or whatever it is, plus one for PC gaming.
Scott: You can't play Mario Tennis online unless you pay for the thing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The second thing that you get is you get this app that will let you.
Scott: basically it's an NES emulator that has a limited selection of games from the NES.
Scott: And they keep adding more games to it.
Scott: And it actually includes.
Scott: it's actually a pretty good emulator.
Scott: You can play the games on your switch, which is real nice.
Scott: And it lets you do save states and other emulator type things.
Scott: And it also gives you remixed versions of the games that will let you like, you know, because they're really hard.
Scott: Like there's one that like I forget which one it was.
Scott: It is like it just put me at the boss, basically.
Scott: I was like, oh, oh, it was Kirby's Adventure.
Scott: I opened up the there's regular Kirby's Adventure, but then there's a separate one that was Kirby's Adventure with like a logo on it.
Scott: And when I open that one, it's like I'm at King Dedede there.
Scott: There I am.
Scott: Right.
Rym: That's fun.
Scott: Yeah, it's a cool thing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it's not worth any amount of money.
Scott: And the other thing is that there is currently one exclusive game and there may be more in the future.
Scott: And that is Tetris 99.
Scott: So you can only pay Tetris 99 if it's free as long as you pay for the service.
Scott: So I wouldn't mind paying for the service if the library of games was much, much bigger.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Imagine paying like for Netflix and there's like one movie.
Rym: Well, more importantly, I wouldn't want to pay for a service like this unless like matchmaking and finding people to play with was an A plus experience, because I get this for free on every PC game.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The playing online should be free in principle.
Scott: Charging for that is complete bullshit.
Scott: Unless it's a class experience.
Scott: I know that Xbox and PlayStation also charge for their online whatevers.
Scott: And that's also a bullshit on the PC.
Scott: I don't have to pay extra like steam subscription fee to be able to play, you know, a Counter-Strike online.
Scott: I buy Counter-Strike.
Scott: playing online is now free.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That's how it should be.
Scott: It's bullshit that a console wants to charge you for a service for that.
Scott: But I actually really want to pay for a Netflix like library of games, as long as it is an enormous library that can compete with my library of emulated ROMs.
Scott: So give me every NES game ever, every SNES game, every N64 game, every GameCube game.
Scott: Just give me all of them.
Scott: I'll pay you 20 bucks a month.
Scott: I'll pay 30 bucks a month.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But right now it is not worth paying for.
Scott: But it is very much worth getting for zero dollars.
Rym: And guess what you can do?
Scott: You can get it for zero dollars.
Scott: Well, sort of zero dollars if you already pay the large amount of money that may or may not be worth it, depending on your circumstances for Amazon Prime.
Scott: And you get a Twitch account for free.
Scott: You can then click some buttons to connect your Prime and Twitch accounts.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The Prime one being non free, the Twitch one being free.
Scott: Now we're assuming that combining them is also free.
Scott: You get now have a Twitch Prime account.
Scott: You can use the Twitch Prime account to get three months of Nintendo Switch online for free.
Scott: But then if you wait a little bit of time after you get that three month free subscription.
Scott: Right at the end.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, well, no.
Rym: It says available after 60 days.
Scott: Three months is 90 days.
Scott: So you get 90 days free.
Scott: But then after 60 days, you can come back to the website and click another button and that will give you nine more free months for a total of 12 free months.
Scott: But basically that's included with your non free Twitch Prime.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Which hopefully you're getting free from Amazon already.
Scott: The trick is this automatically enables automatic renewal.
Scott: So after the end of that second nine months or first 90 days, if you don't come back to get your nine more free months, they're going to take your money to give you the year paid.
Scott: So you have to go into your settings on Nintendo's website, your account settings and disable the free renewal, which you can do immediately.
Scott: You don't need to like wait to do it later.
Scott: And remember, you can come click the link for the three months, immediately go to Nintendo's website, turn off automatic renewal, then set a reminder for 60 days to come back and click the link for nine more months.
Scott: And then you've got your free year of Nintendo online, which is worth it.
Scott: Don't pay for it.
Scott: It is not yet worth it.
Scott: Probably won't be worth it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So the only thing I'm going to do with this probably is play Tetris 99.
Scott: Well, I'm going to play.
Scott: I already played Tetris 99 and I've played some emulated games on there a little bit.
Scott: But I plan to check in with it if and when within at least the first year they release other things.
Scott: But that's it.
Rym: So really brief geek bite in the first look area at PAX.
Rym: I played a bunch of games and there was one that really stood out.
Rym: It's not available in the U.S.
Rym: yet, so I'm just going to wait to get it.
Rym: But Crown of Imara.
Rym: Right.
Scott: So it's pretty much a Euro game.
Rym: But here is the deal.
Rym: It is it's a worker placement game, but instead of worker placement, it's got fucking Rondell's.
Scott: So there are two Rondell's, two Rondell's, two Rondell's with four spaces each.
Scott: And you can only play on one Rondell or the other each turn.
Scott: And you can only move your guy one, two or three spaces.
Scott: You can't go all the way around and repeat the same action.
Scott: So basically you have six actions to choose from on any given turn out of eight.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And things combo into each other in interesting ways.
Scott: And you can't really block anyone.
Scott: They can land on whatever spot.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: But the primary mechanic, because the big problem with worker placement games is that usually the games devolve to political blocking.
Rym: The games devolve to optimal blocking.
Rym: Like getting baby is literally the only thing that matters.
Rym: Like everyone get baby.
Rym: They come down to get more workers is the way to win.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Crown of Imara solves this by having I don't want to get too deep into the details because we'll review it on its own episode, but it has randomness.
Rym: But the randomness is all Puerto Rico style.
Rym: It's all things that will set the stage for the players to try to solve the way to optimize the configuration of this board.
Scott: I always just refer to this as same army, different territory, different terrain.
Scott: Everyone starts the game with the same army every time.
Scott: But the terrain is different every game.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: But the other thing it does other than the two Rondells is that there's a bunch of paths to victory and they all we I played this game twice already.
Rym: They all seem pretty legit.
Scott: Yeah, that is the.
Scott: I think the defining thing that makes this game great is that a lot of board games out there have multiple victory paths and usually one of them is vastly superior to the others.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And whoever dominates on that path will beat people using the other paths.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yet this game, there are many passes like you can see on the board there's a bread way to win.
Rym: There's a book way to win with bread one game because no one else did bread.
Rym: Actually, I won every game of this I played.
Scott: But but did you win with bread every time?
Rym: I won with bread the first time someone else tried to do my bread and I went a different way and I won with basically doing medium on everything and it worked just fine.
Scott: There's so many ways to win, which is pretty cool.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But the other main thing about it is that rather than blocking, what happens is actions on the board either do a certain amount, like get you a thing or or like cost a certain amount.
Rym: Every time someone does these things, the cost goes up or the effectiveness goes down.
Rym: So you're always rewarded for getting something ahead of other people.
Rym: You can still do it if you come later, but it sucks a little bit and it sucks more and more the later you get to the party.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So you're kind of always choosing between optimizing your engine or getting somewhere first.
Rym: So I get those bread points and now Scott is going to get far fewer bread points.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Do I cash in two bread for four each or do I get more bread first and cash them in for three each because someone else is going to go get the bread for four each first?
Rym: But anyway, my high level geek bite, because I do not want to get into the details, is that we just did.
Rym: No, I did not.
Rym: Crown of Amara is a standout game that is going to be good and worth buying.
Rym: The other game that we play that I want to briefly geek bite Smartphone Incorporated, I think it was a Kickstarter game.
Rym: It's it looks like a Kickstarter game, at least I'll say that.
Rym: It's a game about like making a machine to sell cell phone, manufacture and sell cell phones in different regions.
Rym: We played it.
Rym: I played it twice.
Rym: We played it with different numbers of players and the game had one hundred percent devolved into a fixed strategy and guaranteed victory for a player in a particular position.
Scott: It appeared to be a very broken game.
Rym: Then we discovered that because the rules are not that well written, we and almost everyone who played at a PAX was playing it completely wrong.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And it's possible.
Scott: it is good with the right rules, but we don't know what the right rules are because they're written so poorly and I can't even get a correction on VGG.
Scott: We think we know what the right rule is, but we're not one hundred percent.
Scott: We're only like 90 percent.
Rym: I think if the rules are what we think, there is a possibility of a good game here because there is a mechanic of do you raise your price or lower your price?
Rym: And if you have lower prices, you can sell more phones and get in early.
Rym: But you could raise your price.
Rym: And there's a whole thing there that feels like it would be really fun if it worked.
Rym: But I've never seen a game pull this off where it works.
Rym: This one might work, but no one taught us how to play the game the correct way.
Rym: So we'll have to play it with the rules correctly to understand if that mechanic works or not.
Rym: So this is either ground floor or groundbreaking.
Rym: And the last news before we get into the main bit, we didn't talk about this before the but this was a big gaming news.
Rym: Yu-Gi-Oh has a large and thriving tournament scene.
Scott: Really still.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I did see some people playing it at PAX, but actually I saw mostly root and second game.
Scott: The game I saw second most was actually Key Forge.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Very surprising.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: We got to go back in because I played Key Forge and it was fun, but like not enough for me to engage with.
Rym: But a lot of people were playing Key Forge at PAX, like to the point that all of us were like, wow, a lot of Key Forge going on here.
Scott: Yeah, pretty good.
Rym: But Yu-Gi-Oh, I saw some Yu-Gi-Oh.
Rym: Yu-Gi-Oh is big.
Rym: Yu-Gi-Oh has made a major change to the tournament rules for their tournaments.
Rym: So there's a new subsection, Subsection I, Hygiene.
Rym: What has changed?
Rym: This is a new section requiring all persons attending a tournament to be clean and wear clean clothing.
Rym: What does this mean?
Rym: If you or your clothing is excessively dirty or bad smelling, you can be penalized, meaning you could be ejected from the tournament.
Rym: You could be forced to forfeit around to try to correct the problem.
Rym: You could just be penalized in the context of that game.
Rym: This is an amazing rule, and the community is obviously split.
Rym: Half of the community, well, maybe not half.
Rym: Online, a section of the community is saying that this is unfair to the pros, which says a lot about that community.
Rym: And the other half of the community has said, thank God, banished to the shower zone.
Scott: So, yes, good rule.
Scott: But as often comes up in these discussions, someone always brings up the case that, like, yeah, there's some people who have a medical biological thing that just makes them smell bad.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Is there an exception for those people?
Scott: And also, even though I've heard people discussing that biological phenomena that some people just smell bad, there's nothing they can do to help it.
Scott: I've never heard a name for it.
Scott: I've never seen a case of it.
Scott: I'm not denying it.
Scott: Well, I'm just saying, will somebody please send me a link that explains the specific medical thing and the conditions by which someone's DNA or something about them makes them naturally smell bad and deodorant and showers will not solve it.
Scott: I want to see an explanation of it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because that would be good to learn about the next time this comes up.
Scott: I would actually be able to say something better about.
Rym: Now, what's interesting is that the rule is pretty clear about it's dirt and like you have to be clean and your clothes have to be clean because, frankly, every time I've encountered a B.O.
Rym: at a con, it is either because someone does not wash themselves or because those jeans have never seen the inside of a washing machine.
Rym: So I'm pretty sure that situation would be handled appropriately, and I'm pretty sure the vast majority of the people who will be affected by this rule will not have an excuse.
Scott: I mean, I can't someone who does have this problem, you know, if it exists, which because I imagine that person is showering and deodorizing diligently to try to fight, try to help their problem.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Maybe applying perfumes.
Rym: God, imagine being the judge of the Yu-Gi-Oh tournament, who has to determine if this is a medical odor.
Scott: I imagine if it was medical, you'd have some sort of form to prove that you had a thing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, also, most of the time, the smell is I imagine that that person is going to, even though they have this problem, is going to smell a lot better than someone who is clear.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If someone just smells really, really bad.
Scott: You're right.
Scott: It's clear that they're not even right.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So it'll be interesting because if you saw my tweet a while ago about ranking the sources of B.O.
Rym: at conventions at PAX's, the B.O.
Rym: is primarily confined to three areas.
Rym: In my experience, area one is the GameCube area where Smash Brothers Game Cube is being played.
Rym: Area two is collectible card game tournaments and area three is the expo hall.
Scott: I walked around a lot of collectible card game tournaments.
Scott: I didn't smell too many.
Rym: I encountered it twice.
Scott: And the expo hall, it was never like a big problem, but it would be there would be like individuals.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: And it was sort of like when you're playing a video game and you're in that stealth zone, we have to get from like one spot to another through a hedge maze.
Rym: And you pass through a zone of fart control.
Scott: And there's guards who are like looking around and you're trying to dodge them.
Scott: That's what you walk through the expo hall and it's like perfectly fine, perfectly fine, perfectly fine.
Scott: I am in the radius of a bad smelling person.
Scott: OK, I'm out of the radius.
Scott: They're only like maybe like 10 or 20 of them in the whole expo hall.
Rym: But I'm saying it's rare.
Rym: Pax does not have a B.O.
Rym: problem like a lot of other conventions do.
Rym: Yeah, but it does still happen occasionally.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: I ran into at least five instances, maybe.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Almost all the instances I ran into were in the expo hall.
Scott: But they were all like brief encounters.
Scott: It was like someone smells bad nearby and walk, walk, walk, walk, walk.
Scott: OK, I'm good.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It's not like when you go to a smaller con where there's like the tabletop room and the entire room is just a desolate ruin.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So as you guys know, I like to ski.
Rym: But another thing that I used to do a lot, but I don't really do any more often is mountain bike.
Rym: And I started to realize that I'm a pretty good mountain biker.
Scott: Throw yourself down a hill dangerously.
Rym: Or just trail riding, which is not down a hill.
Rym: It's sideways, but on a really narrow track to the woods.
Rym: So I'm going to link to a video that like this is.
Rym: I found someone else and this is about the level of mountain biking that I am at.
Rym: Like this is what I enjoy doing.
Rym: This video is the kind of thing that I like to do.
Rym: But there's another kind of mountain biking.
Rym: And I found a video that explains this thing.
Rym: There is this thing, this feature in Sedona, Arizona, called the white line.
Rym: And mountain bikers talk about it like it's this crazy thing you need to do.
Rym: It's like a fun thing to do.
Rym: So I watched this video where someone explains.
Rym: the video is called the white line.
Scott: trail is sketchy and deadly skull emoji that looks based on the still image I'm looking at.
Rym: I agree.
Rym: Oh, it's even worse.
Rym: You look at this still image.
Rym: And as a mountain biker, I look at this and think that doesn't look that hard because it doesn't.
Scott: I mean, I definitely could imagine, you know, I see people do like free climbs with no ropes or anything like straight, flat cliffs.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I can definitely imagine there are, you know, very good athletes, extreme type people who could do this.
Scott: Some of them will die or get seriously injured, but many of them will make it.
Scott: I imagine it's basically just who can do this.
Rym: So this video talks about something that I never thought about because I don't really watch videos of people mountain biking that often.
Rym: Something that happens with mountain biking called the GoPro effect, where due to the wide angle lens, a GoPro video will often make a mountain biking thing look way less steep or dangerous than it actually is.
Scott: Correct.
Rym: So this expert mountain biker went to check out this white line and do it.
Rym: And he points out that, one, if you look at it from a different angle, fuck that bullshit.
Rym: And two, he points out that this style of mountain biking isn't actually that interesting or that fun, nor does anyone care if you successfully do it.
Scott: You're basically.
Scott: it looks like you're just going straight sideways, slow and careful along.
Scott: So the steepness is to your left and right.
Scott: It's like perpendicular to your to your where you're going.
Scott: So it's really just a matter of.
Scott: it's more like tightrope walking a bicycle.
Scott: It's more like a trapeze thing than a bike thing.
Rym: So he basically said, imagine do the part of mountain biking that's the least fun.
Rym: And if you succeed, no one gives a shit.
Rym: And if you make even one tiny mistake, well, I mean, you're getting a bruise.
Rym: You shouldn't.
Scott: you shouldn't be doing things because how much shit people give about it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But if I was going to do something like this, I've seen people like use wooden planks to make like very narrow paths, like over swimming pools and things like that and stuff like that.
Rym: That stuff's fun.
Scott: And it's like.
Scott: that is basically the same as this.
Scott: Only probably more challenging because you can make all sorts of elevation changes and angle turns.
Rym: But also if you fail, like you mess up like, cool, you fell in the pool and everyone laughs at you.
Scott: But he talks about at one point, if you mess up this, you die.
Rym: The most dangerous part of this ride is a boring standard mountain biking maneuver where you do a 180 down a little steep thing like, well, not a full 180, but you basically go down and make a hard, hard turn.
Rym: Yeah, that's like a standard mountain biking thing.
Rym: It's easy to mess up like I mess that up kind of often, but you shouldn't mess it up that often.
Rym: And when you mess it up, you get a bruise.
Rym: usually like you fall off your bike.
Rym: You go, ah, shit.
Scott: Yeah, but it's the kind of thing where, you know, a pro is going to get it ninety nine times out of one hundred, but still fail one time out of one hundred.
Rym: And if you fail at this maneuver, you die in front of all the people who like to stand and watch idiots trying to do this trail.
Scott: Yeah, the moral is how many people are at the bottom dead.
Rym: So supposedly no one has died doing it yet.
Scott: How many people have been severely injured trying to do this?
Rym: So people don't seem to know.
Rym: They don't seem to be stats because it's not an official trail.
Rym: There's no like official body that organizes anything on this thing.
Scott: That makes it even more dangerous.
Scott: There's no nearby medical services.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So I just thought this was an interesting look into idiots.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: And also the difference between like mountain biking is a dangerous hobby.
Rym: One video is the part that I find fun.
Rym: And one video is something that I would never, ever do, even though the second video is probably technically easier mountain biking than the first video.
Rym: But if I make a mistake in the second video, I would literally die.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So what do you got?
Scott: So, you know, when you go to dry your hands after washing your hands, which you do very often to avoid packs packs like I did because I dry, I washed and dried my hands many times.
Scott: They say that paper towel is the most sanitary way, but I'm not a fan of the paper towel personally, even though I phrase someone who is the day and that's what they say.
Scott: The Internet.
Scott: There was some study or something that was like when you use the blowy kind of blows the water and felt all over the place.
Scott: Yeah, but it also reduces bacterial.
Rym: I feel like anyway.
Scott: Yeah, I prefer regardless of how sanitary or not it is the hot hand dryer because I don't have to touch too many things.
Scott: I don't have to throw paper towels in the garbage and I stand there long enough that it gets my hands one hundred percent dry.
Rym: Most people feeling a hundred percent dry complain about air dryers in bathrooms.
Rym: Either it's an air dryer from like the 90s or they think it's going to dry their hands in two seconds.
Rym: And when it doesn't, they walk away.
Scott: You got to stand there and you got to keep rubbing and keep dry.
Scott: Don't rub.
Scott: I rub.
Scott: You're rubbing stuff.
Rym: I can definitely say rubbing spreads more bacteria around your hands.
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: I just want my hands to feel a hundred percent dry.
Rym: I prefer the Dyson air blade.
Rym: It's all right.
Rym: Twenty seconds to doing this and I'm good.
Scott: I like the hot ones better because nice and toasty.
Scott: I like things hot.
Scott: Anyway, here in the video, we have a different brand of hair dryer, which is most excellent.
Scott: I have never check out not hairdryer hand dryer.
Rym: I've never encountered the airwolf one.
Scott: Check out this most excellent thing of the day.
Scott: Worthy hot air hand dryer.
Rym: All I'll say is that Scott made me watch this video to determine if it was thing of the day worthy.
Rym: And I reacted to it in a way that proved that it is definitely thing of the day worthy.
Rym: OK, it's good.
Rym: In the meta moment, we were at PAX East.
Rym: We got nothing, no conventions, no nothing except fun times until September with PAX West, which we will definitely be at.
Rym: Right.
Rym: So wait for.
Rym: we're going to judge some anime by its cover.
Rym: We're going to make some antenna videos.
Scott: Yet again, the schedules of things have aligned in such a way that we were not able to judge the anime right before the season started.
Scott: We have to wait until just after the season started.
Scott: Guess what?
Scott: A new anime season just started.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So we'll be doing that.
Rym: Some antenna videos we're going to be making.
Rym: I'm going to stream the rest of Wargroove.
Rym: All that content that doesn't happen during convention season is starting up with gusto.
Scott: I'm going to bike and go to the beach.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Sometimes it'll rain and then we'll both edit video and make self share.
Rym: It'll rain.
Rym: It'll rain occasionally.
Rym: You know, we could do.
Rym: we could record a podcast.
Rym: At the beach.
Scott: Yeah, it's on the Marantz.
Rym: OK.
Rym: You know, that's not going to happen, but I can say that we might do it.
Rym: Also, I have video of not the panel we just did at PAX East.
Rym: That'll be coming up soon.
Rym: But one of the panels we did at Magfest that we haven't done anywhere else yet.
Rym: I actually edited and got all the video done.
Rym: It's online and I just got to do some YouTube stuff and you'll all be able to see it.
Rym: But our initial draft of Rare Game Mechanics, where we talk about Rondel's and Buddha Babell is going to be up on YouTube imminently.
Rym: And last and least, well, maybe not least, the Ignites Book Club recently did 2001, A Space Odyssey.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Have you selected the next book since it is your turn to select a piece of literature for us to both consume with our eyeballs?
Rym: So we did the Odyssey, then we did a Space Odyssey.
Rym: I have chosen a book that is.
Scott: Is it an Odyssey?
Rym: It is adjacent to the Odyssey in the sense that instead of our friend Odysseus, we're ostensibly looking at our friend Theseus and perhaps a Minotaur and a Labyrinth.
Scott: However, I like a Minotaur and a Labyrinth.
Rym: So this book is widely regarded by nerds and people that I trust.
Rym: This is not just my opinion as being shockingly good, despite being a literal Dungeons and Dragons Planescape branded fucking book by Troy Denning, Pages of Pain set in the Dungeons and Dragons world of Planescape.
Scott: This does not bode well because I read Timothy Zahn's Star Wars novels, the Thrawn trilogy, which were lauded as the best Star Wars novels, and they were at best mediocre.
Scott: So will the best D&D novel be at best mediocre?
Scott: That is where my expectation level is.
Rym: I last read this book in high school.
Scott: And I remember it being phenomenal.
Scott: Should I select a book I last read in high school that I remember being phenomenal?
Rym: That is not a bad way to go with the book club because we learn things about ourselves.
Scott: All those books are still in print or available.
Rym: But other people have said the same thing about this book, which is interesting.
Rym: And I don't want to spoil anything about it, but it is.
Rym: ostensibly it explains where the Lady of Pain came from in Sigil.
Scott: Well, I must warn you that my never open a game on my phone on the train, but always open the Kindle app instead.
Scott: plan has been going along much better than the last time I went through with this plan.
Scott: I have already read a book and a half since finishing the book club books.
Scott: It's two and a half total books.
Scott: And so once I finish the book that I'm currently reading, I will immediately proceed to read this book and the book club.
Scott: So, Scott, I'm going to read to the book of episode.
Scott: It'll be ready to go much sooner than ever in the past.
Rym: I'm just going to read to you.
Rym: the formal is short.
Rym: The description of this book like this is the cover, like the inside of the cover.
Rym: The Lady of Pain.
Rym: She rules the city of Sigil from behind a veil of perfect silence.
Scott: Or is it Sigil?
Rym: It is canonically.
Rym: it is canonically Sigil because God is dead and that is a terrible canon.
Rym: I pronounce it Sigil until someone corrected me and I found out that I was wrong.
Scott: Sigil?
Rym: Sigil.
Rym: Feared by mortal and gods alike, she flays her worshippers alive and casts her foes into inescapable labyrinths of despair.
Rym: Only fools dare ask her to speak.
Rym: And an amnesian hero has come with the question.
Rym: Now, here's where you might get interested.
Rym: When the god Poseidon tells a man with no memory how to recover his past, the unwitting warrior seeks out the Lady of Pain.
Scott: So basically, this sounds a lot like Planescape Torment.
Scott: Yeah, this book, some guy like wakes up.
Scott: He's like, he's like a guy wakes up with a guy in Planescape Torment, like a zombie or something.
Scott: I forget.
Scott: He's like some kind of not human.
Scott: He wakes up, he wakes up similar to Planescape Torment.
Scott: He wakes up in some like torturey place in Planescape and then goes outside and is like, what the fuck?
Rym: So basically, dude wakes up with amnesia and Poseidon says, yo, you want to get your memory back?
Rym: Go ask the Lady of Pain, who lives in the city that gods cannot get to, what the deal is, and she'll totally help you out.
Scott: I guess she doesn't.
Rym: The Lady of Pain is known mostly in this world for if anyone tries to worship her, she murders them.
Rym: If anyone tries to talk to her, she murders them.
Scott: So what is she doing then?
Scott: Like, what's what's your life about?
Rym: That is ostensibly what this book is about.
Scott: If you're not talking to anyone, why are you even doing just standing?
Scott: Are you just like?
Scott: you might as well just be a statue then?
Rym: So I checked out the reviews of this book on Amazon.
Rym: And there's a lot.
Rym: it's got like four stars, like it's rated way higher than I expected.
Rym: I looked at the one star reviews and one of the reviews is someone complaining that the novel has a non reliable narrator and how that's unfair to the reader.
Rym: So and another one is someone who is super fucking butter that the book did not explain some lore that he cares about in the Planescape universe.
Rym: So and all the good reviews are mostly people saying, wow, yeah, this book is way better than you expect.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Rym: So we'll see.
Rym: Let's find out if a Rym when he was 16 has good taste or not.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Can we do the main bit now?
Rym: Baba is you.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So back quite a while ago, I was watching this on the AGDQ channel.
Scott: They occasionally have these mystery races, which is basically it's called blind racing where you're doing a speed run, but it's a race situation where you're trying to speed run faster than the other people.
Scott: You start at the same time.
Scott: But you've never seen this game before in your life.
Scott: It's like you're thrown into a game.
Scott: It's not like when you go to watch AGDQ, those people have practiced, learned everything about a game, right?
Scott: They're the master.
Scott: This is here's the game you never played before.
Scott: There's two of you.
Scott: There's four of you.
Scott: Everyone play it now and see who beats it first.
Scott: Go.
Scott: All right.
Scott: And it's really fun to watch these.
Scott: And I when I was watching one of these, they played a game called Baba is you.
Scott: And most of the time, because they need to find games no one has played before, they're using weird, obscure indie games, game jam games, tiny little PC games.
Scott: It has to be PC games because, you know, everyone's sitting at a PC streaming or whatever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I saw Baba is you on there.
Scott: And as soon as I saw it, I was like, that game is incredible.
Scott: I must play it.
Scott: And I found out that it was a game and made it a game jam by someone named Hempuli, H E M P U L I. You can get the original game jam build for free on itch.io.
Scott: You can also get the full new version on itch.io, right, because after much time waiting, eventually they released a fully fleshed out implementation of this game that is much, much larger than that tiny game jam game.
Scott: They took that that core concept of amazingness, made a full game.
Scott: You can now buy it on steam.
Scott: I bought it on steam immediately and I played a bunch of it, though I haven't beat it because it's hard.
Rym: Now, I would recommend getting it on the switch because that's just a better form factor.
Rym: I play it on the go a lot.
Scott: Whatever you want to buy it on, you buy it on.
Scott: But, you know, I'm the kind of person who buys things on steam because if you haven't noticed, the Wii eShop is now gone.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Forget the Wii is dead.
Scott: The switch will one day also be dead.
Scott: Yet the steam games that I purchased in 2004 are still available to me.
Rym: But the short version of our review could go away just as well.
Scott: But I trust it more than I trust anything else.
Rym: The TLDR version of this review is that Baba is You is unique, is groundbreaking, and they did way more than with this concept than you could possibly have expected.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: So the game is so much bigger.
Rym: If it had been a quarter as big, I would have been satisfied.
Scott: So here's the concept of Baba is You.
Scott: It's a. it's a block pushing puzzle game, just like Lolo.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Without that, without.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Just like you ever played Lolo, all you do is walk around a little square map, pushing things around in order to get to the exit.
Rym: Those Lolo games are good games.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: This is basically ultimate Lolo.
Scott: The way it works is.
Scott: How do I even explain it?
Scott: So imagine if the rules of the game are also pieces in the game, there is.
Rym: Oh, you said you started a board and it says like there's a block that says Baba, a block that says is in a block that says you and then there's a little Baba guy.
Rym: And because Baba is you, you can walk around.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So whatever is you is controlled by the up, down, left and right arrows on your keyboard.
Scott: If nothing is you, then you can't move anything with the up, down, left and right arrows somewhere else.
Rym: It says flag is win.
Rym: So if Baba touches the flag and Baba is you, you win.
Scott: Also, if Baba is you and Baba is win, you also win.
Scott: So you win.
Scott: Basically, you're always trying to win.
Scott: You're trying to make you win.
Scott: You can't say you is win.
Scott: That won't make you win.
Scott: You has to be something.
Scott: Well, something has to be you and something has to be win.
Scott: If those are the same, something you win or if those are two different somethings, but they're on the same space on the board, you win.
Scott: Those are the only two ways to win.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: No matter what kind of crazy stuff is going on on the map, whether it involves teleporting or ghosts or defeat or moving or any kind of craziness, keys, doors, that's the only way to win is to make something you and something win or make two different something's you and win.
Scott: And then they're both occupying the same space.
Rym: Baba is Baba and has Baba.
Scott: So there are nouns, right?
Scott: Like Baba, Kiki, Key, Door, Wall, Ghost, Ghost.
Scott: And then there are like these descriptors win, defeat, you open, more, move, stop, more, push, all kinds of things like that.
Rym: Has been a fun one.
Scott: And then there's the word is and there's the word has and then more words keep appearing that are sort of conjoining words.
Scott: And if any, you know, subject block right is horizontally, basically you need a horizontal or vertical alignment orthogonally aligned right of subject.
Scott: then has is whatever.
Scott: and then descriptor Baba is you door has key wall is push anything like that.
Scott: And you can reuse the is because you can use the is vertically and horizontally at the same time.
Scott: You can even you can reuse anything you could use, right?
Scott: Because, you know, as long as there's room to push the blocks around, you can have one thing get used as an and you can be like you can like.
Scott: thing is blank and blank now or right away, like you.
Rym: just go to the website and look at these animated gifts that they just posted and you'll see exactly what the deal is with this game, like one hundred percent.
Rym: The important the reason why this game is good, because this concept could be done very badly.
Rym: Yeah, like I can easily see it being bad.
Rym: The reason Baba is you is so utterly fantastic is that one, every combination does something.
Rym: And if it's crazy, it's just crazy.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, right away, the wall is you.
Scott: Fuck.
Rym: You're the walls now.
Rym: Go for it.
Scott: Every subject thing, Baba, wall, Kiki, pillar, cog, heart, key door.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Those are just describing graphics.
Scott: There is no actual difference between a key and a Baba.
Scott: I can tell just things and they're only defined by what they are.
Scott: If key is you and Baba is open, then the Baba's are just doors and the key is just you.
Scott: You're just a key that you just look like a key, but you don't function like a key unless you are open.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Like make key is more in this example and then the room just fills with keys.
Rym: Now you're fucked.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like, you know, you could be heart in one level.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Scott: Graphics are just graphics.
Scott: You're the flag and grasses win.
Scott: You got to get the move the flag until it's on some grass.
Scott: Now you win.
Rym: And the other reason the other thing that makes this game brilliant is that it is not in any way real time, which was where Lolo series started to get downhill because you had of timing and you had monsters and Lolo and fighting a little bit.
Scott: Barely, but it was still.
Rym: the original.
Rym: Lolo's were just puzzles, but then they added some time components in this.
Rym: You can hit a button to back up what you just did.
Scott: One step all the way back to the beginning.
Scott: You can also have a full reset button to reset the whole level.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So you'll die a lot and just be like, no, back it up.
Scott: Basically, when I play this game, what ends up happening is easy levels.
Scott: I finish easily, but most levels I sit there and I experiment a little bit and I think about what I got to do.
Scott: And then I just stare at it for like a long time and eventually come to either come to the answer or go to sleep and start again later.
Rym: I've got a few I have not solved that.
Rym: I backed off and went to other areas.
Scott: There are a lot I have.
Scott: I've basically been going through the game one at a time, not going to a new area until I beat the area I'm in completely.
Scott: But, you know, I've only made so much progress.
Rym: But the fact that you can just back step forward and back as much as you want is part of what makes this game great, kind of like how it was Super Meat Boy.
Scott: It would be infuriating if you had like a reset up, like you set up something and you do it and then it's off by one and you got to redo it all.
Scott: It's like, fuck, you'd be like, fuck this.
Rym: That's where Lolo failed, because Lolo, you push something against the wall.
Scott: Fuck, whole level's ruined now.
Rym: Better kill myself.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Whereas here, it's like, OK, you can step back one space and figure everything out.
Rym: And the other two components, one, it has a world map.
Rym: So if you're really having trouble with like an area, you can go to another area and you can sort of choose your own path through the game.
Scott: It doesn't matter what order you do stuff.
Rym: Nope, doesn't matter at all.
Rym: And there are so many things, the solutions to some of these puzzles, they're not they don't all just turn into a lot of puzzle.
Rym: games will end up having a certain kind of puzzle.
Rym: that's the end game.
Rym: And like all the puzzles would be like that.
Rym: Some of these puzzles have ridiculous solutions, right?
Scott: So the most one of the best ones I've come across so far was there was a line down the middle of the map made of grass.
Rym: Oh, I know which one you're talking about.
Scott: And it said on the right side, it said grass is defeat and that you is no way to change that, right?
Scott: It was.
Scott: there are a lot of times where the maps will be such that the rules are in inaccessible areas and can never be changed.
Rym: Like if they really want to make it clear, they'll put it in like the bottom right of the map.
Rym: So there's literally no way to ever.
Scott: some some levels will be like Baba is Baba.
Scott: Baba is you and lock it in with a wall.
Scott: And also inside that wall will be wall is stop.
Scott: Now there is absolutely impossible for you, Baba to turn into anything else for you to not be Baba for you to get in there and change those rules.
Scott: It's like the lock in certain things.
Scott: So grass is defeat was locked in and flag was win and the flag goes on the other side of the grass and you're Baba and you're on the left side of the grass.
Scott: How do you get over there?
Scott: Well, it just so happens that the rules of the game are such that would defeat means is that if you are the thing that is defeat or if you are on the same space as the thing that is defeat, you lose and you you don't win this map.
Rym: What if Baba isn't you?
Scott: So normally when nothing is you, what happens in the game is the game just goes and you have to rewind to become you again.
Rym: I like the aesthetic because the game is really good atmospheric music.
Rym: I really like the music.
Scott: And but if nothing is you, the music stops and it goes, it makes this noise like it just feels very hollow and sad when that happens.
Scott: But this map also had the the the verb of move.
Scott: You could make certain things move.
Scott: And what that means is if anything is move, that thing will move one space in the direction it's facing per click and you have a button on your controller that waits one click without moving you.
Scott: Normally, if you move, that causes one click of time to happen for every space you move and anything that is move would move one space along with you.
Scott: But you can also just wait in one space and push the wait button and all the things that are move will move one space each time you push the button.
Scott: The way to beat this map was to arrange things such that you are not you.
Scott: Nothing is you, but yet the things that are move will push Baba across the grass.
Scott: So even though you touch Baba touch the grass and the grass is still defeat, Baba is not you while you're touching the grass.
Scott: Then they move in such a way that as soon as you're on the other side of the grass, they push things around so that Baba is you again.
Scott: Then you can move that Baba escape and get over to the flag now that you're on the now that Baba is on the other side of the grass.
Scott: And that was like I managed to somehow do that and I succeed and it was incredible.
Scott: I'm just after staring at it for like 10, 20 minutes.
Rym: But the game also does a good job of depending on as you're going, it'll introduce mechanics one by one.
Scott: Yeah, each area introduces like a new mechanic and then pushes that mechanic all the way under the limit.
Rym: And the limit is way further out than you would expect.
Rym: Like some of these things get kind of amazing.
Scott: I have not seen block pushing puzzles of this magnitude before in my life.
Scott: If you love pushing blocks around in a 2D plane to solve a puzzle, this is the best game like that in all of human history.
Rym: There has never been something as good at being that as this.
Scott: In all the how long humans have been around, there has never been a 2D block pushing puzzle on the level of Baba is you.
Scott: It is the undisputed number one king of that.
Rym: And it's big.
Rym: There are a lot of levels like.
Rym: there's a lot going on.
Scott: I don't know if there's an official level editor, but I have seen people customizing it with some sort of hack, mod, ROM.
Rym: I already saw someone implement Conway's Game of Life entirely within Baba is you.
Scott: Yes, I saw that as well.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I was debating using that as the thing of the day today.
Rym: So this is like it's pretty rare that we'll say if you must buy a game, this is a must buy game.
Scott: If you like puzzle video games that are solo puzzles, especially the 2D block pushing kind, if you like programming games, you like logic puzzles, Zachtronics games.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If you like anything like that, this is adjacent or in some proximity to all of those.
Scott: You cannot miss Baba is you?
Scott: just get it now.
Scott: Whatever the full price is, doesn't even matter.
Scott: Don't wait.
Scott: Play this today.
Scott: And
Rym: even if you feel like you will not be smart enough or capable enough to like fully beat the game, even if that's true, playing the first like 30 levels,
Scott: what I would recommend to you is if you're not sure, the original free game jam version of the game is still available for free on itch.io.
Scott: Go to itch.io.
Scott: Just search for Baba is you.
Scott: You'll be able to see this two links on itch.io.
Scott: One is for the $15 full game, the same one you get on Steam.
Scott: It's like a DRM free version.
Scott: I guess you can get that.
Scott: That'd be good.
Scott: Or you can get the original game jam version for $0.
Scott: Get that and play it.
Scott: If you're not sure, watch some YouTube videos if you're not sure.
Scott: And then if you're sure or you take my advice or you're a cool person, pay $15 or whatever it is to get the real deal.
Rym: And then Baba will be you.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the GeekNights Patrons for this episode of GeekNights now that we are back and bad.
Rym: Craig Oliver, Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol, JustLikeADudeGuy, Jartavishan, LingKiji, Jennifer Hitchcock, Chris Midkiff, MyStacy.com, Jay Benz, Scootalonely, Roberto Kingsley, Sean Yeager, Nicholas Brando, Mr.
Rym: Strong, Strachan, 421 Creations, Usadore, Sharon Van Horl, Rory, Rochelle Montanona, Superboy, Sailor Vista, Joe Shiro, Joe Star, Clinton Walton, Redfin New Zealand, Ryan Parent, Drew Openlander, Finn, Daniel Redman, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer and Thomas Han.
Rym: Like we said, we're back, regular schedule, new episodes of things like Judge Anime and for real, we're working on stuff.
Rym: But now I leave you with...
Scott: >> The way officials tell it, Boston has become the victim of an electronic blight.
Scott: With fewer than 600,000 people, the city has 4 to 5,000 video games, not just in arcades but also in drugstores, pizza parlors, supermarkets.
Rym: >> In some sections of the city, we have a machine or two machines and sometimes three machines in virtually every single corner store in a neighborhood.
Scott: >> City officials today announced that video games no longer will be licensed in residential areas, only in commercial and industrial neighborhoods.
Scott: Officials say they are responding to complaints from parents that children have skipped school or stolen money to play the games and made a nuisance of themselves.
Scott: >> Senior citizens have rights.
Rym: They have rights to go into the laundromat and wash the laundry in peace.
Rym: They don't have to go buy two or three machines or kids congregating and passing fast remarks as they walk in and terrorizing them in some instances as they go in.
Scott: >> Under the new regulations, licenses for about half the video games already in Boston are unlikely to be renewed, including those in the basement of the South Boston Martial Arts Academy.
Scott: >> The reason we requested to have video games is so we could bring in extra money so we could allow those kids that are out in our neighborhoods that can't afford to come.
Scott: >> When they don't have something to do when they're walking the streets, that's when problems are created, not because of machines.
Rym: The lack of machines causes problems.
Scott: >> You're always talking about this demeaning kid or making kids' minds like vegetables.
Scott: Talk about them out on the street smoking pot.
Scott: >> One MIT study of more than 800 video game players found no basis in fact for an underlying fear expressed by parents during public hearings that video games lead to violence.
Scott: Though a conclusive study has yet to be conducted, Boston went ahead with its restrictive rules.