Rym: It's Thursday February 14th 2019.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We're talking about doing laundry because that's exciting.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So I was setting up to do GeekNights.
Rym: so a little while ago And I'm creative cloud like was open and I saw it had a notification.
Rym: So I figured out there's probably some update to like Photoshop or so Notifications for other shit.
Scott: now that are not updates to software.
Rym: I've made some configuration changes to where that I think I only get the ones I care about.
Rym: but I click on it just to see and Sure enough.
Rym: There was a new version of like Media encoder and premiere.
Rym: so I clicked on that and I noticed something I hadn't noticed.
Rym: I noticed that the last round of updates left the old versions in place.
Rym: So I had Photoshop and then I had the newer Photoshop that all the people who are bad at Photoshop We're complaining about because they fixed one of the most glaring UX problems in Photoshop where you don't have to hold control if you want to keep the aspect ratio and a transform by default.
Rym: People are really mad about that change.
Rym: I don't understand why.
Scott: so I noticed that for whatever reason I people get mad about any change.
Scott: Right.
Scott: We've talked about that a thousand times, right?
Scott: Oh sicko sign.
Rym: but I noticed that the creative cloud had done a thing where it kept the old stupid version of Photoshop and Audition and all these things I just never noticed.
Rym: so I found the option That says fucking just keep me up to date.
Rym: Never keep old versions.
Rym: full steam ahead.
Rym: Damn the torpedoes.
Scott: Yeah, I've had that version that for a while.
Rym: So I enabled it and I uninstalled manually every old the old audition the old everything.
Rym: So because I just hit the windows key and type like a you and I said enter I've been used in audition 2018 for a while now, like even though 2019 has been out for a while.
Rym: so this is the first GeekNights and recording 2019 and it highlights the audio that's being recorded currently in like Super red and it took me a second to realize that that was because I have a new version not because something's going wrong.
Scott: Yeah, you know in terms of thing people getting mad about changes.
Scott: It's like remember people are so mad about the Twitter redesign.
Scott: Oh, yeah, we're so mad about Microsoft Office ribbons Just a couple weeks ago.
Scott: people are mad about the new slack logo and I'm sure someone out there just now said it's still ugly.
Scott: But guess what?
Scott: Everyone stopped giving a shit and slack still works.
Scott: You're still using slack.
Scott: So what the fuck does it make?
Rym: the new slack logo is bad because it is primarily lazy Too derivative of every other goddamn logo these days and somehow incorporated like what both a swastika and a dick.
Scott: Yeah, but you know what?
Scott: Uh, it doesn't matter.
Scott: It's of course doesn't?
Scott: it's not a problem.
Scott: It's like you're gonna in in five years if they try to change it again, you'd be like, ah change it back to the dick swastika.
Rym: Well Look at Long Island City.
Rym: There's this giant like ugly neon Pepsi like ad from a long time ago on the waterfront.
Scott: It's like I say same thing with a sicko sign of Boston.
Rym: the same thing with the tour de fell, right?
Scott: All right, so but yeah, don't get mad just cuz there's something changed.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I'm not change yourself I was startled by the fact that there's all this red in the interface that I'd never seen before but it's fine.
Rym: I just had to.
Scott: red is not a good color to use for something scary But I guess red does mean recordings that make sense.
Rym: Yeah, especially cuz that red matches the red of the.
Rym: I have activated this channel to record from some of you know That all that biz.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Anyway, actually before we start the show, I'm curious all of you out there if I was to do a patreon like exclusive thing Would you like like a real talk tutorial how to use audition?
Scott: I mean, yes anything you say would you like someone's gonna say yes and and no one who's gonna say no is even gonna say I only want to do it if a lot of people say yes.
Rym: if one person says yes You can go Google for someone else who did a less good tutorial.
Scott: I'm pretty sure.
Scott: if you have Adobe audition Adobe has like.
Scott: this is an Adobe tutorials like app.
Scott: Oh that is it on the iPhone.
Rym: So I've looked at those.
Rym: it's totally an aside But I have watched the Adobe videos and they're pretty good and I've watched a lot of tutorial videos for this kind of software.
Rym: What I've noticed is that?
Rym: Almost no one talks like.
Rym: they talk about how to use audition, but they don't tell you how audio works and Nothing seems to tell you that.
Rym: I can't find tutorials that actually explain to people Sufficiently like how to use an auto ducker like what a compressor really does and how to tune it or any of that stuff for podcast.
Scott: I think you generally go to school.
Rym: Yeah, but it's not that hard to learn.
Scott: I learned it by reading Every single computer, you know thing even Stack Overflow.
Scott: nothing teaches you how a computer works.
Scott: They're all teaching you except for unless you take like the MIT open courseware, right?
Rym: I guess what I noticed is that the only good resources I found for that stuff are the way I learned which is Literally all these textbooks I bought used from the 90s from like schools on how to do audio.
Scott: Yeah People who have educations and know things Don't often end up actually teaching the fundamentals of those things in it for free.
Scott: Yeah, it's just a thing.
Scott: But as a result online you find specific tutorials to do specific things.
Scott: You can find plenty of like baking videos that are like hey, here's how to bake this specific thing.
Scott: But you can't find something that is like.
Scott: here is the fundamental theory of baking.
Scott: I Can't find that on you If you know where that is on the internet like how.
Scott: I can you know like just from knowing about the chemistry of flour.
Scott: Invent a recipe for a thing without having to like take a recipe from a cookbook Right.
Scott: I've never found any.
Scott: I figured the only way to do that is to go to culinary school, right?
Scott: Oh, yeah, I guess there's no other way to learn that.
Rym: but I guess it's that I specifically see a lot of tutorials that explain How to do a specific thing in Photoshop or a specific thing in audition, but they kind I don't want to say they teach it wrong but they teach it in a way to where it explains why so many YouTube videos and So many podcasts sound like such absolute dog shit,
Scott: man.
Rym: So yeah, there's actually some really good news.
Rym: This got leaked a while ago.
Rym: Like no not a while ago a week ago.
Scott: Well a week ago.
Scott: They were like they threatened it was out and then today they're just like, alright We're going through with our threat and we're like, well good.
Rym: So if you didn't know because it's important that I live in LIC like where Amazon was gonna build their stupid headquarters.
Rym: It's like right there.
Scott: We can see it from the window where if they built it we would be able to see it like from here.
Scott: You know block our view of fireworks.
Scott: That's why it's a good like.
Rym: I literally walk past that thing on a regular basis like the place where it is, right?
Scott: So basically Amazon was they created this big hullabaloo like we're gonna build a building.
Scott: Every city and state.
Scott: please fight to see who will pay us the most to build our building there as opposed to somewhere else.
Rym: Yep, so you have cities being like.
Rym: we will kill every adult male child in our city for you right like Cities were willing to be like you don't ever pay taxes will give you land.
Scott: Please just come right because Amazon won't pay the taxes.
Scott: But the theory is that all the employees of Amazon Amazon still has to pay the payroll tax stuff like that.
Rym: Well, the New York incentive was they would actually give Amazon like a 40k credit against payroll.
Scott: Basically The way the way it would work theoretically right is that you don't care about paying them to come Because in the long term right you every all these cities and states are afraid of becoming Detroit, right?
Scott: Which is?
Scott: it's like oh, no We lost all our industry and now our town is a crap hole.
Scott: you want businesses where you live because then it makes you where?
Scott: You live a flourishing place with lots of revenues Things you've got seeing stuff you've got.
Rym: live in there.
Rym: You've got like low like mid mid-tier cities that don't want to become low-tier cities.
Rym: You've also got low-tier cities and non cities that are hoping this will put them on the map, right?
Scott: So obviously Amazon was only planning.
Scott: it was all it was.
Scott: obviously was only ever gonna go to New York, you know San Francisco Brooke right places where there are people want to.
Scott: you know We're tech.
Scott: people want to live and work and DC to be close to the government and the Washington Post that visas owns.
Scott: So yeah, they already already weren't gonna go anywhere else, right?
Scott: Oh, they have Nashville office too, right?
Scott: Yeah, the locations were bracing already decided like, you know, Nebraska you had no chance.
Scott: That doesn't matter what you were gonna give them.
Scott: You could have been like, yeah free rent for a million years free land.
Scott: They would have not gone to Nebraska in New York.
Rym: now I can't hire good engineer Like.
Rym: I cannot hire people.
Rym: there aren't enough people in New York City doing these kinds of jobs to hire right anyway.
Scott: So the what happened in New York is that the governor and the mayor usually don't get along despite being in the same political party actually came together and Bribed not bribed the legally but created an a plan to you know an offer like Amazon.
Scott: here's all the great things we will give you if you come to New York and They did that with zero input from anyone else.
Scott: It was completely the executive branch of government all in its own in secret Developing this offer.
Rym: polling for the idea of hey, would you like Amazon to come to New York?
Rym: was pretty high.
Scott: Supposedly 70% of people were in favor.
Rym: Supposedly, well, here's the thing.
Rym: I am in favor of Amazon coming to New York.
Scott: Well, I mean anyone who wants to come to New York.
Scott: It has enough money to do so.
Rym: you're allowed to buy land, but that's the thing.
Scott: you're allowed to build buildings.
Scott: I can't stop you.
Rym: Here's the thing.
Rym: The only reason Google has offices.
Scott: they're buying all of Chelsea market whether you like it or not.
Rym: The only reason a couple Amazon wants to come to a place like New York is because this is where all the people who can Do that work live but you come to New York because it's New York.
Scott: That's the only incentive you should need to come here.
Scott: Yep, so apparently that was the incentive they needed to come here.
Rym: 100% fine with Amazon coming like any company.
Scott: could I mean there are a lot of negative?
Scott: Consequences of them coming like all kinds of gentrification fucking up the neighborhood etc, etc.
Scott: Which is gonna happen anyway, but in principle, I can't stop you from coming if you buy land.
Rym: you you're you're allowed to buy land I mean, but here's the thing New York City or really no city should give the richest company in the world tax incentives to move to their city.
Scott: It's like the examples I used right for analogies, right?
Scott: The first analogy I came up with was like, all right, you're throwing a party.
Scott: Yeah, you it's in no invitation.
Scott: Anyone can come to my party and someone is like, oh your party looks pretty good.
Scott: I'd come in there if you gave me ten bucks and I'd be like you can come in the party But like not giving you ten bucks, dude.
Rym: But the dudes like oh, but if I come to your party like cool people will come because they heard I was here Well, then you can fuck off.
Scott: I'm not giving you ten dollars.
Scott: Yeah, you don't want to come to my party don't come.
Scott: and in this case instead of saying Alright, don't pay me ten bucks, but I'll come in your party and they just took their ball and went home.
Scott: Yes, it's the other the other.
Rym: and so what I read is that basically it's not.
Rym: oh, they're moving HQ to somewhere else.
Rym: As far as I can tell there's not fucking doing it at all now.
Rym: So I guess hire the same people they were gonna hire anyway, probably in New York just in different buildings.
Scott: They even admitted in their thing like yeah, we'll continue our expand our existing New York office.
Rym: It's like okay because here's the deal.
Rym: Amazon needs New York.
Rym: There's probably no other city in America where they could hire that number.
Scott: Seattle.
Scott: that's pretty much the area.
Rym: there are a handful of places in the entire country where you could hire a large number of people with that kind of skill set.
Rym: and New York doesn't need Amazon.
Rym: Amazon needs New York.
Rym: like someone pointed out that they were worried about Amazon over like just existing in Long Island City our neighborhood over developing it.
Rym: The place that Amazon's gonna is already overdeveloped is literally that gentrification.
Scott: there is no stopping that.
Scott: you.
Rym: I found a funny map that showed something interest.
Rym: There is no stopping that train that the place Amazon was gonna build is Literally the only undeveloped place left in the.
Scott: it's not undeveloped.
Scott: It's you know where they have the LIC flea next to the plaques all and the art thing.
Rym: Well, it's underdeveloped.
Rym: There's everything there.
Rym: It's still right still.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: It's not the plaques all itself.
Rym: It's the thing across that little canal, right?
Rym: Yeah, right over that building is pretty much empty.
Rym: It has a bunch of small like.
Scott: I went There was that there was like an Instagram ish candy.
Scott: It wasn't?
Scott: it was one of those events where it's like come here eat free eat food and take Instagram photos.
Rym: Oh, actually that gives me.
Scott: I went to one of those in that building.
Rym: You know, what else was there the other day?
Rym: I don't think you weren't with us.
Rym: So me and Emily were walking with the girls and we're gonna go get some food like walk over to like Vernon Jackson area and we're walking by that spot and you know, there's a fence with like that There.
Scott: good luck getting a seat at.
Rym: So that one of the one of the lots.
Rym: that's part of all this.
Rym: There was a hole cut in the fence Mm-hmm, and there was a bunch of lights in there and a sign that basically said like the secret park.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So we go in.
Rym: a bunch of hipsters had set up a bar with free drinks and a bunch of Christmas lights And a bunch of art installations and we're illegally running a like fancy park party in the vacant lot.
Rym: Yep That's what's there right now.
Scott: Anyway, so The argument, you know a lot of people on the internet are actually fighting back at it.
Scott: It's isn't like, you know an onslaught of hooray.
Scott: The internet is like half hooray and half boo because all the boo I see are people who don't live in New York and have No, I saw a lot of New York people who are boo, but they were all.
Scott: you know, they're all Staten Island I don't know.
Scott: some of them were satin on for sure because they were saying come to Staten Island.
Rym: Anyway, anyone who says oh no New York won't get those jobs That number of jobs is a drop in the bucket in New York City.
Scott: The point is the argument that they were making was like look, you know, you give them three billion But it's only X dollars over whatever.
Scott: But if they come we're gonna get you know X dollars and it's like I'd say one We're gonna get the X dollars.
Rym: Anyway, my land is gonna turn into something equivalent to HQ.
Scott: So my argument my argument against that is like alright, so I'm gonna go into the Apple store and I'm gonna say yo Apple Give me that and brand new top-of-the-line iPhone for $1.
Scott: now hear me out.
Scott: I know Alright, that's a big discount you're giving me But if you don't you could get is $1 for me or you can get zero dollars, so I'll go get Android.
Scott: Yep, and you know, you're missing out on all the money.
Scott: I'm gonna spend on apps.
Scott: still It's not like I can get.
Scott: apps are free.
Rym: So to say no further, right?
Scott: So it's like to take your.
Scott: now if you go to the Apple store and try that What does the Apple store say?
Scott: they say fuck off and iPhones $1,000.
Scott: eat a dick.
Scott: So if you come to New York and you're like, oh, I'll give you a whole bunch of money.
Scott: You're gonna get so much taxes if I move in here.
Scott: Just let me have all this stuff tax-free.
Rym: It's like so if I paid the same price as everyone else It's long Island City is the Apple store and you pull that shit and we kick you out.
Rym: Long Island City the way it's being developed already.
Rym: There are like a thousand people in line behind you who will give me hundreds of dollars for that iPhone.
Scott: Yeah $1,000 an iPhone.
Rym: Yeah, it's like we don't need Phone.
Rym: that's just as good.
Scott: It's like it's like bro.
Scott: This is gonna be other people going in that spot.
Scott: It was not you.
Scott: that's let law.
Scott: something's going there.
Rym: That spot is literally the only.
Rym: it's like a tiny percentage of the developable land in Long Island City.
Rym: It's the only one that isn't yet developed.
Rym: Everything else is already like planned for giant skyscrapers and giant buildings.
Rym: Amazon would have been a drop in the bucket and would have ruined the subway.
Rym: Yeah, I am Completely great that this happened and it's mostly thanks to our state senator.
Scott: Is he your state senator also?
Scott: Yeah, I thought he's.
Scott: I thought he's mine.
Rym: I forget we're right on the edge.
Rym: I forget I haven't voted in a while.
Scott: But yeah, so my state senator is this guy Gianaris?
Rym: Exactly where the line is.
Rym: I got a look at that.
Scott: I don't freaking know but basically he He is like always trying.
Scott: he's always in like the New York News.
Scott: He's like this in the New York State Senate.
Scott: He is like the second person right?
Scott: Cuz Andrea Stewart cousins is like number one.
Scott: He's number two.
Rym: Oh, yeah, we're there.
Rym: Look, it's it.
Rym: the line actually goes all the way down to The Pulaski.
Rym: No.
Scott: Anyway, I voted for this guy like twice already, right and Basically Before this whole Amazon thing gerrymandering.
Scott: Yeah before this whole Amazon thing.
Scott: His number one issue was bail reform.
Scott: He was like, let's get rid of cash bail completely.
Scott: That was his number one thing which is a good thing among his many things.
Scott: pretty much any time He ever said anything It was always good and he's always like.
Scott: he feels like he's someone who's trying to become governor or something big.
Scott: Yes It feels like he's an aspirational Politician because he's always on like the local TV stations like New York one and channel 12 and like local radio Always talking about everything.
Scott: but anytime I ever see him.
Scott: He's always saying the right thing.
Scott: I hope he it doesn't have like some secret me to stuff like every other white dude.
Rym: You know, I'm in New York does not have a good track record of seemingly awesome white dudes getting to a higher level of government.
Rym: And then immediately I like our past few attorneys general.
Rym: Yeah We've had a rough run of attorneys general so far.
Scott: He has been a plus dude.
Rym: In fact, if you listen to old GeekNights, we talk a lot about New York State attorneys general.
Scott: We used to talk a lot about.
Scott: that's a real important job.
Rym: It is a real important job.
Rym: Don't forget there.
Scott: You got Latisha James in there.
Rym: There's a special election at the end of the month for what the city advocate.
Scott: No one's gonna vote for that.
Rym: That's a really important position.
Scott: It's not that important, but it's pretty important I'm still gonna vote for.
Rym: well more importantly.
Rym: It's kind of Non-partisan.
Rym: there's like 20 people running.
Scott: It's really go look whether you live in New York or not.
Scott: Go search and look at the ballot for the special election because there are no parties in this election.
Scott: So everyone running writes in their own party.
Scott: So people have written hilarious things.
Scott: Yeah as their party like the first person on the ballot.
Scott: Their party is fix the MTA.
Scott: That is the least funny of them.
Rym: I feel like I want to vote for that one.
Rym: I got to do my research and decided to vote basically the hardest left or the hardest for social.
Scott: the problem is is I looked at everyone and Basically, most of the choices are pretty left and every single person on the left has like something wrong with them.
Scott: It's always they all have a different thing.
Scott: That's wrong.
Rym: It's like we need to fix climate change Yeah, and vaccines are bad.
Scott: Ah, it's pretty much everything and they're all crook slightly slow.
Scott: See, I guess you're gonna have to prioritize which thing you think is more important.
Rym: So I think the thing that's most important about this is that the government was like the the effectively the government of the state and the city Wanted this.
Rym: the business interests wanted it.
Rym: the richest the executive branch wanted it.
Scott: yep, the legislative the new legislative branch Did not.
Rym: the richest met.
Rym: the richest and most powerful man and company in the world wanted it and pretended to on it.
Rym: Yep and Basically the people who live here and one state senator were like, you know what now?
Rym: and that was enough.
Rym: a lot of state centers Yeah, but this state senator was on the committee.
Rym: that as far as I can tell I know he was because of the Amazon thing.
Scott: right Andrea just appointed him.
Scott: Yep to get a seat on the committee.
Scott: that would give him veto power.
Rym: Yes, he had veto power He didn't.
Scott: he's not on the committee yet Cuomo would have had to put him on the committee and there would have been some crazy fighting if he would have been like.
Scott: no I don't want to sign you off on the right.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, so Direct action by the people affected worked against one of the most powerful things on earth.
Rym: That's actually kind of amazing I'm and it goes to show when we talked on geek dance a little while ago like the Latin most recent election New York State's government fixed a bunch of issues and Same.
Scott: it's the same state Senate.
Rym: Yes The same state Senate that might give us single-payer health care in the state and fix a bunch of issues.
Rym: This is like the first thing they could accomplish since the election.
Rym: That's big.
Rym: So it's big news.
Rym: The moral is if you're mad about something like also we we avoided setting a precedent, right?
Scott: It's like alright if we pay them and then they come it sets this precedent like alright.
Scott: now every company in the world can create Sort of fight and competition between all the different You know local governments to see where they go to sort of run down their tax bill.
Scott: and it's like no you can't do that.
Scott: If you try to do that, you're just gonna say no fuck off.
Rym: I want to go further.
Rym: I want to say if a company makes too much money They're gonna pay an extra tax to have the privilege of even opening an office here.
Scott: I think you should have to pay extra money.
Scott: had the privilege of even doing business here.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And if you pass the cost of money above a certain size you gotta pay and you try to pass the cost off onto consumers.
Scott: We don't know the tech.
Scott: you can't do that If you're charging people in New York more money than you're charging people in Indiana, then we'll find you the difference.
Rym: Like here's a very specific example of that.
Rym: So the traditional wisdom among libertarians who don't know what they're talking about.
Rym: Is that so all libertarians all libertarians?
Rym: Is that small businesses don't start in New York and there's not a good startup culture here because state taxes and city taxes are so high.
Rym: So they incorporate in other places.
Rym: But the reality is a shit ton of those companies incorporate here and gladly pay those taxes because the benefits of being in New York Far outweigh that cost.
Scott: Yeah, I pay my company.
Scott: I pay my huge ass rent.
Scott: it gets people say oh your huge ass rent gets you this tiny apartment.
Scott: No, and I'm like central goddamn part and it's like yeah, but my huge ass rent.
Scott: I can just walk over and see every single movie ever even really Super rare ones that get a limited run.
Rym: I could just go see free opera.
Rym: I just free opera here.
Scott: I can go to the Madison Square Garden and it's a subway ride home and I'm gonna deal with the parking.
Scott: Yeah or driving I can.
Rym: I can walk over there and laugh at the spot that was gonna be Amazon.
Scott: I can see legendary historic works of art for free.
Rym: just up there They are.
Rym: I can watch.
Scott: that's all included in my rent and tag.
Rym: I can watch the Rangers lose and then it's only like a 10-minute subway ride home instead of an hour drive and I can get Any cuisine of food immediately after the game even though it's super late at night.
Scott: Haha It's like those are all the things you're getting for that money and you're basically Sagar it don't?
Scott: you could pay the same money.
Scott: and if you got all those things Yeah Guess what your apartment in podunk would just be equally small because you spent your money on that other stuff.
Rym: Look at that from a business perspective.
Rym: You need someone who knows.
Rym: I don't know IBM webs fair MQ horse like animal husbandry and I'm trying to think of another third thing and audio engineering.
Rym: You'll probably get ten resumes inside of an hour if you're in New York and hiring for that.
Scott: Yeah, but if you're in, Nebraska You're gonna get one guy.
Scott: I got a guy who knows about corn.
Scott: You'll get a guy who knows the horse guy the horse guy probably.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Good luck with the web sphere guy.
Rym: Also if anyone knows of IBM web sphere MQ Edmund in New York, I'm actually looking for one.
Scott: you actually use that.
Scott: Yeah, I got There's reasons.
Scott: I thought you knew web sphere.
Rym: Do not let anyone know that I know about was fair.
Scott: I thought you knew it though You were at IBM.
Rym: as far as far as people in my company.
Rym: No, I don't know anything about web.
Rym: sure I want to keep it that way.
Scott: I Should let them know.
Rym: do not tell anyone that I know about web sphere.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: so if you're a longtime GeekNights listener one thing you might know is that I'm a Super rollercoaster nerd like.
Rym: I'm that guy where you're like, oh, that's a really tall rollercoaster and I'm like, yeah That's a B&M.
Rym: You can tell because of the sound it makes and how it's got that little bit at the beginning and see how the tracks are Shaped differently like it's.
Rym: it's a problem.
Rym: So This video is really good.
Rym: You don't need to be a weird rollercoaster to understand it, but it basically talks about how B&M roller coasters this one company that makes a certain kind of roller coaster They have one to find.
Rym: one of their defining characteristics is that they're really loud.
Rym: They make this like it's hard to describe but they make this really smooth resonant whooshing sound When they come over that first hill like.
Rym: it's a very distinctive and loud sound.
Scott: wouldn't you want it to be quiet though?
Scott: Why would you want a loud rollercoaster?
Rym: Cuz it's loud in a fun way like when you're riding in a like you're driving a sports car.
Rym: That is a really fun loud sound.
Scott: Just use speakers and make a fake sound.
Rym: Why this isn't?
Rym: it's not like a Harley where they make it shitty on purpose so it makes the sound it's more like The.
Rym: the engineering of the roller coaster had this side effect where it sounds a particular way.
Rym: That's fine in a normal amusement park But if you have an amusement park that has a bunch of houses around it You can't have this loud ass roller coaster at the edge of the park.
Rym: So this video explains how this problem is solved and it literally involved filling the tracks with sand.
Scott: Hey, we're running out of sand.
Scott: Don't use sand on that.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, they're using sand for this.
Rym: Yeah, and you know, it's even worse They got to use the good sand.
Scott: No, but put that sand back on the beach.
Rym: So what it talks about rather be on the beach.
Rym: the cool thing is they for this one roller coaster They filled the whole fucking thing with sand but because like the shoot like the metal tubes.
Rym: Yeah Well, no, uh, let me find the diagram.
Rym: So they didn't fill the metal tubes because they would have to cut every tube open fill it with sand and close it.
Rym: So they filled the box that holds the tubes up.
Rym: That's a lot of sand.
Rym: but then because of this all the Future version of this days that they designed if they built a roller coaster that uses this particular type of like setup and they knew It had to be quiet.
Rym: They fill the tubes with sand from the beginning Using a way less sand.
Rym: and this talks about how like.
Rym: here's an example of a job That's hard to hire for the road.
Rym: The Canada Water Land needed to hire an acoustical engineer to tell them how to make a roller coaster quieter.
Scott: Imagine having that job grease it up Make a faster okey-dokey just cover the whole thing in grease.
Rym: Have you got any grease?
Scott: Really fish like.
Scott: imagine if like, you know The roller coaster had like the top quality instead of like wheels just like the top quality ball bearings as wheels like sealed in on the track and the track was super lubricated.
Scott: and Um, like it's like so grease that I could like push the coaster along because it was so so Surprised how easy it is to move a coaster car.
Scott: I'm just saying like, you know Yeah If it was like if you even if you just take like a penny and grease it up and put it on a flat piece Of plastic and grease it up and slide it around.
Scott: It's like Right.
Scott: So just imagine a roller coaster like that.
Rym: But anyway, this video is like the right level of explaining this without going too deep into the roller coaster.
Rym: grog nard stuff.
Scott: Yeah, it's a good video.
Scott: So I found a video that was so Rym Oh That I had to claim it as thing of the day so that Rym would not perhaps stumble upon it on his own and use It as thing of the day before me because it is a a plus tier thing of the day.
Rym: that has happened before.
Rym: Scott'll be like hey check out this thing the day and I'll be like.
Rym: I saw that we could go on Fark.
Rym: I claim it.
Rym: It's mine.
Rym: Here's proof.
Rym: I saw it before you anyway, so It's also.
Scott: I'm a rewatching it adventure time for the bidding.
Scott: I'm like in season 5 somewhere.
Rym: That's when it starts that the plotty stuff start.
Scott: now the plotty stuff actually starts in season 1 does But there's a few people keep having this feeling that like adventure time is like is not plotty from the beginning.
Scott: No, it's pretty much all the plot stuff is like in like super early.
Rym: It's like right after the gun grinder.
Scott: It's like when you watch it for the second time.
Scott: It feels like that they had the entire show planned from the start even though they probably did.
Rym: Where a Marceline's dad is like.
Rym: you are the most evil thing I've ever
Scott: encountered Exactly anyway, so here is the famous bacon pancakes Famous bacon pancake song which is amazing In like a zillion different languages, so it's great because a you get to hear this in zillion different languages And they're all using the same tune, but B You get to hear the Jake voice actor from every different country.
Rym: Yeah, because the Jake voice actor is a very important voice actor for this show.
Rym: Oh, yeah, this video is real good.
Rym: This is my jam.
Scott: the problem is is like it's that same guy was a Joe DiMaggio, not Joe DiMaggio John DiMaggio John DiMaggio, I think right.
Scott: and it's like now.
Scott: It's whenever I see bender.
Rym: I hear Jake I hear Jake.
Scott: So because I watched more adventure time more recently than future I when I so it used to be that Jake was bender when I first started watching adventure time.
Scott: But now but now bender is Jake was it's all.
Scott: it's like 90% the same voice Even though he is a talented voice actor who can do other voices.
Scott: He uses that same almost exact same voice to those two characters.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: It's not exactly the same.
Scott: It is slightly different, but it's very similar.
Rym: Yeah, you're running.
Rym: There's a few characters between like Archer Steven universe adventure time.
Rym: there's a few voice actors that you just can't not hear them.
Scott: Well.
Scott: There's a There's a.
Rym: there was a Benjamin you hear him an archer.
Scott: then here There was an adventure episode I rewatched recently where there was a character that was obviously John Hodgman Who was just doing his own voice yeah, and not acting.
Scott: and there's also What's the?
Scott: the woman who does Mabel in Gravity Falls?
Rym: Oh?
Rym: Yeah?
Scott: What's her name?
Rym: She's.
Scott: I knew her name, and then I forgot it.
Rym: well also I'm pretty sure the Fluttershy voice actress did the ponies in the new DuckTales, maybe but anyway Mabel I forget the the woman's name But like she did I was.
Scott: I was watching an adventure time and randomly I hear her voice.
Scott: I'm like a single episode character.
Scott: Oh, I know what you're talking about, and I'm like oh, that's that's who that is and she.
Scott: she always does the same exact voice.
Scott: I don't think she doesn't voice.
Scott: act to do different voices.
Scott: Yeah, just act acts with her own voice.
Rym: funny enough total random aside.
Rym: I've been rewatching Star Trek Voyager, and Who cares it's a good Star Trek.
Scott: so okay?
Rym: The thing about Star Trek is they like most episodes love like one guest star just like they do a roll all right Cuz.
Scott: it's like our actual TV.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So there's one episode where there's this other Hologram of a doctor who's kind of weird and neurotic, and they just old thing and I remember thinking Kind of looks like a young Andy Dick.
Rym: all right.
Rym: That's funny.
Rym: Whatever probably it was it was.
Rym: it was literally.
Rym: It's just.
Rym: that was a long time ago that show was on TV.
Rym: It literally was just a young Andy dick.
Rym: In the meta moment the GeekNights book club book which we will read at some point is so.
Scott: I've been getting bored on the train with the various games I have because most of the good games I have in my phone like need some kind of internet to be worth a shit.
Scott: And there's not enough if people out there make good games for mobile.
Scott: I don't need internet such right such as Narosha Mahakson race for the galaxy Which are both great.
Scott: still if you haven't played those yeah, but at this point, but the point is I've played them both so much.
Scott: I need a new one.
Rym: I can play an entire race for the galaxy between hunters point and Vernon Jackson, right?
Scott: It's like between.
Scott: so it's like I need a new Low mobile app of that caliber for gaming that I can play on the toilet or train.
Scott: and since I couldn't find one I was like all right.
Scott: I'm supposed to use the can read a book.
Scott: I was supposed to use the Kindle app on the train not the game apps.
Scott: Oh, I forgot.
Scott: I've had that plan, and I forgot that plan.
Rym: should I actually start reading 2001?
Scott: I remember that plan and on the one subway ride from home to here just now.
Scott: I read like three chapters.
Rym: all right I'll start reading it to them tomorrow morning.
Scott: It's all about the monkeys.
Rym: Yeah, yeah.
Scott: So 2001 is space odd.
Scott: Also The monolith in the book is not black It's like a translucent crystal thing.
Rym: yeah, that makes sense.
Scott: anyway What else is meta?
Rym: so what is so?
Rym: PAX East is coming the hell up.
Rym: We will be there doing at least one panel.
Rym: It's a brand new one again.
Rym: We're on a roll.
Rym: Sometimes PAX is like even though we have a new panel They'll be like do the one you already did twice because people really like it.
Rym: But we've been on a roll of.
Rym: PAX has given us our brand new panel, so we've got Friday March 29th 3 30 p.m.. In the Cuttlefish theater.
Rym: We are doing the real harm of games.
Rym: It's gonna be a real talk panel right?
Scott: so usually what happens is I come up with something weird happened.
Scott: right usually I come with a thesis and then I Explore a research and get a whole bunch of supporting stuff.
Scott: Just like when I was writing papers in school.
Scott: Yep, right, so I was.
Scott: I had a thesis.
Scott: Mostly I wanted to complain about gambling.
Scott: Yeah, children gambling and I was like I can't just do a panel on children gambling.
Scott: I have to do it or make it a broader thing.
Rym: Yeah, I have so many panels that are only like 20 minutes worth of material.
Rym: So
Scott: I started researching other harms of games besides children gambling and you know what a lot of the things I have to slightly change the thesis to be like look games are The
Rym: moral is gonna be along the lines of games have some harms But they're not the ones everyone thinks they are.
Scott: and here's the one thing that might actually for actually be a harm of games.
Scott: Let's not make this mistake.
Scott: Let's keep games from being harmful.
Scott: Yes Instead of I was the my original plan was going to be this is you know violence isn't a harm of games Sex isn't a harm of games.
Scott: But this is this isn't?
Scott: this isn't?
Scott: this isn't.
Rym: so as children get it turns out there's probably only one.
Scott: Now my thesis is look at right.
Scott: They said violence was a harm.
Scott: They were wrong.
Scott: They said this is a harm.
Rym: They were wrong and D&D made me a Satanist, but there's nothing wrong with that.
Scott: This also this nope, not harmful.
Scott: this not harmful.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Games are super good and not harmful Except children gambling.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So let's fix that shit the exploitative nature of the industry that makes game.
Rym: Yes This will be a good panel.
Rym: Yeah, so stay tuned.
Rym: you notice the other thing.
Rym: that's weird.
Rym: We're on a roll of doing panels that required a bunch of research.
Scott: We I think we might have tied aid an amount of research to where I went one level deeper than Wikipedia.
Scott: Oh for like a number of minutes that had two digits in it Scott for a rare game mechanics.
Rym: I was actually reading essays.
Scott: Oh, no, I read an article on psychology today, which is actually legit website.
Rym: I found an essay like a legit fucking essay talking about Rondell's.
Rym: It's actually really good.
Rym: I feel like I could turn that into a panel on its own.
Scott: I don't think your Rondell panel is gonna get accepted.
Rym: I if it PAX Unplugged might accept a panel.
Rym: That's literally just an hour of Rondell's.
Scott: maybe we should Rondell's and orthogonal adjacency and hexagonal grids anyway.
Rym: Anyway, we will be doing that at least that panel and otherwise we're just four days of PAX like go to PAX East.
Rym: It's real fun.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Beyond that This is actually the end of our long run of PAX's and then we actually have a break from PAX's before PAX West.
Scott: So spend your warm summer months if you're in the northern hemisphere enjoying bicycles or Playing video games cuz you're out of school or whatever or skiing because skiing is great in the summer.
Scott: Well, it's not summer yet I'm talking about between PAX East and West.
Rym: this summer between PAX East and West there is still a little bit of skiing anyway.
Rym: Early April skiing spring skiing is fine.
Scott: so today's episode is about laundry because I had an opening bit about laundry that I Decided to turn into the main bit.
Scott: So that way I'm gonna give you the opening bit right now.
Scott: So I was doing my laundry yesterday night yesterday.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yes two days Laundry like I do in it like downstairs in your apartment building.
Scott: Yeah, I was doing it two days ago.
Scott: And you know, I was just reading the laundry instructions on various articles of clothing And I was reading the the tech.
Scott: I realized, you know I just I was reading on things that didn't know how to wash.
Scott: right to like this would be delicate.
Scott: or can I dry this?
Scott: No dryer.
Scott: I try to make a decision.
Scott: I've done that.
Rym: I have some weird articles of clothing that actually had surprising instructions.
Rym: I did not.
Rym: I had I not read that label out of ruin them.
Scott: So I just I looked at the tag on some jeans, which I'd never looked at the tag on.
Rym: So I'm gonna guess cuz jeans usually say modern jeans.
Rym: wash inside out machine wash cold God line dry do not tumble.
Scott: Yeah It was that first part the inside out inside out Scott never in my hands.
Rym: inside out is like the secret to happiness.
Rym: I didn't know this.
Scott: I've got 36 years of life doing laundry.
Scott: for half those years at least more than half right and Never have I washed the pants inside out on purpose.
Rym: Logically, I figured this out as a kid.
Rym: I've always washed them inside out and here's why reason number even before labels would say it.
Rym: reason number one The stinky bits are on the inside.
Scott: I don't stink.
Rym: Well, sometimes you might stink.
Scott: Yeah, if if you don't wash your jeans my clothes get dirtier on the outside where dirty things in the world touch my clothes.
Rym: But there is sweat like filth of New York.
Scott: Yeah filth of New York.
Scott: Here's the thing dirt from the street.
Scott: So one hobo pee.
Rym: sweats will come in from the inside not the outside.
Rym: So if you want to tear it inside out, you're gonna wash the sweat out.
Rym: Don't have that.
Rym: other pieces of clothing and buttons and shit and the sides of your dryer and the agitator are gonna Scuff up your pants over time.
Scott: I don't care about that.
Rym: if they're inside out.
Rym: They'll scuff up.
Rym: I never had that problem, but that's the reason you wash them inside out.
Scott: No The reason I wash them inside out.
Scott: see when I used to wash jeans not inside out until this week You think this now.
Scott: well, you might not know this because you've never washed them out.
Scott: you I guess you always knew to be inside.
Rym: I've never washed my jeans outside in in my time.
Scott: when you wash jeans not inside out What happens is they actually come out of the dryer right kind of stiff.
Rym: Well, you never put your jeans in the dryer.
Scott: Yeah, I do.
Scott: No, you shouldn't why not?
Rym: Where's the mouth faster?
Scott: They're fine.
Scott: I never had that problem.
Rym: I never put my jeans in the.
Scott: well, so we'll talk about dryer in a second.
Rym: But first have my jeans look like jeans, but they're actually just spandex.
Rym: So I can't put them in the dryer.
Scott: Anyway, so they come out all stiff and The pockets on the inside of the jeans still wet.
Scott: No, they're not.
Scott: they're not wet.
Rym: No, they'll be.
Rym: we're just there.
Rym: if you watch humble dry low, they'll be.
Scott: well No, they're all bunched up and like when you put them on the for the first time They're all like it and you have to write.
Scott: I've never experienced that cuz you never watched inside.
Scott: But now I soon I'm like, oh it says inside out.
Scott: So I put them all inside out just to see if there's a difference.
Scott: and when I took them out of the dryer They were all smooth and the pockets were straight looking like I had just bought these jeans at the store five minutes ago And I was like, whoa, I guess I've never put in jeans not inside out ever again.
Rym: So here's an important nuance to that.
Rym: if we're talking about laundry because this laundry we're just gonna stream of consciousness.
Scott: this So well, let's talk about the dryer.
Rym: Oh, yeah, so well, we'll get to the dryer.
Rym: What you should and should not put in there There are three.
Rym: there are three effective kinds of genes in the modern world when when we're isn't like.
Rym: when I was in middle school There was as far as I knew there's only one kind of jeans Heavy ass denim jeans that you can put in the dryer that are invincible and lasts forever.
Scott: That mean that's yeah.
Rym: So nowadays I have a couple pairs of jeans that are like that like old super heavy denim.
Rym: They're the same jeans I've had since middle school.
Rym: Okay, there's the exact same jeans unchanged.
Rym: Most of my jeans now are Fashion jeans that are not that durable and they look like jeans and they're fashionable and they're tight and they're comfortable.
Rym: but if I like Crawl around in my knees working on stuff.
Rym: It'll just ruin them where old jeans are invincible to that.
Rym: And these jeans do not work well in dryers.
Rym: So they're all like line dry Mmm.
Rym: These are denim interwoven with spandex.
Scott: Yeah, I have some of those but they're just fine in the dryer.
Rym: I didn't.
Rym: these do you put in the dryer?
Rym: They'll ruin them.
Scott: No, they haven't been ruined yet.
Scott: I've been doing it for a long time.
Rym: Have you had them years?
Rym: How often do you wear them?
Scott: You know and when it's cold, okay.
Rym: Anyway, so should we talk about the dryer?
Scott: So the thing I learned actually from loot crane a burning wheel.
Scott: So I just want to point out.
Rym: me and Emily been telling you this for years.
Scott: You always ignored us and then randomly Luke crane says no one ever told me that you came back to us and said hey Guess what?
Scott: I learned.
Scott: I have no memory.
Scott: Yes Anyway, no memory whatsoever Pointing this out.
Scott: So Luke crane was wearing a shirt from like.
Scott: it was like an old concert t-shirt But it looked like he had bought it the day before even though the concert was many years earlier.
Scott: and I was like How's your shirt?
Scott: You know, yeah Does your printed nerdy t-shirt look like it's fucking brand new even though it's clearly not brand new?
Scott: and I've seen you wear it Before and he's like you.
Scott: just don't put it in the dryer, right?
Scott: So any t-shirt like a nerdy t-shirt that is stuff printed on it if you want to.
Scott: I got bit in pristine like a concert t-shirt or a PAX t-shirt or a t-shirt you bought for fan gamer calm or the Yeti Screen printed in the old way like the thick way Yeah, but I mean pretty much any shirt with anything printed on it.
Scott: period your favorite webcomic.
Scott: You bought a t-shirt from to pay to go.
Scott: whatever it is.
Rym: It depends on this on the process because there are some modern methods of printing.
Rym: Don't suffer from the point.
Scott: is all those t-shirts right that you if you want to keep them in a plus condition and not have the print get all cracked or break apart or Fade away or generally get ruined wash them cold.
Scott: I was already doing that.
Scott: Yeah Don't put them in the dryer at All.
Scott: the dryer will even if it won't melt the the printing like immediately like you put in the dryer once you come this out It's like oh, it's fun It's a little crease it a few times and weaken it right.
Scott: be like if you put in the dryer just like one time you Notice any problems at all.
Scott: look perfect.
Scott: two times you won't notice, but over time so gradually that it escapes your notice It will start to fall apart and not be in good condition anymore And you won't realize it was because of the dryer because it's not like you.
Scott: put it in the dryer and take it out and suddenly It's messed up Scott.
Rym: I'm gonna blow your mind.
Rym: There's a third thing you need.
Scott: you hang that shit to dry.
Scott: I'm like a some sort of drying.
Scott: You know if you have the drawing rack hang it straight.
Scott: I haven't a rack.
Scott: or if you had the string out behind your house the clothesline.
Rym: So there's a third piece that I feel like you should have been able to infer.
Rym: When you put it in the washer, especially if you have a top loader that has an agitator.
Rym: put it in inside out.
Scott: It's inside out.
Scott: I said it doesn't really matter.
Scott: It does.
Rym: well It does if it's thick screen printing hmm if it's like.
Rym: if it's like the more die style as opposed to the thick paint style That's not a concern, but if it's the thick style like the mosey shirt if you don't wash it inside out It'll cut.
Rym: that's what causes that cracking.
Scott: well I haven't had a problem since I learned to go without the dryer on those.
Rym: Let's talk about the dryer.
Rym: because one thing I did Draw a lot of countries.
Scott: people seem to not use dryers and well usually hot places and dry places You don't need dryers.
Rym: But I saw my whole life having to wash her in a dryer and basically my use of the dryer is Towels cheats.
Rym: you put them in the dryer on high.
Rym: yeah Gotta make sure that you put them in the dryer to kill all the mildew.
Rym: mm-hmm Cuz.
Rym: you get fabric ones.
Rym: if you're good don't get those like nasty plastic ones the weird smell.
Rym: and Clothes you don't care about like shitty socks old like proper denim jeans that are invincible anything.
Rym: I wear to sleep underwear like Shirts that I'm gonna wear out work clothes anything like that.
Rym: the things I don't feel like like a collared shirt that can go in The drain yep, or shirts that are old enough to where I don't care or like a plain old pant like a pant.
Rym: So I did the thing a long time ago Not a long time ago like about a year ago where I I declared bankruptcy on my socks And I decided that I will only have Like.
Rym: I'll get one type of sock that I like and get a ton of pair of that exact sock Mm-hmm and no other socks.
Rym: all the weird socks go.
Scott: put socks in the dryer.
Rym: Uh I put my regular as black socks in the dryer.
Rym: I do not put my smart wool socks in the dryer.
Scott: No, no, that's I put some more socks in here.
Scott: I think it'll ruin them.
Rym: It wears them out way fast.
Rym: They're fine They'll wear.
Scott: they've lasted years.
Rym: Yeah years mine will last the rest of my life.
Rym: Okay, is my plan also minor?
Scott: people socks not smart wool brand, but it's basically the same.
Rym: Yeah, well so the thing is I I have to kind of this extra usage in that I have a lot of smart Well socks.
Rym: they wear every day like at work because they're really comfy.
Rym: But I also have a bunch of like fancy sport socks to use for like Running long distances and things that like special ski socks.
Rym: those all get hung up to dry because they're really expensive.
Rym: Hmm like I don't want to buy ski socks more than a few times in my life.
Scott: Yeah When it comes to like something that is a delicate item some of them I look at the label and I look at like my Circumstance like am I in a hurry right now?
Scott: How much space do I have in my drying rack right now?
Scott: And it's like sometimes I'll put some things tumble dry low if it says they can tumble dry low.
Scott: Yep, right like Like if I got a hoodie, right if I'm washing the hoodie, I'm usually gonna want to hang up the hoodie.
Scott: I don't want to put that in the dryer.
Scott: Yep, but hoodies do take a long time to dry.
Scott: Yeah, and it says you can tumble dry low.
Scott: So it's like I'll hang it up.
Rym: if I can tumble dry it inside out Zip it up inside out.
Rym: I'm not I'm not kidding.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Rym: It matters.
Rym: It doesn't in the dryer.
Scott: The point is Tumble dry low is the option for some.
Scott: it's like the borderline between.
Scott: I could dry it, but I don't want.
Rym: Here's what I don't put in the dryer fancy expensive weird socks that have like wool and stuff in them Nerd shirts that I actually want to keep.
Rym: uh-huh nurtures.
Rym: I don't give a shit about they just go in the dryer.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: and all my like technical fabric like sports nonsense.
Scott: Yeah, if I got all my heat techs and my clothes my like that all Russian shirt the thing is most of those things are so like hydrophilic bobic.
Scott: That like they're not even that wet when they come out of the wash like my microfiber towels.
Rym: They dry within 30 seconds of me being done with them, right?
Scott: So it's like in the air.
Scott: It's like they're.
Scott: they're all weird fabrics that don't like absorb water like cotton does and they don't come out like of the washer like a Sponge that's soaking full of water like a towel does.
Scott: so I can just hang those up and they'll be dry in like an hour.
Rym: No, I would why I would dry all my cotton stuff.
Rym: But actually as time goes on cotton kind of sucks for most uses.
Rym: So I've gotten rid of almost all my cotton.
Rym: like I don't really wear a lot of cotton anymore.
Scott: t-shirts again That's it t-shirts.
Rym: But even then most of my t-shirts are a cotton like rayon blend Or a cotton nylon.
Rym: like they're always a blend and I prefer to wear technical fabric so I can get away with it.
Rym: Hmm.
Rym: So Here's here's the thing I was thinking about in terms of anecdotes.
Rym: one thing that bothered me a lot at RIT and it still bothers me because I encounter it kind of often is I encounter a Lot of people who don't understand how to do laundry and I observe people when I'm doing laundry Doing laundry or really badly and clearly ruining their clothes and not understanding.
Scott: Well, I think it may not necessarily not understanding but it could just be not caring not caring Especially at college.
Scott: A lot of people are just like they just fucking throw everything in one washing machine.
Scott: No, it's like.
Scott: it saves them money.
Scott: It works.
Scott: At least their clothes don't smell.
Rym: but like Who were afraid to do laundry because they didn't know how and they took all their laundry home every.
Scott: well, that's bad upbringing That's not.
Scott: yeah, that's not.
Scott: no I had it.
Scott: There's nothing.
Scott: laundry specific Society problem that is not topic even in high school.
Rym: Like my family just did laundry in a big unit.
Rym: So I never really did my own laundry in high school.
Rym: even I mean laundry just got done.
Scott: I didn't think yeah, I didn't do laundry.
Scott: that often when I was a kid and my you know, family did my you know My mother did the laundry for everybody.
Scott: Thing is when I was moving away, I'm like, oh I guess I have to do my own laundry now.
Scott: Hey mom, show me how to do laundry.
Scott: Wow.
Scott: I mean when I went to cut when I went to RIT You know the first day I got there I said, all right, you showed me how to do laundry.
Scott: I remember what you said.
Scott: I did it once but I'm like Let's go to the laundry room just to look at it and you tell me which buttons to push.
Scott: Yeah, and it's just like oh, yeah use that one in that one I'm like, okay.
Rym: And then I knew how to do laundry at RIT the first time I did laundry when I like that and basically the first week We were there after anime club at our wag.
Rym: I went down into the tunnels and I went to do laundry and I just looked at the tag and all my clothes And I sorted them based on what the tag said.
Rym: Yeah, that was it.
Rym: it works fine.
Scott: I mean we basically in our goddamn building.
Rym: the point is we tried but in our goddamn building the building we live in now on two separate occasions and Possibly the same person started a fire in the dryer.
Scott: That's that's a problem.
Rym: That is weirdly common because people don't know the dumbest thing.
Scott: if we're talking about dumb things I've seen other people do.
Scott: I saw dumbest thing I've seen someone do in a laundry room is they were drying their clothes and They were putting in.
Scott: you know, they have those dryer sheets.
Scott: I don't use those.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean they have a valid use sometimes.
Rym: Yeah, generally I would avoid those things.
Scott: I don't use them.
Scott: I used to.
Scott: I use them at the beginning cuz I thought like it was a necessity.
Scott: but I've stopped a lot years and years ago, I stopped.
Scott: but it's like When I did use them, I put one sheet in the dryer and that was all I did Right, and I guess it's supposed to reduce static or something.
Scott: Yep, theoretically.
Scott: Maybe it works.
Scott: Maybe it doesn't have a static problem.
Scott: So I guess I don't need them right?
Rym: Yeah, I saw someone ram sticks around ever, right?
Scott: I saw somebody doing laundry.
Scott: They open up the dryer and they were putting in like tons and tons of dryer sheets.
Rym: Oh and one.
Scott: what it was like.
Scott: they put in like maybe 20 sheets for like one dry.
Scott: and I'm like What the fuck are you doing?
Rym: I watched someone in colony at RIT I remember this moment Chris with with crystal alacrity.
Rym: So I'm like doing my laundry and I hated doing laundry Like I tried to minimize the number of times I do.
Rym: what is that fucking laundromat?
Scott: Point that I think because of having to use pay laundry I tend to build up a big old pile and then do it Whereas if I had my own machine like in my apartment or house.
Rym: I just do one load.
Scott: I would be doing it like, you know As soon as I had enough to fill the washing machine, I would do it.
Rym: So I was.
Rym: I was over there like doing an infinite amount of laundry because I had waited until I literally had nothing left to Wear exactly.
Rym: I was wearing the loincloth boxers on that day Under some jeans that were dirty that I wanted to wash but I didn't have anything else to wear to go to the laundromat.
Rym: Yeah, they weren't getting washed.
Rym: Yep, and while I was there I saw someone Basically take a like two cup like kitchen measuring cup pour Completely fill it with detergent.
Rym: Oh, no pour it into the top of the washer.
Rym: No, so I was.
Rym: I was thinking I should stop them.
Rym: They were already too far into the process.
Rym: I just decided to ignore that bubble flood.
Rym: So yeah I Came back to get my clothes out of the dryer and I see that person is now sitting standing there in a panic.
Rym: the water There are suds Covering the floor of the entire laundromat.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And that person is standing there like trying to figure out how to get their clothes and sneak away before they get in trouble.
Scott: So I don't.
Scott: I don't entirely blame that moron for their that mistake.
Scott: I also blame the laundry detergent industry, right?
Scott: You buy laundry detergent.
Scott: I buy that the yellow one that the arvin hammer one with no smells on it.
Scott: That's what I've used my whole life and I a few times and I've used other things.
Scott: I think I got a rash So I always use that same one.
Scott: Yep, but basically it comes on.
Scott: the cup is a lid to the bottle the jug.
Scott: That is also a measuring cup.
Scott: It's super convenient.
Scott: and Inside that cup there's like if you just look at it It's like a ring and I got you know Like a darker ring where like the screw part is and like you sort of feel like your OCD wants to fill up to that Line, right and it sort of like feels like the right amount for that cup.
Scott: But actually if you look in the cup There's like these very hard to see Measurements right and they're labeled a one two, three, maybe even four.
Scott: I forget I only ever use a or one.
Scott: I use one if I like completely jam-packed.
Scott: the whole washing machine full of towels.
Scott: It's like full and I use a pretty much for everything else.
Rym: We use concentrated and is a big like a teaspoon in this one load.
Scott: Yeah, it's like there's a big sign in the laundry room.
Scott: That's like use a quarter cup.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: I'm using less than that Laundry detergent like take some of it.
Scott: It's just like soap.
Scott: It's like whatever and like mix it with water.
Scott: It goes bananas Like crazy.
Rym: part of this is that top loaders need more detergent and are way less good at washing.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I get side loaders.
Rym: top loaders are the worst.
Scott: I've only actually ever used side loaders.
Rym: top loaders are mostly only common in the American Midwest and they're bullshit.
Scott: like In my house growing up the dryer was a side loader But the washer was a top loader.
Rym: uploaders are just ass.
Scott: but it's like ever since I left home.
Scott: I've only ever used a side load.
Rym: Some side loaders use less energy clean your clothes better damage your clothes less and require less detergent to clean the clothes.
Rym: so a lot of people are used to When they lived in their house with their parents the old top loader that actually needed a lot of detergent and kind of sucked at Washing your clothes.
Rym: Hmm modern washers need like a tenth that amount of detergent.
Scott: But anyway, it's like yeah, you don't need that much.
Scott: and Rym see we were talking about detergent before the show we use super concentrated like a teaspoon in.
Scott: Yeah, Rym is using not only the super concentrated stuff, which is fine using like a bunch of different things.
Scott: I just use one thing one detergent to clean absolutely every clothing in the universe.
Rym: We have two kinds of wash it.
Rym: Well, we have normal clothes to wash and we have weird sports clothes that get stinky and need to be washed differently.
Rym: Sports clothes are hard to wash for reasons.
Rym: I don't want to get into.
Scott: I have weird sport clothes for biking And I wash it with the same shit.
Scott: I don't put it in the dryer But I just wash it with the same stuff and it's just fine.
Rym: This is like the compression shirt that I wear running where I make.
Rym: I make one of these stinky and dirty I had almost every day because I run almost every day.
Scott: I have like a base layer II shirt for biking when it's cold and I always I just wash that with regular Detergent just fine.
Rym: Yeah, what's it made out of?
Rym: What's the fabric?
Scott: It's some kind of weird fancy.
Scott: Anyway, I don't look I don't pay that much attention.
Scott: I just said shit.
Scott: I have to bike when it's cold, and I really don't want to let me buy every possible thing That will keep me warm.
Rym: These are I have gym clothes that every time I use them I drench them in sweat.
Rym: So they need to be washed and technical fabrics are hard to wash.
Rym: So we use a different detergent and some borax for that because borax just makes laundry.
Rym: Awesome.
Scott: It just borax is good for Play-doh.
Scott: That's a borax is great.
Rym: Just dump some borax in with your detergent and it'll wash your clothes way better.
Rym: borax also costs Basically nothing.
Scott: it's like free like on Amazon.
Scott: It's like when you're going to buy baking soda and it's like oh, how much is this baking soda?
Scott: It's like 30 cents.
Scott: It's like oh, okay.
Rym: I bought a package of borax that will last us for years possibly and cut it cause nothing.
Scott: Yeah, it's like no matter how poor you are You can back if you're poor or certain things you can afford if you're legit poor and like really need to save money.
Rym: Use borax instead of detergent.
Rym: It'll wash your clothes pretty good.
Rym: Like it's it works and it cost nothing.
Scott: Not like expensive as tied like a lot other laundry detergents like are so expensive that like I was reading stories about like people using laundry detergent as like Currency, it's like buy drugs and other black market stuff.
Scott: I believe it Is the same thing where it's like they would rob a drugstore steal detergent or formula because that was valuable stuff right and then buy drugs just instead of like Selling the formula and then getting money and then buying drugs.
Scott: They would just give the formula to the drug dealer.
Scott: Yeah, and it's like laundry detergent was also a very expensive item.
Scott: So the fires.
Rym: so one day the dryer fire one day We're just.
Scott: I guess someone had a flammable clothing and put it in there and on high.
Rym: So I'm not sure because there are.
Rym: there are three with there's three main ways Dryers will start a fire.
Scott: the main way not cleaning the lint room Yes is in a house there's someone in my apartment building who does not clean the lint trap because every time I Go to the dryer.
Scott: I have to clean it up before I dry.
Scott: I was down there drying and like my neighbor was also down there washing after me and then I go and I go to the Dryer and cuz they were doing they were putting their wash in.
Scott: I just took the wash out.
Scott: So I was going in the dryer and before I go in the dryer I take the lint wrap out and I go to clean it and she's like, ah, I guess you're not the person Someone who doesn't clean the fucking lint wrap.
Scott: and they were checking to see if it was me and it wasn't me.
Scott: And it wasn't them either because they're accusing me.
Scott: they were Suspecting I might be the one and I wasn't.
Rym: that narrows it down.
Scott: It does It's not either.
Scott: it's someone of the other 12 apartments in the building.
Rym: good fucking god.
Rym: Do you know how many house fires that kill people are caused by lint traps not being cleaned out?
Rym: Yeah, every time people don't know the lint trap exists, right?
Scott: There's a lint thing in your dryer.
Scott: every single dryer in the world has this every single kind before it.
Rym: Well,
Scott: hopefully if you tell if you're the only one using it You don't have to do before only after right but before and after a public dryer you take it out You go to the trash and you put all the lint in the trash
Rym: because
Scott: lint is and then you put it back.
Rym: lint from Modern.
Scott: your air conditioner has a filter like this pretty similar to clean that out like once or twice a year Yep.
Rym: So also if you have a you know, if you have a stove, there's a little grease trap in the fume hood.
Rym: Change that periodically.
Rym: Oh, yeah at the top.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Also your drip your dishwasher.
Scott: some dishwashers I think most dish washes like a filter have like a thing at the bottom that you got to clean out.
Scott: go to YouTube to Read about that.
Scott: Yep watch about that.
Rym: But a huge number of fatal fires in the US are caused by people who literally don't know the lint trap exists.
Scott: If you eventually start a follow if you follow New York Fire Department on Twitter They're always tweeting good fire safety tips Like know where the stairs are check the batteries and your smoke detector.
Scott: It is clean out your fucking lint trap in the dryer Flammable if you smell gas fucking run.
Rym: So a corollary that the other thing that lint will cause a fire in is if you have a house The lit you probably have a tube the exhaust exhaust tube.
Rym: lint gets into that tube as well Yep And that tube will slowly.
Rym: if every now and then you got to take that tube down and clean it out someday that tubes just Gonna explode in a fireball.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: So lint is super flammable.
Scott: If you want to start a fire like you're going camping bring some lint with you And then you can start your fire way easy with some lint way better than twigs.
Rym: I had a. I had an emergency fire starter Kit.
Rym: I put in a couple of ziplock bags.
Rym: It was a bunch of lint a bunch of basically, like wire foil and A 9-volt battery.
Rym: Mm-hmm those three together.
Rym: You can start a fire in any weather.
Scott: Yeah lint is like whoo.
Rym: So the second thing that starts fires is the other most common thing.
Rym: people are just dumb and they don't.
Rym: They don't connect.
Rym: the action they took like I am putting this thing in a box That's gonna get hot for an hour with maybe this thing if it gets hot will be dangerous.
Rym: So they'll put like fake leather Clothes that have like rubber on it or flammable shit.
Scott: a lot of times that stuff will just melt and get ruined.
Rym: But I'm not so often fired or it'll melt and ruin the dryer.
Rym: Oh and the clothes another thing.
Scott: so I worked in a dry cleaner for like many years during high school, right?
Scott: And Basically, we didn't do any of the cleaning in the place I was working.
Scott: so I didn't get cancer from dry cleaning chemicals but people would give me clothes and they have to sort out their clothes and tag them and stuff so that we'd give the right person their Clothes back because everything goes in one giant washing thing, right?
Scott: So one thing I had to do was check everyone's fucking pockets on everything to make sure you didn't leave anything in there.
Scott: Right, and I found a lot of pens that would have exploded with ink a lot of wallets full of money And a lot of other weird stuff that people left in their pocket before they did laundry.
Scott: That would have not been good if it got went into the washer and especially the dryer or the dry cleaning machine.
Scott: So now whenever I do laundry Basically as I'm sorting my laundry like into the different loads, I'm gonna do I always check the pockets on fucking everything?
Rym: Oh every now and then I miss something and then the laundry comes out and it's like oh there was a business card in those.
Scott: Never missed anything because I worked But I see it happen to other people.
Scott: I'll go.
Scott: when I open the dryer I'll see like a receipt that's all wadded up and was clearly washed and dry.
Rym: Yeah, basically, I'll see coins in there or sitting in that I was sitting in the apartment and Emily I we both kind of smell smoke.
Scott: Yeah, so I'm like well So we I walk around the apartment like see like I don't leave on the fire alarm, but I leave if I sell smoke.
Rym: So it's definitely not coming from anything in the apartment.
Rym: That's good.
Rym: So I got a hallway and it gets stronger.
Rym: Okay, so I go to the stairwell and I open it and it's like the stairwell is full of smoke.
Rym: Oh, so I'm like, well, we're either gonna stay in our bill We're gonna I'm gonna go barricade myself in my apartment because it's a fireproof building.
Rym: Like I'm safe in the apartment.
Rym: You can take the different the other stairwell or I'm just gonna leave the other side of the building other stairwell also filled with smoke Both stairwells.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Oh But so I hold my breath and I walk down the stairwell Just seeing because the alarm hasn't gone off anywhere.
Rym: and I get to the ground floor and I come out and I see a girl who looks like she's in her early 20s and The doorman and the girl is crying and saying just let me go in I didn't do anything wrong.
Rym: and the doorman just like nope.
Rym: You're staying right here.
Rym: And this basically what happened was she put something in a dryer She shouldn't have.
Rym: yeah, she didn't know how to do laundry and she turned the dryer on high and it fucking caught on fire.
Scott: Yeah, I hope she's got renters insurance.
Rym: Yep, cuz she was responsible for like many thousands of dollars of damage to the laundry room.
Scott: Yeah, of course you are.
Rym: She really wanted to go and get something out of the dryer So she wouldn't get in trouble and it was clearly not her fault because it was clearly her fault.
Rym: So the other thing this happened again, just cleaning clothes is suddenly so dangerous.
Scott: a few months I just cleaned some clothes back in the old day.
Scott: Just taking clothes get him wet in the river rub him on a board.
Rym: so a few months later this happened again starting fires and I Saw.
Rym: that's what I'm pretty sure is that same woman like in the room When they were like trying to sort out what started.
Rym: the small fire wasn't as big a fire.
Rym: Pretty sure it was the same person who caused the problem.
Scott: Did you make the same mistake twice?
Rym: So pull me one time after that by two time the laundry room put up all these signs that were basically like oh my god Don't fucking fuck up your laundry.
Rym: Jesus Christ - here's how to use a dryer.
Rym: Oh my god, so The third thing that will cause a fire in your dryer is something gasoline?
Scott: Well, yes throw a battery in there if you're.
Rym: if your clothes are dirty with say Flammable oils because you were doing bike maintenance do not put them in the dryer unless they've been thoroughly washed.
Scott: Yeah Well, why would you put something in the dryer before you put it in the wash?
Rym: because it's wet because they got rained on And they're dumb.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I guess yeah I guess if you were working on a car you got oily and then it rained and you're like Oh my clothes are wet and you just put it in the dryer immediately instead of going in the wash first.
Scott: Yeah, but yeah The washing detergents are really good at getting rid of oil like actually whenever I get all greasy from like You know messing with my bike chain or something like that.
Scott: What I always use is Dawn dish soap.
Scott: then it's like whoosh.
Scott: It's like oh man.
Scott: So what laundry detergent similarly strong?
Scott: It's just even more concentrated than dish detergent.
Scott: So I don't use that but I could.
Rym: but there is a third thing that will cause fires in dryers that people don't know About.
Rym: I think I talked about it on GeekNights a while ago when I told the story of the fire because I was mad About it.
Scott: suddenly this is about dryer fires and not about laundry.
Rym: Well, the more if you have old jeans that have especially we had to talk about the different moods on the washing machine.
Rym: Oh, yeah, we can finish on that.
Rym: you can end on that.
Rym: Anyway, if you got jeans that have a button fly don't wash your jeans on high and then let it sit for a while Because those buttons will be hot enough if the dryer isn't spinning to potentially ignite Some other piece of clothing that's touching them.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: That is a way that you can start a fire.
Scott: Yeah I don't watch things with metal on high.
Rym: you can avoid all of these problems by never putting anything but towels in on high.
Scott: Pretty much I do towels on high everything else.
Scott: medium, but also delicate things.
Scott: tumble dry loaf.
Rym: Yep, if you're gonna put a nerd shirt in lowest possible.
Scott: Those are the dryer modes pretty much high medium low.
Scott: No other dryer mode matters.
Scott: You got a fancy dryer with other modes.
Scott: They basically don't matter.
Rym: You only need high unless you get the drying rack dryer that doesn't tumble you literally.
Rym: I want one of these.
Rym: you hang your clothes on Hangers in this thing.
Rym: you close the doors and it just circulates air over them without tumbling.
Scott: to dry them without heat I just use the drying rack at that point.
Rym: That's a fancy dryer.
Rym: You only have if you have a fancy house.
Scott: I guess so.
Scott: But anyway, so the washing machine modes, right depends on what kind of washing machine.
Scott: Yeah, there are a lot of washing machines a lot of different modes But the the main mode that people I think don't use correct because people I think people know it's like.
Scott: yeah if it's like if it's like white and you don't care about the colors getting torn out of the clothes and you don't care about the Clothes like shrinking or something cuz they're a sweater Yeah, you can go hot towels hot will clean clothes better.
Scott: white undershirt times, right?
Scott: White undershirt stuff like that.
Scott: You can go hot or warm if you want Right, if it's something that you don't want messed up like say your nerdy t-shirts that you're not gonna put in the dryer Normal wash but cold.
Scott: Yeah, you go.
Rym: Well, here's the thing normal washers like cheap ones or like sideloader industrial ones Like in our building, there's only three modes hot medium cold right.
Rym: what that actually means is six modes.
Rym: Well, yeah So what the minimum?
Rym: what it actually means hot means wash hot rinse cold.
Rym: medium warm means wash warm.
Rym: rinse cold.
Rym: Cold means wash cold.
Rym: rinse cold because it fills with water.
Rym: drains fill the water again fancy dryers.
Scott: lets you set the wash and the dry Independently, so there's also something you got to check is in the back of a washing machine is not complicated.
Scott: It's two hoses a hot water hose and a cold water hose.
Scott: Yeah, a lot of washing machines are hooked up wrong because the washing machine don't know the washing machine doesn't know the temperature of the water It's.
Scott: it just says well if you tell me to use hot water I use hose a and if you tell me to use cold water I use hose B It's the hose.
Scott: a joke.
Scott: But yeah.
Scott: So a lot of times people put the wrong hose on the wrong thing.
Scott: and you tell your washer do cold does hot tells you Hot this cold.
Rym: No, this is extra bad.
Rym: So you say you tell your washer to walk do a hot wash It's gonna wash this closed cold.
Scott: So you get none of the benefits of that hot rinsing.
Rym: It's gonna hot rinse it which just ruins them for nothing.
Scott: But anyway, so other modes in the washer.
Scott: you got to get this delicate mode.
Scott: Which those only.
Scott: so those most use that for some sweater action.
Scott: those tend to only exist in either shitty Toploaders and what that means the ones the ones in my building have they have hot which I don't use.
Scott: Yeah, they have.
Scott: Though they have.
Scott: they've white.
Scott: white is hot.
Scott: They've whites colors brights.
Scott: bright is cold, right color is warm.
Scott: White is hot.
Rym: I do not as I don't like washers that say like what the mode is for.
Rym: I like what does this say?
Scott: There's like what they do.
Scott: There's a guide on the wall that tells you what the modes do.
Rym: Yeah, but I need to know what it does.
Rym: I want to know like it's gonna tumble like this, right?
Scott: So then it has delicates Woolen's which are far as I can tell are identical.
Scott: And then the final mode is the mode I think people use wrongly or don't know or scared of like don't use because they don't know.
Scott: what it means is permanent press.
Rym: Ah Permanent press was a mode I use for most of my clothes back when I had a dryer that had that option, right?
Scott: So permanent press is basically this mode where there's like this like cold rinse at the end.
Scott: I don't know exactly how it works.
Scott: I'll be honest.
Scott: I could go it.
Scott: Yeah The reason you use permanent press is basically to for a clothes that you would normally iron and you don't want it to be too Wrinkly, it washes them in such a way that they won't be too wrinkly.
Scott: They won't right.
Rym: So those are only relevant to top loaders with agitators.
Scott: No Loader as permanent.
Rym: Yes here's the problem.
Rym: the differences between them are way less with the side loader because the.
Rym: the main reason there's so many extra modes in Top loader is that if the agitator spins it fucks up your clothes.
Rym: Anyway, like I read right now on what permanent press cycle washes the clothes that wash and warm rinse cool not cold cool.
Rym: and the agitator is set to low and the spin cycle at the end that rings the water out is Also not that fast.
Rym: So the clothes get dried less in the washer because that last cycle.
Rym: I just I don't want to get into all this.
Rym: but basically the actual parameters you can set in a top loader are That's the heat of the wash the heat of the rinse whether or not there is a secondary rinse how fast the agitator spins or moves how fast the thing moves at the end when All the waters drain to ring the water out.
Rym: Some modes will not do the ring at all because that'll mess up like a woollen for anyway.
Scott: So permanent press is great for like dress shirts.
Rym: Yeah dress pants khaki pants Yeah, pretty much pants with the crease.
Scott: you put permanent press right anything that's gonna get wrinkled and you're gonna have to iron it.
Scott: Or you hopefully maybe want to try to avoid ironing.
Scott: That's when you use the permanent press mode.
Scott: if you've got clothes like that Maybe save up enough of them to fill the whole washer and wash them all together.
Scott: So it's more economical and you don't want to like wash a bunch of jeans and then put in one dress shirt at its own Wash.
Rym: Oh, there's one more parameter.
Rym: I forgot about.
Rym: it really only applies to top loaders.
Rym: How how full is the load like you only wash in one shirt?
Rym: You'll fill the tank with less water.
Scott: Yeah, don't put too many clothes in either a washer or a dryer.
Scott: They have a capacity.
Scott: It's only designed to clean so many clothes at once.
Rym: you put more in your stuff.
Rym: Just won't get clean.
Scott: Yeah, it's like it cleans better when you put the right amount of clothes and you put too many clothes in it Can't clean all them.
Scott: They don't all really get clean, you know, if you put it too much stuff in the dryer It won't all get dry.
Scott: Yeah, you got it right put in the right amount.
Scott: Don't put in some ridiculously tiny amount.
Scott: It'll get super clean, but it's a super waste to run the whole washer to clean like one pair of underwear.
Scott: Right, but make sure you put you know a reasonable amount if you're jamming stuff in and trying to squeeze it in too much.
Scott: Nope, if there's no empty space in there whatsoever Too much.
Scott: Yep, and it should be some empty space, but it shouldn't be like super empty.
Rym: and All this is much less of a concern.
Scott: again If you got a side loader side loaders are still don't want to overload the side loader But at least the side loader won't have like some weird unbalanced problem.
Rym: an overloaded side loader will still wash your clothes better Normally loaded top loader.
Rym: Yeah Anyway, I think that's enough laundry talk.
Rym: Yeah, this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and my comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the patreon patrons for this particular episode of GeekNights recorded in February on the 14th are The.
Rym: I gotta get the patreon thing up.
Rym: I Always record this in one take no matter what no edits.
Rym: So sometimes this happens.
Rym: Here we go Craig Oliver Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol just like a dude.
Rym: guys your tapashen linky G Jennifer Hitchcock Chris midkiff my Sadie calm Jay Vance scoot alone Lee Roberto Kingsley Sean Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas brand on mr.
Rym: Strong stretch in 421 creations Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn Shervin van Horr Rory Michelle, Monta Nona super boy sailor vista Don Schleich Joe Joe Joe star Clinton Walton Renford, New Zealand Ryan parent drew up and ladder Finn Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer Thomas on and now I leave you with
Scott: bacon pancake layer of bacon pancake.
Scott: Cell it bacon.
Scott: a few demon pancake bacon pancake.
Scott: Dean hefty smash me bacon pancake.