Rym: It's Wednesday July 12th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We speak at great length about our experiences at ConnectiCon.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So uh I grew up in a place where tornadoes were commonplace Kansas Texas, Michigan, Oklahoma.
Rym: lots of tornadoes to the point that I mean tornadoes and thunderstorms And we just didn't really care because they tended to follow the roads.
Rym: and not too much damage Not too many tornadoes in New York, Connecticut, I mean there may be one every couple years, but not too many Yeah, which I found funny because when there was like a tornado watch and people in my work were all a tornado.
Rym: oh No, what do we do?
Rym: and I was like why do you sit in your basement?
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty much what you do.
Scott: tornado warning in the basement.
Rym: But it was gone out of the basement despite the fact that so many tornadoes and storms that come through and I grew up with No tornado had ever Affected my life because the where I grew up tornadoes were common.
Rym: so everything was kind of designed in a way that Tornadoes really didn't affect your daily life.
Rym: if a tornado came through it didn't knock the power out it didn't do anything It just kind of went through disappeared knocks a couple trees down everyone on with their lives.
Rym: It took me today five hours to get home from work.
Rym: For five hours I was sitting in my car because a tornado momentarily ripped through some parts of downstate, New York which Crippled the entire road infrastructure of New York City to the point that no one could leave the city.
Rym: Every road going north was closed.
Rym: not only were they closed, but I got.
Rym: I was driving home I left work early, and I'm driving and then Suddenly traffic is stopped up ahead, and there's no egg.
Rym: There's an exit like a mile past this stop, so all right I figured this prime accident.
Rym: I'll get off on this exit right there that I can practically see the exit because it's right there.
Rym: and No, no traffic didn't move at all as in it Just didn't move for two hours couldn't you go in the median and get?
Rym: there's no median It's the.
Rym: it's a parkway in New York City.
Rym: There's a giant cement divider.
Rym: the lanes were narrow.
Scott: It was brick wall lane lane brick wall, haha You couldn't put the tire on the grass or anything.
Rym: no grass.
Rym: Oh, I turned my car off and sat there listening to podcasts and reading a nancy boys for two hours.
Scott: Uh-huh, then I spent the next three hours, and if I was stuck in there I probably could have finished a stupid lensman book.
Scott: that isn't really so stupid.
Rym: three hours trying to get home I eventually got home.
Rym: It sucked.
Rym: so basically my entire day consisted of work Driving podcast soon-to-be sleep.
Scott: Yeah, you know that's the thing is in New York.
Scott: You know it's sort of.
Scott: it's like this up It's like a triangle with the pointy bit at the bottom and then New York City.
Scott: So everyone's trying to get from this is crammed into the bottom of the pointy part of a triangle and then Spreading out to this wide part of a triangle.
Scott: But there's really only like three or four roads that go north and like two of them to go northeast which aren't so useful for us.
Scott: so Since it's still kind of narrow if a tornado goes horizontal perpendicular to those roads Which it did along 287 then there's really difficult to go north.
Rym: and then I called Scott and we're going back and forth trying to figure out how I can get home since he's sitting there with Google Maps being my navigator and Every road was closed.
Rym: It was like 684. now something's crazy.
Rym: It's closed 84.
Rym: Oh shit truck exploded on it.
Rym: Yeah, which is not a joke a sewage truck exploded.
Rym: Then the driver drove the truck away, and they eventually caught him somewhere in Connecticut.
Scott: I thought they he drove it away.
Rym: Well, it's just like it broke and spilled it everywhere, and he didn't want to deal with.
Scott: oh So he unhitched the trailer, and he drove his truck away I think.
Rym: so they caught him at some diner a rest stop or something okay?
Scott: Cuz I mean it's one thing if he was dragging or exploded sewage truck around.
Scott: But it's like your trailer explodes.
Scott: you just unhitch your truck and keep going.
Rym: that's different yeah, but anyway I'm not gonna bore you with the details of that.
Rym: Maybe I'll talk about it on a Thursday or something when it's on the national news.
Rym: go to Google News and search in New York Talk about my experiences seeing in a car for five hours And all the fun.
Rym: I had there yep Tell.
Rym: the longer went on the less clothed that I was.
Rym: no Like it started out like I'm were there police everywhere?
Scott: there were police everywhere, so why would you take your clothes?
Rym: Because I was really hot.
Scott: now all right you have no air condition didn't matter.
Rym: even if the air conditioning works There's no way I could have used it.
Rym: sitting stopped like that with air conditioning for that long We just overheat the car.
Rym: You know many cars overheated caught fire or just broke sitting there for all those hours.
Rym: cuz idiots wouldn't just turn them off their AC.
Rym: Sit in a parked car with the AC for two hours.
Scott: Well, you can't not for two hours, but for a little while again.
Scott: Yeah, maybe like 20 minutes.
Rym: But the nice benefit of all this is once I got past Tarrytown where the real damage was There was not a car on the road and not a cop on the road because all the cops were dealing with the crisis down South.
Scott: well, he's the state cops which are the man the local cops.
Rym: It was all local cops.
Rym: I didn't see a single state cop.
Rym: Well, those are the ones you got to worry about now because they were busy dealing with other more important disasters like on Route 6 And 202 and all that area.
Rym: uh-huh, so I went pretty much a hundred miles an hour the rest of the way home.
Rym: It was real fun because there was no one on the road.
Rym: no no stoplights because they were all broken.
Scott: no Danger.
Rym: no because there's no traffic.
Rym: There were no lights.
Rym: There was no one.
Rym: the road was empty.
Rym: It was just me.
Rym: I didn't see another car for 20 minutes.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: It was awesome.
Rym: I was like I was in my own personal rally race.
Scott: Great.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Anyway, once again, I won't bore you with all the details of that.
Scott: Maybe I'll do a minute by minute accounting of it someday Someday hopefully a long time from now When we don't have to sit around going.
Scott: so I was sitting in the car not doing anything.
Scott: I was sitting in the car not doing anything.
Scott: Yeah, I was sitting in the car still not doing anything.
Rym: All right, so it's anime day and instead of a normal new well anime manga comics day, but there's no manga in comics.
Rym: Well, yeah, it's anime manga comics day, but we're talking mostly about anime today.
Rym: So I'll call it anime day.
Rym: Hmm, but yeah for the benefit of our new listeners We should call it the actual thing because if you are a new listener and you're listening right now just for the ConnectiCon Feedback slash coverage keep in mind that we go four nights a week.
Rym: Mondays are science and tech Linux computers all that.
Rym: Tuesdays are gaming of all kinds.
Rym: Thursdays are anything geeky.
Rym: Wednesdays are obviously anime.
Scott: yep, and You know, that's how it goes.
Rym: Yeah, but instead of a normal news I have kind of a generic bit of talking to do mostly about anime world order.
Rym: Now we sent them a an audio feedback.
Scott: Oh, I know we talked about them so much.
Scott: Do you want to play their promo?
Scott: We've never played a promo before.
Rym: Yeah, I think I'll add a promo in tonight.
Rym: I'm not sure how to deal with promos yet.
Scott: I think we just take it and we'll put it after the things of the day and before the main bit just paste it in There.
Rym: yeah, either that or I'll stick them at the end and is good, right?
Rym: We'll try.
Rym: we'll try because the thing is at least keep in mind if we play a promo That means that we're in some way endorsing it.
Rym: We won't just play a promo because someone else played our promo.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Now we're gonna play the anime world order one because while we disagree on almost every fandom topic There is about anime.
Scott: Oh, no, not everything but we well we're.
Rym: we have this mutual kind of respect cuz they're really cool guys And a girl.
Rym: we just disagree with them a lot Yeah, but they did one our audio feedback which was real good on their previous episode episode 26 And if you like what we say now, you should probably listen to that special episode, but more importantly they reviewed Md.
Rym: Geist.
Rym: Yeah, and Not only was that the best segment ever done on anime world order But that was one of the funniest things I've ever heard on a podcast.
Rym: I Was also Roveling mightily cuz I had seen like the first half hour of MD guys not even like the first 20 minutes.
Scott: I May or may not have seen MD guys.
Scott: if I had seen it I didn't remember any of it.
Scott: But I have seen and heard of MD guys like I've seen the box and I've heard of the show Like we.
Rym: I rented it from blood.
Rym: I knew it was bad and me and my brother watched in a while and we were just like wow This is crap and we turned it off and I didn't know that it ended that way.
Rym: you guys My god, it's still.
Scott: it's not as bad as great the digital target.
Rym: No, cuz I don't think MD guys is bad as an unwatchable.
Rym: I think it's bad as an awesome I don't know.
Rym: just if anything listen to that review.
Rym: if you even if you hate anime You're just listening to today because you're one of those vivacious ravenous GeekNights fans and you Listen to the anime roller or to review of MD guys.
Scott: Yeah, it was two episodes ago because they just released an episode today.
Rym: Y'all link to it episode 26.
Rym: Yeah All right, you know their anime real kind of news, you know The Academy as in capital the capital Academy as in those people who decide which movie they're gonna give awards to but not give Too many awards to.
Scott: and yeah, you know in the Oscars when people say I'd like to thank the Academy Well, the Academy is really just a bunch of movie people actors directors Executives producers writers special effects guys all that sort of stuff musicians.
Rym: now They're the ones who decide who actually wins those things.
Scott: Yeah, they nominate and vote on Oscars.
Scott: That's what the Academy is.
Scott: Well, they've decided to a. they used to be that the Academy was like more and more exclusive and getting smaller but they've decided reason in recent years that they're going to a grow the Academy by about 30 members a year and Also when people retire and or die they will replace them as well.
Scott: Finally now most of the people in the Academy are from the US But they do have many international people and they have also raised the standards of quality.
Scott: So now they used to just you know Nominate people and then anyone on the list who met the qualifications would get in.
Scott: now they actually only pick the best people from the list even if they met the qualifications.
Scott: and Our good friend from Japan Miyazaki.
Rym: we use our good friend in the royal we sense not in the.
Rym: we know the dude since.
Scott: no He don't know me as Aki, but if we did wouldn't we be awesome.
Rym: Oh, yes quite quite.
Scott: Yeah, we know him Yeah of him.
Rym: He came over and used my bathroom.
Scott: Yeah, so Miyazaki has been invited to the Academy which means that There is a chance because generally he's one of the animators in the Academy.
Scott: So usually they have more.
Scott: I think they have it's kind of a secret, but they definitely have more push in you know Nominating works of animation and voting on them.
Scott: So hopefully he can put in some sort of influence and maybe there will be some more Anime Oscars in the future in the very least.
Rym: I'm just very happy that the Academy and these people have decided to Recognize the vast vast Talent that is Miyazaki.
Scott: Yeah now if only they would get you know Cuz I mean some of the.
Scott: there are other animators in Japan besides Miyazaki who are better than some animators in the Academy Not to say that animators in the Academy besides Miyazaki are bad because I'm sure there are a jillion great ones there.
Scott: But you know to have one guy represent all the greatness that is over there.
Scott: I mean I can think of at least three or four more guys who need to be brought over.
Scott: I got some guys have been brought over in their day.
Rym: I can think of some guys who shouldn't be brought over to.
Scott: oh I can think of plenty of those as well, so There you have it.
Rym: So you want to hear people talk about Japanese cartoons, you know.
Rym: But you think the other anime podcasters just aren't nerdy enough.
Rym: sounds like you need to join forces with the anime world order Where each week three self-proclaimed experts offer you reviews of titles both new and classic news and commentary Rants convention reports interviews with fandom and some hentai and yaoi.
Scott: for good measure.
Rym: So search for anime in the iTunes music store or visit our website at anime world order.
Rym: calm Anime world order revealing the truth about anime.
Rym: one podcast at a time.
Scott: things of the day Thingy thingy thingy thingy thingy real.
Rym: briefly thing one and thing two for all of our new listeners.
Rym: This is the segment which comes directly after that wonderful music where we talk about our things of the day Whatever weird crap thing we've seen in the last 24 hours That for whatever reason we've decided to share with our listeners
Scott: because it's awesome and entertaining enough that we think that Every geek who has an internet connection should go and look at it.
Rym: All right, so without further ado What is your thing of the day?
Scott: My thing of the day is rhyme Torrance calm Rhyme Torrance calm, you know, what's that rhyme Torrance calm?
Rym: Rhyme Torrance.
Scott: Well, let me read the.
Scott: the about this was an effort to round up all of the nerdcore hip-hop artists I could find and get them to do new unreleased tracks.
Scott: be warned It will challenge your assumptions as to what nerdcore hip-hop is.
Scott: not all the tracks are easily pigeonholed.
Scott: this product The production quality varies.
Scott: It's free.
Scott: Quit your whining.
Scott: The individual tracks are available So you can make your own mix of your favorite tracks.
Scott: You can even print your own favorite cover art.
Scott: this on this site is a shit ton of Varying quality nerdcore hip-hop.
Rym: Yeah, there is good nerdcore and there is bad nerdcore.
Scott: And there are four torrents.
Scott: The first torrent is all new tracks.
Scott: the second torrent is more all new tracks.
Scott: the third torrent is rare and Classic tracks and the fourth torrent are rare classic and unreleased tracks.
Scott: the fifth torrent Which is coming soon is going to be all unreleased tracks.
Scott: Uh-huh So if you go there There is some awesome you can get the separate torrents or there's one torrent that gives you all the volumes that are out right now.
Scott: So if you are as yet unexposed or only mildly exposed to the wonderfulness That is their nerdcore.
Scott: This is the Sun Boba the bet exactly Exactly.
Rym: Honestly, my favorite is still the Lords of the Rhymes.
Scott: Yeah, let's see What kind of guys are on here the 13 MCs 16 minutes long?
Rym: You know what?
Scott: I got to give mad props to optimus rhyme though to MC MC plus plus MC rection Doc popular zero bitrate ham star Tumsaw Exactly.
Scott: All right Ultra ultra klystron optimus rhyme MC Hawking MC front a lot futuristic sex robots Dr.
Scott: Octagon lots of good guys in here.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I'm sure MC Chris is in there somewhere now.
Rym: Of course, if you've never heard of nerdcore, which what kind of geek are you?
Rym: Suggest you go check out some optimus rhyme MC front a lot and Lords of the Rhymes in short order.
Scott: Yeah, see nerdcore is hip-hop about nerd stuff geek stuff.
Scott: So that's that's what that is.
Scott: It's it's.
Scott: it's like filk.
Scott: filk is nerdy geeky folk music and nerdcore is Nerdy geeky hip-hop.
Rym: I mean, I just remember when I was at Katsucon and the nerdcore artist there The.
Rym: the thing was it was like a black power rally, but it was nerd power and he gave a Fiery burn the frat houses down speech to a screaming crowd of nerds and then proceeded to sing and it was bad ass Bad ass indeed.
Scott: Hence.
Scott: You should go get these torrents now.
Rym: Scott had a new thing of the day So I've countered that with an old thing of the day.
Rym: This is something that way back we were doing kind of retro things of the day, you know things like coin bad Dinner today and lobster magnet.
Rym: That had been forgotten or unknown to many of the younger people online and this isn't that old but it is quite well known among most people.
Rym: but I have a feeling some people might have missed it and The fact that I forgot to bring it up during our retro weeks was a crime.
Scott: Yeah, this one was sort of under the radar.
Scott: I mean I had seen it once after Rym showed it to me and then he mentioned it and I was like I Kinda remember, I don't know maybe.
Scott: and then he showed it to me and I was like, oh, yeah that thing that I saw once.
Rym: Yeah, because someone in the forums was like how come you didn't do dr.
Rym: Tran?
Rym: and I said Because I totally forgot and I'll do it tomorrow Dr.
Rym: Tran, I don't want to ruin what dr.
Rym: Tran is just go to the link and watch it.
Rym: But dr.
Rym: Tran is a real doctor.
Rym: That's all I got to say about that a kick-ass doctor.
Scott: What?
Scott: Well, he has a PhD and kicking your ass, who are you?
Rym: what is going on?
Scott: Alright.
Rym: Alright, so I without further ado We spent the previous Saturday at Connecticut in the Connecticut Convention Center in Hartford, Connecticut.
Scott: Hartford is the capital of Connecticut.
Rym: for you people who do not know about small states Hartford is also as far as I can tell Nothing, but a convention center surrounded by an industrial and commercial zone.
Scott: You you were far away from the actual city of Hartford which is a moderate city.
Rym: Ah, so the convention center is just in the middle of nowhere.
Scott: Yeah, the convention center is on like the edge of the city where the industrial stuff is.
Scott: It's not in the middle of the city where the tall tall buildings are.
Scott: But yeah, it's sort of like Think of it as a mini Albany, you know It's got a lot of state buildings in it and only like a couple businesses not really any major super headquarters You know, I mean the super major headquarters that are Near Hartford are in like the outskirts like my dad works at like the ultra super campus of the Cigna insurance Company which is way out in the middle of the woods.
Scott: It's not in a big tall building in the city.
Scott: So, you know a Hartford it.
Scott: the city itself is kind of not the biggest most amazing.
Scott: It's actually got quite a West Hartford or kind of you know suburb II and then East Hartford is kind of slummy Yep, but anyway, we were at Connecticut and Connecticut which is not really an anime convention It's more of a webcomic convention.
Scott: What does it actually say?
Scott: Cuz it says Connecticut.
Scott: well, no, it said on the banner they like listed all the things that the con has.
Rym: Well, the thing is it.
Rym: it plays out like an anime con because anime cons Are tend to be very general nowadays and very broad and it had all the trappings of an anime con.
Rym: The same kind of people went that the cosplayers.
Rym: it had the masquerade the AMV contest.
Rym: It felt like an anime con.
Rym: It did not feel like any of the other kinds of cons Mm-hmm, but the one thing it had going for it was that it had gaming.
Rym: In fact, it had better gaming than a lot of gaming cons.
Rym: I've been to which was quite surprising and welcome.
Scott: Yeah, it definitely had better gaming than anime next which is surprising cuz you know anime next is a bigger convention than Connecticut at least as far as I could tell.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway, we actually talked about the gaming at Connecticut yesterday on our gaming podcast night.
Scott: So we're just gonna go over what went down at Connecticut in Chronological order.
Scott: Yep, more or less and we'll leave out the gaming parts.
Scott: I'll pretty much say this is the time when I played the game.
Rym: We might make a little nods to it because I do want to say one That the gaming at Connecticut for anyone who was listening today just because of our report was fantastic.
Rym: It was very well done and I give mad props to everyone involved in the gaming at this convention Mm-hmm.
Rym: However in regards to the rest of the convention despite anything we say I want to say right now that Connecticut was by no means A bad convention.
Rym: We've only been to one bad convention.
Scott: That was Ohio con - yeah Pretty sure we went to Ohio con number two.
Scott: And yeah Ohio con - had great moments for us like a Mario Yeah, and it's like a lot of Nintendo related things the midget and the prostitute in the prostitute playing settlers of guitar.
Scott: but the con itself was Bad.
Rym: now ConnectiCon was not bad.
Rym: don't at any point think that we were saying it's bad.
Rym: We went we had a good time.
Rym: But as it'll be apparent while we talk about ConnectiCon that it does a lot of things.
Rym: well But it does a lot of things Not as well as it could which any one of them or a few of them in and of themselves would have been fine But add it up.
Rym: They really Detract from the experience a lot and we I guess we mean this more as constructive criticism than anything.
Scott: Yeah Here's my my two explanations.
Scott: It's sort of like it's not down to the level where it's like a smelly turd.
Scott: It's sort of like an unpolished gemstone and you're sitting there going polish it polish it polish it polish it polish it polish it Fix it fix it fix it fix it fix it fix it exactly exactly.
Scott: and it's also sort of like if you're watching someone play Mario 1 and they run into the first Goomba and Then you watch him and they do it again.
Scott: Or you're watching someone play Tetris and they keep putting blocks in suboptimal places.
Scott: You're just going.
Scott: ah Why aren't you playing a perfect game?
Scott: I could play a perfect game.
Scott: Ah, so The con.
Scott: while not so bad that it was a terrible convention Some of the parts of the convention were screwed up in certain ways Which we'll get to the specifics as we go on now.
Scott: some of them we could feel that we could have fixed.
Rym: Yeah, most mainly because I mean we go to so many conventions or we you know staff or panelists and so many conventions that I guess ConnectiCon had problems with things that almost every other major con solved a long time ago.
Rym: Yep, and they're simple things that would be almost trivial to fix.
Rym: I mean one dude in two minutes could have fixed a lot of the problems they had.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: But we'll get to that and I just it was a good cut.
Scott: a lot of it was lack of foresight.
Rym: ConnectiCon has a lot of potential and I think if they polish it then it can.
Rym: it can be a fantastic con.
Scott: Yep, I agree.
Scott: First off.
Rym: I was gonna go Friday Okay, and because I accidentally got the day off work And the only reason I didn't because actually our friend we're gonna go meet our friend Yuko There and hang out at her table and her boyfriend Brian was also cool.
Rym: and then on Saturday We're gonna meet our friend cat.
Rym: So we had reasons to go other than just the con.
Rym: and the only reason I didn't go Friday Was that my car doesn't have air and conditioning and it was real hot outside.
Scott: I think that's a good reason.
Rym: Yeah that and I didn't actually technically have a place to stay at the con.
Rym: So while I would have loved to just bum with someone I Would have been interesting because it's been a long time since I went to a convention without having a hotel room lined up
Scott: Yeah, and he while you might have been a little bum with someone you might have been on a floor or who knows
Rym: Yeah, plus actually I had a really good day Friday that involved things I shouldn't talk about on the air because they were illegal but some urban exploration that was most excellent,
Scott: whatever.
Rym: Anyway, so Saturday morning we get up and we'd start driving drive drive drive drive drive completely uneventful.
Rym: We get there around what we didn't get lost at all.
Scott: We just went up.
Scott: There it is.
Scott: We went in.
Rym: yeah, because one thing that Connecticut has going forward is that the Connecticut Convention Center is right off of i-84 and 91.
Scott: you can't miss it.
Scott: It's like 84 91 they meet and the Convention Center is right there.
Scott: You can't fail to get in or out of the place on to the freeway in the direction you want to go in.
Rym: unless you're An idiot we had more trouble parking than we did getting there.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Let's start with the parking.
Scott: So we drive up the parking lots.
Scott: easy to find the entrance easy to find as a lady and she says are you here for?
Scott: The anime and I'm like, yes, she says $8 all day and I'm like wonderful I gave her $8 and we go into the parking lot.
Rym: now at this point I would like to say that pretend you're listening to an audio drama and Right after Scott said that there was a dire chord played like that was important.
Rym: that will come into play at the end.
Scott: Yeah, so remember we paid $8 for parking all day and we go into the parking lot and it's kind of hard to find a Spot because the the signs in the parking lot conflict each other.
Rym: Yes It's a parking garage, but it's not a normal parking garage.
Rym: It is definitely a stadium style parking garage wherein it is designed to have people with flags putting everyone into a space.
Rym: Mm-hmm without that.
Rym: It is a chaotic labyrinth.
Scott: And while there were people with flags there weren't enough people with flags and It basically drove up and up until you found a place to park and then you just got the hell out of there as quick As you could.
Rym: yeah we're not gonna talk about all the times we got lost or couldn't find the car in the parking lot because it doesn't really matter as Nothing to do with the con but just so you know The parking lot is interesting.
Rym: if you ever go to Connecticut or the heart or the Connecticut Convention Center Do not forget where you are parked.
Rym: There is no way to rectify that situation.
Scott: Nope Alright, so then we followed the signs to the convention center not hard and we started walking towards what seemed to be the growing number Of cosplayers.
Rym: now there was some other con going on in the bottom floor of the center something to do with military Contractors and Marines.
Rym: Yep, and the other than that.
Rym: I mean the place was absolutely Sparse and empty.
Scott: there was almost no one around but it's also new and fancy and shiny I mean.
Scott: the first thing I noticed was that there were like these TV displays all over the convention center and like at the doors of all the rooms and The displays were listing all the events times and rooms for the whole con which is very snazzy.
Scott: yeah, usually, you know you go to a convention or you go somewhere and they have facilities like electronic LED signs or TV monitors and the convention that you're going to doesn't take advantage of these facilities.
Scott: and you wonder does any Convention actually take advantage of these things?
Scott: and the fact that Connecticut actually did use the things the convention center had to offer was like Oh, all right Yeah Even though it was really empty.
Scott: and eventually we see some people standing around and to be honest those those TVs showing all the events.
Scott: Weren't that useful?
Rym: No, they weren't but you know, but we see this big stairway and we hear the convention upstairs.
Rym: So, all right, there's the con.
Rym: Let's go.
Rym: We start walking up and these people who I don't know if they were staff or not But they were not identifiable as staff started yelling at us and saying no you got to go that way.
Scott: Well, they said where's your badge and I'm like, I want to get one.
Scott: They said go out there.
Scott: Yeah, go out there.
Rym: They just they didn't look like staff.
Rym: They looked like just some some guy.
Scott: I think it was a security guy.
Scott: Anyway, we went outside and there was a little tiny line.
Scott: Maybe I don't know 20 people.
Scott: Yeah, really small and we're on these stairs outside waiting in line And we're standing and waiting and we met some people from RIT.
Scott: What's up, RIT people?
Rym: Yep, that was not entirely surprising because RIT is one of the geekiest places in the world.
Scott: Yep, so we met our RIT friends and they waited in line with us and eventually they said alright now you can go inside Yep.
Rym: Now they gave us a little after filling out the form, of course.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It wasn't stupid like the Philly wizard world forum that asked us really intrusive questions.
Scott: Yeah about the how much money do you plan to spend here?
Rym: Well, zero now bitches.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Rym: But the one thing was that it had a decent idea where they asked for emergency contact information Which I could see for, you know kids going to a con and whatnot.
Rym: but they gave me a little grief when I didn't fill it out and They were like, why didn't you fill this out?
Rym: And I had to say because there's no one who lives anywhere near here.
Rym: who would care if I died?
Scott: It's like who are they gonna call me?
Scott: who's here?
Rym: Yeah, and if I got blown up odds are Scott gets blown up to Emily who's in Japan.
Scott: Yeah, there's no one else here.
Scott: Who's he gonna call?
Scott: Well, I guess our other friends who were also at the con Yeah, but I mean like the next person you could calls maybe our friend in Albany who doesn't have a car Yeah, so what's he gonna do?
Scott: But whatever my parents you could tell my parents.
Scott: That'd be okay.
Rym: I guess we run into the first problem of ConnectiCon.
Rym: now ConnectiCon is very expensive compared to other cons.
Rym: It costs the same as Otakon.
Scott: Yeah, it was a lot of money 50 bucks for the weekend at the door and Otakon is 50 bucks if you pre-register.
Scott: And this thing is way smaller.
Scott: and let you know It's not an insult to say some con is not as awesome and big as Otakon.
Rym: Yeah, because no con can be.
Scott: that's like saying, you know Going up to some Little League team and saying you're not as good as the team that won the World Series last year You saw.
Scott: yeah, it's not really an insult if I say you don't play basketball as well as Michael Jordan.
Scott: Yep, you can't beat up Mike Tyson.
Rym: It's $50 at the door.
Scott: Mm-hmm, or or it's $35 for a Saturday only now Anyone who knows anything that's a DS game and a DS game and some and like five bucks and change.
Rym: But anyone with half a brain knows that the vast majority of ATMs in the world dole out $20 bills Mm-hmm.
Rym: Now the price for a Saturday admission was therefore on Saturday.
Rym: at a convention like this when the majority of people buying basses are going to be buying day passes or Saturday and Sunday passes which also is a multiple of $5 and not $20 You'd better have a whole bunch of $5 bills ready for change.
Scott: Yes Anyone who has run enough conventions has the foresight to realize something like that.
Scott: if I was running that convention or running the registration I would have had someone go to the bank and get I don't know $10,000 in $5 bills or you know a lot of $5 bills.
Rym: or if that wasn't feasible I would have either raised the price to $40 or lowered it to $30.
Scott: I think lowering it to $30 actually would have been the best solution because it is overpriced.
Scott: But then they need tens then they do need tens but tens or you know, you would need less of them.
Rym: Well, no, you would need the same number of them.
Scott: Maybe a captain math, but it would cost More money, whatever.
Rym: Anyway, but not only they didn't plan for this.
Rym: now we got there really really really early.
Rym: like not many people could have gone through that line before we got to the front of.
Rym: And yet they were out of fives as in completely out of fives.
Scott: There was not a single $5 bill to be had.
Rym: they could not register us because they did not have change and we only had 20s and they refused to accept credit cards.
Rym: and I said something like why didn't you?
Rym: It's $35 Didn't you guys think that everyone's gonna have 20s?
Rym: and the staffers were real kind of indignant like well Yeah, we had we didn't have enough.
Rym: leave us alone.
Scott: Yeah, it's like whenever you you know point out that someone didn't have foresight, you know, it's like, you know.
Scott: They think that you know because obviously if you're in that position if someone comes up to you and it's like didn't you see this problem?
Scott: and it's like Yeah, you have you know the 2020 hindsight.
Scott: we didn't have foresight.
Scott: That's not really fair.
Scott: get away from me.
Scott: But yeah, but we would have had foresight.
Rym: I could have told you that because I mean that's one of the first thing I think of whenever you know a convention or anything.
Rym: If I were planning it is quite literally.
Rym: All right, we're going to charge X If people are paying in 20s, how do we deal with that?
Scott: Yeah, well at least you know when I was taking.
Scott: you know You do each part of the convention.
Rym: when I was going thinking about registration That would come up almost or even when I was thinking pricing because pricing determines how much money you need.
Rym: Yep but the only way we got registered at that point was that we combined ours and we paid and I believe Scott still owes me like 10 bucks because of that.
Scott: maybe I think they gave me like five ones.
Scott: I don't remember.
Rym: Yeah, it was a giant pain because we had to pay together so they wouldn't need fives for change.
Rym: But then the people behind us couldn't pay and I hear the reg line took a long long time And not.
Scott: and the other part of the reg line was that we went over and there were two lots, you know we went from the outside line which was short to the inside line, which was two short lines and We didn't realize right away because the signs were hidden by people but one One line said pre reg and one line said reg and we didn't find out until a bunch after a bunch of shifting happened.
Rym: Yeah, because the signs were on the bottom of the table where people would always be standing in front of them.
Rym: So I only noticed it because someone moved and I saw the word pre for a second Yep, and then I finally, you know realized they sold.
Scott: they told us.
Scott: Yeah, you can use either line.
Scott: I'm like then why do you have that sign there?
Scott: Yeah, why why take it down?
Rym: Yeah, it just the.
Rym: now the registration was just a big blob and there was still.
Rym: everyone was grumbling because the line was taking forever Because they didn't have change for five.
Scott: It was a very small registration line That was still moving much much too slow.
Scott: You know that they need to streamline that shit now.
Rym: then I moved to get my badge.
Rym: The badge was typical and nice.
Rym: It was you know, a good combat.
Scott: Yeah, they took a piece of paper They laminated in one of those hot laminating machines.
Scott: They poked some holes in it.
Rym: There you go Yep, but then we got our goodie bags and um Best Buy was one of the sponsors.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: Yeah, this con had a bunch of official sponsors.
Scott: Who were they?
Rym: Best Buy and Funimation.
Scott: They're all Icons on the badge of all the official sponsors.
Rym: Yeah, but the bag, you know, every con has Sarge's comics, which is a comic book store.
Rym: I go to Otakon to give you the bag full of goodies.
Rym: go to Kotsukon to give you a bag for the goodies.
Rym: This bag was not a bag full of goodies.
Rym: It was a yellow plastic Best Buy bag as in the bag they give you when you buy batteries at a Best Buy.
Scott: Yeah, or the alternative was the clear Best Buy bag, which I guess would have been useful in the dealer's room.
Rym: Yep, but in the bag there was nothing but the con book.
Scott: There was the con book.
Scott: There's a piece of paper with changes to the con schedule and such.
Scott: there was a piece of paper that was an advertisement and I think there was one more piece of paper for something else that no one cared about.
Rym: that was it.
Rym: There was nothing in the in the bag, which I don't really care.
Scott: But yeah, it's like usually the bag is full of advertisements and I go yeah, whatever.
Scott: But the point is is like hey You had all these official sponsors and they didn't fill the bag up with stuff and there's no.
Scott: The thing that I really wanted was a mini con book the one that just you know You just have a little pocket schedule, but they didn't have that I had to look.
Scott: use the giant con You know official program to get the schedule which we'll talk about in a moment which we will yes.
Rym: but the other thing was that The bags were.
Rym: they felt so cheap and ever.
Rym: almost everyone just took the bag Took the con book out threw the bag away because it was a cheap nasty bag.
Rym: Unless Best Buy forced them to they really shouldn't have bothered.
Rym: Yeah, that just wasn't worth it.
Scott: I mean, it's like you got someone to sponsor the bag But you didn't get anyone to put anything in the bag to make it worth carrying a bag.
Rym: Also, the bag is a flimsy plastic Best Buy bag.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: All right, but whatever that doesn't detract from the con.
Rym: Now then we open up the book.
Rym: now the book the convention book had been talked up to us at anime next by ConnectiCon staffers Because the whole book is full color and apparently it didn't cost him very much to make the whole book.
Scott: Yeah, the guy was like, oh for only a few hundred dollars more.
Scott: We got a full color con book.
Scott: So we did it.
Scott: We're awesome.
Rym: Now the one thing I wonder and this is pure speculation because I don't know about Kinetic ons fiscal practices, but I wonder if the it's only a few hundred dollars.
Rym: Let's do it.
Rym: policy Applied to multiple things and maybe that's the reason why this convention is so expensive.
Rym: Maybe maybe but the book itself is full color and it's printed very well, but it was put together pretty Poorly yes.
Rym: No, I don't mean any offense to whoever designed it but go to any other con and look at their con book.
Scott: There's a reason.
Scott: first of all, the other con books print their books in black and white because a they are bigger.
Scott: B they have more information and more content.
Scott: and see they have a lot more ads.
Scott: Basically the page count of this is low and That low it's okay.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: it's not that low.
Rym: all the information is in here.
Rym: The problem is that one the well wonder mistakes in it Like we're.
Rym: the one very specifically is our friend Yuko who is you know?
Rym: She was a pan well a panelist and an artist and everything there and she's a webcomic artist.
Rym: They had her name wrong in the book, but you know minor thing.
Rym: things like that happen.
Scott: Another thing is that there there's schedules for everything in this visit.
Scott: You know the set and they separated the schedules and the schedules are printed in a way I like they're easy to read and figure out what's going on.
Scott: The thing is is that they printed all the schedule.
Scott: that schedules take up a lot of room.
Scott: So there's like two or three pages of panels and workshops schedule.
Scott: Then there's two or three pages of board gaming schedule four pages of board gaming schedules.
Scott: So it's like you have to find out what you want to do and then look at the schedule.
Scott: It's really hard to you know, I like to see at one o'clock I could be doing this or this or this or this or this as Opposed to saying what do I don't want to do?
Scott: and then what time is it now?
Rym: It was really kind of confusing and not just to us because Several of the people who were with us at the Connor we talked to expressed various amounts of frustration with yeah It was set up the
Scott: way a con schedule has to be in specifically a pocket schedule because you know No one's get camp can keep whipping out this giant book at a con.
Scott: They need a little tiny pocket thing.
Scott: You had to be able to whip it out and say it's one o'clock.
Scott: What's happening at the con right now?
Scott: And there it is.
Scott: Yeah, that is the perfect con schedule.
Scott: This does not function Is that at all?
Scott: Second of all, it's like you can see in the schedule the names of the events.
Scott: But then to actually find a description of the event you have to go sifting through this giant book, which is not the greatest Though at least the the actual descriptions are pretty good.
Rym: I didn't read them.
Scott: Yeah, and they have a you know a big section like even describing every board game in the gaming room and having all the guests have a big paragraph and a Picture every single anime.
Rym: they show that a picture and a big paragraph and they obviously put a lot of effort into the book.
Scott: But yeah, it was just tricky to find any one of those things.
Scott: But once you found it, well there it was.
Rym: So I guess my suggestions for this are one does it really need to be color?
Rym: And is it worth the money?
Scott: and to even if it's one dollar?
Scott: if the if the color doesn't do anything for you Why do it?
Scott: just because?
Rym: well, it's a I mean a dollar.
Rym: it did really.
Rym: it's a cost-benefit analysis And yeah, they need to look at that.
Rym: But more importantly have a separate pocket schedule, even if it's just a piece of paper with small text on it.
Scott: Yeah, just I recommend a piece of cardboard that folds in half.
Scott: That's the best.
Rym: Yeah, cuz and Look at other conventions like Otakon or Katsucon does a really good job with their schedules and look at what they do And then put that in your con book instead of the format you use because it was just really not the best.
Scott: Yeah, yep.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: But anyway, we flip through that and we saw hey, there's an anime club panel.
Rym: I had right when we arrived basically a how to run an anime club, right?
Scott: You went to the bathroom.
Rym: Yeah I went to the bathroom first and also the map in the book was actually really good Except that it was wrong about where the food was.
Scott: That's correct.
Scott: It was wrong about where the food was but everything else about the book what the map was, correct and good Yes, but we saw this panel.
Rym: that was right when we were ready to go on how to run an anime club how to start an anime club, which I thought would be interesting because I Run along with my friend Scott Johnson.
Scott: that not me.
Rym: Yeah, the other Scott.
Scott: Yeah, I think I'm not on this show.
Rym: I think anime world order got a little confused.
Rym: I think they thought that me and Scott of GeekNights were a new type when in fact It was me and Scott of not GeekNights who are in new type.
Scott: That's correct But anyway, I'll be a new type soon enough.
Rym: those of us me and the other Scott run that exact pad And they'll say positive things about me because they only say positive at every large economy.
Rym: We run it at Otakon We ran it at Ohio con anime central Katsucon.
Rym: We run it everywhere.
Rym: It's like it's our thing and I was curious know.
Rym: All right, these people are doing their own.
Rym: Let's see how it goes.
Rym: and it started late.
Rym: and Then the girl doing it starts explaining that she was kind of thrown into it at the last minute.
Rym: She was a staffer and They just kind of needed to fill in the schedules.
Rym: So they made up this panel and threw her on it and she didn't really know a lot Mm-hmm.
Rym: Well, she
Scott: knew something cuz she did run an anime club, but I forget where she said she was from
Rym: true But after I think
Scott: I'll look up her panel actually in the night
Rym: but while you do that after the second questioner show, so I answered one of the questions that someone had because She was doing a pretty good job and I give her credit especially for being thrown into this in the last minute.
Rym: But she gave dangerously illegal advice as to how to run an anime club.
Rym: There was a specific point in which she suggested that you show some anime and charge some money to see it And at that point I couldn't just sit there and wash and I had to stand up and say that that's super illegal.
Rym: You can get into super trouble.
Rym: You can't do it.
Rym: And then I explained who I was and then Basically, the rest of the panel was people asking me questions as opposed to asking her and it was a pretty good panel.
Rym: I wouldn't mind coming back to run the panel at Connecticut if they need someone to do it, but the panelist was Brittany Davis.
Rym: Yep I mean really I had it to her for pulling off that panel on no notice with very little preparation or information Yeah, but we ended up answering a lot of the questions there.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know what else I can say, but it was interesting because Ohio con and Otakon four years ago were the two other cons where I went to an anime club panel and The person who was supposed to run it wasn't there or No one was really ready to run it and this was the first time.
Rym: I didn't just stand up and try to take it over Immediately.
Scott: Yeah, you know, I think it is is that imagine if you were going to give a panel on Physics and then Stephen Hawking shows up in the audience.
Scott: It's like what do you do?
Rym: I would say.
Rym: All right, Stephen This is your panel.
Rym: I'm gonna go to the bathroom.
Scott: Yeah, it's you know, that's what it was Like.
Scott: it's like she was trying to give a panel and then up me and Rym showed up in the audience.
Rym: Yeah, but actually a lot of people in the panel seemed really interested what we had to say and At the end they all requested our little business cards.
Rym: So I'm curious if we'll get a lot of questions.
Scott: Maybe some of them are listening to GeekNights right now.
Rym: Yeah also at the at the panel There was one guy who asked a question that in all my years of running club summits No one has ever asked anything even close to it and at some point I would love to interview this.
Scott: I give him the award for best question ever.
Rym: To sum it up real brief at a club at an anime club panel This guy is a trucker as in drives trucks for a living But he has a degree a master's degree in aerospace engineering from MIT And he's a big anime fan.
Rym: and he knows a bunch of other truckers who are big anime fans At least, you know adult swim fans.
Rym: Yeah He wanted to form an anime club for truckers and some way where truckers on the road could meet up at rest stops and such while they're trucking and Anime and talk about anime.
Rym: and That was the first time I didn't have any great advice for someone and I've been thinking on it long and hard Because I really want to help these guys out these guys.
Scott: Yeah, the only advice I could really give him is a use the internet a lot Yep, be maybe put signs up in truck stops if that's possible.
Scott: Yeah, he when I said that he's like if you ever been in a truck stop and I'm like, no, not really I've been in some.
Scott: I've been I've been kind of in some you know, like those little travel centers that on the highway?
Rym: Those are no no, no, no.
Rym: a truck stop has Lounges and showers.
Rym: I've showered in truck stops.
Scott: Oh Yeah, okay, and then What was the last suggestion?
Scott: a hand form?
Scott: All right, get a projector and put the you know The anime on the side of your truck.
Scott: Yep, sit outside on little lawn chairs.
Rym: Well, I just thought that was really interesting And now I am prepared to answer that question.
Scott: if anyone ever asks it again watch next time Someone's gonna come out and be like, yeah, I'm in the Antarctic expedition, how do I start an anime club?
Rym: Oh, I can handle that.
Rym: Yeah, I just couldn't handle the truckers because get the penguins to watch with you All right.
Rym: Yeah, so after that we wandered around a bit.
Rym: We met our friend cat who showed up a little later and we hung out with her.
Rym: She's an awesome person Mm-hmm, and then we went in the dealers room.
Scott: Mmm the dealers room.
Rym: It was a typical anime club deal or anime con dealers room.
Scott: There were a lot of dealers who were at anime next and I knew cuz I was like.
Scott: I saw you at anime next.
Scott: What are you doing here?
Rym: Yep, our friends Luke and Gabby who run a big anime store in Rochester, New York.
Rym: We're actually there.
Rym: Yep, which was a total surprise.
Rym: like we're walking and suddenly I hear oh my god.
Rym: And I look and I go oh my god.
Scott: Yeah, they are who we didn't know.
Rym: The other guy was coming and it was several minutes of hey.
Rym: Hey, what's up?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Oh my god We're at a con.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, we both went to the same con without knowing.
Scott: Holy crap.
Rym: also all the Big name web comics that were at the con.
Rym: This is a webcomic convention.
Rym: We're set up in the dealers room instead of in the artist colony.
Scott: Yeah the artist colony was a hallway of tables as opposed to a room of tables which kind of worked and All the big web comics guys weren't in the artist colony.
Scott: They were in the dealers room at tables.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I wasn't sure if the con gave in those tables if they bought them or whatever, but that's how it was.
Rym: Yep, not to sound elitist, but it was definitely all of the well-known major Acclaimed web comics were in the dealers room.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: The first guy I think we saw was dr.
Scott: McNinja guy.
Rym: Yeah, which we didn't have much to say to him other than your comics.
Rym: Great.
Rym: Yeah, I really like dr.
Rym: McNinja a lot.
Scott: I like dr.
Scott: McNinja a lot too, but you know, he was a normal cool guy and we're normal.
Scott: Dr.
Scott: McNinja readers What do we have to say to him?
Rym: Yep, so we went around all the webcomics.
Rym: a lot of them We'd already met or talked to at mocha.
Rym: So we didn't really need to say hey again.
Scott: Yeah, it's like oh I seen you.
Scott: Oh, I seen you and I could waste your time though We had a fun bit with Greg Dean of real-life comics, yes see Greg Dean of real-life comics I've been reading.
Scott: I'm gonna be honest real-life comics Isn't my absolute favorite webcomic?
Scott: not every single comic makes me laugh and roll all over the floor.
Rym: Yeah, I got to admit.
Scott: I liked it a lot more several years ago Yep, but it's still a good comic and I've been reading it for a long time because it's never been.
Scott: you know Some comics.
Scott: they just you know, they get bad and then you stop reading them.
Scott: real life has been good enough You know.
Scott: on average throughout the years I just keep reading it.
Rym: Yep It's got a lot of momentum a lot of history and it's a good comic.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty good and it always you know, it kind of follows the guy's life, too.
Scott: So as his life changes so does the comic and since we're slightly younger than him I think then, you know, it kind of fits our lives as well.
Rym: Anyway, Scott had this shirt.
Scott: I had this shirt when I was a freshman in college, which is about when I started reading real life.
Scott: So that was in 2000. good God, maybe 2001 Maybe.
Scott: I bought a shirt from real-life comics.
Scott: now.
Scott: at the time real life was much smaller.
Scott: it was like still a keen spot or he possibly not even keen spot yet and The shirt was from cafe press and it has characters on it that aren't in the comic anymore doing things that the comic is no Longer about now.
Rym: It's a really good shirt though.
Rym: Now it is Baited stained somewhat smelly and generally wrinkled.
Scott: Yeah, it's a. it's a kind of shirt you wear to bed.
Scott: It's not a kind of shirt you wear around.
Scott: Of course I did wear it around at many Conventions and it gets a lot of compliments.
Scott: like that shirt and my new Boas's shirt tend to get mad compliments.
Rym: Yeah, hint hint.
Rym: remake the shirt hint hint.
Rym: Yeah, make it like a vintage tee or something something like that.
Scott: You know higher quality.
Scott: I'll buy it cuz now you sign this one.
Scott: So I'm not really gonna get my sweat all over it.
Scott: Yeah Anyway, the point is is I went up to the guy.
Scott: the first thing I said to him which is kind of asshole Kinda was you know how long I've been reading your comic?
Scott: and he was like what?
Scott: two days.
Scott: And I was like and I'm like no you gotta check this out.
Scott: and I went and I took out the shirt.
Scott: He was like god damn Holy shit.
Scott: I was like when was the last time you saw one of these?
Scott: and he's like, well, I got one in my closet.
Scott: I'm like, I know you got one in your closet.
Rym: He was just I mean of all the webcomic artists we talked to at conventions other than the ones we know really really well.
Rym: He was probably one of the most personable and just hey, what up?
Scott: Yeah, he was very normal sociable, you know And it was kind of it was cool to meet him at you know, such a con like ConnectiCon because he's from freakin California.
Scott: so he came all the way across the country for this.
Scott: So I figure hey, you know and then we actually had a lot to relate to him with you know talking about podcasting.
Scott: He does a lot of podcasting internet radio stuff, you know, he's into that.
Rym: So, you know we talked about that for a few minutes and then we parted ways Yep, and we didn't actually go back into the dealers room because I did want to go back and talk to some other people there But whatever.
Scott: Yeah, we pretty much did all the dealing that was necessary at the.
Scott: buy one manga get two free table.
Rym: Yeah, buy one get two free.
Rym: I brought a pile of slayers manga.
Scott: Oh, did I buy manga?
Scott: Holy crap We went to anime.
Scott: next it was $5 DVDs.
Scott: We went to ConnectiCon.
Scott: buy one manga get two free.
Scott: because but actually the thing was is it wasn't all.
Scott: Buy one get two free.
Scott: that would have been.
Scott: Scott goes home poor.
Rym: Yeah, no, that would have.
Rym: I would have been like, you know Scott That would have been.
Rym: Scott drives home in his car Rym drives home in the u-haul.
Rym: We rented exactly.
Scott: I would have been like, you know, I already have all of Eagle, but you know what as well buy it again.
Rym: So I have a lender copy and a keeping copy.
Scott: Hey, you know what that LuPone manga They got like in the GTO.
Scott: They've got like 30 volumes of that stuff.
Scott: How much money will I save if I buy it all it only cost me to see 10 times a hundred bucks for 30 volumes Huh?
Scott: Anyway, now it was only on CPM manga because CPM is laid laid off all their staff If you recall a news from a few weeks ago, so yeah, they're kind of going out of business.
Scott: So their manga was on the super discount as well as some other manga.
Rym: No, it was a lot of bad manga a lot of great manga a lot of manga that's bad But I like anyway like geo breeders, which is just terrible, but I love it.
Scott: Yeah, I forgot exactly which manga I bought.
Scott: Oh, I bought some manhwa which is hard-boiled angel because I got volume one of that for cheap.
Scott: I figured why not get two and three?
Scott: I got next world, which is a Which was an overpriced?
Scott: Tezuka manga from Dark Horse, but at buy one get two free.
Scott: It was no longer overpriced and I got like fist of the blue sky.
Scott: I think it was by the same publisher who published first.
Scott: president of Japan in the US and it looks to be sort of a fist of the North Star but Also Yakuza type of thing more of the Yakuza.
Rym: I like Yakuza.
Scott: I like Yakuza a lot So I picked it up.
Rym: So then we went out from there hung around with cat for a bit and then we went over to the gaming room Which if you want to hear about the gaming experiences at ConnectiCon beyond the fact that they were awesome and well done And I give mad props check out yesterday's episode.
Scott: Yes This is the point at which I played Puerto Rico and Rym went to his uber comic panel.
Rym: Yep Now ConnectiCon has a thing that me and cat went to this because Scott was playing Puerto Rico and yuko was still busy.
Rym: But they their stick like the thing.
Rym: the special thing they do is that all the webcomic artists are there like anyone who does a Webcomic can become a guest at ConnectiCon and they do a huge uber web comics panel where Every web comic artist they have there gets on stage at once and I had heard very mixed reviews of this concept But most of them have been very positive.
Rym: So I decided alright in the interest of journalism I will sit there and cover this now.
Rym: the first thing which I talked about yesterday But I'll mention briefly is that there were an infinite number of Nintendo DS is there and there was an entire Metaconversation Simulcast of the entire panel going on in Picto chat.
Rym: It was insane.
Rym: Beyond that the panel I was really really underwhelmed with which I Don't want to say this but it really was kind of boring and luckily I have a lot of constructive criticism on how to fix this now.
Rym: It was a lot of webcomic artists I think.
Rym: after I talked about it I'll say who was all up there because I think I'd like to go through the list of all the webcomics that were at the Con and talk about them a bit.
Rym: But they had a whole bunch of people up there half of whom were Really really funny and personable and had a funny joke or a story for just about any question Anyone asked.
Rym: half of them are real quiet Whatever.
Rym: some of them said things that made the crowd get a little antsy or they'd no one really booed.
Rym: But they there were definitely some grumbles.
Scott: after a few things some comic artists said Oh, could you give an example of a grumbling comment?
Rym: Oh why?
Rym: I have a perfect example that I'll talk about later.
Rym: Awesome when it becomes relevant because that was one of the few Embarrassing things that has ever happened to me in my life.
Rym: I mean wow I can't.
Scott: I can't really possibly be embarrassed like even if that happened to me.
Rym: I would have been like oh no I wasn't embarrassed, but it was an embarrassing moment.
Rym: Uh-huh like it was a thing that could cause embarrassment.
Scott: It was someone else would have been embarrassed.
Rym: It was also.
Rym: it is rare where I will anger someone unintentionally like if I want someone to be angry I make them angry.
Rym: if I'm in a political argument, and I want to pull an and culture I'll make someone angry, but I made someone angry unintentionally.
Scott: You don't make them angry No, I that they get angry.
Rym: fine fine fine.
Rym: I create a situation where in another person of reasonable intelligence will likely become perturbed.
Scott: there you go anyway.
Scott: That's the one.
Rym: now.
Rym: the way they ran the panel was everyone sat up there And they had a couple mics and they had a guy who was kind of an emcee But he really just kind of stayed away And they take a question from the crowd or from a pre-defined list of questions And they'd ask it to the web comics panel And then they would pass the mic around and every single person would answer it sometimes at length.
Rym: Then they would ask another.
Scott: some of the people just go like yep, what he said?
Rym: yep But he said no in fact almost everyone answered everything with a funny quip like well I forget all the questions, but there was something like what motivates you or whatever and one guy's like cocaine.
Rym: I Can't really get all the humor that was at this thing out But it was.
Rym: there were many hilarious moments and many of these people would do very well to run their own panels on unrelated topics and just be funny at a con or Say be on a podcast and tent
Scott: yeah
Rym: but the fact remains that despite the funniness there was a lot of man and a lot of just shuffling time as the mic got passed around and When they took questions from the audience.
Rym: there were a lot of questions I would have wanted to ask but I couldn't because you couldn't really ask a question to an individual person or if you asked any Difficult question that would kill the panel because now every one of them is going to answer.
Rym: it is going to take forever And it was just kind of unmoderated and chaotic and what they should have done.
Rym: This is my Professional opinion.
Rym: they should have had a master of ceremonies and in addition to that a couple of guys who were question takers.
Rym: Now the master of ceremonies should have stood up front and moderated and the way I would have done it now Were other ways people could disagree.
Rym: This is just the way I would have run the panel if I were in charge of it And I were staff at Connecticut.
Rym: I would have had all the webcomic artists up because I'd like.
Rym: the idea of the uber panel of everyone is on this panel.
Rym: It's the giant thing.
Rym: they made a big deal about it.
Scott: Yeah, that's what attracts people to the panel.
Scott: That's what brings it to main events instead of just a normal panel room.
Scott: So you can't really give that up or else the point is lost.
Rym: Now one the MC had that we should have memorized who everyone was and either introduce them all.
Scott: MC didn't knew who everyone was.
Rym: the MC didn't bother with that.
Rym: They just kind of move the mics around on their own.
Rym: I'm just saying what I would do.
Rym: I'm really not covering exactly what they did because it was kind of met and Because actually when they started introducing themselves, they said their name.
Rym: They didn't say what comic they did.
Rym: Yeah, which didn't work because while I know the names of all the comics I know I don't know what your comic is if I don't read your comic.
Scott: Yeah, so everyone really should have said their name what comic they do now what comics they've done.
Rym: They self-corrected on that after about four people.
Rym: but I would have then had an MC and taken questions in the audience and I would have had a Laundry list of backup questions in case the audience didn't have anything to ask and always ask the most interesting question on the list.
Rym: Now what I would have done then is I would have taken a question from the audience and then I would have given it To one two or three of the people on the panel and I would have chosen semi randomly and uniformly except for cases when either a an artist signaled that they have a really good story to answer this question or Someone had already answered it a million times and I wasn't gonna have them say the same thing or you know things like that.
Rym: But like say someone asked Where do you get your inspiration for webcomics?
Rym: I would have said all right, Brian Clevenger What do you have to say about this?
Rym: blah blah blah blah blah blah.
Rym: All right, and I'm trying to think of someone who I am NOT of someone.
Rym: I don't know Chris Malone How about you handle this question?
Scott: or just look at the con guy.
Rym: there's a billion webcomic artists in there Yeah, but I would have taken each question and handed it to a handful of artists.
Rym: that way you could get more questions out.
Rym: I also would have accepted specific questions to specific artists as long as they were interesting or If they could have had relevance to where.
Rym: then I could pick another person to answer the question further Even if they weren't related to it.
Scott: Mm-hmm, and I'm sure that whatever answer one artist would give that The the there would be many tangents spewing from their answer that other artists would love to jump on.
Rym: Yeah And you let them go with that and you make sure there's a lot of humor in there.
Scott: as long as it stays interesting It's as soon as it's not interesting and people stop laughing and stop enjoying themselves.
Scott: Then you got to push it.
Rym: Yeah The basic point is that I would get someone who's very skilled at being an emcee or a moderator and have them moderate it In whatever way they see fit.
Rym: I kind of gave a brief overview of how I would have because that's what I do when I run panels like that But as they just should have had someone who was experienced at that to run it and I think it would have been a lot Smoother it was a lot more entertaining and overall would have been a lot better.
Scott: Yeah, I mean the panel only has so many minutes to it, you know total.
Rym: so just so much of the time was wasted passing the mic around everyone and A lot of people gave really like a lot of you'll get funny answers.
Rym: But a lot of questions like all the funny answers were taken and people would either try to give another funny answer which would fall over flat or Give a boring serious answer that no one cared about or talk at length about a semi unrelated topic and then they and then when they would stop talking there'd be silence for a while and then someone would say Yeah, and then the panel would get back on track.
Scott: So as soon as I finished playing the game of Puerto Rico I walked in the hallway pulled out my cell phone and attempted to call Rym.
Scott: and Who is standing right in front of me?
Rym: me about to call Scott?
Scott: Look at that.
Rym: now at this point we I forget exactly what we did.
Scott: I think we were starving.
Rym: Yeah, we went to get food.
Rym: We finally ran into yuko who we'd been trying to see for the whole combo.
Scott: She was always rented.
Scott: Oh, he did right?
Scott: Yeah, that's right.
Rym: Yeah, she was trying to.
Rym: she was helping Brian with something.
Rym: So we didn't get to see her yet.
Rym: So we ran by her artist colony table.
Rym: We then immediately ran away to get food.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: That was an adventure.
Rym: We went out.
Rym: We couldn't find the car.
Scott: Well, no first I went and asked a guy in the parking lot, you know Can I leave and come back with this parking ticket?
Scott: He said yes.
Rym: So we got in the car.
Scott: we after we found the car now It's like.
Scott: I remembered that I parked in d2 r2 d2.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: We didn't go to r2 or c3 or anything.
Scott: But yeah He went to d2.
Scott: and the thing is he couldn't find d2 because the signs in the parking lot lied Like actually they were wrong.
Rym: There was a sign that said D this way and another sign that said D this other way and one of those signs was not Correct
Scott: and we ended up at the complete opposite end of the parking lot from D And then we ended up at the correct D and we found the car.
Rym: But that has nothing to do with Connecticut and I can't blame the con for that.
Rym: That is just the convention center Yep.
Rym: Now luckily our friend cat he died Is somewhat of a native so she was able to direct us to food which meant we had to get on the freeway.
Scott: Yes near the convention center There is very little to eat so a lot of people ended up eating the convention center overpriced food.
Rym: Now Otakon has finally solved this problem.
Scott: They well, we think they're going to solve this problem.
Rym: Well thing I trust what Jim Vowell said and I trust everything I've read that supposedly at Otakon this year the food at the convention is going to be good affordable and Asian Mm-hmm.
Scott: now Why would anyone eat it when you can walk across the skywalk to the mall?
Rym: Why what if it's the same price or only a tiny bit more expensive, but you don't have to go anywhere?
Scott: That would that might do it.
Scott: that would have to be as good because there's good food over there.
Rym: Yeah, so we'll see.
Rym: but the thing is this con either didn't have enough clout with the convention center to demand something like that or They just didn't even think about it.
Scott: You weren't allowed to bring in outside food.
Rym: Yeah now it theoretically at Otakon and all these other cons You're also not allowed to bring outside food in but they had prominent signs all over the place You cannot bring food in and security guards preventing you from bringing in food.
Scott: Otakon You quote can't bring in food.
Scott: people bring in freaking.
Rym: now keep in mind.
Rym: This wasn't Connecticut security.
Rym: This was convention center security.
Scott: Yeah, nothing to do with Connecticut just convention center.
Scott: Yeah, but the thing is never anal because it's a brand new convention center and they're trying to make their money back on it.
Rym: Yeah, it was six dollars for a burger not even a cheeseburger.
Rym: just a burger was four dollars for a hot dog a Shitty hot dog.
Rym: and the fact is many of the people of the con didn't have cars or couldn't drive or whatever And they were really forced to eat that food.
Rym: and I felt bad for him because I know they don't have a lot of money.
Scott: Yeah, I mean especially after you pay so much money to get to the con, you know the registration.
Scott: So
Rym: yeah but then we ate our food and we came back and then we hung out with you go at our artist alley table for a While and chilled and talked about web comics and fun and we looked around in the artist colony Which sad to say was really kind of lackluster.
Rym: I expected a lot more from a web comics con.
Scott: Yeah I mean there was the same girl I always see who has the cute buttons and there was a guy making some statues and who's really good at making statues.
Scott: But to be honest his painting of the statues was while not crappy and much better than I could ever do It wasn't as good as some of the work.
Scott: I've seen from some of the people I know Yeah, it was just.
Rym: it really was a far cry from like katsu con or Otakon's artist colony or artists.
Scott: It was basically just one hallway of tables with the manga library at the end of it and in the manga library wasn't anything special It's just a manga library.
Rym: Yeah, I just expected such a bigger artist alley and I'm surprised it was so small.
Scott: and also you figure for a web comics panel that like all these aspiring web comicists would be in there but Not so many really.
Rym: Well, I think what really hurt it too was that for whatever design or reason it was all the big name like well-known I don't want to say good but just well-known popular comics were in the dealers room and It seems like all the unknown or second tier or smaller comics for the most part were in the artist colony.
Rym: So all the people who wanted to talk to webcomic people were hanging out in the dealers room all day.
Scott: It's funny how at Otakon the tables for an artist's alley are arranged much more like a colony.
Scott: yet It's called artists alley and here where they're arranged literally almost in an alley It caught the artist colony.
Rym: katsu con was both.
Rym: it had the hallway leading to the artist Alley was full of tables along the wall and then there was a room full of normal shape tables.
Rym: Wow Yeah, Katsu kana is a big artist alley.
Scott: I like big artists alleys.
Scott: That's becoming the best part of the con.
Scott: You know that most of the cons I go to because it's the part that has the interesting new stuff and the right.
Scott: the dealers Rooms are just.
Scott: I've seen all these half these dealers before or I've played all these games before.
Scott: I've heard all these panels before.
Rym: now I'd like to go through because they have all the web comics here and I don't want to sound elitist.
Rym: I'm not making fun of anyone.
Rym: I just want to go through and you know note the comics that I know and the comics that I'd never heard of.
Scott: All right.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Now 8-bit theater was there.
Rym: Awesome.
Scott: I read that one.
Scott: I read that daily.
Scott: Yeah, even when it doesn't update all roses have thorns.
Scott: never heard of it.
Rym: Am I immortal?
Rym: and then you die.
Scott: never heard of it.
Rym: Apple Geeks I heard of it, but don't read it, but I've heard of it.
Rym: I know it's really popular.
Rym: They were in the dealers room.
Rym: now I'll also note at any point if there's an exception where there's a well-known or well really popular comic that Wasn't in the dealers room and that was in the artist County.
Scott: banana chips never heard of it.
Rym: blue and blonde Never heard of it.
Rym: Chugworth.
Scott: I think I've heard it.
Rym: I've read it.
Rym: It's alright the arts really good.
Rym: I really don't like the comic so much but it's not bad.
Rym: It's just.
Rym: it's not my bag.
Scott: Yep Clone manga never heard of it.
Rym: Commenity.
Rym: Commedity.
Rym: No Dead end strippers and box and socket.
Rym: Nope Devil's panties.
Scott: I've heard of that kinda but I've never actually read it.
Scott: I don't think.
Scott: Dominic Deegan I've heard of him, but I don't read it.
Rym: I've read it.
Rym: It's also not my bag so much but the guy who does it is awesome Like the guy who does it in my personal opinion is so much more awesome than his comic is.
Rym: But that's not to say his comics bad just once again.
Rym: It's not something I read.
Rym: Mm-hmm fallen.
Scott: Hey, I know the person who makes that.
Rym: Yeah, you go.
Scott: I don't read it.
Rym: I read it.
Scott: other people read it.
Rym: Yeah, it's it's.
Rym: it's very popular especially considering it hasn't updated so often lately because she's been busy with.
Rym: you know school.
Scott: Mm-hmm flipside.
Scott: never heard of it.
Rym: Duh turning pages on GU comic.
Rym: Okey-dokey panic.
Scott: Never heard of it.
Scott: I'm just saying never heard of it.
Rym: instant classic.
Scott: Hey, I know the guy who does that - it's Brian Yeah, but I don't read that either.
Rym: Yeah, but we hung out with him at the con.
Rym: We're probably gonna get him on the show a bunch of times because we have a lot of interesting arguments with him.
Scott: He won our theme contest.
Rym: Yes for anyone who doesn't know get working whip whip.
Rym: Yeah, mule classic brai or classic Brie as I like to joke Does instant classic.
Rym: and he's also the guy who designed that awesome?
Rym: Banner that we're going to put on the top of our website at some point.
Rym: get working All right turning pages again.
Scott: kitsune Kiki never heard of it.
Rym: Mac Hall.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, I heard a Mac Hall, but I don't read that either.
Rym: Yep mines bigger.
Scott: never heard of.
Rym: monster guy ever heard of mystic revolution?
Rym: No fourth wall break paradox lost.
Rym: No, press start comic.
Rym: No punks and nerds.
Rym: No questionable content.
Scott: I've heard of that.
Scott: don't read it.
Scott: It's awesome.
Rym: I read it regularly.
Scott: All right real-life comics.
Scott: Hey, I met that guy and he signed my shirt that I had.
Scott: that was real old that we just talked about it.
Rym: Yep, my favorite bit.
Rym: No, I have too many favorite bits.
Rym: I'd have to do all show on that.
Rym: Mm-hmm Robin Elliott.
Scott: I don't know them, but I remember seeing them in the artists alley runners never heard of it.
Rym: I gotta say Shawn Wang the guy who does this comic.
Rym: he was sitting on the end.
Rym: He was like the first guy introduced in the web comics panel and he seemed really quiet like he didn't say much.
Rym: But then when he finally said something he was really funny and awesome.
Rym: So I just want to say he was kind of like that white dressed Yakuza guy in that Simpsons episode.
Scott: Oh, I love that white Yakuza guy.
Scott: That's one of my favorite bits Staccato.
Scott: All right I never read this and I never heard of it.
Scott: but I was informed that the funny shirts the ones with the katamari balls that say this is how I roll and The one that I have which is a picture of a Nintendo cartridge that says blow me These guys make those shirts.
Rym: apparently, yes, you should probably check out the comic.
Rym: Mm-hmm stuff sucks.
Rym: Nope Vg cats everyone reads.
Scott: I don't actually read it, but I read it when someone sends me a link.
Scott: Yeah, and wasteland never heard of it.
Rym: Now the one cool thing and it's both a pro and a kind of web of kinetic.
Rym: on That they put everyone and anyone who's a webcomic artist is a guest.
Rym: Anyone who is a webcomic artist is on the uber comic panel.
Scott: You could draw a stick figure webcomic and get on the webcomic panel and it's awesome.
Rym: because I love this idea of Inclusion and that I mean it's a chance for people who maybe have a not so well-known comic to get themselves Well-known because if they're good, they'll explode.
Rym: I mean, that's just the way webcomics work Mm-hmm.
Rym: It just surprised me that I mean I am really into webcomics.
Scott: I'm constantly looking for new ones to read and I'm not constantly looking but I read them ones that I read every day and I just I like it when new Amazing ones fall into my lap.
Scott: The problem is I'm kind of reading like the cream of the crop with like penny arcade and Boasis and such.
Scott: So it's really hard for new ones to make it through Especially because they have to compete with stuff that I don't read anymore like bad boys a computer side.
Rym: Yeah I guess it's just that I'd never heard of more than half of these comics Despite the fact that I'm a massive massive fan of webcomics.
Rym: And I wonder if it's due to the fact that the comics that made it big early are just these juggernaut behemoths that everyone reads and maybe there's just no room or I don't know.
Scott: I'd like to I got to think about maybe the way, you know People just don't look for new webcomics.
Rym: or maybe it's hard to find a new webcomic unless you go to those sites where they're all linked together like You damn kid as a bunch of other comics on the side or a dumbbrella or things like that.
Scott: It's just really hard to make an.
Scott: you know, if the thing is a lot of the good webcomic artists are Already making webcomics and they're not making new ones.
Scott: They're making more of the same comic.
Scott: I mean penny arcade.
Scott: they just they're just keep making penny arcade for years and years and years and there aren't that many New webcomic artists, you know because it was.
Scott: it broke out where there was, you know, all of a sudden there's a new thing.
Scott: So every webcomic artist in the world, they didn't know they were webcomic artists yet they all broke out simultaneously, so there were hundreds and hundreds of webcomics, but you know The rate at which new webcomic artists are generated is years and years and years For actually good ones to come through the line.
Rym: But anyway, I hate to push us along but we've gone a long time talking about this con and we still got a lot to say.
Scott: Okay, so let's move on.
Rym: Yeah, we might have to cover the rest of it tomorrow.
Scott: No, no, we'll finish it All right.
Rym: Anyway, um after that we're gonna skip the next four hours of the con because he played Age of Steam.
Rym: We played Age of Steam in that four hours.
Rym: if you want to hear about that listen to yesterday's show.
Scott: And then we went back to the artists alley to hang out some more.
Rym: Yep now we were at this point.
Rym: we were going to leave the con.
Rym: our friend Kat had already left because she found a ride home and Our friend Yuko and Brian.
Rym: they were out getting dinner or something.
Rym: So I called them.
Rym: They're like, hey reading really?
Rym: I was like, hey, we're gonna leave soon and oh we miss you all.
Rym: We'll see you soon.
Rym: Then I go and meet Scott cuz.
Rym: he was still Cleaning up the Age of Steam game while I was going to see what was going on with our friends And then we decided that we might as well stick around until they get back and hang out and then leave because we're in no Rush.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And I gotta say After those two got back and we hung out in the artist colony for the rest of the night We had some good times.
Rym: That was probably the highlight of the con.
Scott: probably Yeah, just the part I remember the most besides playing Age of Steam.
Scott: just me Scott Brian and Yuko hanging out talking about everything Talking about like we met lots of people walking by and the thing was is when people came by I struck try to strike up Conversations with them, you know about because you're promoting their comic and our podcast.
Rym: Yeah, because actually Yuko had a table and In the artist colony, but she didn't really bring much to do with it.
Rym: So she offered it to us to use.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So we were promoting our podcast in their comic and I asked people do you listen to podcasts and are you going to Otakon now?
Scott: This and I expected people to say what's a podcast?
Scott: Hell's yes I'm going to Otakon.
Scott: the thing is is that pretty much everyone said yeah I listen to a few podcasts.
Scott: or oh, yeah I listen to a lot of podcasts or yeah something, you know They definitely were into podcasting and no I can't go to Otakon.
Scott: or what's Otakon?
Scott: or where is Otakon?
Rym: More people didn't know what Otakon was or where it was or anything about it then knew about it.
Scott: But they all knew Podcasting and I said, yeah If you want to listen to us two schmucks talk you can go to that website.
Scott: and now the guy was like I love listen to geeks talk.
Rym: I have a theory and I'm gonna talk about this in depth someday.
Rym: Maybe someone should remind me hypothesis when I forget.
Rym: Yes Well theory in the colloquial sense hypothesis in the scientific sense exactly.
Rym: But it seems to me based on all of my anecdotal evidence and all my many years are going to cons that there are Circles of people like in burning wheel who go to certain sets of cons.
Rym: because for the longest time I went to Otakon Anime Central Otakon anime central and a lot of the same people went to both.
Rym: So I met people at anime central and then I'd hang out with him at Otakon and then I hang out with him again At the next anime central.
Rym: then I discovered that Katsucon is in the same circle.
Rym: when I went to Katsucon almost everyone I talked to goes to Otakon.
Scott: a lot of people were well because that's in closed geographical proximity to Otakon.
Rym: So true true, but and uber khan?
Rym: a lot of people who go to Otakon and all these cons go to uber khan But almost no one who goes to like ConnectiCon and anime next and all these other circle of cons goes to Otakon or Katsucon.
Rym: and I'm really not sure exactly if it's distance or time and I've got to sit down and think about it and look at maps and See if I can come up with any rationale for this.
Rym: But it's like the people who go to all the small cons don't go to the big cons.
Scott: I think that it's really just a geographic thing.
Scott: Like you could put blobs on the map as to where the fan Populations live my own and then you can see aha this percentage of that one goes to these cons.
Rym: and you know My only argument against that is that anime central is definitely in the Otakon Katsucon circle.
Rym: Yeah, and that is fuck far away.
Scott: Well, at least the people that you talk to I mean there are thousands of people at these things.
Scott: There's no way that you can actually figure that out.
Scott: Hence.
Rym: It was the the Weak-weak hypothesis based on anecdotal evidence and I'm gonna I think I'll do a search for the truth to try to figure this out.
Scott: Maybe all right.
Scott: Anyway, some other funny things happened while we were sitting there hanging out.
Scott: Yep We met some annoying fanboys came up and they bothered us and we got them to go away.
Rym: Yep, we discovered the best way to promote GeekNights.
Rym: We were sitting there and we were talking to rusty holler who is.
Rym: he was a guest at the con and he did all sorts Of cool things.
Rym: I'm not gonna try to read this.
Scott: Yeah, he was a comic artist and he makes some comic called ace and Queenie Which I looked at it and you know, the art was pretty good music good artist, you know But it's sort of an anthropomorphic thing published in furlough.
Scott: So make of that what you will.
Rym: But the thing is he totally surprised us with his awesome knowledge of anime and we had a really good discussion of all the old School awesome anime.
Scott: Yeah at first it's like oh, it's a comic artist who draws something furry.
Scott: Oh, wait a minute.
Scott: He wants to talk about all sorts of awesome Tezuka stuff that I don't know.
Scott: Yes Yes, me and your wise ways of the Tezuka things that I do not have yet.
Rym: Yep now the cool thing is we were talking to him and we're you know loud boisterous people and he was pretty loud to people walking by would stop and start listening to us and Then once they started listening to us we could impress upon them that hey we do a show.
Rym: You can listen to this all the time and that got more people interested in GeekNights than anything we've ever done at a con.
Scott: I was so entertained just standing here listening to you.
Scott: two guys talk and now I can do it four days a week.
Rym: Yeah, one person even said something along those lines.
Rym: Like I would listen to this.
Rym: Yep, and I was like, well now you can.
Rym: Here's a website.
Scott: Yeah, and they were like, oh You know people like, you know, usually you give us, you know it's like when someone gives me a piece of paper and says go check this out, I'm like, yeah and obviously, I know that they're.
Scott: they know that I'm probably not gonna and You know I think that's why I don't hand things out because I always figure people are gonna be like yeah and not actually go see it And it's a waste of time, but it seemed like everyone who I gave a flyer or whatever was genuinely interested.
Rym: like most of the flyers we gave away were because people asked us specifically how they could listen or How they could get in touch with us or if we had a business card or a flyer Mm-hmm, or they'd ask like can I have one of those?
Scott: Yeah, it's like they thought it wasn't free.
Rym: Also, we got some compliments on it because also Yuko who we were hanging out with she did the art for it.
Rym: I finally uploaded it to the server.
Rym: So anyone who wants to promote GeekNights in any con you go to you can just print out that flyer Make some copies cut it up.
Rym: Give it out.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: You don't have to we don't care.
Scott: But yeah now another funny thing Happened while we were there.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Now I was talking about the uber web comics panel while we were in the artist alley Yep, the artist colony and at one point one of the artists said something about furrydom.
Rym: now The question was what is what?
Rym: what is there?
Rym: anything you want?
Scott: point at the uber comic panel?
Scott: Someone said something about furry.
Rym: Yeah well first there was a question of you were coming panel.
Rym: that led to this where they asked like what do you hate or like What do you hate about doing a comic?
Rym: or wait?
Rym: Well, like have you ever gotten hate mail something like that?
Rym: Mm-hmm, and there were funny stories.
Rym: and then this one webcomic artist says and I didn't recognize her comic or anything And she said I'm not even sure which comic it is.
Scott: now that I'm looking through the con guide I'm trying to figure out which one and I can't.
Rym: she said something about.
Rym: I hate it when people see a comic that is anthropomorphic art and associate it with furry culture and went on this whole rant about like yif piles or fur piles and all that stuff and the crowd was like grumble grumble grumble grumble grumble and there was.
Rym: there were a lot of disparaging comments made in the picto chat and after she stopped there was a silence for a while like it really killed the momentum and One I guess The story I was gonna tell.
Rym: and I was telling this to everyone who didn't go to the uber con uber comic God.
Rym: the uber comic web comic the uber webcomic panel at Connecticut not uber con.
Rym: I'm not gonna cut that out.
Rym: I'm gonna leave that in for all of you who you.
Rym: we don't edit the show much But that was a spectacular stumbling over a word.
Rym: I'm proud of it.
Scott: Okay, that was a new enterprise.
Rym: Alright, so the uber webcomics panel and I was gonna use that as an example of how a good MC Could have kept the momentum going.
Rym: but while I was telling the story Before I had gotten even halfway through it this person who is sitting at the adjacent table Drawing and not saying anything turns around and says that was me blah blah blah Blah blah.
Scott: I thought she just said fuck you.
Rym: Yeah, it was a really like.
Rym: she was pissed.
Rym: Yeah, and I think she thought that I was really gonna rag on her about furried him or something.
Scott: Well, we were kind of ragging on her.
Scott: I was like, did you tell him did you yell out and scream?
Scott: You know screw you furries.
Scott: Did he yell out and you know, yep I hope you're saying bad stuff about furries.
Rym: Yep and I'll.
Rym: I would like to do a show on this at some point because because
Scott: burries deserve bad stuff being said because
Rym: this is a it's a thing that's actually coming up more and more at conventions and it's getting to the point where Anime con people who run conventions have to deal with this that there is anthropomorphic art Which I actually am a big fan of there.
Rym: and then there is furry Culture which is a whole different arena.
Rym: That is more of a fetish culture than an art culture and people confuse the two.
Rym: and The problem is that people who are a member of the non perverted part seem to feel really persecuted And as a result tend to be very vocal and as a result tend to be very annoying.
Rym: and as a result There's a lot of hate some of it warranted and some of it unwarranted for furries out there.
Scott: Yeah, because it starts out with a hate against the furry culture.
Rym: that's perverted sex fetish Yeah, and it's not like, you know Like it's a. it's a fetish where I can see these psychological roots in many cases being not good.
Rym: Yeah, as opposed to something like BDSM where I don't really care, you know, like I don't I don't begrudge anyone their fetish.
Scott: I mean whatever floats your boat.
Scott: The problem is is you know, if the culture around your fetish is Not good.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: It has nothing to do with the fact that it's anthropomorphic.
Scott: Yeah, I mean you can still do it all you want, but I'm going to make fun of you.
Scott: Yes That is what I am going to do.
Scott: and really the beef is and I am also not going to respect you or be friends with You.
Rym: yes and I mean just the beef here is that We're not saying anything about anthropomorphic art or furry art or whatever or even about the people who get off on that.
Rym: It's about the culture of people who have a fetish and they're very vocal about having the fetish and then they wonder Why people bother them about it because if you are very vocal about having any fetish There's a lot of people are going to bother you about it.
Scott: Yeah, most people who have fetishes besides furriness like, you know, SNM people very few of them go around You know yelling about how I'm an SNM guy Except when they go to their conventions, yeah, you know, it's like they just keep it.
Scott: You know that they're normal people except for when they're doing their thing, which is when you're not around.
Scott: They don't you know, they don't care to get you involved.
Scott: there's nothing to do with you.
Scott: furries kind of like push their fetish out and They're fans of this art, which is also trying to push itself as art.
Scott: So it's sort of like they're dragging this bad baggage along with them for the ride.
Rym: It's like we've got good independent comics coming out in America now, but there's also all the underwear perfect comics.
Rym: So when someone says hey, do you read comics?
Rym: to someone new who doesn't read comics?
Rym: They think of the underwear perfect comics and they don't know about their good comics.
Rym: Yep, it's the same deal.
Rym: but and then she like she just yelled at us and then turned away and the whole area is silent and we're all like.
Scott: That was awkward And I was like we're gonna talk about that on the show and here we are.
Rym: and then we just kind of Picked back up with our conversation and then everyone else kind of picked back up and she just sat there for a while.
Scott: I was like, what's she gonna do?
Scott: She's just some furry girl.
Rym: Yeah But then I apologize afterward because I tried to explain to her that I was actually going somewhere with that And I wasn't disparaging you.
Rym: I don't even know your comic never heard of it.
Scott: Yeah, I hate that when people take something personally.
Scott: if someone doesn't know you it's not possible for them to give a personal Insult, you know, it's like if you we don't know who this girl is You still don't know her name or what comic she draws or anything?
Scott: So, how is it possible for us to personally insult her?
Scott: Obviously, we're talking about something else.
Rym: No, if she if you happen to be listening At some point I just burped.
Rym: we are going to do a show on furrydom because I did someone put that in the forum.
Rym: yes, but the thing is Since we've got this Skype set up.
Rym: That's probably going to work.
Rym: We're gonna test it tomorrow.
Rym: Probably I wouldn't mind having you and other people like that on the show When we do time if you're listening and you don't hate us even if you hate us we want hate mail.
Rym: Yeah, you've never gotten hate mail.
Rym: We're waiting for it.
Rym: If you want to call in and yell at us for 20 minutes We'll put that right on the air.
Scott: Oh, that'll go in the air so much faster than like Riven Scott are the best That you know Riven Scott are the best.
Scott: we'll just kind of stay on our hard drives and get listened to once a day.
Scott: But yeah Riven Scott our assholes who should die is gonna get put on the air You'll get an interview right away and no faking it.
Scott: We can tell Yep, yep.
Rym: Yep, because really we we want to get opposing viewpoints out because when we argue with each other We always argue over the same things and I know a lot of our listeners like the arguments.
Rym: the best way for you to hear An argument is for you to hear us arguing with someone else.
Scott: Yeah, because it's a tag team effort, you know And I don't want to say this.
Scott: but if me and Rym agree on whatever it is We're not gonna use evil editing tactics like some people on TV and radio.
Scott: But if someone comes up against us and it's us versus them The chances of them winning are not good.
Scott: now me and Rym agree.
Rym: Honestly, it really doesn't even depend on the kind of debate I mean.
Rym: there is debate where people are trying to come to a truth Wherein I think we will prove our point but perfectly or near enough for the other person has no recourse.
Rym: There is also debate where you're trying to win over a crowd, which I think we have pretty well down Considering the crowd is fans of us.
Scott: It's not hard to win you guys over.
Rym: Well also just that Scott is better at the former and I'm better at the latter.
Rym: So if we agree on something we can use all of those tools combined like a giant robot.
Scott: Yeah, it's sort of like if you want to see a very Mike Tyson fight in argument form Try to argue against both of us in something.
Rym: Yep, and some people on the forums is seen though It's more difficult on the forums because I can't check it so often.
Rym: So I'll see an argument that I think is bad and before I can respond to it ten people post and then alright I'm not gonna dig up old news, whatever
Scott: I mean, yeah, if you want to see an example look at the sports argument that we had today in the forum
Rym: Yep, or the libertarianism argument.
Scott: All right, let's finish the con.
Scott: All right, okay.
Scott: So we hung out for a few hours more hanging out talking with cool people about cool stuff And then we finally said, okay, we must go.
Rym: All right now we're leaving.
Rym: the con doesn't go 24/7.
Rym: It was gonna close down in an hour at 1 a.m.
Scott: Or so.
Scott: Yeah, and it was like 1145 ish.
Scott: now we found the car.
Rym: what is about to happen is not the fault of the con But remember when I said to remember something at the beginning of this rant.
Scott: Yep, we go we get in the car and we leave the parking lot.
Scott: now There is a guy in a booth at the exits of the parking lot and there's like six cars in front of us trying to Get out and they're not moving.
Scott: as in they're having to stop and wait.
Scott: and I'm like what is taking them so long to Pay and get the hell out of here.
Rym: and it looked like the guy was arguing with every single person in front of us.
Scott: Yeah, we're like what's going on?
Scott: And then I remembered oh I paid already and we paid as soon as we got into the parking lot for eight Dollars all day.
Scott: and I said wait a minute.
Scott: I looked at the clock and it said 1158.
Rym: I was like son of a bitch.
Rym: if they try to charge us because they made us wait in line past the deadline We're driving through that dead block and I sure as hell was gonna drive right through that stick.
Scott: They got nothing.
Scott: So I got up there and I hand the guy the ticket and what does he say?
Scott: He says not what I expect which is this expired a minute ago.
Scott: You have to pay money.
Scott: It was this expired at 8 p.m To which
Rym: Scott immediately says the lady this morning said it was all Day and the guy looked at us and I think he got the hint that we were not going to back down And he said
Scott: whatever he got here He called someone on his walkie-talkie and he had them push a button which opened the gate and we left
Rym: now
Scott: And I would not have given him a goddamn penny.
Rym: now I saw that some of the people in front of us argued and argued and didn't pay but I saw that a lot of people Did.
Rym: either the convention center was trying to rip these anime fans off by being very very Misrepresentative of the cost of parking or Someone was incompetent.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: There was it was really.
Scott: I think what it was is that you know the convention center, you know.
Scott: They basically said yeah these people you should give a deal for like all-day parking a flat fee and you know.
Scott: They thought that was a good idea.
Scott: But I don't think the people in the parking lot Management realized that the con went until one so that if you wanted to give an all-day parking you would have had to give someone Parking from the right hours.
Scott: there wasn't enough.
Scott: there obviously wasn't a significant amount of communication and coordination between the convention and the parking and such.
Rym: I was kind of disappointed because I saw that Everyone in front of us argued with this guy at length and I was waiting to argue.
Rym: I was all ready to call the police and tell them that a parking garage that we had already paid for was refusing to let Us leave and create some all sorts of a shitstorm.
Scott: Mm-hmm and the guy backed right down and yeah I was like the lady said this morning that this was for all day.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: That was Scott priming.
Rym: I could tell because his voice changes when he's about to start an argument because he'll stop and very calmly He will say the crux of the argument the point at which if he'd if anyone disagrees with this point The argument will begin and I could see it in his eyes.
Rym: He was waiting for it.
Rym: Yeah, and I was all ready to back him up.
Scott: I had my cell phone out and the guy opened the gate and we left.
Scott: so Let that be a lesson to all of you.
Scott: learn our ways and you will escape from parking lots with wallets intact.
Rym: In fact at for the red Otakon last won't even have to open your Jimmy Otakon.
Rym: parking is very expensive.
Rym: second only to Katsucon.
Scott: Oh mad expensive.
Scott: Oh, it's a great story.
Scott: We got to tell it, right?
Rym: Yes, I think we told it once before but whatever.
Rym: so we we stay Thursday morning through Sunday afternoon At Otakon.
Scott: now we park in the parking lot attached to our hotel.
Rym: Very expensive like it costs like between 40 and 60 dollars depending on various factors.
Scott: every year For four days of just moving your car your car sits in there for a long time.
Rym: Yeah, cuz it's a primo parking place.
Rym: I mean you could park cheaper far away, but we don't care.
Rym: even when we were dirt poor We would park there and then not have because it was just so convenient.
Scott: We didn't care.
Scott: Let them rip us off.
Rym: So we lost that.
Rym: Well, I lost the ticket that you have to use to prove how long you were in there and I actually lost it.
Rym: This wasn't a scam though.
Rym: Now.
Rym: I know that I can make it a scam.
Rym: Yep, and I pull up to the booth And it's Sunday and we're about to drive to Wildwood.
Rym: So we're like, whatever we'll pay whatever stupid fine They want us to pay and get the hell out of here.
Rym: Yep So roll down the window and he's like take it and I'm like I lost the ticket and he's like, when did you get here?
Rym: I was like Thursday morning and he stands there for a second doesn't say anything.
Rym: then he says 20 bucks and I said Alright, and I gave him 20 bucks and he waved me through and I'm reasonably certain that he pocketed it.
Scott: I think the strategy here is if there's ever parking lots where you get a ticket on the way in And you pay on the way out
Rym: and it's not in your hometown
Scott: and it's not in your hometown or anywhere near your home Somewhere you're not likely to park again frequently.
Scott: I mean we park in this place annually.
Scott: They're not gonna remember us for shit.
Rym: Plus we take a different car every year.
Scott: Yeah, I know different car everything.
Scott: we Go there at the exit.
Scott: throw your ticket like in like a bin somewhere, right?
Scott: But don't lose it but pretend to lose it.
Scott: hide it in your glove box cuz you want to have it as a backup.
Scott: Yeah, so go up and say I lost my ticket.
Scott: I can't find.
Scott: I can't find my ticket.
Scott: And if they say when did you get here, you know say the trick here is like if they say when did you get here?
Scott: It's are you gonna say be honest or are you gonna say this morning?
Rym: Cuz you have to be willing to go all the way with whatever you just tried.
Rym: Because if you say this morning and he says I have video of you driving in Wednesday, you're fucked.
Scott: Yeah, if he says, you know, well you need to find the ticket.
Scott: Can you look for it?
Scott: Maybe it can't be.
Scott: you know, you parked in here and you didn't go anywhere.
Scott: How far could the ticket have gone?
Scott: Yeah, so if there and then you take the ticket out and he sees that you lied.
Rym: Oh, I recommend not lying.
Scott: I also recommend not lying now.
Rym: the key you got to play up here Is that this guy is probably making minimum wage or thereabouts?
Rym: So if he lets you go and you pay like half of what you owed But he just keeps it that just tripled his hourly wage.
Rym: Uh-huh, so and he has no incentive.
Scott: He doesn't care and the guy who owns the parking lot is making megabucks.
Scott: Anyway, so you're kind of stealing but you're not doing the stealing kind of steam.
Scott: you are going to pay the honest price.
Scott: It's the guy in the little booth who's doing this.
Rym: Yeah, I gotta say that is the same logic from American gods when they pull like the violin scan.
Scott: I know isn't it great?
Scott: It is.
Scott: It's perfect.
Scott: It's flawless.
Scott: There's not a single hole.
Scott: It is cheddar not Swiss.
Rym: No, here's the legal side.
Rym: I do not actually geek dice does not recommend you attempt this.
Rym: it is against the law.
Scott: It's not actually against the law.
Rym: It depends on how you go about it exactly.
Scott: if you lie It's probably kind of in the gray area.
Rym: Don't rationalize it.
Rym: You you are stealing just whatever.
Rym: I'm just noting that by accident we ended up paying far less than we should have.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: This is a completely honest.
Scott: We weren't trying to scam.
Scott: we literally lost the ticket and we said when we got there honestly and the guy said 20 bucks.
Scott: So we gave him 20 bucks and we left.
Rym: Yep, and I even said, you know, we got here Thursday morning.
Rym: I was all set to pay everything.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Now.
Scott: I don't have anything pretty much.
Scott: They can't make you pay more than you legally owe them.
Scott: You know unless maybe there was like a discount that you're getting they could take away a discount.
Scott: So if you're already getting a legitimate discount don't go for more because then you'll end up losing what you already got.
Scott: Yep But they can't charge you more than you know what you're already supposed to be paying.
Rym: Well, no, cuz some garages have like a $100 flat rate if you lose the ticket.
Scott: Oh, that is true.
Scott: That is true.
Scott: That's when you whip out the ticket You're like, oh here it is right here.
Scott: You know, if what you do is you drive up here, let's pretend you'll be the Guy, right?
Scott: All right.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: I lost my ticket.
Rym: No ticket crash.
Scott: Oh, no No, and then he tells me there's a hundred dollar fine.
Scott: so I go oh shit, let me try to look for it some more.
Scott: I can't.
Scott: I don't have a hundred bucks.
Scott: I look for it.
Scott: Oh, I got it.
Rym: Hooray Fantastic, sir.
Rym: Yeah, I'm glad you weren't trying to defraud me in any way.
Rym: Yes your actual bill $60.
Scott: Here you go.
Scott: 60 bucks.
Scott: See you granted.
Rym: There was also the strategy of now given on.
Rym: we've never tried any of these.
Rym: We came up with all of these on the way to Wildwood after we accidentally scammed the guy.
Rym: Mm-hmm Alright he tells you to look for it rummage around and rummage around and keep rummaging around and act all nervous But don't ever find anything and there's a good chance.
Rym: the guys can say god, whatever just go.
Rym: Yeah that that happened to me once when I actually lost a ticket on the New York State Thruway.
Scott: the worst though Here's the worst.
Scott: you're ready.
Scott: the automated parking lots where there are no guys.
Scott: There's only a gate.
Rym: They got me with that at Stewart fucking Airport when I didn't fly.
Scott: Remember when we had to deal with that?
Scott: in Rochester, New Jillians Little tiny parking lot have enough quarters to open the damn gate.
Scott: We couldn't get out or in.
Rym: Yeah, that was fantastic.
Scott: We finally found a quarter under Rym seat and we're like, yeah, I said it like we Was great.
Scott: We were able to escape the parking lot of doom.
Rym: Anyway enough about parking.
Rym: ConnectiCon was alright.
Rym: It really in my eyes just wasn't worth the money.
Rym: I mean it cost almost pretty much the same as Otakon.
Rym: yet it had while it had good things going It didn't have enough to justify the cost in my eyes.
Scott: Yeah and you know since Even though if you took the con if it was run perfectly as in everything there was more staff.
Scott: You know things were run smoother, you know, they didn't have the some of the problems They had that were easily solved.
Scott: even if all those things were fixed There wasn't enough happening there to be worth one other thing.
Rym: their musical guest canceled at the last minute.
Scott: Oh, yeah, that's right.
Rym: So they didn't have bad luck performing.
Rym: Yeah, they had piano squall but I just find it funny that they they're like piano squall appears the musical guest at the anime convention Otakon where he performed for an audience of 3,000. now I just want to say it as a side.
Rym: It was only 3,000 and that was mostly because piano squall appeared like on Sunday in a non main room At Otakon, I think they might be referring to the time when piano squall they say specifically 2005.
Scott: Oh, do they really?
Scott: Yes Okay, because I think at 2004 piano squall performed at the intermission of the cosplay which would have been too much more than 3,000 probably.
Rym: I guess he's a smart guy and I respect what he does, but I'm not a big fan It's it's not that special.
Scott: Yeah, it's sort of like oh that guy makes a good something.
Scott: his works of art are good.
Scott: I do not enjoy them.
Scott: Let him be.
Rym: well, I guess I would enjoy him except it doesn't really change so much.
Rym: It's just piano squall.
Rym: Exactly now also there was a masquerade which looked It must have been good because it was standing room only even after more than half of it had elapsed Usually a lot of people walk out of a small cons masquerade about halfway through.
Scott: Yeah, I knew that the masquerade was going on because the hallways were empty.
Scott: Of course, there is another Hypothesis I have as to why it was so crowded because the con really didn't I mean an anime.
Scott: next everything was happening at night.
Scott: You know during the day there wasn't so much happening But at night the con was happening at ConnectiCon other than the gaming room.
Scott: The con really wasn't happening at all.
Scott: So that you know, the masquerade was an actual happening.
Scott: So everyone flocked to it like finally yes, something is going on.
Rym: Yeah, because honestly there just wasn't much to do for for me.
Rym: I mean I like going to panels and just not many of the panels really interested me and the fact that the only panel I well the First panel I went to was the anime comic or anime can our club panel that I talked about.
Rym: That really led me away from wanting to go to any other panels.
Scott: Yeah I mean if the con had a problem where they didn't have enough panelists and they had to push staff when they were short on Staff into doing panels and to just fill up the schedule Then obviously a lot of the panels aren't probably going to be the best ways to spend my time
Rym: Now.
Rym: there may or may not been true, but that was the impression I got.
Scott: that is the impression I got.
Rym: And also I'll note that they had a dance.
Scott: Of course that was from one panel Yeah, but that's but also from the horse's mouth of one of the staff people Yep, because she said there were numerous panels like that.
Rym: Yep and also just people like our friend cat looked at a bunch of panels and said they're all kind of man and No one like.
Rym: I didn't see anyone coming out of a panel like whoa Yep.
Scott: Yeah, the panels all seems sparsely populated.
Scott: people milling in and out and you know Closed doors like the way that the cut the build would walk right past all the panel rooms not know they were there.
Scott: Yeah, that's another thing is like an Otakon.
Scott: they you know.
Scott: If there's a panel going on and the panel is you know opening or closing the doors are open so you can you know You walk by and a panel catches your eye at this con.
Scott: They kind of had to because the way everything was, you know Laid out in the building.
Scott: you had to keep those doors closed or else it'd be trouble.
Scott: But you'd walk by and you just walk down the hallway past a bunch of closed doors.
Scott: you had no idea There was a panel in there.
Scott: It wouldn't catch your eye you wouldn't hear Someone talking in a room and then be lured in by the interesting things They were saying.
Scott: you know And I think we probably missed out on a lot of stuff going on simply because we didn't pass by and catch it.
Scott: We passed by a closed door with a silence behind it.
Rym: now in regards to saying the con was overpriced I just I wish I could look at their books or see what they spent their money on because I my best guess and this is completely out of the air out of my ass because I have to guess about Every possible thing because I have no information about how much anything cost how much money they had or anything
Scott: I know the thing we could have.
Scott: it could have been true that like the gaming room cost a billion dollars We don't know.
Rym: but it is my guess that ConnectiCon is not actually big enough to warrant being in that Convention Center.
Scott: And it is also my guess that that Convention Center being new Fancy and Union and not used a great deal is very very expensive.
Rym: I have a feeling that if ConnectiCon we're in a large hotel cluster as opposed to this Convention Center It would be cheaper and much better because this is one of those cons that lends itself to People getting together and hanging out all night long Which is very
Scott: especially with the awesome gaming room because they could keep that open all night long.
Scott: It would be relatively good, you know average slightly above average video game room, which they could have gone all night long.
Rym: It would have been a fantastic Fantastic all night con.
Scott: I know if I could have played games all night That would have been like woohoo if I would have stayed especially if it cost less money.
Rym: We probably left sometimes Sunday instead of Saturday night.
Scott: I would have paid in all a three-day if I would have known the gaming was that good before I had gone there.
Rym: Yeah, but I mean, it's just I. I wonder why they're in the Convention Center.
Rym: I mean, is there a reason they need to be there?
Scott: did they know they weren't using the whole Convention Center, you know It's like they had more room than they needed.
Scott: and really cons They you know a lot of cons skimp and that's the thing cons need to skimp.
Scott: You need to spend as little money as possible.
Scott: If you have more than you need that's a problem because you're costing all your member your members money.
Scott: You need to have be like right on the edge exactly what you need not more not less.
Rym: and I just I also wonder if the high cost has anything to do with the Budgetary problems.
Rym: ConnectiCon faced last year.
Scott: Yeah ConnectiCon you know That's the only thing I knew about.
Scott: ConnectiCon before going to it was it was a convention.
Scott: It was in Connecticut.
Scott: a lot of webcomic people went to it and last year They had problems because either a they didn't read the contract They signed with the Convention Center or be the Convention Center screwed them and they should have gotten a lawyer.
Scott: So either way they screwed up.
Rym: Yeah, we don't know the details specifically so we can't say yes.
Scott: But from the internet news that I read I remember the clue conclusion We came to based on that news was either a they were dumb and they didn't read a contract or B They were dumb and they should have gotten a lawyer.
Rym: Yeah, because there's really I can't foresee any other situation that could have led to the thing they had to face.
Scott: Yes, if someone knows more about that situation and would like to clarify and or correct us feel free.
Scott: Yes I would love to get feedback on this because that this is a great thing to talk about is is this kind of stuff?
Rym: I would love to have enough information to one to be able to give advice Because I really think that I give good advice when it comes to conventions.
Scott: Yeah, I think that you know, all this con really needs is polish, you know, it's it's a good con.
Scott: I mean they had a great gaming room.
Scott: They had.
Scott: they had some other good stuff like the bunny bucks, which he talked about yesterday Yep, and lots of good stuff going on a lot of webcomic.
Scott: And if you're getting guys from California where webcomic art is to come to your con, you know, it's good stuff.
Rym: But also bad stuff like, you know the money situation.
Scott: you just had to get the con to run smoother.
Scott: You need to make it cheaper and you know, maybe change the location, you know I think if the con went somewhere else and then outgrew that somewhere else it could move back to the Convention Center.
Scott: You know and I'll see it's really all it needs is just some polish.
Rym: Yeah I just I really wonder where the money goes because they spent the money which Supposedly wasn't so much to get the full-color con book.
Rym: but what if instead of getting the full-color con book they could have used that money to buy better signage for something or a Bunch of fives or something.
Scott: Yeah, I mean they.
Scott: I think the guy said something like it was only 400 bucks.
Scott: So 400 bucks is how many $5 bills?
Rym: Well, 400 bucks could have done a lot of things.
Scott: Yeah, you know It's like.
Scott: they say oh, it's only 400 bucks to get full color.
Scott: and you know You hear that.
Scott: and you say well printing cost thousands of dollars.
Scott: That's a great deal.
Rym: But 400 bucks could have paid for another guest.
Scott: Yeah, 400 bucks could have paid for a lot of things.
Scott: so You just you got to wonder what this con is doing and what goes on there and what the staff and the chair and whoever What they're all up to.
Scott: and remember the guy who came up to us late at night and he was in charge of what?
Rym: Oh, he was in charge of fuck everything.
Rym: Yeah, everything involving webcomics.
Rym: He was some staffer and he seemed like a cool guy.
Scott: and I was like, well, do you have any staff under you?
Scott: He's like no, it's just me.
Scott: and I was like, oh my god, you're running half this con all by yourself.
Rym: Yeah, ConnectiCon needs a lot more staff.
Rym: I mean it takes a lot of staff to run an anime con and they did not have enough at all.
Rym: In fact the ConnectiCon cost so much money.
Rym: but almost any problem a con faces during the convention itself can be solved by having either a More well-trained or experienced staffers or be more staffers.
Scott: Yeah, you can either have an army of gophers or one or two really awesome staff people with loud voices or megaphones or See both both both both.
Rym: Yep, like just there's a whole bunch of tiny little things I really don't want to get into because we've gone on forever.
Rym: It's after midnight.
Rym: I had a five-hour drive home and I'm very tired.
Rym: but a whole bunch of little things like traffic flow and walking was very difficult a lot of areas and it would have been trivial if you had enough staff to have a Sweeping that hallway making sure everyone kept moving a little things like that.
Rym: maybe I would have put that narrow business outside because I I'm proud that you had something cool like that at your con because many cons wouldn't even begin to think about the liability of Having a bunch of kids hitting each other with boffin weapons in convention space
Scott: as an official thing.
Scott: as you know I mean a lot of conventions.
Scott: just kids decide that they're gonna go outside and hit each other with sticks.
Scott: But this is an official like con thing.
Scott: It's on the map of the convention.
Scott: Like here is the area of the convention where people hit each other with sticks.
Rym: I would never have sanctioned that if I were staff or security at a convention.
Scott: I would have put it I mean the Nero guys are having people sign waivers and stuff.
Scott: But I would have been like no you can come to the convention You cannot have hitting each other with sticks as an official convention event.
Scott: You know you could but I would have it outside unless you sign this contract accepting all liability and have it outside Which they may have.
Rym: but even then it just seemed like Especially since they were doing the fighting in the middle of a crowded room with just a rope on the floor around everyone.
Scott: Yeah, but there was a kind of a. the spectators made a little wall around them.
Rym: so yeah, but it just.
Rym: it seemed like a situation that could have turned bad at any second and I Would have handled it differently, but it was definitely sketchy Definitely sketchy.
Rym: I I guess I'm I've been doing this for so long.
Rym: I really tend to edge on the side of safety.
Scott: Mm-hmm Definitely.
Rym: All right, except except when it comes to fireworks.
Rym: Of course, that's a completely unrelated episode.
Scott: Do we do have anything else to say about ConnectiCon?
Rym: Uh, really?
Rym: I don't other than that unless either the price comes down or They invite us as panelists.
Rym: I really couldn't see myself paying to go back to ConnectiCon.
Scott: Yeah, unless they lower their price or they do some changes to their con or something I'm not gonna go back if I have to pay.
Rym: I mean all they need is a little bit of extra planning and someone who's good at being an emcee and more staff.
Rym: Yeah, that's really it and I have a lot of advice on how to handle all of those.
Rym: But if anyone wants to hear that maybe I'll do a GeekNights special or something because I'm tired and I think we're done.
Scott: Yeah, how long is this gun?
Scott: It's a long one.
Rym: We've gone over an hour and a half just on the bit starting with the thing of the day.
Rym: Cool Yeah, luckily we went short on the news and we're running out of lips in actually No, because lips and finally caught up suddenly on the archiving.
Rym: Hooray I think we're gonna push it now because of this super long episode that we just made great.
Rym: But we're we're fine.
Scott: Let's end it.
Rym: All right, it's over.
Rym: Bye and That was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.