Rym: It's Wednesday June 14th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We bring you our coverage of the mocha art festival Which we attended this past weekend.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: It's real hard to do the show now that I have a Mac, and I just want to play with it all day.
Scott: I thought what happened to?
Scott: Only I teased my job.
Scott: I only do it for the money.
Scott: I don't like computers.
Rym: Eh I Like the.
Rym: I like the things I can do with the Mac, and I haven't even gotten to explore it yet.
Rym: There's all these little applications that do things and I haven't been able to do them yet.
Scott: What happened to?
Scott: I hate computers?
Scott: I only do IT for the money.
Rym: I'd only do IT for the money.
Rym: I hate IT.
Scott: Yet you seem to be having a lot of fun doing some IT in your house.
Rym: No, no see the thing is I don't like working for other people.
Rym: I don't like doing the work that come.
Rym: anything that people will pay me to do with few exceptions are things that I believe.
Scott: That when you said that you only did IT for the money You were saying how you didn't care about your computer and bla bla bla bla bla.
Rym: now I was talking mostly about on a global scale.
Rym: I don't care so much about computers and IT.
Rym: I care a lot more about what they can do.
Scott: and I'm really but it was a discussion about me trying to get you to buy a new computer that which you desperately needed.
Scott: So you're arguing against buying a new computer.
Scott: well considering that you didn't want one yet, and you're now turncoat.
Rym: Well, I didn't so desperately need it.
Rym: considering that I'm still recording the podcast on my old Linux box It's about the only thing you're doing in the old Linux box.
Scott: That's only cuz you didn't figure out how to use garage band yet.
Rym: Yeah, I got to do a lot of stuff to make garage band do what I want it to do Mm-hmm.
Scott: But yeah, I was right again okay, and speaking of Computers I got some steam to go in my Ubuntu.
Rym: Yeah, though apparently half-life 2 is slow as shit.
Scott: Well, I don't know.
Scott: It's I'm gonna restart and try it one more time.
Scott: It worked like it ran But half-life 1 ran super smooth like perfect.
Scott: half-life 2 didn't run so super smooth in the first go.
Scott: So I'm gonna give it one more go to see what happens With.
Rym: are you gonna change anything before you give it another go?
Scott: I did.
Scott: I changed some X config stuff.
Scott: Okay I didn't wasn't applied.
Rym: as long as you're not one of those people has a problem.
Rym: and then they tried the exact same thing over And over again and wonder why the exact same thing happens over.
Scott: also when I did try half-life 2 I was a bit hasty and I you know push some buttons that might have screwed it up.
Scott: So I'm gonna not push those buttons this time and we'll see what happens.
Scott: a little more patience.
Rym: so Yeah, we got some news though.
Scott: Oh, we do have news.
Rym: the RIAA the Long-standing enemy of all that is good and holy Has been doing you know the typical bad thing suing people trying to extend copyright or screw copyright up hurting artists and generally being evil.
Rym: They recently just stated that they're not worried anymore.
Rym: They've got peer-to-peer contained and I Just started cracking up and I didn't even read the rest of it.
Scott: They said that it door.
Rym: They said that piracy is not hurting sales anymore And then you can stop suing people.
Rym: and they said that downloads have peaked.
Rym: they flattened out.
Scott: They're not growing anymore to which the Pirate Bay getting a hajillion visitors Three times the more than what it got before people knew about it.
Rym: Well consider this the this is the first time the RIAA has lost so spectacularly.
Rym: I mean the Pirates Bay.
Rym: not only did they flagrantly flaunt the fact that they were being awesome for For year for just constantly there.
Rym: No one could get him.
Rym: No one could sue him.
Rym: They were perfectly immune.
Rym: They finally got gotten once and within three days They're back online fully operational and more popular than ever and they're also back up in their original country.
Scott: So even though they were able to run away to other countries and now they're back up where they started.
Scott: Nothing has changed.
Rym: Now for any of you geeks out there who know how to do this I highly recommend you to a reverse DNS lookup of the Pirates Bay IP address.
Rym: Mm-hmm It is quite hilarious.
Scott: It is quite hilarious.
Scott: Hey, it has been terrific.
Scott: I Also want to say, you know The RA does sort of have a point in that in the early days the Napster days.
Scott: They win MX days.
Scott: I was Honestly pirating songs from them, you know constantly now Songs that my dad has on vinyl.
Scott: so it kind of isn't.
Scott: it's okay kinda sorta.
Rym: Yeah kind of sort of not really.
Scott: but The point is is that for the past?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: three years There haven't?
Scott: I've already got every RIAA song I want.
Scott: I'm not pirating their music anymore.
Rym: there isn't so much new good music at least in our opinion.
Scott: all the music that I'm getting now is Free music that I hear on podcasts that play free music or foreign music That's not technically illegal to foreign music that I can't obtain legally.
Rym: So well, you could you could no don't pretend not for a reasonable price.
Rym: Okay?
Rym: Okay there I'll give you that but don't say oh, I can't get that Japanese music.
Rym: You can't.
Rym: it's just $40 $40 like 50 bucks.
Scott: Yes, screw that now.
Rym: I saw some discounts in that amazement.
Rym: I saw some $35 to make.
Scott: see Oh $35 to me, you know, honestly though if the tables of CDs at the cons We're selling the Japanese CDs for five bucks.
Scott: I'd probably buy a bunch of them hell even for ten bucks.
Scott: There are a few CDs I would have bought, you know, cuz while I can I get a lot of them on bit torrent.
Scott: There there's some that I just can't get.
Scott: they're so old or nobody's bothered to buy them at all.
Scott: So you can't get him now.
Scott: five bucks.
Rym: my early Napster days downloading experience was quite different.
Rym: in that one I had broadband right away.
Rym: Like I was downloading mp3s before Napster even existed But I didn't.
Rym: I mean I like music.
Rym: But the only music I had were CDs that other people had bought me because I just as much as I enjoyed music I could never bring myself to spend my what I don't want to say hard-earned because I didn't earn it but spend the money I had on music on CDs.
Rym: So I go to concerts a lot and I'd get music and I'd go see like bands play and people would give me CDs.
Rym: But I never bought music and as a result, I mostly only liked classical music and classic rock.
Scott: Yeah, I bought music in the high school days before I broadband at least before I had brought that.
Rym: I never bought music.
Rym: Yeah my whole life.
Scott: But all the music I bought was always me ripping off Columbia House.
Scott: people always said Columbia House is a ripoff.
Scott: I figured out the way to beat Columbia House.
Scott: Occasionally, they would send these little tiny pieces of paper You had to be real clever to look for him that you would just put in a number and get a free CD and I would always calculate how much money I had given Columbia House and how many CDs I had gotten.
Scott: and By the time I was done with Columbia House, I just stopped paying attention to them, you know.
Scott: And it turned out I paid something like four dollars for every CD I got from them For all the free ones they gave me.
Scott: so that was you know.
Scott: And then I also got like a box set of CDs for like ten bucks.
Scott: It's like a hundred bucks in the store stuff like that.
Rym: But yeah, yep, but anyway once I discovered that I could download music online I in short order became very interested in a lot of foreign music and a lot of awesome music and my music tastes quintupled.
Rym: I immediately expanded in a million directions and Well, the rest is history.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: So yeah, the oh, hey the reason if the RA has any truth in their recent statements It's the fact that no one cares about their music anymore.
Scott: So no one's pirating it anymore, which I wouldn't be surprised.
Rym: There's a lot of good free music out there.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Yep Yep, as I'm discovering more and more now that I have an iPod to listen to various podcasts on my way to work Yay Finally you're probably the only podcaster who didn't listen to podcast until now.
Rym: I have listened.
Rym: I've currently listened to a grand total of six podcast episodes.
Rym: Holy crap I listened to two anime world orders way back because one I met him and they were cool and then they wanted some help with The Odean episode.
Rym: No, I did not but I it's going on.
Rym: Well, actually it's finished now because the iPods really fast, but it's on my iPod right now.
Scott: It's a hilarious episode.
Rym: Oh Okay, I do know it's sad that now I found out that the Odean that I saw was in fact the shortened version.
Rym: Yes, I can't imagine.
Rym: I even imagine okay, so And I listened to a pen, you know pen radio.
Scott: Yeah, that's not technically a hundred percent podcast.
Scott: It's a podcast.
Rym: I used to listen to it on the radio.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Yep, and I downloaded one of artist Ally because Nury over there also asked for some audio help early on.
Rym: Yeah, seems that most of the podcast I downloaded because people asked me to listen to them and tell them how to make it sound Better.
Scott: Yeah, that's good.
Rym: Now.
Rym: I listen to almost everything.
Scott: Hooray Okay, my news It's a comic news.
Scott: Holy crap.
Rym: Whoa on comic day.
Rym: Yeah, what the hell?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It's crazy now And I don't really care about superhero comics.
Scott: neither is Rym.
Rym: you mean underwear pervert comics.
Scott: Yeah, that's right underwear perverts.
Scott: But if you care about underwear perverts the Marvel underwear perverts and you haven't read that Civil War whatever comic that came out today You probably want to fast-forward a bit because I'm gonna spoil the fuck out of it.
Rym: All right, so fast forward until the thing of the day.
Rym: music unless you don't care about underwear perverts.
Scott: Yep now Unless you want to laugh a whole lot cuz I'm gonna make fun of underwear perverts a lot.
Scott: This might be hilarious Boon - so first I'm gonna explain to you the deal with the Civil War thing.
Scott: I'm gonna in as short as possible because I personally don't even understand it that well.
Scott: And I read the first issue.
Rym: from what little I've heard It sounds like it would kind of maybe be a neat concept in any other genre of literature.
Scott: Yeah, so what they've done is they're trying to make An analogy a metaphor of the current political situation in the u.s.
Scott: The you know privacy and civil civil liberties versus security issue.
Scott: and what they've done is they said They took all the superheroes in the Marvel Universe, at least the ones on earth the ones that make sense Not the awesome ones in space Silver-surfer, I think this little runner.
Scott: Oh, yeah, the Silver Surfer is not there.
Scott: There's a separate thing going on in space that he's doing what?
Rym: how could the Civil War on earth of anything?
Scott: It's not it's.
Scott: it's something else called annihilation.
Scott: Okay, which I know nothing about.
Scott: So all right, all I know is that it exists, but the Civil War storyline the major event is that the government of the United States of the world or what I don't even know is Saying that superheroes are dangerous.
Scott: They're unlicensed Vigilantes and you know a few superheroes who are on who are making a reality TV show about themselves living it all together in a house You know do some damage and destroy a neighborhood and people get killed and it's bad.
Scott: So the government's gonna pass a law that says superheroes have to register and get licensed and reveal their identities and all this.
Scott: You know stuff.
Scott: so that there aren't dangerous Superhero.
Scott: you can't go superheroing unless the government approves you.
Scott: that way there's liability and all that jazz.
Rym: Yeah, so I guess if you've seen The Incredibles, I don't know.
Scott: I never saw that.
Rym: It's actually a really good movie I know but I got it.
Scott: It's weird because I know all those Pixar movies are good, but I haven't seen any sin.
Rym: honestly, I hadn't seen many of them either.
Rym: and Emily who discovered this to be a travesty and after I saw many of them.
Rym: I agreed with her Basically sat me down every chance you got and showed me almost all of them in order.
Scott: Yeah, it's not a story.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't see Toy Story 2.
Scott: I didn't see Monsters Inc.
Scott: I didn't see the one with the fish.
Scott: I didn't see the new one with the cars.
Scott: fine.
Rym: It was okay.
Scott: I didn't see The Incredibles.
Rym: I didn't see The Incredibles is the best one.
Scott: What else is there?
Scott: I Know I kind of want to see him, but I just have it and you know, I'll put them all in the queue.
Rym: All right The point is I think the queue is full.
Rym: Actually.
Rym: I got a look.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Wow, you can fill a queue in Netflix.
Rym: It can only hold 500 per queue.
Scott: Whoa.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So anyway, the Civil War thing is Basically, they're trying to make a talk they're trying to make a comic about the politics of the real world by having similar politics in the Marvel Universe and having a Big deal out of it.
Scott: and what they've done is they had this big shtick and the shtick is what side are you on?
Scott: You know and there's the Captain America side.
Scott: That's all freedom.
Scott: That's the good side.
Scott: And then there's the spider-man Iron Man side.
Scott: That's all.
Scott: everyone better get licensed girl.
Scott: So in the comic that came out today Civil War number two Spider-man went to I think did it said Times Square and those he had a big press conference.
Scott: He said look at me.
Scott: I'm Peter Parker.
Rym: So, I guess we just spoiled the fact that Spider-man is Peter Parker.
Scott: Well, the point is that he told the world.
Scott: Yeah, the issue behind it is that you know Oh, he didn't he didn't want to do it because then people would know, you know Mary Jane and Aunt May and all his relatives, you know People could go to them and before they couldn't.
Scott: before and May was just some old lady.
Scott: now She's you know spider-man's aunt who can be kidnapped and used to control spider-man.
Scott: So Regardless of that what I want to talk about is a the fanboys who are all like some of them go.
Scott: Oh, this is a travesty blah blah blah.
Scott: You can't do this state, you know the old guys back name You know, they can all shut up.
Rym: Yeah, we don't need no small faction here.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: And number two Superhero comics.
Scott: now if you look at this They're just the exact same thing you see on primetime TV all those sitcom things, you know, and all those HBO TV shows.
Scott: these superhero comics are the same bullshit.
Rym: now bear in mind We're talking specifically about a comic you would call a superhero comic not like I don't know ex-mock Mostly the Marvel and DC Universe Comics, I mean there are comics that involve beings.
Rym: you would you could call superheroes that are good.
Rym: These are underwear pervert comics.
Scott: Yes underwear perverts more and more obvious every day that they're writing the underwear pervert comics as if they were.
Scott: you know Television shows.
Rym: I mean, I guess it's just.
Rym: it's like they don't want to give up on the fact that they have underwear perverts.
Rym: This is a good story.
Rym: Why don't they just make original characters and do a comic about that?
Rym: Yep, or make you make up superheroes.
Rym: Why keep using the same underwear perverts over and over again?
Scott: And why do you have to you know, keep this universe, you know?
Scott: Make everything follow everything else and you have all this history and you have to like stick by and be all consistent and continuous.
Scott: Why do you have to do that?
Scott: The only people who care about that are the fanboys reading your shit.
Scott: You know what if you if you if you'd stop doing it the fanboys might get pissed But they're gonna buy it no matter what their fanboys.
Scott: you could print a picture of a piece of poop and put you know Amazing Spider-Man number whatever on the cover and They'll buy it because they have to have every single issue of Amazing Spider-Man no matter what's inside because they're fanboys.
Scott: so you might as well make the content of the comic something that everyone in the world can enjoy and Not forcing yourselves to make something that fanboys will enjoy and you'll.
Scott: maybe you'll sell more copies and make something interesting.
Rym: Maybe the problem is I mean it was mostly rhetorical question.
Rym: We know the answer and it's that they're milking money out of these underwear pervert fans.
Scott: Yep It just instead of getting more fans with the Nintendo strategy.
Scott: Hey, you know Nintendo We don't know.
Rym: instead of blue ocean is what yellow ocean?
Scott: Yeah, it's instead of blue ocean.
Scott: Let's get all those people who aren't our customers to become our customers to make more money.
Scott: It's let's take our existing cut loyal customers and make them give us more money.
Scott: Hey, let's milk them for as much as you possibly can.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: No I think I know what the real reason is.
Rym: They have these underwear perverts and they're running them until their threadbare.
Rym: They're doing it for the same reason.
Rym: I wore that same pair of boxers for over a decade.
Scott: the other problem is is that Back in the day the people writing the underwear pervert comics were writing it like it was their job.
Scott: I mean sure there were some people who weren't but for the most part.
Scott: This is their job.
Scott: The people nowadays writing the underwear pervert comics used to be the fanboys of the underwear pervert comics.
Scott: It's imagine if we let the the otaku run the anime companies.
Scott: What kind of anime would they produce?
Scott: Gainax people It's Gainax.
Scott: imagine if every Anime studio was Gainax.
Rym: No, no, not just Gainax.
Rym: Imagine if every anime studio was the people who like to Gainax's stuff.
Scott: Well, I guess there aren't isn't enough Gainax to go around.
Scott: so yeah, you know.
Scott: now imagine if every movie studio in You know all the whole u.s.
Scott: Was run by those, you know film buffs.
Scott: Scary isn't it?
Rym: you know, I think it also might have something to do with just the passion of the artists and the the fact that a lot of comic at least underwear pervert comics are definitely all about the money and a distributed effort among a lot of people.
Rym: and Then look at say all the cool indie comics out there now where it's basically one guy or a small group of people who are doing something because they want to do it and They're.
Rym: they're getting enjoyment just out of making the comic and the fact that the comic is successful.
Scott: From listening to a lot of interviews on podcasts with the people making the underwear pervert comics they seem to enjoy it and like doing it and You know, but they also have the money factor.
Scott: It's like the guys who the management is all about money and they hire a bunch of people who are all about fanboys To do it and as a result you have a the all the creators want to stick with the status quo Because that's their favorite thing in the world and all the managers who care about money Don't want to take any risks.
Scott: So they stick with the status quo while the reality is that taking a risk is the way to make more money.
Scott: but the creators don't want to do that because they're fanboys and the managers don't want to do it because it's taking a risk and you know, they're okay with that because they make all their money off the movies and It was in the end result is bad comics for everyone that you know have to rely on Cares.
Scott: it's just whatever.
Scott: Why'd you make a comic with an interesting story and not just some crazy event?
Rym: Well, the the important question is when he took his mask off and revealed everything to the world Did he bold every third word or not?
Rym: ah Things of the day now.
Rym: I'm a big fan of practical jokes.
Scott: Everyone's a fan of practical jokes.
Rym: No, I know a lot of people who aren't well, you know what.
Scott: we should pull some practical jokes on them.
Rym: Yeah, we should or pranks if you will.
Rym: Yeah, anyways, I like pranks, especially like tire irons leg pulling All right.
Rym: Now this I'm not a hundred percent sure if this wasn't staged But I don't care because it's hilarious.
Rym: either way and if this is actually real which I'm leaning toward it being real It's a thousand times more hilarious.
Rym: Yeah, it was pretty funny And if anything it's a very clever practical joke that could be fairly easily replicated for humorous results.
Rym: So there's a checkout counter at a grocery store somewhere and they've got.
Rym: you know A lot of places have the security camera and then there's a TV and you can see yourself and everything on the security camera.
Scott: Yep, I see that.
Scott: I wonder why they do that.
Scott: What's the point?
Rym: you know why?
Rym: cuz?
Scott: then the person who might be thinking about stealing looks up and sees themselves on camera and goes Oh, no now that you can see where the edge of the camera is so they can avoid it and steal something off-screen.
Rym: Yeah that too.
Rym: But the thing is there's usually more cameras that they don't show you where they point.
Scott: That's a good idea, but you know, it's just.
Rym: they always want to have one camera.
Rym: That's obvious.
Rym: In fact, I saw a documentary a long time ago where they showed that in a lot of banks You know, you see security cameras on the ceiling.
Scott: Most of them are fake.
Rym: They're fake and the real ones are hidden.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: But anyway, so they've got this camera and they've got a guy dressed up as death with a scythe.
Rym: and then they've got this old guy.
Rym: Then there's this guy.
Rym: three Ubuntu Who's standing there and They have it set up so that they can overlay the death onto the camera image.
Rym: So the person standing there if they look up at the camera, they'll see themselves standing there Reacting normally and behind them is fucking death the cream Three.
Rym: so the first lady is standing there and she's doing her stuff.
Rym: she looks up and she does a double-take and she looks at the cameras.
Rym: that can.
Rym: she moves her head a little and she turns around and They've overlaid the death over this old dude standing there with a scythe Like he's gonna.
Scott: when she looks behind her in the real world She sees an old guy with a scythe.
Scott: when she looks at this television with the video camera on top of it She sees herself doing exactly what she would normally be doing on the camera.
Scott: So it's a real camera.
Rym: But she sees death Where the old man was and her reaction is she stands there for a minute and then she just kind of like puts her head Down and rubs her eyes and looks up again Mm-hmm.
Rym: The best is this is one guy and he just stands there staring at the camera breathing really heavily and looking really really nervous.
Scott: I This wouldn't work on me or someone like, you know any rational person But all those people who actually might think death is real.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: if I would probably give me a little double-take.
Scott: before I assumed that there was a tech ball I would well I would look to make sure my eyes weren't screwed up first.
Scott: Then I would look at the camera and then look at the guy.
Scott: Then I would go and push the guy while looking at the camera and see if it does the same thing And if it didn't.
Rym: I would know there was a camera trick and that would be that yeah Props if they could pull it off with a mirror or something.
Rym: Ooh You could do that with a mirror.
Rym: that was actually a display.
Scott: once we get display technology They set up some sort of motion capture thing like those little VR suits on the guy.
Scott: Oh man, there is clothes.
Scott: Oh man, that would be the best.
Scott: Oh man, cuz that that would fool me for even more minutes.
Scott: I'd like have to take the guys clothes off before The evidence is really piling up.
Scott: Scott, you know what if I'm dead, what does it matter?
Scott: It's dead.
Scott: I mean what the different possibilities are.
Scott: a it's a trick beads death and I'm dead.
Rym: if it's death Just beat him at twister and get on your way.
Scott: I Don't think there was a twister in that store.
Rym: dumb dumb All right.
Rym: So what you think of the day?
Rym: All right, so Seth MacFarlane Why did I ask you?
Rym: I watched it with you right before we did the show.
Scott: Yeah, I'm just so used to the radio, you know, it's actually a relatively old thing of the day.
Scott: by old I mean a few days old and I saw linked to it, but ever watched it until just now by delicious did.
Rym: Yeah, I saw a link to just the stewie portion of it.
Scott: Oh, really?
Scott: Anyway, Seth MacFarlane is the guy who made family guy and he also does a lot of the voices on Family Guy.
Scott: And I think he also made that other show that people don't like What Eric and dad?
Scott: Yeah anyway at Harvard there's the day before graduation he went there to do some sort of What are they motivational speech of some sort?
Rym: Yeah, the kind of speeches they always give a keynote I guess.
Scott: Yeah, something like that.
Scott: I don't know but For the first part.
Scott: He talked as himself Seth MacFarlane and for the second third and fourth parts He talked his three different Family Guy voices.
Scott: So it was as if Seth MacFarlane Peter Griffin Peter Griffin Stewie Griffin and Quagmire All four of those people showed any to give speeches to Harvard.
Scott: it's pretty funny.
Scott: you should watch it.
Rym: Yeah, it's definitely worth watching.
Scott: Yeah, well, you don't even really need to watch it except to go.
Scott: Oh, that's what Seth MacFarlane looks like.
Scott: the rest of the time you can just listen to.
Rym: yeah I did actually just because I didn't actually see it.
Rym: I just listened to it while Scott watched it and As long as I didn't see him, I just assumed that Peter Griffin was standing up on that stage.
Scott: yep Someone should Remix this video, but with a little by putting Peter Griffin and Stewie up there and animating their mouth.
Rym: Katie Yeah, it's kind of scary But I got kind of good at saying giga because you practiced it Partly because it's just double and triple tonguing like I used to do when I play the trumpet.
Scott: yeah You couldn't do it when you first tried.
Rym: no I did practice a little bit.
Scott: you practiced for many days.
Scott: You know what increase your giga tees.
Rym: It's a valuable skill.
Scott: I'm sure it is.
Rym: It'll get me far in life.
Rym: Yep All right, Katie.
Rym: Okay, so we're going to To this week this past weekend.
Rym: We went to it not really convention, but close enough.
Rym: So we're treating it like one the fifth annual mocha art festival in Manhattan.
Scott: If you don't know the mocha is the Museum of Comic and cartoon art and it's a museum in the city and you can go visit it and you can join it.
Scott: if you join It you get all kinds of goodies and it doesn't cost that much.
Scott: Yeah, I think I might actually join it.
Scott: the low Maybe the low-end membership.
Scott: Yeah, they get a magazine and you get access to special events.
Rym: Yeah, these are definitely the kind of people who deserve our money.
Scott: Yep, and You know they have exhibits there.
Scott: I think the current exhibit is a Todd McFarlane thing if I if I recall correctly I don't know offhand.
Scott: Yeah, but it's pretty cool.
Scott: And they once a year their biggest fundraiser, but by no means their only fundraiser is this Arts Festival, which is pretty much a Gigantic artists alley of independent comic artists.
Rym: I mean, there'll be web comic artists comic artists Some writers independent publishers pretty much everyone except underwear perverts.
Scott: Yeah, even though there were a little bit of underwear pervert in his.
Rym: yeah There was one guy who was drawing a sketch of Colossus for someone and I saw that specifically and it stood out in my mind.
Rym: Yep,
Scott: but I mean this stuff ranges from schmuck with a webcomic to schmuck printing stuff out of a laser printer at Kinko's folding it and stapling it and then giving it to you for a Quarter to a guy who has a professionally printed book Laying it out on the table and going hey, what's up?
Rym: And then to people who made like hand-bound art like they made a bound book by themselves There was a guy who was he painted a comic like he painted it.
Scott: Each comic was fully handmade by him painted and he had so many of them.
Scott: not a whole lot But you know like 20 or so.
Scott: So he's selling them for $20 and either they see sold out where he started selling him too fast.
Scott: So you raised it to $30 and they didn't.
Scott: the rate of selling did not decrease.
Scott: so So then he he had one left.
Scott: He just kept it for himself because he wasn't gonna sell them all.
Scott: and yeah, that's the kind of stuff that goes on here.
Scott: It's a crazy artists alley of awesome.
Rym: Now to the person in the forums who kind of tried to lambast us for our appraisal of Philly wizard world and underwear pervert culture.
Rym: This was a comic convention.
Rym: this was comics.
Rym: This was the heart of comic re and you know what.
Rym: it was completely the opposite of Philly wizard world.
Rym: It was awesome.
Scott: observation number one.
Scott: There were no annoying Corporate type things going on none.
Rym: I mean even though there were some somewhat large publishing houses there They just had a little table right next to everyone else's little table.
Scott: Yep Maybe some of them had a few extra tables or a few shinier books or more books or more staff and nicer name badges and t-shirts, but that's about it.
Scott: and Also many more ladies.
Scott: Yes, I'd say there were probably more ladies there than men's.
Rym: Also along with that a distinct lack of fanboy funk.
Scott: Definitely no funk even though it was crowded and warm.
Scott: There was no smell.
Scott: It was it smelled like old building in New York.
Scott: Yeah Also There were people of all ages.
Scott: they're not just you know, the the old, you know middle-aged type of comic guy.
Scott: There were young punk kids there.
Scott: I saw some like mom and mom.
Scott: There are a lot of moms and dads pushing babies around.
Scott: There was some old people there.
Scott: You had all ages at this place.
Rym: And of course finally the crowd was incredibly friendly and easygoing and everyone was very sociable.
Scott: Yep, pretty much you said I wore a shirt That was from the webcomic boases Boa SAS
Rym: boy on a stick and slither Which
Scott: is a relatively popular webcomic and before I even got in the door some guy in the street Complimented me on the shirt and at least 10 other people said hey, I like your shirt.
Scott: Hey, have you seen the guy who makes the comic?
Scott: is he here?
Scott: I know he wasn't there, but we'll talk about that later.
Scott: You know, I just people kept coming up to me and saying hi, I like your shirt.
Scott: Comic convention.
Scott: not a single person.
Scott: I didn't already know came up to me and talked to me.
Rym: zero in fact, people would generally avoid my gaze.
Scott: yep, and You know, I when I tried to interact with people they would be like You try to interact with someone.
Scott: it's hard to get them to shut up.
Scott: it's like alright good I just said I now you're not going away.
Rym: And of course a general observation about the actual Exhibitors at the mocha art festival.
Rym: No one was pushy.
Rym: No one was bothering me or trying to get me to buy stuff.
Rym: In fact, one guy was really cool.
Rym: I'll talk about his stuff.
Rym: I thought I saw what his books were about and I bought the first one and Someone said I think it was.
Rym: Scott actually said yeah, you should buy all of them buy them all.
Rym: and the artist himself said Hey, man, only buy one buy the rest later if you like that one, you know As opposed to the Philly wizard world where people were practically trying to force me to pull out my wallet and buy their $5 Crappy little comic.
Scott: now keep in mind there were some people who did have a sales pitch But they didn't deliver the pitch until I was already Standing at their table looking at this stuff of my own free will and already interacting with them.
Rym: Yep, like if you made eye contact with someone who obviously had a stick You know, I look at someone's table.
Scott: They're like, you know, they give me the nod.
Scott: then I go up, you know.
Scott: I look at them.
Scott: they say hey, how you doing?
Scott: They show me what's on their table is free samples.
Scott: I read it, you know, and then if I look please they go, you know And I start looking at something else.
Scott: then they deliver the sales pitch.
Scott: They don't reach out into the aisles delivering the sales pitch as not everyone but some people did at wizard world Philly.
Rym: Also, there were a lot of cool free things.
Rym: In fact one particularly cool free thing.
Rym: I'll mention it now because honestly, I don't remember who had them at their table.
Rym: Yeah, I feel bad because you guys were awesome.
Rym: They were.
Scott: they were super super awesome people Giving away.
Scott: they made arts and crafts out of wood and they painted them and they were super cool.
Scott: And they gave out little tiny pac-man ghosts that were all unique and individually painted in different ways And they were all super cool and they were free and they were free.
Scott: little wooden pac-man ghosts painted uniquely Not even like.
Rym: they weren't even marked as like.
Rym: oh they come to our thing.
Rym: or they was just free.
Rym: They were just doing it because they wanted to.
Rym: they were having fun with this.
Scott: Yeah, but I forgot to take a little piece of something to say who they were.
Rym: I did.
Rym: I made a point of taking one of their business cards.
Rym: The problem is I took a lot of business cards and I don't remember whose business card was.
Scott: We can just go to all the websites till we figure it out.
Rym: Yeah, we can try that later So we'll post it.
Scott: if we find out who that was We'll post in the forum because they're awesome because I really like my little ghostie.
Scott: Love my little ghostie.
Rym: and also one more general observation before we talk about the meat.
Rym: at Philly wizard world When I if you wanted an autograph or if you bought something It was basically just a business transaction And if you ask someone they'd either charge you.
Rym: it was tough to get people to sign things.
Scott: I didn't have that.
Scott: every time I bought something at Philly wizard world well when I bought something from the Creator they just signed it.
Scott: but you know, the Profession like the people who were there to do autographs the famous people.
Scott: you had to get in lines get tickets Yeah, all that sort of stuff.
Rym: but not only did the people here sign things but every person with a couple exceptions who signed something for me drew an awesome sketch of somewhat complex Drawing skills.
Scott: Yeah, that is something that was different Is it Philly wizard world?
Scott: and people sign things maybe because it was more, you know, they were signing more things But I don't think so.
Scott: It was pretty crowded at mocha, you know Mean.
Scott: so any given person was doing just as much business as they.
Scott: you know, I imagine someone at wizard world was doing They you know wizard world.
Scott: They just signed it and gave it to you at mocha.
Scott: They tend to be personalized.
Scott: They would write your name and they draw a little funny picture.
Scott: They'd ask you what you wanted to draw.
Scott: They talked to you, you know, and then they would sign it.
Rym: Yeah They'd spend pretty much as much time as you were willing to spend with them talking unless there was a huge line or there were People really in the way.
Rym: and
Scott: even when there's a huge line I remember seeing like, you know a whole bunch of people waiting to talk to someone and the guy was still personalizing and drawing little pictures and all their stuff and Even like a guy walked up with like all like all volumes of some guys thing and he did all of them.
Scott: He didn't care.
Scott: He was like You know wizard world they're like, alright, I can't do all these.
Scott: you're bringing up too many.
Rym: Now, of course Scott and I went with our friend Yuko who actually knows a lot of the webcomic artist and is a published comic Artist herself.
Rym: Yeah, so she Introduced us to a lot of awesome people.
Scott: We had an insider
Rym: yep, like instead like a
Scott: little tour guide
Rym: like a lot of the cool wet like particularly the people who do questionable content and I'm trying to remember who else offhand before I look through all my stuff, but We got the little like they were instead of just oh, hey, we like your comic.
Rym: It was oh, hey, these are my friends blah.
Rym: Ooh, and then we got to talk to him for a while.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So let's talk about who we saw.
Rym: All right, right, of course I want to start right away with Brian Lee O'Malley.
Scott: Okay, because he's a little bigger than most of the other people there But yes, he is but I want to start with him because Scott pilgrim is fantastic.
Scott: All right, so Scott pilgrim I think the aim of it is like teen girls mostly but it's fucking entertaining.
Scott: Let me tell you that.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: I'm not exactly sure what I like so much about it.
Rym: I haven't I haven't thought about it enough to figure it out But for some reason it just really sucked me in and I love it.
Scott: My favorite part was the end where it turns in like this.
Scott: It's sort of like a big dance type of you know, it's The fighting.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, it's like normally the fighting is the worst part But here the fighting was like this huge amazing Super.
Scott: it felt like a little party while I was reading it.
Rym: the fact that the coins came out of the guy after he beat him.
Rym: Yeah Yeah And the dialogue is really just funny and witty and the art style is somewhat unique.
Rym: it stands out.
Scott: Yeah, if you're not reading Scott pilgrim, you are a. this is a new shtick that someone else started another podcast.
Scott: But if you're not reading Scott pilgrim, you are a fool fool.
Rym: And of course Brian Lee O'Malley himself was very cool.
Rym: He signed the book that I didn't even buy from him at the con.
Rym: It was actually the book was given to me as a gift from someone else and then he signed it.
Scott: Anyway, yep, and he was selling all his books of the con even his newest volume.
Scott: He had plenty of stock.
Scott: Just you know all-around friendly.
Scott: Who else was there?
Scott: Oh Here's some guys.
Scott: We didn't even know about until we got there.
Rym: Yeah, they basically Dragged us in and gave us some swag and then we realized what their comic was all about and that was it.
Scott: now This is pretty much if Rym has an alley This is a laser slicing that alley in perfect symmetry down the middle.
Rym: Yeah I mean there are a lot of weird things I like but this is one avenue of humor that I for some reason just can't Get enough of.
Scott: yes now The website is wonder mark calm W-o-n-d-e-r-m-a-r-k dot-com now.
Scott: I don't remember the guy.
Scott: I think his name is mark.
Scott: That's just a guess.
Scott: Yeah, I Really don't remember his name.
Scott: Wonder yes, but the comic that he does at least the one that we care about is called Poop jokes and top hats.
Scott: or was it the reverse top hats and poop jokes.
Scott: I forget that.
Rym: That should sum it up nicely.
Rym: It is exactly what it sounds like and that is what Rym likes.
Scott: Rym likes poop jokes and Rym likes top hat.
Rym: Yes, I do.
Scott: The the drawings the art style looks really.
Scott: It looks like the Quaker in the haha guy.
Scott: Haha.
Scott: That's what it looks like.
Rym: I'm making a poop joke.
Scott: That's right It's all it looks like, you know, like 1800s Semi-realistic Character sketches going clever dialogue very clever dot.
Scott: You want me to let's read a comic?
Rym: All right, you have one in front of you and I don't I do.
Rym: I'm looking at our next.
Scott: okay, so there is a relatively normal Built man with a funny 1800 style beard, you know where there's a mustache.
Scott: But the chin is shaved and the mustache connects to the beards on the side.
Scott: Yeah, all right, and there's a really really fat guy who looks like Taft.
Scott: the fat guy says Pie.
Scott: I demand pie key lime banana cream cherry apple or meringue.
Scott: The normal guy says how tragic a victim of society's scorn you cope with the stigma by drowning your sorrows and further consumption.
Scott: the fat guy says as Interesting as your amateur analysis may be it fails in one important respect.
Scott: It does not in fact produce pie for me to eat.
Scott: The skinny guy says but I understand you I accept you for who you are.
Scott: The fat man says I'm a man who needs pie.
Scott: That is who I am Yeah, very penny arcade esque.
Rym: well certain I mean there's different types of penny arcade that is true.
Rym: It's the ones where taiko talks a lot penny arcade.
Scott: Yes, that is the type of penny arcade Type comic that this is and the entertainment value is high.
Rym: Yeah I've noticed that lately the comics we like the most at least web comic wise are the ones that we don't really.
Rym: I mean the art Is usually stylized or something?
Rym: but the dialogue is witty to the point of being stupid like overly witty dialogue a core something that Might have a moral or a lesson but probably doesn't.
Scott: mm-hmm like a boa says so if you're a fan of A penny arcade or top hats or poop jokes go to wondermark.com right now.
Rym: Yep now right along those lines another hilarious little comic that we were turned on to is the mighty Skullboy army by Jacob Shabbat Shabbat Chabot Shabbot J bot.
Rym: I don't know CH a BOT.
Rym: Sorry Jacob Yeah, he's from beetle bug comics.
Rym: now that I bought the little 50 cent comic and you go bought the bigger one And there's a whole bunch of in my rental.
Rym: I read as much of this as I could get my hands on.
Rym: It's just hilarious.
Scott: It is pretty freaking hilarious.
Rym: It's just this little Skullboy who honestly His personality is almost identical to black mage from 8-bit theater.
Scott: He reminds me sort of a black mage but also sort of a Dexter or a mandark from Dexter's lab.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Yes or Did you ever watch?
Scott: there was that other Cartoon Network show that was more recent that had the grim reaper on it?
Scott: And there was the girl in that show Sort of like that girl only Not as you know in Like one aspect of her not the whole character.
Scott: Yeah, she was really smart and whatever.
Scott: but yeah you get the idea and it's just.
Rym: it's very Simple and very hilarious and I'm not sure how much else I could say about it.
Rym: You really just have to read it.
Scott: It's a skull boy and he has an army which consists of a stupid robot and a smart monkey kind of and for a brief period an intern yes, and He's in school, but you know, he has his army.
Scott: that does things and it's just hilarious situations and craziness.
Rym: So if you're into that sort of thing Now also I ran into webcomic artist wise one of my favorite webcomic artist John Allison who does a scary-go-round.
Scott: It's that comic you like.
Rym: Yeah, I Recommend to everyone out there at least read a little bit of scary-go-round.
Rym: You might like it.
Rym: You might not but I Absolutely adore it and all I can really say about John Allison is that he is the most charmingly British person I've ever met.
Scott: Oh, he's British.
Rym: Yeah The comic is really really unique and it has that same kind of good dialogue thing going with it.
Rym: Plus of course, he signed the little book.
Rym: I brought from him.
Scott: Hooray Is it a book of scary-go-round comics?
Scott: Of course, is it like from the beginning?
Scott: or what is it?
Rym: It's from mostly the beginning.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: Did he have books for all of his scary-go-round?
Rym: He had a whole bunch of books.
Rym: I would have bought more but as you know because I borrowed money from you to buy this book I didn't have so much cash on me at the time.
Scott: Oh, yeah, you owe me 20 bucks.
Scott: I didn't take back.
Rym: I'll give you 20 bucks after we do the show.
Scott: Hey better Okay Another guy people we met were Dale Baron and David Hellman Writer and artist.
Scott: of a lesson is learned Had the damage is irreversible, which is a fantastic web comic.
Rym: It's more.
Rym: it's art it's it's not.
Rym: it's all art Yeah, but it's not.
Rym: I'm trying to think of what I would classify it as it is a comic in that there are you know?
Scott: Panels some to kind of and There is characters a dialogue in those panels kind of.
Rym: I'd say it's experimental But usually when someone uses that term for art what they actually mean is bad.
Rym: Yes, and I don't mean bad.
Scott: Yeah Instead of making a comic book with you know pages and pages of stuff with every single one of their Comics is more like a poster and that you they even sell it like that.
Scott: You don't buy a book of all their stuff you buy a poster of the one comic they did that you like.
Rym: in fact I bought a poster of one of my favorite comics they did about solipsistic cat.
Scott: Well, you tried to buy it online.
Rym: I tried to buy it online months and months ago as a gift and they just never responded in my email.
Rym: So when I explained that to them at the con they were like, oh, we're so sorry Uh-huh, and then I bought it from them and it was awesome.
Scott: Yep So, you know every they do basically one-shots didn't?
Scott: they once have some continuity Like between two or three of them.
Scott: every now and then there's a little bit a little tiny bit but usually it's they make one big thing and it's it's pretty short and meaningful and Really cleverly drawn.
Scott: but at the con they had this thing printed on a piece of paper.
Scott: that I think is hilarious.
Scott: And it's it's bitches and hoes.
Scott: now it's be bitches bit c h e z and ampersand hoes h o s e.
Rym: It's little dogs who are firemen little female dogs who are firemen.
Rym: It's their comics are like that.
Scott: I mean it is and hoes firemen hoes and This particular comic that they gave out for free was is called in the shower and basically the fire they show up.
Scott: and Well, it's.
Scott: I can read this part Bitches and hoes.
Scott: since you're the only all-female puppies fire squad will be up to you to rescue the burning building where pretty ladies go To shower and clean their delicate bodies in the nude.
Scott: the next panel is dogs standing next to a fire hose spraying water at a fire and all around the fire are Pretty naked ladies going.
Scott: teehee.
Rym: This is in fact the comic where we got the word bargo from that we use so often.
Scott: Oh is it?
Scott: Yeah, I thought we just made that up.
Scott: No.
Rym: No, I think we still.
Rym: we got it indirectly from the comic though Bargo apparently is a guy having a heart attack and not someone vomiting.
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: And then at the end of this comic they randomly invite the bitches and hoes to a Passover Seder Which is which is pretty funny because apparently I forget which one of the guys The other writer or the artist but I talked to him a bit about.
Scott: I was like, hey you Jewish He's like, yeah, so now, you know meeting more atheist Jews every day.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Yeah You know, they were also.
Rym: they were just really If you if you read their comic You'll probably have a idea in your head of what kind of people they are.
Rym: and if you meet them, they're exactly like that.
Rym: Yep, they they they're the same.
Rym: They're exactly the kind of people you would expect to write a comic like this.
Scott: I Didn't really try to.
Scott: I didn't.
Scott: I never thought about what they would be like.
Scott: You know when I read the comic but once I met them, uh, you know, I was like, oh you're the guys to do that.
Rym: I really wanted to interview them because I have a lot of like.
Rym: I could do a whole show just asking them about this comic and what they do and why and how.
Rym: but Honestly, it was really too loud to do anything like that at the mocha art festival.
Scott: Yeah It was cramped.
Rym: Yeah, if I had had a booth or something, but now I just had my little microphone.
Scott: Yeah There was a podcast there that had a booth indie spinner rack Which I listened to a few episodes of and it's pretty good.
Scott: What they do is they?
Scott: their comics podcast only about independent comics and they'll interview independent comic artists and writers and they'll they'll review the latest independent comics that are popular.
Scott: and so if you're interested in Non-underwear pervert comics And we don't talk about them enough or frequently enough on GeekNights So you can listen to indie spinner rack and they will cover the non-underwear pervert comics for you.
Rym: quite Now another thing that I didn't even notice it.
Rym: I was just walking around and I finally I was looking at someone's table and I saw this book called the collected prison funnies By chips d'arski and it said at the bottom for mature readers and has a little picture of a so obviously a prisoner on it.
Rym: So I figure all right.
Rym: This is interesting.
Rym: I really like Oz.
Rym: I like dark humor.
Rym: Let's see what this has got and It was absolutely hilarious.
Rym: I am quite pleased with it.
Rym: It was a whole bunch of like newspaper comics only there were horrible and about prison I mean one of them like a riot breaks out and it's just three panels of violence.
Scott: Yeah, that's it I Mean.
Rym: I don't want to rue or try to read them or spoil the humor from them But they're.
Rym: I really enjoyed this.
Rym: and then there's a whole bunch of guest comics where other artists did prison comics.
Rym: And then there's two full-on short story comics at the end.
Rym: That's cool all that.
Rym: and this was like three bucks four bucks Awesome, and this is the guy who when Scott prompted me to buy all his stuff He said only buy one now buy the rest later.
Scott: Yeah, he had more funny prison stories.
Scott: You should have bought them all.
Rym: I'm gonna order them all from his side.
Rym: I just haven't gotten a chance to yet.
Scott: That's a good idea.
Rym: It's really good.
Scott: Really isn't comic really dark?
Rym: and apparently there's a lot of other stuff in the book Like he talks about how it was popular in prisons actually among prisoners.
Rym: oh Yeah, there's.
Rym: the book is really well worth it.
Rym: At least the first one.
Rym: There's a lot of extra content other than just the comic.
Scott: Yeah, that reminds me of another comic I saw there that didn't really look that interesting and I don't forget who did it But it was they had.
Scott: he had true stories of Like undersea disaster and then true stories of wild animal disaster.
Scott: Oh, yeah, it's sort of like those Fox shows like world's worst animal.
Rym: world's blankie is blank.
Scott: Yeah, world's blankie is blank of comic books.
Scott: and he had a comic and the whole comic was just drawn in graphic form panels and whatnot.
Scott: True story is a hundred percent true.
Scott: He checked out to make sure they were all true.
Scott: He said he just kind of looked him up on the internet of real times that you know an animal mauled a person or a fish a shark bit someone or all that kind of stuff.
Scott: and I just remember that because I talked to that guy and this reminded me of that because it's also sort of true prison stories.
Scott: Yeah, true animal mauling stories.
Scott: Yeah world's blankie is blank of comics.
Rym: I Also ran into at one point a booth of with a girl at it and she said that the comic like she told me this comic right here is the dirtiest comic at this entire event.
Rym: and I said, all right I'm game.
Rym: and I opened it up and I flipped through it and it was indeed the dirtiest comic at that entire name.
Scott: one Horrible thing that was in it.
Rym: Just just naked people killing people dogs exploding Breasts, it was just insane.
Scott: each of the killer worse or better?
Rym: I couldn't say worse only because it wasn't that realistic.
Rym: Uh-huh, but nothing can really get more realistic than each of the killer.
Scott: Each of the killer isn't really realistic.
Rym: I think well, it's realistic.
Rym: in terms of the portrayal.
Rym: Yeah, I mean it looks like they're doing what they're doing.
Rym: I guess We should do a show on each of the killer.
Rym: ooh tomorrow We could talk about yeah Okay, yeah, we got a thing.
Rym: we do tell the whole story of that.
Scott: oh, that's a good idea.
Rym: That was a good story.
Scott: We could that could be a fable.
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: All right.
Scott: So, let's see who else is there.
Scott: the guy Andy runton who does owlee was there.
Rym: owlee is fantastic.
Rym: I I just I love owlee.
Rym: It's very sweet and innocent and it's not really.
Scott: and as soon as I saw the guy I was like, that's the owlee guy, isn't it?
Scott: He was just like this jovial kind of happy dude.
Rym: Yeah, he just looks really tall and good-natured And he was very good-natured.
Scott: very it was extremely good-natured.
Rym: He had but it was only the prototype or something.
Rym: But he had a stuffed owlee with a wormy on its head and I really wanted it But it was obvious that he only had the one.
Scott: he had owlee t-shirts and all his books and he had the free comic book that he gave out in free comic book day.
Scott: and You know you just talking all kinds of people hanging out drawing out leaves for people just having a good time.
Scott: Now not owlee isn't for everyone honestly, it's it's like a nursery school comic.
Scott: Yeah, it really isn't particularly full of depth and allegory But you know one thing is that that I always like to point out.
Scott: is it nowadays if you look at kids television?
Scott: It's really only kids television.
Scott: adults really can't watch Teletubbies.
Scott: It's painful.
Scott: You know what I'm saying?
Scott: You can't watch Power Rangers.
Scott: It's painful.
Scott: It's stuff like owlee or stuff like the Sesame Street that I watched when I was a kid or even stuff like Rocky and Bullwink Furola, Furola Kappa, Furola Kappa.
Scott: Yes stuff like Furola Kappa or stuff like that Japanese show with the With the Rube Goldberg machines.
Scott: Oh, yeah, you know kids watch it cuz it's it's meant for them But it's all ages.
Scott: anyone can enjoy it and I really really like all ages stuff.
Rym: Now actually all ages a lot anything that says all ages.
Rym: in America It usually means aimed at little kids and only for little kids.
Scott: Yes, I Say that, you know if something is meant for kids and adults won't enjoy it It should say kids.
Rym: but at the same time I really don't like things that adults can't enjoy that are designed for kids because that's really just dumbing things down for kids Which isn't going to serve them?
Scott: Well, yep, if I have kids, I don't want them to look at the stupid for kids shit.
Scott: I want them to have the all-ages shit, which is something everyone can enjoy.
Rym: But it just seems that a lot of people on this Mario everyone can enjoy Mario.
Scott: Yeah, Mario's all ages You know.
Scott: and another good example of all ages actually is an underwear pervert.
Scott: if you go read Marvel adventures Spider-man, which is the spider-man comic that has nothing to do with all the bullshit and it's just the one that you're supposed to give Your kids.
Scott: it's actually really good no matter what age you are And it's printed in you know, manga digest format for cheapness nah and color because it's spider-man.
Scott: spider-man He's not gay.
Rym: No, no way.
Scott: Let's see.
Scott: What else did we see at mocha?
Scott: There were.
Scott: there were some good independent publishers there the Audi publisher top shelf.
Scott: They have a lot of good stuff.
Scott: top shelf Pantheon.
Scott: they print like all the greats like they print the rabbi's cat which is up for an Eisner.
Scott: Not even one one.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: they print Mouse.
Scott: They you know all the great Graphic novels they print.
Scott: that's that's Pantheon books, you know the the stuff that's literature, you know I mean if there's a will.
Scott: Eisner pretty much invented writing a Graphic novel as a work of literature as opposed to you know Just a comic book or whatever.
Scott: and he died recently.
Scott: and and it's kind of sad that not too many people followed suit in writing graphic works of literature.
Scott: But some did in there, you know, they're pretty much all really awesome.
Scott: And if they exist Pantheon books is likely the publisher.
Scott: So that's another good company to look out for The webcomic companies or a day fee press day free press and umbrella, right?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, at least I forget which one does which stuff.
Rym: Yeah If there's anyone we met who we forgot to mention It's just because we'd forgot to pick up a business card or we we just forgot.
Rym: We're sorry.
Rym: We met a lot of cool people.
Scott: Yeah, there were a whole lot of people to meet and in one day we really couldn't you know, really meet everyone.
Rym: Yeah Especially since a lot of these people were people that we knew of but we'd never actually seen.
Rym: Yeah as a result we met a whole bunch of people and we forgot half of them.
Scott: You know, maybe if we would have spent all weekend there We could have you know gone to each and every spot and you know had a big old conversation with everyone.
Scott: But you know, we had to go home.
Scott: We had stuff to do.
Rym: Yeah, we did.
Scott: Yeah Anything else going down there?
Rym: Well, we had.
Rym: we finally have a good passable GeekNights flyer to pass out of cons.
Rym: Oh, that's true because while yuko was here for the weekend We had the stick figure flyer that I had made at an amazement.
Rym: well, I had commissioned someone to make at an amazement and then I had modified and She couldn't stand for that.
Rym: So she made us an awesome awesome awesome GeekNights flyer that once we have the final version will put up on the site one so she can get credit for it and Two so anyone who feels so inclined can bring it to their favorite convention with them.
Scott: Yeah, we got a. I gotta get a scanner and go down to my parents house because they have two and they're not using either One.
Rym: Yeah, my scanner doesn't work anymore.
Scott: So I'll get a skull ghost to get the scanner for my parents house.
Scott: Then we could scan the flyer in Fire in digital format.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, so maybe we'll just throw it up on the website and then if you want you can print out GeekNights flyers and Give them to all your friends family and post them up around town and all that good stuff.
Rym: Yep, mostly because intent because until now we've never advertised.
Scott: Yes until now.
Scott: The only promotion the GeekNights is done is Is Being places.
Rym: that's really it.
Scott: places at conventions talking to other podcasters mostly other podcasters talking to us and also You know telling our friends to tell other people and of course the podcast itself Google, etc, etc.
Scott: It's yeah.
Rym: And while I mean we we have a graph now that we have we have enough listeners now to where the statistics we get are Meaningful and it's a steady upward stream.
Rym: Like it's a perfect correlation.
Scott: Yep So we're going to soon create the first long delayed GeekNights promo clip of audio.
Scott: Yeah for other podcasts to play and we're actually going to start a push to promote GeekNights and get as many listeners as we Can because you know that there are thousands upon thousands of people out there who would love to listen to you.
Scott: guys Just don't know about it or you know don't care.
Rym: Well, especially since some of our listeners have pointed out to us that and this is not our opinion this is our listeners because as Full of ourselves as we are I would really be uncomfortable making this sort of statement about myself.
Rym: But other people who listen to our show have told us That they like our show a lot more than they like a lot of the other very highly ranked podcasts.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: So if you are a listener of GeekNights and a big fan and not just you know Listening for the first time but if you're listening the first time and you like what you hear that's good enough.
Scott: Now is the time to start Helping us promote GeekNights in whatever small or big way you can.
Rym: Yep It's basically a ramp up until Otakon when most likely we'll do a big show and then from there We're going to go to the con.
Rym: I mean this year we're doing the convention circuit mostly as attendees and press.
Rym: Next year going around we're basically going to be guests and panelists at almost every single freaking convention.
Scott: Yep so You know do what you can tell other podcasts about us post about us in your blog.
Scott: Tell your friends and family Vote for us and all those stupid things even though I hate the stupid voting shit.
Scott: Yeah, God It's a don't.
Scott: vote for us in those things because I hate those things but also But also vote for us in those things because it actually does do something as people do.
Scott: look there.
Scott: Yeah Write reviews of our show on places like iTunes and and The reviews I actually like because that means something.
Scott: the stupid voting mechanism just means that you got your listeners to sit around all day Clicking and changing IP addresses and clicking again.
Scott: Yeah or writing bots to do that or writing bots Yeah, but the reviews mean something.
Scott: cuz that means someone thought about it and they you know They wrote about our show and gave us a star ranking even a bad reviews better than no review.
Rym: Yeah, cuz we want negative feedback.
Rym: if anyone's got it we have it.
Scott: I'm still waiting for the first GeekNights' hate mail.
Rym: Yeah, because we've tried.
Scott: we've tried to offend as many people as we could and it seems like when we offend people They they either just keep their mouths shut or maybe they don't exist or they just leave without saying anything.
Scott: I don't know at best.
Rym: We had someone respectfully disagree and we had a good argument as a result.
Scott: Yeah We need someone to be like, yeah, you guys are going to hell bla bla bla.
Scott: That's what I'm looking for.
Rym: Yeah, maybe some Luddites will come out of the woodwork.
Scott: You like Rym.
Scott: Yeah Rym the Luddite.
Rym: Yeah, we've obviously done talking about mocha because we slipped into the meta bits at the end.
Scott: Yep, so if you like comics and you are anywhere near New York City next year You should go to the Museum of Comic and Cartoon Art Arts Festival because it is ta awesome.
Rym: Yep, and of course on GeekNights the site keep an eye out for the updated site artwork Which at some point in the future hopefully before the 200th episode is going to be up.
Scott: Yep and also keep a lookout for the GeekNights promo to play on your podcast.
Rym: keep an eye out for The night's promotional flyer to print out and toss around your town and it won't be too long once we finalize the logo and the artwork and everything where we'll have GeekNights swag, which we will sell at Cost basically.
Scott: Yep, and keep an eye on the forum for pretty much everything Especially how half-life 2 works in wine and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.