Scott: It's Tuesday September 26th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Scott: We discuss the old board game Stratego.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So today, I realized the next week.
Scott: I only have to work three days.
Rym: Theoretically I only have to work four days.
Rym: They haven't actually told me if I get Friday off or not.
Scott: Really, yeah, worst case.
Rym: I'll come Friday evening on my own.
Scott: Okay, because on Monday is the Jew holiday Yom Kippur Which is the day where you don't eat and all your sins go away, and I don't believe any of that.
Scott: but I'm gonna take off Rovonika and Friday is Sittacon.
Rym: Yeah, so once again we're gonna plug it all week this week and next week because we're going and While we have gone to many cons as GeekNights and as other things This is the first con that is offered to pay our whole way.
Scott: Hooray for Sittacon.
Rym: Not just our badge in or hotel.
Scott: Yes, Sittacon is the SUNY IT Anime Club convention.
Scott: It is an anime con in Utica, New York, and it is pretty cool.
Rym: Did you sound any less enthusiastic?
Rym: That was like the most horrible.
Scott: I'm just cuz.
Scott: I'm just giving the information now.
Rym: Whatever.
Rym: It's gonna be awesome.
Rym: We're doing a whole crazy ton of stuff at this camp.
Scott: We're running a game show and we're doing panels.
Scott: We're doing what?
Rym: three panels?
Scott: Yeah, we're doing an artist alley table and we're doing all sorts of crazy batshit like this con.
Rym: So if you're anywhere near you should go now, I know we have a good number of listeners back at RIT.
Rym: It's not that far from you guys.
Scott: It's only like two to three hours ish.
Rym: Yeah, probably two hours I mean, it's a little bit past Syracuse on the Thruway.
Scott: Yep, that's that it's you know, right in the middle of New York State, you know equidistant from anywhere in the entire state.
Scott: so if you're in New York State or Southern Ontario or Western Connecticut, Massachusetts Vermont New Hampshire Something like that.
Rym: Yeah, that was great Scott.
Rym: Yeah Pretty much.
Rym: if you live within a few hours this place I'd highly recommend you go because one.
Rym: it's one of those small Anime cons that's just starting out and they're almost always awesome because the only people who go to them tend to be awesome people Yep, and they tend to be really cheap.
Scott: The other thing is I've spoken to the guy running the con.
Scott: They sound like they know what they're doing.
Scott: So I really doubt it's gonna be one of those.
Scott: Oh people tried to run a con, but they screwed it up deals.
Rym: Well, they've got their act together more than at least half of the cons.
Rym: I've been talking to in recent memory.
Scott: I know if you look at the guests they've collected.
Scott: I mean they collected a bunch of podcasters, which isn't hard.
Rym: They got entertainment system.
Scott: They got entertainment system and they got the video game pianist guy, which you know just shows.
Scott: Hey, they they're up to something now.
Rym: No, we actually have a relevant anecdote about entertainment system.
Scott: Yeah, we do.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know if I think I'll save it.
Rym: Yeah, I'll save it for next week the pregame.
Scott: Okay, we'll save it.
Scott: Regardless go if you're thinking about going www.s.
Scott: I ta con.
Scott: Sit a con like sit a con it really whips the llama's ass.
Rym: Really we're there we're we're.
Scott: we're really whips the llama's ass.
Rym: whatever it's video game day.
Scott: Yeah, it is.
Rym: I'll let your news go first because my news is a is a Jack Thompson news.
Scott: Oh god That's all right.
Scott: I think half of your news is Jack Thompson and Sony news.
Rym: You know what on video game day it is because there's not much other video game news I care about.
Rym: I mean, I'm not gonna report on rumors about the Wii or Rumors about the PlayStation 3 or rumors about any.
Scott: I'm not gonna report on rumors about anything either.
Rym: But and I was gonna talk about white knight because penny arcade went nuts about this game and so did half the internet.
Rym: But while the trailer was really pretty and it looked really cool There is absolutely not enough information to say anything valuable about this game.
Scott: No, there was other than that.
Rym: It was very pretty.
Scott: Yep Alright, so I want someone to go and look in the archives of front row crew comm and find out how many times Rym has made a Sony news and how many times he's out of Jack Thompson news.
Scott: So we get a little tally going up here, you know on the virtual chalkboard.
Scott: That is the forum.
Rym: Well, remember they both have the same standard.
Rym: they have to do something crazier than something they've already done.
Scott: Alright anyway Everyone knows that, you know Nintendo seems to be getting it on with opera, you know they have an opera browser for the DS that costs 30 bucks and it comes a little flashcard and whatever and I don't know if that's out yet in this country.
Scott: But it's gonna be for sure.
Scott: and the Wii is gonna have opera for your web browsing pleasure.
Scott: But it was just announced today a hundred percent sure not a rumor that Opera for the Wii will be free until June of 2007.
Scott: So if you get a Wii before June of 2007, you can download opera and install it on your Wii For nothing.
Scott: just click there it is now.
Rym: think of this not so much for us as gamers because many of us gamer types probably already have a computer plugged Into the TV and it's not a big deal.
Rym: We run our emulators there and everything But we're not the focus of all these things.
Rym: They're putting in the Wii.
Rym: Imagine normal people to whom if you showed them a computer booked up to a TV with an emulator and a web browser They wouldn't know what to think.
Rym: They just go nuts.
Scott: Well, here's another thing.
Scott: I want to point out is that The Wii first of all, the wiimote is a is a very good pointing device, you know.
Scott: Which is good for using a browser - people are really familiar with using a remote control.
Scott: So if they can use a remote control device to browse the web You know, my grandma has a hard time using a web browser because she's an old grandma.
Scott: But if she had a remote control to browse the web, I imagine she'd have a much better time of it.
Rym: I know that my grandpa has absolutely no trouble surfing the web.
Scott: Yeah, my grandpa also kind of doesn't.
Scott: it's mostly that They don't know what they should do.
Scott: You know, not that they don't know how to do it as much.
Scott: I mean, they really don't know.
Scott: but anyway also We currently have a computer plugged into our TV a Mac Mini with Firefox and that's all well and good for browsing the web But it's not perfect for browsing the web on a TV.
Scott: I mean you can't maximize things on a Mac.
Scott: You can't full-screen Firefox on the Mac.
Rym: There are ways around that.
Rym: We just haven't.
Scott: there are ways around it and you know, you have to keep adjusting font sizes.
Scott: But if if I had a Wii and I had opera on it I would probably end up using that to browse the web a lot more especially since it'll have flash and all this other stuff.
Scott: You know playing flash games with the wiimote.
Rym: Hello Well beside all that I mean once again to all the normal people out there.
Rym: So, I mean this is a crazy thing.
Rym: you buy this Wii.
Rym: it's 250 bucks.
Rym: It's a next-gen console.
Rym: additionally, it checks the weather for you and It effectively emulates all of the functionality of web TV and more.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty badass Very badass.
Scott: and I'm actually you know, the weather thing.
Scott: at first I'm like weather.
Scott: What are they talking about?
Scott: But I'm probably gonna use that weather a lot because all the weather checking I do on my computer either takes too much effort.
Scott: You know visit a website type in the zip code, press enter.
Rym: wait Scott you realize that you can just go into the widgets on the Mac, which is also right there and see the weather.
Scott: I know but not like.
Scott: not with the maps and everything, you know, it's not the full weather It's just the summary.
Rym: there are widgets that do that.
Scott: Yeah, but yeah It'd be like it'd be easier to turn on the Wii with the remote control.
Rym: or you know The Mac that's already on and has a remote control.
Scott: the remote control doesn't do the widgets.
Rym: you can fucks with remote control.
Scott: I didn't know how to fucks with the remote control already.
Scott: It's more effort.
Scott: The point is is while we might be able to do that You know with a little bit of effort it now requires no effort, which is good for dumb people.
Rym: I guess in general the Wii is just coming out gangbusters.
Rym: I mean, they're gonna have a million units at launch in the US alone.
Rym: It's real cheap.
Rym: It's got this crazy launch lineup.
Rym: I can't imagine better news to come out.
Scott: Yeah, I mean the thing I wonder though is opera unlike Mozilla opera is a profit company, aren't they?
Scott: And they used to make their money.
Scott: they're putting ads in opera But now they give opera away for free which they kind of have to do to compete with Firefox.
Rym: Well considering up one of the main things opera always claims to have going forward and a lot of people agree Is that it?
Rym: Generally is better for devices that don't have the best displays because of the way it handles scaling and that sort of thing.
Scott: yeah, opera is basically making their money by making versions of opera for non computers.
Scott: if it's not a Computer opera is makes a version for it.
Scott: They've got like opera palm Opera for any, you know little weird cell phone.
Rym: now I'll bet that Nintendo and opera have some sort of deal where Nintendo probably didn't pay very much if anything Because this is a lot of press for opera it is but I still wonder where exactly the money comes from.
Scott: I mean sure if someone buys opera DS opera gets money and I'm pretty sure that when opera is no longer Free on the Wii that if you have to pay for it They'll get money or what?
Rym: if I mean how for-profit is opera?
Rym: how much money do they make?
Rym: is that public?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I had to look that up.
Rym: They could be like ghost script where they're for-profit, but yet they don't make any money.
Scott: I'm gonna really I'm gonna think I'm gonna spend tomorrow like Google's new charity.
Rym: don't think technically they're for-profit because it's easier that way.
Scott: Yeah, I think tomorrow I'm gonna do some research into how opera makes money and how much money they make and I'll come back with a report.
Rym: So Jack Thompson.
Rym: Oh, I love you.
Rym: You provide so much joy.
Scott: Wait a minute.
Scott: Rym loves old man.
Scott: write this down.
Rym: You know, I killed a man in Reno once just to watch him die.
Rym: Yeah All right anyway Jack Thompson.
Rym: now the the news itself is not the issue here because the news is some kid played a bunch of Grand Theft Auto Went nuts shot some people and now there's a 600 million dollar lawsuit against the makers of Grand Theft Auto Vice City, which they claim he played Obsessively claiming that basically this game caused him to do it now 600 million dollars and claiming that this game the game that they allowed him to play Obsessively
Scott: game they bought for him
Rym: the game they bought for him and allowed him to play kid 14
Scott: Uh-huh, and was the game rated M
Rym: Yep,
Scott: so even if I was take two when I lost this lawsuit to Jack Thompson Which the chances of are basically nil because Jack Thompson doesn't want a lawsuit in his life as far as I know At least not everyone that mattered.
Scott: Well, can I would just counter sue the parents?
Rym: Now now that's it.
Rym: I mean they talk about how he obsessively played the game for several months before he shot all these people.
Rym: is that in the state custody whatever?
Rym: Now the quotes around this trial are the actual news here because if they hadn't said these things I would let this slide.
Rym: This wasn't a big deal.
Scott: All right, bring on the funny quotes.
Scott: I will rate them on a scale of one to five five being hilarious pee in my pants one being.
Rym: Now I'll begin with the obvious one because he says this all the time Grand Theft Auto series depict police killings and other acts of violence.
Rym: a lawsuit calls Here we go virtual reality murder simulators.
Rym: Jack Thompson has said that phrase more than he said any other phrase ever.
Scott: Yeah, I'll give it a two just because a lot of people don't know.
Scott: Jack Thompson says that now.
Rym: now here's a nice one.
Rym: But for the kids use of these products he would not have killed.
Rym: Five because it's false Straight up in perfect logic that because he used Grand Theft Auto He killed and if he had not used it, he would not have killed Quo-quo.
Scott: if they could demonstrate that in a court of law, I will eat my hat.
Scott: Good cuz I had to go buy a hat now.
Rym: This is the part.
Rym: I mean there's a whole bunch of quotes in here, but this is my favorite one.
Rym: the game trained him.
Rym: quotes How to point and shoot a gun in a fashion making him an extraordinarily effective killer Without teaching any of the restraints constraints and responsibilities needed to inhibit such a killing capacity.
Rym: ten But before I you know laugh hysterically I want to try to say that.
Rym: well if this were true Let's say that Jack Thompson is right.
Rym: Let's say that that sentence and everything.
Rym: He said is correct.
Rym: That means that by playing counter-strike through college.
Rym: I am a dangerous motherfucker now.
Scott: You'd better watch out for me.
Scott: I'm coming to freaking hose everyone down the cops on people to touch me.
Rym: Yeah I mean according to this lawsuit Scott and I could single-handedly if I had a Mac 10 and Scott had an mp5 and a Desert Eagle take out the entirety of the law enforcement in the United States.
Scott: Only the only problems we could have is running out of ammo and/or money to buy more ammo other than that.
Scott: Are you pretty invincible?
Rym: you get money every time you kill someone?
Scott: Yeah, dude, you better freakin lock up fatality.
Scott: He's gonna kill everyone.
Scott: Why don't we just send?
Scott: Fatality, you know, what's his name?
Scott: Jason Wendell, right?
Scott: Whatever Fatality, why don't we send fatality call back the army call back the Air Force?
Scott: Just give fatality a truck full of weapons and send him over to Iraq and he will kill every Terrorist and no one will be able to stop him.
Rym: Hello, duh Yeah, they also claim now that here's just another funny quote.
Rym: There's a two-quote two-word quote here talking about, you know, Sony of America.
Rym: take to its subsidiary rockstar games.
Rym: The lawsuit accuses all of these companies of a quote civil Conspiracy.
Rym: oh my god That's all I got.
Scott: if there was a civil conspiracy right then how come Sony and take to haven't hired Fatality to go kill Nintendo and Microsoft and their competitors.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I mean, there's no way they'd even know he did it cuz he'd be so badass and playing all those ninja games No one would see him.
Rym: Well, I gotta say yeah, dude.
Scott: I played Ninja Gaiden when I was a kid.
Scott: You can't see me.
Scott: Can you?
Scott: I have such ninja skills.
Scott: I might.
Scott: I can go be bad Scott.
Rym: You have no idea.
Rym: I am a bad enough, dude.
Scott: Are you a bad enough dude to rescue the president?
Scott: I must be because I played through half of bad dudes at one point in the arcade.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I actually really didn't like the game bad dude.
Scott: The bad dudes is a bad game.
Rym: I came sucked.
Rym: it did suck.
Scott: But the point is as I played Street Fighter and hung in a sonic boom you to God knows where.
Rym: sonic boom.
Rym: things of the day.
Rym: This one's gonna be nice and quick here.
Rym: It's a video that I think you should all watch now.
Rym: I'm sure everyone is familiar with the - world in Super Mario Brothers.
Scott: If you don't know what the - world is crack lack.
Rym: if you don't know - world is get the fuck out.
Scott: You don't know shit anyway.
Rym: So now Mario Brothers wasn't just released for the Famicom in the NES It was also released for the Famicom disk system.
Scott: Yeah, a lot of people don't realize this.
Scott: in Japan There was a very popular Famicom disk system Which is an NES where the games came on disks and there were a lot of games released for that that are very important.
Rym: so a Supposedly this video here on Kotaku is of what happens if you go into the - world in this slightly updated version of Super Mario Brothers.
Rym: the - world is Crazy and amazing and I guess the one thing this illustrates since a lot of my things of the day have illustrated various things lately Is that two types of people.
Rym: well I guess three types of people watch the video.
Rym: type a type one won't have any idea what the hell's going on.
Rym: You know 90 year olds and Jack Thompson Type two or beta will see this and think all right.
Rym: He did something glitchy with the video game Whatever.
Rym: and the third type of people will just be utterly amazed Especially when they see the third world and they'll whoa check out.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: And they just won't shut up about it.
Scott: and I'm the third type as am I all right.
Rym: So this is a nice test will show this video to people and see how they react.
Rym: you can tell whether or not they're a true gamer Mmm.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So this video is actually posted in the forum I think by water is poison and I think it's good enough to make a thing of the day.
Rym: It quite is it is.
Scott: it's called Farid or D&D or like the Battle of Farid or whatever and it's a short D&D live-action movie, you know like 12 minutes long sort of like that fear of girls, you know a little short movie about D&D playing
Rym: a lower cell for say ah
Scott: Yes, these guys they are from Quebec With the French Canadian.
Scott: In fact, it's on goo.
Scott: It's on video google.ca for Canada.
Scott: Anyway, what happens in this video is?
Scott: This guy goes to meet up with some old friends He used to play D&D with to play some D&D like the good old times and the DM is a cool, dude and he's a cool dude, you know, but the other two guys playing are sort of super serious about D&D and Conflict occurs as a result
Rym: Boba Fett.
Rym: Yeah, Boba Fett It's funny up until a moment when you think one thing is going to happen and then yeah There is one thing that happens in it.
Scott: That's sort of disturbing like It's not disturbing.
Scott: It's more like oh
Rym: I just started cracking up because yeah
Scott: But I think the point of this video is that not only is it hilarious but it illustrates in very plain terms This is bad D&D and this is good D&D and it can show people even if they haven't played D&D before.
Scott: See D&D is.
Scott: it looks like this the stereotype but really it can be like this.
Scott: That's the good stuff.
Scott: That's what we do and that's what those nerds do.
Rym: Yeah, I mean there are different.
Rym: I mean Baron pretzels.
Rym: D&D has its place.
Rym: Yeah, but there are honestly some people out there take it way too seriously.
Scott: Yeah, I'm not talking about here's the thing.
Rym: They don't even take it seriously.
Rym: in like a serious role-playing way.
Rym: There are people who take it seriously.
Rym: in this just scary kind of.
Rym: you could reach eighth level tonight.
Scott: Yeah, I'm not talking about it.
Scott: good D&D and bad D&D.
Scott: in first of you know, having fun versus you know Seriously being in a fantasy world.
Scott: I'm talking about, you know, the attitudes toward the game being good and bad.
Scott: You know one guy has the right attitude towards D&D and the other two guys They have a bad attitude that make the game kind of sucky.
Rym: I know people and I know people who have known people who played the kind of D&D that you're seeing in this video.
Scott: Yeah, yep, and so I suggest that everyone go watch this and learn and laugh.
Rym: Also as a total aside just because we talked about it just a little while ago to make a long story short our group has been debating a lot about the nature of D&D lately because our recent D&Ding hasn't Been as great as it used to be
Scott: Mm-hmm,
Rym: and we realized Scott and I a little while ago while watching some other stupid video That wasn't good enough to be a thing of the day.
Rym: The key factor that we have lost The table the table in the middle of the room.
Rym: We stopped playing around a table and that's when everything went to hell.
Scott: Yeah, we've been playing D&D for like six or seven years just in a room with everyone laying down You know reclining on a couch or sitting in a different area of the room all about the place and we realized hey When you all sit at a table, it keeps everyone in the game.
Scott: It keeps everyone involved.
Scott: People aren't off in their own world.
Scott: people are you know, they're in physically and it makes a big difference.
Rym: Yep and I had all these flashbacks to like some of the best D&D games I had were even if they're not I had a table Everyone was sitting in a circle and everything was centralized and we're gonna do it.
Rym: We're gonna show in the future about D&D and how we play it and how to play.
Rym: but yeah We realized this just now and I think it is going to usher in a new era of.
Scott: I mean Look, we played that awesome burning wheel.
Scott: We were at a big table with a whole bunch of people around it.
Scott: Yeah, and that was key very key.
Scott: So I Recommend to everyone if you were playing any sort of tabletop role-playing game Don't leave out the table.
Rym: in the very least How could we have have a big room and sit in a circle in the room on the floor?
Scott: Yeah, don't let people lay all around the place like we've been, you know We got too casual and we realized now that that was probably or most likely the cause of much of our Not as good role-playing.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I've just now thought of a couple other little things, but that'll be another show.
Rym: Yep, because tonight we're talking about something so completely the opposite of D&D.
Scott: We're talking about a very old board game.
Scott: I think.
Scott: when did Stratego first get made like Early 20th century, right?
Rym: I believe it was invented by Leonardo da Vinci.
Scott: It wasn't real.
Rym: No, no Scott.
Scott: No I'm being silly.
Scott: You couldn't get the sarcastic tone of my voice.
Rym: No, because there have been times in the past where you were entirely non sarcastic about similar things.
Scott: Oh, well, I know that it wasn't made by.
Rym: well, uh for anyone who doesn't know what I'm talking about I'm gonna pull a Cromartie here and I suggest you look in the forums.
Scott: Oh, well, it says here The origins of Stratego can be traced back to traditional Chinese board game jungle Also known as game of fighting game of the fighting animals or animal chests.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Scott: Yep Yeah, there was a 1910 version that was French and it kind of yeah, so that's how old this game is 1908.
Scott: Yeah, it was what like five bucks.
Scott: This game was wicked cheap.
Scott: I mean I had a copy of Stratego when I was a kid as did I. that was the 90s version and you know It probably cost ten bucks and the new one is pretty similar.
Scott: It's a different production a different printing of the game.
Rym: We're gonna bitch about something in the new version that I think most of you who didn't grow up playing board games We'll just think we're idiots.
Scott: Alright, let let's.
Scott: I'm gonna start by giving a short description of the game because you could probably describe in great detail how the entire Game function.
Scott: Yeah, it is a very simple game.
Scott: You're ready.
Scott: There's a map.
Scott: The map is a bunch of squares and there what?
Scott: how many squares on each side?
Scott: One of the or five six seven a ten time forty squares on each side, whatever?
Rym: Yeah big grid with two sets of water in the middle that no one can walk.
Scott: There are two sets of water in the middle which means there's only three different pathways that connect one side to the other side and each of those pathways is four squares in a square.
Scott: and on one side You fill the map with blue pieces and the other mat side is filled with red pieces and they fight and one guy wins.
Scott: Now, how do you win?
Scott: capture the flag move one of your guys to the other side of the map?
Scott: Find the flag piece and Touch it and you win.
Scott: Now the thing is not.
Scott: every piece is the same.
Scott: some pieces.
Scott: There's one piece.
Scott: That's the flag.
Scott: there are some pieces with numbers on them and In the original version that we played when we were kids number one was the most powerful piece Yep, and number nine was the scout.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: nowadays in the version We just bought recently semi recently number ten is the most powerful piece and number two is the scout.
Scott: So the game isn't changed except they reverse the numbers to confuse us.
Rym: now the rationale.
Rym: I've heard a few people posit as to why they changed.
Rym: it was simply that people are dumb and Higher numbers should be more powerful because otherwise people don't get it and those people are stupid.
Rym: and yeah Yeah I got to say it.
Rym: It's weird how much that messes me up because I played the game as a kid and it's so ingrained in my head Like it's really sort of an arbitrary decision.
Scott: Like it wouldn't matter.
Scott: It's just the fact that we're used to one way.
Rym: I think eights I think eight.
Rym: so I keep seeing my eights which are now the kernels But I keep thinking they're miners and I have to force myself to think otherwise and I often put pieces where I didn't want to Put them.
Scott: Yeah, I'm starting to get used to the new system.
Scott: I'm generally a lot looking at the pictures a lot because the miners have the point on the head a little spear coming out of It you know, so anyway The way that so you have these guys and the very powerful guys the number ten the nine and the eight you don't have So many of those.
Scott: you have only one number ten guy one number nine guy two eights, you know, etc, etc.
Scott: But the scouts you have like a whole mess of them.
Scott: Now the other kind of piece you have is the bombs.
Scott: bombs don't move.
Scott: if Anyone touches a bomb they die unless they're a minor in which case they defuse the bomb.
Scott: So, obviously the way this game works is you have one you you put your flag on your side and you surround it with bombs.
Scott: if you don't it's stupid because someone's gonna come in and take it and then the other guy is forced to fight you and Also to find where your flag is.
Scott: Bring these weak weak units the miners all the way over to the other side of the map defuse the bombs and then find the flag.
Scott: and Yeah, it makes for a lot of fun To do this.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Now the game is not terribly strategically deep despite the name of the game being Stratego.
Rym: I mean it is until a point because there are a lot of gambits and a lot of chess like trees of decision-making in the game, however usually it's pretty obvious what you should do and There's really not a lot of actual intelligent decision-making.
Scott: in the end A lot of the game if you have two good players playing against each other to win.
Scott: a lot of it just comes down to The initial setup, you know if this guy sets it up initially like this and the other guys sets it up initially like that They might as well just turn over their pieces and say who wins.
Rym: Yep, because you need a clever setup and there's also a lot of psychology Because there is a lot of psych.
Rym: I mean the most powerful piece in the game is the ten or the one or the marshal Can kill anything on the board except if he kills.
Rym: if he hits a bomb he dies.
Rym: And of course if the spy attacks him he dies.
Scott: Yeah, there's one spy unit that's basically useless unless it attacks the number ten.
Rym: Now if the ten attacks it it dies.
Rym: only if it attacks the ten and if a ten attacks another ten they both die.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So you have got to.
Rym: the best way to win is to somehow get the other person to lose a high-ranking piece that you still Have because now that piece is utterly 100% invincible unless it attacks a bomb.
Scott: Yeah, for example Let's say Rym marches is nine forward and I attack it with my ten.
Scott: Now.
Scott: I have a ten and a nine and He doesn't have a ten.
Scott: Yeah, I still have a ten, but he doesn't have a nine.
Scott: So now I can run my nine around all willy-nilly and it's just as powerful as my ten But it doesn't have to fear the spy.
Rym: So it's not just as powerful because it can still be killed by my ten by the ten.
Scott: But then if I see your ten, I'll have no qualms about double suiciding it at all You know, well no because if you lose your nine to my ten and then you double suicide now, no No, it's if you've lost your nine and then our tens double suicide.
Scott: That's good for me.
Scott: Oh, yeah, that's what I'm saying.
Scott: That's what I said.
Rym: But there's a lot of psychology that I mean even down to the point.
Rym: the things I used to do a lot especially when I was a kid to beat my Brother at this game to beat my dad at this game and my friends is and I showed Scott all this He's like how you fucker but now he does it too.
Rym: Yeah, yeah is I'd move a piece.
Rym: I'll go from like the least bastardly to the most bastardly.
Rym: I'd move a piece as Though it were more powerful than it was like I know it's his ten.
Rym: I start moving up freaking two or three or four toward it and a lot of times the other person will back off.
Rym: Whoa, wait a minute Got it?
Rym: Got to be careful here and you can use pieces because every piece is equally threatening until you finally find out what it is.
Scott: Yeah, it's every piece on one side.
Scott: They all look the same.
Scott: the flag looks the same as a bomb looks the same as the ten looks the same as a two To the other guy.
Scott: He doesn't know what you've got and he doesn't know where it is.
Scott: So if you start moving around a four in the same way You would move it as if it were a spy.
Scott: The other guy might think it's spy and you can maybe bluff him out and thus bide some time to make another move on the other side of the board.
Rym: Yeah, and the obvious optimal strategies are pretty much just to be very defensive.
Rym: Don't move a piece if you don't have to because the moment I move a piece I have now told the other person that that piece is not a bomb and it's also not a flag.
Rym: Yes, it's not the bomb or the flag.
Rym: So us what if I say cuz this happened once in a game where I destroyed Scott's 10 with the spy I Still had my 10. that meant that my 10 could kill any piece on the board that moved with no danger.
Rym: So what I would do is I would wait for him to move a piece cuz you have to move a piece or you lose.
Rym: As soon as every time he moved a piece, I just chase it down with my one and kill it ten one.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, cuz he knows it's not a bomb and he knows it can't kill his ten.
Scott: So anything that moves he can kill and eventually with that process.
Scott: He's gonna kill everything I've got.
Rym: Yep, another very.
Scott: all I can do is trick him into moving it into a bomb.
Rym: now moving up from there.
Rym: Another very classic thing I would often do is I'd be think considering my turn and say I have two guys adjacent to one of Scott's Guys, one of those guys is a bomb that can't move and one of them is like a three.
Rym: now I'll sit there like I don't act like I'm considering my move and I'll Pick up the bomb or put my finger on the bomb like I'm gonna move it and then change my mind.
Rym: now Psychologically my opponent might think he was about to move that piece.
Rym: There's no way it's a bomb.
Rym: Haha, it's a bomb.
Scott: I don't think that at all.
Scott: I wait till I seen it move.
Scott: Yeah, yeah But other people might be fooled by that.
Rym: you can do the same thing with the scouts because scouts can move in any one direction unlimitedly.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So if you have a scout you can move it forward ten spaces and the point of the scout is not to hurt anything Cuz it really can't hurt anything.
Scott: It's to see what's up ahead.
Scott: So like let's say you've cleared out a lot of his side of the board and you you see a piece over there That hasn't moved.
Scott: you send your scout all the way to the end of the board in one turn.
Scott: You just say what's that and they'll say it's a bomb and then you know where to send your miners.
Scott: because that's what the bombs Are at, you know, that's the point of a scout.
Scott: Yep, but let's say you have a scout what if you move it one space at a time?
Scott: now you're tricking the other guy into thinking it's not a scout and He might go after it.
Scott: but oh you just went after a scout.
Scott: you wasted your time.
Rym: There's one thing I very often do is I'll never put more than maybe one scout in my front line Because scouts die against anything except well the spy.
Rym: So what I would do is that way and Scott always falls for this to this day whether I win or lose He always loses almost all the scouts right away because I put a bunch of bores or sevens at the front of my line Which is the weakest unit that will kill a scout.
Rym: and then Scott will send his scouts up right away and they all die against My front line.
Rym: and now I have more guys left.
Rym: He loses his scouts which gives me an advantage.
Scott: Yeah, as a result of this I've only slightly changed my strategy because I still keep a bunch of scouts on the front line Because I want to see.
Scott: you know, you never know it could his front line could be anything at all.
Scott: I don't know if he's gonna use the same strategy every time and By discovering what he has on the front line right away I'm able to rearrange my front lines and set up the proper defense and you know Arrangement and then go out because you know, who knows if I'll set up the proper arrangement luckily In my initial setup where I have no information at all.
Rym: But you have to be careful because when you're it takes very difficult to rearrange because it's difficult to move pieces.
Scott: It is that's why the scouts go out and die.
Scott: They also free up space for the rearrangement right at the front.
Scott: Where is the exact spot where I want to rearrange now?
Scott: The other thing though is I am careful to save three or four scouts until later in the game After I've cleared out much of his area.
Scott: I need to send those guys down there to find out where the bombs are without you know Dangerously moving my high-ranking pieces around stepping on things that haven't moved.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Now in the game We recently played I actually lost this one.
Rym: I made a critic.
Rym: It was.
Scott: it was not so much an error as a Yeah, we just played the game before the show to freshen the mind.
Rym: Yep as a bad tactical decision.
Rym: Uh, we both had our tens were both dead.
Rym: double suicide because while it was not likely that I was going to lose my ten And he wouldn't there was a small chance and I decided it wasn't worth the risk.
Rym: So I suicided.
Scott: Yeah, we both basically had our spies right there waiting.
Scott: So if one if either one of us decided to move the ten forward and actually start killing things.
Scott: That person would have been screwed because their ten would have been lost right away.
Scott: But at the same time pulling back the ten wouldn't have worked so well either.
Scott: So it's sort of like the left side of the board was locked up with the tens and the spies not moving at all.
Rym: Yep, so it came down then that we both had a nine.
Rym: I Sent my nine up to clear out all of Scott's resistance.
Rym: now My nine was so far away.
Rym: Scott sent his down to clear up my resistance But because of the way I was set up I couldn't very easily counter his guy there and I ended up losing as a result.
Scott: Yeah he sent his nine down like the left side.
Scott: where am I?
Scott: the board was sort of crowded and I Moved my guys in a way So that you know He would constantly like have two different guys to go after and there were guys in his way And it just made it difficult for him to move.
Scott: I sent my nine right down the side and I had scouts there checking in front of him all the time so that he was Able to just go go go go go.
Scott: I found the miner and then I found the bomb.
Scott: I sent the miner straight down the right side of the map.
Scott: Just click click click click click click click click.
Rym: Yep And there was my critical error because the nine was out of the way and I had an eight.
Rym: But the eight was trapped on the other side of a bomb and I could have gotten him over there.
Rym: But it was there was.
Rym: I didn't have time to get him over there because I had to move another piece out of the way.
Rym: I left a piece in a place that prevented my eight from defending against his miners And I had no other pieces in the area that could attack the miner other than my own miner Which he had another miner ready and that's actually how I got rid of his first miner.
Scott: Yeah, I'd actually at the end of the game I had lost all my miners because he got him all but nine was there.
Scott: So I just moved the nine in and I the miner had cleared out.
Rym: just I would have been I would have been guaranteed to win Except that I had left one hole in my bomb defense.
Scott: So the miner I cleared out just enough bombs and then my nine was able to just walk in and take the flag.
Scott: Yeah, he had one more bomb or moved a bomb, you know in a different direction?
Scott: Oh, that would have been it.
Scott: I would have had a little trouble there.
Scott: But I did have an eight waiting the whole game in the corner.
Scott: I didn't touch him.
Scott: I resisted the urge to move that eight for so long just in case we both had the eights ready to go.
Scott: I know but mine wasn't trapped by bombs.
Scott: He was in the corner wide open.
Scott: He wasn't
Rym: trapped by bombs He was just there's a bomb and like a five in his way It would have taken like three rounds to get the five far enough out of the way to bring him in and you would have Gone after the five and then your nine would come over.
Scott: Yep That's another advantage of I think of sending the twos out right away.
Scott: Is that if I need to like pull the spy out of like a crevice I can do that more easily Because all these twos are dead at the beginning of the game.
Scott: I've cleared out like five spaces.
Rym: see I'll also opt to often lose pieces But I have to lose the sergeants the ones just of course those seven for the most useless pieces in the game.
Scott: Yeah, the fours are pretty.
Rym: I pretty much load up my front lines with him.
Rym: I send them forward to be effectively scouts.
Rym: They eventually die.
Rym: I've freed up my lines almost as well and now right behind them are all my scouts.
Rym: Well half my scouts.
Rym: I always keep one Scout one minor and one eight hidden together Somewhere like out of the way for an emergency.
Rym: win the game like send a scout up to grab the flag or something.
Scott: Yeah, see what I actually do is since there's three pathways connecting the two sides You know with the water in between as I jet I make three three forces, you know They have powerful guys in the front but with you know scouts Powerful guys miners, you know.
Scott: So my front lines are scouts powerful guys miners in each of the three columns And then I hide the bombs and the flag somewhere in the rear way back, you know that way.
Scott: You know if his flag happens to be in the left in the middle or in the right I have guys there ready to go in at you know that part of the map and go get him because you know sometimes the game could just come down to you know, I. So it took too long for me to go over and get it.
Scott: this way I can go in on the left and if I've Gotten deep and there's no flag.
Scott: I can just forget that and go in from the right You know, which is much closer than going all the way across the board.
Rym: Yep I think in terms of zones of control and I'll generally put my Nine and my one actually kind of close together is that I have a powerhouse where my nine can kick ass yet I've got the ten there to back him up and then the other side will be kind of eights I always have.
Rym: one area was really poorly defended.
Scott: See, I don't really eat the way that they're trying to keep it even here's the reason I do that.
Rym: Like there are three basic pathways.
Rym: So by loading up two of them I'm basically saying if Scott attacks from those two I'm going to win.
Rym: if Scott attacks on my week one I'm going to lose but I give myself almost a two-thirds chance of winning instead of a 50% chance.
Scott: Perhaps.
Scott: the other thing though is I think why that fails you is because I don't really attack.
Scott: I Kind of wait I get hit a little bit to see what's there and then once I see what's there I push in right where I see the weak spot.
Scott: Well, I always It's like a counter punch.
Rym: I always put all my strong guys back a bit But the thing is that often I often do win with that because I didn't do that in the game.
Rym: We just played in the game.
Rym: We just played.
Rym: I did a completely different strategy Where I put the ten by himself with the spy and then on the other side I spread all my other powerful guys out in an actually a very carefully arranged array.
Scott: Yeah Anyway, as you can see Stratego is a pretty good game.
Rym: It's not the greatest game ever But there's a lot more to it than you might think.
Scott: there is a lot to it, you know.
Scott: And you know, it's pretty fun to have a have this army.
Scott: you arrange the army any way you want.
Scott: You could put all your bombs in the front line, but then you'd lose immediately because you couldn't move anybody.
Scott: But you know you can you know.
Scott: Arrange these guys in any way you want and then you fight two armies against each other quite directly.
Scott: Yeah, almost as if in a real battle.
Rym: It's very fun.
Rym: There's a lot you still think.
Rym: a lot I mean, there's a lot to think and consider about and you do make a lot of fairly important strategic decisions.
Scott: I think the biggest advantage that this game has is that it's a non Random two-player game.
Scott: There are very few two-player games that aren't just asked and it bluntly and it's cheap and People can play it even if they aren't super gamers, you know I know we I have friends that really aren't way gamers dude.
Rym: I used to play this game with my entire family.
Scott: Yeah, I mean what kind of game can you say?
Scott: What are their army military war game?
Scott: Can you say that the fan the whole family will enjoy it?
Rym: Not many, you know I'm surprised Jack Thompson isn't going after these violent board games.
Scott: Yeah, I know freaking.
Scott: I've learned so much about Battle strategy from playing Stratego.
Scott: you think if I just got a bunch of my friends together
Rym: With
Scott: my military strategy
Rym: I picture you standing there at the Crimean War and next to you is a bowling ball candle bomb and Behind that is your little flag and you've got a guy in a silly hat standing in front of you and you somehow think that You're invincible.
Scott: Yeah, that's pretty much what it is.
Rym: But to me the greatest advantage of this game because we love incredibly horrid We need to make like a live-action Stratego video.
Rym: That'd be pretty funny.
Scott: Maybe here Larry's you got bowling ball candles and miners.
Rym: I think we'll have to look and see if someone's already done it or not.
Scott: Yeah, we will and no one.
Scott: Oh, that's another thing.
Scott: I looked on the internet to see if there have been any other podcasts about Stratego ever and As far as I can tell there haven't been although it has been mentioned on some podcasts.
Scott: Like I think someone said Stratego once But no one's actually done a podcast about Stratego.
Scott: This is the first Stratego podcast.
Rym: everybody Yeah, but I mean there's fun strategy involved and all that.
Rym: but most importantly the game is real quick to play like 10 minutes Maybe.
Scott: well if you know how to play a lot dumb people might take too long.
Scott: But if you're playing with people who know what the hell they're doing the instructions say between 30 to 120 minutes.
Rym: Yeah In 120 minutes, we can almost knock off a game of Dracula.
Scott: Yeah, so this is you know it for smart people.
Scott: This is a quick game and for not so smart people Not so smart,
Rym: I guess I mean there are a lot of throwaway decisions in the game like once you especially because it's very hard to very meticulously design your entire board especially with the physical game with the other guys sitting there watching you because you're so afraid that he's gonna See the order.
Rym: you put pieces out in
Scott: and figure out like if what I generally do is I take all my pieces and I Put them out and then I just rearrange them if you just take them off the board Like if I just take the pieces and like huh Scott starting by building his you know Army from the rear left of the board where he built this triangle shape and then he's filling in the rest.
Scott: You know in columns and rows, I guess his bomb is in the rear left.
Rym: Yeah, but even if you do it your way It's pretty cuz.
Rym: you're probably certain pieces depending on how it like.
Rym: if I see you replace all the pieces in a certain area I'll depending on the area.
Rym: I'm usually pretty sure that's where your bomb is.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, it's kind of tricky to set up.
Scott: You know one thing you might want to do to be sure that no one's doing one guy sets up Then it leaves the room other guy comes in sets up Or you take a piece of paper you write down.
Rym: god, no, that's a terrible idea that would take forever.
Scott: It works, you know.
Scott: or you know if you have like pre-built Stratego Maps Like I could sit down one day and prepare like four or five Stratego's and just come out and put one together.
Rym: In my eyes the best way to set the game up physically is to take all the pieces off put them face down on your Side shuffle them up and then flip them all up in a row and then just start building in a random order.
Scott: Yep, that's it.
Scott: That's generally what we do and it works out.
Scott: There's no one ever knows exactly where the other guy's flag is.
Scott: I mean whenever a guy is moving around down in the rear, you know lanes of the other guy's board.
Scott: They're like Hope it's not a bomb.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, I guess the game is very simple.
Rym: The game is not terribly mentally challenging at all though It is more strategic than say.
Rym: What was that?
Rym: camels through the desert game?
Rym: We played.
Rym: Oh, I forget Timbuktu Timbuktu Timbuktu which was just a nothing game.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, there's enough to it to where.
Rym: don't underestimate this game.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: So yeah, Stratego is a Milton Bradley game for your family two players.
Scott: It's fun.
Scott: You can actually get this nice wooden version now if you really like it.
Scott: You should pay for that because it's way cool.
Scott: But if not, I recommend you get the wicked stupid cheap.
Scott: You know $10 or probably less than $10 version that we have now.
Rym: I like how Wikipedia says that this game has medium rules complexity and high strategic depth.
Scott: They don't know what the hell they're talking about.
Rym: I mean, I guess it has high strategic depth compared to every other Milton Bradley game except for I don't know Shogun.
Scott: Yeah Wonder what board game geek says.
Scott: board game geek is at 5.9 out of 10 stars and the only other information I see about it besides factual information is That there's an article that says you can't go wrong with Stratego, which is you know, you really can't go wrong.
Rym: We played this game to death.
Rym: I mean playing the game is not really a matter of who's smarter or who's more strategic But it's more a matter of the luck of who set up what kind of thing and how it plays out and there's not much To it anymore, but it's still fun to play.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Yeah board game geek says it's a medium light to light game Whatever.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, yeah go Wikipedia, I think you know, there's all these initiatives like the heavy metal improvement initiative.
Rym: I think we need the board game article improvement initiative.
Scott: Yeah, they should just sort of make.
Scott: someone should write a script that can turn a board game geek page into a Wikipedia page.
Scott: You know and then at least to the you know How some of the pages have that big bar on the right with all the you know vital information.
Scott: It should just loot board game geek for the vital information on the right side of the Wikipedia page and then you write an article.
Rym: Yeah, let me like.
Rym: I'm looking through these strategy listed in the Wikipedia article and it's pretty much just logical obvious answer.
Rym: Logical obvious thing.
Rym: there are no obvious obvious obvious thing during gameplay players must identify bombs without Sacrificing too many troops determine the probable location of the enemy flag form an attack plan.
Rym: Yeah, yeah misdirection plays a role as well.
Scott: Yeah, look at this, you know, it's got an average rating of five point eight seven, but on board game geek 1916 people own the game.
Scott: that tells you something.
Scott: Yep You know, no one's gonna say it's the best game ever like Puerto Rico or anything.
Scott: But everyone's got it and people tend to like it and they play.
Rym: Yeah, unlike other games.
Rym: Everyone owns like monopoly This game is actually fun.
Rym: Yep, and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.