Scott: It's Tuesday February 28th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Scott: We talk about the penny arcade collectible card game.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So yesterday I talked about list all and a few of the things I said were either Slightly incorrect or they changed overnight literally.
Rym: now I have a quote from Scott that he said this on the show a couple weeks ago.
Rym: I could play it if you really wanted.
Rym: I have to dig it up But I believe the words were I am infallible.
Rym: Perhaps are you indeed infallible Scott?
Scott: if I said it I guess yeah.
Rym: But you said now that you were a little bit incorrect about some things.
Scott: Well, no, it wasn't incorrect.
Scott: It was incomplete as in there was either things I didn't know or things which changed since then to now because list all changes.
Rym: so bad Alright, so what's up?
Scott: So literally Remember I said you couldn't add anything manually.
Rym: now you can.
Scott: now you can.
Scott: you can just go and type in a video game.
Scott: so NES games ahoy and The second thing they added a new tab the movies tab.
Scott: So now any movie that's an IMDB somewhere You can say I've watched it or I want to watch it or neither one of those, you know, and then you can rate them and Review them and all that.
Rym: so yeah Well, if it weren't the fact that I'm already using IMDB for that Netflix you mean?
Rym: Oh, yeah, well Netflix.
Rym: I use the IMDB to find out if a movie's good.
Scott: Yeah The thing is is that until they implement the sort of?
Scott: Automatic suggesting thing it's really hard to remember every movie you've seen and go through and try to find them all.
Scott: So it's the data entry is really painful for that And I really think they should.
Scott: just why a movie and DVDs separate?
Scott: there really should be just video of all of all sorts including TV and everything and VHS and movie theater and everything.
Scott: then Text of all sorts comic books regular books everything.
Scott: Then games of all sorts board games video games.
Rym: Well, I think that just goes way beyond what the guy you did list all originally expected to do.
Scott: I know but he it's called list all.
Scott: he's got a list at all.
Rym: It's not called list all.
Rym: it's called list Al.
Rym: yeah, if it was if it's list all you get some spammer websites.
Rym: Like I said yesterday.
Scott: Yeah, well you see the thing is the reason is called list all is because eventually when he adds everything then you'll add the other L.
Rym: Yeah, but I mean for now you.
Rym: so you can type your own thing in.
Rym: right if I type something in one way and someone Else types it in another way Yeah, but there are certain things that sort of prevent that.
Scott: like you don't have to you only have to type in the name of Something.
Scott: but here's an example.
Scott: I typed in.
Scott: I was tagging all my books today, right because I was bored yeah, so I tagged some books as Dark horse because they're published by dark horse, whatever I Typed in dark horse.
Scott: It found other people using the dark horse tag and it modified my dark horse tag to match their dark horse tag Really?
Scott: Yep So if you typed in a game name like close to another game It would be like.
Scott: is it any of these?
Scott: and there are certain like ID numbers?
Scott: They'll ask you to type like.
Scott: if you type in the UPC It'll see if there's already UPC matching that in the database somewhere and then it'll just give you that one instead of You know, huh letting you make your own.
Rym: so that's good because I own.
Rym: I don't have UPCs or anything for anymore anything.
Rym: I have a bear NES cartridge.
Scott: Yeah, that's the reason he wanted to not add this feature in the first place But now he's got systems to mitigate the damage.
Scott: It will cost from having duplicate entries.
Rym: Well, we'll see how it goes.
Rym: Yep, but in the news Microsoft.
Rym: well at least an analyst that may or may not have been paid off by Microsoft or hired by Microsoft.
Rym: But some analysts out there and this is on slashdot said that they expect that the Xbox 360 will sell 12 million units by the end of the year.
Scott: All right, how many have sold so far?
Rym: about 3 million if that?
Scott: So they've got.
Scott: how many months has it been since it came out?
Rym: Uh, a few a few Alright, not even if you came March starting tomorrow.
Scott: It came out in December or November.
Rym: I think it came out in late November.
Scott: So it's three months three million.
Scott: So at a million a month They've got eight months left in the year.
Scott: That's they might make it.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, I mean basically that they're basically talking about how the only reason that the Xbox hasn't sold Well currently is that there isn't any supply.
Scott: There's a billion Japanese ones.
Scott: They could bring them on over.
Rym: not even that.
Rym: They keep saying oh, there's no supply.
Rym: You can't get him.
Rym: They've been slowly making their way into retail spaces and a lot of stores just have an Xbox if you go in there.
Scott: I haven't seen one.
Scott: every like when I go into stores, they barely have Xbox 360 games.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but according to this study at least many retailers have at least one or two base Xbox 360 systems.
Scott: Hmm, maybe people are just waiting for the premium ones or anyone who wanted one pre-ordered and got theirs because there weren't more than three Pre-orders.
Scott: that's you know, that's just nuts.
Scott: Yeah, so all the pre-order people anyone who wanted one pre-order one and got one and no one else wants one.
Rym: well, I guess my Evidence that there's really the demand is not as high as they're saying and that the supply is not affecting this as much as they seem to want it to be is Simply that if you go on eBay and try to find an Xbox 360 premium or otherwise There are plenty to be head and they're really not going for any more than you pay in the store
Scott: Are really
Rym: yeah, I just did a search just now.
Rym: I saw seven at least in a couple pages just from the search of Xbox 360.
Rym: They were the premium system.
Rym: Some of them also were through in like two wireless controllers extra or a game extra.
Rym: they were going for about four hundred four hundred and fifty Dollars, I thought they're like three hundred dollars in the store.
Rym: what for the premium?
Scott: No, no, no Why are people buying these?
Scott: to begin with?
Scott: that's way too much money.
Scott: Uh, yeah Yeah We'll see It could be either way.
Scott: I mean at the rate of a million a month.
Scott: if they keep this rate up I mean, they didn't need an analyst to tell them that they'd sell, you know, eight million more in eight months, but At the same time maybe there is no more demand.
Scott: Who knows?
Rym: Well, I mean, I guess I brought up.
Rym: I brought it up not because this in itself is big news I mean analysts like this come up all the time but just the fact that they keep trying to blame the lack of sales and the fact that there aren't any Xboxes and I really think that even if there were Xboxes, it's not gonna matter.
Rym: Of course then again It won't matter anyway Because the PlayStation 3 if anyone's to be believed is gonna be like ten years late and cost a million dollars Or according to Sony it'll be here like in a couple months Yeah, but Sony just said they're gonna delay it.
Rym: possibly pa.
Scott: they said we could delay it.
Scott: Yeah, great.
Scott: Good job Sony.
Scott: whatever Sony hasn't gotten anything right in years.
Scott: What's the last thing Sony got right beside since the ps2, uh, there was that ps2.
Rym: after that Halo Xbox Dr.
Rym: M. Oh, no, they got bad DRM.
Scott: They canceled the eyebo.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: Sony was real good at not putting malware on people's computer.
Rym: Oh, wait a minute I guess they're not real good at that.
Scott: Oh, they tried to come out with that little, you know iPod competing bean thing.
Scott: Okay, they canceled that one.
Rym: Oh that you know the fact that it took me that long to realize what the hell you were talking about.
Scott: Yeah I mean Somebody's not doing well the PSP.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah PSP.
Rym: Yeah, I wanted to hear more about origami.
Scott: actually Yeah, we'll find out soon enough about the origami.
Rym: Yeah We'd better because I'm I'm actually a little excited about it depending on how much it ends up actually costing and what it actually does.
Scott: And I just figure even no matter what it does is smartphone like one of those HTC wizard things is just as good What I want to do with it.
Scott: Anyway Anyway, so the real big news everyone is Apple did something today.
Rym: Whoo Yeah, though.
Rym: It wasn't quite as who as I was hoping there was actually.
Scott: that's why they didn't make a huge deal out of it.
Scott: They sent like this little simple invitation and you know, just cuz Apple the internet makes a big deal out of it.
Scott: Apple doesn't seem to care.
Rym: now my office made at work and of all the things that were announced the one thing that I was slightly excited about was something that wasn't actually announced.
Rym: it was just a communication disconnect here.
Rym: Mm-hmm, but my office mate at work is He's.
Rym: he has a bunch of max.
Rym: He loves max so he's sitting there like in a chat room with people who are there with cell cams like Giving him up-to-date.
Rym: Steve Jobs just walked out.
Rym: He said this.
Scott: he said this Yeah, see I just wait for people to type that in and then when when he's all done I go and I read the whole thing at once.
Scott: I don't sit there as they type it.
Scott: That's just nuts.
Rym: Yeah, so, you know it was a new Mac mini and I said, oh expect a new Mac mini is pretty good.
Scott: Actually, that's it's got more USBs and it's wicked fast and it's cheap and it has front row and Bonjour On it.
Scott: So now you can really plug it into your TV for some awesomeness and the way Bonjour works.
Scott: this is the thing where Apple computers or any computer with Bonjour.
Scott: I'm pretty sure only Apple computers can have it can like share their media.
Scott: So Theoretically if you have a computer, let's say you have a power a double a superpower tower Whatever they call them, you know the dual CPU thingies upstairs, right?
Scott: Yeah, and you buy an episode of a TV show on the iTunes store Downstairs on your you know, your Mac minis plugged into your TV with front row.
Scott: in Front row if you say watch a movie the Bonjour thing will connect to the other apples on your land and say uh-huh There is a movie up there that we can watch.
Scott: Oh, ho ho ho and that is is a French.
Scott: That was why they call it Bonjour.
Rym: That's your French impression.
Scott: I am NOT a good at the French accent.
Rym: Wow I don't even have anything to make funny if or just God.
Scott: whatever the point that's you know, I think that's pretty cool.
Rym: Yeah, but I mean it's cool.
Rym: It wasn't really Unexpected like it was.
Scott: actually it was very expected.
Scott: Everyone was like new Mac mini.
Scott: Hooray.
Rym: Yeah, so no one went.
Scott: Yeah, but it is a hooray Mac mini.
Rym: the next thing was the.
Rym: The person sitting in my office was like he's called it a boombox because everyone said oh, it looks like a boombox.
Scott: It is sort of a boombox.
Rym: Yeah, it's the hi-fi the iPod.
Scott: Hi-fi Basically, it's an iPod dock and it's also a giant box with a bunch of speakers in the front that makes supposedly really nice sound.
Scott: I think the box looks really weird and kind of strange.
Scott: I don't.
Scott: it doesn't look mean it's white and appley, but now here's the two problems.
Rym: I've seen things like that for a lot less money than Apple's gonna sell this.
Scott: They're a lot smaller and a lot less powerful.
Scott: This thing's like $400.
Rym: Oh, yeah, this thing's big and expensive and powerful.
Rym: But I'll point out that the media you put on an iPod is not always the highest of quality music.
Scott: anyway, I think the point of this is that if you use this it's getting the audio out of the Digital iPod dock connector in the bottom and not the not using the iPods Chip to do the decoding.
Scott: so you're getting much better.
Rym: So how long until I get a lick sang or Chinese Korean knockoff bootleg dongle that I stick on the bottom of my iPod and get SPDIF out?
Scott: now they already had the.
Scott: What do you think my I trip does?
Rym: Yeah, so well that then uses the FM modulation, which actually makes them it really really down samples and make some.
Scott: Yeah, that's bad.
Scott: But you know, it's the point is whatever I mean if you're reading the if you're trying to get the audio out of the digital connector at the bottom that you use to dock as opposed to the Audio hole you're basically using the iPod as a hard drive and reading the mp3 is off of it.
Scott: That's all you're doing.
Scott: Yeah, so you're not using the you know deep mp3 decoder in the iPod.
Scott: you're using someone that you have somewhere else.
Rym: So I guess in that case why not just buy a flash drive or a firewire drive and carry it around?
Scott: The point of this is that this device This big boombox thing Supposedly has really good sound.
Scott: I'll believe them.
Scott: It's pretty portable.
Scott: It runs on D batteries where a lot of the other ones seem to plug in.
Scott: It's really big which is not so good.
Scott: But it's also a hi-fi stereo component like you.
Scott: can you know, you got your receipt you got your all your stereo components.
Scott: You can put this one in there too to put iPods in.
Rym: Yeah, I guess it's just.
Rym: it's too pricey for me.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know why I didn't win $400 on it.
Rym: I mean, I hate all those audio file types, but I like my audio a lot.
Scott: This Logitech makes a thing that does the boom Bose does too where you just plug an iPod in and it plays with the music And speakers.
Rym: Yeah, this wasn't.
Rym: it was surprising.
Rym: I didn't expect anything like this to come out.
Scott: No, no one did.
Rym: It doesn't really do anything for me.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: now the confusion came when My office mate turns to me and says they're gonna have an iPod nano five gigs for a hundred dollars.
Scott: And I was like, there's no way.
Rym: and I was like If you can verify that I'll buy one right now.
Scott: I was like.
Scott: that makes absolutely no sense.
Rym: That's a little fishy.
Scott: Yeah, how could they?
Scott: Right now a four gig one is two hundred and fifty dollars.
Scott: How are they gonna save a hundred and fifty dollars?
Rym: Now what got me to where I was?
Rym: I almost believed it was that then he showed me this grainy cell cam picture.
Rym: I looked at it and it was a guy.
Rym: it was someone on stage holding a nano Mm-hmm, so I thought hot damn.
Scott: then I immediately took it.
Scott: with the conference is over by the time we found You know, I heard this from him.
Scott: So I went to the complete You know typing up report of the keynote and I searched for the word nano.
Rym: now there was in fact a product.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't see the word nano there.
Rym: Anyway, but then it turned out there was in fact a new product.
Rym: It contains the word nano in it and it is a hundred dollars.
Rym: Mm-hmm It is a leather or something like that Cover for the iPod nano.
Scott: Well, it's also for the newest iPod and Such.
Scott: it's just a leather sleeve to put the iPod in its Italian real high quality leather from Apple.
Rym: That's a hundred dollars.
Scott: that's it's what leather costs.
Scott: I guess I don't know.
Scott: no, it's a huge freakin mark up on it.
Scott: You know it.
Rym: I'll point out that I for anyone who knows me I haven't worn them in a while because I haven't been taking care of them.
Rym: So they're sitting being soaking in oil, but I have some high quality Leather like leather leather leather boots.
Rym: They cost me about a hundred and fifty bucks total.
Rym: There is not even an eighth of the amount of leather in this iPod thing.
Rym: Yeah Who would pay that much money you're paying for the little Apple logo on it, you know, what you know what I'll do here Here, I just drew the Apple logo on a piece of paper 50 bucks trademark infringement.
Rym: Fine now, it's an orange awesome.
Scott: No, but I mean like.
Scott: I will pay You know some money to get first party, you know accessories like if my car Needed a part I would pay ten bucks more to get a Mazda part as opposed to a You know crummy aftermarket part.
Scott: or if I wanted a Nintendo controller I would spend ten bucks extra to get a Nintendo controller and not a Mad Catz controller but to pay $50 more for an iPod sleeve that is not functional or more functional in any way than the $30 iPod sleeves I can purchase from various accessory manufacturers.
Scott: Why that?
Scott: what the fuck?
Scott: just cuz it goddamn.
Scott: who do they think's gonna buy this?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I mean, I guess from my perspective It'll be another useful thing if I see someone with it.
Rym: I know that they're a fool who is easily parted with their money or very or very wealthy in which case Maybe I can get some money out of them.
Rym: maybe All right, there is one more little news today Last but certainly not least because it's something I'm probably going to buy.
Scott: Yeah well the DS lite which you may or may not know about is sort of like the DS SP and Lick sang got their hands on one, you know our happy importing friends lick sang.
Rym: Yes, apparently They said it was bright, you know, it's a play on words.
Rym: It's light because it's lighter and it's light because it's brighter.
Rym: Mm-hmm, the lowest lowest brightness setting on this new one is as bright as the current DS yep, and Apparently the highest setting will hurt you.
Scott: It may burn your retinas.
Scott: Well, the thing here is that they've actually increased the battery power output from 850 milli AH whatever that milliamps, I don't know to 1000.
Rym: so does that decrease the battery life or is there a bigger battery?
Scott: Oh, it means that actually if you keep the brightness at the same brightness at the lowest brightness level Which is the current brightness level of the normal DS.
Scott: You actually get a longer battery life.
Rym: Oh somewhat they increase the milli watt hours.
Scott: then yeah, and if you raise the The battery light if you raise the brightness all the way up You'll get pretty much the same battery life as the current DS.
Rym: not bad Now apparently like Scott told me just before the show.
Rym: They also changed the AC power recharging connector.
Scott: Yeah see Nintendo likes to keep the same connectors from system to system like the SNES the N64 and the GameCube all had the same AV connector and the the SP and the DS have the same power connector, but the micro obviously needed a different a smaller one.
Scott: So now the SP the DS light comes out and everyone's thinking.
Scott: Oh, it'll have the same connector as the micro.
Scott: No, it has some brand new connectors.
Scott: So I guess they had to.
Rym: yeah, I'm curious as to why I want to see it.
Rym: I haven't looked at the pictures of this yet.
Scott: Yeah, so it just probably comes with a new AC adapter.
Scott: You can't use your DS one or your SP one.
Scott: Yeah, what are your light one?
Scott: Whatever?
Scott: Also the you can't turn the backlight off all the way.
Scott: Oh well The stylus is longer and thicker.
Scott: I guess that's good for big American hands.
Rym: I don't know I don't know I can make a joke about a penis.
Scott: But yeah Oh and here's the big one you're ready.
Scott: the big one the negative The GB.
Scott: there's a little over the GBA slot.
Scott: There's a little cover Huh, which is good because right now there's no cover on the GBA slot.
Scott: It's kind of like a.
Rym: my GBA slot is never been unoccupied.
Rym: Oh, of course, of course, but the point is I mean, it wasn't it Tycho penny arcade who called it like a second holster of gaming.
Rym: Yeah, of course, or like the second barrel in my gun of gaming or something?
Scott: Yeah, that's exactly what it is something to go ish.
Scott: But at the same time it would be nice if there's like a little flap there or a little removable cover, you know My cell phone even has a little tiny rubber thing that sticks in the bottom data port when I'm not using it.
Scott: Yep, so it would be nice if there's a cover and on the light.
Scott: There is a cover.
Scott: However, there's a problem if you put it.
Scott: if you actually take the cover off and put a GBA cartridge in there The GBA cartridge sticks out about a quarter an inch Huh?
Scott: See the reason there's a cover is because you're not gonna want to keep your GBA cartridge in there constantly.
Scott: You're gonna want to take it out when you're not playing and put a thing in there.
Rym: I don't know what I think about that because currently there I keep two games in it and I keep the thing in my pocket.
Rym: So that way I just have two games with me or I bring the whole giant carrying case around.
Rym: I'm not gonna leave a game in it if it jumps out like that.
Rym: Yeah, that means I'm only carrying one game with me or I'm carrying all my games with me Mm-hmm.
Scott: If you're carrying all your games with you, then the smallness of the light isn't really an advantage.
Scott: Huh, you're really only getting a benefit from the brightness.
Rym: Well, basically it comes down and it's better looking.
Rym: I guess for me when it comes out I'll go to the store and I'll look at it and I'll probably buy it anyway Just because my DS it's already gotten a lot of use and I'd like to have a new one.
Rym: Yeah, and I could.
Rym: I honestly I probably give my current DS away.
Rym: I know a number of people who would probably be thrilled to have it.
Scott: See thing is you know my DS works fine and I use it a lot and I'd probably like to upgrade to like a light.
Scott: because I remember when the GBA came out and everyone had the SP and I was like, oh my GBA is just fine and it was just fine.
Scott: But wait a minute.
Rym: That's the kind of thing.
Rym: I usually say it was the other one.
Rym: He usually says no upgrade at all cost.
Scott: Well, because it was there was no, you know, the SP wasn't really an upgrade It was just the same.
Rym: I submit that the SP with its backlighting was.
Scott: but yes The thing is I didn't need the backlighting, you know Just like I don't need the GBA cartridge to stick out a quarter an inch.
Scott: But nowadays my GBA is really useless, you know, so I can't even play with it.
Scott: I can't even use it to play Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles or anything.
Rym: Well, you scratched the hell out of your GBA, too.
Scott: Yeah, the other thing is that the GBA using batteries back in the day wasn't a problem.
Scott: But now the batteries are a problem because I don't because nothing I have really is batteries anymore.
Rym: Honestly, remember when I said I had all those interviews from Katsucon and we couldn't play him.
Rym: Well, the last device in our house that really uses batteries was that boombox.
Rym: We just threw away.
Rym: Yeah, the one that was full of batteries It was also full of battery acid.
Rym: one of the two was not inside of the other of the two as it should have been Mm-hmm.
Scott: So, you know, well, I didn't want an SP back then and it really wouldn't have helped me back Then.
Scott: it helped me now and it's too late to trade in a GBA for an SP and get a discount.
Scott: So maybe I could.
Scott: if there's a really good deal of trading in a DS for a light I'll do it but other than that Maybe I'll just hold off and buy one in the future or I'll wait until the DS light comes out with some great new colors Like there's a green one or something.
Rym: So things of the day.
Rym: This is kind of an old thing.
Rym: Well, actually it's very old.
Rym: I'm not gonna talk about it much But I think it's interesting and any of you who play chess out there and if you've not heard about this you may find it Fascinating if you've never if you don't like chess you will find this incredibly boring.
Scott: I have a feeling that people who like chess already know about this and people who don't like chess have no idea what the hell's Going on.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, it's just something.
Rym: it's more.
Rym: it's not so much that I found out about it, but I found a transcript of it.
Rym: it's called the immortal game and basically it was a chess game between two semi famous very good chess players a long time ago and The game itself is widely remembered as one of the most cool interesting and/or strange games of chess that ever happened.
Rym: That was recorded.
Scott: At least what was so interesting about it.
Rym: I'm not good enough at chess to really say can't even say one thing.
Rym: well, I can say that the way the game worked out is it started out very simply and Then one guy set up this really cool like defensive wall Diagonally and they were jumping back and forth.
Rym: Anyway, that's that's the deepest analysis I can give of it not being very good at chess myself.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Can you at least say why?
Scott: it was the immortal game?
Rym: It's the immortal game because it's the most widely remembered long-lived game.
Rym: All right, that's that's the explanation I'd always been given because I had a friend back in high school who was really good at chess like he could meet it in tournaments.
Rym: he was really good and No one would play chess with him because he just won.
Rym: I 15 year old we found on the street.
Scott: I hate people like that with the chest just beating you.
Rym: It's kind of bleh what someone's good at something.
Scott: No, no No, cuz like usually when you play against a master if you're an amateur your random amateurness kind of messes them up.
Scott: But in chess if someone knows they're doing this kick.
Rym: Oh, actually if you want to get into the details, it did mess him up and he hated playing against me because He'd win every time.
Scott: well, then he wasn't a real master.
Scott: cuz I know the real masters just kick your ass.
Rym: Well, no cuz he wouldn't kick my ass partly on purpose because you know, that'd be an asshole thing to do.
Rym: but basically it would screw him up because I'm just kind of moving willy-nilly and He just kind of pieces would go back and forth.
Rym: and once I got down where I only had like three pieces left or five pieces left I could think real far ahead and I could hold him off for a long time and do a lot of damage, but Then he just beat me.
Scott: Well, cuz you only had five pieces left.
Rym: Yeah, and one time I asked him to go all out on me and not pull any punches and he just creamed me immediately.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway this game I'd heard about a lot.
Rym: he'd mentioned it before.
Rym: a lot of people who played chess that I've known have talked about this before and Here it is.
Rym: Here's a move by move transcript of this famous game of chess.
Rym: I've got no more to say about it.
Scott: It's like a little video.
Rym: Maybe no no video.
Scott: Maybe someone will make a video.
Scott: we can watch it fast-forwarding or something.
Rym: Well, my one nice thing about this site that I found is that it talks about this game of chess as though You don't know anything about chess.
Scott: Oh, that's cool.
Rym: So it was.
Rym: it's an interesting read I think.
Scott: hmm, so Everyone here knows video games and cosplays and all these nerdy things.
Scott: There's a girl in Britain and she's kind of cute kinda.
Scott: I mean her face is pretty cute.
Scott: Her body's kind of normal.
Scott: That's not the point.
Scott: the point is this girl cosplays.
Rym: she cosplays specifically as Princess Peach fairly well as Princess Peach I might add.
Scott: I think she's just a Princess Peach fanatic.
Scott: Actually.
Scott: I'm 100% sure she's a Princess Peach fanatic.
Rym: Not that there's anything wrong with that.
Scott: There's absolutely nothing wrong with that.
Scott: In fact, it is good is two more commendable.
Scott: Yes So she started an eBay auction today for poses.
Scott: you pay her money and she will pose in any pose.
Scott: You want any non dirty pose?
Scott: Yeah, so she won't show you her boobies or you know her bits But her boobies her naughty bits.
Rym: you called them her boobies.
Scott: Well, she's if she's a princess peach their boobies.
Rym: Okay, what if she were Daisy?
Rym: What would you have called them then?
Rym: knockers?
Scott: All right, so there you go, um And you can pretty much.
Scott: she has a lot of props.
Scott: like she has Bob bombs and and question blocks.
Scott: I saw a change change arms.
Scott: So if you or mushrooms, I'm sure.
Scott: so if you could tell her like I want you to pose You know smiling and holding a mushroom in the air or something like that.
Scott: or you know holding the rutabaga from Mario 2 over your head like you just dug it out of the ground.
Scott: or and She would you know get a picture taken of herself wearing this cosplay in the pose you want and send it to you.
Scott: So that was what got the attempt heard the internet-wide attention today.
Scott: eBay auction.
Scott: But also she has a nice little store.
Scott: I think it's called peach paradise or something and she sells all kinds of really good Nintendo stuff.
Scott: Like she had a Zelda pin that was caught kind of cool that I wanted and like an f1 racing Mario pin and she had some gift wrapping tape that had like little mushrooms and Bloopers and all kinds of cool stuff on
Rym: ha ha ha,
Scott: you know, I think I might go buy some of this stuff.
Scott: It's pretty cheap.
Scott: It was all in British pounds though.
Scott: So it's actually more money.
Scott: and the shipping because you know, she's British.
Rym: Yeah, you never know.
Rym: Maybe she'll go to an Otakon or something.
Rym: Yeah, right Hey people from Japan came to Otakon two years ago just to see that band.
Scott: Yeah, we'll see if anyone comes this year, but maybe I'll order some stuff from this cool store before someone else buys it.
Scott: I mean, I don't think her stock is too big.
Rym: No, and now that she's being hit by every freaking site in the world including us.
Scott: Yeah, so that's all I gotta say.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So moving on to the topic.
Rym: We said we'd talk about and It's a topic that's generated a lot of anger here in the geek house.
Scott: It seems to have only generated anger.
Scott: No.
Rym: No, it generated a little bit of desperation a lot of anguish and almost a crying.
Scott: it got rid of Disappointment.
Rym: Oh, yeah disappointment.
Rym: It also killed at least a couple hours.
Scott: Yeah, but at least some of the all the a lot of the hours that killed were me at work So it actually saved me from some pain.
Rym: So penny arcade has their card game.
Scott: Well, they don't really have the card game.
Scott: It's.
Scott: it's more like they want to make merchandise to make money, which is cool because that's how they make all their money.
Scott: Yeah and they decided making a CCG would be a good idea or I don't know if maybe the other people decided it would be a Good idea and ask them to do it.
Rym: But they have this game and it's part of the universal fighting system by saber-tooth games.
Scott: now the idea of the universal fighting system is the There.
Scott: theoretically there would be a CCG where you could Collect all sorts of different cards from all sorts of different sets and mix and match them and they would all work according to the same role,
Rym: so right now I could have taiko versus Gabe or Gabe versus Taki from Soulcalibur.
Scott: Yeah when we bought this we you get a gave in a taiko box.
Scott: It's basically two boxes.
Scott: One of them is Gabe and one of them is taiko.
Scott: and it comes there pretty nice little card holding boxes.
Scott: They're really cute and they have lots of art on them.
Rym: And in fact right now we're gonna talk about every positive aspect of this game.
Scott: The box it comes in is cool and the art is awesome penny arcade art.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I'm opening it right now.
Scott: It's high quality with a piece of velcro.
Scott: Hear that velcro.
Rym: Yeah, the piece of velcro is really key here.
Scott: There's a little card that that's your life meter.
Rym: It's really thick in quality and it's got art on it.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: That's really says my character's name here.
Rym: It says taiko at the top in all caps Mm-hmm The cards smell really nice.
Rym: Yeah, not as good as magic cards, but definitely a nice smell here.
Scott: They smell a lot like Pokemon cards did back in the day.
Rym: Um, there are some funny texts on the cards.
Scott: Oh, yeah, this one card here.
Scott: Let me try to find it mine leapin John I'm leapin.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: My favorite card here is skullduggery.
Scott: That's pretty.
Scott: that says good picture on it.
Rym: All right.
Rym: This is one of the worst games I've ever experienced.
Scott: Wait, wait, wait, it's better than Hellas All right.
Rym: Now see I disagree on that.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: No, wait There's only one reason why I think this game is better than Hellas because we did figure out most of the rules.
Scott: in Hellas There are rules questions that can never be answered because no one is there to answer them Because the universal fighting system people at saber-tooth games have a forum.
Scott: all of the questions in this game are eventually answered Possibly because I'll note that they've stopped Answering questions on the forum.
Scott: Oh, no, that's that's not true.
Scott: that would Basically, they had people who staff the forums like paid employees and yesterday There was a guy there and he was watching the forums Like he deleted one of my posts because I tried to bump up a thread and I didn't realize they didn't like it when you Bump up threads, but today it didn't seem like there was any forum activity whatsoever.
Scott: And I'm sure when those people get back to work that the forum activity will continue.
Scott: But there was of all the question.
Scott: I went through every single card in this game and every single rule in the shitty shitty rule book or rule paper whatever you want to call it and I found every single problem I could possibly think of.
Scott: and there was still one unresolved question.
Scott: because Not because of anything in the rule book even because they added a rule that is not in any rule book anywhere in the forum.
Scott: So imagine if a game has just this rule that only exists in the forum and you don't even.
Rym: it's not even an errata It's just some bits that you saw on someone's website.
Scott: Yeah, it's a brand new rule that's on their website and nowhere else Like oh, yeah, there's also this rule.
Scott: You should play with it.
Rym: Now the first time we played the game we were struggling through the rules and basically at every juncture at every point I tried to play a card draw a card do anything.
Rym: There was a rules dispute.
Scott: Not only that but if there wasn't a rules dispute there was a feeling of oh that game mechanic is dumb.
Scott: I understand it and it's stupid.
Rym: Yeah, basically every turn would go along like this.
Rym: I try to play an attack called large animal tranquilizer.
Scott: It's got has the best picture on it.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: All right, so I have to make a control check.
Rym: Whatever.
Rym: How does that work?
Rym: I thought it worked this way.
Rym: No, it actually works this way.
Rym: Oh That's kind of shitty.
Scott: Yep, pretty much no matter what happened.
Scott: We were either stuck in a rut of Misunderstanding and confusion or dread of.
Scott: we understand but it's terrible because the truth sucks.
Rym: We've never actually completed a game completely to the end where one of us was dead.
Rym: Yep, the first time we played the game sucked like it really sucked where we won't stop playing a game.
Rym: All right This is one of the game.
Rym: this and goa are the only games we have ever given up on Halfway through the first playing.
Rym: but at least goa We're gonna come back to because that was just a bad time to try to learn that game and it's a really complicated game.
Scott: this is also really complicated, but this is Complicated with.
Scott: no it doesn't seem like there's a reward for your efforts goa.
Scott: I think is actually a good game once you understand it.
Scott: Yeah this no matter how much you understand the game doesn't get any better.
Rym: I mean consider this the first time we played it the rules didn't work and we couldn't figure it out.
Rym: It was not fun.
Rym: So we endeavored to learn how the game really worked and Scott did all his research and then we came back to the table the next day or a few days later knowing exactly how to play.
Rym: and The game was worse.
Rym: because now we were actually following all the horrible horrible arbitrary crap.
Rym: poorly written infinitely adjectives rules Mm-hmm.
Scott: I mean there are just so many things in this game like They expect little kids to figure this stuff out.
Rym: little kids they expect me to figure this game out.
Rym: We're fucking veteran German board gamers.
Rym: We play games that say four hours on the outside of the box and do indeed take four hours.
Rym: This game is not playable.
Scott: I Think that soon as I open up the rule if it comes a little paper that you unfold with all the rules on it And the rules are written so poorly like I don't know what they were thinking Like.
Rym: I mean.
Rym: basically the rules are really kind of meandering and slow and they skip around.
Rym: They don't explain concepts in detail.
Rym: They don't use precise language Which that's the number.
Scott: one thing is the language is so incredibly imprecise.
Rym: I mean look at a German board game.
Rym: the rules will say something like on your turn You must do X. you may then do Y if you choose.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So I have to do X and then if I want to I can do Y but I can choose not to do This game.
Rym: there was none of that.
Rym: it was just like some fifth grader wrote a paragraph on something.
Scott: Yep, it's like.
Scott: I don't know how they does.
Scott: It seems like they came up with a base idea for a game and then he just kept piling stuff on to it.
Rym: Yeah, basically my guess as to what happened is that they wanted this game and they wanted to be extensible.
Rym: So they made the base game and then they started play testing it and it seemed to work.
Rym: Then they started writing cards and adding cards to the game and I think every tenth card.
Rym: They said wait a minute that card breaks the game.
Rym: Oh Well, what if we just add this rule in?
Rym: Oh that fixes it.
Rym: Okay, and I think they did that often Mm-hmm.
Rym: Now, I guess we could go into a description in great detail of these specific game mechanics.
Rym: that piss us off.
Scott: Why don't we?
Scott: let's talk about check this out All right.
Rym: So aside from the fact that the rules are unintelligible and that the people who made the game Saber tooth the people who made this goddamn game cannot clarify their own rules in an effective manner Alright, so let's start out with the first thing.
Rym: the basic fundamental thing in this game is the control check which alright It took a while to understand once we understood it.
Rym: It's stupid.
Rym: It's just arbitrary random and silly.
Scott: every card has two numbers on it one in the top left and one in the bottom right.
Scott: the top left is the Difficulty and the bottom right is the control value.
Scott: I guess I guess that's what you want to call it.
Rym: Yeah, you know what?
Rym: I call it the as value.
Scott: Yeah So let's say in your hand you want to use a card.
Scott: the card has a difficulty of four.
Scott: If you want to use it What you do is you take the top card of your deck and turn it over into your discard pile and you look at the?
Scott: Control number.
Rym: All right, let's say it's a two.
Rym: I didn't make the check.
Rym: I needed at least a four.
Rym: So I either have to put use other cards which I'll get to to bring that number up to four.
Rym: But if I fail this control check, I have to discard the card.
Rym: I tried to play and the card.
Rym: I just flipped over.
Scott: Oh and your turn is over.
Rym: Yeah, your turns over immediately if you ever fail one of these things, too Yep, so you basically play things.
Scott: play things play things.
Scott: you fail the control check your turns over.
Rym: Basically every time you try to do something There's a chance your turtle just end and that chance increases the more things you try to do.
Rym: Mm-hmm, it adds a lot of randomness into the game.
Rym: It doesn't really add strategy.
Rym: The most it adds is that you can risk trying to play one more car that you might not get out there.
Scott: I think the real point of it is that what they trying to do is if you made a CCG where this customizing and collecting and You don't add all this crazy shit like this What happens is if cards just do something and have a base value to them People will just select the best cards and make the best deck and it'll be easy to do So.
Rym: now magic the gathering solve this by having cards cost different amounts of mana And you have to tap different lands to bring out cards and more powerful cards took more taps to bring out.
Rym: Mm-hmm This game does it with a system.
Rym: I like to call a random bullshit.
Scott: Yep, it's if the card is more difficult to use and more powerful.
Scott: Your chances of being able to use it are more or less as opposed to in magic where you could eventually use everything.
Scott: It just took longer and you would have to do it later in the game.
Scott: So yeah, it's not the greatest game mechanic But what it does is it really makes you think when you're making your deck because now you have to say Alright, let me use all these really powerful cards that have high difficulties.
Scott: Oh Every single one of my cards is a really low control number.
Scott: I'll never actually be able to get anything out.
Scott: now I have to take out some of these really great cards with high difficulties.
Scott: put in some crap cards with low difficulties and high control numbers or you know, it's.
Scott: there isn't even really a pattern to it like some cards have high control numbers and high difficulties and Some cards are useful for blocking.
Scott: so you don't want to actually use them You want to hold them into your hand to block with them and God?
Rym: Yeah, I'm starting to think that while they tried to balance the game I don't think they really balanced it mathematically.
Rym: I think they balanced it haphazardly.
Scott: They definitely balance it haphazardly.
Scott: There's even a lot of.
Scott: there is even stuff on the card that isn't used in the base Tycho and Gabe game but is used in the full Customizable uso on my little Tycho evil genius card.
Rym: It has little pictures on it.
Rym: You know like say it has a picture of a skull or a picture of a scale.
Rym: Now it doesn't.
Rym: there's nowhere in the rulebook to say what these are other than that They're not used unless you play with other decks are used in the full UFS rules.
Rym: Basically, they're kind of like mana but they're more like you have to have one of those symbols on your character card in order to play another card.
Rym: and There's all these other rules of all.
Rym: I'm not gonna get into the details.
Rym: Now Tycho's deck comes with a card the fruit fucker that under those rules He cannot ever under any circumstances actually play.
Scott: Yep, so if you were playing in a UFS tournament, you couldn't actually use the Tycho deck You'd have to remove the fruit fucker and at least one other card I know of.
Rym: yep That is just not legal according to their rules the rules that are online that are not in the rule book that came with the game and they're in the forums.
Scott: and actually there was one more problem that came up when we were playing just now and I went online because I thought the answer was there and I thought didn't know if I forgot it or not and I could not find it.
Scott: It's not there Here's.
Scott: it is another is an example of something else stupid.
Scott: So you have a card right and the card has an ability on it and it the ability says Do something with this cost.
Scott: then it says right under that You may only you know do this Under the fall under this condition and as a condition It doesn't say.
Scott: it doesn't specify because of the wording is so vague Whether that condition applies to just the ability above it or The entire card itself.
Scott: It says you can't play this unless.
Scott: does that mean I can't play the card unless which doesn't work?
Scott: Or does it mean I can't play the ability unless?
Scott: the answer is it means you can't play the ability unless but the type setting didn't Lend itself to me automatically Associating that conditional clause with the ability because it was a. there was a carriage return.
Scott: Now also the wording didn't either.
Rym: there's this mechanic of you make attacks.
Rym: That's the primary way to win.
Rym: you attack the other person to do damage to them.
Rym: now attacks can be blocked.
Rym: But get this an attack can be high medium or low and you can block high medium or low.
Rym: Mm-hmm and different cards have different attack values and different block values.
Scott: Well, only attack cards have attack values.
Scott: Well, yeah.
Rym: Yeah, however the the way blocking works is counterintuitive because Basically, you take the number of the quickness on the attack card and add it to the number of the block on the block card.
Rym: You're playing.
Rym: then you have to make a control check of the number you just got and beat it.
Scott: So if the attack is fast and has a high speed value you have to make a tough.
Scott: it makes the control check to block Harder.
Scott: that's understandable.
Scott: if the block has a very large number that makes the control check to successfully block Even harder.
Scott: you would think that maybe they just put a minus.
Scott: so that high block numbers Would make sense makes it easier to block things not harder.
Scott: But no a block of plus zero is the best block that I've seen.
Rym: Now the also net benefit of this Well, I guess not net benefit, but the exact opposite of that is that blocking is apparently almost impossible.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, I don't think an attack was ever successfully blocked without a special ability in any of the times We played this game.
Scott: Yeah taiko has the ability to automatically block an attack but Gabe has a lot of attack cards a whole lot of attack cards and a lot of a built ways to attack multiple times And just get right around that ability.
Scott: Like he has an attack card mine leap in where he attacks and even though if the attack is blocked he can still use his enhanced abilities during the attack to deal some damage.
Scott: and then if taiko used his ability to block that now Gabe can come in with more attacks and deal a crap ton of damage.
Scott: and You can't block unless you have a block card in your hand.
Rym: and then then you probably can't.
Scott: and even then you could only block If your block is, you know only one distance away from the type of attack.
Scott: So if he attacks low and you have a high block you can't block with it And then you can only block if you make the control check.
Scott: and if you don't make the control check you to throw the block out.
Scott: so I Had only one block in my hand and during most turns So all Rym had to do is attack once and usually I failed the block And if I didn't you just dealt a bunch of damage to me.
Scott: It's like a race to do damage.
Rym: Now all that aside the game mechanics are kind of broken.
Rym: the rules are vague and hard to understand errata is almost meaningless and hard to find and It's just not fun.
Rym: Yeah, but maybe there's a game there.
Rym: you'd think if the game's so complex There got to be some sort of strategy going on.
Rym: Well, the answer is a Can of coke could play this game much like you go.
Scott: Well, the thing is in yugioh.
Rym: I think the mechanic in the mechanic in yugioh is draw card play a card draw card play a card till someone wins, correct?
Scott: So in yugioh, you don't actually need to have any Sort of human thought in this game, you know, there's actually it's.
Scott: it's.
Scott: there isn't a strategy like decisions You have to make but a can of coke could not select the correct card from the hand to play.
Rym: Well, no, but I'll bet a monkey could.
Rym: a monkey probably could if it could read yeah, basically the only factor that decides who wins is One what cards are in your deck?
Rym: two?
Rym: Do you or what order do you draw them in?
Scott: What order are they in your deck?
Scott: because what do you turn over for?
Rym: control also matters because the decisions you make in this game?
Rym: There are basically two kinds of decisions.
Rym: You can make a decision that has a random effect on the game and may or may not help you win but you have no way of knowing or You can make the correct decision when there is a choice for example do I play this attack card or do I not?
Rym: and the answer is always obvious.
Rym: and Basically, you always make the optimal move because if you don't make the optimal move You're either not a sentient being or you didn't have the cards to make the optimal move.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: There's no game.
Scott: I mean you.
Scott: basically the hard part of this game Not that it's hard is just paying attention to all the cards you have in front of you.
Scott: If you you know Someone will lose like I had an ability on some cards in front of me.
Scott: that says if I have more cards in my hand Than Rym and is currently a fight going on.
Scott: I can deal damage to him for free of course if That situation arises.
Scott: I'm going to want to do that 100% of the time and it would be stupid not to Because it's free damage.
Scott: Why not?
Scott: You know, he starts out with less health than me because taiko has left health less health than Gabe.
Scott: That's how the game works.
Scott: So not dealing free damage is dumb.
Scott: But the hard part is just remembering that they're there and remembering to use them.
Scott: The person who loses this game is the person who just forgets to use all the cards they have available to them.
Rym: So at no point does skill enter into it.
Scott: No, all that matters is Reading all the cards you have knowing all the cards you have Looking at the other guy's cards knowing what they are.
Rym: You know, it's just knowing and spending hours actually learning how the rules work.
Scott: Yeah I mean, I don't know how a little kid if I bought this for a little kid How the hell would they play like a 15 year old kid?
Scott: How the hell would he figure it out?
Rym: You know what?
Rym: They weren't wouldn't care.
Rym: They'd read the rules once and they just play it wrong with each other.
Scott: Yeah, they probably would.
Scott: I played magic wrong the first time.
Scott: really we played magic the first time everything had trample and we thought trample did something else.
Scott: So like I would because it you know It kind of made sense.
Scott: if I attack with four and he defends with one I do three damage.
Scott: That made sense and you know for little kids.
Scott: Yeah, you know, but then the second time we played we went.
Scott: oh That's not right.
Scott: Hmm, and we fixed it up.
Scott: But at least that was easy to fix and we did that only with little tiny rule books that came with magic.
Scott: Think about the rule book that comes with.
Scott: this doesn't even come with an example of play not a single one.
Scott: I had to go online and there was a shoddily written example of play.
Rym: It's rambling and arbitrary.
Rym: The game is rambling and arbitrary and horrid.
Rym: horrid is the only word I can use to describe this game.
Rym: I cannot stress to you enough Do not buy the penny arcade game if you have any intention of playing well the penny arcade Collectible card game from saber-tooth games using the UFS.
Scott: There might be another penny arcade game in the future.
Rym: This is currently the only penny arcade game that you can buy with money.
Scott: Oh, I think there is a video game with some penny arcade mod.
Scott: But what this doesn't count.
Scott: now that doesn't count.
Scott: Yeah, this game is just bad bad bad bad.
Rym: now in addition to the game being bad the website of Universal fighting system, you know saber-tooth games.
Scott: In fact all the entire saber-tooth games website is atrocious.
Rym: I don't think they know how to use these interwebs.
Scott: They barely talk on their forums.
Rym: Yeah, they definitely did not hire Good web developers or anything.
Scott: They seem to be pretty good at publishing games though.
Scott: I mean, this is well put together.
Rym: Yeah high production values for the game too bad.
Rym: They didn't design a game for it.
Scott: Yeah, I Mean, I wonder if taiko knows.
Scott: taiko's a gamer and I'm sure he's tried to play his own game.
Scott: I wonder if he realizes it's crap.
Scott: He hasn't said anything about it.
Rym: Yeah, I'm really curious what they'll have to say.
Scott: I mean you.
Scott: if you really like penny arcade a whole lot and you better like it more than we like it and we like It a lot You should buy this for the you know, the art and the little stuff that comes with elk row.
Scott: Yeah velcro man beat that and the funny cards but That's only if you know, you never plan on playing it in the first place.
Scott: You're just gonna keep it there and then look at it and have fun with it.
Rym: I mean I know we're kind of ripping this apart and People who listen to GeekNights often know that we're kind of assholes about things like this.
Rym: But we're not kidding that.
Rym: we're not exaggerating.
Rym: This game is terrible.
Scott: If anyone wants to I will bring this to every convention I go to and if you want I will teach you Cuz I know all the rules now.
Scott: I will teach you how to play this game and play it with you.
Rym: much to your lament and you know what if you cry We're not going to feel sorry for you.
Scott: If you enjoy the game I'll sell it to you.
Rym: if you enjoy the price tell you what.
Rym: if you play the game with me and You enjoy it and you can tell me you enjoyed it with a straight face.
Rym: I'll just give you mine.
Rym: You can have it but straight face.
Rym: You got to keep a straight face for at least a minute while you tell me why the game is good Yeah, and what you enjoyed about it.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So tomorrow is the much-awaited New York comic-con wrap-up.
Rym: You know what more like a beat-up or we can talk about how we're gonna do themed weeks.
Rym: Well, it looks like this week is turning out to be suck week at least for two of the days Because the penny arcade game sucks and I hate to say it.
Rym: but the New York comic-con sucked too.
Scott: Yeah You know, I don't know what some other podcasts are saying especially comic-related ones about the New York comic-con.
Scott: you know, of course people who got in as opposed to people who did not get in or saying something different, but You'll hear all of what I have to say about my trip there and what happened tomorrow.
Rym: Yes, well at hmm the word debacle comes to mind.
Scott: yeah compare it to the 2005 US Formula One Grand Prix.
Scott: but Also Tomorrow I'm gonna teach you all about how comic books are distributed in North America and how it sucks.
Rym: Yeah, I'm holding in my hand a Bible Testament to evil Yep.
Rym: Yeah previews magazine or previews whatever.
Rym: That's a catalog.
Scott: I don't freaking know its previews.
Rym: Yeah, diamond comic if you've ever heard of previous God Yeah, it's it's the Holy Bible of crap.
Scott: Just just listen tomorrow and You'll learn all about why comic books in the u.s.
Scott: Suck and how I think they should be fixed.
Rym: And that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-15 37.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.