Rym: It's Monday April 24th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We bring you our live panel about podcasting from Toricon 2006.
Scott: let's do this.
Rym: So we're back and we're tired after a long weekend in Rochester.
Scott: Oh Yeah, I'm pretty tired.
Scott: Yeah driving how much total driving did I do?
Scott: like 600 something miles you drove?
Rym: 640 miles plus the driving around Rochester.
Scott: Yeah grumble grumble.
Rym: Yeah, screw you I once drove and I say this a lot, but I'm gonna say it again for the perp for all of our listeners out there.
Rym: I once drove from Poughkeepsie Which is by New York City to Lansing, Michigan and then two days later drove from Lansing, Michigan to Wildwood, New Jersey.
Scott: It's cuz you're stupid.
Rym: Actually was because I finished my co-op and I was technically with IBM and I was technically homeless for a month Not really a month like three weeks almost a month and I could have gone back wherever.
Rym: instead I drove out to Michigan to see my family because I hadn't seen him in a while and my brother was going to college And I promised him I'd see him and I couldn't afford to fly.
Rym: I was poor back then but I could afford to drive believe it or not.
Rym: And then I went to Wildwood and lived there with our friend Scott Johnson at his beach house for the rest of the summer.
Scott: Yeah, because you could afford to drive after you know, the repoed car.
Rym: Yeah, well see that the repoed car was way when I didn't have money Had money if you didn't spend the driving around like an idiot.
Rym: now the driving was real cheap.
Rym: It was a lot cheaper than flying and I really couldn't not visit my family.
Rym: I hadn't seen him in a while.
Scott: Well, if it were the gas prices what it is now, you'd be in big trouble.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: The gas prices weren't what they are right now.
Rym: In fact, they were quite low.
Scott: Yeah now it's what I think.
Scott: It's a paid 312 today at the good gas station.
Rym: Yeah now it probably would have been cheaper to fly.
Rym: if My life as it occurred many years ago occurred in this today who would have thought that jet fuel would be cheaper than car fuel?
Rym: Yeah, I think is that the airline industry isn't doing so well on its own.
Rym: Yeah, the jet blue price is actually going up not down but yeah, I got a real cheap flight out to an amazement Which I'm actually looking forward to quite a bit.
Scott: When is that?
Rym: Oh beginning of May middle of May sometime Maybe end of May.
Rym: I don't remember.
Rym: I got a plane ticket.
Rym: So I'm going.
Rym: I got to check and make sure and then We should go looking around.
Scott: Maybe there's like another convention We can go to.
Scott: they're missing maybe like a gaming one or something in the nearby area.
Rym: Well, we can hit ConnectiCon which I hear is really fun.
Scott: Isn't it like July or something?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: It's not in my con repertoire.
Scott: Yeah I pretty much I was like I've been like within a hair's distance of it.
Scott: I think I was at the school with the summer camp the day of the con at one point And I saw like an Inagasha cosplay running around in the field, but I didn't go to the con at all.
Scott: I just went home.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I mean I go to a lot more cons than you but that's because I started early Like I got hooked.
Scott: Yeah, I just you know I won't go very far put a lot of effort into a into a con unless it's Otakon unless I know.
Rym: yeah Now you should probably come to Katsucon next year.
Rym: It's really good Maybe but I digress cuz today's Monday and tech day and not anime day alright, but since our live show that we did at toricon was about podcasting and not about not Podcasting or anime.
Rym: so much it fits, you know tech podcasting.
Scott: Maybe we should have done a show about anime podcasts instead of I don't know.
Rym: Oh, well Yeah, our audience seemed to like what we did.
Rym: Yeah Okay, so Newsy have in the news New York State had a bit recently and a lot of people are pricing the headline that you can't be fired for surfing the internet While you're at work.
Scott: was this the guy who got fired by them by Bloomberg for playing solitaire?
Scott: I don't know if I was different guys.
Scott: I don't
Rym: know if it was him directly, but he is somewhat related to this that this issue came out partly because of him and basically the judge ruled in this suit that he was wrongfully fired the guy whoever the guy was because Surfing the internet and doing computer things is in this day and age no different From making a personal call while you're at work or reading the newspaper or hanging around the water cooler.
Scott: But I thought that New York is one of those states so they can fire you for whatever any reason they want.
Rym: Oh, yeah They can except that one company still.
Rym: If they're not if they could either give no reason at all or they can give a stated reason.
Rym: usually there's a company policy and They'll say like we fired you because you broke corporate instruction 916.
Rym: Don't masturbate to pornography in your office.
Scott: Hello Well, they can't fire you for discriminatory reasons like you're too old or you're black or we don't like you because you're.
Rym: though Here's a nice bit of trivia there.
Rym: There is a list of protected classes and you cannot discriminate based on those classes.
Rym: However, you can discriminate all you want openly to anyone that is not in one of those classes for any reason that has nothing to Do those classes?
Rym: I don't remember them all but you cannot discriminate based on age gender race religion Sexual orientation, but not in all states.
Rym: It's kind of stupid because some people are really backward and prejudice, but I digress Mm-hmm.
Rym: However, it is perfectly okay to discriminate based on obesity body body odor Um certain types of appearance.
Rym: It's complicated with appearance because you could discriminate against a guy who has say a tattoo of a spider across his face Yeah, but maybe not so much if he claimed that was part of his religion and gets all complicated at that point.
Scott: You said to have a spider my face part of our religion.
Scott: Yeah, haha.
Rym: But yeah, I think I mean basically a company.
Rym: if they're going to fire you they're going to fire you.
Scott: I think that a company should be allowed to fire, you know, pretty much whoever they want for almost whatever they want.
Rym: Yep, and it really is that way in New York.
Rym: Yeah, some states it isn't but there aren't many non right-to-work states left in this country.
Rym: the United States not.
Rym: We have a lot of foreign listeners.
Rym: I really got to not be so Us us us.
Scott: Yeah, I'd like to know what it's like in other countries.
Scott: Can people just fire anyone they want?
Scott: or is it you know their laws about?
Rym: we know how it is in France.
Rym: Nah I mean, I love France.
Rym: I'm some would consider me a Francophile, but god damn.
Rym: That's not the thing to protest about.
Scott: I mean if I could see the u.s.
Scott: Writing like they're firing us for browsing the web and listen to the podcast.
Scott: Let's a riot.
Rym: No, we riot when football team loses For all.
Scott: they're right.
Scott: when the soccer team loses.
Rym: no, they're right thing they write.
Rym: when their football team loses They play real football.
Scott: Well, they just call soccer football and we call football football.
Rym: Anyway football, I just think the news here is that we here's a judge who?
Rym: Recognizes that the internet is not special.
Rym: It's basically become as important and relevant to our lives as the telephone is.
Rym: It's something you just.
Rym: it's rare to see a judge who's on top of things.
Scott: Let's find the name of that judge and try to.
Scott: maybe he's a voted judge.
Scott: We had might have to vote for him.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: if he'd be in a district where we could vote for him It might be a state judge or something.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Yeah, but either way he should become a one-level-up judge.
Scott: Give him a little green and white mushroom.
Rym: Doo doo doo doo Yep, yeah, wait till my thing of the day tomorrow.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So what's your news?
Scott: So there's a big news about this Convention in Vegas right now or recently for the National Association of broadcasters.
Scott: hmm, those are like, you know the people who deal with the radio and TV broadcasting and and that shit.
Scott: and Apparently a bunch of nerds went there and they came back with some stories and The biggest story apparently is this camera called the big red one or the big red camera or whatever.
Rym: Is it red?
Scott: No, but it on the front of it looks really wicked cool.
Scott: Like wow all future II and shit Like there's a bunch of holes to mount stuff on it and it's really really professional like this is not something we will ever buy.
Rym: Yeah, granted.
Rym: We are not camera experts by any stretch.
Scott: This is something for like movie crews and film studios and TV shows.
Rym: I read us off the impressive part the specs.
Scott: Okay Well at first of all The only thing read about it is that it has this red light on the front to make.
Scott: that kind of makes it look like how.
Scott: So I just want to get that across.
Rym: so I'm sorry Dave I will not allow you to film yourself.
Rym: I was gonna make a joke about masturbate.
Scott: Yeah, that's the DRM.
Scott: is that this?
Scott: how is in there?
Scott: and if you try to videotape if you because this is a better quality Than your TV.
Scott: So if you try to film your TV to copy the video house, like I will not allow you to violate the DMCA.
Rym: That's not actually true.
Rym: Yeah Just making sure.
Scott: If it was I'd be great Just for the hilarity.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: Yeah Anyway, so there's a company called red digital cinema and the founder is the same guy who founded Oakley the sunglasses company.
Scott: So that's what part I think.
Scott: why the camera looks so cool is because you know, Oakley sunglasses look cool They ever tell everyone my law of sunglasses.
Rym: You might have but it might not be a recent episode to go nuts.
Scott: Oh, so the law just is a little Non sequitur little, you know tangent.
Scott: You can go to the like a I don't know the free bins that the Lions have for sunglasses and get sunglasses for free.
Scott: You can go to a flea market and get like $2 sunglasses.
Scott: You can go to a rest stop and get $10 sunglasses or you can go to like, you know The sporting goods store.
Scott: get Oakley's for like 200 bucks.
Scott: You can go to like sunglass Hut and get ray-bans for like 500 bucks, right theoretically the sunglasses I have cannot be gotten for any price.
Scott: Theoretically, yes.
Rym: Yeah, I told that story.
Scott: So yeah, but The what reason that sunglasses cost more money isn't because you know a sunglass that cost $100 is any better than the $10 Sunglass.
Scott: no, no No that the rule is that The more a sunglass cost the greater a percentage of the population will look good in them.
Scott: For example the $5 sunglasses from the flea market only look good in a very specific type of old lady.
Scott: The $10 sunglasses from the rest stop only look good on people like me and maybe people like, you know average-looking guys the hundred-dollar Oakley's look good on just about anyone who doesn't weigh more than 200 pounds and The $500 ray-bans look good on anyone with a human face.
Scott: That's that's the reason.
Scott: more expensive sunglasses are more expensive because they look good on anyone.
Rym: Yeah, though don't don't forget that there is a line about below which sunglasses are not only cheap but dangerous.
Rym: If you get like cheapo cheapo sunglasses, they're probably non polarized and they're probably not really protecting your eyes from UV rays.
Scott: Yeah, I'm just talking about the price to look good ratio I don't.
Scott: we're not talking about the quality of the lens and its sun protection or any of that.
Rym: Are you ever hear of a sunglass called blue blockers?
Scott: No.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I have a story about blue blockers that I'll say for another day.
Scott: Okay, so that's the law of sunglasses.
Scott: because just because the guy who founded Oakley founded this camera company Let's get to the camera.
Scott: The camera is an HD digital camera a video.
Scott: it can record 11.4 megapixel.
Scott: now I have a. what like a is it?
Scott: it's not even 10.
Scott: It's like a 5 or 6.
Rym: Yeah, the camera in my phone is a 1.4 megapixel.
Scott: Yeah, so My can my digital camera.
Scott: you can go to my flicker.
Scott: actually this toricon photos there.
Scott: Not many not many though cuz I suck and I don't use my camera enough that I spent so much money on.
Scott: cuz I don't Want to be like a photo guy anyway And you can see is a pretty damn good camera like really high resolution pictures.
Scott: This is 11.4 megapixels.
Scott: Holy shit, and it can take 11.4 megapixel pictures.
Scott: a second 60s like 60 FPS is holy shit.
Scott: considering TV is what like 32 Movies are like nothing.
Scott: So that's like holy crap pictures of digital.
Rym: now I think the really amazing thing here is the cost compared to those specs.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Scott: So you have this amazing amazing camera that takes like the most beautiful HD imagery ever.
Scott: it also comes with you know, the amazing sensor that lets this happen and You know storage to store all that crazy video and all this shit.
Scott: Now normally according to I don't know this because I'm not a camera guy But according to these professional camera guys who went there something like this they expect it to cost, you know $250,000 $200,000 something in the house range, you know get a house for $200,000 got bad.
Rym: Yeah, when I wear all over the place the cheapest house anywhere near us is at least half a million.
Scott: That's a really fancy house.
Scott: No, no, that's like a four-bedroom or five-bedroom house.
Rym: You realize that There's a housing development right near us that has crap.
Rym: Oh like subdivision houses the same houses you see in any subdivision suburb anywhere.
Rym: six seven hundred thousand.
Scott: Well, that's just nuts.
Rym: Yeah, there's no cheap houses here.
Rym: I would kill if this house cost two hundred thousand right now that we're living in.
Rym: I'd buy it in a second.
Scott: There are two hundred thousand dollar houses.
Rym: Yeah, not here.
Scott: Anyway now where we live That's not the point.
Scott: The point is is that two hundred thousand dollars is like a house price.
Scott: this camera costs Car price.
Scott: we're talking $17,500.
Rym: Yeah, like definitely not low budget But definitely not high budget like by any means.
Scott: in other words if you were setting up Take to make a movie a digital movie and you know, you're gonna use film You just buy a whole shit ton of these instead of buying one of the normal cameras.
Scott: yeah, or if you're gonna make I don't know a Really professional video podcast just scoop one of these babies up.
Scott: You know.
Rym: nice easy independent houses art houses little film houses.
Scott: Yeah, you're gonna see independent movies looking a lot better if this thing isn't fake.
Rym: now I'll point out that there is one big problem with that is that When you have a camera that high quality and you're recording at that high quality The all the other factors become a lot more important.
Rym: now the makeup has to be a lot better The lighting has to be a lot better Thing and the framing have to be a lot better, but at the same time couldn't you know, I'm not a I'm not an expert.
Rym: So yeah, I know what you're gonna say because I was just thinking that as I was saying since your image is so perfect Can you just bring it back down?
Scott: Yeah, I figure you could just compress it back down and then all the mistakes go away.
Scott: But then you have a really high quality source material to work with.
Rym: Yep, because I know that's how we do it with audio.
Scott: Yeah, now I think this thing's like a 30 millimeter lens, but you can buy a 300 millimeter lens for $5,000.
Rym: Now, of course, there's a tiny chance that this is semi vaporware.
Scott: Yeah, apparently like it was locked in a cage and shit.
Scott: So no one would mess around with it.
Scott: But the pictures of it look wicked awesome and if it's real expect awesome things to start showing up in Independent movie theaters and TV shows and all sorts of stuff expect a lot more HDTV Things of the day.
Rym: now many of people who know us realize that we're not particularly into that whole alcohol thing.
Scott: No alcohol not so good Poison.
Rym: very few of us drink at all and even the ones who drink I mean, I enjoy wine a lot and things like that.
Rym: But we our group of friends really doesn't get into that whole standing there holding a red solo cup Culture yeah, and anything, you know more or Somewhat less or sideways from alcohol.
Scott: No one does.
Rym: I don't think anyone smokes weed or smokes or no one we're really friends with currently does any drugs.
Rym: a few people did in the past and Interesting stories as a result, but drugs are bad and gay.
Rym: Well, the thing is I mean, I enjoy alcohol.
Rym: I really like wine and sake and that sort of thing now.
Rym: I Really don't like dealing with people who are drunk.
Scott: I Don't like being drunk.
Scott: Of course I've never been drunk because I don't drink.
Scott: but yeah, I know I don't like it.
Rym: I've been drunk and there's a level of drunkenness that is fun and it is not very much drunkenness because beyond that it is not fun.
Scott: If I'm eating no good, yeah, I mean you vomited everyone's vomited.
Scott: Yeah, it's not nice.
Scott: So why don't vomit if you if you vomited on by accident or because he ate something bad or because you were sick with like The flu.
Rym: Yeah now don't do it on purpose and more importantly don't do to yourself What the guy in the video that is my thing of the day did Don't want to be this guy.
Scott: I mean, I'm never gonna be that guy.
Rym: I mean god damn it's funny Because this guy's drunk and he can't stand up and some kid has like a handicam and he's just filming it and The guy just can't stand up.
Rym: He's so drunk.
Scott: Yeah, I guess not being able to stand up is a little better than vomiting.
Scott: I imagine whoever he is already vomited copiously Perhaps but perhaps he is such an old Disgruntled drunken hobo that he doesn't vomit anymore.
Rym: Haha It just kind of oozes out of him and turns into those clothes.
Rym: Hobos wear exactly not hobos winos.
Rym: Some hobos are cool.
Scott: I think hobos technically are the people who do work.
Scott: So I don't think he was a hobo.
Scott: I think he's a bum.
Rym: I think he was just like, uh, you know what?
Rym: He's probably a former college frat guy.
Scott: He ended up homeless, how do you go from college to homeless?
Rym: alcohol?
Rym: Oh Pund Yeah, I mean definitely we're not prohibitionists.
Rym: We're not against alcohol.
Rym: I hate him.
Rym: Yeah freedom random.
Rym: But uh, yeah, if you're like this guy, I'm not going to help you off the street Nor will I respect you?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah or possibly even talk to you or recognize your existence as a worthwhile Living organism.
Scott: Yeah, the the the bacteria on my foot might get more respect.
Rym: Perhaps bacteria are dangerous little bastards.
Scott: They are they are they don't get drunk.
Scott: They're smart.
Scott: Yep Not getting drunk.
Scott: All right, so I'm sure everyone has played the types of video games.
Scott: You know where you walk sideways.
Scott: and yeah, you beat things up.
Rym: Final Fight River City Ransom Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles 2 and 3 and Streets of Rage Simpsons.
Scott: Yeah, all those the the beat-em-up the 8-man x-men game.
Scott: Oh the 8-man x-men game.
Scott: Oh, isn't it 6?
Scott: It was four for the little one and six for the big.
Rym: Yeah, it's just the one with two screens.
Rym: that's right and a bunch of nerds with a pile of quarters.
Scott: I think there was also a cheap for the cheap.
Scott: arcades had the four-person version.
Scott: We had to crowd around one TV.
Scott: Yeah, that one wasn't so good.
Scott: Anyway Some guy made an animation.
Scott: It appears to be that he made it with flash, but it's an MPEG if you download it and He created it.
Scott: What is this?
Scott: an animated short?
Scott: Which is just like one of those games.
Rym: only it's not a game.
Scott: it's not.
Scott: it's not really a game.
Rym: I tell him the title.
Scott: Oh my god, it's pirate babies cabana battle street fight.
Rym: That is probably the best title.
Scott: or is it super ever had a battle street fight 2006?
Rym: All I got to say is pirate baby is an awesome villain.
Scott: Yeah, this I didn't know.
Scott: I Was told the name of this and then I said this better live up to the name.
Rym: Yes, two of our listeners sent me links to this last night But since I was dead from Tarakhan I hadn't even looked at him yet and then I Scott showed this to me and then I realized that that's what you'd link me To.
Scott: yeah, everyone had seen this already probably while we were away for the weekend.
Scott: But yeah, I would have probably seen it yesterday if I was home.
Scott: But you know, we wouldn't do a show till Monday anyway, and even if everyone's seen it This is just so good that even if one person out there has not seen this yet.
Scott: They got to go.
Rym: yeah, because there are some videos we have that are from the internet that if we if all of our friends 20 of us 30 of us are sitting around in our living room and One person says, huh badger mushroom.
Rym: What now?
Rym: I never seen that.
Rym: Or NASA.
Rym: Well, who's NASA?
Rym: it is cold We all we suddenly jump to the TV turn out the computer and watch it.
Scott: yep, you don't know what radis skull is.
Scott: Oh my god.
Rym: All right, as an aside if any of you out there don't know who radis skull is rad Is ku ll as in I am the radis skull and I will kill you one by one just for fun.
Scott: Yeah, so this video way cool if you like.
Scott: walk sideways beat-em-up games.
Scott: there's a lot of things in here that are total cliches like the video screen in the back with the repeating image of the villain and You know the way the bosses work and the weapons and the special it.
Scott: There's a really the thing that keeps you going because it would get kind of boring but they keep doing different special attacks that are all humorous in some way and The graphics are really authentic.
Scott: if if monochrome it is definitely an homage Super homage, I mean you'll even notice stuff in there like the Megaman octopus and Such and the Christopher Walken.
Rym: Oh Christopher Walken my hero.
Scott: So if you haven't seen this go watch it.
Scott: It's freaking awesome.
Rym: Yeah, there's a lot of cowbell in this game too much cowbell.
Rym: In fact, so moving on to the main bit We're actually going to play since we realized that we went to torque on over the weekend.
Rym: as we've said many times I know I didn't just realize that I went to torque on.
Rym: I realized that The show we recorded live in front of a real audience at torque on Had nothing to do with anime and we basically just talked about podcasting.
Scott: Yeah, so why would we play it on Thursday when we have plenty of things to talk about on Thursday?
Scott: I mean Wednesday as a boat.
Scott: Yeah as opposed to Monday when we don't have Ideas awesome.
Rym: So I suppose without further ado here it is our live show from torque on entirely unedited.
Scott: Oh my god.
Rym: So, uh, I'm Rym, I'm Scott and this is GeekNights, let's do this All right.
Rym: I'd like to say that this is our first stop on the first ever GeekNights tour of nowhere.
Rym: Well, actually we're going.
Scott: we're going to Otakon.
Rym: Yeah, we're been invited As panelists.
Rym: an amazement.
Rym: we're doing a show.
Rym: Well, I'm doing a show.
Rym: Katsucon found out that we were there last year.
Rym: We are now guests of Katsucon next year and we're gonna be running part of the video game room possibly Yep, so at least we got a show going there.
Scott: Yeah, and all the other conventions that we may or may not go to as we desire.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway, uh, we do a podcast.
Rym: now at any you listen to podcasts.
Rym: Any idea what a podcast is?
Rym: ever heard the word podcast?
Rym: alright a Podcast is basically just internet radio, which has been around for a long time only done.
Rym: Well, it actually works and a lot of people are starting to use it.
Scott: Yeah in the olden days you've wanted to listen to radio on the internet.
Scott: it was pretty much streaming.
Scott: you had to go at the time they were talking and push a button and Who knows if it would work or not?
Scott: It was real media and the quality was low and you couldn't hear anything.
Scott: Sometimes it wouldn't even work.
Rym: It was just terrible Yeah, and it really didn't take off at all.
Rym: So Apple and their infinite wisdom decided to push this thing called podcasting which when I heard about it I thought it sounded stupid because I didn't really understand it.
Scott: Yeah, it was actually not invented by Apple is the actual technology behind.
Scott: It was made by some other people a little earlier, but no one cares.
Rym: Yeah, it has very little to do.
Rym: You don't need an iPod.
Rym: You don't need iTunes.
Rym: Don't even need to like Apple.
Scott: You just need a computer.
Rym: all it is is syndicated audio or even video.
Rym: basically You subscribe to a feed which we could talk on length about that and then anytime whatever the feed is updates you get the mp3 File or whatever file it is automatically downloaded to whatever computer mp3 player you have.
Rym: so gig nights We are four nights a week.
Rym: So every weeknight a new gig nights episode appears around midnight one depending on when we finish.
Scott: Yet, so it's really just mp3s that you download that someone makes it's really all it is.
Scott: Yes with a fancy name with the word pod in it in to make it Harder to get people to listen because they think oh I need an iPod.
Scott: No, you don't need an iPod.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, I mean some of the big podcasts have what 50 60 thousand listeners.
Scott: I think there's some company.
Scott: they said their goal is to get like 500 million total podcast listeners in the world.
Scott: I don't know how close they are to getting that but there's a whole lot of people.
Rym: Yeah I mean I'd really say that I mean you all know the webcomic boom how mega Tokyo got popular and Exploded and then webcomics exploded.
Rym: Podcasts are probably about a year or two right before where mega Tokyo and all that was before webcomics exploded.
Rym: So it's kind of a niche market and it's gonna explode one day.
Scott: It's like when it first came about, you know, some people got into it and then iTunes actually implemented podcast support.
Scott: So then it exploded some more and now it's kind of gradually growing as like real companies make Podcasts like penny arcade just came out with one that like jumped to number 12. that beats out like ESPN and stuff.
Rym: It's Penn Jillette.
Rym: if Penn & Teller has a podcast.
Rym: That's fairly awesome.
Scott: Yeah, well, he does like a real radio show one hour every day every weekday.
Scott: So he just he got his radio company to start putting those on the internet and he took the ads out Which makes it a lot more pleasant to listen to.
Rym: yep now I mean, it's basically like radio.
Rym: Usually it's talk radio.
Rym: A lot of people do techno or music.
Rym: There's actually a lot of good music out there like normal radio.
Rym: They'll play techno from South Africa or something cool like that.
Scott: Yeah, that's one.
Scott: My favorite podcast is what I think it's Derek the Bandit Sound Republic.
Scott: All it is is electronic music from South Africa.
Scott: This guy's in Johannesburg South Africa taking his techno music and other people's techno music and like every once in a while He makes one big mp3 of it and you get it automatically and then you listen in the car.
Rym: It's great And I mean a lot of the content is creative commons or free or there's no copyright involved.
Rym: so you can just play it Share it whatever and the artists really don't care.
Scott: Yeah You get in big trouble if you put like real music like if I went and got like the Beatles music and put in my Podcast and they found out I get sued sued sued sued.
Scott: So what you do is there's all these musical artists who are you know independent?
Scott: Maybe they're really local to one area and To get you know their music out there in the world is they say hey everyone if you want to podcast my music go for It and it's called pod safe music and that's what most people use.
Scott: because then you won't get sued and you help out some independent Artists somewhere.
Rym: Yeah, but I mean we don't play music.
Rym: I don't listen to any of the music podcast.
Rym: We just do a talk show get nights a late-night talk show for geeks.
Rym: Think like the late show or late night with whoever whoever only with us.
Scott: And Not so often is there a guest?
Rym: Yeah, every now and then we get guests.
Rym: We really haven't had any big guests yet Though we've had some big names.
Rym: agree to future interviews?
Scott: Yeah, it's the technology really behind interviews is a little tricky sometimes.
Rym: Yeah, we can answer anything like that in questions.
Rym: I don't know how much you care about the technical details of trying to interview someone far off in a way.
Rym: Though our best guest so far was how many of you know Mike Pfeffer?
Rym: Alright, how many of you know Jewish wolf would?
Scott: Jewish would is Mike Pfeffer.
Rym: He doesn't like to be known as Jewish wolf would It actually?
Rym: he asked us specifically not to refer to him as Jewish wolf would be
Scott: referred
Scott: to him as Jewish
Scott: Wolf would only once in the recorded part of the show.
Rym: Yep But anyway, we decided to do this partly because we went to RIT.
Rym: We both graduated.
Rym: I ran this anime club for three years.
Rym: I Founded the cosplay.
Rym: that happened right this time the year before Tora Khan was founded the next year by the president after me.
Rym: So we've been around a while.
Rym: we both graduated all our friends graduated and we always talked about doing a radio show.
Rym: Well, well friends talked about.
Rym: our original idea was a little different Yeah But it was basically we would sit around and talk and people who didn't know us would laugh a lot At the things we said.
Scott: looking at some people out there.
Rym: Yeah, like they were just it was hysterical to them.
Rym: We couldn't figure out why and people always said you should just record yourselves do a radio show.
Scott: So one day, you know when I got my little nano You know actually used iTunes because the stupid work laptop with windows.
Scott: Yeah, we don't use windows.
Scott: But you know, I discovered how look I'll actually try this podcasting thing and I was like You know what?
Scott: It's real easy to make one of these damn podcasts.
Scott: Let's freakin do it.
Rym: Yep, and shit talk I love audio and all that stuff.
Rym: So I immediately went out and bought a bunch of professional equipment and it's not that professional.
Rym: I mean as professional as we're ever gonna get unless we get syndicated by someone with money.
Scott: It's as professional as pretty much anyone needs.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, so if you want to make a podcast which you might or might not want to do depending.
Scott: all you really need like minimum Is a microphone and a computer an Apple computer?
Scott: It makes it a lot easier if you don't know about technology because then you can use garage band garage band.
Rym: Hit a button your podcast appears in iTunes.
Scott: Yeah, it's dead stupid If you have an Apple computer, if you don't have an Apple computer, it's a little bit trickier, but whatever.
Rym: But there are a lot of podcasts out there that are just like one dude ranting about Linux or one, dude.
Rym: There's a podcast for everything.
Rym: What was the weird one?
Rym: We found it was a South African housing market.
Scott: No, that was the Australian.
Scott: There's an Australian real estate podcast.
Scott: Yeah, there's a very popular podcast only about knitting like Knitting.
Scott: Yeah, and it's it's old ladies talking about knitting and knitting techniques and all this or their freaking radio shows about everything.
Scott: There's one where it's just independent music from Scotland.
Scott: Yeah, it's very very popular.
Rym: It'll make you feel really rich.
Rym: It's this guy and he summarizes the New York Times for you every day.
Scott: Well, it's actually yet.
Scott: That's actually made by the New York Times.
Scott: It's a new.
Scott: it's an official New York Times podcast and the guy summarizes the front page of every second.
Rym: You've got like a little butler sitting there just reading it to you while you're having your morning coffee.
Scott: The onion radio news is also pretty good.
Scott: This guy comes on with like a two-minute podcast every day Just reading like the headline of an onion story in a quick summary and it's much funnier than reading the actual onion.
Rym: because yes The onions I guess is degraded over the years.
Rym: Yeah Now they're also videocast which are the same just with video Except it's a lot harder to do video for reasons that a lot of RIT students probably know very well.
Scott: Yeah, some of the popular video podcasts a ninja ask a ninja has a ninja.
Scott: ask a ninja is hilarious.
Rym: If any of you've never heard of ask a ninja I recommend checking them out.
Scott: ask a ninja calm.
Rym: It's a dude dressed up like a ninja answering questions.
Scott: That's it.
Rym: Like ask a ninja.
Rym: How do you kill someone?
Scott: Well How fast do you want me to kill them and how painfully you know?
Scott: I look forward to killing you soon.
Scott: Yeah But now that homestar runner actually converted to like video podcast format now so you can just subscribe to strong bads email Whenever there's a new strong bad email just it shows up and you watch it.
Scott: You don't have to do anything.
Scott: You don't have to visit homestar runner every damn day now.
Rym: We'd like to talk a lot about the show We do now.
Rym: I mean we're recording this now and we're gonna put it on the air next Wednesday on anime day Wednesday Wednesday night.
Scott: So it's really Thursday for normal people unless you sit up all night and wait and then it like around midnight 1 a.m Just there.
Rym: it is because that was the big idea We had is every podcast updates like Monday morning and it's usually once a week.
Rym: So we update at night and you know, it's a late show, but those shows are recorded like Sunday at 11 a.m.
Rym: So we actually record at night mostly because we have jobs and we're lazy.
Scott: Yeah, so while our show we say Monday night Tuesday night Wednesday night Thursday night It's really Tuesday morning Wednesday morning Thursday morning Friday.
Rym: Oh some of our fans I sit there and I'm doing post-production late at night and suddenly right around midnight when I start getting messages Hey, the show's not up yet something wrong.
Rym: Hey, where's my show?
Scott: Yeah, yeah, but actually we're pretty consistent.
Rym: We've missed what one show or something cuz I was at it missed one other show because I screwed up and deleted it after we Recorded it.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: You forget.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, well we did another show But actually that's the worst we lost.
Scott: we lost half the show and what we did is we put the half the show we still Had up on the internet and then we put a sorry Rym deleted it thing in the other half.
Rym: cuz honestly I mean we just talk and talk and talk.
Rym: but imagine if you had to do something like taught to give a speech on the fly And then you had to give it again.
Rym: You really don't have the energy to say the same things.
Rym: Like if I crack a joke, I can't crack the same joke again.
Rym: And if I try it just sounds stupid.
Rym: So if we lose an episode, we're just done we cry and go to sleep.
Scott: It's our podcast really isn't scripted or written like beforehand so we can't just read it again.
Scott: It's you know We just bring up whatever topic it is and then we just talk and then if we've already had the discussion How can we have the same discussion again and have it be so genuine?
Scott: It would just be us going.
Rym: Yeah, yep.
Rym: So uh, so yeah, that's so we actually force ourselves to not talk about things We're gonna talk about on the show like if there's news about I don't know Microsoft CEO kills Someone and a baby ninja.
Rym: I don't know something crazy.
Rym: We acknowledge that the news exists, but we won't talk about it till we turn the mics on at night.
Scott: We usually what we talked about before is we'll be like, alright Do we want to do this one or that one?
Scott: You know because it's really hard to pick two news stories a day because some days there's like 20 news stories And it's like oh my god, which two are the best.
Scott: and some days is like all this news is boring as hell.
Rym: Yeah, the news that other people that was important people bothers about it until we talk about it.
Rym: Yeah like to no end Mmm.
Rym: now we really could talk a lot about how we do the show and the show itself.
Rym: But first before we get into that You guys have any questions about podcasting Podcasts everyone is you can come up here and get on the air with us if you like or you can just ask your question And we'll do our thing.
Rym: Why don't you?
Rym: we had a mic right here?
Rym: We're we're on ball run the ball.
Scott: So I was wondering how long?
Rym: between when you record your?
Scott: Well, okay for us it's different than most people.
Scott: Yeah, we pretty much record it and then Rym starts editing it and then he puts it on the internet that night.
Rym: Yep Well, it most podcast.
Rym: they'll record over the course of like four hours and they'll do like a show once a week or once a month and then they'll spend hours and hours editing and cutting down until They make like this thing that they can put up.
Rym: We really don't edit.
Rym: What do you hear is exactly what we said cutting out like when Scott burps.
Scott: do we cut out burps coughs?
Scott: Um, like um, like Yeah, those are big long pauses Anything like that.
Scott: we cut out, but we don't cut out anything.
Scott: we say that's English words.
Rym: Now it used to.
Rym: when we first started it took me about two hours to do the post-production.
Rym: I mean I had to run all these filters dynamic range compression and normalization, which if anyone wants to know I can go to Excruciating painful detail about and then we bought this machine.
Rym: Yes, then we bought this machine here Which took all that out of the equation.
Rym: so now and now I've gotten good at editing.
Rym: it takes about 20 minutes total and that includes the time it takes to encode it to mp3 on my slow ass computer that I bought six and Years ago, yeah
Scott: right now the major things that take a lot of time are his slow ass computer and uploading the file and then waiting for the stupid Hosting company to get the file and get it properly set up and then typing up the notes for the show.
Scott: So yeah, that's the hard part which isn't hard.
Rym: Normally just we do four shows a week Which is kind of crazy like we have more episodes than friggin any other podcast out there with a few exceptions.
Scott: Yeah, there are podcasts that are like old way older than us.
Scott: how long we've been going since I got since over of 2005?
Rym: it's over 2005 four nights a week.
Rym: So we've got 97 episodes up plus the 11 beta episodes that none of you will ever hear.
Scott: Yeah, you're never gonna hear those but their podcast been going since like 2004 which is when it really started.
Scott: But they have like a hundred episodes maybe even less.
Scott: There's something like 20 episodes.
Scott: you do one a month or something like that.
Scott: We already we're coming up on a hundred.
Scott: Yeah, what number is this one?
Rym: This is gonna be 90.
Rym: Well, this is gonna be 101 cuz it'll be later.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: All right any questions anyone you want to come up you wanna.
Rym: So we've got Kate here who's walking up toward the state.
Rym: I don't wanna have dead air cuz that means I have to cut it out later.
Rym: I really hate having to edit so I try to avoid it at all cost.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: It's on just talk unless she turned it off.
Rym: Is there any subject that's completely off-limits?
Rym: considering the episode we did last Thursday, you know Here's the thing about aim and nothing is out of bounds.
Scott: well at least for us.
Scott: you see the thing about Podcasting is there's no rating system.
Scott: There's no nothing like that.
Scott: But on iTunes specifically there's this explicit tag and you can't really it sucks because you can't put in a split Explicit tag on just one episode.
Scott: your I your podcast is either explicit Which means it's really dirty and you talk about sex and drugs and violence and God knows what.
Rym: there are a lot of.
Scott: There are quite a few.
Scott: that sees there does a Nazi podcast out there?
Rym: wait Nazi is a neo-nazi.
Scott: No, as in it's a yelling white supremacist guy.
Scott: Oh Yeah, and everyone like demanded he'd be taken off a bunch of lists.
Scott: It's a crazy story.
Scott: Anyway, there are other podcasts which are just nothing.
Scott: they're playing which means they might say shit They might say whatever but you know, they were rated between pg-13 and our.
Scott: yeah for our show.
Scott: Yeah Um, but other shows, you know, we're just mostly normal.
Scott: now if your show is guaranteed You're never gonna curse, you know, you're gonna bleep out all the bad stuff.
Scott: You're gonna cut out anything little kids shouldn't hear.
Scott: you can put a clean tag on it and that can't put the clean tag.
Scott: We can't put the clean tag, but we don't put the explicit tag either.
Rym: It's like a magic word.
Scott: Yeah, you see it's not.
Scott: if you put on a real radio show the FCC can come down and you like a ton of bricks If you say fuck.
Scott: Oh But if you just put an mp3 somewhere for people to download what are they gonna do to you?
Scott: Yeah, you can say whatever the hell you want now.
Rym: I mean it is GeekNights.
Rym: We're geeks.
Rym: We talk about geekery.
Rym: so we basically broke it up into four like days of the week and the scary thing is that each one of our days is Pretty much a full-on podcast by itself.
Rym: are like Mondays.
Rym: We do science technology Linux all that sort of stuff.
Rym: Tuesdays are gaming video gaming board games all that.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime and manga and comics and despite the fact that it's just one day of the week for us It's pretty much the biggest anime podcast out there.
Scott: Well, it's not the biggest one out.
Rym: Yeah, we shuffle between number one number two and number three on Yahoo podcasts for anime.
Scott: Yeah, Yahoo podcasts are just a little sketchy, but another good one.
Rym: I'll recommend them right now and give them a shout out.
Rym: anime world order is really good anime world order.
Scott: These people like they're older school fans than we are and they're a little fanboy and fangirl.
Rym: ish.
Scott: But at the same time they know everything.
Scott: like we did an episode about Lupin and We pretty much got everything wrong except Zenigata.
Scott: So the guy sends me this giant email telling me Excruciating details about every other character and all this stuff that we missed and I was like, okay You guys know everything about anime is to know.
Rym: now Thursdays.
Rym: We decide we couldn't come up with anything.
Rym: So we decided it's like special topics, which means whatever the hell we want to talk about.
Rym: Usually we rant about things.
Rym: Sometimes we do interesting things like last Thursday.
Scott: Yeah, some of our most popular Thursdays were like toys of our youth.
Rym: Yeah, that episode has been linked to more than other than with one exception is our most linked to episode.
Scott: Yeah, TV shows of our youth.
Rym: Yeah, we talked about Thundercats once.
Scott: how not to suck at college.
Scott: How not to.
Scott: that's one of our things.
Scott: how not to suck.
Scott: Yeah, how to not suck.
Rym: Right grammar captain.
Scott: grammar captain Graham.
Scott: Mr.
Rym: Perry will be all over you.
Scott: Maybe you will all right.
Rym: It looks like someone in the audience is excited to ask a question So I guess he can come up and grab a mic unless he's not willing to step up to the challenge.
Scott: He's planning on asking a question, but we got him.
Rym: We have always had this question for you.
Rym: Oh, how how do you get that perfect European hair of yours to stay ever so beautiful?
Rym: Well one herbal essences Conditioner - I condition twice.
Scott: don't you do something else of the conditioning?
Rym: I'm a homies fan.
Rym: I would refer to you to previous Thursdays episode if you want to know more about that topic.
Scott: How many times are we gonna beat around this bush?
Rym: That's are you?
Rym: that's a rather.
Rym: that's a rather loaded statement.
Scott: I think we'll leave it at that.
Rym: Actually, we put a pseudo explicit tag on that one episode so we wouldn't get in trouble.
Rym: Plus we had disclaimers like every five minutes in the beginning.
Scott: Yeah It's another thing that some you got to watch out with some anime podcasts because they won't tell you when they're gonna spoil something.
Scott: We have our thing called the spoiler line.
Scott: Like if we talk about a show We'll talk about it and then when we're gonna start spoiling it we say this is the spoiler line.
Scott: Stop listening now, if you haven't watched the show, we'll say it like ten times.
Rym: then we're like, yeah Everybody dies at the end of something.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Yeah, as soon as you're over that line, it's all your fault.
Rym: Okay, any more questions about podcasting any?
Rym: Well, I think we've tapped the well here.
Scott: Well didn't have so much water in it.
Rym: No, not really Can't stop beating this dead horse.
Rym: Don't be shy.
Rym: don't be shy.
Rym: got to keep filling the dead air.
Rym: Hold the mic closer to your face.
Scott: Sorry about that Kissing the mic here.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Um, how much does it cost to get?
Scott: Listed on Nothing, nothing.
Rym: Nothing.
Rym: All you have to do is submit it have at least five episodes and not be terrible.
Rym: Usually someone looks at it.
Rym: if your podcast is terrible or your feed is broken or something isn't working I choose the email you and say man you suck go away.
Scott: Yeah, and iTunes is you'd like.
Scott: some people complain about them because they do sort of sketchy stuff.
Scott: They'll be like they unlisted my feed Those bastards But other times it's like okay your your podcast is like.
Scott: You know bleep bleep bleep in the title and you didn't put an explicit tag on it.
Scott: Apple sends them an email.
Scott: You better put an explicit tag on it or we're not gonna list you, you know bad about bleep bleep bleep.
Rym: What's your robot?
Scott: This is a dirty robot podcast.
Scott: Actually, I see it would only made two episodes and then it went away.
Scott: That's how I just made it up.
Rym: Hmm.
Rym: There's actually there's a big issue.
Rym: They call it pod fading.
Rym: Yeah, I hate the fact that people come up with these silly.
Rym: We've got someone else in the back who's excited which means she is now on the spot to ask a question and she seems No, she's hiding.
Rym: Okay, she's hiding whatever.
Rym: It is yuko aka.
Rym: I do of Fallen fame among other things.
Rym: and now that she's on the spot.
Rym: She has to ask a question.
Rym: I'm killing that air here again.
Rym: Our podcast called GeekNights, we've already covered all that.
Rym: you don't need to show.
Rym: Tell me about your most controversial.
Scott: We already talked about that.
Rym: Conrad asked me about my hair.
Rym: Bubba boo-boo-boo-boo-boo-boo-boo-boo-boo-boo-boo-boo-boo-boo-boo.
Rym: what family guy?
Scott: Okay Are you sure?
Rym: nothing what I pod fading.
Rym: for some reason everyone in this it's like webcomic art isn't come up with like names For all their like things.
Rym: and this is the same kind of thing.
Rym: Most podcasts don't make it to ten episodes.
Rym: Yeah, a lot of you really into it.
Rym: They start a podcast They suck they stop and the podcast disappears.
Scott: a lot of people get into podcasting.
Scott: They think oh, this will be so easy.
Scott: I'll plug a mic into my laptop and I'll record a show but then they don't really have anything to talk about.
Scott: Or they only do it when they feel like it and they don't do it regularly Or the one fanboy talking about his favorite hentai every day.
Scott: Yeah, and Those podcasts don't stick around for more than like two episodes and then they die.
Scott: But all the episodes are still there in iTunes.
Scott: Yeah, and it's called pod fading.
Scott: because you'll go around and you'll find this podcast pod fading.
Rym: people call it pod.
Rym: Yeah, that's right sucking.
Scott: Yeah, but you'll go around you'll find some great podcast and then after like seven episodes They'd be like no more and you'll never see another one.
Scott: You'd be like god damn it.
Scott: It's like if a TV show just ends and it wasn't canceled or anything.
Scott: just go.
Rym: What was that good video game when you were listening to?
Scott: that disappeared those gamers of jobs radio?
Scott: They did 25 episodes and then the the guy went to work for the escapist so they had to stop it.
Rym: Yeah, that's really too bad.
Rym: I wonder if they should start something up again.
Scott: Yeah, maybe because there really aren't any good video game podcasts because they're they all suck except for that one.
Rym: All right.
Rym: We got another guy here with the question.
Rym: Hey, Rym and Scott Do you like how I covered just coming up here and not having to like fill dead air.
Scott: That's fine Before you don't need to be introduced.
Rym: I'm our boy.
Rym: I've been on the show before once to talk about non food.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: It was awesome.
Scott: We'll have you on some time talking about our related things.
Rym: I have an actual question for you right here at the the lovely Tora con at the.
Rym: yes, we are in fact campus.
Rym: Yes, what are you guys going to be doing about the con?
Rym: that that you are going to maybe talk about either another podcast or?
Rym: Well, honestly, we did a whole series on anime conventions and gaming conventions and one how to not suck it going to them Because a lot of our friends it's a good running theme how to not suck at things with us.
Rym: a lot of people We've known have gone to cons and screwed something up Like the hotel was broken or their friends are all idiots.
Rym: They got into a fight or just craziness.
Scott: Yeah, and a lot of people go to cons and then they don't really.
Scott: they don't know how to get the maximum enjoyment out of The con.
Scott: so he did a thing on that too.
Rym: Yeah, but ourselves we really only go to cons to do stuff like this.
Rym: I mean I speak on panels at like every con I go to and Once again, I'm here speaking on a panel.
Rym: Yeah, and we hang out with our friends and play DS games.
Scott: Yeah, the DS is like revitalized the whole convention scene because now every convention is Yeah, pick up the mic.
Rym: It's I know again What panels were you guys all All right.
Rym: The long story short is that at Ohio con - we all bunch of us went and we went into the anime club summit panel And no one was there to run it.
Rym: so being the kinds of people that we are we sat down in the front pretended it was ours and ran it and Then we went to Otakon that year and the same thing happened.
Rym: So we sat down and ran it only this time.
Rym: the staffers said hey You guys know what you're talking about.
Rym: run the panel forever.
Scott: and you ran that panel for like three years.
Rym: four years four years And I'm still running it this year.
Rym: I mean my friend Scott Johnson.
Scott: and now we had another panel.
Rym: Yeah, anime central.
Rym: the same thing happened.
Rym: Katsucon.
Rym: I don't speak at it, but one of my friends does and I usually kind of slip my way in Katsucon.
Rym: we're gonna do stuff at like.
Rym: I said before toro khan.
Rym: Obviously, we come back every year since we're alums.
Scott: Yeah, that's always a big advantage.
Rym: Yeah, so basically we warmed our way in and we just stayed Alright.
Rym: back to DS.
Scott: is the DS is like the king of the convention scene?
Scott: Yeah, anytime there's a grouping of geeks the DS is like All right, I'm up ripping out.
Rym: their DS is All right.
Scott: We're all good.
Rym: All right, we've got another question.
Rym: This is a Brian of instant classic fame.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Hi Is there life beyond podcasting?
Rym: Is there anything to strive from now that you're on this level?
Rym: Well, actually there are a lot of directions to go because we're growing at a rate.
Rym: That's kind of scary for one since we didn't start that long ago.
Rym: We haven't advertised.
Scott: Yeah, we haven't advertised at all.
Rym: Advertisers tried to make money straight up.
Rym: as in I'm gonna sell my podcast.
Rym: those people have all failed.
Scott: Well, some of them had a little bit of success, but generally like one guy.
Scott: He's like some famous British dude, like Ricky Jervis or something like that.
Scott: I don't know, but he had a podcast that was yeah, maybe his podcast was wicked popular and funny.
Scott: I never listened to it, but that's not the point.
Scott: He decided that since he was so wicked popular starting with like the fifth or the tenth episode He was gonna sell every episode for like five bucks.
Rym: That was the end.
Scott: Yeah Well, you know his popularity dropped way down, but he made money.
Scott: because you know, okay now I have a hundred listeners instead of a thousand.
Scott: but a hundred times five bucks is money, you know Other people sell ads and those people sometimes make money sometimes not.
Scott: some of them are trying to cover the costs.
Scott: Some of them are trying to profit.
Scott: Yeah, it just very.
Rym: there have been stories.
Rym: I haven't heard any specifically like.
Rym: I know the guy where people were picked up by local radio stations or Not really big radio stations.
Rym: yet because they needed voice talent.
Rym: They found someone who was good and just hey come work for us.
Rym: We'll pay you to do what you were doing for free.
Rym: whoo in his defense though.
Rym: He is the creator of The Office.
Scott: I don't know what that is.
Rym: So God doesn't watch TV.
Rym: The office is awesome in my opinion.
Rym: Well, that's why I'm just Okay.
Scott: Thanks for thanks for the information.
Rym: Yeah, we have nothing against him just against his idea of podcasting.
Rym: Yeah, because our philosophy is that we're doing this for fun and we can afford to cover all the equipment.
Rym: So we Refused to advertise on our site refused to make money.
Rym: if we make t-shirts, we'll just sell them at cost.
Rym: The question was how many listeners do we have?
Scott: Well, it's hard to measure.
Rym: We have a few hundred currently which isn't too bad considering we just started and considering we've never advertised ever.
Scott: Yeah, but there are different ways to measure listeners.
Scott: Like we can tell you how many people downloaded a specific episode, but there's four days a week.
Scott: Some people only listen Monday.
Scott: Some people only listen Tuesday.
Scott: Some people listen like Monday Thursday, but not Tuesday Wednesday.
Scott: Some people listen to every day so the number of listeners is kind of Feed.
Rym: we average what like 1.6 new listeners per calendar day Even even days where there are new episodes almost never lost listeners other than that one kid we banned from our forum.
Scott: He said I think he said that he was still listen.
Scott: I think he said he's still listening.
Scott: But so mr.
Scott: Flaming geek I guess the guy who wasn't really in Japan and can't speak English.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah No, but there's also the issue of people's might subscribe to your feed.
Scott: So I know that someone is subscribed to like the Monday feed, but they might not download every single Monday episode.
Scott: So it's like he's a listener.
Scott: He's not a listener, you know, or some people download and never listen to it.
Scott: They just let their iPods fill up and don't play him ever, you know.
Scott: And then eventually they go what the hell is this and delete it all?
Rym: So basically I'd say after about six more months to a year We'll have enough statistics to actually do math and figure out exactly.
Scott: but I'd say at least a few hundred Yeah, and then considering we haven't done any pushing whatsoever Like we barely push it, I think we just put it in our signatures and like slash that.
Rym: yeah, this is our first public appearance and I think Otakon is gonna be our kind of big tipping point since we're doing a Podcast at Otakon live.
Rym: We might be getting all sorts of space at Otakon to do other fun things.
Rym: You're really not sure what the deal is yet.
Rym: But I think being in the program book at Otakon is gonna explode us.
Rym: Yeah, well pretend I never said that.
Rym: Alright we have a question from Kate here.
Rym: I just wanted you to break down the costs for overhead and Okay.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: So the first cost you have is a microphone.
Scott: now if you don't care about being high quality a microphone is 10 bucks.
Rym: Yeah I mean we went way overboard.
Rym: most podcasts are.
Rym: a dude with the crappy microphone that he found in the box his computer came in Plugged into his computer.
Rym: He's recording in like Windows recorder and then encoding and like I don't know Nero.
Scott: Yeah, the Logitech headsets are pretty popular.
Scott: the little like come out.
Scott: It's got a little microphone a little.
Scott: what's it called?
Scott: Boom boom little stick.
Scott: Yeah, they're usually like the gaming headsets you use if you want to play like counter-strike online.
Scott: But those things like 20 bucks and like some people when they want to add more people to their podcast just buy more headsets.
Rym: You know You need some sort of hosting and usually you want some sort of blog or blog software to go along with it Because I know webcomics usually wants some sort of automated system of I upload a comic and everything gets taken care of.
Rym: So you need the same sort of thing and there are a lot of cheap cheap cheap services that will offer that though You can do it yourself fairly easily.
Scott: Yeah, it all depends on your bandwidth because I mean if your host gives you a hundred gigabytes a month Right, if you only have so many listeners and your podcasts are only so many megabytes Maybe you can you know do it there and not have to pay any more fees.
Scott: But what eventually happens to most podcast is since of mp3 is pretty big and you're not bit torrenting it Which some people do actually bit torrent their podcast to save bandwidth.
Scott: But most people just let you directly download the mp3 which means lots and lots of bandwidth costs.
Rym: now I won't go to all the hosting details because we've run our own Linux server up in the sky and then we host our feeds with feed burner.
Rym: We host our mp3s with libsyn which I'm gonna recommend them to people who don't have any other option But I don't really recommend them because I don't like them terribly.
Scott: Yeah, libsyn isn't the greatest company, but really for like 10 bucks They'll let you do what 200 something megabytes worth of podcasts per month Many down.
Rym: if you get a million downloads, you're still good and they'll give you a blog that they'll run.
Rym: It's kind of like WordPress and they'll hate take care of your RSS feeds and all that sort of stuff.
Rym: Yeah, the RSS feeds are a little tricky But yeah, we paid total about $80 a month for all of our hosting combined, but that includes other websites we run.
Scott: Yeah, we do other stuff with the hosting.
Scott: So one hostings 40 bucks the line.
Scott: Oh, the libsyn is 20 bucks.
Scott: Let's see the mixer.
Rym: Yeah only need a mixer.
Rym: See we we have two people on the podcast which is rare.
Rym: Most people who have are either one person or a bunch of people talking over Skype.
Rym: I can't help you if you do the Skype thing because Skype is Complicated in the fact that it's closed source and you can't fiddle with it.
Scott: Yeah Gizmo is a little easier because you just open up gizmo call someone and push the record button.
Scott: with Skype you either need like two Computers wired together or a crazy wiring configuration or there's a freeware Windows program that lets you record Skype conversations.
Scott: I don't know the name of it because I don't use it.
Rym: We've spent a little under $200 on equipment, but once again, we went way over the top.
Rym: I mean gig nights is one of the highest quality in terms of audio podcasts out there.
Scott: Yeah, that's just because we put so much effort into it.
Rym: I mean you can get that mixer was like 60 bucks.
Rym: It'll handle a whole bunch of inputs.
Rym: We've got a compressor there, which is our newest bit of technology Which I'm not gonna go explain it Unless someone wants me to but basically it reduces the range between the loudest sound and the quietest sound.
Rym: So if I get quiet while I'm talking and then I get loud again It kind of evens it all out and more importantly it squishes the audio down so we can record on that crappy laptop right there With yeah crappy crappy sound card is it?
Scott: you do need a computer.
Scott: the computer doesn't have to be that good But they should hear the computer.
Scott: the you know, you're gonna run into trouble processing.
Scott: It's gonna take forever.
Scott: editing will take forever and you need a lot of hard drive space to store all the podcasts.
Scott: because don't trust All your podcasts and then you're screwed.
Scott: plus you want a hard drive lossless like original.
Rym: I mean you'll make an mp3 and upload it but you want to keep the original original WAV file or whatever Because in the future you're gonna want to be able to make a high quality master for whatever reason.
Rym: You know.
Rym: maybe you wanna put a DVD of your whole podcast someday or you get picked up by a radio station or You just want to re-edit them now that you know how to actually edit Or you want to release your outtakes?
Rym: Yes.
Rym: We have we have outtakes.
Scott: We have outtakes.
Rym: Software is free.
Scott: The software is free unless you want to get fancy.
Scott: the first fancy software That's kind of free is garage band, which isn't really free.
Scott: But if you buy a Mac you get it for free.
Rym: garage bands great.
Rym: if you have that you're all set.
Rym: You can just podcast now.
Scott: Yeah Garage band has like amazing podcast tools for idiots like a Doofus could just click on the podcast button and garage band start talking and click the finish button and it takes care of everything for You considered buying a MacBook just for it.
Scott: Yeah, there's another piece of software that's pretty popular called cast blaster cast blaster Windows, isn't it?
Scott: Yeah, it's not free but it's very very Fancy and it takes care of everything you need to do for podcasting even typing in your show notes and everything from start to finish Like you push a button in music plays and you push another button for wacky sound effects and the volumes and everything.
Rym: Yeah now beyond that there are things like Pro Tools Which if you don't know what that is, you don't need it.
Rym: Even if you know what it is, you probably don't need it for a podcast.
Scott: Yeah, Pro Tools is for real radio people and all kinds of fancy production studios who seem to use something called audacity Which is that's that right there.
Rym: It's free.
Rym: It's really easy use.
Rym: it works in Windows.
Rym: It works on Macs.
Rym: It works in Linux.
Rym: I can't really speak badly of it except for the fact that installing it can be a pain if you're using a Good Linux distribution because we're not gonna talk about this, but the guy who coded this doesn't know what he's doing.
Scott: Yeah, you can ask us any questions about non podcasting geekery after the show because we know but I mean most of you will have No problem and it works great.
Rym: If you have Linux you can use something called resound re z ou nd.
Scott: That's what we use.
Rym: I swear by.
Rym: it's a beautiful beautiful program.
Rym: The guy who wrote it isn't the best coder But he knows a lot about audio and he wrote all the algorithms himself and it works really well.
Scott: And considering, you know, you don't have too many other Linux options.
Scott: That's what we went with.
Rym: so you could do a decent podcast on I'd say 20 bucks a month total Plus maybe 50 bucks worth of equipment.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much and if you spend what we spent you'll have a crazy awesome radio quality podcast Mm-hmm.
Scott: Here comes another question watch out.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Here's a question for you.
Rym: I noticed that you guys have forums on your.
Rym: we do indeed have forums.
Rym: Now do you think that first of all, is it necessary to have forums for podcasting?
Rym: and second if you do What are some good tips to managing forums?
Scott: Well, all right You want to take this?
Scott: Yeah, sure If you have a podcast you generally have a website that goes with it.
Scott: That way people can find your podcast with Google or something.
Scott: It's kind of necessary but you know Usually your website can add a minimum contain your show notes and links to your shows at a maximum.
Scott: You can try to build a whole community around your podcast, you know forums and all kinds of stuff.
Scott: You don't need to.
Scott: It's just something that's good to interact with your listeners and all that sort of good stuff.
Rym: Also, it helps you gain momentum because if there's a community there, they'll all stay by you just like in webcomics.
Rym: It's like everything else.
Rym: I mean, we know some webcomic artists who stop updating and their fans bother them for like the next five years.
Scott: When's it gonna update?
Scott: when's it gonna update?
Scott: Yeah, the other thing is that you know, if you only get feedback from your listeners via email then you know It comes in when someone really has the urge to email you.
Scott: they won't just email you casually But if you can get someone to join your forums Which is about as much effort as getting them to send you one email Once they've joined and once they've gotten used to going to the site They'll just give you feedback constantly and start talking about all kinds of stuff.
Rym: Yep Now you're gonna have to watch out for flamers trolls and general spam bots Which is really too complex a topic to get into now.
Rym: Yeah, I used to say we've had to ban one person already.
Scott: Yeah, but technology will solve you most of those problems.
Rym: Yeah and off the air we can tell you exactly how to deal with that.
Scott: Yep Anything else?
Rym: any more questions?
Rym: What's happening at all?
Rym: I think we've recorded enough for a show at least.
Scott: Yeah, I think we have 18 minutes left.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So anyway our show we haven't.
Rym: it's GeekNights.
Scott: Listen to it GeekNights.
Scott: front row crew calm.
Rym: Yes as in the front row crew from the anime club I don't know who here is even old enough to remember what that is.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: All right, there are some people.
Rym: They're all my friends already.
Rym: So front row crew calm Yep, and we're out off the air and we'll probably take less formal questions starting now.
Scott: now now or maybe later Perhaps or really?
Rym: Yeah, really and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com and if you want you can leave us a voicemail.
Rym: at GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.