Scott: It's Thursday August 31st, and this is GeekNights tonight the geek fable of the bamboo and the vision.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So in an occurrence that has repeated yet again.
Rym: This is the third time this has happened in recent recent memory.
Rym: I won a board game But by a single point with Alex being right there behind me.
Rym: And if anything in the game had gone at all differently Alex would have won.
Scott: Yeah, if anything had gone slightly differently I could have won.
Scott: I wasn't too far back.
Rym: Yeah, not in the most recent game We played but in uh the Amon Ray game.
Scott: Oh the Amon Ray game I don't know what happened.
Scott: like I felt like I was doing better than any Amon Ray had ever done.
Scott: And I did.
Scott: I did two stupid things which basically just threw away four points that were free.
Scott: I just threw them away and And Even with those four points it wouldn't have made me win.
Rym: so I just noticed that I find it interesting that when you beat me you beat me by a lot and when I beat you I beat you by a lot, but Alex tends to lose by like one point or win by like one point.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know what's up with that.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know either.
Scott: Oh Anyway, oh, I gotta remember to say this cuz I'm gonna forget.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: It is quite the meta bit.
Scott: Yeah, if you have applied for membership to the forum and you have not received an email that says Congratulations.
Scott: You are now a member of the forum It might be because you're using hotmail, which is the suck.
Rym: Yes Because the fact is we have never denied anyone membership because no one has presented themselves with that stupid of a facade.
Scott: Yes, and we've only banned one person ever.
Rym: So yeah and goddamn was that kid annoying.
Scott: So If you have applied for membership to the forum chances are your membership has been approved Within maybe an hour or so, but you know, we're guaranteed it'll be approved within like a day.
Rym: Yes Because while we haven't been posting to our own forum as much as we used to because we've been incredibly busy The forums have been rocking a lot and we do watch them to make sure that new members get taken care of and the mr Perry does his job.
Rym: Yep, so done it so much lately.
Scott: If you apply to the forums go back to the forums in like a few hours or the next day and you'll be all set You know, even if you don't get an email saying so and two nice bits about the forums.
Rym: one I'd like to say oh, you know, we hit like a milestone in number of hits But we had a hundred thousand hits like a long time ago, and I just gave up on even looking at that.
Rym: Yeah whatever and If you google image search or Just google search for a lot of random things our forum comes up number one or two.
Scott: I think the reason for that is that any forum is number one a place that is full of links.
Scott: and Number two, you know people link to various discussions in our forum because we make them public and a lot of people's forums out there They don't let you read the forum without signing in so that gives our forum a distinct advantage.
Scott: also The the lusimo vanilla nature of our forum, you know is You know, it's coded very nicely HTML wise which Google also enjoys.
Rym: the other thing I've noticed is that our page rank is soaring because a lot of Websites that have a lot of clout and have linked to our forums multiple times.
Scott: Oh one more thing.
Scott: Is that mr Period because he enforces good grammar and all that good stuff that helps the forums out a lot also on Google.
Scott: You know a forum that's full of loot wheat bear loot we loot we loot we.
Scott: It's a new thing.
Scott: I just invented no loot We're OMG is not gonna be so high on the googles as something that's like hello.
Scott: How are you doing?
Scott: Hi, I'm fine Thank you, blah blah blah.
Rym: So then I guess another warning to all of our new listeners who have joined the forums While he hasn't been active for the last three or four days too much.
Rym: Mr Period is there and he has full authority to edit your posts.
Rym: if you post with bad grammar and spelling now I don't mean like if you spell one word wrong occasionally or if you just happen to make a typo.
Rym: He doesn't even bother with that.
Rym: if you make the same mistake more than once in the same post or if you make a grievous error Yes, it has to be pretty bad.
Rym: You have to be killing Jedi.
Scott: Yeah All right.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But anyway, we've got a little bit of news.
Rym: today It's Thursday, which is usually either the silly day or the tired day or whatever the silly tired day something like that.
Rym: We'll go a little light on the news.
Rym: I know we've been light on the news a lot lately, but there hasn't been a lot of non real-world news lately.
Rym: I mean there's a lot of important news.
Rym: if we wanted to talk about news we could talk for hours and hours every day About what's going on in Iraq what's going on in Mexico right now with that almost coup, but that wouldn't be fun.
Rym: Yeah, it would basically be me Sounding really really pissed off about world politics Scott sounding really really pissed off about various other things Mostly world politics and mostly indifferent about the stuff that Rym is pissed off about.
Scott: Yeah, but other things entirely.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, like you'd be like this sucks because of that and I'm like, no, I don't care about that I only care it.
Scott: it sucks because of this and I'd be like what.
Rym: but that doesn't even.
Rym: Yeah our political discussions.
Rym: We should do a couple shows on politics.
Rym: I don't think that's the greatest idea, but I think our political leanings are fairly well known to our listeners at least I hope so.
Rym: Yeah, I think it's pretty obvious.
Rym: Yeah, actually it really isn't.
Scott: No, it's not Yeah, because I mean it so doesn't fit in with anything normal.
Rym: Yeah, there's no label.
Rym: I mean a lot of people would say oh, they're just liberals, but I am so far from a liberal.
Scott: I'm a wig.
Scott: I know I know I forgot what they stood for but that the point is is that my Like.
Scott: if you took all of my political stances and tried to arrange them into a party It would be a very old party that no longer exists a current one.
Rym: The only two parties I've ever identified with though a couple of recent parties are starting to get my interest are The bull moose party.
Rym: Yeah, and I'm serious First party was great.
Rym: This party was great and the anti-federalist party, which was actually pro federalist, but don't get me started on that.
Rym: Anyway now talking about that today.
Rym: We got stupid useless completely not in any way relevant news.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: All right now, I don't know if this is a rumor or what?
Rym: I don't really trust the press this came out of but it was on slash shot and no one really said hey This is a rumor So I'm gonna run with it as though it's true.
Rym: but I will say now that there are many grains of salt in what I'm about to say.
Rym: it appears it is possible that Microsoft is intending for Windows Vista to have a Startup sound that is not able to be turned off and not able to be modified.
Scott: Whoa Well, first of all, that's not possible because someone can modify it.
Rym: It's not what if it's in some sort of Encrypted protected part of the image install and it has checksums and it just won't boot.
Rym: if the checksums are wrong Then it's not.
Scott: it's not any more difficult to break that than it is to break any other DRM.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but remember this won't hurt people who are smart or people who pirate.
Rym: it'll hurt corporations and normal people.
Rym: because I remember before I became an IT guy and When my knowledge of computers was basically user knowledge when I was learning like I would figure out how word processors work.
Rym: You know the early days One of the first things I figured out how to do and one of the first things that most non tech people do when they you know get a new Windows computer is They moved the icons around and they modify their desktop and they change the desktop theme and they change all the sounds Windows makes.
Scott: Yep, that's what you do like.
Rym: the first thing I would always do when I got a new Windows install when I was young was make some sort of Monty Python sound my opening sound.
Rym: Yep, and Microsoft taking that away doesn't affect me because I don't care But that's going to affect all the people who are the way I was when I was 11.
Scott: All I got to say is that over time what's happened is with Macintosh operating system and the Windows operating system I mean you have a computer that can do X things.
Scott: X is a very large number if it's a general-purpose Computer with a lot of peripherals.
Scott: It has a very large range of capabilities.
Rym: You could make an argument that it has effectively infinite possible capability infinite digital capabilities.
Scott: Of course, it is limited by speed at which it can perform those activities.
Rym: However, we have currently not yet hit any reasonable speed barrier.
Scott: Yes but the point is is that the Windows and Macintosh operating systems seem to be
Rym: all about
Scott: you know Allowing you to very easily do a few things that your computer is capable of doing and making it Impossible for you to do other things that your computer is capable of doing or
Rym: making it very difficult
Scott: or making it very difficult while Linux and I guess BSD but mostly Linux and Linux distributions are all about Letting you do as many of the things your computer can do as is possible And that is why the Mac pissed us off in so many words.
Scott: So this is just yet another example of that phenomena.
Rym: Yeah, though again the Mac didn't totally piss us off.
Rym: not totally actually as we've used it more and more.
Rym: It is pretty much the perfect solution for us in the living room except for except for emulating.
Rym: Yeah, we're working on that.
Scott: We pretty much sacrificed emulating in favor of having less shit under the TV.
Scott: Yes less noise in the living room and also the just I guess an even trade Well one.
Rym: once we get a receiver with some optical input, I think we're gonna be all set here.
Rym: Yeah anyway, I Someone on slash dot says something along these lines and I'll paraphrase because I was thinking the same thing.
Rym: But they made but they made up some terms that seem useful.
Rym: they said that this is basically a problem between a Product centric view versus a user centric view or a brand centric versus a user centric to Microsoft.
Rym: This is great.
Rym: It provides a uniform thing.
Rym: every Windows computer makes this noise.
Rym: this noise joins the psycho scape of Windows, you know, you hear this sound and you think that's the sound of a computer starting.
Scott: Yeah, I think it's pretty obvious.
Scott: That's the reason that they want this to be because you know, but the thing is that provides absolutely no benefit to the user at all.
Rym: No, they're trying to market it as though it does that in fact Supposedly what kind of benefit does that have?
Scott: Supposedly itself turned on a Windows computer from the article.
Rym: the article that may or may not be true about all this basically said that The Microsoft guy said that one of the reasons for this and they gave a whole bunch of reasons.
Rym: I didn't even read all of them.
Scott: Whoa, I couldn't even think of one.
Rym: Alright, one of them that I found silly was that now when people boot up a computer They don't have to sit there and watch it.
Rym: They'll just hear the sound and know it started.
Rym: I don't have anything more to say about this other than if it is true.
Rym: I know that it's not going to actually affect Windows adoption except possibly in corporate situations.
Scott: I Mean, yeah, there are a lot of corporate situation.
Scott: Well, first of all in a corporate situation You usually don't have speakers know you do.
Rym: now You don't work in IT.
Rym: pretty much every computer that is put in a corporate environment.
Rym: Now because of the way the computers are made by Dell and all those companies They have perfectly serviceable speakers built in to the computers themselves in the micro ATX case.
Scott: Oh, it's no good.
Rym: My computer at work has speakers in it.
Rym: And when I first got to work it made noise.
Rym: That's not good and I didn't realize where the speakers were.
Rym: then I realized that PC speakers now are real speakers.
Scott: That's not good.
Scott: But yeah, so that that's a bad thing a very bad thing.
Scott: But anyway now you don't want to walk around an office or people are trying to work and you know rebooting computers Just keep making noises all over the place.
Rym: But you shouldn't need to reboot your can.
Rym: Oh, it's Windows.
Rym: Now I hate to make a joke like that because Windows doesn't need to be rebooted that often anymore Unless you're ready to be rebooted less often than old Windows except more often than Linux and Mac Except when I worked at IBM.
Rym: you realize how many of our enterprise level, you know Windows critical servers had Daily reboots or weekly reboot scheduled because that was the only way to keep them running.
Scott: Wow Yeah, awesome.
Rym: And these weren't all.
Rym: these were like Windows 2000 and Windows 2003 awesome.
Rym: one of them I built.
Scott: You built it poorly if it need a reboot.
Rym: no, no my build had nothing to do with those reboots.
Rym: Yeah Okay, I could tell you what had to do with those reboots, but that's a story for a Monday.
Scott: All right So I got some news.
Scott: Yeah, the news is this Defective by design org which are those people who are fighting DRM, you know the people who?
Scott: Wear the hazmat suits outside of the Apple stores.
Rym: those people we didn't get to see because Scott couldn't find the Apple store.
Scott: Someone told me it was near the Empire State Building which is not true not true at all.
Rym: It's true in the sense that everything in Manhattan is near the Empire State Building.
Rym: relative to I don't know.
Scott: It was true that it was on the same avenue.
Scott: But anyway October 3rd, they have declared is the day Against DRM and they start out with this interesting quote.
Scott: and I'm gonna read this quote because it's that good you ready?
Scott: Here's the quote.
Scott: if Consumers even know there's a DRM what it is and how it works We've already failed.
Scott: that quote is from a Disney executive that is unnamed Wow.
Scott: so according to defective by design the way to defeat DRM is Making people aware of it.
Scott: if we make it so that people know that there's a DRM what it is and how it works Then we win.
Scott: So on October 3rd They're gonna do everything they can to make sure they get the word out about DRM.
Scott: and there's a little is a cool website here.
Scott: well, there's a cool part on their website where they're listing things that you can do and there's having I. they're posting idea submissions of What should be done on October 3rd to get the word out about DRM and some of these are pretty hilarious.
Rym: I think we should just go to her Best Buy and have some fun.
Scott: That sounds like a good idea.
Scott: Here's what get arrested for violating your own copyright.
Scott: Create a Yahoo question.
Scott: create an anti DRM video.
Scott: sell sandwiches with strings attached at lunchtime.
Scott: Put posters up but have the posters be protected by DRM.
Scott: Get the guy who does Dilbert to write a strip about DRM.
Scott: All kinds of ideas here.
Scott: So well, I know her third is gonna be.
Rym: I know we're gonna do October 3rd.
Scott: It's gonna be a fun day.
Rym: We're gonna do a podcast about DRM.
Scott: It's on October 3rd.
Scott: Let me see which day October 3rd is.
Rym: doesn't matter what day it is.
Rym: I mean we missed International Day of Slayer.
Rym: We've got to make up.
Scott: All right, it's a Tuesday But if we do the episode Monday night, then it'll be out Tuesday, which I say is good enough good enough And that's a tech day good enough.
Scott: So Monday October 2nd DRM podcast.
Rym: For all of our new listeners that music means that it is time for things of the day.
Rym: All right, which is basically we say the art thing of the day the most interesting or funny thing We've seen on the internet in the last day.
Scott: I got this cool thing.
Scott: Yo, it's mad cool.
Scott: Well mines got naked people mine has Almost naked people.
Rym: All right real.
Rym: briefly There's a town in Vermont that has a problem with punk kids hanging out naked because apparently are they underage?
Rym: Yeah, they're just punk kids.
Scott: Well, then isn't there some kind of low?
Rym: No The thing is Vermont has no state law banning nudity at all.
Scott: Oh, yeah, that's cool.
Rym: so unless an individual town is specifically banned it which many haven't because they never even thought to a Whole bunch of kids found this out and they're all hanging out in the middle of town naked.
Rym: and there's this rash of Just punk kids hanging out naked all over the place.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Well, if it's not freezing cold out then you know for that problem is solved.
Scott: problem, too.
Scott: Is it like God?
Scott: is it like coed, you know hanging out?
Scott: Probably then, you know Wouldn't you get some little erection action?
Scott: go nothing wrong with that?
Scott: You know, yeah, I think you're not allowed to have an erection in public.
Scott: That's cuz.
Rym: you're not allowed to be naked.
Rym: It depends on where you live and what the laws.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So it's a problem number three It's legal for little kids underage kids to be out in public naked.
Scott: Yeah, right It's legal for me to take pictures anywhere in public.
Rym: If you want to make that example, you probably shouldn't have said me Okay.
Scott: Yeah, cuz I wouldn't.
Scott: but the point is you know what it create.
Rym: The thing is the police basically said there are laws against like obscenity in these towns and the state and there are laws against you lewd and lavicious behavior.
Rym: so as Long as they weren't doing anything sexual.
Rym: It's perfectly legal.
Rym: and I think though I a na l You could probably take pictures of anyone in a public place doing anything.
Scott: Yeah, so I don't know.
Scott: I just see a whole lot of contradictions, but it's cool hanging out naked school.
Rym: I gotta say if I were a punk kid and And when I was living in sterling heights and I found out that was perfectly legal to be naked in public You can bet your ass that me and half of my friends in high school would be wandering around naked Doing the thing from that thing.
Rym: That would have been a thing of the day if I was doing GeekNights when we found it and it's going to be my Thing of the day next week.
Rym: Scott knows what I'm talking about.
Scott: I would totally do that if it wasn't illegal.
Rym: All right, I got a thing of the day.
Rym: I'm gonna save it for next Thursday.
Rym: I'll give a hint every day for the next week.
Scott: if anyone can guess you'll remember to give a hint.
Rym: We'll see if I do.
Rym: Okay If anyone remembers or if anyone figures out what it is or if you remember to make it you're thinking that reminds me to do A hint because I forgot to after a day.
Rym: You'll win some sort of non monetary non-physical prize.
Scott: awesome anyway.
Scott: My thing of the day is a flash game called dark.
Rym: But is this some sort of goth game?
Rym: No, it shows a wrist and you have to slice it a little bit just enough to look cool But not enough to kill you.
Scott: It's the flash game of medieval surgery.
Rym: Wait, so cutting off boils and applying leeches.
Scott: Yes, exactly Awesome.
Scott: I mean this is sort of it's like a really cheap really quick trauma center.
Scott: That's got four levels in it as if three or four levels.
Scott: I don't remember.
Rym: Well wasn't level three of vampire.
Scott: Yes, level one is remove an arrow from the soldiers leg level two is cut off some plague boils and Level three is kill a vampire.
Scott: If there was a level four, I forgot it.
Scott: Maybe there isn't one and after you beat all the levels They give you a score based on how quickly you beat it.
Scott: so it's sort of like a quick and easy trauma center where you have to use the keyboard and the mouse combined to try to Beat the game really quickly and at first it's a little tricky because you got to figure out exactly what to do.
Scott: But after you do it all once it's like oh I see and just go whoosh whoosh whoosh whoosh and beat the game.
Scott: But it is a lot of fun to do horrible medieval surgeries on poorly drawn flash animations.
Rym: But of course the moment you've all been waiting for.
Rym: now We are going to relay to you one of the greatest geek fables of our era the story of the vision and The bamboo.
Rym: now there are actually three fables rolled together into one.
Rym: I like to call this day the day of destiny for This is one of the periods of 24 hours in my life Wherein I got more stories in that time than from many other periods in my life.
Scott: Okay, first we have to set up the background.
Scott: you ready?
Scott: It's summer at RIT.
Scott: I I'm in I'm working for a company.
Scott: do it on co-op I believe and Is not there.
Rym: I'm living in downstate, New York.
Scott: I am living alone in colony working all every weekday and not doing anything else at night or on the weekend Except for hanging out with people who are still in Rochester.
Scott: One of the people I was hanging out with was my good friend Ian who I met in Israel in the summer of 2000.
Rym: Yep, Ian like he's not really so much a member of the front row crew because we don't see him a lot But he is definitely an ally to the front row crew.
Scott: He's mad cool, dude, and he has his own crew.
Scott: Yeah, so what we were doing mostly was playing a lot of Mario Party Mario Party 5 to be specific because that was the Mario Party that was available.
Rym: Now you have to understand that when Scott says they were playing Mario Party.
Rym: They were not playing Mario Party.
Scott: They were playing Mario Party, we were seriously playing some Mario Party.
Scott: There was another guy Frugal and he there was his apartment that we were playing most of the Mario Party in and there were a couple other guys I forget their names and you know, they were their friends that were also playing Mario Party and it was all cool.
Scott: Everyone's hanging out having a good time.
Scott: Mario Party now.
Scott: We had a Mario Party shtick.
Scott: shtick number one Right was that we they had purchased, you know, the the professional wrestling toy belts and they had the tag team one and a couple other ones and Depending on what kind of Mario Party game you had just played whoever won would get the belts.
Rym: Yeah, so they had various, you know world championships that would come and go and they were a big deal.
Rym: everyone got really Really into it having those belt.
Rym: I mean if you were playing for the championship the belts would be sitting there on top of the TV through the whole game.
Scott: Okay shtick number two Frugal who I just mentioned it was his apartment.
Scott: He had a little Wario toy With like this little and he had like a necklace with Wario on it with a big Wario toy hanging and he would put it on to play Mario Party and he would be.
Scott: Wario was his character and he would like rub the Wario and stuff and he was pretty good at Mario Party.
Rym: now this started growing Among all of us in our gaming and for a while each one of us had a unique totem that we would bring whenever we played A significant game.
Scott: Yeah, I made my little booze at a perler beads because I was always boo.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, and you know, I'd bring him in and yeah, it was good times and let's see Oh, we had a little DK toy and the DK toy that Donkey Kong toy would sit on the GameCube.
Scott: and You know, the DK is a rare event in Mario Party at least Mario Party 5.
Scott: So whenever DK happened, it was like DK And it was a lot of fun, I think there are two more sticks.
Scott: the One shtick was you know when it's you this time for a minigame in Mario Party?
Scott: It displays like a list on the screen and then it randomly selects one of them.
Scott: Everyone of course yells out the game that they want to play.
Rym: now at this time I believe the the microphone for the GameCube.
Rym: they did not have it.
Scott: No The microphone for the GameCube didn't come out until Mario Party 6 or 7 and this is only Mario Party 5 6 wasn't out Yet, but they knew that it was someday going to exist.
Scott: No, we didn't.
Rym: I thought you did.
Scott: No, not at all.
Rym: Is there been rumors?
Scott: No, we had no idea until much later.
Rym: I'm pretty sure there were rumors.
Scott: Well, we didn't know.
Scott: we had no idea.
Scott: what we did is whenever you know We made up a thing in our mind because you'd call out the minigame you wanted it to be and it would land on the Minigame you called out.
Scott: so we were like, oh there must be some sort of microphone in the GameCube That heard us calling out for that minigame and then it selected the one we wanted.
Scott: So whenever you called out a minigame and then it selected the one you called out you would go microphone microphone.
Rym: Now I'll say it this time that these are all mostly Scott and all their shiks because I had nothing to do with it.
Scott: Yeah Rym wasn't there remember?
Scott: and When I?
Scott: that's why I'm telling most of the story.
Rym: when I found out about these they were mostly kind of uninteresting.
Scott: today However, you ready?
Scott: Here's the one that's important the vision.
Scott: see in This.
Scott: in Mario Party 5 the way the items work is you get an item ball from a gumball machine and you can choose to Either hold on to this item and pay some money to use it on yourself You know, which is always good.
Scott: if it was like a wiggler or for absolutely no cost to you You could throw it at one to ten spaces and it would land on that space and inhabit it.
Scott: and If you were to land on that space or if anyone else were to land on that space at a later time It would be as if they had used that item on themselves.
Scott: So, you know, let's say you got like, you know It's a good a spiky shell.
Scott: you could throw the spiky shell have it land on a spot and then Anyone who were to step there would have a spiky shell happen to them.
Scott: Yeah, so one of the items was the poison mushroom.
Scott: The poison mushroom makes you small and makes you walk very slowly.
Rym: It only gives you one very small dice to roll so you it doesn't will die die It doesn't let you move very far if you land on it.
Scott: Yes, so frugal, you know had a vision.
Scott: He goes I have my vision I have a vision and his vision was to line up the poison mushrooms Just one after the other on the game board so that if you landed on one of them You'd be forced to roll a very small die and you would land on another one and be forced to roll a very small die.
Rym: Now at this point these gentlemen all decided that now they have to see this vision through.
Rym: they have to strive to create the vision.
Scott: So pretty much every game of Mario Party be played.
Scott: since he came up with the vision We would take every single poison mushroom we had and just line them up on the board.
Scott: And as we did it every time something happened either someone landing on one of the poison mushrooms or someone adding to the vision Frugal will go.
Scott: my vision my vision And his vision came to be many times.
Rym: now of all of that up I will venture forth the word crap.
Rym: The vision is really the only one that I found funny and that stuck with us at all.
Scott: Yeah, the other ones notice because we start.
Rym: I mean the vision started coming with great frequency mostly from Scott mostly ignored But we had many visions nonetheless.
Scott: Yes the vision was the only stick that's actually useful outside of silly Mario Party.
Scott: and You know silly Mario Party ended as soon as school started and more interesting things happened because there were more people around.
Scott: You're pretty much using the Mario Party as a means of entertainment.
Scott: in the lonesome Rochester summer.
Rym: Mario Party is a game that does nothing but kill time pretty much.
Rym: Yeah It's not really that good a game.
Rym: It just kills time.
Scott: it would be a good game if they cut back on a lot of these slow useless Animation.
Scott: it takes hurried up with the mini long to play that goddamn game.
Rym: I can't deal with it.
Scott: Yeah If they really if they they could do a lot to make Mario Party a much quicker play or at least have quick play Options where they wouldn't do extra useless animations.
Scott: It would just you know, the die would immediately roll your guy would automatically move forward, you know, etc.
Scott: Etc.
Scott: Not anyway, yeah now I'm not a Mario Party review.
Rym: now I came back to Rochester because it was about that time when I was gonna move back into school and all that and hang out.
Rym: so I come back and right before Scott tells me that He wants to challenge for the tag team championship belts and we need to do a two versus two Mario Party.
Rym: now I haven't played Mario Party in a while, at least especially not this Mario Party that I'd never played before Mm-hmm, but I I rose to the challenge and I decided alright I will come and we will play this for the honor of the front row crew for the honor of ourselves And for the belts against the current reigning champions.
Scott: now I didn't give us very good chances of winning, but I had a vision.
Rym: but I had a vision of us losing.
Scott: Well, see I figured that we did have a chance at winning.
Scott: I just didn't think that we were not the fear of the ever really the underdogs But we did have a chance, you know, despite this we were playing.
Rym: I mean the game.
Rym: there is much randomness in Mario Party and if we could have Befallen some great star and also despite the lack of my playing for a long time There are certain kinds of Mario Party games that I do not lose.
Rym: that Yeah, and combined with Scott who has his own list of games that he does not lose that we were doing very well We could.
Scott: we could have beaten most people at that Mario Party easily now because this was that I mean.
Rym: this was the end.
Rym: This was the world championship.
Rym: This was for the belt.
Rym: This wasn't just some piddly, you know class Joe.
Rym: This was Mike Tyson versus Mike Tyson.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: All right, so just imagine Mike Tyson boxing Mike Tyson.
Scott: Okay, so first we'll tell the Mario Party and then we'll tell the bamboo.
Scott: All right.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Well, the thing is the game starts and you know There's a lot of trash talk.
Rym: trash talk was probably more important than the actual game.
Rym: I agree and The vision played heavily because I had a vision of us winning at this point.
Rym: our of my vision was strong.
Scott: Yes, we were both.
Scott: both teams were gaining stars at and somewhat equal rate, you know, like we got a star They got a star they got a star.
Scott: We got a star.
Rym: it was it was going good Everything was happening and cool and then there was a stretch where Scott and I were ahead by a star for a while.
Rym: We were doing.
Rym: I mean we were.
Scott: I mean, yeah We were like a third of the way almost halfway through the game and we were you know doing really well And we were winning, you know about our fair share of the minigames and everything was going good.
Rym: We were about a star ahead and we were gonna be okay.
Rym: every time we they advanced we advance we're keeping them back We're keeping them at bay.
Scott: They weren't winning enough games to overtake us and then in one turn Or I think maybe was two turns.
Scott: All right, so it doesn't matter pretty much in the span of one to two turns of Mario party.
Scott: We were stolen by the boo.
Rym: First we played a duel Wherein they gained a star and we all right, you know, that's right.
Rym: then They got a star legitimately.
Scott: Then we landed on a star star which makes us lose a star.
Rym: then Right after that we landed on a star two stars.
Scott: you got to understand.
Scott: in Mario Party a Star is a super rare terrible thing.
Scott: that makes you lose a star into a bottomless pit.
Scott: So but we were.
Rym: you know One bad thing.
Rym: I was like.
Rym: we can still win another bad thing We can still win another thing we can still win.
Rym: We landed on that second fucking star.
Rym: I just dropped my controller and I just I just couldn't.
Rym: I didn't even know what to say.
Rym: I just and they didn't know what to say either.
Rym: They weren't cheering.
Scott: They were just sitting there like wow It's like the game which is a pretty even match of two on two.
Scott: Mario Party became a complete and utter blowout Whereas we were destroyed by random Star.
Rym: if you can picture it, there are four men playing Mario Party and suddenly in the middle of the game a Three horrid whirling cocks rise out of the GameCube.
Rym: the controllers pin Scott and I down and sodomize us furiously.
Scott: Yeah We got punned.
Scott: So but now the game of that footage was randomness because after we got punned by the stars I will admit we started.
Scott: we did not win the majority of the minigames after that point But I think a lot of it was just because you're so downtrodden from being anally raped.
Rym: Our spirits were broken.
Rym: Yes I mean it got to the point like right after that I was like my turn began and I went from winning to no chance of winning.
Rym: and I'm sitting there and I have items I'm just like, you know what whatever?
Rym: and I say they
Scott: yeah
Rym: but
Scott: after that point in the game we pretty much slowed our rate of star getting and They got a whole bunch more stars
Rym: and also the game exploded into anarchy for a while in that everyone was yelling and screaming about The star after you know it said in what had just happened and we really all kind of got distracted.
Rym: and I'll back it up a little bit because the Story we're about to tell has a little bit of backstory from maybe five minutes earlier before.
Rym: this is our head.
Rym: Yes Okay, now is at one point frugal or was it frugal?
Scott: I don't know It was very as soon as we got.
Scott: you know what anytime.
Rym: it's not mere Scott.
Rym: I'll say it's in.
Scott: Okay So where's when we got there, right?
Scott: Someone made a cut.
Scott: now you got to understand the layout of this room.
Scott: there is a kitchen there is a big-screen TV and There are people sitting all around the big-screen TV and the kitchen is to the left of the TV and to the right of the TV is like we're frugal and Ian are and closer to the kitchen is where me and Rym are.
Scott: and On that side of the room where frugal and Ian are there is a mini fridge and on top of the mini fridge It's like a lamp.
Scott: Okay now over near them.
Scott: There's another kid there.
Scott: I forget his name and All right him yeah, and over he's sitting near the mini fridge and he's complaining about a nasty smell.
Scott: and He complained about it like when we got there.
Scott: and he complained about it a little while later and It was he didn't do anything about.
Rym: he was like man something smells.
Scott: We got to clean this place out and he and her girl like yeah, whatever Yeah, I think someone looked in the mini fridge once and was like, you know Cuz it was coming from that area which is far away from us because we weren't smelling it.
Scott: and you know They didn't see anything in there, but like soda cans and beer cans and whatever.
Scott: So, you know, they were like, uh, I guess nothing's rotting in the fridge.
Scott: What could it be?
Scott: Whatever?
Rym: so we ignore.
Rym: I mean, I didn't even smell anything so I didn't care.
Rym: Mm-hmm and the game's going on.
Rym: and then you know right before the star.
Rym: I remember Ian or might have been frugal, but one of them who wasn't I don't remember when exactly.
Scott: It was definitely during the game because it interrupted the star was it but this wasn't the interruption.
Rym: They just said like, you know, I kind of smell like vomit or something.
Scott: It definitely had a vomit atious smell and everyone Amethyst odor.
Rym: so Ian says something like I kind of smell vomit and we all look and we sniff around over like Whatever I don't see any vomit.
Rym: let's finish the game.
Rym: Yeah, cuz we were still winning at this point.
Rym: I was still on high spirits.
Rym: So after the second star and after my life was ruined and my ass was sodomized but before the end of the game Suddenly frugal sits up.
Rym: He's like, you know what?
Rym: I still smell vomit vomit.
Rym: There's vomit somewhere.
Rym: I gotta find it.
Scott: Yeah, it was.
Scott: he were complaining.
Scott: it must have been a rank rank odor.
Scott: if they were, you know They couldn't stand it.
Scott: They had to get up and find the source of the vomit smell.
Rym: now It was just frugal.
Rym: I think that stood up.
Scott: I'll say I don't remember but it was.
Scott: everyone started looking around trying to find the source of the smell.
Rym: Yeah, though it started out with just like one of them stood up while we're playing Yeah, sniffing around and then everyone else is like, ah, if you're gonna do this, then we can't play until you're done.
Rym: We better find this odor.
Rym: Yeah And I still couldn't smell anything.
Rym: and they're sniffing around.
Rym: and you know I walk over to the kitchen and I look in the garbage dispose and I look in the garbage and there's nothing around.
Rym: And he's like like he starts taking stuff out of the fridge and trying to see if there's anything.
Scott: they're taking stuff out of the cabinets Even though the smell is coming from the other side of the room.
Scott: I was assuming that the smell was coming from outside the window, which is right behind the mini fridge.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I started.
Scott: I was like, let's go outside and look for a dead skunk or something.
Rym: I started looking under the couches, you know, maybe a dead animal outside.
Rym: I was convinced that someone had vomited somewhere and hidden it or something something like that.
Scott: Of course, all the couches are raised up with their stadium seating.
Scott: So and then I'll say in because I don't remember who did it suddenly like goes bolt upright and goes It's right there and he goes, you know He leans over to sniff at this thing and I couldn't really tell what it was from where I was.
Scott: any backs off.
Rym: That's off and he's like, it's the bamboo That fucking bamboo fucking bamboo and we're like what no way.
Scott: So I was like a bamboo.
Scott: I wasn't quite sure what they're talking about.
Scott: I'm looking out for like a giant bamboo stick or something.
Rym: So Ian walks over that he's like, what do you mean?
Rym: And he's like right there and he points at the little bamboo.
Rym: He's like what and he's yeah He doesn't gingerly he leans over and goes and then he makes a noise like Like he's about to vomit.
Scott: Yeah now we I didn't quite understand what they meant by the bamboo.
Scott: I mean, I knew what bamboo is but I wasn't like.
Scott: I was like is there a stick of bamboo somewhere in this house?
Scott: That's all rotting or what?
Scott: It was his little tiny porcelain Pot thingy with dirt in it and a little tiny bamboo shoot coming out of it Maybe like a few inches long and there was only like a half inch of dirt and the rest was just water.
Scott: Yes, there was standing water in this tiny little and the water was clear.
Rym: There's nothing floating in the water.
Scott: It was clear water with dirt under it and a shoot of bamboo.
Rym: So, you know Ian backs off, you know making this gagging noise and fruits like say say see as someone vomited in the bamboo.
Rym: And then it's like but it's clear through his gagging.
Scott: All right, so now Scott is sitting down.
Scott: I'm sitting in my.
Scott: everyone goes back to their seats.
Scott: you know like Natalie found the source of the odor and Ian was going to Dispose of the bamboo.
Scott: as we all sat and waited for him to get that over with because no one else wanted to be near The thing.
Rym: now I didn't really believe him that it smelled that bad.
Scott: So he brought it over, you know to different people in the room like here.
Scott: smell it man smell it.
Scott: So everyone was able to experience the.
Rym: the problem is he's walking across Hazel pleasant, you know, I forget who bumped it, but I think it was you know, I remember exactly the bumping.
Scott: I remember.
Scott: yes.
Scott: So he's bringing it around the room and then he brings it to me Right and he's like trying to bring it near me like he got a smell and I didn't want to you know Even though everyone else wanted to have their olfactory nerves stimulated by the amazing bamboo.
Scott: I Yeah, I decided I would rather you know avoid having the reason.
Rym: I was curious because I didn't believe them.
Rym: I was convinced that there was something in there.
Scott: I didn't want to have the odor of puke infecting my nasal passages.
Scott: So as he brought it over to me to have me smell it I put my hand out to do like the Kramer like, you know, stop with the flat hand.
Rym: and it bumped now like a drop of the liquid that was in this little container fell out and like bounced off a Scott and kind of rolled away.
Rym: and There was one drop.
Scott: Well, no, it wasn't one drop a little tiny bit.
Scott: There was quite a. it was basically a splash.
Scott: It was like splash.
Rym: It was a tiny little.
Scott: there was one splash that got drops on me on the chair and on some other things.
Rym: There was less than up an inch and a half of water in this thing.
Scott: It was very little water, but it was a. it was a splash.
Scott: It's like as if you took you know, it's like you had a glass of juice and you drank it all but then you know There's always some left.
Scott: It was like if he took all of that and splashed it around the room But there was still a lot left in the container.
Scott: there was left in the little thing.
Rym: yes, it was a tiny amount and a Relatively tiny.
Rym: so this tiny amount of liquid has entered the room now and has dissipated itself.
Rym: It is no longer as cohesive.
Rym: it is now spread out and At this point no one in the room could speak or we were all trying to not vomit.
Scott: It was the most rank odor.
Scott: I think I have ever experienced.
Rym: It was the worst thing I've ever smelled and I stepped in a dead deer once uh-huh.
Scott: But oh my god, you had no idea.
Scott: like there was a drop of it on me.
Scott: There's a drop of it on the chair Drop of it like on the couch.
Rym: Scott ran away like trying to get away from it But like the kid who had the string of firecrackers taped to his leg.
Rym: He could not get away because it was on him.
Scott: It was it was the worst smell ever When it.
Rym: I mean the exact secret of splash pause gag scream.
Scott: Yeah, I mean they quickly managed to dispose of the actual bamboo itself after this point.
Scott: But everyone the room exploded.
Scott: everyone was like, oh god Oh god running around screaming trying to clean this up and rid the world of this odor now in as soon as possible.
Rym: Now these there's still some left in the thing.
Rym: So he reads decides that the rest of this liquid needs to go away forever.
Rym: So he runs into the kitchen with what's left of it and he dumps it down the drain and Then he starts running hot water over it and that Unleashed the final smell that that just filled the room.
Scott: Yeah, I mean you'd think that doing that would send the odor to its death.
Scott: But no, apparently the odor must have been coming from the dirt or it was most concentrated under the water.
Scott: So by doing that he actually started, you know Disseminating the odor quite a bit and it you couldn't even go near the kitchen anymore.
Scott: It was like oh god until eventually a few minutes later It did all get washed away when they took the bamboo out to the trash.
Rym: Of course, the first thing we thought was we should give this bamboo to someone.
Scott: obviously magical obviously But it was much ruckus for quite a few minutes Perhaps 10 to 15 minutes running around the room trying to clean up and get the odor out opening windows blowing fans Spraying Febreze all kinds of stuff.
Rym: It was the worst thing I've ever smelled in my life.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it didn't just smell like vomit.
Scott: It's not like vomit.
Scott: think about this.
Scott: you have a very small amount of liquid in a glass right and standing about five feet away from this glass smells like someone vomited in the room and It's a very small amount of liquid.
Scott: going near it and smelling it makes you gag and almost vomit yourself.
Scott: Spilling that liquid everywhere makes the room explode and people run around yelling and screaming.
Scott: Now dumping it down the sink and pouring hot water after it makes people flee the apartment.
Scott: That's how bad it is.
Scott: So after about an hour I would have paid someone like a hundred dollars to just take the thing and either like Drink some amount of the water or just put their nose right into it and take a big ol whiff.
Rym: I just would have walked into Gracie's and knocked it over and walked away.
Rym: That would have been hilarious Especially if I made some vomitous noises right beforehand.
Rym: No, even better you just put it on the little conveyor that goes into the I Mean.
Rym: people used to put you know gloves filled with stuff and pennies in the rolls.
Rym: Someone put a glass of that pennies in the rolls.
Rym: I never understood that one You realize because it made a horrid ruckus and a mess.
Scott: I know but it's like they'd have to know what was going on behind there in order to know that that would cause trouble.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: They did know because everyone knew.
Rym: okay anyway.
Rym: So after about an hour we calm down and then you know, we're trying to finish the game of Mario Party But it's over and we're basically no one's saying anything other than what the fuck was that?
Scott: Yeah, what the fuck?
Scott: this is now the phase of what was making that bamboo smell so bad.
Rym: I mean literally the conversation was like what the fuck was that the fuck?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: was there a bacteria growing in there, but it was clear.
Scott: does bamboo have some sort of Odorific properties that we were unaware of?
Rym: was it some kind of vomit bamboo.
Scott: Yeah, it's like what the hell was it?
Rym: No, we sure it was the vamp bamboo.
Rym: What if it was just someone poured a liquid in there?
Rym: What if it was a practical joke and someone poured some art stuff in there?
Rym: What if the container broke and there was something in it?
Rym: What if aliens came?
Scott: Yeah We had no idea.
Scott: maybe it was you know, the some fertilizer in the little bamboo plant.
Scott: Maybe it was the dirt.
Scott: Maybe who knows we had no idea.
Scott: It was a mystery.
Scott: It's still a mystery.
Scott: Google didn't even know But yeah,
Rym: well eventually we found the answer that apparently Bamboo plants that grow in water like that, especially confined are somewhat susceptible to a number of Infection not really infections, but there are things that will grow in the water that make a smell like that And apparently whatever conditions that little bit of bamboo had been sitting in were exactly perfect for that thing.
Rym: Whatever it is to fry I think it was mainly due to the being on top of the mini fridge and thus being warmed up I think also not being moved or disturbed in any way for like a year.
Scott: I don't know how old the bamboo was because it wasn't in my apartment.
Scott: It was in an apartment I only went to to play Mario Party.
Rym: there was a win.
Rym: when they picked it up I remember there was definitely a lot of dust around it and no dust under it.
Rym: It had been there a while.
Scott: Well, you know apartments pick up does pretty quick.
Scott: So that's not a hundred percent It's a good tell.
Scott: Maybe it was just rotting dust.
Rym: I don't know dust Yeah, just a random guess.
Scott: but yeah, that is the story of the vision and the bamboo.
Rym: now The moral here.
Rym: I'm not gonna play the wave file.
Rym: Oh you suck because the wave file is so low quality.
Rym: Fine if you find me a better wave file, which you did but you never gave to me and I'm not waiting.
Scott: I didn't find a better one.
Rym: Yeah, you did.
Rym: I did I the one you played from the DVD a little while ago.
Scott: Oh that one.
Rym: Anyway, the moral of this story is that if life gives you shit Throw it away and make lemonade.
Rym: Might not make sense, but consider this in the course of that day We lost the world championship of Mario Party and the championship belts.
Rym: Yep by a lot we got.
Scott: we got smelly ass bamboo all over ourselves.
Rym: Yes, and despite that it was one of the funniest days we've ever had.
Scott: Yeah, you know it was a total party.
Scott: Everyone had a lot of fun.
Scott: Everyone had great stories to tell from it.
Scott: You know, it's like hey life gave us Vomit smelling bamboo, but that day was awesome.
Rym: I mean a lot of people cuz.
Rym: actually I remember a long time ago like when I when I was a junior Seeing I think was when I was a junior at RIT.
Rym: I wrote an article I might have been a senior for Gracie's Dinnertime Theatre and the article I wrote was basically I'm always happy haha, and I got a lot of hate mail from this about you're not happy you're lying.
Rym: and I think that the only real difference between me and all those people not just me but you know the crew in general me and Scott and the whole front row crew was that When good things happen, we laugh and enjoy them and when bad things happen We laugh and enjoy them as best we can and in the very least no matter how bad something is that happens to any of us No matter how bad it is.
Rym: At least there's a good story to tell about it.
Scott: Yeah, I mean you can even make jokes about 9/11 that are funny, you know I mean sure when something serious you got to deal with it seriously but that doesn't mean that you have to be you know, personally upset and Unhappy and you know tormented and depressed, you know you.
Scott: something terrible happens, you know You deal with it.
Scott: Seriously, you treat it seriously.
Scott: your actions are you know Respectable and such and you know, you don't you know say certain things to certain people But you know you still you gotta.
Scott: if you don't make the best of it You're just gonna become a depressed loser.
Rym: If any time something bad happens to you The best thing you can do is just remember that.
Rym: now you've got one hell of a story to tell.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, remember that time I got shot.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Yeah, even if it's like an ultra terrible story like oh my god Horrible things happened, you know, I mean we know something.
Rym: I mean we have friends in the crew who you know survived cancer and they joke about it Constantly.
Scott: Yeah, that's what you need to do and is what you need to do.
Scott: so the next time you get smelly ass bamboo water all over your shirt and You know you almost puke a couple times in addition to getting starred Twice in one game in the span of 1.5 rounds of that game.
Scott: Yep Just go to some forum on the internet somewhere and tell the story or write it in your blog or make a podcast about it Or just tell your friends at conventions and it'll be a good fun time.
Rym: I really wish there was a way for me to send the smell of that bamboo over TCP IP to all of you out there.
Scott: Well Smelter net is not yet up and running.
Rym: I don't think we're not kidding.
Rym: That was the worst thing I've ever smelled.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I've set off stink bombs.
Rym: I found dead not human bodies But I found dead things before.
Scott: dead animals smell dead animals like one of the worst smells ever.
Scott: bamboo was worse.
Rym: yeah, I mean I once let a sack of potatoes rot and Rotting potatoes smell apparently a lot like a rotting human corpse in the certain conditions Mm-hmm.
Rym: That was not even a quarter as disturbing as the smell of that bamboo.
Scott: It was bad.
Scott: I think it was mostly due to the strength of the odor and also the fact that we were taken completely flat-footed by that.
Rym: Yeah I mean the the scene was that there's this bad smell and the guy, you know he's walking over with the thing and he's gonna dispose of it after letting everyone realize how bad it is and In the span of like a second.
Rym: it goes from this little, you know, like a minorly bad odor.
Scott: It's in.
Scott: it's basically an incredibly strong odor contained in an incredibly small place.
Scott: It was we let the cat out of the bag.
Rym: It was a flashbang of odor.
Rym: Yeah If the SWAT team wanted to get us all all they'd have to do was throw one of those little bamboo fuckers into the room.
Rym: And that's the end of us.
Scott: Oh my god stink bombs on an airplane.
Scott: Oh my god All right.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Yes So to all of our new listeners every episode we've ever done is up in the archives.
Rym: the last 100 episodes are up in the feed.
Rym: Join the frapper map on the website www.frontrowcrew.com.
Rym: Join the forums.
Rym: They're really really rocking and awesome.
Rym: There are links to everything we talk about on the website in the show notes for every episode.
Scott: Mm-hmm I think that's about it.
Scott: join the forum And if you don't get an email saying your application has been approved you were approved join the foot go sign in.
Rym: Yep, and there may or may not be an episode on Monday because Monday is a holiday and we know that's right.
Rym: We might do an episode we might not.
Rym: we might do a special.
Rym: we're not sure yet.
Rym: We're not we don't know.
Scott: Yeah, I have to go see what the old schedule with the family is there?
Rym: Yes, and Emily is coming back from Japan.
Rym: Well, she's back from Japan and she's coming back to downstate New York this weekend.
Rym: Yes, I am quite happy As long as she doesn't bring me bamboo.
Rym: And That was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening themes.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is accorded with absolutely no studio and no audience But unlike those other talk shows it's actually recorded at night.