Scott: It's Thursday September 7th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Scott: We discuss how to not suck at talking.
Rym: Let's do this Today at work.
Rym: I had the privilege of going to one of those places most people only see in the movies.
Rym: I went to the Bronx regional high school, which is one of those stereotypical inner-city high schools And I worked at the clinic there on the computers and the well more Specifically the closet where the routers and switches go, what's it like there?
Scott: I mean it can't be that bad if they have routers.
Rym: and here's the thing it looked exactly like in all those movies about troubled youths In the inner city.
Rym: you know the school was really locked down on the outside bars everywhere, and there were guards at the doors and Everything was real.
Rym: you know Everything was really locked down, but every student.
Rym: I ran into and I was during class.
Rym: I was walking through the halls trying to find the clinic area and Aside to the fact that I walked past one student who was showing off her baby to a number of other students Mm-hmm high school mind you yeah, but aside from that I all the punk kids I ran into were typical bright looking normal punk kids and all the teachers seem to be teaching normal classes, and it seemed Exactly like any other high school I'd been to even to the fact that they seem to have plenty of money.
Rym: they had plenty of computers like all the textbooks I saw look brand new and everything looked really nice.
Scott: See this is what I keep telling people that you know it.
Scott: just because you grew up somewhere where you have inner city schools Doesn't mean you can't learn anything.
Scott: It's all about how much you try.
Rym: and well see the thing is I don't.
Rym: I don't know what they were actually teaching and I saw A small wing of the school, and I'll note that there was another wing of the school That was locked from that side like from the side.
Rym: I was in to the other side.
Rym: I don't know if maybe all the troublemakers were in that side.
Scott: Yeah Those are the kids who shouldn't be in school in the first place because they don't want to be and they're not gonna learn anything.
Scott: no How good the school is.
Rym: here's the problem with that?
Rym: Most I'd say most kids don't want to be in school when they're very young.
Rym: I didn't want to be in school for much of my schooling.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean you know there's a lot of kids Or you know there are kids where if you expel them they go yay, and there are other kids.
Scott: You you expel them, and they go.
Scott: no my life is what.
Scott: what's the line?
Rym: I mean if you expelled me when I was in first grade I would have thought that was the best thing that ever happened to me And I would have spent the rest of my life playing and looking at pictures and books hey.
Scott: Hey, no you wouldn't He could.
Rym: it's eventually become a homeless bum Yeah, and then I would have had the same books to look at.
Rym: cuz I couldn't buy new picture books Yeah, and I'd learn how to read the words night train fortified wine MD 2020.
Rym: Anyway real quick before we get into the news and everything I have a short short short geek back from our good friend and scientist Lisa Mm-hmm.
Rym: I just want to say I want you to know or when I'm reading the wrong quote because I have a quote from my news Article as well.
Scott: Oh good job.
Rym: I think your bamboo problem was bacillus Pumulus basilisk as in turns bacillus as in a little bacteria Not a snake.
Scott: the B?
Rym: a ci?
Rym: ll?
Rym: u s p?
Rym: u m?
Rym: i?
Rym: l?
Scott: u s so maybe it's bacillus.
Scott: Yeah, that of bacillus.
Rym: I've heard things like that said either way.
Rym: I'm sure Pete and Lisa will correct both of us.
Rym: Yeah, I'm sure yeah But she is pretty certain that that is it because it's a small bacteria found commonly in dirt thrives in water smells like vomit and she is 100% confident that it smells like vomit.
Scott: Well, um that seems to fit the description perfectly.
Scott: Yeah, I'd bet money on it.
Rym: I will assume that the problem was in fact this tiny little bacteria.
Scott: Can we get some of this bacteria to use on people?
Rym: What do you mean use on people?
Rym: It'd be easier just to vomit on people But it didn't smell.
Scott: a vomit doesn't smell as bad as bacillus.
Scott: I heard is.
Rym: I could make you some vomit.
Rym: We'll get it.
Rym: We'll get a still we'll make some concentrated vomit.
Scott: Oh, no.
Rym: Oh, no We'll get a bag of vomit and leave it in the washroom for a week or two.
Rym: Okay, as long as the acid doesn't eat through the bag.
Scott: Anyway Let's cut the disgusting.
Rym: Let's get on to the news.
Scott: We have a pretty good topic today All right, so we told you a while ago that some guy broke the fair use for WM Thingy, which allows you to take the DRM off of fair play protected music files.
Scott: So though that includes, you know music you buy from Napster and Yahoo and some other places that can be played on Microsoft's Windows Media Player some other players and any plays for sure device.
Scott: Um, so of course Microsoft put out a patch so that fair use for WM doesn't work anymore.
Rym: No, I thought Microsoft only put out patches on Black Tuesday.
Scott: They usually do only put out patches on Black Tuesday, which is the second Tuesday of every month.
Scott: You know, that's the typical thing is the second Tuesday of every month Microsoft will put a whole mess of patches out.
Scott: you go to Windows Update.
Scott: You'll be all gay.
Scott: Yeah all good.
Scott: Okay, yeah, I guess my.
Scott: Okay, I don't know why I said that but I'm really curious.
Scott: I don't know whether it's you know.
Rym: I just know that today I've listened to two radio people say a euphemism for homosexuality instead of their intended word.
Scott: It's a virus.
Rym: It's going around his pendulum And he said the word fag and then he stopped and he said I didn't mean to say that word.
Scott: I meant to say Yeah Well, he must have been talking about a cigarette.
Scott: He's British, you know Okay.
Scott: Anyway, the point is is that Microsoft usually patches everything including Extremely dangerous security vulnerabilities in its software on the second Tuesday of every month.
Rym: So if a horrible vulnerability so if there's a virus going around the internet destroying everything and it comes out on that Wednesday You've got to wait a whole month.
Scott: You got to wait a whole month before you're getting able to defend against it unless you have some sort of other company within any virus protecting you somehow.
Scott: so someone broke the DRM on Windows Media files and Within three days, which is faster than Microsoft has ever released a patch ever They put out a patch to fix these holes.
Scott: Of course, it didn't work for long.
Scott: fair use for WM version 1.2 Basically makes the patch useless.
Scott: And now there's gonna be this very long firefight in which you know fair use for WM upgrades and then Microsoft patches and back and forth and back and forth and back and forth and I have a feeling fair use for DRM is gonna win.
Scott: I just had this feeling yeah Yeah, I wouldn't bet against that but the point is you can tell who's really.
Scott: you know controlling things at Microsoft.
Scott: You know that they can dedicate resources To.
Scott: you know, making sure the record companies are happy that they can get a patch out in three days Whereas when is an extreme security vulnerability and a danger to the entire internet?
Scott: Oh, it's okay.
Scott: It could wait a month.
Scott: it's no big deal because you know, that doesn't really hurt Microsoft's wallet so much.
Scott: and Yeah Microsoft bad DRM bad.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, my news today is something it's been going around the internet for a while And I kind of ignored it because there's news like this all the time.
Rym: But for some reason a lot of people have been talking about it.
Rym: I mean a lot of people.
Rym: and then Recently, I discovered because I did a little bit of follow-up and I saw the final Consensus answer as to what was going on and this just really illustrates what bothers me about.
Rym: You know people who are credulous of things when they really shouldn't be.
Rym: There is a tree in San Antonio that one day started spouting water from a small hole on the side of it in great quantity Mm-hmm.
Rym: now interesting the people who own the property and the locals almost immediately began to believe that this was some sort of miracle water because one lady who was friends with the person who loaned the property said that she sprinkled the water on her spider bites and they disappeared.
Rym: and Then another another woman associated with the homeowner said that she soaked her ankles which were arthritic in water from the tree and Their arthritis went away Uh-huh.
Rym: Yeah, and there are all sorts of claims like this.
Rym: So people were coming around and bottling up the water and you know, oh, it's miracle water keeping it protecting it.
Rym: She called the state a few times, you know, hey test this I want to see what's up about that Which you think all right, maybe she's rational and she wants to you know, find out for sure what's going on.
Rym: But I'll I'll destroy that little tiny burst of optimism a little bit.
Rym: But first they have all these interviews and she's saying, you know It's miracle water miracle water.
Rym: and then they talk to her son who says I don't believe any of that superstitious crap.
Rym: And you think all right this kid's smart.
Rym: But then he goes on to talk about how we think the water tastes better than the tap water.
Rym: So he bottles it up and puts it in the fridge.
Rym: so Eventually, you know some people come and they investigate and to make a long story short They discovered now despite the fact that everyone involved said there's no way it could be a burst pipe or anything because that just couldn't happen.
Rym: There enough the tree one of its roots had Penetrated an old water pipe and the pressure had been forcing water through the tree where it then manifested at this hole in the middle of the truck.
Scott: Oh Now the reason would have thought that that there was a perfectly rational bull, you know rational reasonable explanation.
Rym: Now the reason they discovered this.
Scott: the best part would have thought that people tested the water.
Rym: Not only was it tap water but it was Filled with a very high Bacterial load probably because it was filtered through water and then a tree and that it was dangerous to drink.
Scott: well dirt and then a tree.
Scott: I mean the water It was dangerous to drink.
Scott: Oh, good job.
Scott: You smart people got what they deserved.
Rym: Now the woman who said she wanted to get it tested and kept calling the state, you know Come and test this come and test this you might think.
Rym: well She wants to find out what's going on because there's obviously rational explanation.
Rym: Here is exactly why what she wanted the state of Texas to test for quotes, I just wanted to know if it was a healing tree or Miracle water.
Scott: Yeah, there's a difference somehow I don't know.
Rym: I don't know ever.
Rym: I can't believe that of so many people were suckered in by this and looking around the internet There are a lot of people who are still talking about how amazing this is now.
Rym: Yeah, you scientist.
Rym: You can't solve this one.
Rym: Yeah, we just solved it in like a minute like the article I'm linking to came out before they discovered that it was a you know a pipe and The article is really kind of slanted toward the view that we can't solve it.
Rym: It's a magical mystery.
Scott: Just cuz he can't solve it doesn't mean we it just we haven't solved it yet.
Rym: I guess I wish reporters would be far more incredulous when they talk to people because it seems that whenever reporter Interviews one of these people who says that their statue of I don't know Liam Neeson is bleeding through the eyes and they want you know, it's a miracle.
Rym: I don't know why I picked Liam Neeson I don't know who that is.
Rym: anyway Find their statue of Princess Leia.
Rym: I know leading through the eyes We have a funny Princess Leia story, but that's neither here nor there.
Scott: No, it's not.
Rym: actually it's right over there.
Rym: Yeah Reporters always interview the person as though it's true and they act as though everything that person says is true because they report it as though I'm Just reporting what this person said.
Rym: It is not my place to judge them.
Rym: I Really wish a reporter would ask the serious questions.
Rym: Like wouldn't it make sense that this just penetrated a pipe?
Rym: What makes you think that there's anything other than a rational explanation?
Scott: Well, I think what it is is, you know on the news they pretty much have bad stories and good stories.
Scott: You know a bad story is anything to do with national or international news at all is always negative.
Scott: They get as negative as they possibly can.
Scott: we're talking about anything out there.
Scott: And whenever they talk about local news, that's not crime.
Scott: They focus on the most positive thing They possibly can.
Scott: they make it as positive as possible as all the fluff pieces.
Scott: so the reporters, you know doing the local stuff are never gonna be negative about it because It's sort of like putting down your audience.
Scott: It's like You know the peep the local stories.
Scott: Those are the people watching the news.
Scott: you're gonna go around.
Scott: People are gonna watch the local news and see the news make fun of their neighbor or their friend down the road.
Scott: They're not gonna like that, but they don't mind you making fun of you know, some guy in another country or some politician.
Rym: Well, it's not just the local news.
Rym: It's something.
Rym: take the evolution debate.
Rym: It's even though it's not really a debate.
Rym: It's just one group of people yelling and other group of people ignoring them.
Rym: But anyway It seems that the news always tries to appear fair and objective and balanced.
Rym: So they always give equal weight to every argument, which is crazy.
Rym: I mean say Scott Alex and I are arguing over whether or not the thing I'm holding in my hand is the DVD are.
Rym: We look at it and all three of us agree.
Rym: It says DVD are on it.
Rym: It's obviously a DVD are.
Rym: and then some hobo who escaped from the insane asylum up the road breaks in through the window and says That's not a DVD.
Rym: are at the squirrel.
Rym: But you don't need to even acknowledge the fact that the hobo said it was a squirrel.
Rym: you and if you do You make sure to mention that this is a crazy hobo and not a DVD are expert.
Scott: Well what you got her understand.
Scott: the news doesn't care about giving the news properly.
Scott: They care about ratings.
Scott: There's one.
Scott: I understand why there's a popular opinion, even if it's completely wrong.
Scott: There'll be one-sided to the popular opinion and if there's an opinion that people debate on They'll try to be sort of fair so that no one gets mad at them.
Scott: Yeah, and if there's an opinion that you know everyone believes the right thing then they'll report the right thing.
Rym: You know that's unless they report the wrong thing just to generate controversy.
Rym: so people watch to see what they're talking about.
Scott: Yeah, generally what you do is don't watch the fucking shit mainstream news god damn is it worthless?
Rym: yeah go to the Bloggers and places like GeekNights instead because we have the real news.
Scott: No the idea is to read as much information on the internet as you possibly can and sort it out for yourself Which doesn't work.
Scott: if you're an idiot so step one.
Scott: don't be an idiot.
Rym: We should do a. how to not suck and not being an idiot show someday mmm next Thursday how to get the news truthfully as possible.
Rym: things of the day.
Rym: I Didn't give nearly as many hints as I probably could have as to my thing of the day one thing of the day Two things of the day and three things of the day.
Rym: well just to just Nobody expects the third thing of the day because there isn't one.
Rym: it's our fanatical devotion to the Pope anyway.
Rym: Now there were a lot of guesses to what my thing of the day is and I'm surprised no one guessed lemon party because naked men really Lemon parties what most people would think of.
Scott: she just said it was lemon party and let them go see what lemon party.
Rym: Don't go see what lemon party is though.
Rym: It's probably the tamest of those things on the internet now, but the point is I gave a few hints there were a lot of guesses and Pretty much everyone in the front row crew knew immediately what I was talking about But no one else did and I don't think many people know about this and it's one of those things I really hope makes an internet resurgence because I find it to be one of the most philosophically inspiring videos I've seen on the internet in a long time.
Scott: Yeah, I mean we saw this how many years ago at least two or three.
Rym: It's pretty old may 2004 2003 perhaps and it spread like a virus.
Rym: everyone who saw it showed it to everyone they could and Everyone who saw it then tried to spread it to more people.
Scott: It's the kind of thing you would expect You know like because there's a lot of old stuff that I saw a year or two ago is showing up on dig and gotten Really popular among all the people who haven't seen it yet.
Scott: So I figure this one's gonna come back, but it hasn't yet.
Scott: So maybe we can help it now.
Rym: I'd suggest if you're at a computer that you stop listening right now and watch my thing of the day.
Rym: It is called a heap of trouble.
Rym: Yep, it's a short video now.
Rym: I'll assume at this point that you've all watched it.
Scott: Well, it's not safe for work by the way.
Rym: Oh, yeah, there are naked men lots of them now.
Rym: It is tastefully done.
Rym: It is no worse than what you would expect from.
Rym: I don't know a bunch of naked men walking down this road Causing a heap of trouble for all concerned.
Rym: Yeah, but it's not like erotic It's just naked guys like a nude beach and not like a penthouse, but the video begins with typical suburban Scary, you know black hole Sun types kind of standing around.
Rym: you know kids like playing in the in the street and a girl eating ice cream this nice cream man and all of the parents all of the adults are standing around and you can't really hear what they're saying, but it's definitely a Rabble rabble rabble rabble kind of thing, you know.
Rym: Oh, how dare those blah blah blah blah blah blah?
Rym: I'm all indignant cuz I live in the suburbs exactly and then everything stops because something is coming in the distance and Everyone starts getting really nervous and looking ahead.
Rym: Three naked men and four naked men and five Naked.
Rym: and eventually nine naked men just walking down the road Cause a heap of trouble.
Rym: The lyrics are nine naked men just walking down the road will cause a heap of trouble for all concerned.
Rym: Yes, nine naked men and it just repeats over and over again
Scott: Occasionally they do the countdown, you know One two three four and then they just go back into the cars
Rym: and sure enough over the horizon and around the corner come nine naked men Marching in a line singing this song.
Scott: and I'm nine naked man of a rage of ages ages and body types.
Scott: No, not pleasant to behold.
Rym: This does not go over well with the simple townsfolk.
Rym: They Start in various ways freaking out.
Rym: the first a bunch of little kids like leg it and they run and the mother like freaks out And like starts grabbing the kids and trying to drag them inside now and the ice cream man is like oh shit He's like hiding in his thing.
Rym: But then One of the men the dad the dad of the primary family in the video.
Rym: He doesn't run away he stands there staring at them and He has this inspired look on his face and he slowly puts his daughter down and you know it cuts to.
Rym: it cuts to everyone else running around and you know panicking and then it keeps coming back to him and he's Staring want only and slowly unbuttoned in his shirt At which point his wife and children see him and they physically drag him into the house.
Rym: while they're dragging him in he keep you like you hear him saying like no naked Down the road like he's trying to sing it and it's trying to get out of him and they drag him into the house And it keeps cutting different panicking and then it cuts to the naked man and they start marching by singing their song and they're
Scott: still Wearing socks and shoes, which is way cool
Rym: Not like like the little girl who has the ice cream drops and starts crying But everyone's gone and they're marching and the ice cream man is in his ice cream truck and
Scott: he starts to take off his tie.
Scott: But then he puts it back on like oh, oh shit.
Rym: like he sees himself taking off the time He freaks out like what am I doing?
Rym: And then they're getting closer and he's trying to hide he's covering his ears He tries to climb into the freezer and then they start doing the countdown one naked man.
Rym: And then it gets to nine naked men and meanwhile a new naked man is running forth and then he sings ten naked men And he has joined them and is marching off toward awesome.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Go ice cream, man.
Rym: so then it cuts back to the people inside and the father is stripping himself completely naked and Desperately trying to get outside and the family is physically restraining him and yelling and screaming and then finally like he loses it He's like, oh it happened again and he's crying.
Rym: Yeah the naked man leave and they're gone.
Rym: and as their song fades away it cuts back to the father and he's like And his family's like yes, dear he's like.
Rym: And then the credits roll, yep, well the credits are before that.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but it fades to black.
Rym: Yeah, it fades to black.
Scott: now This video is just as odd.
Scott: remember that I had a thing of the day where some dad beat up some punk kids skateboarding.
Scott: This is the opposite of that because it shows what society should be.
Rym: I mean this first of all, there are so many.
Rym: this is like utenna.
Rym: There are so many ways to interpret it now.
Scott: First I think we're definitely reading more into it than the creator did.
Scott: but that's okay.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I wonder.
Rym: I'd like to I'd like to talk to the people who made it.
Rym: But anyway, first off if you take it at face value It is nine naked men marching down the road causing a heap of trouble for all concern, which is awesome.
Rym: It's absolutely hilarious.
Rym: The comedic timing is impeccable Mm-hmm.
Rym: Now if you look at it from one metaphorical perspective those men represent that Libertine freedom that is so lacking in American society.
Scott: They are the awesome.
Rym: These are men who have decided that you know fuck all with Convention and all of your you know, rabble rabble rabble crap.
Rym: I am naked.
Rym: I'm proud I'm marching down the street and it is my right to do so.
Rym: I beg all of you to join us in our revelry and our libertine wanton fun.
Scott: And it also shows you that all you know, the men in society, I guess but you know The people of the world want to join them secretly, but because you know, they have this bullshit suburban life You know, they're withheld and they you know, they're concealed and they're holding in their inhibitions.
Rym: I mean the ice-cream man clearly wants to join them but he is so repulsed by the idea of joining them that he becomes very Conflicted and the only time he becomes happy is when he realizes that that's what he really wants.
Rym: so he goes and does it.
Rym: meanwhile the father who think of this like a a fundamentalist group that is against homosexuals.
Rym: many times the rationale is that Homosexuality is something that is that can easily get you they can convert you they can make you be that way and it seems to me that the only people who would think that are people who are Homosexual and do want to be that way and think that everyone else feels that way And that it's you know a seductive thing.
Rym: and it's the same thing.
Rym: the father.
Rym: He obviously really wants to do it and his family forces him not to and he ends up being one of them self-hatin.
Scott: Yeah, he's like, oh they almost got me.
Rym: it's so sad Oh my god.
Rym: Meanwhile, the only time in the whole video he actually looks inspired is when he wants to join them.
Scott: Yeah, the rest of the time he's all.
Scott: he's either crying or he's just kind of bored and useless.
Rym: Also the fact that society will use peer pressure as in, you know, everyone's saying no, this is horrible run away But it will also use coercion if it can to oppress you meaning they physically prevented him from joining the naked men.
Scott: Yep Let it just be said that you know Rym and Scott are on the side of the naked men and if there were naked men marching down the road They would be plus two most likely except that they would probably then become registered sex offenders.
Rym: Now, of course the third way to look at this that I just remembered that we were going to talk about We kind of skip is that these people are doing something.
Rym: Not really, but you know if these were real people doing something really and not for a film they're doing it something that we like to call Freaking squares.
Scott: Yes, you might remember the Simpsons episode.
Scott: I believe it was the one with the Tamako.
Rym: No, it was completely different.
Scott: Those are with Ben and Jerry.
Scott: Yes, and because that also involved a farm.
Scott: That's why anyway
Rym: Homer and the hippies decided to go freak some squares meaning go out Find people who are living their mundane life and do something that they can't just automatically react to kind of like what those Living theater people who do like Invader Best Buy or be slow-motion for 10 minutes in a Home Depot do?
Rym: yep Where you suddenly do something that people just can't deal with or it's something that people can't just rationalize Automatically and they have to stop and think.
Rym: and your hope is that when they stop and think they might realize That they're kind of living their life like an automaton Mm-hmm.
Rym: I mean I I do it occasionally where little things like if I'm standing in an elevator and everyone's facing the door I just kind of turn around and face all the people and it's amazing how absolutely uncomfortable everyone else in that elevator gets immediately.
Scott: Yeah, that's always a fun one.
Rym: or I'll just make eye contact with someone and not break it and they don't know what to do.
Rym: Really people just don't know what to do.
Rym: if I'm walking down the street And I'm like like I'm working in a lab somewhere and I just look up at someone to make eye contact and don't say anything They immediately look away like he saw me.
Scott: Oh No, I'm not invisible anymore.
Scott: What do I do?
Scott: Oh, he has true sight.
Scott: Oh, I'm so screwed.
Scott: I can make a visual joke.
Rym: Oh, yeah Scott made an incredibly hilarious joke, but there's no way I can possibly impart over the air.
Rym: Haha.
Scott: It is so inside.
Scott: It's inside our house still.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: I made another inside joke that no one can see.
Rym: If anyone remembers this episode the next time they see us in person ask us about the inside jokes and see if we remember.
Scott: haha Okay, I have a thing of the day.
Rym: Why bother my thing of the day was so unbeatable.
Scott: It's an okay thing of the day man.
Rym: Is it?
Scott: Yeah, so there's a prison and a guy breaks out.
Scott: I don't know how he broke out But he did and I guess he either did it by awesome skills or by stupidity the guards and hopefully it was awesome skills.
Scott: I'm guessing it's awesome skills because of what he does in the video You see this guy's that break broken out of prison running down some train tracks.
Rym: now Meanwhile, all the police know that a man who looks like this gentleman has just broken out of prison in this area.
Scott: So of course running down the train tracks, who does he come across?
Scott: but a police officer?
Scott: Now, of course He doesn't just get up and run because well the cop would get in his car run Chase after him in the car hit him with the car Get out cuff him and put him in the back of the car.
Rym: Also, probably call for the helicopter and the guards and say and the dogs and these the dogs and the bees the dogs That you bees out of the other car.
Scott: That's a little while down the tracks and yeah.
Scott: So he stops and talks to the police officer.
Scott: He's got like a power rate or a Gatorade or something and you know, he's not wearing prison garb I think he's.
Scott: he changed his clothes and whatever and the cop is like man.
Scott: this guy fits his description.
Scott: So he keeps a radioing, you know for help, but the cops picture of the guy isn't the highest quality.
Scott: so he's not a hundred percent sure and The cop really questions the guy out and the guy isn't the brightest guy Like you could you?
Scott: it's possible to have been much more smooth But his level of smoothness is sufficient to outwit this police officer and the cop just lets him go even with his Incredibly shitty alibi.
Rym: now Scott and I view this slightly differently.
Rym: I say that while he I mean, I don't know what the man did.
Rym: so I'll assume that he murders babies.
Scott: Yeah, I have no idea what the guy didn't seem like that evil a guy.
Scott: He seemed like a normal kind of.
Scott: He probably wasn't a killer.
Rym: Yeah Let's assume he was a baby murderer just for the sake of argument.
Rym: that way we're arguing the most extreme case.
Rym: that way no matter What it's less bad than we think.
Rym: okay, so The cop let him go.
Rym: I would rather the cop let the baby murderer escape his custody Then have arrested someone who just happened to be walking down those train tracks.
Scott: I gotta agree with that.
Scott: But I do have to say if you watch the video all I'm saying is the cop does a real shitty job of checking to See if this is the guy I mean.
Scott: You know the odds is someone coming along who meets the description so well And then you accepting the shittiest crap alibi like yeah, I'm in a hotel I don't even know where the hotel is my brother You know.
Scott: drop me off some miles down the track so I could go jogging to the hotel and yeah.
Scott: But then again I didn't even know the names of the towns around here.
Rym: the guy's story follows the pattern of See.
Rym: I'm gonna give you guys a little hint today because it really goes into what our main bit is.
Rym: But if you want to lie to someone like a police officer or an authority figure one of the biggest keys you can do is to have a Somewhat strange story.
Rym: don't ever say something generic like I'm just out for a walk.
Scott: Or I think this guy says his name is like you know George Rogers or something so generic.
Scott: Robert Robert Jones is what he says.
Scott: his name.
Rym: when I was caught by the police as a child doing things I shouldn't have been doing I always gave my name is like Steve something hmm.
Rym: I just always use the name Steve.
Rym: But anyway, if you need to lie to a police officer about something now of course I'm not advocating legally that you lie to a police officer who is doing his pursuant duties In a way that would get you in trouble.
Rym: however That is simply the thing that I must say.
Scott: isn't there not actually a law that says you you can't?
Scott: there's no law that says You're not allowed to lie to a police officer?
Scott: No, just a law that says anything you can or say will be held against you if you're arrested.
Rym: Yeah, you can lie to police officers all you want.
Scott: Yeah if a police officer comes up and asked you and says do you know how fast you were going?
Scott: and you know you can say I have no idea.
Scott: or you can say I was going two miles an hour officer.
Scott: Yeah, you can say whatever you want.
Scott: Let's say you can say monkey purple Thursday.
Rym: Unless he happens Unless he happens to have a judge with him and they put you under oath right away Yeah, then then you you can't lie, but there's no.
Rym: or or if he's judged dread.
Scott: Yes if it's judged don't lie to judge dread.
Scott: or if it's a lensman cuz a lensman will know and He'll just get the truth out of your brain.
Rym: But the point is Oh and Wonder Woman make your story a little bit off But not make it a little weird, but don't give too many details, but give at least one strange detail.
Scott: Yeah, this guy goes beyond one strange detail into.
Scott: basically he's obviously making it up on the fly.
Scott: Like if you showed me this video without telling me it was the guy who was running he was escaping prison I would have figured out in about five seconds.
Scott: I've been like, oh, that's the guy cuz he's just making up shit.
Scott: Yeah, probably doesn't know what.
Scott: he doesn't know where he is.
Scott: He doesn't know anything.
Rym: Well, just remember there's a you have to make up.
Rym: I'd say a good baseline if you're panicking is make up three Details as to what you were doing and don't give any more details because if you give more than three or four details When a cop asks you that's a sign of nervousness.
Rym: and the moment you're showing that kind of nervousness The cop is going.
Scott: is the thing is the guy it was acting kind of nervous and the cop did kind of suspect.
Rym: Oh, no, no, no the cut.
Rym: Yeah, the cop didn't obviously know what I'm telling everyone.
Rym: You I mean you can get away with lying to people who are dumb.
Rym: I think I had no idea how to lie to people who are somewhat smarter than this cop.
Rym: Yeah, give three pertinent details.
Rym: Make sure at least one of them is somewhat strange and make sure your story is not just run-of-the-mill.
Rym: but don't make it like don't say a bear killed me and Now I'm on these train tracks.
Scott: Yeah, the point of this video is look at the stupid cop.
Rym: Hahahaha.
Rym: Anyway, our topic today is how to not suck at talking.
Scott: No.
Scott: Wow, that's kind of generic.
Rym: Well, the thing is we originally were going to do a show on how to do a good panel and we realized that Doing a good panel is one specific topic.
Rym: but public speaking in general and the presentation of you know Your voice and your speech and your person Really could do to be an entirely separate show because a panel discussion would also have to talk a lot about the content Which I don't want to bother with today.
Scott: Yeah, I guess it depends what kind of panel you're doing.
Scott: But anyway Public speaking.
Rym: Yes, public speaking is something that the majority of Americans cannot do well and are afraid of.
Rym: in fact, and There are many studies that show that more Americans are afraid of public speaking than they are of dying.
Scott: Now here is my first piece of advice to anyone who is Nervous at all.
Scott: if you have any amount of nervousness in your body when you get up to talk to more than one person Like you're standing on a stage or anything on a podium What the hell are you afraid of?
Scott: what the fuck's wrong with you?
Scott: I mean, what do you think?
Scott: They're gonna throw tomatoes at you, but they're all gonna boo you and you got to run away.
Scott: They're gonna.
Rym: music's bad and you should fail that.
Scott: Yeah, it's like even if even if you're absolutely terrible you give the worst presentation Imaginable of whatever you're doing and everyone in the audience hates you and they think you're the worst person ever You know, they treat you like a baby raper.
Scott: What's the worst they can do?
Scott: What?
Scott: you're not gonna go to jail You're not gonna get killed, you know, you're not gonna be anally raped You're not gonna.
Scott: nothing bad is going to happen now.
Rym: granted That sounds like very easy to follow advice that for many people is actually very very difficult to follow.
Scott: Yeah, I I just I can't understand it because I never had the problem.
Rym: Yeah, whatever.
Rym: Anyway, I at least understand that it's not you.
Rym: just because someone's afraid of something and you tell them that it's not something to be Afraid of.
Rym: that doesn't make it any easy.
Scott: Oh, I didn't say it does make it easy.
Scott: I'm just saying I don't understand where the fear comes from because I don't have it.
Rym: most people Scott who are actually human beings and not some kind of masturbation bod Know that they are afraid.
Scott: I just don't know.
Rym: most humans have an innate fear of being embarrassed of being discredited of being ridiculed.
Rym: Many people have low self-esteem.
Scott: Well don't have those things.
Rym: many people are speaking for a grade where something bad can happen to you.
Rym: a grade is not important It can be not really now, uh, yeah It can be.
Rym: once Scott if I had a GPA of less than 3.4 IBM by their policy would not have even looked at my resume.
Scott: Yeah, that's not such a big deal.
Scott: Yeah, it is terms of your greater life.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: it kind of is because working for IBM is pretty much what made me the Badass that I am today in terms of being able to get a job wherever I want.
Rym: Hey working for IBM has greatly affected my life as much as many other of the greatly pivotal events in my life.
Scott: Yeah, but it's not like if you didn't work for IBM you would have worked somewhere shit.
Rym: Also, if I had not had a 3.4 GBA I would have lost all of my scholarships.
Rym: Thus I could not have afforded to go our go to RIT.
Rym: Thus.
Rym: I would have had to immediately drop out.
Scott: Yeah, you would have still made it somehow.
Rym: No, I probably wouldn't have.
Scott: I couldn't have generated that much money and I certainly You would have gone somewhere else, you know done something else.
Rym: Yes My life would have been completely different, but it would have been bad.
Rym: The point is that a grade can affect your life.
Rym: or for example Say you're giving us a big presentation to a client for a company.
Rym: if you botch the presentation and the client doesn't buy and it's a Big account you're there's a good chance.
Rym: You might just be fired.
Scott: that that is possible.
Rym: Yes So yes, don't say that there can't be consequences.
Scott: because there can be I guess but I've never had to give a speech or presentation with severe consequences.
Scott: Yeah, I guess it's the best kind to give because if you suck at public speaking don't go giving speeches With consequences.
Scott: do the non consequence ones first to build the skills.
Rym: Well, the thing is I mean, honestly, I have a lot more experience with this partly because I you know I was I was on the eboard of the anime club.
Rym: So every week for much of my college existence I had to get up in front of a few hundred people or a couple hundred people and you know Generally keep their attention not get laughed at talk about things.
Rym: I Do it.
Rym: I'm starting to suspect that not many places actually force people to do this much anymore.
Rym: But at RIT pretty much any class you took you generally had to give at least one somewhat significant Presentation to the class.
Scott: Oh, yeah in some of my classes.
Scott: I had to give presentations weekly.
Scott: Yes for computer classes I'd have to get up and talk about the project I was working on every week and give status reports and all sorts of things.
Rym: one seminar I took on political speech giving a political communication.
Rym: Not only did we have to present something every class but every week for every other week a Student was responsible for teaching to the entire class an entire lesson.
Scott: I love that because a as I love teaching the class and because I think I do a better job than some teachers.
Scott: and Be that take that teachers awesome and lazy so they get points.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Yes That was one of my favorite classes ever.
Rym: Yeah Even though we I mean it was 12 people and we were all pretty smart and the teacher knows a lot about political science.
Rym: He was convinced Absolutely convinced that John Kerry was not going to get the Democratic nomination.
Scott: He shows you how much of a science political science is.
Rym: Anyway now addition, I actually took every Communications class that RIT had to offer because I had free time in my schedule and I really liked that major.
Rym: But I realized I could never get a job with that major.
Rym: so I took a Concentration in it and I used that as an excuse to be able to sign up for all the classes that I normally couldn't sign Up for.
Rym: and what I did is I never filled out the paperwork to complete the concentration.
Rym: Thus I was always in it and I could keep taking the classes long after I'd fulfilled the requirements.
Rym: Mmm, good move which was a big deal at RIT because class those classes build up almost immediately And if you didn't get in early in the crazy registration system, they have you could never take these classes.
Scott: Yeah, I remember when I went to the liberal arts department.
Scott: They're like you took too many liberal arts classes.
Scott: I'm like, uh, it's fine.
Scott: Just fill all these other slots with them.
Scott: I don't care.
Scott: Yeah All right.
Rym: Yeah, I also took a class specifically on public speaking and speech giving.
Scott: I took the best speech public presentation class that I ever had was actually in my senior year of high school because there was this really good teacher.
Scott: basically what He did is the whole class was come up with a speech and give it to the class and do it over and over and over and over and over and By the end of that class pretty much everyone was awesome like I even had a friend in that class who was just so nervous to go and talk in front of even like two people and He would get up in front of the class and start giving these great speeches and halfway through he just be like I can't go On and then he'd sit down even though he was giving this great speech and no one thought bad of it.
Scott: That's how good the teacher was.
Scott: Wow.
Rym: Yeah Alright.
Scott: Anyway, that's I learned.
Rym: actually I remember because I'll say that I used to when I was very young Despite how you know loud I tend to be nowadays when I was very young I was actually very nervous about speaking in public or speaking in front of a crowd.
Scott: So I guess in first grade they made me the narrator for the little pigs play.
Scott: Oh I always hated that but for completely different reason and I would cuz I was loud and I was the only person who could speak Loudly and clearly I Read.
Rym: Yeah, that's what bothered me the most about school when I was very early schools that whenever the class would read something as a Whole I would read the whole thing like ten minutes while the class took an hour because apparently everyone else in the room couldn't read at All and they couldn't actually Say what they were.
Rym: so that's for sure host to say Yeah, it just it bothered me and I'd always get in trouble because the teacher would call on me like I ran And you got to read something.
Rym: I'd be like what I was asleep.
Rym: I was done.
Rym: I already read it.
Scott: I always seem to get stuck with the narrating job.
Scott: I remember middle school with Odyssey of the Mind.
Scott: I got stuck with being the narrator with you know My loud and concise speaking but at least when I'm reading something when I'm coming up with stuff in my head It's not so good.
Rym: in seventh grade suddenly our English teacher decided that we had to learn how to speak in public and what she did is she had everyone write down a Topic.
Rym: Well, she didn't say what was going on.
Rym: She just said write down a topic you're interested in.
Rym: So we all wrote something down.
Rym: Of course.
Rym: I was the nerd who asked the question Can it be anything?
Rym: and she said yes, it can be anything.
Scott: However, did you write down?
Rym: We'll get to that.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So then I like how this is.
Scott: now geek fables of public speaking instead of how to not suck.
Rym: Yeah, we'll give a bunch of advice real quick.
Rym: Okay the end anyway.
Rym: So then she puts them all in a hat and she says alright starting now with in alphabetical order Everyone is going to draw something from this hat and give a two-minute speech on it to the whole class and the whole room goes Oh shits
Scott: What if it was something you didn't know like someone else wrote down like car racing.
Scott: you didn't know shit about cars exactly.
Rym: It was a test of extemporaneous speaking skill.
Scott: Oh, wow Yeah, it's pretty good.
Scott: That'd be good for college.
Rym: So the first person goes up and they get something I don't remember whatever.
Rym: the second person goes up.
Rym: They pull something out of the head.
Rym: They look straight at me.
Rym: They say Brandon, I hate you.
Rym: Yeah, and then they say I don't know anything about Norse mythology.
Rym: Awesome, I remember that mine was flowers and I was really nervous and I got up and I start babbling Flowers.
Scott: flowers blah like a gibbering mouth thing.
Rym: Yeah, I said the word for flower in German because someone had said that to me not two days earlier Uh-huh, and I finished and I realized right then and there that the class reacted to me The exact same way that they'd reacted to the people who'd gone before me and then as I watched To the same way to everyone that went after and with one exception or someone who gave a really funny speech No one was treated any differently by the audience at all And in fact, no one cared one shit except
Scott: for nerdy.
Scott: McFinkster who got picked on.
Rym: Actually, no, no one can't like no one in the audience cared.
Scott: Maybe nerdy.
Scott: McFinkster was in the class across the hall.
Rym: Oh, no no one in the audience cared at all how good anyone's speech was.
Rym: and After the class was over and it ended I realized then that I can just give a speech and it doesn't matter cuz no one Cares.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much So.
Rym: then we had to actually give speeches in class like we had to prepare two speeches an informative one And I forget that a persuasive one something like that doesn't really matter.
Rym: No, I did my my.
Rym: I did my one that effectively was persuasive on Dungeons and Dragons.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: and Actually, I'm very proud of my other speech my informative one.
Rym: I did a spoof of John Cleese's how to irritate people.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and I talked for an hour about for 45 minutes about how to irritate people and it was hilarious Uh-huh.
Rym: So I guess the first bit of advice to actually tie this into the advice is Remember that no matter how afraid you are in most cases like Scott was saying until I completely are disagreed with him.
Rym: But it is true in many cases.
Rym: The audience doesn't give a shit.
Scott: No, I mean most likely they're just gonna go to sleep And they don't care.
Scott: I mean depending on where it is.
Scott: I mean if it's a panel at an anime con they want to be entertained and informed Yeah, but if it's like a business thing you want to convince someone but most of the time In all the situations I can think of its people are there because they have to be or something like that.
Rym: Let me put it this way If you don't like public speaking you probably avoid it.
Rym: as a result if you are in a situation where you are public speaking Meaning it is mandatory.
Rym: You did not elect to do it.
Rym: You have been chosen to do it by some force.
Rym: You have no control over.
Rym: Odds.
Rym: are the people who have to listen to you don't care any more than you do and aren't any more interested than you are?
Scott: And also though if you are forced into a mandatory situation where there might be Consequences if you've been avoiding it all this long time you're out of practice and you're going to screw it up.
Scott: So if there are ever opportunities to speak in public with no consequences just take them because no one will care.
Scott: now I mean you will improve your skills at something which is not easy to improve your skills at.
Rym: I can at this time give a Nod to.
Rym: I mean there are a lot of organizations out there for people who are afraid of public speaking.
Rym: Really the most prominent one is the Toastmasters.
Scott: Oh, do they just give toast you just go there and keep toast.
Rym: See, I thought it would be cool and I joined at IBM and I realized it was kind of lame because for me at least But for a lot of people really helps them.
Rym: the Toastmasters are clubs.
Rym: They have annual dues, but they're trivial.
Rym: It's some piddly amount of money like a dollar.
Rym: It's like 60 or something bucks, but it's not much.
Rym: That's and you can go to their meetings for free pretty much Okay, and all they do is they give speeches to each other and then critique each other.
Rym: Usually every group or Chapter has one or two experienced speakers and then a bunch of people who want to get better and it's usually a very good thing.
Rym: I personally found it very cheesy and boring but After I did one speech at IBM, the guy said why are you even here?
Rym: You want to run this?
Rym: Yes, and I never went back.
Scott: See I would go to it not to improve my speeching skills But I would go to.
Scott: you know, give many persuasive speeches to the group of people there.
Scott: Yeah to convince them of things that they were.
Rym: here's why the Toastmasters suck.
Scott: Here's why Toastmasters suck.
Scott: Here's why God doesn't exist.
Scott: Here's why Linux is the best.
Rym: Yeah So anyway, the fear thing we can't really cover anymore Other than the best way to get over your fear is to realize no one cares and to do public speaking whenever you can.
Scott: Yeah there are other things you can do about it that a lot of people suggest like look at one person in the audience and just Concentrate on them.
Scott: or you know Imagine a chicken dancing in the back of the room or get your friend to wear a chicken suit dance in the back of the Room and all that kind of BS, but that's just.
Scott: you know ways of getting around the problem without pulling it out by the roots.
Rym: Yes Actually, I remember the advice that I gave to a friend in high school.
Rym: that was stupid and hilarious And I wish there was a funny follow-up story, but there isn't though pretend there is one pretend.
Rym: I told a funny story that happened as a result of this because none actually happened.
Rym: I'm not going to make something up, but I Had a friend in high school who's very afraid of public speaking and my and he was like he was a guy and my advice was Think about Naked women.
Scott: Oh my god, because I knew a guy who said he did this But I didn't believe him.
Scott: is that when he was gonna give a speech you would bring up his speech notes and a plate and A center a playboy centerfold and he would put it one next to the other to give the speech.
Scott: See do okay now.
Rym: I told him you know just think about that stuff and it'll take your mind off of how afraid you are.
Rym: Now my intention was that he would have a giant erection during his speech in class, which didn't happen.
Rym: Yeah You know what?
Rym: yeah, it happened.
Rym: He had a giant erection in class and everyone laughed at him.
Scott: good thing He wasn't a naked man walking down the road and then he died of cancer.
Rym: Now in terms of actually being good at public speaking or in terms of you know Speaking to a group of people no matter how large it is is that there are a bunch of very simple tricks.
Rym: one Don't make.
Rym: I will make eye contact with the audience But if you are uncomfortable doing so or and actually if you have the trouble I have where if I make eye contact with someone it tends to either unearth them when I'm giving a speech or I lock on To them and then it's obvious that I'm staring at someone.
Rym: Yeah the idea is look at everyone's foreheads and kind of look through everyone with a thousand mile stare because then Every single person in the audience thinks that you're making eye contact with them when in fact You're not making eye contact with anyone.
Scott: You gotta be like the Abe Lincoln statue in the Lincoln Memorial.
Scott: He's not looking at anyone.
Scott: He's just got these eyes that are kind of going out over the whole area there.
Scott: But if you look at the statue, it looks like it's looking at you.
Rym: So that's the first see.
Rym: we're gonna give very specific advice as opposed to the generic a blah blah blah.
Scott: Yeah, you gotta have your eyes not looking down not looking up at the ceiling.
Scott: You gotta have them looking straight out, but not you know, if you're on a stage or if you're elevated at all I mean if the people are sitting and you're standing your head is above them.
Scott: so if you're in order to look people in the face and in the eyes your head is going to have to be pointed down a Little bit or your eyes are gonna have to be pointed down.
Scott: if you keep your head straight and your eyes Straightforward you won't be looking at anybody.
Scott: You'll probably looking at like the back of the room or the chairs in the back or people's hair But everyone will think you're looking at them which is now.
Rym: that was the effectively beginners advice.
Rym: Yes, the advanced advice is that you really don't want to ever make eye contact with anyone in the room.
Rym: However, what you do want to do is it depends on what kind of speech you're giving.
Rym: but my general advice if you want to Appear confident and strong and you're trying to persuade the audience of something the best Mode your head can be in is you want to be looking Downward slightly.
Rym: your head should be angled down just a little bit like you're looking at the ground But your eyes should be angled up.
Rym: So you're kind of looking at everyone through slightly lowered gaze.
Rym: So you're looking up like past your eyebrows at everyone.
Rym: now don't do it Obviously.
Rym: this has to be subtle but that sort of body posture Puts forth an extremely strong almost predatory.
Rym: Look that will keep the audience's attention very well Mmm, then doubt that is not so useful in front of very very large crowds But it is incredibly useful if you were talking to a small group of people Yeah and if you even if you're talking one-on-one using that kind of body language at the and then Increasing it slightly just as you make your important point Will very easily bowl over people who aren't ready for it or who are easily persuaded
Scott: Regardless
Rym: of what you're saying.
Scott: that also reminds me if there's a camera of some sort Like let's say you're on TV and as a video camera There's usually like a light or a thing that you're supposed to look at that, you know You know how Jon Stewart's always looking right into the camera.
Scott: That's what you got to do.
Scott: You got to find where the thing you're supposed to look at is and look right into it or else You know the camera is gonna look at it like the side of your head.
Rym: That's not good Though you still in a camera situation.
Rym: You still want to Basically pan your head from left to right and back and forth very slowly and somewhat erratically while you talk.
Rym: So it looks like you're engaging a large crowd.
Scott: You don't want to look like a statue.
Scott: You want to look like, you know.
Rym: More importantly if you were trying to impress people or do a good speech.
Rym: if you're looking straight at the camera It doesn't matter to the people in the audience so much but to the people watching on TV It looks as though you are only speaking to the camera and that you have no audience at all.
Rym: If you're looking to the sides a lot the audience Subconsciously at home will get the impression that there's an incredibly large crowd there.
Rym: It's just kind of a subconscious thing that you can use to your advantage Especially to make it look like you're giving a much more important speech than you really are.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Now in terms of voice you have got to be loud or have a microphone.
Rym: There are no bones about that.
Rym: There's no way around that.
Scott: preferably be loud with a microphone.
Rym: If you are a quiet person and you have a quiet voice or if your voice is damaged or if there's some reason you can't Talk loudly you must get a microphone.
Rym: Yep, I'm not going to talk about microphone etiquette and microphone technique because that would be an entire other episode.
Rym: Yeah suffice to say if you're holding the microphone don't fiddle with it.
Rym: Don't hold it in front of your face.
Rym: Hold it down.
Rym: Scott holds it in front of his face.
Scott: That's where I'm holding it now and Be consistent with it.
Rym: However, you decide to hold it right or wrong.
Scott: don't change that unless someone who is directing you tells you to yeah But what it all comes down to is that if no one can hear what you're saying it doesn't matter what you say.
Scott: nothing else matters because no one can hear you and That's that's bad.
Rym: Now in order to give a good speech or to talk to people in an engaging way You really the best way to do it is to speak extemporaneously Meaning don't have notes don't ever prepared speech just talk.
Rym: say whatever you think you should say, which is Incredibly difficult if you haven't done it before.
Scott: well, I mean, you know, we're do it on this show.
Scott: We don't have any prepared anything.
Scott: We just talk the way we would talk in public to our friends or to anyone on the street.
Rym: See the thing is people have a lot of trouble doing that to a crowd and more importantly usually You are speaking about something that isn't colloquial.
Rym: I mean if I was giving a speech and act like I was political speech or something I probably wouldn't be talking the way I'm talking now.
Rym: No, probably not and but basically the Speaking as temper.
Rym: extemporaneously.
Rym: the best way to do it is if you're speaking about something you were knowledgeable about the more you know About the topic at hand the easier it will be for you to give a speech with less preparation.
Scott: Yeah, I mean well first of all, it is very important to prepare.
Rym: Well, yeah to a point.
Rym: Yes, I mean don't over prepare we'll get into that.
Rym: But in terms of actually giving the speech if you know about the topic The more you know the less you have to prepare.
Rym: think of it.
Scott: Yeah, for example, if Stephen Hawking was gonna give a speech on some sort of astrophysics thing He already knows he doesn't have to go and study it or write up a bunch of notes He just get up there and start talking about it.
Scott: If you ask me about like to give a speech on You know doing a GeekNights podcast or Linux or anything I know a lot about I can just get up and tell you everything I know about it.
Scott: It comes right out the mouth.
Rym: now the other thing is Even if you know like say you're the quiz bowl master and you memorize all the facts about Greek mythology That doesn't mean you'll be able to give a good speech on Greek mythology because unless you know the subject Intuitively as opposed to knowing the facts of the subject.
Rym: While you'll be able to give perfectly accurate information and this seems to be the problem a lot of informative speakers seem to have Yeah, you PowerPoint people, you know all your stuff.
Rym: You know it.
Rym: You have the knowledge you were imparting the knowledge But because you don't truly understand the content you don't emphasize the proper things and you over emphasize The things that don't matter so much.
Scott: Yeah, you're essentially just a talking in monotone encyclopedia a lot of the time Which no one wants to hear because they could just read the encyclopedia.
Rym: now Along these lines a lot of people can't speak Extemporaneously for various reasons and because it is a difficult thing to do and there are many times when I have not been able To do it and I've been forced to prepare.
Rym: When you prepare a speech very simply don't write the whole thing Unless you plan to memorize it.
Rym: if you write the entire speech out word for word and then you try to read it You will completely fuck up.
Rym: or you will look terrible.
Scott: or you have a teleprompter and you know how to use it.
Rym: Yes, however rare case.
Rym: However, if you have never used a teleprompter, it is not easy.
Scott: No, it is not good.
Scott: You have to spend a lot of time learning how to use one of those freaking.
Rym: Yeah, cuz you're talking to it because we had one in one of our classes and you look away at the audience and you look Back you lose trip play track where you are and you're completely fucked.
Scott: Yeah, it's it's sort of a. if you're the president talking on TV That's when it's for.
Scott: it's not for anything else.
Rym: But if you if you're gonna write a speech out you would better memorize it.
Rym: and by memorize it.
Rym: I don't mean memorize it I mean Say it often in front of mirrors for weeks before you're giving your speech.
Scott: Yeah when we're talking about preparation, you know I wasn't talking about you know, you write down every single word you're gonna say I'm talking about.
Scott: you give the speech over and over again to yourself to your friends to anyone else in the house.
Scott: But you know the more important the speech the more you want to practice it and you see what they think of it.
Scott: and you know if they seem impressed like You know or you do it to the mirror and it seems right and you don't sound like an idiot then you know You're doing good.
Scott: You know if you can't even give the speech to like your mom your dad and your friend sitting in the room you're in trouble.
Rym: Yes, don't think that you'll magically pull one for the team or suddenly bust out amazingly.
Scott: No, if anything you'll suddenly crumple, you know Hey, it's.
Scott: but even there's a chance that even if you did it successfully for you know your friends and your family that you'll screw up the best happy medium.
Rym: if you know a topic but you don't know it intuitively Or if you think you're a good enough public speaker to where you'll be able to just blow through it the best way I've found to prepare is to make you know little note cards or a sheet of paper that have a Basic outline of the order you want to talk about things in and the key points you want to talk about and Then have like a line or a piece of something or a bit or a statistic or all the things you want to remember For sure to say like say you have a really awesome line or a quote you want to use in the middle of a section.
Rym: Put that down verbatim so you don't forget it, but don't put anything else down verbatim.
Scott: That's what I would do In when I had to write speeches.
Scott: for that class is I would write a speech and then it would go through and for every Paragraph I would delete the entire paragraph from the from the word processor.
Scott: But I would write like a phrase that you know.
Scott: get the idea of the paragraph.
Scott: So if I wrote a paragraph about you know the memory manager I would just write talk about the memory manager or I just write memory manager and if those is Statistic or a particular piece of information in that paragraph that I'd remember a number I would put that one with an indent and I would just do that for every single paragraph and in the end I had one measly index card with the topic of each paragraph and Maybe a fact for some of those paragraphs.
Scott: and that's what I would go in with.
Scott: you know And I just knew you know I looked down whenever I was stuck.
Scott: You know whenever I was about to run out of things to say I'd look down at the next word and I would Transition right into that and just say everything I knew about the next thing.
Rym: All right, we've gone a little long.
Rym: I imagine we'll talk about this many times in the future with more and more details since there's a lot more we could say.
Rym: One last piece of advice because I think this is the most important piece that you can have when you're speaking publicly and that is You know there's the voice coming out of your mouth And then there's the voice in your head.
Rym: the voice that's there that when you think to yourself you hear it in your head.
Scott: Mm-hmm when you were speaking to not the voices in your head that are like telling you to kill people Not that one.
Rym: Yeah, those are the fire voices.
Rym: those are separate.
Scott: those are bad.
Rym: now when you were speaking to a crowd You really need to somehow find a way to make the voice that is in your head be perfectly in sync With the voice that is coming out of your mouth.
Rym: don't be thinking Independently of what you were saying because then you will forget what you were saying and if anything disturbs What is coming out of your mouth you will completely lose track of what you're doing?
Scott: Yeah, you'll go uh like I do on the podcast all the time.
Rym: Oh, so instead of thinking you basically you want your thoughts to be your word.
Rym: So everything that you were thinking is what you were saying and you have to concentrate to do this now.
Rym: the Concentration will keep you on topic and prevent you from straying.
Rym: It'll also prevent you from getting distracted in your head because many times it has happened to me where I'm speaking At a thing where I'm not really prepared at all like say it's a GeekNights episode But I didn't really read the news article I'm talking about and I'm tired or I'm I'm fiddling with something on my desk.
Rym: I'm not actually I'm fiddling right now.
Scott: You are fiddling I see that fiddle.
Rym: now at that point my mind Wanders, so I'm thinking this little figure of kagali is really cute.
Rym: I wonder if I can unscrew this thing but my mouth is still talking and Then suddenly my mouth a little buffer in my mouth runs out of things to say and my mind is still thinking And suddenly I have nothing to say.
Scott: it generally happens to me when Rym talks for a while And then I start thinking about something else besides Rym saying and then it's my turn to say something that go what.
Scott: oh Shit I had to say something.
Rym: so I hope there are at least some useful nuggets in that long Ramblings somewhat disorganized talk about talking G.
Scott: We just did we did a bad example And it's supposed to be.
Scott: well.
Rym: see the thing is while GeekNights is often informative.
Rym: our primary goals are Insightful and more often funny.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Scott: I don't know if funny is the goal.
Scott: I think it's more of a side effect.
Rym: funny is my goal But then again, the goal of my life is mostly funny.
Scott: Okay, my goal life is to have funny to view and hear funny things, you know making funny things just sort of happens.
Rym: So if anything in the forums ask us questions about public speaking and I I'm sure we can give you Very detailed pieces of advice.
Rym: Yeah, you'll probably do a show with those pieces of advice sometime in the future and watch for our upcoming episode on how to do A panel at a convention.
Rym: Yeah, we'll give the specific panel bits and That was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.