Rym: It's Thursday July 27th, and this is GeekNights tonight on a very special GeekNights.
Rym: We bring you our first hate mail.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: You know at this point our lives are pretty much on autopilot until Otakon.
Rym: Most of what I do now is just prepare for Otakon or relax.
Scott: Yeah, it well.
Scott: I'm not really thinking about what I do today or the next day or anything like that.
Scott: It's just gotta burn through these days the kind of like you know.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I'm taking care of all my business so when I get back two weeks from now The house is absolutely not dirty in my room is not a mess.
Scott: Yeah, I think I have that under control already, but there's some other things I need to do like finish something at work, which is due when I get back.
Rym: Yeah, I'm trying to finish a bunch of stuff.
Rym: next week is gonna be terrible.
Rym: I don't know what I'm gonna do.
Rym: I mean, I'll basically be sitting at work thinking Otakon's coming Otakon's coming whoop Otakon's coming.
Scott: Yeah, I'm gonna bust out of work.
Scott: I might even go, but I don't know.
Rym: I'm going Wednesday Whatever.
Rym: yeah, I mean we're leaving Thursday Whenever we wake up.
Rym: pretty much.
Rym: Yeah, we'll definitely be in Baltimore by noon.
Rym: so anyone who's going to Otakon And you want to hang out with us try to find us Thursday in the Renaissance Hotel probably in the pool.
Rym: Yeah, we're gonna have a pool party on Thursday, and and then if you're awesome We'll invite you to the wine and cheese party afterward.
Rym: Yeah Well technically it will be a party where in there are both wine and cheese.
Scott: We'll see therefore.
Rym: It is a wine and cheese party.
Scott: We'll see.
Rym: see you see that's what I did there.
Rym: Cuz I'm so full of myself.
Rym: So I call it a wine and cheese party and everyone thinks oh It's a wine and cheese party when really it's just us sitting around drinking wine and eating cheese.
Scott: I see what you did there.
Rym: See that's very relevant when we talk about what we're gonna talk about for the second half of the show.
Scott: Oh great This episode is such a throwaway.
Rym: Whatever next week is gonna be even worse.
Scott: Yeah, don't listen next week.
Rym: It's gonna be don't listen until after Otakon in fact.
Scott: Yeah, then it's gonna be really really good.
Rym: Yes All right, well actually have some news, and this is a non tech non geek news Definitely a nerd news because it is a affliction that really seems to affect nerds in great propensity.
Rym: Well it afflicts nerds who have a propensity for eating with a propensity of problems and a propensity of not moving.
Rym: Yeah, something like that people who lead sedentary lifestyles.
Rym: the problem is that?
Rym: Hospitals do not have the facilities to deal with really really fat people at all.
Rym: Now the article is funny because it even goes on that Really obese people not only do x-rays not penetrate their body whoa But whoa They can't.
Rym: even if they do get x-rays and MRIs to work They usually can't see otherwise commonly treatable problems because there's so much fat in the way.
Rym: You just can't.
Scott: you know.
Scott: it's wondered like what if a fat guy needs.
Scott: I don't know His appendix taken out.
Scott: How do you get to the appendix?
Scott: He's like cut him wide freaking open and dig through all this blob.
Rym: You know what you do whenever you have to operate on someone like that your liposuction him as part of whatever you do it.
Rym: I guess I don't know.
Scott: I don't know either.
Scott: all I know is the smart doctors.
Scott: yesterday What did they say?
Rym: you know what?
Rym: let me put it this way.
Rym: This is a massive Massive hospital, this is a extremely well-known research hospital too and all the hospitals.
Rym: I work at are huge.
Rym: I mean, they're New York City.
Rym: They treat lots of people.
Rym: They don't even really have the facilities to deal with these kinds of people.
Rym: they probably would send them to the Bronx Zoo.
Scott: Were any of the doctors fat?
Rym: no there is.
Rym: not a single doctor I've spoken to was obese.
Rym: some of them were overweight But that's because they were old.
Rym: I mean, there's a big difference between overweight and obese and morbidly obese.
Rym: This is not even talking about obese people.
Rym: This is the morbidly obese as in more than you know.
Scott: I don't know 400 pounds as in at least the Bronx Zoo is right there.
Rym: Yeah Now you think I'm kidding.
Rym: they really do send people to the zoo because the zoo's have to do doctoring on things like Elephants and walruses, so they're right not so lots horses Ryan ocelot say Lol rofl rofl lol.
Scott: exactly That's right, that's a lot that money.
Rym: No.
Rym: It's funny.
Rym: in regards to the second half of the show oh You know what else they have at the zoo, what do they have at the zoo?
Rym: monkeys Okay, okay enough inside jokes enough enough whatnot.
Rym: But they in all serious silly Thursday will send patients who are really fat to the zoo.
Rym: and At one point someone this wasn't here this was somewhere else in the country someone sued for the humiliation of being sent to the zoo And I don't remember the outcome of the lawsuit.
Scott: if I was the other lawyer I would say you can't sue someone else if you humiliate yourself, and then I would sit down.
Scott: I'd be like I rest.
Rym: Yeah, so you got a news.
Rym: we I think we got.
Scott: I got a shit news.
Rym: I think we got to get past the front bit before we just lose it.
Scott: so tomorrow Friday Which is probably today because a lot of people listen to this on Friday It seems the day after.
Rym: yeah, it seems that most people listen to an episode the day after.
Rym: but I'll say this This is kind of weird kind of an off off-topic bit.
Rym: it seems that almost every single episode We have is downloaded a couple times every single day.
Rym: Yeah, like every episode.
Scott: Yeah, anyway, okay?
Scott: Tomorrow Friday July 28th is sis admin day.
Rym: now I would have been a lot more excited about this if I was still a sis admin because I'll bet the people I worked with Nominated me at least as a joke because I wasn't.
Rym: I was good, but I was also an asshole.
Scott: Yeah, I'm just generally against all these kind of holidays.
Rym: Oh you mean like Secretary's Day or bosses day or Valentine's Day or Christmas?
Scott: Yeah, it seems like they just keep making up holidays of day Which isn't a joke to sell cards and shit.
Scott: and while sis admin day seems to be all dirty and cool It seems like it's just wait a minute.
Rym: wait a minute now if you're against these sorts of holidays.
Rym: What of the International Day of Slayer?
Rym: what of talk like a pirate day?
Rym: what I was.
Rym: what if no pants day?
Scott: those Holidays were not invented by card companies true, but or do they sell cards for those?
Rym: well wait a minute.
Rym: Do people sell cards for sis admin day if anything?
Scott: I think they might.
Rym: I don't know cuz I can't see they might be getting ready to.
Rym: I Don't know cuz.
Rym: I think there's a big market for talk like a pirate day memorabilia.
Scott: Well you buy it from that talk like a pirate day official website.
Rym: No no it's got to be bootleg you know.
Scott: So if anyone can find a sis admin day or happy sis admin day card I don't know even if it's just a flash thing on a website.
Scott: You know those email cards.
Scott: I'd like to see that now.
Rym: at IBM We had an award that we would pass around and it's not too related, but it's related enough, and it's a funny story now.
Rym: We I mean we were all admins of a whole bunch of really important servers and We were also really not given enough money to deal with everything.
Rym: and because we played so fast and loose we often would break things or screw things up and Morale was really low in IBM for a lot of reasons.
Rym: so our boss is part of this bosses initiative where this was handed down From way above to her and she handed off to us.
Rym: We had to do this kind of team building thing where we'd make some sort of department award and whenever someone did something on You were supposed to give it to them and to be this rotating thing.
Rym: so she left and we sat around and we decided we were gonna make an award all right and Someone welded a bunch of old token ring cards together And it was the dumb shit award and you gave it to someone who fucked up And it was and it would sit there until someone did something worse than whatever you just did And it lasted a few months until she figured out what we were using it for.
Rym: she made us get rid of it.
Rym: I got it once because I wasn't paying attention, and I plugged a 220 line into a 100 10 volt power supply.
Rym: It wasn't even my server.
Rym: I was installing someone else's server, and I plug it in and it goes BAM And it's like sparks hit me and it knocked me back.
Rym: and then smoke came out And I'm sitting there and the guy says you okay, and I said I'm fine And I stood up and I said you got another power supply.
Rym: Why?
Rym: The other guy who got it after me He actually was in the data center, and he was working on a completely useless server that no one cared about While he was working on it.
Rym: He bumped into the power cable for an extremely critical server, and he unplugged it.
Rym: He didn't unplug it enough to unplug like it didn't look like it was unplugged And it was still on.
Rym: like you know I get a computer that screwed up The lights still on, but it's not doing anything anymore.
Rym: Oh, yeah, oh So suddenly all the calls start coming in about.
Rym: you know something's wrong.
Rym: something's wrong.
Rym: And here's all the phones going off, and he's thinking man something's going wrong somewhere.
Rym: Luckily, I'm working on a shit server.
Rym: Someone walks back.
Rym: He's like hey.
Rym: Did you just do anything back here?
Rym: He's like no You're the only one back here by the time he got to his office the award was just sitting there on his chair.
Rym: All right, you know I get like 10 more of those stories.
Rym: I'll save him for another day.
Rym: That award was beautiful, and I can't believe they made us get rid of it.
Scott: if I ever started company I'll know to have one of those.
Rym: When it comes to movie reviews what you want is intelligent Grown-up conversation.
Rym: if we hear any will let you know.
Scott: hey Kostner your Mac belongs to me.
Rym: Movies you should see from simply syndicated find us at www.simplysyndicated.com/movies-you-should-see.
Rym: Anyway things of the day.
Rym: Oh, baby.
Rym: All right you want to go first, okay?
Scott: You know what I like a lot.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: biting in hockey.
Scott: Oh How did you guess?
Scott: did someone tell you what the thing of the day he used to be?
Rym: Maybe the fact that we watched the beginning of it just a little while ago?
Rym: Yeah I really wanted.
Rym: I want to say stuff about this But it's your thing of the day because you call dibs on it, so you get to describe call dibs on this Absolutely amazing thing of the day.
Rym: yes This is probably going to go down in history is one of our best things of the day.
Scott: probably now people have seen You know fights in hockey at least I hope you've seen fights in hockey.
Rym: if you haven't we're gonna do hockey fight week Sometime.
Scott: yes well Here is a fight between the Ottawa Senators and the Philadelphia Flyers two teams known for their I don't know ruffian age.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: I mean roughhousing.
Rym: They are teams that rely especially the Flyers.
Scott: the Flyers beat the shit out of me.
Rym: They relied.
Rym: have.
Rym: let's see the thing is in every other sport you call these people thugs or assholes.
Rym: in hockey.
Rym: They're called enforcers.
Rym: I Just want to note that.
Rym: notice how Scott didn't say to flaky players.
Rym: He said to hockey team.
Scott: Oh, yes, yes, yes.
Scott: So what happens in this video is?
Scott: There's a you know slight.
Scott: How do we say?
Scott: I was guffal a disagreement a scuffle between two players Yeah, and they get into a nice good old hockey fight with some haymakers and whoa craziness, and then you know some other players start fighting And eventually everyone on the Isis fight Even the goalies.
Rym: now I gotta say that is fucked up because I've never seen a goalie Do anything to another goalie or involved in a fight ever.
Scott: I've seen a goalie hit a guy a couple times But I have never seen Two goalies fighting.
Scott: now the thing is no one else is gonna fight with a goalie except the other team's goalie.
Scott: because well He's got a zillion pads, and you've got much less pads, and he's gonna kick the shit out of you.
Rym: also, I think there's the thing that you don't want to be the guy who hurt a goalie.
Scott: and also if you get into a Fight with the goalie you might not get.
Scott: just get a fighting penalty you might get a goalie interference penalty yep And all sorts of trouble.
Scott: yeah It's not good to fight with a goalie mainly because you don't want to die.
Scott: But I mean that two goalies fight each other.
Scott: holy shit.
Rym: I mean the.
Rym: until I saw this video the biggest hockey fight I'd ever seen was in an odd add a minor league game Between the some team in Michigan and some other team from somewhere useless new teams and it was the Detroit Falcons.
Rym: that was the name of the team and I don't know who they were playing.
Rym: but after they get the game ended and There was some fighting going on to the whole game and suddenly both teams just rush each other And there's a brawl and even some of the audience got involved.
Rym: Yeah But despite that the only people on the ice not fighting Were the two goalies who were on the other side of the ice by themselves standing next to each other laughing their asses off.
Scott: That's what goalies do now in this video though.
Scott: I don't know what caused this fight.
Scott: It might have been you know some name-calling going on before the fight.
Scott: there might have been some you know your mom jokes going around But yeah, there was a big hockey fight.
Scott: So eventually the refs clear up the fight many minutes later many minutes later, and they start playing hockey again.
Scott: Now of course all the fighting players were into bucks.
Scott: They put them in the box for two minutes.
Rym: That's what they do for four minutes.
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: yeah, maybe ten God knows.
Scott: um.
Rym: so After the hockey game starts again Two guys immediately start fighting like literally the guy drops the puck one guy jumps the other guy, and they start fighting.
Scott: So apparently you know these guys must have been you know in the the benches You know yelling curses at each other while the fights were going on.
Scott: They they get their chance to come out on the ice and they start fighting And everyone else on the ice starts fighting.
Rym: it ends up being like three on three hockey And there's no one on either band.
Scott: so after a whole you know they start the game fighting they stop the game They start the game fighting, okay?
Scott: They start the game again.
Scott: There's like three players left on each team on the ice and the goalies and The benches are pretty much empty.
Scott: There's like one player and the coach at each bench.
Rym: now the crowd is just a sea of standing people screaming as loud as they Can and the three-on-three hockey.
Scott: they drop the puck and they start fighting?
Scott: I Think.
Scott: I think what the story was is that the game was basically almost over so they didn't have anything to lose by fighting.
Scott: So they all just let loose with everything they had.
Scott: If you see one hockey fight ever see this one.
Scott: if you see two hockey fights All right, and right this one and all right all right all right all right.
Rym: well I'll make it a thing of the day during hockey fight week.
Scott: I think we might have made it a thing of day in the past.
Rym: I'll make it a thing of the day again if I have to.
Scott: all right all right and right and right and right and right Right right all right all right.
Rym: I got a thing of the day.
Rym: Okay Now this is a very serious video.
Rym: No Actually, I did kind of is it's a video that we found kind of randomly, and then we found a better video of it.
Rym: I'm linking to that one of James Randi of the famed James Randi educational foundation totally debunking Uri Geller the famous guy who pretended to bend spoons and pretended he had psychic powers.
Rym: and It shows when this guy was on the Johnny Carson show and Johnny Johnny Hated these people as much as James Randi as much as Houdini as much as Penn and Teller as much as me as much as Scott.
Rym: He absolutely hated them and Uri Geller was gonna be on his show.
Rym: so he calls up James Randi because you know he's a magician And James Randi's a magician.
Rym: And he said how can I get this guy?
Rym: and James gave him a bunch of advice.
Rym: and then the video shows Uri Geller Completely failing to do all of his so-called magic bullshit on the show and getting really angry about it.
Rym: Yeah, and also as a nice bonus James Randi shows you exactly how you and your home can do all of his tricks.
Scott: Yeah, what it really comes down to is there are people in this world who are magicians And they do magic tricks, and they say watch me do magic tricks whoo You know.
Scott: and they hey pull rabbits out of hats and you know that they did it with like a rabbit up the sleeve.
Scott: or But you know they.
Scott: they don't tell you what it was just so they can amaze you and entertain you.
Scott: There are other people who do the exact same thing Except they tell you that it's actually magic, and if you're stupid you believe them.
Scott: I mean what if I was David Copperfield and instead of saying I'm about to do a trick and then I fly around I said I can freakin fly join my wacky religion.
Scott: Why - Twa.
Rym: And those people are bad I mean just if you've never we talked about James Randi a lot you might notice that we even have a category on the website Called Randi r-a-n-d-i and that category will show up whenever we talk about something that is bullshit.
Rym: Yes bulls hit bulls hit.
Rym: And also as an aside to that for anyone who lives near us you know New York City.
Rym: There's a good chance that on Halloween Penn Gillette and teller and Michael Godot are going to be in the city for a spectacular monkey Tuesday to do.
Rym: Now I can guarantee Absolutely guarantee that if that happens GeekNights will be there.
Rym: Absolute guarantee and anyone who lives anywhere near New York City should also be there.
Rym: Anyway now it's time for our very first hate mail, holy crap We I remember I read it and I the first thing I thought was there's no way this is real.
Rym: The first thing he does is accuse us of being gay.
Scott: So we got a sort of a hate mail, but later he calls it an irritation mail.
Scott: But that's not the point.
Scott: The point is is that we're gonna turn almost the whole episode into this email Because there are a lot of tangents we can take from it and it's entertaining.
Scott: and I think we said at some point The first time we get a hate mail will be all crazy about it.
Scott: So here you and we have nothing better to do.
Rym: Yeah, not nothing at all.
Scott: And even if you don't like this episode It's incredibly entertaining for us to make this episode.
Rym: Yes As you might be able to tell them the fact that we can barely keep a straight face.
Scott: So here's two middle fingers to you if you think this episode sucks.
Rym: Yeah, it's all you geek back haters.
Rym: Here's a whole geek back episode.
Scott: All right, so I'm gonna read the original email because it's not that long.
Scott: I'll try to read it quickly.
Rym: Well, we'll have to read the second one because that's well, okay.
Scott: So first he sent us an email and a few things about the email were broken, but I replied and Then he sent us the same email again with all that was corrected.
Scott: So obviously he clicked the send button a little too soon.
Rym: now I found it interesting that he changed some of the wording between the two drafts.
Scott: Yeah I'll give him the benefit of the doubt and read the second one.
Scott: All right, the guy's name is is store.
Scott: I guess I store is to our.
Scott: I guess he's not gonna give us a real name.
Rym: Oh That was barely relevant, okay.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Here's the email.
Scott: the subject of the email is How not to suck it.
Scott: podcast it.
Rym: how to not suck it podcast Which is interesting because I saw incoming links to in our forum to a thread we had called just that Yeah that had one post in it.
Rym: It's an ass old thread that no one read or did it.
Scott: I don't think has anything to do with this.
Rym: I don't know because it came from Gmail and Yahoo and a bunch of other.
Scott: Yeah, whatever anyway, so anyway The Guy says okay.
Rym: Yeah, okay.
Scott: Okay, you guys don't suck You're two idiots.
Scott: arguing shtick can be fairly entertaining.
Scott: In fact, that's sort of how I described the podcast to others.
Rym: This is great right here.
Scott: It's called GeekNights.
Scott: It's two gay guys.
Scott: Not that there's anything wrong with that.
Scott: I think that they're together, but I'm not sure who are exceedingly average at best, but think they're bright Arguing about games and tech.
Scott: It's kind of funny.
Scott: Okay now First thing we're not gay.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know how else I can refute that.
Scott: We're not Yeah, we put the penises in the vagina.
Scott: Well not in the butts.
Scott: The butts say do not enter on them.
Rym: Yeah, I mean in all seriousness I've been dating a wonderful girl for like three years now.
Rym: and Scott while he is not currently dating anyone No I don't have anything to follow that with yeah.
Scott: Oh and cuz some people seem confused especially his store.
Rym: I am Scott I am Rym and this is GeekNights.
Scott: Don't be confused.
Rym: I think we're gonna add a. I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, especially since we seem to be getting a lot of new listeners at somewhat frightening rates.
Scott: Yep, okay.
Scott: And also how come?
Scott: whenever anyone says, you know, oh he's gay They always have to say not there's anything wrong with that like by default.
Scott: You're somehow you know a homophobe Anti-gay person and you have to say you're not.
Rym: yeah I mean to me by default Being gay is cool And if it only if someone goes out of their way to express to me that they are somehow against gayness What I even consider that they would be.
Rym: that way
Scott: Yeah like if I say You know you can tell unless there's something wrong with your brain by the way Someone says something or the way someone word something whether you're saying, you know now rims gay prim is so gay Rims a fucking faggot, you know You can tell if someone is against gay people or is just using the word gay as in yeah, they're gay.
Scott: That's what they are now.
Rym: The funny thing is he won't let this go and in the follow-up emails Which I'll touch on he won't.
Rym: he won't accept the fact that we're not gay.
Scott: Anyway, let's continue with his email.
Scott: All right, of course There are a few things you might want to address and here's where it sort of becomes a hate mail.
Scott: number one Learn to pronounce preface.
Scott: It's starting to get irritating.
Scott: That's Rym.
Rym: I pronounced shit wrong all the time.
Rym: What do you want from me?
Scott: There you go.
Scott: You admitted it.
Scott: We're good.
Rym: Yeah, of course you do too captain.
Rym: Titan.
Scott: number two Stop pronouncing pun and teh out loud.
Scott: No boond awesome Three you're not hardcore board gamers.
Scott: Give it up.
Rym: All right before you read the A B and C of this point I just want to note that anyone who ever says that someone else is not hardcore That's like the whiny kid who likes Sony who says you Nintendo gamers aren't hard car enough.
Rym: I mean seriously.
Scott: Hey You get rules wrong on a regular basis which He never really answered.
Rym: that because we tried to go.
Scott: we're gonna I'm gonna.
Scott: I did reply to this email to add more meat And I'm gonna go to that eventually.
Rym: Well, you said you wanted me to read that part.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Okay, you want to read it?
Rym: You can okay.
Scott: Yeah, but be your game analysis is naive at best and sometimes degenerates to pure new business.
Rym: Yeah, I'm really curious about that.
Scott: one see your strategies are laughable.
Scott: I imagine that's mostly a result of a and B But you get owned by anyone with even the slightest modicum of intelligence.
Rym: Well, I guess the only people who actually beat us on any sort of regular basis are each other and by each other I mean the whole front row crew.
Scott: Yeah for you are not skilled arguers, especially the slow talking one.
Rym: I assume he means you because I tend to get excited.
Scott: Yeah You do realize that repeating the same things over and over isn't a valid argument.
Scott: what you to engage in is rhetoric not argument.
Rym: now One I do often engage in rhetoric because it's very useful, but I don't think we have ever actually had an argument on GeekNights.
Rym: It's all been in the forum.
Scott: Yeah, not a real one.
Rym: Anyway, yeah, it's hard.
Rym: You can't really have an argument unless you have you know multiple sides and you actually argue it out and debate it out Which we usually don't do between each other.
Scott: at first you have to say what you know What are you arguing about and then you got to prepare?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Okay five the one with the higher pitch voice That's me.
Scott: I assume not the one that sounds like he's stoned constantly.
Rym: I assume that's you.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: You might want to cut back on the self back padding.
Rym: What can I say?
Rym: GeekNights is freaking awesome.
Rym: I am an ubermensch.
Rym: Scott is a god among men.
Rym: the front row crew are our veritable Adonis sigh.
Scott: It was amusing at first but over time your inflated sense of self-worth is starting to get irritating.
Scott: I suppose that the company you keep has resulted in this false conception of your ability Now that right there the land of the blind the one-eyed man and all that right there is a low blow.
Rym: It's one thing to call a man egotistical which I am.
Scott: you are.
Scott: indeed I'm not and it's it's good to see that someone else agrees points it out and doesn't like it because sometimes I feel like I'm Granted Scott you're kind of full of yourself - not as much as me not even not even close.
Scott: No, see the thing is is I my full of selfness is truth?
Scott: It's like.
Rym: The only reason I'm laughing is because all the people we know are gonna yell at both of us about that.
Scott: whatever It's I say I am as awesome as I actually am.
Scott: Rym says that he is more awesome than he actually is.
Rym: the worst thing is it's because I think my propensity to exaggerate in order to tell good stories that Everything I do is awesome to me and everything my friends do is awesome to me because I'm not even just full of myself.
Rym: I'm full of my friends.
Rym: like I'll talk GeekNights up crazily or if someone of my friends does a podcast or something I'll be like, it's awesome.
Scott: It's the best thing I've ever heard like five minutes ago where you said we're getting listeners.
Scott: You know some insane rate.
Rym: Actually, we are because we we've.
Rym: I can show you the graph that actually it's becoming a square as opposed to a linear.
Scott: Yeah, but the wrong number.
Scott: linear Numbers are still not increasing exponentially yet.
Scott: No, but the trend is and I trend is yeah I've extrapolated a line using so we aren't actually acquiring listeners and it's not in great yet.
Scott: Yeah, we are just acquiring listeners at a normal rate.
Rym: I'm fine.
Rym: We're To speak the perfect truth.
Rym: We are gaining listeners at an increasingly increasing rate.
Scott: We are indeed.
Rym: Anyway, the point I want to get to is not that you know, it calls me egotistical.
Rym: I'm fine with that.
Rym: It's kind of a low blow though that He basically seems to say that the reason I am is because my friends are all stupid such as our friends.
Rym: Thing is the people who are actually stupid aren't really our friends.
Rym: No, honestly in all seriousness I would say that the members of the front row crew all of us are some of the smartest and most awesome people I know.
Rym: Yeah, and
Scott: I mean, you know considering that all the stupid people who were friends at one point either left on their own or We kicked their asses away Yeah
Rym: I mean quite literally all of our friends who weren't that bright or had issues Eventually started hating the rest of us and stopped talking to us
Scott: because of said arrogance and self back patting Yeah, and they were unable to pat their own backs because they weren't as smart as we were.
Rym: We had people back at RIT who you know We're still in the anime club after we left actually wishing that me and more importantly wishing that Scott were still there Because when a fanboy was being stupid and annoying Scott would say wow You're stupid and annoying and make him go away and no one else would do that.
Scott: Yep All right, so I replied to this saying is this a hate mail because we asked for it?
Scott: or do you really mean it?
Scott: Please reply honestly, but I personally hope you really mean.
Rym: Oh, you didn't read the end of his email.
Rym: Oh, I want to read.
Rym: I want to read okay all in all though.
Rym: You guys are fairly entertaining.
Rym: Oh He left a comma.
Rym: Yeah Good job.
Rym: between the inflated sense of self-worth these pseudo intellectual arguments and the Bolloxing with an X up of board game rules You definitely make it easy to waste an hour or so a week at work.
Rym: dot dot dot.
Rym: So don't change too much if you stop being two morons arguing.
Rym: you'll likely lose listeners.
Rym: signed uppercase I or lowercase L?
Scott: Yeah, I think it's I cuz it's store.
Rym: Yeah, but you never know.
Scott: He might be all L Okay, so I asked him if it was hate mail or not and he says I wouldn't qualify it as hate mail.
Scott: It's more like irritation mail.
Scott: I honestly do enjoy the show usually and would probably like you guys in person or at least get along with you.
Scott: I did mean everything I said though.
Rym: Now.
Rym: Here's where it gets funny.
Rym: He goes on to say that he anime world order is far worse than us Even if that even if they're things that irritate me, I recognize it could be much worse.
Scott: I listen to that anime world order number 26 to hear the review.
Scott: that was supposed to be funny dot dot dot and it was.
Scott: But the rest of the show was painful to listen to.
Rym: now really anime world order is Bar from painful.
Rym: listen to those guys are more informed about anime than we are by leaps.
Scott: And in fact, yeah try if you think anime world order is painful to listen to.
Rym: Try listening to all right.
Rym: I'm gonna start bashing some people straight out.
Rym: All right, try listening to Metroid nation.
Rym: Oh, yeah I'm sorry, dude, but you need some help.
Rym: Let's see what other podcasts are particularly bad the French pod class and maybe it got better but the first ten are pretty piss-poor.
Scott: I'm trying to think of a really bad cuz he I just deleted all of them So I can't.
Scott: it's hard to think of the really bad ones.
Rym: Oh taco generation is definitely not really really bad But I can't listen to it.
Rym: Yeah, it'd probably better if they fix their audio a little.
Scott: yeah There's some podcasts that are bad because the person's voice is just annoying or the auto quality is You know horrendous and painful.
Scott: and there's some.
Scott: we're just what they say you don't want to listen to.
Rym: But I don't know how this guy could find listening to anime world order painful Especially with all of the claims he made against us because those guys pretty much just tell you exactly like it is and they're right.
Rym: Well usually except about opinion issues and then in which case they're all a hundred percent wrong always All right, so I replied to you know, his first email giving a point-by-point.
Scott: I said we're not gay, you know, blah blah blah.
Scott: now when he got to the board games, actually I think we didn't talk about this yet is you know, I said hey, you know There are some times we got the rules of board games wrong, you know, I think we played Amun Ray incorrectly for a long time
Rym: Yep, and it's usually because we would just not read the rule book and just go at it Yep,
Scott: and I was like if we actually said something wrong, please tell us what game it is so we can play it correctly.
Rym: No, we're not gonna read the rest of all this.
Scott: No.
Rym: No, there's a lot of it.
Scott: I'm just summarizing this board game part.
Scott: and then I said also when we talk about board games or any game or any anime we summarize things and we generalize and We try to give a real general paraphrased summary Explanation of things that anyone can understand without going into all these details that are useless.
Rym: So like we try to do the spirit of the game as opposed to the goods of the game, right?
Scott: So Sometimes in our oversimplification of concepts or games or rules, you know We say things that you know aren't a hundred percent correct because they're generalized Like he really went on about how he said we claimed to talk.
Rym: one He said we got a rule wrong in Carcassonne, which we totally don't know we don't.
Rym: and two he really goes on about how we were wrong about the river and he goes on and on about how the river isn't the Way we said and our strategies are crap and we don't understand the game.
Rym: and we didn't talk about the river So long at all and we really just got one sentence about the river or two.
Rym: I mean if you wanted and in all series, you can do an episode about the river.
Rym: We could do an entire show about the river.
Rym: We and I think way in the future when we start running out of stuff to do or we start having slow times I think we'll actually do episodes of you know, like the tactical analysis of a game.
Rym: You'll do how to win at X Yep, and as to our strategies being new bish or our uber strategies I don't think we've ever explained one of our detailed strategies on the show in any depth at all.
Scott: Yeah I don't think at any point ever we have said this is our uber strategy and talked about a strategy in detail any strategies we've given on the show up until now or General strategies like here's how not to get completely hosed.
Scott: on your first try You'll want to kind of try to do this.
Scott: You want to kind of try to make these kind of decisions?
Scott: Yep, here's something you want to pay attention to to help you make your decision.
Scott: This is the way to win at this game.
Scott: do X Y & Z?
Rym: in this order and in terms of a lot of board Games, we really actually have analyzed them in a great deal like settlers of Catan.
Rym: I don't think anyone who knows a lot about board games would disagree that the game is really Fundamentally kind of broken when four people who know what they're doing play it.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: as are many many games I mean, there are basically only three strategies.
Rym: There's the brick and wood.
Rym: There's the Cities and then there's the tripods and various combinations thereof and placement really matters more than anything else.
Rym: I mean with skilled players.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Well other than obviously dice rolls.
Rym: Now I could talk about that for two hours, but I'm not gonna because no one wants to hear that just yet.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Hey, what else do we want to do?
Rym: is I want to get this because I'm gonna read this section because he won't let Go this gay thing.
Rym: Okay, as Scott says we're not gay Rym.
Rym: as a girlfriend of many years I'm always in search of quote female companionship.
Scott: I didn't put quotes around that.
Rym: No, I I said quote to ensure that they know that you said the words female companionship.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Now why if you put quotes around that that really changes the meaning of your sentence now, doesn't it?
Scott: I know it's why I was worried you were gonna put quotes around it.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Now he says quote.
Rym: really my mistake My gaydar must be broken.
Rym: It sure is.
Rym: you realize his girlfriend could just be a beard, right?
Rym: Maybe he's just waiting for the right moment to pounce on you and then he says it again This is because I was emailing the guy.
Scott: so if he says you he's talking to me.
Rym: Yes, not that there's anything wrong with that.
Scott: Okay, so either he's having fantasies about me and Rym together, which is whatever floats your boat.
Rym: I'm fine with that.
Scott: But no Emily isn't a beard.
Scott: She was on the show and I've seen her many times in many years.
Rym: She is quite awesome.
Scott: She is.
Scott: She's a real person and she has boobs in a vagina.
Rym: So that is not quite all I would describe.
Scott: Well, no, I'm just saying that she's not a beard.
Scott: Yeah, and she doesn't have a beard either.
Scott: Yes, she is real.
Scott: yeah and not the country.
Rym: and now the thing is we.
Scott: oh you miss my joke.
Rym: God the front row crew.
Rym: We actually joke about our sexuality a lot all of us.
Rym: I mean we have this running gag of the yaoi couch.
Rym: Oh, you don't know what yaoi is.
Rym: Don't worry about it.
Scott: But at the same time none of us are really perverted.
Rym: not only we're not converted healthily Sexual, I mean, I think Pete was the one who said this and I don't know if he was quoting someone.
Rym: I forget and I'm not gonna get it right at all But he said something to the effect of that's like two Vikings having sex.
Rym: It's so manly.
Rym: It's not gay.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know old and Greek guys, you know back in the days of Greece, you know You were gay, but it wasn't gay to be gay.
Rym: That's an interesting way to put it.
Rym: But I know yeah, except we're actually not gay, right?
Rym: I wouldn't keep talking about this, but he really seems to have a bug up his butt that we're somehow gay.
Scott: I think he wants us to be gay because he's gay.
Rym: See the thing is pouncing.
Rym: Scott would be like having sex with a beanbag full of antlers.
Scott: He's one gangly, dude You know, there's some meat on me in places.
Rym: Yeah in 1.5 places.
Rym: There's meat on you.
Rym: Hey, I just really wanted to make my beanbag antlers joke because I make it a lot and it never gets old with me.
Rym: Okay, I don't even know where I got it from.
Rym: you beanbag full of antlers you All right.
Rym: What else was particularly good in this?
Rym: He really doesn't like the fact that we say we say elite words like fair and I like how Scott was like, by the way You know when we say fear, we're actually saying ph33r.
Rym: Did you notice?
Rym: I Found that hilarious.
Scott: He's like they are part of printed slang.
Scott: No more.
Scott: pun is pronounced own just as fear is pronounced fear.
Scott: Well, no pun is pronounced pun and Owen is pretty.
Rym: There is an alternate pronunciation of pun called pone which seems to come from new world elite.
Scott: It's pun.
Rym: Yes, that is where it originally was spoken.
Rym: Oh and as far as opposed to what he says what next?
Rym: finding a pronunciation for emoticons, I've done that.
Rym: I've done that many a time.
Rym: Yeah, I will make emoticon finger motions when I talk to people colon smiley colon parentheses.
Rym: In fact, I had a thing that was funny for about a day and then got really hyphen
Scott: close paren
Rym: where I'd always make a slash With my finger and then say whatever someone would say after a slash on FARC Which was funny and then it got really dumb and then even I got sick of it.
Scott: Yeah, so I asked him who was the slow one and he says I'm like I said me and he says yep Though the slowness may be relative to your buddy's speech patterns.
Scott: as far as arguments.
Scott: I know one when I hear one.
Rym: Yeah well For anyone who's curious about seeing an argument that we're involved in that's a good one because the World of Warcraft one isn't good yet Because no one's really I keep trying to make it good.
Scott: But because I really hate having this argument I have the World of Warcraft argument so Often and everything that can be said has been said.
Scott: so I'm really trying to mix it up and say new things and use new examples and analogies.
Rym: I'm staying out of it because I take a much more moderate position and Also, no one really addressed any of my questions bully.
Scott: Yeah, it's like no one really Understands the way that I'm talking about the game is like because it's like they can't look at it from the same perspective as me.
Scott: So I can't really communicate the ideas.
Scott: I'm trying to get across the best example.
Rym: I mean we talk in the forums about how we had a big argument where we got people to agree that we were right on A few points which are critical to the argument going on in the forums.
Rym: now We're arguing with Pete and Scott Johnson both of which were in the forums now talking about that Kremlin and the whale shark and both I said both of which I should have said both of whom Mm-hmm.
Rym: But anyway, both of whom also play World of Warcraft.
Rym: But yet they argued with us and conceded these points and a good three-quarters of the argument ended up with us explaining in great detail Game theory and our terminology so that we could actually have the argument.
Scott: Yeah, it's like let's say there's someone on the street who knows nothing about computers But they insist that the internet is made up of tubes.
Scott: exactly It's now.
Scott: if I'm going to argue against them I have to first teach them that you know I have to give them information and make them learn it and understand it.
Scott: and that's very difficult because I'm trying to argue game theory Against people who don't understand game theory.
Scott: it also if I tell them is it you know It's a game of imperfect information blah blah blah blah blah.
Scott: They have no idea what the hell I'm talking about.
Scott: So I have to give all these examples of like shells and balls and stuff.
Rym: And yeah, like when we say when I say something like a game requires no skill I don't mean the game requires no skill.
Rym: in a common use of the word skill I mean the game requires no direct tactic direct meaningful non arbitrary tactical decisions.
Scott: exactly You know.
Scott: because when we argue in person we use words that are so specific.
Scott: And when I write you know any post on any forum online I use words.
Scott: So even more specifically like I say exact words to mean an exact thing.
Scott: and then when people read it they just kind of take the general gist and They lose.
Scott: you read every single word and figure out exactly what I am saying.
Rym: I am saying no more and no less than that now just so because his primary thing is that we're arrogant.
Rym: and well We are.
Rym: but I will note that when we say you know these words We're not saying like oh people just don't understand words.
Rym: It's more that when you're argue about a technical thing or anything that has a wealth of information and research about it There is something called jargon the definition of jargon.
Rym: but jargon is is jargon are words that are very specific to a specific field and have Specific meanings within that field that are commonly unknown to people who are not deep in deeply mirrored in that field.
Scott: for example the word theory as you know the con the colloquial use is very different from the scientific scientific use.
Rym: yeah, so but anyway if you want to see a good example of an argument that actually We used our not our full abilities because it was kind of like beating a dandelion to death But these sports argument in the forums.
Scott: Oh that is a fantastic one.
Rym: That is one where there was really no opposition and all we did we just pulled out.
Scott: It was just a beat down basically beating a dandelion to death.
Scott: yeah Yeah, that that one was fun cuz it.
Scott: It was like it was like a soft toss baseball, and I just didn't ready to go with my metal bet.
Scott: Yeah, but he says he's probably not gonna join the forums.
Scott: This is store guy because he has enough stuff to do But you don't have to join the forums to go read them.
Scott: So if you have spare time go to the forum and read that sports argument And you'll see how we can really get on someone.
Rym: Yeah, also if you don't have time to read the forum.
Rym: you seem to have plenty of time to send us hate mail.
Scott: Yeah, I mean you're applied pretty quickly, so You got time for that shit.
Rym: Yeah, I Don't know we could make fun of this some more.
Rym: you spelled some words wrong.
Rym: Oh Yeah, if you spell the word wrong - it happens.
Scott: No one's perfect.
Rym: No it shouldn't happen mr.. Perry to be all up in your ass.
Scott: Well, I'm not in the forum, so what's he gonna.
Scott: Do to me true.
Rym: We've never actually met him in person.
Rym: so Well you know if watch for all you know he's like seven feet tall.
Rym: he's like 400 pounds.
Rym: Would it be funny if mr.. Perry actually was like someone?
Scott: yeah, I know.
Scott: anyway Is store?
Scott: you know I think is store would have a problem in the forum because you'd have to really carefully write all as opposed To avoid mr.. Perry.
Rym: yeah Who?
Scott: there's someone in the forums now who's really bad and mr.. Beard keeps getting them.
Rym: Yeah, you know what I just we should say we're done with the hate mail our out of the meta bits.
Rym: If you go back and read a post you made and there's a bunch of red marks all over it that means mr.
Rym: Perry had got you.
Rym: look at what those red marks are and try to learn.
Scott: Yeah, when you if you come to our forum before you post something push the preview button read it carefully reread it Make sure you use the spell check thing that we installed there.
Rym: Yeah there versus there versus there it's versus it's lose versus loose.
Rym: good God people I Mean.
Rym: penny arcade has a huge forum and a huge community around it And it's basically a den of iniquity insane.
Scott: Yeah, if you go look and penny arcades form.
Scott: It's basically like fear.
Rym: whoo No crap There's enough of that on the internet.
Rym: so we decided early on that if we were going to have a community around GeekNights We were going to make sure that it is like this ivory tower Oasis in a sea of horridness like a bastion of logic and reason and at least grammar if nothing else grammar.
Scott: Yes, if you're forced to look at your grammar and make sure that it's correct Then you'll also be forced you know to reread what you wrote and possibly rewrite it in a more intelligent fashion.
Scott: Also
Rym: it a lot of people say oh grammar doesn't matter I still understood what you meant and that comes back to the problem Scott has and I have a lot with arguing with people is That yeah, you can get the gist of what someone means if their grammar is bad.
Rym: But if the grammar is bad you lose so much of the very specific Meaning that's there.
Rym: and someone like me who if we're arguing and I'm trying to read the specific meaning you have so I can specifically Counter it your bad grammar means that the point you think you're making is not the point you're actually making.
Rym: in which case I'll say I'll say something about the grammar and then usually people respond with oh You're just a grammar Nazi pet in ivory tower blah blah blah blah blah
Scott: Yeah, and also people who have better grammar and better writing skills tend to have better reading comprehension skills.
Scott: So when they read other people's posts, they can better understand the fineries of their word smithery.
Rym: I like that a lot.
Scott: Yes,
Rym: plus honestly, it's bothering me more and more because every job I've had even other than the doctors who seem to actually actually know grammar Whoa,
Scott: go go go doctors
Rym: most of the people I work with not just like in my company But I'm saying very broadly like in all my years as a technology professional and even when I was at RIT in classes People it's not like they don't.
Rym: they don't even know grammar as far as I can tell I mean I could get to the point where I write a short memo to someone and Because it has proper grammar and spelling and formatting my boss or my boss's boss will say something like wow Good job on that memo.
Scott: and whenever I write any email or any forum post anywhere for any reason I always like double check it in three times.
Scott: Check it to make sure everything is as good as I can in a.
Rym: Quotes from Scott on our show.
Rym: We don't do super in-depth hardcore Analysis.
Scott: Okay, you know, I'm not perfect though.
Scott: I can only check it so many times.
Scott: Oh, yeah speaking of ivory towers This is a non sequitur.
Scott: great.
Scott: We're getting some referral links from ivory tower calm.
Scott: Now if you go to ivory tower calm Let me go type it in here while you're typing it in I'll entertain the crowd with my super inflated ego.
Scott: you get this website that says ivory tower calm.
Scott: Welcome to ivory tower.
Scott: Welcome.
Scott: You must log in to continue blah blah blah blah blah.
Scott: I e6 is the preferred browser.
Scott: blah blah blah blah.
Scott: There is no way to sign up for this site.
Scott: It is like an invite only secret forum site.
Scott: It's a real ivory tower.
Scott: if you go to Ivory tower calm.
Scott: there is a real ivory tower there.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: They've probably got so many life points.
Rym: It doesn't even matter anymore.
Scott: Yeah, you click on what is this and it says to enter this site?
Scott: You must already be a member.
Scott: requests for membership are not accepted.
Rym: now here's the thing.
Rym: secret societies like that are really cool, but if you Advertise the fact that you're a elite secret society.
Scott: Yeah, I would have just put like a fake blog there and I you know Or something like that.
Rym: Hell I would have had a fake like terrible job way.
Scott: You're really secret.
Scott: You know if you're a secret society showing that it exists isn't really a secret society.
Scott: Yeah, there's people who want to go around town saying oh, I'm a member of a secret thing that you can't be in.
Rym: Yeah, because then you're just a Freemason.
Rym: Yeah Nobody wants that.
Scott: No, if you're actually have a secret society That's really secret that no one knows about.
Scott: and you do things in secret that no one knows about.
Scott: they don't even know your society.
Scott: There is a secret to be.
Scott: you know to find out the island.
Scott: you're awesome.
Rym: It's a secret to everybody.
Scott: exactly if it's a secret to everyone.
Scott: It's cool.
Scott: If it's ivory tower comm it's not cool.
Scott: Now all I really want to know is if anyone listening can get into ivory tower comm or knows more about it.
Scott: I just want to know what in ivory tower is linking to us.
Scott: I think it must be on their forum or something.
Rym: Yeah, cuz lately I've been having a lot of free time at work like in downtime when I'm just you know Like between projects.
Rym: I'm waiting for something.
Rym: I'll just look at all the refers we're getting and try to see who cares about GeekNights.
Scott: Yeah, apparently ivory tower comm cares about one thing.
Rym: I gotta say we people search for some weird freaking shit and find our forums.
Rym: Yeah, good God.
Rym: Well, they should also.
Rym: what's really cool is that we show up really high for a lot of Google searches like a Ultraviolet movies.
Rym: we show up real high cool Yeah, and a lot of people come to the forums after searching for that way.
Rym: cool Which gives me faith in mankind that there are people out there who enjoy ultraviolet movies as much as we do.
Scott: All right, you want to just cover some meta bits and then be done with this.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, it's just the end of the week.
Rym: next week is pretty much It's gonna be silly and the week after that is going to be sillier.
Scott: Yeah, I Fixed the website a little bit front row crew comm.
Scott: on the right side The the link you can click on to subscribe to GeekNights and iTunes is fixed The down at the bottom right.
Scott: not, you know up near the top but down at the bottom bottom, right?
Scott: There is a link to frapper which is a map of pushpins and there should be a pushpin for all of our listeners.
Scott: But there is not.
Scott: so if you are listening and you do not add a pushpin You should go to that rapper link and add a pushpin
Rym: and while you're at it I like I'm not gonna ask you to vote for us now those stupid vote for podcast Websites because I think that's really kind of dumb and That sort of thing has been going around since the early days of the internet and they were never useful ever
Scott: Mm-hmm,
Rym: but if you listen to us on iTunes and it's not a bother You should totally actually rate GeekNights because that's one of the few things iTunes uses to figure out what people are listening to.
Scott: Yeah I mean, I hate asking people to do any of those voting Rating reviewing things on any directory.
Rym: So I didn't realize you could rate things in iTunes until like three days ago.
Scott: Yeah, like the podcast alley and all that stupid shit You know because if it's people telling their listeners to do it Then it kind of games the system in that it should be people doing it of their own volition because the shows are so good.
Rym: But at the same time people who just listen to shows and like a show don't even bother with that crap.
Scott: I know it's it's it's a catch-22.
Scott: It's a really bad system and that's why I don't tell anyone to do it.
Scott: In fact, I tell you not to do it.
Scott: Don't do it for any podcast.
Scott: don't vote on the stupid podcast alley.
Scott: We need a better system for people to find podcasts they like and is manual voting mechanism where Listeners have to do work so that the podcast they like can become more popular is stupid?
Rym: Yeah, I'd like to see some sort of like delicious of opmls or some sort of tagging people who tag things more often.
Scott: Yeah, that would be cool.
Scott: Check it out ready.
Scott: Everyone has an opml in their podcatcher and You have a little plug-in in your podcatcher that automatically submits your opml to.
Scott: you know, some website every week that website Aggregates all the opmls figures out which podcasts have new, you know, the most new subscriptions the most total subscriptions.
Scott: Which ones are actually getting listened to versus not getting listened to?
Scott: that would be a good system.
Scott: We should set that shit up.
Scott: I just came up with a great idea.
Scott: Holy crap.
Scott: Yeah, no one steal it.
Scott: No one steal that.
Rym: god damn it all of you.
Rym: I have the evidence right here prior actually actually Well, because our good friend Alex who is equally intelligent to both of us He's a cool dude, and he's moving out to where we are.
Rym: That's it.
Scott: Alex.
Scott: You listening That's what we're gonna do when you come here.
Scott: We're making that project happen.
Scott: Yeah, because we have a lot of items and we'll start it with an iTunes plug-in.
Rym: We have a lot of projects that are on the back burner only because this one is the most urgent right now.
Rym: The guys takes up too much of our lives right now to do all these other things like we can barely manage that gaming club.
Scott: Maybe we can piggyback off of audio Scrabble.
Scott: er last FM.
Rym: Yeah, maybe we could.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: We're gonna have to research this a little bit, but we got dibs bitches.
Rym: Yes, if any let it be said it's word of God.
Scott: if anyone steals this idea.
Scott: I'm so coding this right away.
Scott: Okay So yeah.
Scott: Also in the bottom right of front road crew comm is a link that says send me an audio with this pink star.
Rym: We've gotten some already One.
Rym: bear in mind if you send us audio Don't feel bad if you don't use it or we don't use it right away Because we can't use all the audio we get you.
Rym: We've got a lot of audio that we haven't even had a chance to use yet.
Scott: yeah, so the way send me an audio works is you click on it and this little flash program shows up and you click record and you talk into a microphone plugged into your computer and it can record what you say.
Scott: and it's sort of like leaving us a voicemail and Even if you don't like what you say you can like trash it and try to say something again.
Scott: So it's much better than calling us on the phone where you might say something stupid.
Scott: At least with this you can practice and take a few different takes until you say what you want to say correctly And then you click send and it shows up in our email as an mp3 Which is perfect because you can put that right in the show.
Scott: so if you want to send us audio feedback, that is currently the best way.
Scott: and What else?
Scott: Oh, yeah, we have a forum that we've talked about a hundred times The forum.
Rym: it gets about a thousand.
Rym: Well, it gets a thousand unique hits a day.
Scott: now it gets a lot.
Rym: Yeah, it gets like four thousand hits a day minimum.
Scott: It's pretty crazy in that forum there.
Rym: Yeah, it's very happy I make.
Rym: I'm very happy and it makes me very pleased that the forum we created has got a self-sustaining community.
Rym: now to where if Scott and I disappeared from the forum for a while people keep talking to each other.
Rym: It's a wonderful thing.
Rym: And actually one of the more recent people who joined actually said that the reason he joined was because it was a best.
Rym: He said that basically it was one of the few places on the internet where intelligent discussion was happening.
Scott: Yeah, I mean even in places where there is some Intelligent discussion happening.
Scott: There is lots of idiot discussion also happening And there are also some other places on the internet where there is intelligent discussion, but it isn't open to all.
Scott: You know, it's sort of like this locked in.
Rym: Yeah We've never denied anyone access to the forums yet And we've only banned one person ever by popular vote of everyone in the forum after a lengthy court-martial Mm-hmm, and he was really annoying too.
Rym: If you're still listening, we're glad you're listening, but you were really annoying.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, there's some people who are in the forum now who are a little annoying and so I won't mention them because they'll be upset.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: Everyone's gonna think is it me?
Rym: and you know what?
Scott: if you're thinking that yeah Yeah, but they're they're above the line There's a line and if you're below that line, then you're in trouble.
Scott: the lines real low Seriously, but you know It's still high enough to filter out most of the crap because there's so much peep There's so much below that low low low line that filtering that out makes the forum just fantastic.
Rym: I mean how many GNAA posts go to every single article on slash dot?
Scott: I know seriously Yeah, and mr.
Scott: Period really helps with that because you know some people just get pissed off and leave which you know that you can Do that if you want to.
Scott: but some people, you know, they actually try and have better grammar or they cheer on mr Period.
Scott: well, they call like mr.
Scott: Period help me in this thread.
Scott: This guy is terrible.
Rym: Yes, and Maybe if we grow we might have to get other moderators to assist him.
Rym: I don't know what we'll call him.
Scott: Mr Question mark and mr.
Scott: Exclamation point.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: Yeah, I guess we'll just go with that.
Scott: Mr.
Scott: Comma.
Scott: Mr Comma's got to come first.
Rym: Yes, cuz commas are probably the second most poorly used things in the forum right now.
Scott: Yeah, I use them correctly.
Rym: Yes And I got to say I think I'm gonna write a little thing.
Rym: or maybe we'll do a special show on grammar one day when I'll talk about the differences between Spaces commas semicolons and colons.
Rym: they all have uses all of them Even the semicolon.
Rym: if you don't know what a semicolon is and how to use it one don't use it - I don't know What to say.
Rym: cuz you should be using them.
Scott: Yeah, and mr.
Scott: Period informed us today of the the intero bang Which is not a punctuation I knew about before.
Rym: Well, I used it all the time.
Rym: I didn't know there was a word for it.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: mr.
Scott: Period's like, yeah, that's perfectly valid There's an intero bang and that's what that is.
Scott: And I'm like, oh shit.
Scott: Yeah, look at that.
Rym: So, yeah, all right, we've gone on long we're kind of episode is crazy, you know what it's fine it's Thursday I don't know.
Scott: Don't listen to GeekNights until um, I mean there's gonna be some crap episodes.
Rym: No, they're not gonna be crap because I found that the more we'll dislike an episode the more our listeners seem to love it.
Rym: Yeah I mean we had an episode way way back where we just got pissed at each other and argued for bringers.
Rym: the whole thing Not really arguing but rhetoric.
Scott: ing.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Don't expect good GeekNights until August 14 That's all.
Rym: I at least don't expect GeekNights that don't involve us making inside jokes and laughing at ourselves Constantly.
Scott: so until August 14th.
Scott: He nice is gonna be silly.
Rym: Yeah, maybe we'll get a guest spot or something for when we're gone or maybe we'll run some classic bits.
Scott: We're not sure that would be awesome If we just got people to make GeekNights episodes instead of us and then we put them up each day, huh?
Rym: You know what?
Scott: I don't know if we can do that on such short notice, but we do have like two weeks, right?
Rym: Yeah, but everyone we know is going to Otakon.
Scott: Well, no, no Like other podcasters who aren't going every podcaster I know is going to Otakon all the anime geek podcasters.
Scott: But there's some people who aren't going and you know what?
Rym: You know what way if I can get the guy who does the 12 Byzantine Empire's Emperor's podcast to do us a special.
Rym: That guy's awesome.
Scott: I was thinking more a lot along the lines of a listener who isn't going to Otakon who has the ability to podcast And you know could just make a show in the GeekNights format and we'll see how they do.
Rym: Yeah, we might I don't know.
Rym: we'll figure out what we're doing.
Rym: Yeah, if you want to know more about what may or may not be going on if you think yeah If you think you are capable of creating a GeekNights podcast by the week of August The week after next week exactly.
Scott: So either August 7th 8th 9th or 10th.
Scott: if you think you can make GeekNights on one of those days Send us an email.
Rym: Yeah, and we'll work something out possibly.
Scott: Yeah, where you send us an mp3 We upload it and with all that we might just give you the double deuce.
Rym: We're not sure what we'll do.
Scott: Yeah, if you suck, we'll give you the double.
Rym: Yeah All right.
Rym: We're actually done for tonight.
Rym: It was a long episode.
Rym: We're very happy to have gotten our first hate mail.
Rym: The homosexual bit is the only thing that makes me question how much of a hate mail it is.
Rym: Yeah, and the final thing I'd like to say is that if that's all anyone can get on us.
Rym: I'm real happy with how this show is going.
Scott: You know, he even said it was an irritation mail not a hate mail.
Scott: So I'm waiting for there to be a real hate mail.
Scott: Like I hate you guys you guys suck Your show is crap.
Scott: You guys are evil something something.
Rym: I want someone to say I'm evil.
Rym: I've had people tell me you.
Rym: I've had people tell me I'm evil before and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.