Rym: It's Wednesday November 1st.
Rym: I'm Rym and I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We review Boku Patiliro.
Rym: Let's do this and Thus a successful Halloween.
Scott: I neither egged anyone's house nor was my house egged Nor did I toilet paper any houses and my house was not toilet paper.
Rym: Have you ever toilet paper to house?
Scott: I toilet paper to tree.
Rym: Have you ever egged a house?
Rym: No, no, I've never done either.
Rym: okay, my pranks were always much more insidious involving butter butter butter.
Scott: anyway.
Scott: We didn't get any trick-or-treaters.
Scott: That's because we turned the light off.
Scott: But also I didn't see any.
Rym: I saw a bunch.
Rym: You see you weren't out after dark.
Scott: like I was I looked out the window a bunch of time.
Rym: Where were you gonna look from?
Rym: from one side of the house?
Rym: You see the car dealerships from the other side of the house.
Rym: see the car dealerships from the other side of the house.
Rym: You see the forest.
Scott: I was looking at the street.
Scott: if there were trick-or-treaters They would have been walking down the street, um, which street.
Rym: they wouldn't have been walking down the street with no houses on it.
Rym: No the street that we live on the street that we live on all the houses are way away from us and I saw a Bunch of trick-or-treaters over there.
Rym: where the houses are.
Rym: our house is separate from those houses.
Rym: uh-huh, in fact as I was driving in I saw a bunch of trick-or-treaters and I thought Huh?
Rym: I better not just turn the light off.
Rym: What if they walk over here and I turn it off as they're halfway over?
Rym: that'd be the biggest bummer for some little kids ever.
Rym: Sorry kids no Halloween for you.
Rym: mean old guy over there turned his light off.
Rym: You saw you coming.
Rym: Yeah, so I waited and they never came and then I turned the light off because I had stuff to do.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: every year we say we're gonna do an awesome Halloween something and we don't do shit at all.
Rym: What are you talking about?
Rym: we had the lat the beginning of season two of GeekNights and we had an interview with Luke Crane.
Scott: Yeah, we didn't do that on Halloween.
Scott: Yeah, and the year before that we just started a brand new podcast.
Scott: We didn't trick-or-treat or or anything.
Rym: Well, you know what what we were planning on doing.
Rym: the reason we didn't have any other Halloween plans Is that way back.
Rym: Penn Jillette said he was gonna do a New York show So we had pretty much banked on going to that.
Rym: the show turned into Five people get to go and have a little party with him.
Rym: Yeah, you had to call in live and do all this stuff talk about shit talking.
Rym: There was no way.
Rym: Well, the thing is he didn't technically say there was definitely going to be a show.
Rym: He just said there's a 99.9% chance there's gonna be a show.
Scott: Yeah, I noticed how he mentioned it once when he came up with the idea and then he totally didn't mention it ever again.
Rym: Well by once he talked about it for half an episode Yeah, and then he suddenly brought it up again the day before Halloween when it was too late.
Scott: All right, it's anime day and we got some news about anime Expo.
Rym: Yeah, we this.
Rym: this is the only anime news out there.
Rym: We both found it Scott'll use it as his because he said he would and I didn't care.
Scott: It's sort of a little complicated news.
Scott: Anime Expo put out this press release that has been spreading around various places like sort of a mini wildfire Anime Expos that big big convention out in California if you didn't know.
Scott: Anyway, they have announced that they are going to open the anime Expo travel store.
Scott: It says in the press release it will provide discounted airfares hotels and auto rentals throughout the US and abroad for travel hungry fans Planning or booking their trips to conventions or personal vacations.
Scott: So wait, wait, it's a travel store opened up by a convention.
Scott: now when you hear that Like if I told you Otakon opened up a travel store you would think huh?
Scott: They're gonna make one easy place to get hotels and transportation to Otakon.
Scott: Well, this is not a place to get Tickets in hotel rooms for anime Expo.
Scott: It is a completely generic travel store in every sense of the word.
Rym: So a travel agency Pretty much.
Scott: It's just a website that allows you to purchase Tickets rent cars get hotel rooms anywhere Basically anywhere at any time for any reason even if it's not anime related It's just a travel store with an anime Expo logo on it.
Scott: That's all it is It's.
Scott: it's kind of weird now.
Scott: then I realized when I looked at the URL that the URL they tell you to go to is Ax travel store.com.
Scott: Yeah, ax travel store.org.
Scott: when you actually go there the URL suddenly becomes travel dot.
Scott: I a n dot-com.
Scott: Well, what's I?
Scott: a n dot-com?
Scott: the interactive affiliate network a division of hotels?
Scott: Dot-com is a leading provider of affiliate marketing services and the supported travel affiliate market since 96.
Rym: So basically all they've done is contracted out gotten a front end for a thing that is kind of related to them But not really.
Rym: and there's probably some money changing hands.
Scott: Yeah, basically an affiliate network it on the internet is this new semi popular thing among people trying to make money.
Scott: and What they do is you have instead of have let's say new egg wanted to have affiliates, right?
Scott: Well new egg is a store.
Scott: What they would do is if new egg wanted to start an affiliate network They would allow you Rym to open up rims computer shop a brand new website on the internet that sells computer parts.
Scott: Really?
Scott: It's new egg.
Scott: It just says rims computer shop on it And if you do any business you get some of the money that new egg would have made.
Scott: So all Adam expo did is try to make money By becoming basically a front end or yet another front end for the interactive affiliate network.
Scott: And they're passing it off as some sort of special Anime Expo travel store for anime fans.
Scott: and really it's just hey, please buy your make your travel arrangements at this Slightly shady website.
Scott: So the anime expo gets money.
Rym: Well, you see I don't even care about what's actually going on behind the scenes.
Rym: What I would point out is that it's not at all difficult to prepare your travel arrangements for an anime convention.
Rym: You call ahead of time.
Rym: how early you call depends on how big the convention is.
Rym: You get a hotel room and then on the day of the con or the day before the con you drive fly or take a Train to the city.
Rym: you check into your hotel room.
Rym: You might want to pre-register for the con.
Scott: I mean this would at least be a little acceptable if there was special discounts.
Scott: for you know anime Expo but I did a search on their site to get a hotel room for anime Expo the next one and All these hotels are like special deals special deal.
Scott: So I searched for a random date to get a hotel room in Buffalo and everything said special deals special deal.
Scott: Ah, it's no different.
Scott: It's just a travel site with the anime Expo logo on it and they're passing it off To try to milk anime fans for money who don't know any better.
Rym: Oh, well I don't see anyone intelligent using this sort of thing to get to a con because anyone who knows what they're doing or has any level of intelligence just reserves a hotel room at the con rate and then Pre-registers are doesn't pre-register depending on whether or not they want to pre-register.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: I think we should do is we should just open up an affiliate, you know our own affiliate They're a GeekNights travel center and then we should open up like the GeekNights new egg affiliate and the GeekNights everything affiliate and we buy stuff from Ourselves and get a cut.
Scott: so it's like getting a big-ass sale on everything we buy But we'll get our own hotel rooms through the GeekNights travel center.
Rym: Well, anyway speaking of NPR because I didn't have a segue there.
Scott: So I thought it was the craziest thing.
Rym: I thought I just kind of jump in with that.
Rym: All right There wasn't any other anime news because that stupid travel agency thing was pretty much the only thing out there that you guys would care about.
Scott: So there's some licenses.
Rym: Oh, whatever Chevalier.
Rym: Yeah, everyone knew Chevalier was gonna get licensed.
Rym: We all know Nana's gonna get licensed Yeah, but there's been an issue for a long time with XM satellite radio and Sirius to a degree with the fact that Most people who get it don't have a car that can accept an auxiliary input into the radio.
Rym: So they end up using a little FM modulator kind of thing Which is basically a tiny FM transmitter that transmits the audio from their series box onto an empty radio station.
Rym: Then they tune their radio to that.
Scott: Some of them also have a wire that is basically mimics the antenna of a raid.
Scott: You know the radio antenna and plugs into the antenna hole.
Rym: They're identical.
Rym: Yeah, there's no difference between them.
Rym: Really?
Rym: Yeah, the point is that these things Actually tend to be very very powerful to the point that if someone drives near them and they're tuned to this station Which should be empty, but they can set whatever they want.
Rym: They'll hear Howard Stern instead of whatever radio station.
Scott: This is very annoying because I had an I trip.
Scott: I got rid of my I trip.
Scott: I have something much better now.
Scott: that was expensive but worth it.
Scott: But the I trip followed the law and was as powerful It was allowed to legally be and it would get overpowered by XM.
Scott: So if I was using my I trip to listen to my iPod and I drove near someone listen to Howard Stern Howard Stern would overpower my iPod and have to pause the podcast.
Rym: now I note that I've never heard anything other than Howard Stern when this has happened to me in my entire life.
Scott: I think the only reason people one of the only reasons people buy satellite radio is to listen to Howard Stern.
Scott: I don't think there are really any other.
Rym: Very few.
Rym: the news Robin.
Scott: Yeah There are very very few people who have satellite radio who use it for something other.
Scott: Listening to Howard Stern at least around here I mean he's road.
Rym: even when I a few times I rode with a co-worker and For various, you know things I had to do for work and without fail if they had satellite radio They played Howard Stern the whole time.
Rym: We were driving.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: but these things are way more powerful than they're legally allowed to be like blatantly and Obviously and there's been a lot of legal disputes between the radio industry Which is a terrible industry that is on his knees and the satellite radio industry, which is doing very well.
Rym: But I'm not particularly a fan of it for a lot of reasons.
Scott: Yeah I think the reason they want it to be powerful is twofold.
Scott: number one people driving around or randomly hear Howard Stern and maybe Really want to get satellite radio.
Rym: I really doubt that was part of the plan.
Scott: Yeah, but - it's they want satellite radio to sound good.
Scott: They don't want it to like cut in and out and they don't want people who don't have Auxiliary inputs to not be able to get satellite radio.
Scott: So the solution is to have a really powerful You know RF coming out of there so that it sounds great doesn't get interrupted Doesn't make satellite radio look bad and you can use it in any car.
Rym: now I had the problem with my.
Rym: I didn't have an i-trip.
Rym: I bought a nice Belkin transmitter, which is still within the law for my iPod.
Rym: But what I did is I mounted it to my dashboard and then I took the antenna off of my car Thus removing all outside interference and now I get great audio.
Rym: Yeah, I should have done that but I like my little antenna my car see I don't and I don't care because there is nothing On the radio I will ever care to listen to Unless the nukes fall and I need to find out how to avoid the radiation.
Scott: I will use the radio in my car in very few circumstances But there are some.
Scott: for example if the nukes fall if the nukes fall if I'm stuck in a traffic for more than an hour.
Scott: I got to find out what's up.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I found if you're stuck in traffic for more than an hour.
Rym: The traffic news will not help at all.
Rym: All they'll say is that people are stuck in traffic or they'll say there was an accident.
Rym: They'll never give you any useful information.
Scott: or if like I knew there was a big blizzard coming I can find or if I used to use it for a school cancellation.
Scott: if I ever have kids That's what I'll use a radio for.
Scott: cool cancellation.
Rym: We just use the TV or the school's website.
Rym: have a TV or the school's website.
Scott: our school didn't have a website.
Rym: My high school had a website.
Rym: You could go you had it.
Rym: There's a number at the school you could call and they would have a pre-recorded message that either said there is school today.
Rym: There is not school today.
Scott: We are not sure if there's school today and If there's a super super important sporting event.
Rym: Okay, yeah.
Rym: Anyway, the issue here is that regular radio, you know?
Rym: normal old-school broadcast radio has been suing and trying to stop or get Regulations stuck on satellite radio for a long time.
Rym: They claim that it's unfair that people can say fuck on satellite radio.
Rym: But but but they can't say it on their radio and that is hurting their ratings.
Rym: So instead of lobbying to be allowed to say the word fuck.
Rym: They've been instead trying to make it so you can't say fuck on satellite radio and all sorts of crap.
Rym: Now lately the the first challenge that looks like it's actually gonna stick has come from NPR Who has pointed out that all these FM transmitters are in flagrant violation of all sorts of laws.
Scott: They are in flagrant violation of all sorts of laws.
Scott: to that.
Scott: I must agree.
Rym: and furthermore it particularly affects NPR because NPR stations across the United States tend to be in a certain area of frequencies The same frequencies that tend to be used the most often by these FM modulators.
Rym: So NPR tends to be blocked or overshadowed more than anything else.
Scott: They do sort of have a case.
Rym: Well, no, they have a case in the against the FM modulator manufacturers who are usually Subcontractors of the satellite radio companies who have nothing directly to do with them.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: And also while I agree with all the claims that NPR is making I also generally feel that radio as it is is Silly out of date and dead and I wouldn't care at all if they freed up that bandwidth Over the air for better and greater things.
Scott: Oh, I would be so happy if they freed up the bandwidth because really you don't need that many radio stations.
Rym: Well, not only that you could need that many radio stations and I can think of a lot of cool ways to use all that.
Rym: the problem is I Mean we live in I mean we live near New York City and there are radio stations that are clear and listenable on every single frequency and sub frequency.
Rym: I if you tune point by point there's always a station and Almost all of it is playing the same shit music or FM radio.
Scott: They're all playing the same radio.
Rym: It's crazy conspiracy theory Monday.
Scott: crazy conspiracy theory.
Scott: 2 a.m.
Rym: Yeah, and of course you've got the morning wacky wavy inflatable arm flailing tube man.
Rym: Crazy radio guys saying crazy stuff.
Rym: I can't believe he's saying these crazy things on the air, but oh, he can't say fuck.
Scott: Yeah, there are really only two radio stations that I would even consider listening.
Scott: Well, maybe three because a pen radio.
Scott: if I had the chance I might listen to pen radio I would accept the couple times I did.
Rym: there were these ads.
Scott: Yeah, that's the only reason I want the other two stations I would even consider listening to on the radio.
Scott: and this is if there was absolutely necessary your 880, which is pretty much Constant monotone news and nothing else.
Rym: Yeah I'm sure our listeners care about the frequency on a.m That you listen to.
Scott: that is only available in a small portion of the United 80s in CBS radio and in New York is like one of the loudest most powerful stations in the country.
Rym: Yeah, you know what?
Rym: Most of our listeners probably can't get it But I probably can't.
Scott: and 660 which is all the New York sports all the teams.
Rym: I'm fan of which again I'm sure no one cares about.
Scott: Yeah, that's it.
Scott: That's the only thing I consider listening to to radio station.
Rym: when the CD player in my car started going I started listening to NPR a lot and I like NPR.
Rym: I listen to NPR podcast almost as much as I listen to any other podcasts, but regardless we'll see where this goes.
Rym: I kind of hope that radio just loses at every turn and eventually gets dismantled.
Scott: I kind of hope they both lose like I want them to have to make RF modulators that follow the law.
Scott: But at the same time, I don't know if I like that law.
Scott: The RF modulator shouldn't be illegal.
Scott: to have a powerful RF modulator.
Rym: The RF modulator thing is totally moot and doesn't matter at all because modern Car stereos are just gonna come with auxiliary inputs.
Rym: Like they should have ten years ago.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I don't know it all sucks.
Rym: Go podcasting things of the day.
Scott: Oh, man.
Scott: This is a Larry's video.
Rym: I gotta tell you I got a video That wasn't so hilarious.
Scott: No, not hilarious.
Rym: Not at all.
Rym: In fact, it's kind of an offbeat thing of the day here, but it is animated.
Rym: So I'm gonna run with it.
Rym: You remember the Simpsons every year on Halloween would have the treehouse of horror Where they did a kind of a sketch show about Halloween scary kind of things.
Scott: Well, the best Simpsons episode ever is in fact a treehouse of horror episode.
Rym: you want to get sued.
Rym: That's really it's time.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, probably the most quotable episode of the Simpsons ever and I defy anyone to argue Otherwise, no beer no TV.
Scott: make Homer something something feeling fine.
Rym: Anyway Now the Simpsons has been going on for a long time and I stopped watching it pretty much right after I got to college When I just didn't watch TV anymore since I had too much other fun stuff going on in my life didn't even own a TV.
Scott: That's also when I stopped watching TV and the Simpsons.
Scott: I watched the Simpsons right up until the end of high school and then got to college didn't watch it anymore.
Scott: I mean maybe a few times it would be on because Simpsons is a popular thing to be on a random TV At college.
Rym: Oh, yeah, we would watch daykillers a lot.
Scott: I mean if I was you know walking around and the Simpsons were on TV and there was a TV on Somewhere at the college.
Scott: odds are the Simpsons was on it, but I didn't watch TV.
Scott: I didn't have time to sit there and watch a whole episode.
Scott: So that was pretty much the end of it for me.
Rym: Yeah Now the treehouse of horror was almost it was the closest thing to religion my family had.
Rym: we would get a gather round and watch This thing every year as a family event because they were always hilarious.
Scott: Well, you want to hear something scary.
Scott: What?
Scott: what season the Simpsons is it?
Rym: Why?
Rym: this is the 17th treehouse of horror Which when Scott again Scott asked me this question He said I got a thing to show you.
Rym: and he shows me the most recent treehouse of horror that was on Yesterday Halloween, which is my thing of the day.
Rym: I've linked to it.
Rym: You can watch it on the internet for free.
Scott: It's actually some preview copy that wasn't meant, you know for people that someone got in trouble probably for sharing this Definitely or someone stole it which would be okay.
Rym: now He says to me how old do you think this is?
Rym: What sees?
Rym: how old do you think we are?
Rym: What season was this from?
Rym: I was like 17 out of the blue and I got it, right?
Scott: Yeah I think you saw the Roman numerals.
Rym: No, I cuz I was a big Simpsons fan.
Rym: I watched it from the beginning until I went to college.
Scott: Anyway, that's not the important part.
Rym: the important part is a lot of people have said that the Simpsons isn't funny anymore and that it's just really kind of lame and Poorly-written and slow and blend, you know, he's kind of ignored him because I didn't care and I didn't watch it.
Rym: I figured they were just haters.
Rym: We have a lot of theories as to why a show that once was super popular like Family Guy Suddenly people don't like it in its modern form.
Scott: Yeah, I mean we hadn't watched the Simpsons so we couldn't give the real answer.
Scott: But like at one time I thought well Maybe it's just because they seen those old episodes so many times that they've discovered all the jokes.
Scott: You know now when they see a new episode they don't see all the jokes right away.
Scott: But as the episode gets old it sort of gets better over time.
Scott: like wine does well good wine does yeah saw debatably.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, we don't actually know the real answer.
Scott: That was just a hypothesis.
Rym: So now having actually watched a recent episode of the Simpsons.
Rym: I gotta say that show shouldn't still be on the air anymore.
Scott: It's not funny.
Scott: No, why is it still out there?
Scott: I mean there was a God the store.
Rym: the stories don't go anywhere.
Rym: they start and they don't finish.
Rym: the it's just it's not.
Scott: even that was my.
Scott: well There were two problems.
Scott: number one is that it was obvious when they were making a joke But only about 25% of the jokes are funny.
Scott: back in the day the Simpsons glory I'd say slightly more than half of the jokes are funny.
Scott: the second thing the biggest problem was that there were three short segments because it's a treehouse aha and None of the segments had resolutions.
Rym: they just stopped.
Scott: It's like it's like you're watching an episode and they they do a joke they do a joke they do a joke they do a Joke and then after one of the jokes that just randomly it's over and a new one starts
Rym: and the jokes weren't even funny They were just really forced and bleh.
Rym: Even worse the third segment was probably the most ham-fisted social commentary I've ever seen.
Rym: Yeah, aliens invade earth whatever and then it cuts to.
Rym: like three years later The aliens are having a rough time and they say basically Man, it sure was a bad idea to try and occupy these humans.
Rym: Yeah, hearts and minds blah blah blah.
Rym: Yeah, blah blah blah.
Scott: and you know now that I think about it.
Scott: I think someone was trying to be ham-fisted on purpose thinking that would be funny.
Scott: But guess what?
Scott: It wasn't.
Scott: it was lame.
Scott: Really really lame.
Rym: I don't think that they were that smart because all the other jokes were equally ham-fisted.
Scott: Yeah, I Don't know.
Rym: but but then not only is it ham-fisted but the ham fist is holding ham.
Scott: I was gonna have best hold a because it doesn't have fingers.
Scott: cuz at the end it's like Man, bacon tentacles holding on to another hand.
Rym: They're like man.
Rym: This is bad Dot dot dot just like Iraq's gonna be.
Scott: and then it was taking place in the olden days.
Rym: and then the episode ends.
Scott: It was pretty pretty bad like two-fisted ham technique I mean, it's got to the point where the Simpsons comic books are funnier than the Simpsons cartoon.
Scott: I mean, I'm using only one episode to judge by you don't know.
Rym: know that we're perfectly justified in using one.
Rym: We are perfectly justified using one episode because it was the treehouse of horror which has always been the pinnacle of the Simpsons.
Scott: That's exactly right.
Scott: I just you know, I got to point it out.
Rym: All right, so let's get off of this.
Rym: I don't want to sidetrack the show cuz we got a fucking animator review.
Scott: I tell you what, holy shit Do we have an animator review?
Rym: this is our.
Rym: you're my hero.
Scott: Yeah, but first before we review the anime I do have a thing of the day that I almost forgot cuz I was so excited about the anime.
Scott: I gotta keep this short.
Scott: Back in the day people were stupid.
Scott: Do you think people are stupider now?
Scott: You think people are stupider now.
Scott: they used to be.
Scott: you're wrong.
Scott: You're you're absolutely wrong.
Scott: Here's the evidence.
Scott: This is a video of a Canadian daredevil named like Kenny Powers or something like that and he tries to jump a car Over the st.
Scott: Lawrence River, isn't that over a mile?
Scott: It's pretty damn far now.
Scott: Not only that but the car.
Scott: it's like a jet engine powered I think he says a Lincoln Continental.
Scott: I don't remember two little wing-a-lings with two little wing-a-lings on it not wings.
Rym: These aren't wings.
Rym: These are like f1 wing-a-lings.
Rym: They're like a footlong.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Now if you look at the headline of this video It's exactly what I was thinking before I read the headline and it says back before physics existed Daredevil's performed any stunt they wanted without knowing any better.
Rym: now, I think we shouldn't ruin what happens.
Rym: Let's let the the listeners see this stunt and see how it unfolds.
Scott: Yeah, all I can say is that it's obvious that this stunt is physically impossible.
Scott: It is not possible to jump a jet-powered car.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: over a mile, you know what.
Scott: you could Theoretically turn the car into a plane in which case you could fly a mile.
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: all right, you know what?
Scott: What?
Rym: I don't think he thought his clever plan all the way through.
Scott: Oh Didn't any physicist tell this guy what he was doing?
Rym: I don't know if I was a physicist and a guy was like I'm gonna jump my car You know what?
Rym: It's like it's like that Monty Python sketch for the guys Like I'm gonna jump the English Channel.
Rym: And then he goes out and he jumps like two feet and lands in the water, yeah, that's exactly what it is.
Rym: alright, so Nobutaka Nishizawa.
Scott: Great.
Rym: Nobutaka Nishizawa is is known for a number of shows that he's directed over the many years such as slam-dunk and Mazinger Z the movie Dragon Quest a crying Freeman.
Scott: Well, I'm not.
Scott: if I'm not mistaken anime world order refers to him as the niche Nobutaka Nishizawa.
Scott: It might be some other niche.
Scott: We it might be some other niche that they call the niche, but I don't know.
Scott: You'll have to ask them.
Scott: They'll probably listen to this episode and tell us.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: No, I wonder if they've seen this show.
Scott: I do wonder if they've seen this show because this show You see shows today, you know, there's a genre of anime.
Scott: That is the crazy wacky comedy.
Scott: you know the Excel sagas the Elf-princess rain the galaxy Fraulein Una I don't know any other ones freaking chromati All those.
Scott: this is a really really old one Really old.
Rym: so the show we're talking about today is called Patiliro Patiliro or Patariro.
Scott: I think it's kind of weird because in the title everyone seems to call it Patiliro Patiliro P a ta ll i r o. But in the show the character Patariro looks at his watch on his wrist and in the watch It says P a ta r i r o two R's.
Scott: so Patariro I don't know.
Scott: It's that Japanese LR mix-up that happens all the time now.
Rym: the premise of this show Is that there's a little little short son or prince of a dictator of some oppressive country.
Scott: Yeah, some Eastern European nation most likely.
Rym: I generally get the North Korea feeling from it But that's probably just because this is the era I live in.
Rym: yeah, but Imagine that it's like Kim Jong-il as a kid.
Rym: that's what this show is about.
Rym: and he goes off on diplomatic missions as a little prince and Hilarity ensues.
Rym: and by hilarity, I mean horrible pedophilia Homosexuality a lot of homosexuality go.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Now anyone who knows us knows that we are in no way Offended by homosexuality.
Scott: No, they're not this show.
Rym: All right go.
Rym: before we describe the plot I just want you to go to the link that we have put in the show notes You know to the anime news network encyclopedia and it shows a bishonin looking guy about to kiss this girl.
Rym: nope, nope, it shows a bishonin looking guy about to kiss another bishonin looking guy and the main character the little Patilero seems to also like the guy and Or the other guy and that everyone in the show wears mascara and yet no one in the show is female.
Scott: Yeah, let me sum up this plot of the first episode a little bit God.
Scott: The dictator is coming to France I don't remember and he's supposed to be on some diplomatic thing or something.
Scott: The other prince is coming to France not the dictator.
Scott: Yeah dictators is dead.
Rym: He's the little dictator.
Scott: little dictator is coming to France on some diplomatic mission But really he's going to steal a painting because someone lied to him.
Scott: Well, you don't know about the lie yet.
Scott: You find out the lie at the end.
Scott: big deal.
Rym: Yeah, now don't get us wrong.
Rym: The show is hilarious.
Scott: Yeah, it is freaking you just for the craziness.
Scott: The
Rym: opening scene is there's all these diplomats and police like standing out of runway waiting for a plane to land the planes coming in and after about 30 seconds of this Scott says oh the show looks really boring and not at all what I thought and he's about to turn it off.
Rym: and then we point out that The plane veers way to the left and then it cuts to the crowd and they all turn their head to the left.
Rym: and then It the plane veers way to the right and the crowd all the way to the right and then they realize that the planes coming Straight for him and they panic and run away And then it cuts to the inside of the plane and this little dictator is just attacking the pilot for no reason and like tickling Him or something.
Scott: Yeah He was fucked up.
Scott: anyway, he comes to France is gonna steal a painting and With the little dictator.
Scott: He has these onion head guys.
Scott: The onion head guys are the generic henchmen of the little dictator.
Scott: They show up whenever he needs henchmen.
Scott: Yeah other North Korea all looks the same.
Scott: There is this guy, I don't know what the guy's name is I don't remember anyone's.
Rym: it was a ban koran.
Rym: It doesn't matter.
Rym: Yeah, no one's names matter.
Rym: Don't even worry about it.
Scott: Yes, but dude looks like a lady All right.
Rym: It's this tall thin the shonen guy with long black hair who wears eyeliner.
Scott: Oh, no, that's not the guy I'm talking about.
Rym: Oh, you're talking about the other tall Long haired guy who wears eyeliner.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, they all wear eyeliner even a little dick to you.
Scott: Yes, lots of it.
Rym: No, we're not talking like they just look like they have.
Rym: no they they have eyeliner on really poorly done Eyeliner.
Scott: Yeah, like a whore or those girls in that district of Japan
Rym: Now they call well, alright, so the little dictators sitting there at this table and he's got this woman, but it's actually a dude Attending to him and I you get the impression almost that there's some kind of romantic tension there Which the tension is explained later is something else and you wouldn't think it was romantic until you see what follows.
Rym: Yeah for this other guy who's tall with long black hair and eyeliner comes in and he's the what?
Rym: Bishonen killer or something like that.
Scott: Yeah, apparently the guy's nickname is Bishonen killer.
Scott: He's always like a detective or an.
Scott: oh, he's an mi6 agent.
Scott: He's like James Bond, right?
Rym: Yeah, he's gonna be a bodyguard for the little dictator while he's in town to prevent a diplomatic incident.
Rym: Yeah But really he's the Bishonen killer because apparently young boys fall in love with him in a very homosexual way And he's not the Bishonen killer as in.
Rym: I am a Bishonen who kills the ladies.
Rym: He's the Bishonen killer as any causes, but the Bishonen to go crazy?
Rym: Yeah, even though he's a dude and right away the attendant to the little dictator Blushes and gets all meek and totally wants it.
Scott: The attendant is the first person I was trying to talk about.
Scott: so it's a dude who looks like a lady Who's a bit gets all blushed from a dude who looks like a lady.
Rym: This show is the opposite of brother dear brother.
Scott: Yet the dudes who look like a lady cannot get together because this is really annoying.
Scott: little dictator in the way.
Rym: Yes, and the little dictator decides this is where the show goes really off the rocker.
Scott: It makes no sense.
Rym: So he's planning it and the the bodyguard is like, I know you're planning something.
Rym: I'm not stupid.
Rym: I better keep an eye on you.
Rym: The only way to do that is to sleep with you tonight.
Scott: So they share a bed and the little dictators all like, ooh, I love you Bishonen killer and he keeps hitting on him Even the little dictators also a dude who doesn't look like a lady but does wear lots of eyeliner.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, yeah and it goes off from there.
Rym: the plot doesn't really matter.
Scott: Yeah, there's an interesting bit where you see how little dictator actually pulls off the heist of stealing the painting.
Scott: But right after that, it's back to the Bishonen action.
Rym: Yeah, then the episodes over you get the sense that the little dictator and this guy are beginning to fall in love Which is kind of scary.
Rym: It wouldn't be that scary except that the little dictators like five.
Scott: Yeah, it's like this little tiny tiny kid.
Scott: Well, it doesn't even like a pet.
Rym: Oh in the opener, he has this magical cat that we haven't seen really yet.
Scott: Yeah I look at the anime news network encyclopedia entry and there's only like seven characters in this show and considering the little dictators from a country far away and The Bishonen killer is from Britain, I guess You gotta wonder how are they gonna physically get back together.
Rym: since well we saw the episode two thing We're apparently the little dictator comes back on another mission because he wants to see this guy again.
Scott: It's just gonna constantly keep flying over to Britain and France to see this guy.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: That would probably make more sense than anything else in this godforsaken show.
Scott: god damn This show is crazy this show.
Rym: Don't watch it alone.
Rym: Get a big group of people.
Scott: Oh, if you watch this alone, something is wrong with you.
Scott: You know, I know you're gay.
Rym: You watch you watch Pata lira alone, but seriously get a group of friends and watch this show especially if you want to have some fun.
Rym: get all your friends like anime and get that one friend who doesn't like anime and Then corner him and sit down have a grand old party and watch this show because I'd like to see how normal people react to this because at least Haven't seen a lot of anime and being in that whole anime culture a show like this is just hilarious.
Scott: Huh, I see a story on anime news network that was posted in March of 2005 Wow a long time ago and it says Maya Mineo.
Scott: However, you say that Pata lira sayuki is to be made into a TV series scheduled to air June this year on kids Station.
Scott: the manga was previously animated as Boku Pata lira Broadcast on Fuji TV in 82. the one we're talking about is Fuji TV.
Scott: Yes, ooh, so there might be a newer one But that you know can be seen.
Rym: well, all right how many episodes of this anime do you think there are?
Scott: It says right here.
Scott: There are 49 49. oh, I see what happened.
Scott: the original manga right was for is the?
Scott: that's the show We're talking about.
Scott: the original manga was turned into an anime called Boku Pata lira.
Scott: Oh, and it was 49 episodes in 1982 and the genres listed are adventure comedy and romance.
Scott: Pata lira sayuki is the story of you know sayuki and Goku and all that junk Told with the Pata lira characters.
Rym: Oh, yeah, that's where I screwed up because that's listed here as a link not as alternative time.
Scott: That's a 26 episode show from 2005 of the genres adventure fantasy and shonen.
Scott: I don't know how it's not also comedy.
Rym: Well, I guess we'll have to see it.
Rym: Yeah We're reviewing now Boku Pata lira, we'll have to watch Pata lira sayuki before we could pass judgment.
Rym: Yeah, you know what?
Rym: I don't think it matters.
Scott: It really doesn't matter.
Scott: It's all the same crazy bad shit.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if they suddenly make Excel saga sayuki I don't think it's gonna be that much different.
Rym: now We we could just make fun of the things that go on in this show more.
Rym: But just watch it cuz you can't make in front of a show like this is like beating up a dead guy.
Scott: Yeah, we basically just be repeating ourselves at infinitum.
Rym: Yeah now in terms of everything else.
Rym: The animation quality is pretty bad.
Scott: Well, it's 1982.
Scott: So for 1982 I say this is run-of-the-mill.
Scott: You know, this is as old as we are this show.
Rym: Yeah, there is a lot of Boys stand around looking at each other.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, there's not a lot of colors.
Scott: it's pretty much solid colors everywhere and Nothing really moves fluidly and a lot of things are sometimes drawn in a scary way like oh, I don't look at that.
Rym: Yeah It does.
Rym: you remember I would run in stinky when you were a kid watching right in stinky the old red and stinky when you Wasn't allowed to be disgusting.
Rym: not the new terrible red and stinky where suddenly out of the blue.
Rym: Sometimes he just show this still zoomed in frame of like Ren's Pus-filled oozing sore.
Scott: Yeah, it's cuz he couldn't animate like a high-definition painting.
Scott: He would just paint a still frame and then zoom in on it.
Rym: This show does that with a little dictator like turning his face and his mascara and eyeliner and everything becomes super super Like out there.
Rym: and it's like.
Rym: I can't describe it.
Rym: You just got to watch this show.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, Boku Patiliro is a scary scary show That is hilarious to watch one episode of and I pity the fool who watches more than one episode.
Scott: Maybe if you were drunk and you had a bunch of people at your house and you were looking for something crazy Like hey, man, check out this crazy shit.
Scott: Yeah, you would show two or three episodes of Patiliro.
Rym: apparently the show was moderately well known or at least Finally remembered because when we had the first episode laying around and we started to put it on and asked Emily what it was And she knew immediately But she hadn't seen it.
Rym: So when we told her that it was about what we just said it was about She kind of flipped and we still have to show her to her to prove it.
Rym: I don't think many people we've shown we've talked about the show with have actually believed us as to the sheer level of Homosexuality and sexual tension that is present between these three characters.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know any more about the history of the show or the manga or anything like that but I do know that.
Rym: What do you know, you don't know nothing.
Scott: I do know that I'm not watching anymore of it.
Rym: See here's the thing I kind of want to watch.
Rym: Oh god a few more.
Scott: I know you're gay.
Rym: now.
Rym: that the reason is that I want to see if the show Changes at all or goes in other directions or if it's just 49 episodes of that.
Rym: I I submit to you Sailor Moon and Dragon Ball star.
Scott: Yeah, but when you find out why he's trying to get steal this painting I think that's the tiny thing that ties into the other.
Rym: he's trying to learn about his daddy and where he came from Being a little dictator in some weird country somewhere.
Scott: Yeah, I think that's that's the real plot.
Rym: That's speaking of Dragon Ball.
Scott: You mean the thin plot that ties together a whole shit ton of comedy.
Rym: But speaking of Dragon Ball apparently the episode director of this was none other than dice K Niccio who's responsible for Dragon Ball.
Rym: Dragon Ball GT.
Rym: Dragon Ball the movie 1.
Rym: Dragon Ball the movie 2.
Rym: Dragon Ball Z. Dragon Ball Z the movie 1 2 3 5 6 the Dragon Ball Z special 1 and the Dragon Ball Z special 2 in addition to one piece.
Scott: So the guy who did Dragon Ball learn the ropes on Patilero.
Scott: Is that what you're saying?
Rym: I'm not making any sort of correlation of Effect study or anything here.
Rym: I'm not gonna make any claims.
Rym: I'll just note that this guy worked on more Dragon Ball than he worked on anything else.
Scott: Well, I mean if you work on Dragon Ball, it's hard to have time to work on anything else.
Rym: Yeah, so I'm sorry if we didn't review this show to the standard where we normally review shows.
Scott: The show is kind of hard because the show's whacked out and crazy.
Rym: I mean we watched the whole first episode and immediately forgot every character's name because it totally didn't matter.
Rym: yeah, and I don't know what else I could say just watch this show and Tell us what you think about it.
Scott: Yeah Really?
Scott: I think the main reason we reviewed this show is just to get someone else to watch it to make sure that we're not insane And hear what someone else has to say.
Rym: Yeah, I'd like someone to point out that they're not really Homosexual pedophiles.
Rym: It's actually this blah blah blah some sort of artistic thing that symbolizes the inner struggle between a child looking for a father figure.
Scott: No, it's just a bunch of dudes who look like ladies.
Rym: Yeah shooting guns at each other and being all dramatic.
Scott: Yeah smoke bombs going off Paintings getting stolen but not Lupin style.
Rym: Yeah, but still in a fairly clever way.
Rym: Yeah, pretty clever and I got to say I laughed out loud when the little dictator starts running away with that painting.
Scott: Yeah, little dictator is layers cuz he's little and cartoonish Despite also wearing mascara.
Rym: Yeah, this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our crapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week Covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front road crew calm or you can send audio feedback Via audio.
Scott: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit Don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.