Rym: It's Thursday April 13th, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We deviate from the GeekNights standard course affair and bring you a somewhat explicit and possibly interesting episode Tonight.
Rym: GeekNights is going to discuss masturbation.
Rym: Let's do this Well tonight again.
Rym: I am here alone though Scott will be joining me for the second half of the episode.
Rym: I will be doing the news anything of the day as I tend to do when Scott is not here.
Rym: Now first off I would like to say again because while GeekNights is not an explicit or Particularly are or whatever rated podcast.
Rym: I feel it is my duty to inform our listeners that tonight we are talking about a somewhat delicate topic and If you feel for whatever reason that you should not be listening to it Then I suggest that you do not listen to tonight's episode tonight.
Rym: We are going to be discussing masturbation.
Rym: Now While it is my personal feeling that this is a somewhat silly topic for anyone to get bothered about or uptight or whatever There are laws in some of the more restrictive countries in this world such as the United States barring Certain people from listening to certain types of media describing certain types of things.
Rym: Thus all I will say before we continue with the show is that quite simply if you are living somewhere in the United States Where you will violate United States law by listening to this episode Then I urge you to not listen and to not violate any laws.
Rym: if you live outside of the United States I could care less what you do because your laws don't apply to me.
Rym: But anyway more on that later.
Rym: first in the news.
Rym: I don't know how many of you are aware of this but the internet is subject to the same tax laws that the rest of the world is now.
Rym: a lot of people buy things online and They're usually pleased when they don't have to pay any sales tax on it.
Rym: Or sometimes I know people get miffed when they order something and for some reason that retailer seems to charge them sales tax Even though no one else does.
Rym: Now the IRS has the right to collect sales taxes on anything sold online not just online actually but anywhere.
Rym: and The issue here is simply that due to a lot of complicated laws that I'm not going to get into Most online retailers do not charge sales tax at all.
Rym: This is because they cannot deal with the fact that every state has different sales tax laws.
Rym: some states have no sales tax at all and some two states it shit.
Rym: it varies as low as by county or by city and the basic rule is simply that if you order something online or purchase something from a cut from a company that Does not have a significant presence or any sort of base of operations in your state Then that company is not obligated to in any way collect sales taxes from you And in fact you are obligated to report and pay those taxes to your state under what is called a use tax.
Rym: Now many people ignore these taxes But they're actually fairly widespread and you can get into just as much trouble by not paying them as you can by not paying your other taxes.
Rym: Anytime you purchase something outside of your state Anything that you will ever use in your state take into your state or enjoy the benefits from in your state You have to pay a use tax on it because your state didn't get its cut of the sales tax that you would have paid On it.
Rym: It's kind of a low thing.
Rym: I very much disagree with a lot of it, but there's nothing you can do.
Rym: that's the law and The news here is simply that the IRS is starting to really go after people who don't pay now.
Rym: This isn't really news.
Rym: This has been going on for a long time.
Rym: There's always been a lot of controversy about sales tax on the internet and whatnot.
Rym: The news now is that many of the states which are experiencing some budget shortfalls or are in other ways strapped for cash.
Rym: I've decided that this is a nice untapped revenue stream and they're going to start enforcing use taxes as as fully as they can.
Rym: Now, what does it mean to you?
Rym: It means that if you get audited the IRS can require your bank statements and credit card statements and can look through them for any Purchases you may have made out of state or out of your county.
Rym: and if you were caught Having bought something in another state or another county or on the internet and having not paid the proper use tax on it You can be screwed just as much as if you cheated anywhere else on your taxes.
Rym: the states are really starting to crack down or at least they say they're starting to crack down and Here is the interesting part that at least I've noticed.
Rym: Whenever states crack down on this because states have cracked down on the use taxes once or twice in the past it seems that one they go over after businesses more than people and Two.
Rym: while they won't go after many people directly or obviously they will make a huge public media debacle scandal whatever they'll put all the word out that hey, we're coming after you.
Rym: you'd better come clean.
Rym: and I really believe that the rationale here is simply that if they tell everyone that they're going to enforce it strictly and they tell Everyone that they're going to go after them then people might be more likely to just pay the tax or pay the Recommended minimum use tax in order to avoid being caught or get in trouble Despite the fact that if they just kept their mouth shut they probably wouldn't get caught.
Rym: Now I cannot legally give you tax advice for a number of reasons.
Rym: All I will say is that I have not paid any use taxes.
Rym: However, I will also say that I did not last year purchase anything in any sort of very Verifiable way from any state other than New York or from any County other than the county in which I live.
Rym: ha ha Now in some more fun news South Park, which is a show that I like and I've respected more and more over time Has gotten in trouble with Comedy Central yet again And in fact Comedy Central has seen fit to censor them and prevent them from showing part of an episode that they made.
Rym: I'm sure you're all familiar with the Muhammad image scandal where a Danish newspaper printed a few images of Muhammad.
Rym: now to many followers or adherents of Islam an Image of any kind of Muhammad is a terrible graven whatnot?
Rym: and it is something that cannot be done.
Rym: it is a sin to do so to have it to draw it to show it and A Danish newspaper printed a number of these characters and there was worldwide uproar.
Rym: now South Park decided that they were going to do a nice spoof on this and the episode includes all sorts of nice funny Censorship themes and it gets to a point where they're going to show an image of Muhammad instead of showing it.
Rym: the episode was forced to show some black text saying that Comedy Central had prevented them from showing the part of the episode they plan to show.
Rym: and While technically Comedy Central is perfectly within their rights to censor an episode.
Rym: I mean, it's their network.
Rym: They can do whatever they want.
Rym: They claim that their rationale was for the good of public safety or something stupid.
Rym: I Think this is a very cowardly act on their part and that freedom of speech should always supersede When at all possible any other interests.
Rym: now the really interesting part and I only bring this up because a few nights ago Scott and I happened to watch the episode involved.
Rym: but almost four or five seasons ago South Park actually had Muhammad not only as an image but as a central character in one of their episodes the super best friends episode.
Rym: That actually includes the giant Abraham Lincoln who was then killed by the giant stone John Wilkes booth that we talked about in the forums a little while ago.
Rym: So in fact South Park has already shown images of Muhammad and Comedy Central did nothing.
Rym: so I guess it says a lot about the Climate of the world and the tension that's around now that something that was just common and funny and no one even made a remark About it five years ago is suddenly this horrible life or death.
Rym: We must censor it.
Rym: We must deprive you of your free speech issue And frankly, I've just lost a lot of respect for the executives at Comedy Central who made this decision.
Rym: So my thing of the day I don't know how old this is, but I discovered it on the internet very recently It is a story written in the style of HP Lovecraft of Cthulhu fame But it is not about Cthulhu or demons or anything.
Rym: It is a story that is written about a baby and a man who is supposed to change this baby's diaper.
Rym: But as it is written in this Cthulhu type style, it's rather creepy and disturbing Especially if you don't actually realize what the story is about now Once again, I don't know how old this is But I noticed it today and I read it and I found it absolutely hilarious.
Rym: and I do know that a long time ago I found a website that had a whole bunch of stories written about mundane things or about things you wouldn't expect But they were written from the style or the perspective of a famous author.
Rym: Someone wrote one about changing a light bulb, but it was hemming away and all sorts of funny things.
Rym: I don't know if this was part of that or not.
Rym: I don't remember where that was, but I found this funny.
Rym: So without further ado, I now present the much awaited and much maligned GeekNights episode on masturbation.
Rym: I give one final caution that if you are in any way averse to explicit or sexual content I recommend you stop listening right now.
Rym: now there's been a lot of hype for today's episode.
Rym: a Lot of people have been bothering us about it talking it up various things And there are also a number of terms for what we are about to discuss
Scott: such as Fondle the fig
Rym: Dragon the dragon
Scott: Paddle the pickle
Rym: spanking the monkey
Scott: Shoot putty at the moon
Rym: choking the chicken
Scott: shaking hands with the unemployed
Rym: beating off jerking off stroking off
Scott: mangling the midget
Rym: Night on the town with Pamela Anderson and her five friends
Scott: waxing the dolphin
Rym: verbing the noun
Scott: snap the monkey.
Scott: tonight we're going to talk about Masturbation and if we were really cool, we could go the rest of the episode with using a different euphemism every time.
Scott: But we're not that cool.
Rym: Yeah, considering that googling around for masturbation euphemism gave us enough comedy fodder to last the rest of time Bludgeoning the beefsteak.
Scott: Yeah, we would be able to do that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So anyway, in fact, there's a Star Wars list.
Scott: It's like 15 Star Wars euphemisms for masturbation.
Scott: You wouldn't think there'd be that many Yeah, but until you've groomed the Wookie, you know, you don't really know.
Scott: yeah, all right.
Rym: So last week near the end of a fairly long episode we ended up deciding on the air that we were going to talk this week about masturbation.
Rym: and the day has come and We're not ones to.
Rym: um, as we've said before shit talk.
Rym: So here we are.
Scott: Let's start by saying that we are experts Masters if you will.
Scott: yeah, if you think that we're professionals and we know everything we're talking about when it comes to like how a computer works and what To buy we are double experts when it comes to this now Like relatives and things aren't listening.
Rym: Oh, I know they all are.
Rym: I'm sure this episode is gonna come back to bite us.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: Now.
Rym: I just like to say my grandma doesn't listen.
Rym: I would like to say to anyone out there that one if you've just tuned in to GeekNights for the first time ever I'm sorry, you picked the wrong day.
Scott: We have archives.
Scott: You can listen to old episodes first.
Rym: Yeah, this is a special episode and that one we said we'd do it and now we're held to doing it too.
Scott: This is probably the first and only I guess explicit GeekNights ever To figure out how to put the tag on just this episode somehow.
Rym: Yeah, this episode will be marked separately.
Rym: Yeah, I mean we we generally are somewhat foul-mouthed and such but this is a fairly Delicate or touchy if you will topic for many people at least for Americans.
Rym: Yeah, if you live outside of America, whatever nothing we're gonna say is new.
Scott: Yeah so let's start at the beginning.
Scott: when it comes to Draining the dragon.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Now we're not going to go into a long Socio-economical whatnot?
Rym: religion talk about masturbation.
Rym: nor are we going to talk a lot about the biology of it?
Rym: No We're only going to talk about it from a practical human standpoint and also from a to Guy geeks who recently got out of college Standpoints.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Well it all started when Puberty, yep I remember very clearly the day the very moment when I realized the opportunities that awaited me.
Scott: I Also remember the same thing.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Now one last disclaimer is that this episode is going to be mostly personal anecdotes.
Scott: It really can't be much else.
Scott: Yeah, I mean an impersonal anecdote would be non masturbatory.
Scott: I mean if someone else you can't be masturbated by someone else.
Scott: It's just.
Rym: yep That's the other thing.
Rym: We're not going to talk about sex relationships anything else.
Rym: This is purely masturbation as it stands on its own auto-eroticism not however Autoerotic asphyxiation.
Rym: No while I don't you wouldn't think I'd need to make that disclaimer.
Rym: You would be surprised how often that term comes up on the internet in casual conversation Scarily often.
Rym: So anyway the exact moments.
Scott: Well, it all started, you know my guy like to look at naked girls looking at some porn and mr.
Scott: Wee wee goes.
Scott: It feels real good when you when you look at naked ladies
Rym: see I remember when I was very young and I was just starting to go through puberty and I'd be like I'd be swinging around on Monkey bars and I'd my pants be moving a certain way and I'd feel something like that's a good feeling whatever it is And I never quite knew where it came from and it would come and go randomly.
Rym: Yep, and it was one day that I was sitting in my little bedroom and I'm thinking like I've heard of beating off That's what everyone called it where I was when I was young and like I'd heard this term and it wasn't really like.
Rym: I basically Knew from sex ed in school and various things.
Rym: I knew what a penis was.
Rym: I knew that I had one I knew what it did in most cases and I knew that sex made babies and all that sort of thing.
Rym: but I wasn't quite sure of the mechanics of Autoerotically arousing myself.
Rym: I didn't really well.
Rym: I obviously didn't think of it in those terms and I just remember one day I'm sitting there and I was thinking about things.
Rym: I was thinking about Someone I knew when I was that age and I was going through that sort of time and I thought well they call it Beating off do you hit it?
Rym: and that didn't work.
Rym: That was a bad idea.
Rym: And then I thought back to my little sex ed book where they talked about, you know, how sex works and I thought oh Maybe if I just kind of simulate the action of it going into something.
Rym: What'll I use?
Rym: Well, I got this sock and the rest was history.
Scott: Yep me it was more like, you know, I knew that.
Scott: Well at first when I was a little kid I had a little book I said how babies are made and I knew that like Sperms came out of the man and went into the woman but didn't know that they were like Actual, you know, I didn't quite grasp the concept of these physical things.
Scott: I sort of I guess when I was a little kid, I imagined them crawling across the bed Going.
Scott: I don't know what I was thinking You know.
Scott: and then sex ed came around that I knew that You know penis shot out white stuff and that was the sperms and all that.
Scott: and I knew that.
Scott: look at it Girlies made it, you know stand up and feel good and I knew that you put it in the girlie You know to make the stuff happen.
Scott: But you know, I like how you say girly.
Scott: Yeah But well in those days it was a girly.
Scott: you still say was I yeah, whatever?
Rym: But I didn't really fully realize like oh, yeah, you know, yeah Yep, I had all sorts of kind of vague notions and I really wasn't sure.
Scott: yeah So, you know, I would look at prawns on the internet and playboys or whatever and you know I didn't really do that so much.
Rym: I just had a very active imagination.
Scott: Yeah, even when I I would imagine also sometimes laying in bed at night and such.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yep and I think every kid has the the recurring theme of you're laying in bed and your mom opens your bedroom doors terms in and You're in a way pitching a tent.
Rym: So what you do and I think every boy learned right away to do this is you immediately pull your knees up Yep, so you're just laying there your hands probably behind your back or behind your head like nothing's going on.
Rym: You're just kind of the knees are holding the sheets up kind of keeping everything hidden.
Scott: You got to use a bigger tent to hide a little one.
Rym: You don't roll over on your side, but that doesn't work because then you just crush it.
Scott: Yeah, and then one time, you know, I mean I knew that there was some sort of masturbation.
Scott: people talked about it But I never did it.
Scott: and then you know one time I like I'll touch.
Scott: Ooh If I touch it, it feels good.
Scott: Well, it didn't take much after that and you know I just you know, I touched it and it felt real good.
Scott: That was that.
Scott: and then one day I was like, you know The stuff doesn't come out.
Rym: Oh, I have a story about this.
Scott: Yeah, and then I was like Stuff's supposed to come out.
Scott: Hmm what if I all right, I'm gonna do it this time I'm just gonna keep playing with it until the stuff comes out.
Scott: Yep, and it worked.
Rym: I had the exact same thing is the first time I ever did anything and I Did it a little bit like a minute maybe and I stopped.
Rym: I was like that was the best thing ever.
Rym: Yep Like I don't screw video games Seriously, and I and I didn't realize that I could have kept going.
Rym: I stopped because I was afraid I was gonna break it or Myself because it's so close to pain.
Rym: It's like one step before pain is awesome.
Rym: Mm-hmm And one day I was like, what if I just keep going?
Rym: Well, they'd keep happening and I learned that no does not keep happening.
Rym: It comes to an end.
Rym: I make a mess and then I go to sleep exactly.
Rym: Then I decide it became integrated as it does with every young boy unless you have a very tortured childhood.
Rym: It became integrated into my lifestyle.
Scott: Yeah I mean You sort of have this biological need To do it every once in a while.
Scott: if you don't it comes out at night in this in your sleep And it doesn't feel good.
Rym: Yeah, it makes a mess all of the people who maybe.
Rym: well if you haven't gone through puberty yet I hope you're not breaking any laws listening to this because America's actually kind of prudish about this sort of thing.
Rym: stupid America But especially for women out there.
Rym: I hope you all realize that You might think men are vulgar for masturbating as often as we do or you may not realize how often men in general actually Masturbate, but I am not kidding when I tell you that there are consequences to not masturbating that are painful and annoying for us.
Scott: Yeah, if I don't do it after like I don't a couple weeks.
Scott: It hurts and I get headaches and it's really uncomfortable and I'll keep getting erections all the time.
Scott: Yes It really wants to go because it's full up with sperm and they have to get out and then eventually we'll just have a wet Drain and make a horrible mess.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I'd rather have some good feelings, you know while I'm awake and Be able to manage the mess in a way that is Clean then have to go to sleep not get any good feelings wake up with some goop in my pants And it's not good.
Rym: Yep But integrating it into the lifestyle is out.
Rym: for I mean, we have a lot of listeners not in America And I guess I would like to say that it's very different in America than it is in many other places
Scott: Not like we know what it's like in the other places
Rym: No, but just from what we've read and what we can tell Americans are very.
Rym: it's one of these situations where everyone does it and Despite this no one really wants to talk about it which created many awkward situations in college, which we'll get to.
Rym: Oh, yeah Yeah, we have college stories But as it became apparent to me, especially after puberty kind of finished and I was.
Rym: now I'm a man I am I'm manly in my ways and manner and I am fully ready to copulate and all that sort of thing.
Rym: I Remember it.
Rym: it took some effort to actually properly integrate it into the lifestyle in the sense that you had to hide it from everyone Despite the fact that everyone knew what you were doing.
Scott: Yeah, it's not like.
Scott: I could just You know whip it out and do it in the minute.
Scott: It's not like, you know, you got to pee.
Scott: Well, you go up and you go to the bathroom you pee.
Scott: Well once a you know every few days or so You got a jerk off.
Scott: It's not like you just get up and go jerk off.
Scott: You have to find a private place someplace secret.
Scott: We have enough time Yeah and enough tools if you need tools.
Rym: and yeah, I'm more of two minds than that.
Rym: I have almost never engaged in pornography.
Rym: in terms of masturbation I usually just use my imagination which is quite fertile.
Scott: Yeah imaginations fertile, but you know, it's like catalyst porn, you know, you want to maybe speed it up or you know Get going quicker and then you know, you look at the horn to get going and then you turn it off.
Rym: There are definitely two kinds of masturbation for men.
Rym: There is the I am masturbating because I am aroused and this is the only way to sate me because I'm alone Haha, and then there is the I have to masturbate now.
Rym: I'm going to do it and be done with it like it's a chore and then go to bed.
Scott: Of course just because it's a chore doesn't mean it can't be fun.
Rym: Yeah, but it's definitely not as good as the other kind.
Rym: Yep, I mean there are definitely times when it's like And you do a little like two-minute quickie make a mess into a tissue and go to bed.
Scott: I actually I would highly recommend against tissue, but we'll get into that All right, and then we get in there right now right now to deal with the mess.
Rym: All right And the mess he also comes into play in terms of how to avoid getting caught by your parents Even though don't kid yourself.
Rym: They know what you're doing.
Scott: Well, that's it.
Rym: We'll do how not to get caught after we do how to clean up all right, but I will say right now your parents know what you're doing and Most kids don't realize this until long after they finished worrying about their parents.
Rym: then they realize that wait a minute Every time I was in the bathroom for like an hour and dad was standing out there.
Scott: He knew ah but Yeah, unless you have crazy like I don't know.
Scott: What's the religions that care?
Rym: whole bunch of them?
Scott: Yeah, unless you're one of those religions that care Your parents know and just don't talk about it or if they're really cool.
Scott: They'll talk about it.
Scott: That's like, you know, you got good parents.
Scott: if they say something Yep, but if they say something like don't do that and they beat you.
Scott: well now you have crazy religious parents.
Scott: Yeah, you should get rid of them.
Scott: not really All right, so how to clean up the mess?
Rym: well one there are many schools of thought here.
Scott: Yes, uh to be honest the first thing I tried because I didn't really under you know I didn't knew what how it was gonna come out what it was gonna be how much.
Scott: So the first time I ever did it I had a cup.
Scott: I caught it in a cup to see what it would take so I could examine it and shit Yeah, I used the inside of a sock.
Scott: Yep The inside of a sock is a highly recommended method.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: However, make sure your sock is not terribly abrasive.
Rym: Yes get to do not do not Accidentally put that sock on.
Scott: Yeah So what you want to do is you want to find a buy all new socks or find socks?
Scott: So you don't wear anymore, you know You've got socks.
Scott: like you buy socks and you buy different socks And then you still have some of the old ones.
Scott: use those old ones.
Rym: now in the very least Just if you have all new socks, just pick a pair put it aside treat it separately from the rest and Just keep track and use that one all the time.
Rym: Here's a.
Scott: here's a helpful hint.
Scott: take a sharpie put a black mark on the inside of the of the side.
Rym: Yes, now don't write.
Scott: Masturbation saw no just like a black line in there something like that.
Scott: I have a couple socks with a black line on him.
Rym: Ah Actually, what I did is I have one.
Rym: I had a pair of boxers that was old and ratty and it was literally a loincloth.
Rym: Yeah, I had that pair though I wore that pair of boxers.
Rym: actually that's a different pair of boxers.
Rym: Oh, wow I'm the kind of person aside from masturbation who just doesn't throw clothes away and I had a pair of underwear that I finally threw away because it was basically just a loincloth and it disintegrated entirely one day.
Rym: No washer, but no I had one pair one pair of boxers that I always use because it was nice It was the right consistency it washed Well, it didn't stain too badly and I just always use that boxer.
Rym: and when I was young and my mom still did my laundry I washed it on my own in the sink and made sure that she never came into contact with it.
Scott: Yeah, that's a good move.
Rym: I assume she just thought I lost that boxer if she even knew or cared.
Scott: That's the thing about a sock is if you You can sometimes get your mom to clean the socks because she won't know that they're any different from any other socks.
Scott: Or she might know and not say anything.
Rym: She probably knows probably because if you think you're all clever wad the sock up She'll flip it out and she'll know right away.
Scott: Yeah, if your mom's cool, she won't say anything.
Rym: if your mom's if your mom's awesome She'll say I'll buy you a frickin rag.
Scott: Just don't Don't lay socks.
Scott: Yeah, if your mom's uncool she'll yell at you or something.
Rym: now I very much love the mind though when I was very young I often did it in bed just because I couldn't get away with doing anywhere else But bed still a good place because I'm of the opinion that if you're reclining it is much more pleasurable.
Rym: Yes, though often I found that standing is very good.
Scott: And as a result, I have a trouble with the standing.
Rym: I primarily masturbate in the shower something.
Rym: I never thought I'd say on the internet Hmm.
Scott: Well, there you have it.
Rym: Yep, almost always I I don't want to say that every time I take a shower but 90% of the time when I take a shower in my own home.
Scott: Yeah, well, let me quote the man show.
Scott: actually I remember I was watching the man show when it was old and good and One guy from the audience asked if I go to like my friend's house, you know, and he has a wife.
Scott: I never I didn't see this but I've heard this one like if he's the guy basically was gonna sleep over at a friend's house and the friend had a wife and kids and everything and He's like is it you know?
Scott: Is it good etiquette for me to masturbate in the shower?
Scott: and the man show said and I agree and I think everyone else will too That not only is it okay to masturbate in the shower, but that is in fact the good etiquette I mean, we're also gonna masturbate the kids bedroom You know like a sign of respect.
Scott: yeah, the shower is the best place because number one The mess goes away.
Scott: You don't worry about it.
Scott: Yep, usually number two No one's gonna bother you in the shower.
Scott: privacy.
Rym: now number three Not only is it easy cleanup, but you've got a lot of water there.
Rym: That's very handy.
Rym: You can direct that showerhead in certain ways.
Rym: You got some conditioner there, which I highly recommend using conditioner.
Scott: Nick soaps good depending not depends on the soap.
Scott: Yes on the soap.
Scott: soap soaps will fuck you.
Scott: some soaps will be just great.
Rym: Yeah when in doubt use conditioner.
Rym: It's probably the most benign substance in there.
Scott: Yeah, baby lotions good.
Scott: Yeah, just water though not good.
Rym: No no just water is worse than nothing.
Scott: Yeah, just water.
Scott: It'll be all dry and chafee and you'll hurt yourself.
Rym: Yeah, like literally just water you'll feel like it's all lubricated, but no you're basically just scraping it all off.
Scott: You're scraping that skin right away And you'll come out and you have this red stick right in front of you And you go ow every time something touches it and you'll put underwear on.
Scott: it'll hurt.
Scott: Yeah, don't use just water.
Scott: I mean a Plain hand with hand oil that's.
Scott: the other thing is in the shower your the oils on your hand have been washed off.
Scott: that Really, it's better to do with a bare hand on a bare penis than a wet hand on a wet penis.
Rym: Yep, now we said the mess goes away, and that's usually true.
Rym: however one because we've run a follow this before one.
Rym: I do not masturbate in other people's showers actually or in hotels or any any place where I'm with other people Masturbated in a hotel.
Rym: once however Someone we don't know who when we were at Otakon two years ago masturbated in the shower and left some leavings.
Scott: Don't do that.
Rym: Yeah When you make the
Scott: shower head off and aim it at it and disintegrate it and make it sure it goes down
Rym: because unless because most People I assume are not staring at their own penis when they're masturbating
Scott: nope I
Rym: would I would probably say that many of you especially if you're new at this I don't know May not realize the force with it with which it is ejected and the fact that it will go far and beyond Anything you could imagine.
Rym: you will find it in the damnedest of places.
Scott: this is a fact if your penis was the width and girth of a fire hose and You jerked it off aiming it at a steel door.
Scott: You would knock that door down.
Rym: I have hinges and all I have anecdotes that I probably would not want to share because they're not directly related to masturbation But let me just say that it goes quite far.
Scott: Yep, and with quite a bit of force It's all sort of Gaussian in its push push push push push push push go Like a gauss rifle only without magnet.
Scott: It's a gauss rifle without magnets.
Scott: That's exactly what it is.
Rym: But yeah If you for whatever reason decide to masturbate in someone else's shower make sure you didn't leave anything behind.
Rym: That's all I ask.
Scott: Yeah, cuz if people see that, you know Whether their opinions about masturbation are doesn't matter.
Scott: They're gonna be like, oh You're disgusting person.
Rym: Oh, yeah, because once again even me and Rym will say you the basic etiquette of masturbation seems to be everyone Does it.
Rym: everyone knows everyone does it but don't talk about it and more importantly don't get caught doing it.
Scott: Yeah, even if you don't talk about it getting caught doing it is just.
Scott: you know, people don't care that you do it.
Scott: They care that they had to see you doing it and even though I don't want to see you doing it unless you're a hot girl.
Rym: Talking just about male masturbation here though I will point out that more than one of our female friends when they heard that we were doing this episode said that they're going To record or do their own sort of female version of this for us.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: That is awesome.
Scott: Totally awesome But that's something I need to know more about As does the world.
Rym: but I digress.
Rym: Where was I going?
Scott: You were jerking it.
Rym: No, I really wasn't.
Rym: I'm wearing my dog Zelda pajamas.
Scott: Yeah, you know what those are for actually?
Rym: No, they're not.
Rym: I wouldn't want to defile these.
Scott: I know I know All right, so we talked about how to prevent the mess You can use.
Scott: a sock is good a tissue is bad.
Scott: toilet paper is bad because they disintegrate.
Scott: not
Rym: only they disintegrate But usually in the heat of your you know Self-inflicted passion you will end up holding the wad of tissue or whatever directly against the penis and as a result you will come if you will if I may if I might and The tissue will now be effectively rabbit.
Scott: you might glued to the end of your penis or worse The moisture from the gisms will disintegrate the you know paper Because it's a weak-ass paper like a tissue or a toilet paper and little bits of it will get stuck all over the place.
Rym: Also, you now have to dispose of the tissue and I'll tell you that if you just put it in the garbage Everyone knows if they see your garbage full of a thousand tissues and you don't have allergies.
Rym: You're done.
Rym: I Have allergies.
Rym: I'd have an excuse even though I never I've never used a tissue in my life.
Scott: And what are those box of tissues right there?
Rym: I have allergies.
Rym: All right I masturbate into those boxers that are in my hand.
Scott: Anyway Yeah paper towel works.
Scott: Okay in a pinch because it doesn't disintegrate and it absorbs and it's a lot bigger.
Rym: and if you can catch it with however Do not use the paper towel in any way to stimulate.
Scott: no No, no paper towel will chafe you to hell.
Rym: paper towel is just high-grade sandpaper.
Scott: Yeah, you want to keep the paper towel.
Scott: what you do generally is you jerk it with some other means which we will explain and Then at the last second you grab the paper towel and hold it in front.
Rym: Yep Now we said we were gonna talk a bit about how to avoid getting caught and such.
Rym: now growing up I remember it was very much a game of cat and mouse and luckily I had my own room.
Scott: So my room is key.
Rym: Yeah, so I'd go into my room and I actually had a lock on my door.
Rym: So there were other than the few times when I didn't lock the door and even that I never really got caught because I was Very quick about it about putting my.
Rym: oh, I was very quick about putting my stuff away or some way hiding what I was doing.
Scott: Yeah, the key to not getting caught is if you're in a house with a family or something You're that young you want to do it in bed under the blanket late at night or something like that when no one's home.
Scott: All that good stuff.
Rym: Um, I've known people who would when they were in the bathroom.
Rym: anyway You know as a number two sitting there, they try to kill two birds with one stone.
Rym: bad move.
Rym: It's a bad move mostly because one everyone's gonna wonder why you were in the bathroom for an hour.
Rym: Mm-hmm Number two, you're probably gonna make a mess.
Rym: You didn't realize.
Rym: mmm number three This has happened to people I'd never happened to me or anyone I knew but I've heard many Anecdotes of people who I mean a lot of people will often be very tired or fall asleep after they finish.
Rym: Nothing is worse than falling asleep in your bathroom and being woken up an hour later by your mom and you're laying there with your Penis in your hands.
Scott: or you're sitting just asleep and you got poop in the toilet and there's some white stuff on the wall and There's a really funny image in my head, yeah That should be in a movie or something.
Rym: There's actually a webcomic that did that exact thing.
Scott: Yeah now in college, which is probably the next phase of your life.
Scott: Yes, you uh, it's pretty easy.
Scott: You're gonna do it either in the shower.
Scott: Just all right.
Scott: Just make sure you wash it away because you're sharing showers in a dorm Or you do in your dorm room in which case the roommate is there now?
Rym: Despite the fact that everyone's in college.
Rym: Everyone is a freshman and thus no one knows the etiquette.
Rym: Luckily the etiquette is passed down from upperclassmen unto the freshmen fairly quickly.
Scott: step one share your schedule with your roommate.
Rym: now No one says here's my schedule.
Rym: make your masturbation schedule.
Rym: what happens?
Rym: and and it's funny Oh every guy in college does this like automatically or if they don't the upperclassmen mention it and then they do it.
Rym: You put your schedule just somewhere in public.
Scott: you print it out and you like bulletin board.
Scott: you put it on a bulletin board And it looks like it's the for you to reference.
Rym: But really now you assume that the other person will do the same and they will Because they want the same thing you want unless they're one of those crazy religious people.
Rym: in which case Well, we won't get into that.
Rym: Yeah, we have stories But then all you do is look at their schedule and say oh, all right He has an economics class from 6 to 10 every Wednesday.
Rym: That is now masturbation day for him.
Scott: Now what you got to do here is he's not gonna go to that class on 6 to 10 every Wednesday.
Scott: He might skip it and that's where you got trouble.
Scott: What you do is You don't do it until 7. if he's not there at 7 that means he went to the class.
Scott: If he is there at 7 that means he's not going to the class.
Scott: you say yep, or you might say hey Don't you have a class or something?
Scott: You know, maybe well if he skips one class, you know He's probably not gonna skip the next one now.
Scott: There are some specific situations such as a roommate skips every class.
Scott: You know You have two or three roommates.
Rym: Oh my god, we can tell the story about Greg.
Rym: Yeah our friend Greg The poor bastard he had a roommate who didn't do anything but play.
Rym: What was the Asheron's call?
Scott: played Asheron's call He went to class He slept barely and he would go to the food place get food bring it back and play Asheron's call.
Rym: while eating He was basically always in the room to the point that our friend could probably not ever masturbate Effectively or I mean he really had no way to do it easily.
Rym: Yep Yeah, he was not a happy person Unhappy as hell because once again headaches.
Scott: What you can try to do is wait until you know The other guy is a hundred percent asleep and then try to do it under the covers.
Rym: I've done that.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It's fine Yeah, it's the other guys.
Rym: It because there was one.
Rym: there were a couple times.
Rym: I'd be laying in my bunk and I'd be just laying there and I'd hear And it's obvious to me.
Rym: All right, that dude's masturbating I'm just gonna.
Rym: not I'll ignore it because he was probably awake a few nights ago when I did it.
Scott: Yep now if someone uh, you know, if you're in a dorm room and some guy says you jerking it just be like Just be like, yeah, what of it?
Scott: Yeah, I'll be like, you know, like you do it too.
Scott: What down man.
Rym: now when I did it I learned right away that if I'm gonna do it I wouldn't just jump into my bed and lay there and do it.
Rym: because if he walks in and I'm laying in my bed at Like 4 in the afternoon.
Scott: Yeah No, you do it at night when everyone's asleep.
Rym: That's actually like.
Rym: I knew he'd be at class.
Rym: So what I do is I'd sit in my computer chair and I'd open like slash dot Just so it'd be there ready and I have the mouse ready and I do my thing.
Rym: but I have my pants kind of like down a bit but Ready because it.
Rym: basically there was always a thump and then a click and I had about four seconds between when I heard a noise Until the door could actually be opened.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and I was the Mac master of pulling my pants up pulling my shirt down.
Rym: I'd looks like I'm surfing slash dot once.
Scott: I was almost saved by the chain because we have a chain the door.
Scott: that way at The absolute worst he opens the door.
Scott: It's chained.
Scott: He can't get in I have to unchain it after getting my pants on.
Rym: however Bear in mind that in college if your door is chained That means I was just masturbating.
Scott: and I have now told you exactly the one time I got the pants on and I took the chain off and then you open the door.
Scott: It was it was masterwork.
Rym: I Remember one time.
Rym: I'm pretty sure he'd figured out what I was doing because I pulled my.
Rym: I did my you know standard trick and I'm surfing slash shot and he walks in and he stops a second and he looks at me and I'm sitting there and I'm just kind of moving the wrong mouse around cuz I'm like And I click on a link And he just walks by me with this.
Rym: he did.
Rym: he knew it's obvious.
Scott: He knew he knew something was up.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know what he thought I was doing, but he probably thought I was masturbating.
Rym: Yep And once you're out of college, well, once you're out of freshman year, it changes.
Scott: Oh, yeah Well, it depends if you move if you're still in a dorm or if you're living with someone, you know Or who they are because
Rym: after our freshman year all of us all of our all of us who were good friends the front Row crew as it is today.
Rym: We all moved in together not in one place but we all like lived with other members of the crew and At that point there was a there basically came a time fairly early on when everyone one day someone just like all right I'm gonna masturbate so you stay in that room.
Scott: Yeah, like literally I just like Rym can you just stay in the bedroom there?
Scott: I got a gonna jerk it and the etiquette disappeared.
Rym: Well that etiquette disappeared and from this day forth the etiquette is simply been I'm gonna masturbate.
Scott: don't bother me Yeah, you just say it.
Scott: I mean the other guy doesn't care, you know, and if the other guy, you know You should want to make friends with people who don't care.
Rym: Yeah, if your friends care that you masturbate like actually care unless you also care you're probably not really good friends.
Rym: It there's probably something wrong.
Rym: I mean, it's one thing to be like.
Rym: you don't want to be that guy who runs around like masturbate.
Scott: Yeah, and if they are really good friends, but no one, you know masturbation seems sort of taboo.
Scott: Just start talking about it and make it not taboo by talking about it, but don't go overboard.
Rym: You don't want to be that guy.
Scott: You don't want to be that guy who's just like constantly talking about sex, but You know make it not taboo in your group to say yeah I'm gonna jerk it.
Scott: or you know start a conversation about jerking techniques or Listen to this episode with all your friends.
Rym: Oh my god techniques.
Rym: Okay, take now time before.
Rym: techniques vary greatly based on geography and knowledge passed on by older kids and Experimentation and websites that are no longer existing.
Rym: You got some burping problems.
Scott: I do hate those hot dogs and whatnot.
Rym: Now when we were in college, I believe it was sophomore year Maybe junior your price.
Rym: sophomore year We discovered a website that no longer exists in the form It used to exist in.
Scott: it now exists as a shitty pay site.
Scott: Don't pay attention to it.
Scott: We're not even gonna link to it.
Rym: Yeah, no, but it used to be Jack insider calm and it was quite literally a masturbatory resource.
Scott: Is the IMDB of Dragon draining?
Rym: quite well dragon dragon dragon dragon.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Well, I didn't know you were into that sort of thing.
Rym: So anyway This website introduced us to a variety of techniques that we were dubious of but I will say that I did in fact Experiment with to great success the rosy palm and my personal favorite chopsticks chopsticks.
Scott: All right chopsticks work for there's also the banana Which we'll talk about.
Rym: god the banana.
Scott: All right, first, let's talk about some some general things.
Scott: if you want to end it quickly Just go nuts go Until you're done.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: No, I don't think we need to explain to the guys out there how the penis works.
Rym: I don't think we need to say that the glands and it does this and this part does this.
Rym: The only thing I can say is that I do not know How foreskin comes into it because I do not have any.
Scott: I also do not have foreskin and therefore cannot comment on it.
Scott: Well, I can comment.
Scott: I looked on the internet for pictures of foreskin to see what I was missing foreskin org and despite what?
Scott: You know Randy and all those people say yes circumcision doesn't prevent disease.
Scott: I know yeah religious bullshit about it, whatever Penises with foreskin or nasty looking and penises without foreskin look nice though.
Rym: I would say that They're probably only quote nasty looking unquote because they're alien and you're not used to them.
Scott: That could very well be true.
Scott: And in fact, I'm pretty sure it is but I don't care.
Scott: It's my opinion that I dislike penises with foreskin.
Rym: Well, I generally just like penises.
Scott: Oh that that true.
Rym: I really only like mine.
Rym: Yeah, my name and mine is generally annoying because he's often Bothersome when I am NOT in the mood to be bothered by him.
Scott: I mean, I like the feelings that mine generates but as a a work of art mine isn't really the great.
Rym: Oh mine is like a like a Greek God.
Scott: Well, maybe mine is a Greek God in size and shape But alright so much We'll get this out right now.
Rym: We always have a joke in our group where you know, two people are arguing and someone will say alright Just get the rulers bring them out and measure them.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So we did.
Rym: one day we did Basically, we both went into opposite rooms with rulers Got it to an erect state Put the ruler on Walk back out holding the ruler so that the amount of ruler protruding from our fist was the length of our penises.
Rym: and we
Scott: came up with a measurement standard like we're gonna measure from this spot to this spot
Rym: and we're like
Scott: Ha
Rym: and I will say right now that Scott's penis is almost exactly one centimeter longer than mine
Scott: one centi Yeah, so ladies if one centi means a lot You can you know call
Rym: yeah, mr.
Scott: That's Rym's not even single.
Scott: So if you know if you want to call anyone I'm free.
Rym: Yeah, Scott Scott's a little free and desperate and such not so desperate.
Scott: I mean if I was desperate I would be putting some more effort into it.
Scott: Also, if you're like not of age I'm not a pedophile and I don't like little girlie.
Scott: So I don't know who's listening.
Scott: Yeah, college girls are nice.
Scott: Anyway graduated girls are nicer.
Rym: All right, we're talking about masturbation not finding you a girlfriend.
Rym: Yeah, okay Well, I could do a whole show on finding you a girlfriend god damn, but anyway.
Scott: So the general technique you want to do to make it feel really good is hold out as long as possible.
Rym: Yep, in fact one of the techniques that was listed on Jack insider Which I used a great effect was the alarm clock method where you would masturbate.
Rym: However, you would look at a clock and basically every other minute on the digital clock You were not allowed to touch your penis at all.
Scott: No matter what It's a good method.
Rym: so you go and you're going you're getting close and then the minute changes and you just pull your hand away and Resist any urge to touch it and after about a half hour of that you'll go insane.
Scott: Yeah, basically what happens is is just the tension builds and builds and builds and builds and builds over a long period of time.
Scott: so you have a whole bunch of time where you feel really good the whole time and you keep feeling better and better and Better.
Scott: and then finally, you know It's it's like when you put a kink in the hose and this giant giant balloon fills up and you let the kink go when it Finally can't hold out any longer.
Rym: now while we're not talking about sex.
Rym: We may someday do an episode on sex.
Rym: I mean, I don't know how popular this particular episode is going to be.
Rym: Mm-hmm But I will say that the tech the the thing we just talked about is very Pertinent to sex as well.
Scott: Not just masturbation Yeah, when if you want to make someone feel good during sex make that happen to them You know make it so they don't finish and you just keep holding out all that on and explode.
Rym: Yeah, except for the one in wonderful thing that women can have many orgasms as opposed to our one.
Rym: Yeah, yeah bastards.
Scott: Yeah alright, so another good thing is The tip is the sensitive area as I assume, you know And the shaft is sensitive but much less sensitive and the balls are nice to play with.
Rym: and well, you know, yeah I think we should go into all the unique techniques that we know.
Scott: Alright, but generally if you go for the tip, you're gonna.
Scott: you know It's like put on the afterburner sort of it so to speak.
Scott: Yes So you gotta you gotta manipulate the throttle properly to stay at the right speed And then you cross the finish line when you know, you're ready.
Rym: Now there were two techniques in particular that I remember from Jack insider that were used to great effect.
Rym: One was the rosy palm, which honestly I use to this day.
Scott: The rosy palms a good one.
Scott: I use it a few times.
Rym: the basic of the rosy palm is that you masturbate as normal One-handed, however, you avoid the tip and the most sensitive parts.
Rym: But you generally masturbate when you're getting close and you're getting near the end.
Rym: And once you cross the line because guys know this girls may not men have a line There is an a dead exact line and we know the exact instance that we cross it.
Rym: It is the line of no return.
Rym: once you cross that line one you were done sexually for at least a few minutes after that because you're Something's going to happen - you're going you you're going to have your orgasm No matter what.
Scott: you can't prevent it and hold out any longer.
Scott: you're done.
Scott: Now the problem is pink in the hose has been let go.
Rym: the best analogy I come up with for the line is Landing a jet on an aircraft carrier.
Rym: Now landing a jet normally you throttle down you slow down you come into a nice landing.
Rym: If you're landing a jet on an aircraft carrier, you have to come in at full throttle Full full throttle.
Rym: if you let off on the throttle, you're probably going to die.
Rym: Now when it comes to masturbation if you let up at all Once you've crossed that line the orgasm is gonna be so unsatisfying.
Rym: You might as well have not even masturbated.
Rym: Yeah
Scott: basically all feeling will immediately evaporate and the stuff will come out really weekly and you'll be done and
Rym: you'll feel kind of a
Scott: Yeah, like you won't feel like because when you you jerk it you sort of have this tension that builds up and then the release is the great part.
Scott: if you don't release properly then this does remaining tension and Like some of the goop might not even make it all the way out.
Scott: you have to pee it out or something.
Scott: Yeah, and that's that's terrible.
Scott: Don't even try it.
Rym: So I guess this also applies to sex in that once you get to that point Don't back off.
Rym: Don't stop.
Rym: You must finish it to the end.
Rym: now this creates interesting situations when say Someone's knocking on your door at the exact wrong moment.
Rym: Yes, because you really have no choice but to finish up.
Scott: I Let go.
Scott: Then yeah, then I realized wait a minute.
Scott: who says I had to let go.
Scott: you get to the line and you just go at It more than ever and you just you're over the line and you can keep running and running and running for five minutes.
Scott: You can't turn around but you can keep going.
Rym: Yep Now the rosy palm technique is that you're doing the normal masturbation and you're avoiding the tip and right when you're about to hit the line Especially right when you hit the line.
Rym: now, I'm assuming you're right-handed your right hand Wow, we're going into great detail.
Rym: here is gripping the shaft The in a in a in a in a grip type fashion like you're holding a staff Mm-hmm.
Rym: I like how I use staff as opposed to stick or penis and then the left hand you take the palm and you put it over end of the penis and just kind of Rub the palm and kind of need yourself into it and finish yourself off all at once.
Scott: Yeah, you got to watch out.
Scott: one thing with the rosy palm is you don't want to get the goop on your hand.
Scott: Well, you're gonna get it on a head anyway, but you could but you do it properly.
Scott: Yeah, but you don't want someone to catch you with goop on your hand.
Rym: Yeah, make sure you can wash your hand.
Rym: You don't want to start the rosy palm until you're over the line or at the line.
Rym: Otherwise, you're just going to hurt your penis.
Scott: Yeah, that's one thing.
Scott: if you can't get some sort of lubrication or whatever You have to be really careful not to chafe your penis.
Scott: at least once in my life I've chafed some skin off and I got like a red Sort of mark and it hurts to touch it there.
Scott: and then you can't jerk it because if you do it hurts Because you scraped your skin off.
Rym: that only happened to me once and that was after I ran like two or three miles one day in silk boxers.
Rym: Don't ask me why I don't know what I was thinking.
Scott: So you got to be real careful if you start to like burn the flesh off of your wiener stop Or get some sort of goop or something.
Rym: Now the chopsticks method.
Rym: I was also very fond of Basically, this is very simple.
Rym: You take your two fingers like you're making a peace sign or a V sign and You just put it on either side and just kind of go up and down.
Rym: But the rule is you can never use anything other than the middle of those two fingers.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: It makes a very slow leisurely yet strangely powerful Session to use the term session.
Scott: Yeah You know, generally what I do is, you know, you start out slowly like, you know little chopsticks going.
Rym: Why that song?
Rym: I don't know All.
Rym: I thought I just pictured clowns and that's not what I want to picture.
Scott: No, it's not.
Rym: I don't like clowns.
Scott: but then you know, you go a little faster, you know a little more contact.
Scott: I mean, it's a you know little curve exponential growth Log arithmetic, I guess not like really.
Rym: Yeah math get it log arithmetic.
Scott: Oh Okay The other method that was in jack and cider that caught our attention, but I've never tried it.
Scott: you ever tried the banana?
Rym: I'd like to say yeah, I did but no I really didn't.
Scott: Okay So I'm gonna describe the banana But I cannot attest to the quality of the banana because I've never done it and rims never done it.
Rym: We will say however that the people who responded because jack and cider had forums and all sorts of things the response was Overwhelmingly enthusiastic to this method.
Rym: many described it as perhaps perfection in masturbation.
Scott: And as soon as you hear the method if you're a guy, I'm sure you can Imagine what it will feel like and it'll probably feel really good.
Rym: So do you want to describe the method?
Scott: you take a banana a banana?
Scott: Hopefully that is larger than your penis if you cannot find one.
Rym: I don't know what to say to you.
Scott: Yeah, get a plantain.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: See the problem I had is that it's really difficult to import girls to me.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, we made a joke.
Scott: we're gonna do an episode about bananas we're not joking?
Scott: yeah, really okay, so take the banana.
Scott: cut microwave the banana for like Five seconds ten seconds.
Rym: Yeah, 30 most don't make it hot.
Rym: Don't burn yourself for the love of God.
Scott: Yeah, make the banana warm and mushy.
Scott: now Chop the end off the banana like you're circumcising it.
Scott: Then you want to chop up the end that has the little twig guy on it.
Scott: obviously stem chop it off then Don't break the banana peel apart.
Scott: Just squeeze all the banana fruit out of it.
Scott: You know sort of like you squeezing the toothpaste out of a tube of toothpaste, right?
Scott: Take the remaining intact peel and you now have a warm and squishy synthetic fruit based vagina have at it.
Rym: I'm not you normally.
Rym: I always ask our listeners when we talk about something.
Rym: We haven't tried to try it out and let us know I can't recommend you try this.
Rym: no however if anyone is if anyone has already tried this for whatever reason Feel free to I don't know.
Rym: Tell us how well it works Maybe in the forums, but don't bring anything horrible into my forums, please.
Scott: yeah I'm telling you I don't recommend you do it, but if you do do it Against my recommendation.
Scott: I would like to hear about it.
Rym: That's probably the best way to put it.
Scott: Yeah, and I feel really bad for the banana.
Scott: So make a banana bread out of the fruit that is untarnished.
Rym: Now in terms of lubrication a lot of people use baby oil works really well baby I was good.
Rym: if you have any astroglide works Fantastically.
Rym: however it has the distinctive smell - it makes a mess Yes, so only use a more advanced lubrication.
Scott: You know like Ky.
Scott: Which is designed for this sort of thing.
Scott: if You can clean it up, and you know you're prepared like it's gonna be a big production.
Scott: You don't want to use it for like a quick one-off here and there.
Rym: yeah You save this for the special occasions like the fine wine.
Scott: yeah Do not ever think.
Scott: okay, I had a friend is a true story.
Scott: He He was in a locker room after a sport a school sport.
Scott: I think it was track.
Rym: Oh god I remember this story.
Scott: any.
Scott: He had some.
Scott: you know Ben gay I see hot.
Scott: it was actually I see hot in this case But Ben gay and other similar products.
Scott: They're all the same.
Scott: I think you know where this is going.
Scott: Now if you don't know about these products They're basically ointments which are supposed to like ease like strained muscles after intense physical exertion and They generally like they're hot.
Scott: like you if you put Ben gay on your arm It'll sort of sting and make it really warm and relax your muscle over there.
Scott: Like if you put Ben gay on someone's nose their nose will hurt like ow.
Scott: So this guy had some icy hot and he thought hmm icy cool refreshing hot warm tingly sensational.
Scott: I Think I'll take a big wad of this and put it on my balls.
Rym: if you can't guess what happened Go try it go nuts.
Rym: No.
Scott: This is something you really don't want to do.
Scott: I recommend the banana.
Scott: before recommending this he lost like a layer of skin from his scrotum just came off.
Scott: He was screaming and up like.
Scott: it's terrible.
Scott: Yeah, take sure that when you choose a lubrication you choose something that is not going to harm you physically.
Rym: Let me put it this way if you ever decide to do something that you and any point think wait a minute.
Rym: This might be dangerous.
Scott: Don't do it.
Rym: No Google for it because someone else already did it and wrote an entire site about why you shouldn't do it.
Scott: Uh, a good tool is an ice cube.
Scott: actually.
Rym: Actually ice is very useful in a number of bits of play.
Scott: Yeah, go ice.
Rym: Yes, be careful with ice as usual.
Scott: We're not talking about icy hot now.
Scott: We're talking about actual ice cubes.
Rym: Yes, a single ice cube can be used to great effect because hot cold is not a stimulation you would normally get from.
Rym: you know Your right hand.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: So like, you know, you're getting pretty close.
Scott: Just drop an ice cube on there.
Scott: rub an ice cube around Maybe a little on the tip or something, you know, and then whoo you can get somewhere.
Scott: But of course watch out.
Scott: remember what I said about water before that ice cube melts on there.
Scott: You could be heading to chafe city.
Rym: Yep any other Excellent techniques that we run out of things to talk about in regards to masturbation.
Scott: I don't think we did.
Scott: I just think they're not coming to mind right now.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, we've talked for over 45 minutes Entirely on the topic of male masturbation.
Rym: awesome.
Rym: I think that's a new internet low though I know it's not because I've read websites.
Scott: I'm sure there are other podcasts already discussing this topic.
Scott: I just haven't found any of them or search for any of them.
Rym: I like how you had to add that second part.
Scott: Yeah, it's like You haven't found any because not having found any and searching is something different from not finding and not searching.
Rym: But I guess my final thoughts here would be simply that everyone does it.
Rym: It's perfectly natural Go nuts.
Rym: Have at and have fun.
Rym: Yeah, however, do not be the guy who?
Rym: Masturbates to the exclusion of I don't know the rest of your life.
Scott: yeah, and If someone else is doing it don't get all a yeah, let him masturbate.
Scott: Be free feel good.
Rym: And thus concludes the first controversial episode of GeekNights.
Scott: I know it's controversial.
Scott: It seemed like everyone wanted to hear it.
Scott: Kind of actually would mean that someone was against it.
Rym: I'm sure there are people against it.
Rym: Hopefully they're not the kinds of people who listen to GeekNights.
Rym: I don't expect that chiropractors super religious people Acupuncture is People like that don't listen to GeekNights.
Scott: That's good.
Rym: If you do.
Rym: Well, that's awesome.
Rym: Send us some hate mail.
Scott: Yeah, we still haven't gotten any hate mail.
Scott: Flaming geek might send us some.
Rym: he might since we called him out in a spectacular fashion.
Scott: Yeah, so remember GeekNights at front row crew.
Scott: calm front row crew.
Scott: calm for a crew.
Rym: calm Yeah, and let us know what you thought of this kind of episode.
Rym: I mean we don't weren't.
Rym: GeekNights is not going to turn into sex nights.
Rym: No, it's not going to turn into poop joke nights either.
Scott: Yep, I mean even if I find a girlfriend somewhere I'll still do this.
Scott: I won't do the girlfriend to the exclusion of GeekNights.
Rym: My point is just simply that I don't really have a point.
Rym: Yeah And that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at Www.front row crew.
Scott: calm if you like our podcast.
Scott: you'll love our forums.
Scott: make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206 1 5 3 7.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.