Rym: It's Wednesday, November 8th.
Rym: I'm Rym and I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We review trigone.
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: So before I even woke up this morning It was raining and when I left the house it was raining and all day during work It was raining.
Scott: and when I got home still raining and now I'm not sure but it might still be raining.
Rym: It in fact is for I just looked out the window.
Rym: Holy crap I. it took me over an hour and a half to drive home because many of the freeways going out of New York City Blooded and I drove through more than six inches of standing water on multiple occasions.
Scott: Yeah, it took me an extra 15 minutes to a half hour to get home back.
Rym: at one point I ran a red light on purpose because I was sitting at an intersection in about several inches of water and I don't know what was happening up the road.
Rym: But kind of suddenly this small deluge of water is slowly approaching me and It's a significant amount of water that was probably going to put part of my car underwater.
Rym: That shouldn't have been underwater.
Rym: Oh, so I just kind of gunned it and went into the intersection and kept went on my way.
Scott: That was a good move.
Rym: Yeah Like the what.
Rym: the level of water was rising very noticeably and quickly, you know It made it kind of worse.
Scott: but kind of better was the fact that Since it's not daylight savings time anymore.
Scott: We set the clocks back.
Scott: It was dark like halfway through home.
Rym: See, that's just terrible.
Scott: Uh, I kind of like darkness, but it did make my drive getting home longer.
Rym: See, why do you like darkness?
Rym: I would love the Sun to be out at every moment that I'm awake during the day cuz it hurts my eyes.
Rym: Okay, so you're just a wuss.
Scott: No cuz it hurts my eyes.
Rym: So you're just a wuss You don't?
Rym: you don't like it to be sunny outside.
Rym: You just want it to be eternal night like a vampire or fungus if it was warm out.
Scott: Hell, yeah Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, you're the one who doesn't like to go on hikes or anything.
Rym: So I guess I can say it.
Scott: Whatever All right.
Scott: What kind of news is going on besides weather?
Rym: Well, I figure since this will be the last time we'll have to talk about it for a long time a
Scott: year
Rym: I note in the news that the Democrats in America took control of the House of Representatives and it is 99% likely that they also took control of the Senate.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: This proves to me that all that stuff about voting machines being rigged and mass conspiracies Was not quite as true as it seemed.
Scott: that the voting machines are just crappy.
Rym: Oh, yeah, the voting machines are just kind of dick and I think d-ball should be held accountable.
Scott: Yeah, they're not cheating to you know, make one side or the other win.
Rym: They're just bad though I have to admit I'm kind of 50/50 on how the results went even though the evil Sue Kelly has not only been booted from our congressional district, but the guy we didn't Back at all, but we voted for anyway.
Rym: now that I've learned more about his history He's pretty awesome and I retroactively endorse John Hall.
Scott: Yeah, I still don't know anything about John Hall.
Scott: He was the alternative to the bitch Sue Kelly.
Rym: See I read about his policies and I liked him But now I read about his history and who he was and he he's a pretty awesome, dude.
Scott: Yeah, how awesome is he?
Scott: He's fairly awesome.
Rym: He did some writing for rock bands.
Rym: He was in some rock bands.
Rym: He was wait.
Scott: Wait, so we have a rock and roll guy as our house representative.
Rym: Why?
Rym: Yes, we do.
Scott: That's kind of crazy.
Scott: He doesn't look like a rock and roll guy.
Scott: He looks like a bald tall jolly man.
Rym: He's not bald.
Rym: He's balding.
Scott: Okay, he is really smiley looks even if he's balding.
Rym: He totally shaves his head He's tall and he has a really really big hand.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah He looks like like he was crouching down way like he must have been kneeling.
Scott: in one of these pictures I saw where he's with a bunch of old people.
Rym: But like I said, I'm kind of 50/50 on how the elections went because on one hand I wanted America to kind of reject this whole neoconservative thing, but at the same time The neoconservatives have gotten America into quite a bit of a quagmire over there in the great sovereign nation of Iraq You know occupying it at all and I have to say Part of me really kind of wanted them to stay in power so that they'd have to deal with this mess.
Scott: Well, I think what's gonna happen is if the Democrats don't fix it pretty quick relatively quickly, you know and say I don't know four to six years Then we're gonna see people go.
Scott: Hey, you didn't fix it and they'll go right back to the you know, the Republicans again.
Rym: Yeah, or maybe maybe they'll go toward I don't know a different political party.
Rym: my hope my dark horse is that Howard Dean and Al Gore
Scott: and all those
Rym: cool Democrats not the generic milquetoast Democrats but the ones who actually are doing some kind of vocal and crazy things will band together and break away from the Democratic Party or form some sort of Internal democratic schism where you'll have people who lean not necessarily to the left But definitely not to the right.
Scott: Yeah, you keep dreaming about your crazy whatnot.
Rym: What I just want fiscally conservative socially liberal Intellin on.
Scott: yeah, I want fiscally conservative socially liberal socially liberal non libertarians.
Rym: Yeah, that's tricky except pretty much positions.
Rym: I want libertarians in every judicial position.
Scott: There is Supreme Court full libertarians, that'd be kind of crazy heavy amazing.
Scott: He's stupid crazy.
Scott: Yeah, they'd be letting everyone off the hook like almost everyone.
Rym: I think a lot of people should be a lot off the hook.
Scott: I do too But not that many people.
Rym: which is gonna come up because I was called up today for jury, dude You know what that would do.
Scott: that would make lawyers so pissed because they Prosecutors at least because they would never get anyone in jail.
Scott: libertarian judge would just be like, whatever Let him go.
Rym: Not really because the libertarians.
Scott: Well, there are juries.
Rym: So yeah, but libertarians are also for a lot of laws at least many of them some of them.
Rym: But yeah, I was called up for jury duty.
Scott: All right, you just got a jury due letter today.
Rym: I'll bet money to our listeners out there though Depending on where you live it may or may not be legal for you to actually bet money But that I will not be allowed to serve on any jury.
Rym: G.
Scott: I wonder why huh?
Scott: Could it have something to do with you going in and saying I know about jury nullification.
Scott: Don't let me be here anymore I want to go home.
Rym: I think it'll even if I didn't do that.
Rym: I have a feeling that in any sort of examination to determine juries in some sort of jury selection process Would involve asking me questions out of which my mouth would come.
Rym: I wanted to use a weird sentence like that answers that bordered on sarcastic possibly sardonic maybe a little bit snippy a Big ol can of salty sardines.
Rym: I can't imagine many questions that they could ask me in jury selection.
Rym: That would not get an answer that nobody in the room wanted to hear.
Scott: What's your name?
Scott: Where do you live?
Scott: What kind of car do you drive?
Scott: You see the first take you to get here.
Rym: The first question involves a lot of stories until they make me shut up.
Rym: The second question is Complicated because I still have a lot of ties to Michigan.
Scott: whatever That's you and your loose interpretations of simple questions, well plus they wouldn't ask me stuff like that.
Rym: They already asked all that.
Scott: I know I know I'm just giving examples.
Rym: It's asked me things like how do you feel about blah?
Rym: and I'll tell him exactly how I feel about blah.
Rym: All right in excruciating detail.
Scott: Okay, so let's get back to the eakiness instead of the politickness.
Rym: Yeah, we're done with politics unless something interesting happens in the next while probably not gonna.
Rym: well The thing is we already know that Rumsfeld stepped down and Just don't feel like talking about it.
Scott: So it's not much to say now.
Scott: anyway Best Buy the store that I don't like that much, but I don't hate as much as Walmart is selling Imported Nintendo DS games.
Rym: hot damn Best Buy plus plus.
Scott: Yep If you go to Best Buy, there's a good chance.
Scott: You will be able to buy jump superstars.
Scott: and or What's the Naruto game called Naruto?
Scott: something?
Scott: something for?
Rym: you could have just said the Naruto game?
Scott: No, because there's a whole bunch of Naruto games and only selling one specific whatever Naruto Saikyo ninja die kiss you.
Rym: is it a?
Rym: is it a fighting game?
Scott: I have no clue.
Rym: I'll bet it's a fighting game.
Scott: It very well could be see.
Rym: I remember when I went to a lot of anime cons earlier in the year that Everyone had DS's.
Rym: I mean everyone had DS's but Almost all of those people were playing these imported games.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I just wanted to continue.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: I was talking about yesterday with earthbound and how the stupid companies don't bring games over here, but yet Best Buy just about the most mainstream video game selling place you can get.
Scott: next, you know after Walmart is Importing games and selling them for 50 bucks Not 40 or 30 like normal DS game sell for but 50 and people are probably buying them.
Scott: A lot of people are probably buying them.
Rym: Well, it's like when Walden books started selling raw Japanese manga.
Rym: Yeah
Scott: So the question is now it's even dumber for them not to bring something over like earthbound the mother 3 You know call it earthbound DS or whatever because not only would it sell but you could sell it for 50 bucks Because all the people who really want it really want it and everyone else doesn't even know about it.
Rym: Yeah You know, I mean you really don't even have to localize these games and they'll still sell.
Scott: well earthbound You need to localize but jump superstars.
Scott: You don't need to localize that.
Scott: there's barely any text.
Scott: You can't look.
Scott: all you need to localize is the instruction books and people know how to freakin play.
Rym: No one even looks at instruction books anymore.
Scott: Yeah, apparently there's a sticker on these games in the store that says these are imported games.
Scott: Don't worry They work with your American DS.
Scott: go to import facts calm to get information, huh?
Scott: So I went to import facts calm and is a really crap.
Scott: Lee made Standard.
Scott: it looks like a cookie cutter website that has a picture of a DS and a picture of a PSP Which makes me think huh?
Scott: Maybe they're gonna import some PSP games.
Rym: what PSP games are coming out in Japan that aren't coming out here that people care about?
Scott: I have no idea because if I click on the PSP It just is coming soon.
Scott: And if I click on the DS it says Naruto for jump superstars So whatever and there's barely any information about the games there.
Scott: There's like a short blurb that describes the game in only, you know, the most back-of-the-book kind of way.
Rym: Yeah, that's fine because anyone who's gonna buy something like that is already knowing everything they need to know about it.
Scott: Yeah, and there's a little form you can fill out to ask questions about the game.
Scott: But I think they're actually putting this out there in the holiday season is a really good idea because you know A lot of parents go to this like I've seen parents with or without their kids shopping for video games at the store.
Scott: And you know, they don't read video game magazines.
Scott: They don't know what games came out.
Scott: They just look at the covers in the backs of the games and pick one out.
Rym: I have often explained to parents at video game stores what the difference was between a Gameboy and a Diaz.
Scott: Yeah, so when they see jump superstars and Naruto Whatever for all they do is they look at the package and they'll see the characters that their kid likes on the package and they'll Pick that up.
Scott: So and there aren't too many Naruto Dragonball jump superstar type games out in the US to you know, also have those characters on them things of the day.
Rym: This is some scary shit that I got right here for you.
Rym: So we were talking a while ago about it.
Rym: Nothing scares people anymore, at least nothing scares us.
Rym: No media is genuinely frightening anymore the closest thing being HP Lovecraft.
Scott: But I guess if he showed me a real live surgery of someone that's not all their guts cut open.
Scott: It's not scary, but it makes me all queasy.
Scott: Really?
Scott: Yep That's like.
Scott: the only thing that get like gets me in any way like if you start describing Surgeries or talking about deadly illnesses in detail like I'll get all queasy.
Scott: Really yeah, that's the only way to get me.
Scott: You know.
Rym: that explains it because every now and then when I've brought up diseases or things randomly in conversations I never really put two and two together.
Rym: Yeah, I've told you this before Yeah, but I never realized that when I was describing diseases that you were thinking about that sort of thing I always figured it like I'd have to show you a guy's beating heart on YouTube.
Scott: No, it's like I always like.
Scott: imagine myself getting cut open or something.
Scott: I'm like, ooh Like.
Scott: I watched that video with the guy's bicep exploding which is not my thing of the day.
Rym: good but Man, I was like, oh no, I had to close it.
Rym: I've seen a far more horrible video.
Rym: I'm sure there's plenty of a weightlifter who had something else explode.
Rym: I were that guy.
Scott: actually it's weird because like something like that won't really bother me.
Scott: It's only when it gets medical.
Rym: It's like is this go it was medical because then they were trying to figure out how to help this guy.
Scott: See that's when I would have gotten all queasy.
Scott: But yeah, it's like if someone's get like gets their head blown off with like a rocket.
Scott: I'm cool for some reason I don't know why.
Scott: but then if like a doctor tries to reattach like the body part they got blown off then I'm all like.
Rym: So you want to know.
Scott: it's really interesting even though it should be the opposite.
Rym: seeing something bad happen a video or anything Never bothers me like it'll bother me in a logical way like that's horrible, but I don't feel Disgusted or like.
Rym: I don't feel any sort of visceral effect and I don't cry or anything.
Rym: But if I see other people reacting to something that sets me off.
Rym: So if something tragic happens and I see it, I just think oh that was tragic.
Rym: But if I see other people reacting to it, I'll get choked up.
Rym: It's really kind of strange and I was thinking about this actually yesterday and while I was driving home.
Scott: The other thing is if I see a video of like someone getting their guts ripped open by say a bear I'll be I'll be all good.
Scott: But if I see someone in person like I'm standing right there and I see a guy get mauled by a bear Then I'll probably be all vomiting.
Rym: You can't be a pair.
Scott: All right, what are the things of the day?
Scott: All right.
Rym: So this video.
Rym: I'm not even going to bother telling you how I found this and I don't know if any of you have seen It or not.
Rym: I haven't seen it around the internet.
Rym: I might dig it or something just so other people can see this business.
Rym: It's a video done in the 60s to teach people how to ride a bicycle safety Safely.
Rym: now that might not seem so scary.
Rym: You might expect it to be one of those 60s.
Rym: If you turn left without signaling you'll die and then you know gory scenes of teenagers being killed Because that was the style of the times with the onions and everything And not even the belt.
Scott: Yes, it's a style of the time, I understand.
Rym: It is one of those videos.
Rym: In 1957 or 58 Except the intention or the intent if I may.
Rym: This video is one of those except now I'm just gonna describe it and then I'll keep giving you more details.
Rym: Everyone is dressed up as a monkey, but what's the title of the video?
Rym: One got that.
Scott: What does that have to do with bike safety?
Rym: I'll get to that because I wondered that too until I watched the whole video.
Rym: It was it was kind of a almost a Hitchcock twist ending except it was a lame Non Hitchcock at all twist ending.
Scott: so it was corny.
Rym: It was one of those.
Rym: I see what you did there.
Rym: So it's one of those videos, but everyone's dressed up like a monkey.
Rym: when I say dressed up like a monkey I mean, there are normal people who have these basically steel Windy tails looks like bent up rebar sticking out of their butts.
Scott: How did they attach it to their butts?
Rym: like stuck to the back of their pants?
Scott: Okay, so then you shove it up their butt.
Rym: Um, it's not that kind of video.
Scott: It could be it's the 60s.
Scott: It's the style of the time you understand.
Rym: No, it wasn't All right.
Rym: So the only other costume element they have other than these tails because they're otherwise normal people is that they have monkey masks.
Rym: on Grotesque monkey masks.
Rym: they live rotting scary Skeletal monkey mask.
Rym: these things are scary.
Rym: you show this video to a six-year-old and he will cry himself to sleep that night.
Scott: Yeah, this is before the times when they invented modern mask making technologies, you know things like rubber and latex and all that I mean, they're.
Rym: they're kind of like melded with the people's faces But they're all wrinkly all over and scary looking and they're really big So lace.
Rym: their mouths like stick way out and they're grinning like the Joker and in addition their eyes Are really really sunk because it's just the actors eyes in the back.
Rym: so it's like they're.
Rym: they're like zombies skeleton monkeys and Their facial expressions don't change and they're moving this kind of pantomime way.
Rym: This is some scary shit It sure is.
Rym: and then one by one all of them die in horrible ways Riding their bicycles, of course because it's a bike safety video.
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: like one doesn't signal and then he gets hit by a car and then one doesn't see a stop sign and she gets hit By a bigger car one rides on like the wrong side of the road gets run over by a steamroller Yeah, and it just keeps getting worse and worse and worse.
Rym: now The plot is that they all have their lunch all of them have a little lunch bag with the name on it and every time one like they're all Riding along and one guy has all the lunches in his bike because he's the fat kid.
Rym: I guess or he's gonna be the fat kid because he's got all these lunches Mm-hmm, and they're all right.
Rym: And every time one dies it cuts to the lunch bag with the name and it says something like little Billy should have paid attention.
Rym: I'll bet he wishes he had but he doesn't have a second, you know the stuff like that.
Rym: And it finally gets to the end and all the monkeys are dead except for the one who had all the lunches.
Scott: Well the one who is a human.
Rym: Well, you see that's the twist.
Rym: You get to the end and they don't show you the last one's face.
Rym: all the shots are from the back and you know Now he's got everyone's lunches because all the other monkeys died.
Rym: and then he find out he's actually human because he was smart enough to follow All the bike safety rules and as a result, he didn't die.
Rym: a horrible death though He doesn't seem terribly put off by the fact that all of his skeleton zombie monkey friends are dead again.
Scott: Well, apparently they were all idiots.
Scott: So he was kind of glad they died now.
Scott: He's got all their lunches.
Rym: You don't have to watch the whole thing.
Rym: Just look at these Disturbing costumes got damn.
Scott: Yeah, that's the reason we described the whole thing Is so you just look at the costumes and move on.
Scott: god If you watch the whole thing, you'll be frightened beyond belief.
Rym: These things are really creepy.
Rym: I can't stress that enough.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Scott: So my thing of the day is totally unrelated in every possible way.
Scott: There's a dude in Germany he is known as the train rider or the train surfer and what he did is He would jump on the back of a bullet train.
Scott: now You got to understand.
Scott: a bullet train goes about 200 miles an hour if at you know when it's going.
Scott: So I think that's.
Scott: I don't know if that's a top speed or the average speed But it goes really fast faster than any roller coaster you're ever gonna go on.
Scott: and he had this wicked Powerful suction cup like super powerful with a handle on it and he would attach it to the rear window of the train Right before the train started going
Rym: like just before it goes he kind of runs up goes hop up up shoot
Scott: and he suction cups to the back window of the train and he has a rope tied to him and tied to the handle and he rides the back of the train as it goes and It's super crazy.
Scott: Now the twist, I don't know It's not a good twist really and the reason the dude was doing these daring stunts is because he had leukemia And he was gonna die.
Scott: So he spent the last year of his life doing crazy shit riding the backs of trains at crazy high speed.
Rym: Now aside from the fact that this video is absolutely amazing.
Rym: I can't imagine the thrill of what that man was doing.
Scott: Yeah, it's like the only thing master that man that kid was younger than us He was.
Scott: he was born three years after us and he died last year.
Rym: Well this year.
Scott: Yeah, right It'll soon be last year.
Rym: You know, we have some time.
Rym: Yeah, either way I gotta say this guy really embodies almost everything I live for because he knew he was going to die.
Rym: He his life was over.
Rym: There's nothing that could be done.
Rym: and instead of moping about it or whining about it or wasting his last days He decided to live as awesome of a life as he could for as long as he could doing as many Dangerous and amazing things that yeah, cuz he didn't care.
Rym: He had nothing to lose.
Rym: so he figured he might as well just go all out and go all out.
Scott: He did just like Captain Jack.
Rym: I have a lot of respect for this guy and for yeah, this guy's about the same as Captain Jack.
Scott: He's you know in the same page in my book You know guy who was living a crazy lifestyle and died living the crazy lifestyle of awesome
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: but yeah, there's not much you can do on earth to go that fast and drive an f1 car Drive some other crazy car
Rym: jump out of an airplane without a parachute.
Scott: We go 200 miles an hour.
Rym: I think so.
Rym: If you're wearing the right kind of clothes, what's the terminal velocity?
Rym: I don't know and I don't feel like looking it up me either.
Scott: Maybe one of our listeners will yeah There's not much you can do to get that thrill, especially not for so low a price as buying a suction cup Yeah, and some rope.
Rym: yet some rope some rope.
Rym: He also had a little mask on his face.
Scott: Oh, we had a. he had like a bandana to keep his face from getting burned up or hit by bugs and shit.
Rym: I guess probably, you know worried about wind shear and all that.
Scott: Yeah that too.
Scott: He had a little hoodie.
Rym: But really this video is absolutely amazing.
Scott: Yeah way to go guy Rest in peace, I guess.
Rym: So tonight kind of out of the blue we have decided to review an old classic probably an old classic from the 90s An old classic from our days at RIT one of the in my opinion best anime ever made.
Rym: It's in my personal top five and I would put it in a semi objective top 10 or 20 easily.
Rym: Yeah, probably it's a really freaking good show that has a lot going for it.
Scott: It's definitely it's not as good as you know, the greats But it's definitely better than all the average shows.
Rym: putting it up there on the the awesome list I mean really in terms of maybe not best but definitely my favorite not favorite in the sense of you know My favorite shows that speak to me like utenna and captain Tyler and all that.
Rym: But my you know top five list would definitely be in no particular order Cowboy bebop eska flown a Evangelion.
Rym: try gun.
Rym: and usually the fifth spot is whatever show I liked most recently.
Scott: Yeah, so try gun.
Scott: Let's see what we got a lot of stuff to say about.
Scott: try gun.
Scott: Yeah, we've seen the whole show.
Scott: I've read a lot of the manga but not all of it.
Rym: I've read enough of the mom.
Scott: You don't need to read much of the manga.
Scott: We'll talk about that later.
Scott: I met the guy who invent who created try gun night.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Yes the hero night.
Scott: Oh Yeah, lots of stuff.
Rym: so we'll talk a bit about the origin of try gun and we'll just kind of go from there.
Rym: I mean, it was originally a manga by Naito.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: And okay, there's a trick with the manga.
Scott: It was originally a manga by Naito published in one magazine and then that magazine got cancelled.
Scott: So then he restarted try gun in another magazine But he called it try gun maximum.
Scott: and that's why if you try to buy the manga It's like two volumes that are like the gold and the silver volumes.
Scott: That's the original deal.
Scott: then this try gun maximum which comes after that.
Rym: now, I'll say pretty much straight up Don't bother with the manga I'm really serious.
Scott: Yeah, if you're really curious you can get the gold and the silver whatever.
Scott: but don't bother with try gun Maximum unless you're crazy.
Rym: I mean you'll learn a lot because there are elements of the show that we're kind of glossed over or Altered and by reading the manga or at least flipping through the manga You can fill in a lot of the details as to what was specifically actually going on.
Rym: Yeah, but the manga itself much like the Sailor Moon manga is not incomprehensible.
Rym: It's fucking incomprehensible.
Scott: Oh, it is totally Impossible to understand what the hell is going on.
Rym: in parts of the mug It's just there's panels and there's stuff in him and I can't for the life of me figure out what's actually going on And I would go ten pages at a time not even knowing who was in the scene.
Rym: Let alone what was happening.
Scott: Yeah, you'll see like a fight scene right and the fight scene will be say three pages and each panel will have someone shooting Someone getting shot, you know someone hating someone with something but you can't tell where they are.
Scott: You can't tell who's fighting who who's on what side especially if it's more than a two-sided fight.
Scott: You can't tell who just hit who with what.
Scott: it's totally crazy.
Scott: And then when you basically had to skip over it I mean, it looks pretty cool, but the skip over it get to the end of the fight and then you're like, okay What just happened?
Rym: Yeah, and then there's the one guy who was made of midgets.
Scott: Yeah, it's it's really just out of control If you're if you like the anime and you really want to read the manga?
Scott: No, don't read try gun maximum.
Scott: Just get the gold and the silver if you're gonna get anything at all.
Rym: Which get the manga if you're a try gun nut if you're the kind of person who would say try gun is my favorite anime Ever buy the manga.
Rym: Otherwise, I I'm serious.
Rym: It's probably okay to skip this.
Rym: You're not missing much.
Scott: Yeah I'm just saying the gold and the silver volumes are like 50% craziness and the maximum is the hundred percent craziness.
Rym: It's maximum crazy.
Scott: That's why they change the name like that.
Rym: So when we talk I mean the story.
Rym: the basic story is pretty much the same but we're gonna talk about it almost entirely from the perspective of the anime because that's What makes try gun shine to me?
Rym: Try gun was a mediocre manga that was somehow miraculously turned into a very amazing anime.
Scott: Yeah, well because the characters and the Basic plot of the manga are really really good.
Scott: the thing is the specific way things turn out in the manga and the order in which they any order and timing of which when things are revealed and when things happen isn't so good.
Scott: and there's a lot of extra characters that are useless or silly or Just pointless.
Rym: Yeah, the anime also goes to great lengths to kind of condense the plot make it sensical take out elements of the story that were usually kind of gratuitous or stupid and replace them with really meaningful or Elucidating stuff.
Scott: Yeah, it's like in the manga.
Scott: There'll be stuff that you just know all the time but then in the anime, they'll reveal this stuff to you like way near the end like So it's a totally different thing.
Scott: Even though what's happening is the same you get a totally different effect now.
Rym: because of that I normally wouldn't really mention anyone other than the director when I talk about an anime.
Rym: but Yosuke Kuroda who wrote the or at least he did the script for the Try Gun anime did a pretty phenomenal job.
Rym: I'd say yeah, he.
Rym: I think he is one of the big points in making this shine.
Rym: If you look I'm not gonna list it, but he wrote scripts and did screenplays for a whole boatload of anime.
Scott: Yeah, the director of Try Gun.
Scott: It's kind of weird that this guy is done.
Scott: Basically Nothing else of note whatsoever.
Scott: He's just some useless.
Scott: Well, he's not completely much Satoshi Nishimura.
Scott: Yeah, he's basically done nothing.
Scott: He's directed one other thing that no one cares about and he did storyboards and key animations there.
Scott: But yeah, somehow he was the director of Try Gun and he did a good job.
Rym: But also I mean Naito who wrote Try Gun.
Rym: the only other thing he's done is more Try Gun and Gun Grave.
Scott: Yeah, the Yasuhiro Naito the only things he's done in his life are create the Try Gun manga.
Scott: He helped design stuff for the gun grave video game and he helped design stuff for the gun grave anime.
Scott: That's all he's ever done.
Rym: Well, he went to Otakon and shook your hand.
Scott: Yeah, I met him at Otakon.
Scott: He's a quiet Japanese dude who doesn't know English.
Rym: now Try Gun is also One of those kind of deceptive shows if you start watching it because at least a lot of people have different tests.
Rym: but back in the day when we were at RIT the test of any show was four episodes or the first DVD whichever was longer and The first four episodes of Try Gun are very different from the rest of the show.
Rym: the show starts out very loud-hearted and gets progressively darker and darker and darker and darker and it just doesn't stop getting darker and it gets really preachy and serious but in a good way and There's a lot to it that if you just saw the first few episodes you have no idea what to expect.
Scott: Yeah, the basic premise of Try Gun is that there's this guy.
Scott: Well, there's these two insurance agents and they are.
Scott: there's one girl Millie and the other one is yeah It doesn't matter.
Scott: I forget their name.
Scott: We'll talk about.
Scott: it's been a while.
Rym: We'll talk about a lot of these things when we do the Try Gun spoilers episode because I have a lot to say about Try Gun that I can't tonight.
Scott: Yeah, I'm only doing the basics.
Scott: and at the setup here is you have these two insurance agents And there's an outlaw named Vash the stampede.
Scott: anyone who says Vash come over to my house.
Scott: I'll kick you in the nuts.
Rym: Now he's also.
Rym: he has many nicknames including the humanoid typhoon.
Scott: Yep Now no one knows who this guy is But supposedly he like destroys cities and he freaking.
Scott: he's just a crazy most dangerous man alive.
Scott: No one can take him.
Rym: the insurance agents are looking for him because they work for an insurance company that's taking a bath on his damage.
Scott: Yeah, so what they want to do is supposedly these are two badass insurance agents sort of like master Keaton of the olden days and they are going to find him and Prevent him from causing more damage to keep the insurance company in business
Rym: or at least document the damages He causes.
Scott: yep That way if anyone tries to make a claim Saying it was Vash the stampede when it wasn't the insurance company won't have to pay out.
Rym: now Vash the stampede You don't.
Rym: I mean you can guess who he is in the show and everyone knows who he is because Vash is a very Iconic anime character.
Rym: these days you see at least 10 or 15 Vash cosplayers than any major anime.
Scott: It's one of those obvious secrets where in the first episode There's a crazy guy wearing a bit a long red trench coat and he has this yellow spiky hair and he's obviously really important, but he acts like a total doofus and he doesn't say who he is.
Scott: and You totally being a viewer, you know, he's Vash the stampede.
Scott: You just know that's not a spoiler You fucking know unless you're an idiot, but they never tell you for sure Only ever 99% sure until like the fifth or sixth episode.
Rym: Yeah, I mean seriously for the first few episodes.
Rym: It really is kind of a plot thing of is he really Vash the stampede or is he just pretending to be Vash the stampede?
Rym: There is a lot of evidence until you see more that yeah He's just some guy pretending to get free money and free doughnuts and stuff.
Scott: Yeah This is sort of why you want to watch the anime and ignore the manga because if you see the manga the manga doesn't do That.
Scott: the manga is like.
Scott: here is Vash the stampede.
Scott: It's sort of boring But the anime does something like that holding information from you.
Rym: So yeah, the insurance agents find this guy.
Rym: They're not sure if he's Vash or not at all.
Scott: So they have no idea.
Rym: They follow him around because they have nowhere else to go and this is the best lead they've got.
Rym: and maybe This'll draw Vash out and they have hilarious adventures.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, it's basically it's monster of the week for a little while.
Scott: You know go someplace new.
Scott: There's a bad guy.
Scott: They get out of a tough situation.
Scott: go someplace new.
Scott: There's a bad guy to get out of a tough situation.
Rym: Now the other operative thing here is that aside from all that Vash has what a 60 billion double dollar?
Rym: Bounty on his head.
Scott: so people if they find out who Vash the stampede is They immediately want to arrest him and bring him in to get 60 billion double dollar.
Rym: So pretty much everyone in the world is after Vash the stampede.
Rym: and if this guy really is Vash the stampede He's really kind of a doofus, but yet not really.
Rym: I mean we talked about master Keaton and you know master Keaton was kind of a doofus But he was actually badass or irresponsible captain Tyler who was kind of a deuce doofus, but he was actually really bad.
Scott: Yo, yeah captain Tyler was it was more of a Badass by accident.
Scott: Whereas Vash the stampede is clearly badass not by accident.
Rym: Well early on it's not a hundred percent obvious.
Scott: Yeah, that's another thing is they don't let you on but then you know like something will happen even in the first episode.
Rym: So a couple things happen and you wonder did he do that on purpose or did that just happen?
Rym: Was that important or not?
Rym: I can't tell.
Scott: yeah another thing eat and try gun.
Scott: He has a gun this and it's like this big freakin giant gun this big-ass revolver And he doesn't use it at all Until like many many episodes in like I say I think at the fifth episode he uses it.
Scott: I don't even remember if And that you totally like wonder.
Scott: hey that guy hasn't used his gun and they make note of it And then when he finally uses it, it's like whoa, he used it.
Scott: Holy crap.
Rym: Now we've talked a bit about you know, the quote-unquote plot of try gun.
Rym: Here is what the actual plot is.
Rym: as far as I can go without spoiling things Vash the stampede is a Semi superhuman badass.
Rym: there is something up with his past that makes him Incredibly badass which becomes more and more apparent as the show goes on.
Rym: He is also Committed unto death a pacifist.
Rym: He will not kill anyone for any reason ever.
Scott: He won't even kill animals or anything.
Rym: He is more opposed to Death and suicide and murder than he is to anything to the point that he would rather take a bullet From someone trying to kill him then even risk hurting someone to the point that they would die.
Scott: Yeah, he has no problems hurting people to prevent them from killing, you know He'll freakin.
Scott: he has no problem damaging property either, you know If he can knock down a building to save one life, he'll just do it in a second like boom There's.
Scott: the building is knocked down.
Scott: now He doesn't care.
Rym: following this concept and everything we've told you this sounds like a romp.
Rym: You've got this badass guy with a gun.
Scott: He could just kill everyone if you wanted to.
Rym: who's afraid to kill anyone?
Rym: as a result He gets into these really bad situations and hilarity ensues.
Rym: You've got these insurance agents.
Rym: You've got this bounty.
Rym: You've got all these crazy characters in this world all over the place going after Vash going after each other blowing stuff up.
Rym: It's absolutely hilarious and crazy.
Scott: Yeah Cuz you see him get stuck in a hostage situation And there's crazy killers coming in with crazy weapons and rockets and guns and he's got to find a way to stop them from killing Anyone without killing them because if he wanted to he could just shoot them all.
Scott: but no He's got to do it in some clever and crazy way and that's what makes every episode of the show Awesome.
Scott: now is regardless of the overall plot you have this incredibly interesting Monster of the week solution to find out now after a few episodes.
Rym: They're hardly ever monsters because it doesn't take that long.
Rym: the show fairly quickly Takes a very dramatic turn and it starts hinting at it bit by bit.
Rym: He meets this priest named wolf wood who for various reasons is a gunslinger like Vash But unlike Vash is not a pacifist and he's actually.
Rym: he's a good man, but he will kill people to save other people Mm-hmm, and all these other characters come and go but there's a point at which the show Very suddenly and very dramatically takes a turn from which it never recovers.
Scott: Yeah It's a 26 episode show and in the 17th episode they reveal to you basically everything like.
Scott: you'll start the episode 17 and you will not realize this is an episode of trygun.
Scott: You'll say hey, what's wrong?
Scott: What this isn't look like trygun to me.
Scott: and then it is and you go.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, there's two points I really want to talk about because these are kind of the two linchpins where you start to think.
Rym: the first one you think Wow This show isn't really what I expected.
Rym: and then the second point where you don't even know what to say.
Rym: Yeah, cuz it's silly and silly and silly.
Rym: and then he gets on this train this land train.
Scott: It's kind of like a cruise ship or a train but it goes over more like a cruise ship That doesn't have tracks and it goes across the desert.
Rym: Yeah, but it's very like.
Rym: it's kind of hard to control all this.
Rym: whatever it's this big thing.
Rym: think the Titanic in a desert and He's on it.
Rym: and simultaneously this terrorist thief guy what dynamite neon something Dynamo, whatever is whatever the hell is awesome.
Rym: regardless this crazy terrorist thief guy Hijacks it to try to get all the money, you know, basically Robin out of the safe.
Scott: There's a big safe on the thing.
Rym: open the safe.
Rym: So he decides he's going to turn the engines all the way up hold everyone hostage Ram this thing into the wall of a cliff thus Busting it up killing everyone on it opening the giant safe and then he can loot it at his leisure.
Rym: Yeah now You think all right Vashj is gonna fight this crazy guy all on his own and he meets this little kid and there's gonna be This all sort of hilarious fight.
Rym: and but the thing is as he's trying to save these people He starts he gets in situations where you know a guard or one of these Hijackers is there and the easy solution would be just kill him and everything would be fine, but he hesitates.
Rym: He won't kill.
Rym: In fact at one point he accidentally shoots one of them and wastes time Sitting there bandaging them and trying to do everything you can to make sure they don't die.
Rym: and he gets shot a couple times Because he's so averse to killing that he really can't do this.
Rym: Yeah, and I mean I can't.
Rym: I'm not gonna ruin what happens in the fight.
Rym: It's probably obvious that he doesn't die because he's in pretty much the whole show But the show starts taking a turn.
Rym: you start seeing that wow His lifestyle of being a pacifist gunfighter really isn't working out so well and isn't so easy.
Scott: Nope, the other thing about Trigun that's really interesting and awesome is the setting.
Scott: the setting is badass.
Scott: What you've got basically is a giant desert Wild West world, but there's a bit of more modern technology sort of steampunk ish Sort of electricity sort of.
Rym: yeah, there's a lot of old lost technology.
Rym: you get a very long past post-apocalyptic setting yeah.
Scott: And you see these giant light bulbs Everywhere and they start referring to them and apparent you realize that these giant light bulbs are where all the stuff comes from to maintain Human life because there's no water or anything, you know, it all comes from these giant light bulbs.
Rym: I mean people find old technology and adapt it and there's kind of this mishmash of ancient misunderstood, but very powerful technology and The piddly crap that humans have actually been able to come with since whatever apocalypse happened long ago.
Scott: Yeah It's all.
Scott: it's mostly Wild West.
Scott: and then you'll see like a giant crazy gun that shoots Whacked out stun bolt
Rym: and you'll start picking up along the way that Vash seems to know a lot about this Technology from the ancient past
Scott: a lot more than other people do
Rym: and he also has some of it.
Rym: Yeah, that you like he'll do things that seem like magic and then you start to people notice that he's got this technology That might as well be magic as far as anyone else is concerned.
Scott: Yeah, it's just really interesting Setting because it's post-apocalyptic Western desert steampunk technology.
Rym: way cool now I said that the show has two points where it takes turns and I already talked about the first one.
Rym: now up until this Anyone who has actually opposed Vash or tried to hurt him or hurt people around him has been very swiftly dispatched.
Rym: Vash just steamrollers through anyone.
Scott: It's sort of like initial D where he wins he wins he wins he wins he wins.
Rym: and then there's an episode Near the middle where a guy not to reveal any story But there is a man who goes to a city and starts indiscriminately killing people left and right murdering people in cold blood.
Rym: Oh, yeah that part and Vash is trying to save these people and he can't.
Rym: people are dying and there's almost nothing he can do.
Rym: He's doing everything he can to get out of this city and the guy Realizes that the best way to draw Vash out is just to start murdering people and then Vash loses it.
Rym: And he there's the scene where Vash takes this guy out and he's got him on the ground and he's got a gun in his Mouth.
Rym: and Vash you can see that he wants to pull the trigger.
Rym: He really wants to pull the trigger and he's just screaming over and over again.
Rym: You killed them.
Rym: They're dead.
Rym: They can't come back hot.
Rym: I should kill you.
Rym: There's no reason why I shouldn't kill you.
Rym: and it this scene is.
Rym: It might sound silly especially as silly as the show may sound but starting at this point That is a chilling scene.
Scott: I think that's like episode 13. ish Yeah 11, 12, 13.
Rym: that is one of the most chilling like spine tingling scenes I've seen in anime.
Scott: Yeah So the show starts to get dark like up until then.
Scott: Crazy stuff happens and you get the idea of you know, what people's feelings are and the characters are developed.
Scott: But it hasn't actually gotten dark yet.
Scott: This is like sudden darkness Like there's even a scene I think at the end of one of the episodes or like dark and Vash is there with like these Blue glowing eyes and it's all kind of whoa.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yes, but it starts with this one scene.
Rym: It is just I say chilling over and over but this if you haven't seen the show before you'll get to this point And I almost guarantee that you'll shiver a little bit when that happens and Vash is there with this guy And all these people are dead.
Rym: Yep, and from there the show becomes Absolutely amazing.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Now the ending.
Scott: some people have different opinions of the ending, you know It's it.
Scott: it really depends on what you wanted to happen.
Scott: What did happen?
Rym: Well, there's also I mean there are several kind of plot linchpins near the end of the show where I mean I can't ruin this at all.
Rym: No, I will say that there is a scene in the show.
Rym: it is famous among the front row crew because we watched all of try gun as like 320 by 200 real video Fan subs with separate subtitle tracks in Scott's dorm room a long time ago.
Rym: And there is an episode where something a character dies Mm-hmm a character dies and it is widely regarded among anime fans as one of the most well-written And well-acted death scenes in the history of anime.
Rym: I'm sure anime world order will come up with other ones But I don't think anyone can disagree with me that this is a very very well done death scene.
Scott: The thing is I don't think it happens that way in the manga whatever.
Rym: Yeah Forget the manga.
Rym: Yeah, forget it, but we're all guys like you're manly at freshman in college The world is our oyster and we're at a tech school and we're all standing around and we all know each other.
Rym: We're not really close friends yet.
Rym: The front row crew is burgeoning it hasn't quite blossomed yet and We're all standing there and the scene happens and everyone's just kind of really quiet.
Rym: and finally like I think Someone turns to me and I look and I see that they've got Tears in their eyes and I've got tears in my eyes.
Rym: We were all crying I'm not.
Rym: we were all seriously crying and trying to hide it from each other and then we all Realized that we were all crying and then we all started crying.
Rym: So happens and then I think like some I think your roommate was in the room or he walked in and he was like why?
Rym: Yeah, he was just a soccer dude Yeah, but he walks in all these guys watching this tiny cartoon and crying their eyes out.
Rym: Yep But I to this day if I even hear the song that plays during that death scene I get kind of emotional.
Rym: I tear up a little bit.
Rym: That's a really powerful scene.
Rym: The show really.
Rym: the issues at stake are actually very simple.
Rym: It has to do with what motivates people to live.
Rym: what motivates people to kill is Killing right.
Rym: Is it ever morally acceptable to kill someone and you keep like Vashil be put in more and more situations?
Rym: I could kill this one person to save this one person.
Rym: I could kill this one person to save these ten people.
Rym: I could kill this one person to save every other human being on this planet.
Rym: yep, and Vashil's boss is a pacifist.
Rym: He does not want to kill and this is a very difficult and almost untenable position.
Scott: And the big metaphor they use the whole show is like should you kill the spider to save?
Scott: You know the fly that's caught in its web or should you not you know?
Rym: Yeah Which is made to very stupid melodramatic effect in an otherwise very popular anime music video done to this show.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, one of those videos that ends with a bunch of text like that Video.
Scott: if that music video took out its text captions to be a lot better Yeah, anyway.
Rym: But I mean the show really gets into a lot of very deep issues and doesn't give you easy answers.
Rym: a lot of shows will pose a question like is it okay to kill?
Scott: or yeah like a Gundam show?
Scott: a Gundam show will say is it you know?
Scott: Should you protect your friends and shoot at your other friends at the end?
Scott: It says no everyone gets along and war is bad.
Rym: Yeah, I mean the morals are very simple or even if they're complex a lot of shows tend to give you a very direct answer At the end like
Scott: even if you don't like the answer they might give you an answer you disagree with But they give you an answer.
Scott: that is the opinion of the creators.
Rym: Trigon's answers are very up in the air Very half and half and very uncomfortable.
Scott: I think that's sort of why people don't like the ending so much.
Scott: I mean not it's not a solid.
Scott: is the answer?
Scott: yay It's.
Rym: I mean depending on how you look at it the show says two very very important and controversial things that are directly opposed.
Rym: It says that you shouldn't ever kill ever and that killing another sentient being is never the answer to a problem.
Rym: And at the same time it is saying that that position is Entirely untenable and will cause far more suffering in the world than then not then killing a single person could ever do Yep, and it doesn't really say which way is the right way Don't don't?
Rym: I have my opinion as to what it's saying.
Rym: I can't back that up without spoiling the entire show or asking some Japanese people.
Scott: See I think that's part of what makes the anime so cool.
Scott: Is that it's?
Scott: basically they took the characters and the setting from this manga and the manga had none of this message.
Scott: I mean you might be able to say it does but it fucking doesn't.
Scott: it's just action.
Scott: and whatever The
Rym: manga is gunslingers shoot wild
Scott: west steampunk craziness God knows and then they somehow take those characters and redesign them a little bit and they take the setting and they simplify it a bit and they take the part of the plot and a few of the like.
Scott: You know one-off little separate storylines in the manga like a few of the early episodes are actually Sort of like just single chapters from the manga expanded to a 20-something minute episode You know.
Scott: and they somehow take all that and they add so much to it and shift it around Into something that actually doesn't suck.
Scott: usually people take like a great manga and they'll either make like a direct translation to an anime.
Scott: or They'll leave stuff out in the anime or they'll change it in the anime and it doesn't turn out as well.
Scott: You know The only other example I can think of that does it as nicely as trygun is initial D Where they change the order of like a bunch of the races for the first season of the anime to actually increase the dramatic Effect instead of decrease it.
Rym: So if you've never seen trygun or if you stopped watching it after the first three episodes seem like just a generic comedy I highly recommend just watch the first 12 or 13 episodes.
Rym: If you I mean, it's not that hard to get a hold of if you can Netflix it you can buy it super cheap.
Scott: Yeah, you could buy this thing super cheap.
Scott: now a genie on I think is still putting it out and they have like super Special cheapo like anime watchers choice DVDs that are stupid cheap.
Rym: I Can't recommend this show highly enough.
Rym: It is dead seriously one of my top five anime and I don't think anyone can watch this show Without at least tearing up a little bit.
Scott: No, not the whole thing.
Rym: Yeah, not the whole thing.
Scott: You could be a cruel heartless bastard, but you could have seen it already and then it won't.
Rym: probably won't work on you Yeah, or someone could have spoiled a bunch of things for you.
Scott: Oh, it says let's see Looking on Amazon.
Scott: You can get the whole thing for $70.
Scott: That's a little bit steep.
Rym: Yeah, I'd Netflix it if anything.
Rym: Yeah
Scott: Netflix is definitely a way to go because Another thing is if you even if you don't like the serious part of the show The first four episodes are really funny like there's a lot of hilarity going on early in the show This joke after joke of you know crazy stuff happening.
Scott: You know as this guy does this guy's acting like a doofus and doing wacky shit to get out of crazy situations.
Scott: But the bad guys are all like comically Strange.
Rym: it's like miss critical moment only with a gun.
Scott: Yeah, it's.
Scott: it's very funny Especially the ensure a lot of the supporting cast is comical early on.
Rym: Just remember that the show is not all that it seems and you will very quickly be drawn into a very deep very complex discussion on the nature of pacifism and life.
Rym: And it's also if you watch long enough.
Rym: the show is hard science fiction.
Rym: That's all I'm going to say because to do anything else would spoil a lot in the future.
Rym: We are going to do another episode on Tragen where we'll talk about all the spoiler points because I have very Specific views on what this show was about and what I think it was trying to say and I would really like to talk about That.
Rym: well, you'll get your chance someday someday some but I want to give all of our listeners a chance to watch the show.
Rym: cuz while I Sometimes agree with Dave and Joel's fast karate for the gentlemen statute of limitations on spoilers at the same time It's not worth it to spoil the show for anyone.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm.
Scott: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.