Scott: It's Wednesday September 13th, and this is GeekNights.
Scott: tonight We continue origins week with the story of how we discovered the anons.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: Know what I did today at work play DDR play DDR at work, so you actually pulled it off this time.
Scott: yep That's what I did.
Scott: I installed me a nice step mania on the work laptop and a bunch of songs Pretty much first mix through eighth mix and a whole bunch of the side mixes and oh yeah I got down for about an hour,
Rym: so you didn't do the other thing you've been known to do at work when no one's there.
Scott: No, no, I didn't I've just I just played some DDR.
Scott: I think I'm gonna play DDR for like an hour work every day and to become the master again because I have no longer the Master I don't know.
Rym: you seem to pick it up pretty quick.
Scott: and Wildwood when we played for three days straight Yeah, I did pick it up when he in Wildwood we play for three days straight.
Scott: however I was not up to my previous level of awesomeness.
Scott: You know we're Maniac on everything so we're gonna get back up to that level of awesomeness and hopefully beyond that way when I go to the Wildwood will just be like yeah, Oni mode whatever and I've got all the songs for that.
Scott: I got the max 300s and all that jazz, so I'm gonna go for it.
Rym: Yeah We'll see.
Rym: cuz I know that it took me a good month of solid practice to be able to pass the trick version of all Those max.
Scott: oh yeah, I think an hour every day is plenty.
Scott: an hour five days a week.
Rym: I think you should work on dropout.
Rym: first.
Scott: I'm headed there.
Scott: I was too busy playing music and going yes.
Rym: Yes, yes See if only the floor in our house wasn't so absolutely flimsy we could play DDR every day.
Scott: Yeah, yeah That's that's what we do.
Rym: And you know they used to be an arcade with fourth and fifth mix right here But now there isn't.
Rym: yeah it went out of business about a month before you moved in Awesome.
Rym: I used to play there almost every day.
Scott: If only we had known we could have bought their machine and put it in our house at the shaky floor And they would have crashed into the base.
Rym: No, you know we would have done.
Rym: We would have put it on the back deck with a canopy over it.
Scott: Yeah, cuz that works so well for our bikes.
Rym: just your bike.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, yeah, you got some news.
Scott: I do indeed.
Scott: I'm gonna appease some underwear perverts.
Scott: I'm gonna give an underwear pervert news sort of an underwear pervert news actually.
Scott: It's about a comic.
Rym: I read all right.
Scott: There is a comic called runaways.
Scott: It is awesome.
Scott: You should read it.
Scott: It's about These kids where they're.
Scott: they discovered that the parents were horrible evil supervillains, so they ran away.
Scott: yeah, and It's cool.
Scott: And it's been written until from issues like up to issue 24 by a man named Brian K Vaughn who has never written a bad comic in his life.
Scott: I pretty much buy every single thing He writes ever and it is awesome.
Scott: But they announced that as of issue 20 issue 24 would be his last issue and everyone went.
Scott: no No They're the guy who was the best writer is writing one last comic.
Scott: no now you know You know people like me and some of our friends.
Scott: You know who also read it.
Scott: we're kind of like a. what do we do now?
Scott: and then they announced the new writer and It didn't excite me as much as I know.
Scott: it excites everyone else.
Scott: But it's that that their Joss Whedon guy is gonna write.
Scott: really yeah, really really yeah, really oh really Yes, really see.
Rym: I don't know why you don't like fireflies so much?
Scott: pretty much.
Scott: I've never read the guys comics.
Scott: I know he writes that astonishing x-men comic, but I don't like any of his TV shows so much.
Scott: So I'll probably buy like issue 25 which is his first issue to see.
Rym: well see it depends because I love Firefly.
Rym: it's probably one of my favorite shows ever made, but I really didn't like Buffy and There was one scene in all of angel that was even worth noting.
Scott: Yeah, I pretty much have the same opinion of all that stuff.
Scott: Is that it's not bad?
Scott: It's not like going to watch a bad like Bono's It's not Manos the hands of fate bad or the head gray digital target bad fucking awesome.
Scott: I know It's not bad like MD guys, but it's just not.
Scott: it doesn't make me feel like yay.
Scott: I want to watch it.
Scott: It's just kind of a show yeah, except.
Rym: I've noticed you say that about just about everything.
Scott: yeah, yeah most stuff sucks Including that stuff.
Rym: see I don't know how you can be such a crotchety old man.
Scott: I'm not a crotchety old man.
Rym: if you complain about everything.
Scott: no I don't.
Rym: well We'll be sitting there watching like Arrested Development And you'll be laughing hysterically and then when we're done watching you'll say that was all right because it was kind of man.
Scott: It's an okay show.
Scott: get off my lawn.
Scott: It's a better show than fireflies.
Rym: get off my lot.
Rym: You realize you probably pissed off every single one of our listeners.
Scott: anyway the point is is that this is really twice.
Rym: No, yes, you did.
Scott: What did I say to?
Rym: I said the point is is that?
Rym: Do I have to go back and play it for you?
Scott: It's not the point.
Rym: that was the point.
Rym: He's a no Killarney in the forums who has pointed out not only every mispronunciation we've had.
Scott: yeah, what was that?
Scott: what learn?
Scott: What's wrong with saying lure?
Scott: It's lure.
Rym: He got me for saying asbestos instead of as asbestos.
Scott: no he got.
Scott: the correct pronunciation is asbestos and not as best dose.
Rym: you realize that Most people say it the latter way.
Scott: I say it either way like or sometimes.
Scott: I say lure sometimes.
Scott: I say lure.
Rym: I'm lure.
Rym: ruler of planet Omicron Persei.
Scott: There's.
Scott: there's a difference between a pronunciation like that like lure and lure which is sort of a dialect type of thing.
Rym: That's the point.
Scott: I tried to make and there's another kind of mispronunciation.
Scott: Which is like the o-taken or As opposed to o-taken.
Scott: it's like this you know that is a Mispronunciation whereas lure is like a dialect change you know.
Rym: but in the very least he did get us a couple times when we tried To pronounce the name of that bacteria.
Scott: Yeah, well I knew the correct.
Rym: when I see We still said it wrong.
Scott: you said it wrong.
Scott: I knew the name of the bacteria.
Rym: all right lure.
Scott: Yeah, it's right.
Scott: anyway.
Scott: I think this is gonna be good for this comic either way because even if at the worst case scenario He completely screws up this comic At least the attention from his fame will bring people in to read the comic and they'll go and pick up the awesome 24-plus issues that the guy the good guy wrote.
Rym: I can say with certainty that Kremlin in the forums will buy every comic that has Joss Whedon's name.
Scott: Oh, yeah, he already knows the the score with this.
Scott: You know I was talking about it.
Scott: Oh, I was trying to hinted that before but you missed it.
Rym: fancy though because I actually wasn't paying attention.
Rym: I was pulling a Michael Godot, and I was busy reading a computer screen.
Scott: I actually have like the first five this.
Scott: actually the best thing about runway runaways is that they print it in the digest.
Scott: I mean they don't only print it in the digest, but they do so.
Scott: it's like little manga books So it's happy to read.
Scott: if you know you're not into the underwear perverts.
Scott: You can pretend.
Rym: It's a manga in color Alright, so there's this news.
Rym: It's been going around.
Rym: I saw it all over far can?
Rym: people were talking about it on dig and It would have been news by itself.
Rym: the headline was IT people are twice as likely to wear heavy metal t-shirts.
Scott: I believe it alright.
Rym: I thought this is gonna be some interesting demographics and everyone's talking about it.
Rym: I'll talk about it, too.
Rym: It'll be my news because I went in.
Rym: they talked about how IT people are more likely to wear Black jeans more likely to have ponytails, and I'm thinking this really kind of describes me, and I'm an IT guy.
Scott: Hey, basically the article said the stereotype is true.
Rym: behold alright now That if that was it that would have been it and I would have talked a little bit about.
Rym: you know they talk about things Like yeah, IT people are in the news today people from urban areas more likely to enjoy Hip-hop music, but it had stuff like.
Rym: IT people are more likely than business people to carry both cars both a Maglite and a Leatherman.
Scott: I only reason I'm a Leatherman is because too much money.
Rym: I Had a Gerber which is basically the same thing as a Leatherman, but someone at IBM stole it.
Scott: But maybe I'll just shell out and buy one one of these days.
Rym: So if any of you from IBM are listening, and you took my Leatherman, I want it back Because I know a lot of you listen.
Rym: Actually the thing is all the people who listen.
Rym: I know they didn't steal it yeah because they were actually pretty smart anyway.
Rym: Now that would have been it.
Rym: But no it appears that no one on the internet actually read this article about IT people having long hair and ponytails and crap.
Rym: Because one.
Rym: it was on small business IT world, but it just has a blurb there And it links to intermediate net where the actual article lies now.
Rym: intermediate net looks like a hosting company.
Scott: Intermedia tenant is a hosting company.
Scott: why host exchange servers?
Rym: host exchange server now?
Scott: Why would a hosting company put a news story on its website?
Scott: that makes no sense.
Scott: now
Rym: even better It seems like a lot of the articles of small business IT world are like this They look like an article and the blurb looks like an article But if you follow it it goes to some company's bullshit website that has some bullshit article on it that starts out.
Rym: I mean this article starts out.
Rym: given all these facts.
Rym: I people type people do this and IT people do that and business people do this and that.
Rym: and here's some data.
Scott: But intermingled sounds like a stand-up comedy routine.
Scott: That's all racist like white man Dude, it's a black man do that and a Spanish guy do this but intermingled and all that are all of these little bits like blah blah blah blah blah.
Rym: intermediate nets gold certified Microsoft blah blah blah.
Rym: team was comforted by the news blah blah or.
Rym: Many people are implementing Microsoft Exchange hosted environments blah blah blah and it's nice to know their customer demographics.
Rym: and If you haven't figured out by now, the article is complete horseshit.
Rym: It is nothing more than a classic marketing ploy where the company takes some sort of news that they know the people they want to target would be interested in and They make up news about it.
Rym: Then the news is actually just effectively a press release or ad copy about their company.
Scott: You think that the hackers would be able to recognize the Trojan horse by now.
Rym: then they submit it to some other site like small Business IT world and then they submit it on that site to somewhere like dig.
Rym: or maybe rollin pig Paley's blog Or maybe he's some here Gupta.
Scott: ah summer Gupta probably my favorite we should do an episode on some mere good.
Rym: We could have Samir Gupta week.
Rym: All right, it's an aside.
Scott: if you don't don't it takes too long.
Rym: I'm gonna say is if you want to know ahead of time Google around for a man named Samir Gupta spelled the way you'd Think an Indian man's name Sam.
Scott: I are Gupta.
Scott: Yes, GU PTA Samir Gupta.
Rym: We have things to say about him.
Rym: we do indeed, but this is such a classic Obvious marketing ploy and the thing is this particular one isn't even done.
Rym: Well at all.
Rym: It's so obvious if you read the article.
Rym: But from what I can gather no one read the article and everyone's talking about this like it's actually news.
Scott: News stereotype is true.
Scott: No news companies are putting articles on their websites that are actually ads and then getting people to link to them.
Rym: so I implore all of you if you see someone talking about this news about how IT people wear heavy metal shirts as Awesome as that idea may be Hit them and tell them that they're wrong and that this is just some company's scam to trick people into using Microsoft Exchange through them,
Scott: you know I actually kind of blame Google because the thing is with Google is most people you search the internet with Google and you only show up in a high rank on Google if a lot of people link to you and in addition to that if you have a high rank on Google.
Scott: that's gonna result in a lot of money.
Scott: if you're a company because You're gonna get a lot of people visiting So no one's gonna link to just a hosting company.
Scott: I mean, what reason do they have to link to the hosting company's website?
Scott: Not much.
Scott: So companies that normally would just put up a website for themselves are now putting things on their website like fake articles that are actually Ads and such in order to get links to those things to get their own Google rank up.
Rym: You know the sad thing is our Google rank at least for the forums on from recruit comm is Crazy insane and we haven't done anything.
Scott: Well can see the thing is all that search engine optimization stuff is pretty much like hey if you do this You Google rank will go up.
Scott: Hey, if you do this your Google rank will go up.
Scott: But the thing is if you actually look at the most, you know modern search engine optimization things.
Scott: All of them involve making your bullshit spam site You know seem to the Google bot like it's more legitimate.
Scott: if you're just legitimate You don't have to do anything because the Google bot is built to recognize and respect and pump up legitimate good websites.
Scott: So if you run a good legitimate website, your Google rank is gonna get pumped up.
Rym: Yeah And as a result if you search in all caps for one flew over the cuckoo's nest essay You will find the front row crew forums on the first page.
Scott: The point is you only need search engine optimization if you have a bullshit spam Fake trying to make a lot of money website and you want your Google rank to go up.
Scott: because if you just make one Of those kind of websites Google will shut you down the hole.
Rym: So the moral here is simply if you want a hosted Microsoft Exchange environment Don't go to intermediate net.
Scott: no buy a computer and buy a copy of Microsoft Exchange.
Scott: And if you're smart, you won't use Microsoft Exchange.
Scott: We get like open exchange or something for free and just install it.
Rym: The problem is for most corporate environments I hate to say it but exchange is usually for what they need the best solution because the other solutions either cost more in admitting or They end up being something like Lotus Notes.
Scott: or have you looked at open exchange lately?
Rym: No, I haven't.
Scott: It's actually pretty much it does the same thing as exchange with open source stuff.
Rym: It's been over a year since I looked at that.
Scott: Yeah, it's actually pretty awesome.
Scott: Thing is it's it's not feasible for a company already stuck with exchange to go to it.
Scott: But if you start a new company don't buy exchange use the open exchange.
Rym: You know what.
Rym: use Google mail for domains, that's also a good idea.
Rym: So on to the main bit.
Rym: we're going to continue origins week talking about how we got into Anime since there have been a lot of threads in the forums lately about you know, what was your first anime?
Rym: How'd you get into it?
Rym: And considering we chose this theme for the week?
Rym: It seems that we will go right along with this topic.
Rym: We've also got a special guest Emily who is back from a long stint in Japan.
Rym: yo I'm sure in the few and sometime in the near future We're going to get her on the show to talk about her experiences.
Emily: I want to talk about the big three.
Emily: I really want to talk about the big three.
Emily: Yeah, big three What the big three summer anime movies that I went and saw in the theater?
Emily: So, yeah lots of news and that I figured that was the one thing I could lord over these two because it was.
Emily: it was Kind of funny.
Emily: like a while back in the forums I brought up the idea of recording segments and I actually did use my little you know
Rym: Headphone
Emily: micro or headset microphone to record some little I don't know five minutes or so and They really didn't turn out that great not just because of microphone quality But just listening to me kind of rambling by myself and then putting that in the midst of the Scott.
Rym: Oh, we've we've learned that lesson.
Rym: I mean Did you hear the episodes where Scott was by himself or where I was by myself?
Emily: We couldn't do it and I just paused for a really long time and have to cut out these.
Rym: Yeah, when I did my first episode by myself, it took me an hour to record 20 minutes.
Emily: Yeah, so so it's tougher than it looks and I give these guys credit for maintaining the energy they do every day of the frickin week.
Scott: So let's.
Scott: it's just hard to do it with one person if it's two people.
Scott: It's like we.
Rym: It becomes more conversation than a talking to myself in the middle of my you know studio plus there's a lot less incentive to Wait a minute, I could just re-edit myself and make myself sound perfect.
Rym: I got to keep editing because I never sound perfect on.
Emily: Oh, yeah, but so anyway The the biggest thing was that I I figured you know, I'm in Japan.
Emily: I can be this Japan correspondent But the thing is they'd they'd figure out stuff before.
Emily: I did you know with the internet?
Rym: What was it?
Rym: that cup noodle thing up noodle thing?
Emily: I I go downstairs to the lobby where I got my Wi-Fi cover in mind.
Emily: she's in Japan where all of this comes from and so I I see I'm like What could I talk about that Rym and Scott wouldn't know about through like dig and gadget or whatever.
Emily: and I go downstairs And on the TV this amazing commercial comes on for cup noodles, you know, it's it's anime.
Emily: It's you know 3d cell shader, which is beautiful.
Emily: Looks like Akita.
Emily: It's it's great and I go up and I really excited and I record this bit and I call Rym on Skype.
Emily: I'm like for him.
Emily: I have this thing It's and then I listen to the podcast and it was like the podcast that day was like, yeah cup noodle freedom Scott's like I have this thing.
Emily: I'm like he's not gonna say it is he.
Emily: and then he's like, yeah The Akita guy did a commercial.
Emily: No, no, how could they possibly know about Japanese commercials before I do?
Emily: I can understand like technology.
Scott: Well, the trick is you know, since Japan is the the place of awesome anything that's significantly awesome Like escapes Japan and comes here, you know See the trick is is that if you're there you can collect all the stuff that is just slightly less awesome.
Scott: That doesn't make it out Like it's stuck there and you got to kind of scoop it all up so that you know people outside go There's the stuff we're missing.
Emily: that's the thing like all the all the stuff you can get at like convenience stores Like the little Gundam candy and stuff like that.
Scott: That's not just physical things.
Scott: It's like, you know information or you know other things like that like oh there's something that all the Japanese people know.
Scott: or through the grapevine kind of yeah, or You know, here's the thing that Japanese people have access to that Americans don't.
Rym: seems like the only barrier We have left is the language barrier because like there's the Mario manga that no one's translating I would pay large amounts of money to read that.
Scott: Yeah I have volume one for a dollar.
Emily: You know, where's the Mario manga?
Emily: and we we found it at book off.
Scott: Yep next to the Kirby manga.
Rym: But anyway, it's since we wanted to talk about origin stories I guess we'll begin with Scott because he is the crotchets member of the.
Scott: what's it?
Scott: the tragedy lately?
Scott: first Versus the sedentary lifestyle.
Scott: now, it's the crotchety old man next to Scott.
Emily: You're so dead Scott.
Scott: yeah, the corpse Scott.
Scott: He's just dead dead.
Rym: yet You're just an old man keeping kids off your lawn with your sedentary lifestyle.
Rym: Yeah Anyway, so how'd you get an anime Scott?
Scott: Well, you know like most kids a little kid I'm watching me some Voltron and watching me some transformers and Thundercats and not realizing this Japanese I'm like this.
Scott: just cartoons is what kids watch, you know, and then I think It had to be some time like late middle school early high school ish When I realized that there was a thing called anime that existed that were there were cartoons from Japan that were somehow different You know than the ones from America And you know, I knew about them and I think like there's a big deal when sci-fi was gonna show Akira because
Rym: You know Well,
Scott: it was all mature and stuff and like I did I kind of like watch like five minutes of it And then I went to bed at that point.
Scott: But eventually I think I don't know remember exactly when it was but you know I was watching, you know Thundercats and stuff on Toonami when multiar was the host in high school.
Rym: You mean the best era of Toonami?
Scott: Yes Good area of Toonami when they still had Space Ghost and Hercule Oids in the middle.
Scott: and you know There was Dragon Ball and Sailor Moon and stuff on there, but I wasn't watching that.
Scott: but you know The anime was coming in, you know Sneaking in there.
Scott: and then sci-fi channel had a week of Godzilla movies.
Scott: now I already like Godzilla movies.
Scott: So I watched all of them especially the best Godzilla movie Which is Godzilla versus Mothra.
Scott: and anyone who wants to argue with me on that Head to the forums.
Scott: cuz Godzilla verse.
Scott: Mothra is the best Godzilla movie ever.
Rym: Well Mothra is the best monster ever.
Scott: therefore no shit.
Scott: The second best movie is Mothra.
Scott: Take that.
Scott: so anyway I was watching that and during that because it was a whole week of Godzilla movies You know, they had ads like.
Scott: next week is all anime movies and I'm like, okay Maybe I'll stick around and watch that.
Rym: So what movies did they show?
Scott: I remember seeing a Fatal Fury because you know It's that Neo Geo fighting game with the guy with the hat and I watched it and not having seen many anime movies before It was okay.
Scott: I mean, hey, I probably wouldn't watch it now.
Scott: But I remember one scene where there was a huge fight in a giant Neo Geo arcade with arcade machines flying everywhere.
Scott: It's pretty awesome.
Scott: God, and then they showed.
Scott: eventually I think they showed the sequel and some other movies.
Scott: But the only movie that I remember or care about was the first two Galaxy Express 3 9 movies Which were and still are awesome.
Rym: Yeah, we watched them again recently.
Scott: In fact, the old the first one.
Scott: We don't watch the second one again.
Scott: Well, I want to anyway, we should real soon have it.
Rym: So see I guess I got into the game a bit earlier than you.
Rym: I remember very very specifically.
Rym: I posted in the forums a bit about it.
Rym: But my mother and she has said this to me many times in my life.
Rym: There's gonna be something on TV.
Rym: That's a lot like those Castlevania games.
Rym: You like watch it.
Rym: She said that about the never-ending story and she said that about this thing this cartoon thing That was gonna be on the sci-fi channel when I was in fourth grade.
Rym: So I sat down some Saturday and sure enough I catch the last Two thirds of vampire hunter D. Mmm.
Rym: to my fourth grade mind.
Rym: That was the most awesome thing ever.
Rym: D was the coolest person I'd ever seen depicted in television.
Scott: Yeah after I saw that Galaxy Express I was trying to watch the Saturday morning anime on sci-fi as much as I could but it got canceled and they kept changing the Time around and I tried to dress up as D for like three Halloween's afterward.
Rym: But my parents always talked me out of it saying that no one would know what I was and they think I was weird.
Scott: You just gotta have the mouth in the hand and everyone will know what you are.
Emily: I Remember when I dressed up, um, my dad but when he went on a business trip, he bought a VHS of Princess Mononoke.
Emily: that was like my favorite movie when I was in.
Emily: let's see I must have been in like ninth grade or something.
Emily: Oh, wow.
Emily: Yeah, it was.
Emily: it was a long time ago.
Emily: it was even before it came over to the US and we had like this raw VHS and I loved it.
Emily: and Um, so I dressed up as son and the only person who figured out what I was.
Emily: Everybody else thought I was a cave girl and they were like the exchange student from Japan was like, oh my god.
Emily: So that was kind of satisfying but nobody got it.
Scott: I remember I discovered Princess Mononoke cuz I went to F. between high school and college.
Scott: I went to Israel and while we were there there was this guy named Ruben like.
Scott: his first name is Ruben.
Scott: My last name is Ruben, but he spells his first name differently.
Scott: Anyway, he was there and on the trip with us and he was talking about this movie Princess Mononoke I'm like, I never heard of this movie, you know, and Ian was not.
Scott: that's where I met Ian And he was all into Gundams and stuff.
Rym: You may remember Ian from the epic smells.
Scott: Yes, he was from the epic smells story that Ian and he was just a Gundam nut.
Scott: He still is a Gundam nut, but you know, he was just ranting about Gundam.
Scott: So that's how we got into the anime discussion and then like you're passing by a movie theater in Israel And there was a poster for Princess Mononoke.
Scott: We didn't watch it because we you know We couldn't just stay around and watch a movie in the middle of some trip.
Scott: But no there it was.
Scott: and then when I got back to the US I was like, aha There we go.
Scott: And then the anime club started like two months after that.
Rym: So yep See after vampire hunter D I was hooked and I stayed all day and I watched like project a co and dominion tank police Robot carnival, which was the only one I didn't like an eight-man after.
Rym: and then years later I saw the Tenchi Muyo movie and I got obsessed and I bought the entire OAV.
Rym: and then through high school every Sunday We'd buy like two or three tapes of anime and then we'd watch them all between our two sessions of D&D.
Rym: And I pretty much was an anime nut from fourth grade until now and I'm still an anime nut.
Rym: Mmm, the RIT anime club did nothing except give me more access to anime because I already rented everything in blockbuster.
Scott: Yeah, I remember our blockbuster had some stuff, but I couldn't really it wasn't enough.
Emily: Oh, oh, I have a blockbuster story.
Emily: I'm sure they've told you about video barn, right?
Emily: That was like the hangout of all the RIT kids.
Emily: They go there.
Emily: It's just a no-name video star with just a ton of foreign films and anime like all these cult hits all these like Really really obscure pretty much every movie ever.
Emily: It's it's actually quite impressive.
Rym: It's no Kim's no Kim's but it's it's pretty much single-handedly got us into Asian kung-fu action flicks.
Emily: When I was in high school I used to beg my mom to take me to the blockbuster across the street from video barn Even though it was like half an hour away Because it had like 20 anime.
Scott: Usually the no-name video places have crap these days, you know Yeah, but like video barn is one of those rare ones.
Scott: That's like this one per state that has everything.
Rym: Well, the thing was the guy who ran it knew a lot about this stuff.
Rym: I mean, he wrote things like very good sword fighting on the front of movies that had very good sword fighting.
Scott: Yeah We went to the video barn and we were like, do you have attacked the gas station?
Scott: He just pulls it right out.
Scott: It's right there and I'm like she.
Rym: You know, you could tell he was just really into it.
Rym: You like to tack the gas station.
Rym: they also had a real big porn section in the bag with the creepy way like the ritual of getting porn where they had like these drop boxes and you pick because we saw him and I asked the guy what they were.
Rym: I asked the guy what the deal was.
Rym: He was like that's so people can buy porn without looking like they're buying porn or renting porn.
Rym: You would pick out all the porn you want and put it in a cubbyhole in the bag.
Rym: then you walk out with nothing in your hands, then you've read something normal and when you go to check up you say and Number four and then the guy would just discreetly take all the stuff from QB number four and put it in a brown paper bag.
Rym: It's clever.
Rym: He also had parking around back.
Rym: Sad thing is I'll bet he made more money off of that porn than he did off of all those Asian kung-fu movies.
Scott: Yeah, well, they also had every anime ever.
Emily: Yeah, pretty much they had like a hentai section.
Emily: You could see it wasn't like in the porn corner.
Emily: It's like you were walking down the aisle like they literally had an anime aisle and you're walking down the aisle.
Emily: It's like normal normal normal.
Emily: Oh my god, scary
Scott: titles and then the door to the
Emily: sex taxi I haven't heard of that one Title start getting kind of surreal and I'm like
Rym: I always hear people talk about like Oh Genki clinic or cool devices or my lady innocent or another
Scott: lady.
Scott: Well, I always hear about For men or I keep hearing like Bible black and discipline I don't know.
Emily: Actually the the video store in Leeroy had basically no anime.
Emily: princess Mononoke I think I had Magic Knight rareth who.
Emily: the anime I did have was like ancient like Unico and stuff.
Rym: Wow It seemed like where I grew up.
Emily: Maybe that's why Kate new Unico and nice to go Don't know.
Scott: She's doing it right as she listens to this, you know, you realize you probably you've primed a cake grenade.
Emily: When you come up Sneak up behind Scott for me.
Rym: Yeah, I think I'll try to record this horrible shriek that our friend cake.
Rym: Anyway, the the video stores near me all had the same anime because I went far and wide when I was like middle school with my parents and everyone from head like Demon City Shinjuku and Harmageddon.
Rym: Aris line was If the last episodes get crummy The thing is.
Rym: the weirdest thing was all these stores had like three random tapes of Evangelion But they all had the three same random tapes.
Rym: It wasn't like tape.
Rym: one two and three was table like one four and seven And I thought it was.
Rym: I mean I saw it and I looked at.
Rym: I was like that's some religious show isn't it?
Scott: Yeah, it was weird like I didn't even realize just how many anime things you could buy in the US.
Scott: I figured that you know, like you just couldn't get that stuff here.
Scott: and then like the first Yeah, I know but I mean like the first year at RIT was like this way crazy Transition.
Scott: because I came into RIT that first year at the beginning of the year, you know It was like here the old VHS's that we're watching from the anime club library and at the end of the year We're buying DVDs and downloading fans up.
Scott: It's like that.
Rym: all that stuff happened in that one number of two thousand while we were freshmen at RIT was when digital fans Subs suddenly exploded.
Scott: Yeah, it's the year 2000. all that stuff came to me.
Rym: It was when and I remember specifically because I almost got kicked out of the RIT anime club by the tape Nazi Greg Young Because the eska flown a movie had come out and it was the pretty much the first widely distributed digital fan sub.
Rym: And I found it and I oh my god.
Rym: So I made like a ten copies of it and I was given to people like check this out It's the eska flown a movie and the anime club was like that's bootlegging We're gonna kick you out of club.
Rym: and then the next year the club was showing fan subs.
Scott: Well, they were doing it that year.
Scott: They had gatekeepers the first one.
Emily: I remember living in Japan that I think it was 2002 when I was checking the RIT's Watching stuff that I couldn't watch because it was on too late.
Emily: and you know everybody was bit torrenting by this time and bit torrent got really popular like 2002 and I just remember checking the website and being like what's it watching that that hasn't even come out on video yet You know, I can't even rent it from Sataya mad, you know
Rym: but I mean it's.
Rym: I love the fact that my anime fandom went from seeing horrible dubs on the sci-fi channel to Literally watching shows the day after they're aired in Japan translated into English.
Rym: Yeah So I think Emily here has probably the most extensive and earliest history in anime compared to the two of us.
Emily: It was kind of weird because it's basically opposite of everyone that I know Because everyone's like my parents don't understand my hobby.
Rym: I had no freaking idea what this stuff was.
Scott: You know, my parents kind of get it.
Scott: I mean they go to the movie theater when there's a Ghibli movie out, you know Yeah, it's fine they kind of get it, you know, they're not like they don't really get it but you know, they're down.
Emily: Yeah Well, I got into honey me because of my parents and actually my extended family.
Emily: the first manga I ever got was gotten by my uncle Dave who was he's a Comic book artist slash graphic designer lived in Chicago and he got me the Harlock Actually as an Ani manga, but it was all in Japanese.
Emily: is I had no idea what's going on That there were Nazis and planes and aliens with blues.
Emily: But um, I remember specifically like my parents have always been really into foreign films and indie films in particular and they were shopping in the foreign film section of media play.
Emily: may it rest in peace.
Emily: and They came across like a very small shelf and half of it was like kind of suspicious looking porny things.
Emily: But they're like Japanese animation and I remember them talking about a title they thought was funny was all-purpose cultural cat girl nukunuku, and they thought that was a funny title for a. But they picked up Oh my goddess and you're under arrest cuz they're like, this is the stuff Dave was talking about and it might be kind of cool But we don't know if it's scary cuz.
Emily: like so much of that stuff looked kind of kind of sketchy Like everyone who didn't know what anime was like a small shelf and half of it was just like porn porn porn I think.
Scott: what it was back in the day when the sci-fi channel first started picking up all this anime is.
Scott: they were like Check out anime.
Scott: It's this ultraviolet ultra hardcore wicked for adult animation stuff.
Rym: They showed like vampire hunter D, but then they showed like erosa yatsura - yeah But it's like.
Scott: that was what the ads were.
Scott: That was how they were marketing it.
Scott: You know, they they pushed Akira like.
Scott: this is something kids shouldn't see but it's a cartoon.
Scott: Oh my god.
Emily: That's from the past when I was hanging out with the a Ken the movie club when I was at Nagoya.
Emily: I Opened a box and it broke.
Emily: and guess what was inside like a whole stack of really really old erosa yatsura Manga, I love that manga.
Emily: It was so funny to read it.
Rym: in fact My friend Ken had like all of it in this giant stack of like these huge books that the binding would break pretty much immediately.
Rym: His manga was really rare when I was a kid Like in Japanese, so it was in English because that stuff was translated mad early.
Emily: Yeah, I think we have the same volume you're talking about.
Emily: That's like huge.
Rym: It's like an inch and a half thick and the whole bunch of stories from it They like took out the only the best store, you know, he was bitching about that and I didn't even know.
Rym: All I could think was how does he know stuff's missing?
Emily: Yeah, I noticed and that's also like when they released Maison Ikoku I realized like a few years ago that they cut chapters out of it and I was like, why'd they do that?
Rym: Well, it's weird where I grew up.
Rym: I mean other people I've talked to.
Rym: there was a lot more Anime in the stores and in the video rental places in my area than in most areas You know when I was in fourth grade, but there was zero manga.
Rym: There was absolutely no manga anywhere.
Rym: But one time I went to Florida to March with my marching band in like the Citrus Bowl or something.
Rym: Yeah, and we we ended up on the last day.
Rym: Our chaperone was supposed to take us to the hard rock cafe and then wait for our plane But our plane was late at night.
Rym: So we had all day.
Rym: our chaperone said I'll pretend you were with me all day Don't get killed.
Rym: and he wandered off On a trip like my friend Dan and my friend Ken went down like downtown.
Scott: we're adults.
Rym: now every trip is like that and we found this virgin mega store and we wandered in and they had a Manga or as we said a manga said god.
Emily: God everyone does that.
Rym: Yeah, and I remember I was in awe Absolute awe and I bought as much as I could afford to buy.
Rym: I spent all my money buying tenji muyo manga And I read it all it like the plane trip to Chicago, but anyway.
Emily: So I started out with oh my god.
Emily: actually even before then we were really into Ghibli movies because my mom had rented my neighbor Totoro.
Emily: and Even before my dad started going to Japan on business trips and for a while like when I was in sixth grade we thought we were like the whole family was going to get transferred over to Japan and It didn't actually come to pass.
Emily: but my dad still goes back for business fairly frequently.
Emily: so that's how I got like my neighbor Totoro and Majo no takibin and stuff like that and he also brought back like the raw Mononoke, which was like basically sealed my anime fandom forever.
Emily: and as far as manga is concerned they Also bought most of my manga like my dad really likes.
Emily: He's funny because my mom tends to go more for as far as comics go She really likes the American indie stuff more like those biography kind of.
Rym: I just find it so cool that your parents I mean my parents I remember her buying daredevil comics.
Rym: They couldn't understand what this anime thing was or what this manga stuff was.
Rym: My mom was convinced that the comics were just boobies Mainly because I had Tenchi Muyo, which had a lot of yeah.
Rym: Yeah, but in the anime I remember my mom was watching beautiful dreamer while I was watching and she was doing housework and at the end She looks at me and she says wasn't this about Nazis in the beginning?
Rym: Where?
Rym: what's going on with this show?
Scott: Yeah, my parents are never really into anything Like.
Scott: I think my mom bought like an X-Files comic book once like we were just in the comic book store.
Scott: She saw it and she went ooh, and she bought it, you know Like whatever I want.
Scott: if I like, you know, comic books then that you know That's what we'd go get if I have a video games and we go do that too, you know, whatever geeky thing I wanted they were like, okay whether they understood it or not
Rym: at least to my mom's credit when I one time I was 16 and I wanted a copy of dragon half because that show is fucking hilarious.
Rym: Good God, if you haven't seen dragon half go find it dragon half.
Scott: We got to talk about that sometimes.
Rym: Yes If nothing else look on YouTube or Google video for the closing theme.
Rym: In fact, that'll leave my thing of the day in the future.
Rym: awesome.
Rym: so never mind, but the thing is it had a for adults only sticker on it because there's a Short nude scene in the very end of it.
Scott: So scandal.
Scott: so I got boobies.
Rym: So I went to media play and I tried to buy it and they were like you can't buy this you're 16 And I was like what I have a mustache.
Rym: I'm not 16.
Rym: They're like, let me see some ID and like oh and I left you should have fake ID.
Rym: So I went to my mom and I said mom buy me this show called dragon half and she goes she's like, alright She's even questioned why I'm asking her to buy this for me and she goes and she comes back with a bag and she says They said this is only for adults.
Rym: What did you ask me to buy?
Scott: but at the same time It'd have been like you should have said watch it with me and you'll say I did.
Rym: and at the end she said that was weird.
Rym: Meanwhile my dad totally different story He used to sit there and watch Sailor Moon with me, which he thought it was just kind of weird and girly.
Rym: but then one day I was watching the tenchi muyo if he's the original ryokio AV and My dad was watching it and he like he walked into the room.
Rym: He was doing something He saw it on and he started watching and then he kept watching.
Rym: then he just sat down He watched the whole OAV with me and at the end He just looks and says that was really kind of funny and not what I expected at all.
Rym: And since then I've been giving.
Rym: he likes cowboy bebop and he really likes.
Rym: read or die.
Emily: See cowboy bebop is is like the best transitional anime to get Americans hooked.
Emily: totally.
Emily: I think it's like your friends say anime sucks and you show them bebop and then they're like, it's weird though Like.
Scott: I have discovered a few people recently who are like, I don't like it and I'm like what the hell's wrong with you.
Rym: Most of the people who at least know about anime and don't like how we bebop are all mod like new fans.
Rym: well, I guess haven't seen a lot of anime yet.
Emily: or They see like shows anything that hasn't come out yesterday.
Rym: They hate yep, or any show that isn't a thousand episodes.
Rym: I saw some fanboys complaining in a forum about how Those old shows are only like 20 episodes long Actually really good and high-budget shows now.
Rym: They they still limit their yeah Mm-hmm, cuz you can't tell me these kids are like in a yasha went on for a thousand episodes.
Scott: So a thousand episodes of crap versus 26 awesome.
Rym: Yep, I mean everyone always forgets that.
Rym: two of the greatest anime ever.
Rym: Thank you.
Rym: No eska flown a and Evangelion we're both supposed to be 39 episodes and they ran out of money and they had to cut them down to 26 Which made Eva kind of incomprehensible, but on the same Wait a lot of philosophical discussion.
Rym: Are you claiming that Ava would have been comprehensible somehow if they've been able to add more bullshit to it If they had if they'd had twice as many scenes of Shinji going.
Scott: Dave and Joel's They had the best thing when they were talking about Shinji.
Scott: They were like if someone comes up to you and says, you know, you had to pilot the giant robot like the only two answers are like, you know, like Okay, when?
Scott: Or like I'm already in let's go.
Scott: Something like it was.
Scott: it was much more funny when they said it.
Rym: but yeah We can't really rip them off like anime world order does.
Scott: no no, but it was quite hilarious.
Scott: I was laughing for like five minutes.
Scott: I had to rewind their podcast actually the best.
Emily: like I said, my parents are Part of the reason I got into film in the first place, but they they picked out bebop.
Emily: They picked out Lane.
Emily: you know most of the stuff.
Emily: my mom would read reviews and stuff online and She she'd pick out these shows and they were always the best shows.
Emily: So Gay to my parents my dad Into mezani koku and yotsuba.
Emily: Those are like.
Rym: well Yotsuba is not human.
Rym: Yeah That's what I told the library.
Rym: even our friend Brian who like seems to really dislike all anime manga He's just like vehemently against it.
Rym: But yet but yet yotsuba.
Rym: He goes nuts over.
Rym: He just it's too good.
Scott: How can you know?
Scott: I mean there are underwear perverts scary guys I know that, you know, they don't.
Emily: the whole underwear pervert you didn't do.
Scott: we've not explained this like ten times You didn't okay.
Emily: We're talking about the.
Rym: the comic Problem is we did a show where we did a show where we talked about this as a news.
Rym: Well, the problem is that it was common news But then it disappeared off the internet like it wasn't widely linked to and it was basically.
Scott: it was news in the 70s But everyone forgot it until recently and Marvel and DC have trademarked the words superhero and super - hero.
Scott: I don't forget.
Rym: I forget which company has which word but technically we can't really use those words in that context.
Scott: So no, so boing boing said they've discovered this recently.
Scott: so boing boing said fine, we're not calling it superhero anymore We're calling it underwear pervert.
Scott: So we're just going along with that.
Scott: Yeah, and that's what that is.
Rym: But since we don't want to go too long in the episode one thing I find interesting.
Rym: I always like to you know categorize things like this.
Rym: But it seems like all of us here despite the fact that we all got into anime over You know a span of many years at different times.
Rym: We're definitely I would call a second gen anime fans.
Rym: In terms of that zeroth gen is like the people who watch star blazers in the 70s.
Scott: Yeah the people who watch Robotech knew that it was Japanese knew that they destroyed three Japanese shows to make it and they were copying tapes at conventions back in The day.
Rym: and zeroth gen I think even includes the people before VHS.
Scott: Wow, they were copying beta tapes at conventions.
Rym: No, they were copying nothing.
Rym: But then like they stole
Scott: some film and they were watching it in a projector at a convention
Rym: Yeah, like these are the oldest of school Before there was downloading
Scott: Translations from the internet on paper and looking down and at them and then up at the screen
Rym: Scott Downloading from the internet.
Rym: No, they were getting them on paper in the mail Long long time ago and I was.
Emily: I might have been in elementary school but we I must have been in seventh grade because we had AOL and we downloaded like a Watch a couple of shows with scripts and you know what it really sucks.
Scott: Yeah, but then first generation you've been using gen locks to add subtitles.
Rym: Don't get me started on gen locks.
Rym: I really wanted to learn about that technology until I realized that it really saw.
Scott: now it's obsolete.
Rym: Thank you God, but There's the first generation fans and those are basically the people who are running all of the anime conventions today.
Rym: I mean if you listen to anime world order, they're pretty much the Trailing end of the first generation fans just as we are the bleeding edge of the second generation fans.
Rym: Third gen are the kids coming up now watching.
Scott: I don't know Naruto bleach Z Yep Man, I actually just remembered something that back in the day like the early 90s and I went to the comic book store.
Scott: They had like a one little tiny shelf that had Ranma and Dragon Ball Z tapes And they had a little tiny TV that would show them and I remember I would look at it for like a minute and go.
Scott: I don't like that.
Scott: That kind of like I did and I don't think they they might have had some manga on that shelf, but I don't remember it.
Emily: Well third gen fans.
Emily: I always thought are people who take one Anime on television for granted like they don't remember a time where there hasn't been constant anime?
Rym: Yeah, or even better that the travesties like when Fox tried to do eskaflowne.
Emily: or they grow up with the internet You know, they don't remember ever having say a dial-up.
Scott: Well, it's like these kids where the PlayStation was their first system and Final Fantasy 7 was the first Final Fantasy they ever played.
Scott: It was like what's what the hell?
Rym: but then again, there's the first gen fans who were like Yeah, you kids suck because we had to go through a lot of difficult effort to get our fandom.
Rym: you kids just get.
Scott: that's like We're awesome because we're right in between.
Scott: we're not the crazy guys and we're not the young punk kids.
Scott: We're the in-between awesomes.
Scott: No one will ever be as awesome as we are.
Scott: We're better than everybody.
Rym: I think we're just the crazy punk guys.
Scott: Yeah, the people older than us suck.
Scott: the people younger than us suck.
Rym: The problem is that's what everyone thinks I know isn't it great?
Rym: except the punk kids the third-gen fans don't even know we exist.
Rym: Yeah, they don't even notice us.
Rym: They probably think that we're like someone's parents when we go to the con.
Emily: It's like they don't remember a time when it wasn't mainstream.
Rym: yet I think back and I can't remember a time when I wasn't playing Nintendo games.
Scott: Yeah, that's true.
Scott: That's true.
Emily: Well, it came out like the year after I was born.
Rym: So yeah Anyway, okay This up Yeah, you want to feel old.
Scott: you're young we're the old ones.
Rym: no, you know who's old?
Scott: our friend Scott Johnson and the World when you and your dad brought home that modern.
Scott: Okay tape.
Scott: I was like done with high school.
Rym: Okay, yeah, luckily a lot of our listeners are a lot older than us which makes me feel a lot better about myself.
Rym: Okay, once again, that was our very hastily put together origin story of anime.
Rym: Once again tomorrow being Thursday where we can talk about anything We have a very special topic that we're not going to reveal just yet because they didn't think of it yet.
Rym: quiet you.
Rym: It's supposed to be some sort of mystery.
Scott: It is a mystery to me.
Rym: tomorrow We're gonna talk about something that we got into and how we got into it.
Rym: Awesome It might just be like how we got into the cupboard or how we got into I don't know.
Emily: Heap of hot water.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, but to end with a couple quick meta bits.
Rym: Um, if you have been for whatever reason not joining the front row crew GeekNights for a little boogers Yes, you are full of boogers But if you blow your nose, there is no reason not to join the GeekNights.
Rym: What are you doing?
Rym: are growing to the point that we can barely contain their awesomeness?
Rym: Their people are posting there faster than I can read.
Scott: Yeah, I used to like respond to all these threads all the time.
Scott: now I just can't.
Rym: it's just not possible And I'm starting to see a couple of some people who don't really even listen to GeekNights that much.
Rym: They just really like our forums.
Scott: Yeah Also, I want to pimp the long neglected frapper map.
Scott: If you go to a front row crew calm and on the right side There's a little icon II thing that says add yourself to the frapper map.
Scott: So go do that and there'll be little push pins for all our listeners on there.
Emily: I was so sad because I wanted to be the first person in Japan and there were already like three people.
Emily: No, there was one person.
Scott: They're actually like three or four legitimate people over there.
Rym: now hello, Japan Is an American who's teaching English there?
Rym: Yeah, we also have.
Rym: it's funny.
Rym: We have a lot of listeners in Australia and Britain and we have a Dutch listener.
Scott: There was the guy from Hong Kong.
Scott: Yeah, and there was a guy from New Zealand.
Rym: I think we're more popular overseas than we are in the US.
Rym: No, I don't think so But it's at least like 60/40 at this point.
Scott: It's like 70/30, but it's still.
Scott: it's still a lot of international goings-on Ray for you learning English.
Scott: Yes Sorry, we don't know your languages except for Emily.
Rym: Anyway, since they were descending into chaos join the forums join the frapper map go to the website.
Rym: You get links to all the things we talk about like the wonderful things of the day.
Rym: You can also vote in the forums as to what topics we'll talk about and we have.
Rym: this is anime related So I'll throw it out last sometime in the somewhat near future.
Rym: There's a good chance.
Rym: We're going to be finally actually interviewing Jim Vowles the con chair of Otakon 2006.
Rym: We interviewed him in the forums text wise which you can read that there.
Rym: But if you have questions, you would like to ask the con chair of Otakon ask away.
Rym: We're gonna take the best questions and if he consents to the interview, we're going to ask them them.
Scott: Oh shit I almost forgot.
Scott: sit a con.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Okay, so I'm not gonna give all the details now.
Scott: I'll give them next week on Wednesday.
Scott: But if you go to sit a con comm www.s it a con.com.
Scott: We're gonna be at this convention in Utica, New York in early October.
Scott: So Yeah, check it out.
Rym: Yeah, and when we say be there we mean we are running all sorts of shit.
Scott: we're gonna be down at this convention along with some other anime podcasters and Entertainment system and Martin Leung the video game pianist and other awesomeness is going down there.
Scott: So Be there be square.
Rym: and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.