Rym: It's Thursday April 27th, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We are going to discuss the Nintendo announcement that we just couldn't resist talking about.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: I like to personally thank Nintendo for making today's episode so easy.
Rym: Yeah, I mean there's really nothing else we could possibly do than talk about what we're about to talk about.
Scott: We really need a little counter in the bottom left.
Scott: for how many times we're gonna say the bottom left of what our video?
Rym: But yeah, yeah We've got some actual news.
Rym: news that isn't just.
Scott: you know Yeah, what the main topic of today's episode has to be by law yeah something We couldn't really wait until next Tuesday to talk about.
Rym: nope nope nope Yeah, so anyway.
Rym: We'll try to get through this with this minimal.
Scott: You open the can of worms All Right.
Rym: so uh Yesterday on slashdot there was the thing about spyware and your spyware IQ and there's a little test where they would give you a bunch of sites.
Rym: you have to figure out which ones have spyware and which ones don't and The billing of it was that oh a lot of people can't tell the difference.
Rym: even techies are getting some of them wrong and who?
Rym: spyware is really bad and even if you're a professional you can't always pick it out I Pretty much complete bullshit.
Scott: Yeah, I mean what it does.
Scott: I took it this morning I think and it basically gives you a choice of two different websites similar websites that both provide a similar service and one of them always looks really snazzy and one of them always looks kind of like homegrown crap from like 1990 something and it says which one is spyware and which one is safe and One of them is spyware and one of them is safe.
Scott: But it's stupid because Only an idiot would go to either one of the sites.
Rym: Yeah, I mean all the sites.
Rym: They pose their things like get free screen savers or freeware applications for your computer.
Scott: Yep, and while some site fonts that offer free screen savers are not spyware You should never go to a stupid website giving free screen savers.
Rym: Yeah if you're going to a website like that spyware or not you deserve spyware and you're probably gonna get it because 99% of sites like that are spyware sites.
Scott: Yeah, so I mean I was ready to be like I don't trust either one of these sites and there was not an option.
Rym: Yeah I'm reasonably certain that this whole thing about the quiz is part of a run-up for an advertising campaign trying to Get people to buy various anti spyware applications when in reality All you have to do is either one not use Windows to at least not use IE or three not go to bad websites.
Scott: Yeah, I mean the thing was given by like McAfee, what do you want?
Rym: I mean, what's with people going to those crappy websites?
Rym: I can't believe there's still people.
Rym: I mean, it's like people who go to I don't know.
Scott: anime wallpapers calm and all papers that comes.
Rym: Okay It's alright, but if you ever been there without full of ads.
Scott: Yeah, if you don't go with an ad blocker you're in for trouble.
Rym: Yeah, or like anime cubed or all those sites that just have pictures from anime.
Rym: Mm-hmm I'll give you a little hint here Google Images.
Rym: Yep, you'll find the same thing.
Rym: In fact better two more two more.
Scott: Okay, so I'm not gonna go through all the details of this incredibly stupid news story that's been going around today But I want to talk about it only because I want to talk about something else related We we.
Scott: there's a guy who got in big trouble for hacking into the government computers.
Scott: Apparently it was some big hack job like the biggest ever and there are all these windows boxes that were completely unsecured, etc, etc.
Rym: Yep, and I mean I would like to say that if he were looking for some information that was more relevant to the world or some Sort of good thing.
Rym: I would have been much more in favor of him.
Scott: Yep He was looking for information about aliens and shit because he's a nutcase I'm gonna say right now.
Rym: It is possible that there is life out there somewhere in space in fact probable.
Rym: However, they are not coming to earth and abducting you.
Scott: No, no, they're not.
Rym: if they were someone would have noticed I mean Someone would have a picture of a spaceship.
Scott: That wasn't blurry.
Rym: Yeah, I mean think about it way back when the UFO craze started which incidentally was right after work right around right after World War II.
Scott: I mean think about this.
Scott: I was into the UFO thing when I was younger so was I and then I realized oh, this is just stupid.
Rym: Well what it came down to the fact that all right a long time ago There not many people had good cameras and cameras were shitty and it was hard to disseminate that sort of information.
Rym: nowadays Everyone in this civilized world has a camera with them or near them or someone near them as a camera.
Rym: their cameras everywhere.
Rym: The cameras are high quality.
Rym: There are lots of people all over the place yet the only people who ever get abducted by aliens are crazy people.
Scott: Don't you think that you know news stations have had cameras in trucks high quality cameras and trucks with live broadcast?
Scott: Capabilities for over three decades, I think.
Scott: oh and let me tell you and they have never ever Taken a video of an alien or UFO or anything like that.
Rym: and if you think it's some sort of conspiracy I can tell you right now that any one of those reporters would kill Absolutely kill to have video of a UFO and no amount of conspiracy BS would have stopped them.
Scott: Yeah, if you're the local TV station schmuck who manages to drive out into the woods and catch the alien You know eating some cows On your camera and you broadcast it on live TV.
Scott: Guess what?
Scott: tomorrow you're in New York, so Everyone wants to videotape aliens and they haven't there aren't any if you believe in them.
Scott: You're a nutcase.
Rym: Yeah, well, no, they might be out there.
Scott: But yeah if you believe they're coming here and fucking with human if you believe they're a little green men and that alien abduction video is Real and that there was something crazy in Roswell besides weather balloons and Air Force projects Etc.
Scott: You got a problem.
Rym: Yeah, also note that a quote alien sightings have been decreasing as communication and technology have increased.
Scott: huh.
Rym: Also, I actually Bill Cosby did a good bit on this in the 80s in his stand-up really where he talked a lot about UFO Sightings and he said something along the lines of you never run into you know, a businessman or a scientist who saw an alien.
Rym: Yes, I was sitting there drinking my martini with my wife and I saw an alien.
Rym: They came down and they said hello to me and then they left.
Rym: It's always some redneck or some crazy, dude.
Rym: Yeah, I have to.
Rym: I had like nine beers and then I got abducted by an alien.
Rym: They gave me some chicklets It's true.
Scott: Yeah, it's true.
Rym: and then they gave me a chicklet.
Rym: If I can find it because I got a cassette tape of it somewhere I'll play it on the air.
Rym: Right be damned.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So yeah this guy I say give him the full brunt of the hacking punishment.
Rym: Yeah, it's not like he was doing anything good like trying to expose.
Rym: Hey, look the war was a sham.
Scott: now Here's the thing.
Scott: The guy had some pretty specific claims say about alien information.
Scott: He found either a he's lying.
Scott: B there's some stupid people in the government posting that sort of stuff and it's not true, which I wouldn't surprise me at all.
Scott: See he misinterpreted it, you know, there's a whole bunch of possibilities But I really don't think any of them are.
Scott: oh my god, there's aliens.
Scott: even the comments on dig there.
Scott: I don't think there was a single comment that was like yeah, there's aliens.
Scott: This guy is totally gonna bust open the conspiracy.
Rym: Oh my god, well look at our government.
Rym: our government couldn't handle the disaster relief of one city in New Orleans.
Rym: I don't think they could.
Rym: for over a period of more than 50 years.
Scott: They couldn't keep their evil prison camps in Europe a secret.
Scott: They couldn't keep Guantanamo Bay a secret.
Scott: They couldn't keep anything a fucking secret.
Scott: They're not gonna keep the fucking aliens from outer space that you can't possibly miss and have laser beams and abduction Technologies a secret.
Scott: there's no way.
Scott: you know why?
Rym: wait, you know what?
Rym: a lot of people have telescopes.
Rym: A lot of people are looking for stuff telescopes like the Hubble telescope.
Scott: Yeah, if there were aliens they would have seen it.
Scott: They had that SETI thing which is actually not the worst thing in the world.
Scott: if there were aliens They would have fucking found them.
Rym: Yeah, or they're too far away for us to really care other than knowing that they're there.
Scott: Yeah, so
Rym: honestly It's my belief or at least my opinion that I wouldn't be surprised if we discover intelligent life out there possibly with our lifetimes You know with SETI and all that but at best it would be a the best we could get is yes There is intelligence out there.
Rym: It is too far away to ever reach.
Scott: Yeah, the fact that we haven't encountered some sort of Intelligent life yet tells me one of two things.
Scott: one The universe is so incredibly vast that the odds of anyone finding us is like one in a trillion jajillion years or even the odds Of anyone finding anyone.
Scott: Yeah - there really isn't possible to make some sort of transportation technology akin to hyperspace.
Scott: or.
Scott: Three the universe is really so young that we're like the first intelligent race and the other ones haven't come around yet.
Scott: I always read like sci-fi stories about the precursors that were like the earliest race that had the best technology And then all the other races came way after we could be the precursors for all we know.
Rym: It's like episode one of Futurama where the cities get destroyed by the aliens and then castles get rebuilt And then the castles get destroyed by the aliens and then cities get rebuilt.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right, so aliens crazy I Alright.
Rym: so Scott you can do your thing of the day first since mine is ancient and relevant.
Scott: Yeah, and as soon as my thing of the day is done.
Scott: We're gonna open up a big can of Keep that can close for now.
Scott: We why?
Scott: Why?
Rym: My why?
Scott: All right.
Scott: So there's a cool blog I discovered today.
Scott: It seems a pretty old blog but it also seems to be a frequently updated blog.
Scott: So it's all good.
Scott: the blog puts up clips from YouTube and Google video and whatnot of Japanese TV shows.
Scott: and wow Japan.
Scott: yeah Wow like I've seen some Japanese TV.
Scott: like you know some morning Musume about Takashi's castle.
Scott: yeah I've seen some stuff around.
Scott: you know mostly anime but other stuff also.
Rym: this guy finds the best of the best clips from stuff like if you thought morning Musume versus the lizard was funny or weird that's got nothing on some of this.
Scott: yeah if you thought that like Yatta was like the be all end all yeah yeah you got nothing.
Scott: compared to the things this guy is finding on a daily basis.
Rym: what was the one you watched just before we did the show about Chucky.
Scott: it was just.
Scott: someone came out of a booth doing a poor impersonation of Chucky while they were basically like jittering like someone with that disease that makes you jitter all over the place.
Scott: Wow and I was just like what the hell is going on here.
Scott: so if you would like to laugh at funny Japanese TV you should probably subscribe to the RSS feed for this blog and check out all their stuffs.
Rym: yeah I'll warn you that this site may become a future source of possible things of the day.
Scott: yeah that's I decided to use it as the thing of the day as opposed to picking out one or two things because then I would just for the next like year just pick out yeah that guy's blog would be basically the thing of the day.
Scott: blog wouldn't be good all right.
Rym: so today we're going to talk about the Wii and my thing of the day.
Rym: I had this other thing of the day.
Rym: I've said a couple times about some World War one stuff but whatever this thing of the day is ancient.
Rym: I mean ancient ancient.
Rym: this is an ancient ancient ancient I want to keep saying ancient part of internet history.
Rym: we found it under the pyramids this is and next to the temple in Israel this is so old that I had not actually heard or seen it in at least three years.
Rym: yeah despite this it was the first thing the very first thing that came to my mind when I heard what Nintendo called the revolution.
Scott: you were not alone as there are links abound in every thread I saw any place the comments could be posted about.
Scott: I saw the link posted to the old.
Rym: so I'm not going to assume that you've all seen this because I realized that we're kind of the old man of the internet.
Rym: now mm-hmm.
Rym: so gonads and strife gonna tend to lightning gonads in the rain.
Scott: all right it's a video somewhat of a video.
Rym: it's more like a flash.
Rym: it's in the all your base or whatever the hell that was and it appeared a long long time ago and it was one of those things that you'd like go to new grounds and watch back with like stick death that kind of internet humor.
Rym: e bombs world stylin yeah old e bombs world like back in the day yTMD and I'm surprised that everyone in the world seemed to remember it suddenly when the name of the revolution was announced.
Scott: I wonder how many people today discovered this for the first time ever.
Rym: yeah in fact tell us if if you had never seen the gonads and strife video until I linked to it tonight I talked.
Rym: tell us I really want to know.
Rym: maybe we'll make it a poll or something.
Scott: tell us what you think about it because this is like ancient.
Scott: there would be no things of the day if it weren't for things like this back in the day.
Rym: a good way to put it.
Rym: so without further ado let's talk about the we.
Scott: for those of you who do not know the Nintendo revolution is not going to be called the Nintendo revolution.
Scott: we have known and have always known that is only the code name.
Rym: yes there but there's been a lot of speculation as to what it was actually going to be called.
Rym: some people said was going to be called the revolution.
Rym: anyway some people said the Nintendo go was a good idea.
Scott: some people came up with a bunch of random ideas all over the place.
Scott: whatever today it was we're a hundred percent sure because I went to the official Nintendo website before it was down and I went to the official Nintendo Japanese website just before the show and checked to make sure we weren't insane.
Scott: the Nintendo revolution is really going to be called the Nintendo we.
Rym: now there was some debate initially as to whether it was pronounced why or we why to which I say if you think it was pronounced why why you're dumb yes it was called.
Scott: it is called we.
Scott: why as in you and me or Rym and I we?
Rym: yeah now the thing is Nintendo really gave a whole bunch of clever answers like oh we'll see we look two eyes.
Rym: it's like two people sitting there playing the game but it's also we as in we are going to enjoy the game together and and all these sorts of you know very Japanese type ooh look clever wordplay.
Scott: the eye looks like the controller but it can also be a person but it can't.
Scott: oh look at that.
Scott: ooh this and I see why they picked we.
Scott: it's because number one a lot of things have the letter I in them.
Rym: I Mac Wi-Fi did that.
Rym: if I thing if I buy whatever the hell it was if I was just DRM.
Scott: yeah so the letter I is real popular.
Scott: iPod yes and Nintendo is trying to sell this product not to the people who are PlayStation Xbox II but to everyone else and things with names like this TiVo seem to be selling to just about everyone.
Rym: yes this strategy.
Rym: we talked about it before.
Scott: they call it blue water and that well they called it the blue ocean strategy.
Scott: I think we're gonna change the yellow ocean strategy but we all right in French when you want to say yes you say we we.
Rym: you gotta be kidding me.
Rym: oh my god that is hysterical.
Rym: what do you say for no doo-doo I'll be right back.
Scott: I gotta go take a wicked.
Scott: yes there goes the what there goes.
Scott: one joke off my little list of jokes I wrote today.
Rym: oh my god I couldn't talk about this with my co-workers because not only would they not have understood but I probably would have just been annoying.
Scott: yes so the reason I think Nintendo picked is because it's such a flexible idea.
Scott: the problem with the idea is that it's not inspiring.
Scott: like you could sit around going.
Scott: yeah I'm gonna get the revolution all right.
Scott: you can't sit around going.
Scott: yeah I can't wait to get the Wii.
Scott: it just doesn't is?
Scott: it doesn't have passion behind the name.
Rym: yeah I mean I had.
Rym: I just had these visions of when the revolution of like a kid Che Guevara style holding the controller over his head as other kids rush forward.
Rym: but now I don't get that with Wii.
Scott: yeah the problem is is that even if we got revolution revolution doesn't really appeal to anyone but us cool gamer types.
Scott: yeah my mom doesn't want to buy the revolution.
Scott: my mom might buy the Wii.
Scott: you know it's.
Scott: it's a brand that what they?
Rym: the brand sacrifices the passion of the gamer for the acceptance of more people which is possibly okay because it's kind of like the story of capstone at RIT little geek fable.
Rym: here there were a whole bunch of apartments that they're building nice ones at our campus and they were still constructing them while we went there and the year before we attended RIT they were like a twinkle in some fat old man's eye and they didn't say what they were gonna be called yet.
Rym: but there were these construction crews building them and the construction company was called capstone mm-hmm.
Rym: so everyone called the new apartments the capstones mm-hmm.
Rym: then the apartments were unveiled and they were called University Commons and for many people called them capstone.
Rym: yes everyone who was old enough to know better or new people who were old enough to know better called them capstone and you could tell the people who were kind of out of the loop socially because they called it University Commons.
Scott: yes also at RIT the group that performed maintenance was known as physical plant.
Rym: that's a very nice name.
Rym: I like names like that physical physical plant.
Scott: that's an awesome name physical plant.
Scott: then like our last year there or the two years before I graduated they changed the name to what FMS facilities management.
Rym: yeah I actually forgot what it was.
Rym: it
Scott: doesn't matter I kept calling them physical plant and whether they liked it or not
Rym: yeah they didn't like it because I often had to interface with various people on campus you know requesting services and all that and I'd always ask for a physical plant stuff and they'd give me this glare like physical plant doesn't exist anymore and I'd stare him right back down can't?
Rym: does I need a freaking janitor?
Scott: janitors from physical plant not maintenance laborers from facilities management services?
Rym: yeah yeah physical plant.
Rym: we go on and on about that.
Rym: but I see that happening with the revolution.
Rym: I think a lot of people at least hardcore Nintendo fans are going to continue to call it the revolution forever.
Scott: it's weird because they've had code names for every system so far.
Scott: we had dolphin dolphin the ultra 64 and people just gave up the code names and a lot of them are forgotten.
Scott: I don't think the revolution name is going to be forgot.
Rym: I think part of it was that every other system Nintendo released I mean dolphin.
Rym: the GameCube was the first one where it was widely known before the system came out.
Rym: before then the internet wasn't so ubiquitous and like when the SNES came out no one in America knew what the code name was for it except some developers.
Scott: no one really cared either.
Rym: yeah and even the n64 no one knew.
Rym: revel our GameCube.
Rym: people started to know but they heard GameCube before they heard dolphin.
Scott: mm-hmm.
Scott: I heard dolphin before I heard game.
Rym: yeah but most people didn't hear dolphin.
Rym: dolphin wasn't.
Scott: dolphin was the thing.
Scott: dolphin was the thing you hear if you read video game magazines and video game website yep which many people don't revolution they use that name a lot more.
Scott: in fact there was like a revolution link at the top of the Nintendo website plus.
Rym: Nintendo talked about the revolution a lot I mean before the n64 was really announced.
Rym: they didn't talk about it much at most.
Rym: they'd mentioned you know a new console is coming someday.
Scott: yeah there wasn't really a whole lot of Nintendo wasn't generating buzz about the dolphin.
Scott: they were just saying you were coming up with a new console the code name is dolphin and then they didn't generate buzz until they actually had you know the GameCube.
Scott: then they started generating buzz.
Scott: Nintendo here has been generating buzz about the revolution for so long and now they changed the name to Wii right before they announce it.
Scott: whereas you look at Microsoft or PlayStation they had their names set in stone long before their big reveals.
Scott: well ps3 still hasn't been revealed but like PlayStation portable they had the name right away.
Scott: there was no code name for that because their names are just straightforward and stupid.
Scott: but Xbox 360 like right away Xbox 360.
Rym: I mean I guess my only real fear here of the Wii Wii is not our silliness because this is what you would expect from you know Nintendo fans.
Rym: I worry that the word just doesn't really seem to resonate with American sensibilities and American speaking patterns.
Scott: it all depends on their marketing because oh it does heavily.
Rym: but I just I note that revolution is a word in English that just feels good to Americans yeah but it doesn't really feel good to grandma.
Rym: no it doesn't.
Rym: but at the same time or mommy I just I see that Americans tend to not like words that sound foreign or different or look weird or spelled weirdly.
Scott: yeah well there's an interview and we link to with we public relations guy for Nintendo and the game informer.
Scott: people actually seem to have some balls in this interview.
Rym: yeah they basically asked so uh we we we P?
Rym: yeah what's the deal?
Scott: so the guys like plenty of people have things named like TiVo and Napster and all sorts of weird names.
Scott: Nestle yeah and those all things get credit and credibility.
Scott: Virgin Airlines no one makes jokes about that.
Scott: you know Virgin Mobile caterpillar.
Rym: how could you make fun of caterpillar?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: there's no naked juice.
Scott: there's naked juice you buy in the store.
Rym: I made fun of that the first time I saw it.
Rym: yeah in fact it was at Otakon.
Scott: Yahoo you know.
Scott: he uses all these examples of other companies with weird names and how.
Scott: no one really makes fun of those once they validate themselves in the marketplace.
Scott: yeah and he's probably right that eventually the Wii jokes will run out but not for a while not on your life.
Scott: but Nintendo was smart in that.
Scott: the reason they announced the Wii now as opposed to at e3 is that way.
Scott: at e3 people are concentrating on the names the games and not the names.
Rym: yeah I really still expect them to drop some sort of bomb at e3.
Scott: oh man they're gonna be Bob arms with parachutes all over the shizzy.
Rym: I could.
Rym: just I can imagine what I really know.
Rym: I can't imagine what kind of announcement they would make but there's got yes connection God and holy crap because there's got to be at least one more like secret that we don't know about the revolution.
Scott: I guarantee there's like a whole shit ton of secrets and they're gonna bust them all out like in a row and whoever's there is gonna be like.
Scott: they're gonna say one thing oh my god another thing oh my god.
Scott: and then at the end they're gonna say oh we forgot to say this.
Rym: I mean like in the interview.
Rym: it was great because they at one point the guy asks.
Rym: so we heard a rumor that the one of the secret features coming that's going to be announced is that the nunchuck part of the controller is also a motion sensor and the guy answers with really that's interesting.
Scott: yeah we've heard a lot of speculation some of it true some of it not.
Rym: I remember when the GameCube was coming out and people were speculating whether or not it would come with a holographic projector.
Scott: oh yeah yeah oh no I think that was original revolution before we even knew it was a controller.
Rym: that was a long time ago.
Scott: yeah that was.
Scott: that was original revolution speculation actually not GameCube speculation if I recall correctly.
Rym: yeah IIRC.
Scott: but I'll repeat something I also saw in many forums you know arose by any other name.
Scott: the name we which we can talk about for now until the end of time does not diminish the awesomeness that the revolution will undoubtedly be.
Rym: no it does not.
Scott: it's funny because I'm referring it to his revolution now.
Scott: and so is the Nintendo guy like he didn't actually say we.
Scott: he said once you touch the revolution this will make more sense.
Scott: well shouldn't he have said once you touch the we this will make more sense.
Rym: because he asked them to touch his we he might go to jail.
Scott: I know it's so terrific about this thing.
Rym: so uh Scott when it comes out you want to stay in our house and play with our we all day you kidding I won't be going anywhere without my we all right let's start talking about.
Scott: there's my list of things here.
Rym: oh yeah Scott made a list.
Rym: I was doing work at work and apparently Scott wasn't.
Scott: every time something new came to my mind about the we I wrote it down.
Rym: well there are the nights who say we we Xbox alright.
Scott: so first of all where do you think they came up with the name we?
Scott: well according to the interview whatever.
Scott: but I think that some guy was playing picto chat with his DS and he got a message.
Scott: you know the typical message you get on picto chat and he said that's it.
Scott: in fact that's what we'll call the next system.
Rym: that's beyond.
Rym: I mean that's like since an ACK ACK in CCP IP.
Rym: that's like the standard greeting of two guys with DS's.
Rym: it's the DS comes on.
Rym: you have joined picto chat a picture of a penis.
Rym: I must respond with a better picture of a penis and then you can talk.
Scott: yep that guy must have realized but everyone was doing a picto chat and he said I know people love penises.
Scott: we'll use penises to sell our system.
Scott: we'll call it the we.
Rym: well the controller is shaped rather fallically.
Rym: it is granted I hate people who say something's a phallic symbol because I'll note that many things are vaguely cylindrical.
Scott: you know if you take the lowercase I and turn it upside down it looks like a penis with one nut.
Rym: if you turn it right side up it's an ejaculating penis.
Scott: whoo all right.
Scott: secondly you know how for the DS they come up with games like Mario DS Tetris DS.
Scott: we're gonna get Mario we princess between huh Tetris with that controller Wario we Tetris Wario we Kirby we.
Scott: it's like a cong we.
Rym: somewhere on FARC someone referred to all will rights.
Rym: P alright P on us will right?
Rym: yeah oh.
Scott: I wanted to point out also how while the name may not be a good name you know in terms of many things at least in terms of the fact that it didn't immediately like resonate with the masses there it does have an advantage.
Scott: that is rather obvious now.
Scott: if they would have just said we're gonna keep the name revolution everyone would have gone.
Scott: yeah they're keeping the name revolution.
Scott: that would have been it.
Scott: if they would have said we're gonna use Nintendo go everyone would have said yeah they picked the one that we liked.
Scott: we're good because they picked we which wasn't something that people like really like to ride away.
Scott: it caused an internet explosion and I think Nintendo knew that right out.
Scott: that's why they did it because they knew it would cause an internet explosion right before e3.
Scott: they did it on purpose and it worked.
Scott: no press is bad press.
Rym: yes all publicity is good publicity.
Scott: why do you think the Nintendo PR guy was ready with an interview with Game Informer on the same damn day.
Scott: come on people.
Scott: they did it on purpose and it's working.
Scott: the fact that we're doing a whole podcast about it and we're not being paid by Nintendo shows that it's working really really.
Rym: you should have heard us when we came home from work.
Rym: I walked in the door and I heard we and I walk upstairs and I go and I ran into a house and there's a guy all right.
Scott: secondly a lot of people were saying okay it's only the name in Japan.
Scott: well no it's the name everywhere.
Scott: in fact the Japanese website has the exact same flash video that the American website has yep.
Rym: and now they even said that part of the reason they picked this name is that it's language neutral and that you can call it the same thing worldwide and it's going to be part of a global branding campaign.
Scott: that's good because previous Nintendo things did not have the same brand globally.
Scott: I mean the DS and the GameCube did but not the Famicom or the Super Famicom.
Scott: yeah it's really a new thing to have the same name globally for Nintendo.
Scott: I mean some Nintendo games don't even have the same name on both sides of the world so giving their system the same name on both I mean mother earthbound yeah yeah.
Scott: so giving it the same name everywhere is really gonna help them out.
Rym: speaking of which isn't mother three out in Japan it's out for the GBA in Japan.
Rym: it's not fair.
Scott: ah you bastards yeah so I just noticed though if they're gonna use the same name worldwide that's fine but the name has different meanings worldwide.
Scott: in France it means a wee wee.
Scott: well no it means yes but and in Ireland and Scotland it means oh it's a wee leprechaun.
Scott: you got there huh what that was a nice mixture of Scottish and Irish I know I know I went for it.
Rym: huh Willie's got a wee.
Scott: Willie as a wee bit a gaming console.
Scott: you got there.
Rym: okay anywhere anyone else you want to make fun it's a wee wee I got.
Rym: anyone else you gonna make fun of here.
Scott: okay so yeah do we?
Rym: I'm not sure what I think yet
Scott: I think that's the idea is that they want you to think
Rym: yeah if anything they threw me off guard because I saw the earliest earliest like cutting bleeding-edge news if it's gonna be called the Wii and it says something that usually when I get cutting news like that you can't you have this bullshit filter of alright
Scott: that immediately I thought it was bullshit because I first saw it at an unreputable source.
Scott: yeah and I went straight to nintendo.com and clicked revolution.
Scott: and there it was and I was like well now it went from 0% true to 100% true in about 30 seconds.
Rym: usually I'm really good about that like I'll see a story and I think all right this is obviously bullshit.
Rym: I'll wait for someone to retract it or I'll wait for someone to prove this wrong or debunk it or I'll see something all right.
Rym: that's probably legitimate this one.
Rym: I immediately there's no way that could be true I thought wow someone just made up a funny word and tried to make a rumor.
Scott: within one minute it was verified as 100% true.
Scott: one minute I want to.
Scott: that's something else I was talking about.
Scott: how you know this created a lot of buzz my Google News RSS feed which has one entry for video games.
Scott: when I looked at that RSS feed about an hour after the Wii was announced it had four separate blocks of Wii stories.
Scott: four of them.
Scott: that's more blocks of stories than there have ever been for a single topic ever.
Rym: Fark had the topic immediately and it filled up.
Rym: slashdot had it a bit later and it filled up.
Scott: yeah it it exploded all over the internet.
Scott: so you might not like the name Wii but if you like what the system is which you should because you know again a rose you should be glad that it exploded.
Scott: it's exploding a lot more than Xbox or PS2 did.
Scott: they must Reggie's doing his job really really well.
Rym: now one thing that I wonder because we obviously take we it's the secret word.
Scott: but I wonder because I saw initially the the topics and the forums where people were talking about it start.
Rym: basically the trend was they started with.
Rym: that's not true.
Rym: that can't be true.
Rym: it is true that's stupid.
Rym: Nintendo sucks.
Rym: no one would buy something that called the same thing as pay and I just wonder what I mean.
Rym: obviously over time people are going to take a shot into it or people like us will go.
Rym: I will see what happens or I see why they did that.
Rym: I wonder if Nintendo is going to respond to the significantly negative that response they've gotten to this.
Scott: they did in the interview that we just read.
Rym: oh yeah but I mean in general it seems at least that maybe it's because people like us don't post so often on forums anymore
Scott: things because the people posting on forums are the ps2 Xbox types and all the Nintendo people even the ones who don't like the name are like.
Scott: I'm buying it anyway.
Scott: you know it's all about what it is and the only reason they date because the brand matters to people who don't know about what it is true it's like.
Scott: look at an iPod.
Scott: if you actually know about digital music players you probably don't buy an iPod even though I did but you know there are many other players out there.
Scott: iPod sells because of its brand and style to people who don't know about digital music players.
Scott: they're trying to do the same thing.
Scott: the other the game consoles sell to people because of the company and the games and such.
Rym: yeah though these days I think it's a lot.
Scott: it has a lot to do with the exclusive games more than anything yeah but if Nintendo is trying to sell to people who don't know about game consoles they need to sell a brand to those people.
Scott: and Revolution is not a brand you can sell to people who don't know about game consoles.
Rym: well possibly I could see a lot of ways you could spin the marketing.
Rym: I mean revolution could be revolution.
Rym: games are different now games are for everyone or some sort of campaign.
Rym: yeah but the thing is they could do the same kind of campaign with any name they pick.
Rym: yeah the campaign.
Scott: they could have picked a different brand.
Scott: besides we like we isn't the most ins they.
Scott: the problem I we is that while it's good for so many reasons it's not inspiring at all.
Rym: it didn't resonate it.
Scott: it could have picked something that was both inspiring and useful in all the same ways and I guess they just didn't.
Scott: yeah I mean it's too late to turn back.
Rym: we'd have a very different conversation if it was a word that just really really kind of clicked with us.
Scott: but can you think of a word revolution?
Scott: yeah but a word that you can easily sell to everyone.
Rym: all right okay well I'm surprised we tapped it so quickly but we really don't have much else to say about the we until e3.
Scott: yeah I guess you know I had all this stuff written down and I lost the stupid text file.
Rym: but yeah well we were planning.
Rym: I mean originally we figured whenever this news came out we'd wait until the Tuesday and talk about it.
Scott: but it exploded so much we had to talk about it today yep and it was gonna take a lot more than just the amount of time for news to talk about.
Scott: so we made the whole episode about the Wii?
Rym: yeah there's really no other way because if we hadn't we would have had nothing but a flood of emails from all of you saying why didn't you talk about the Wii?
Rym: what's up with the Wii?
Rym: you guys hear about the Wii?
Scott: yeah trust me we heard about the Wii a minute before or after anyone else actually heard about it.
Scott: a minute after some people because instead of a minute before because I was doing some other shit.
Rym: the best thing was I heard it right and I went to our forums at the GeekNights forums because I was going to type to everyone hey guess what?
Rym: and someone had already posted it and all I could think was yes yes followed by the person is just as fast as we are and tapped into the new.
Rym: who was it?
Rym: anyway?
Rym: I don't know I whoever whoever posted it first in the forums gets a prop not props.
Rym: just one prop cuz it was cool.
Scott: ooh yeah is that prop like a fake chair with a broken leg?
Rym: or it's gonna be a duck like a bowling pin trained duck?
Rym: all right yeah but like we said in previous days we have promised a few various people various generally crap o prizes in the forums which will be coming as soon as we have some merch mm-hmm.
Rym: so just don't be impatient because we've got stuff coming and we got stuff in the works.
Rym: we got a hopper.
Scott: yeah and if you think it's annoying hearing us go all the time during this episode don't worry we decided that because this is the Wii episode.
Scott: we're not really gonna make fun of the Wii and go any more after this episode.
Scott: we're just gonna refer to it either as the revolution or the Wii.
Rym: yeah I mean seriously.
Rym: there was at least a 15 minute period when every time I said the word we I said it we.
Rym: I was like hey what are we going to eat for dinner?
Scott: it was bad it's real bad but by next week we should be all good and we will refer to it as the Nintendo Wii or the Nintendo Revolution normally without joking without squirrels.
Rym: I've heard some people call it the we evolution already.
Rym: oh yeah that might catch on.
Scott: wait a minute wait a minute evil.
Scott: yeah I like weevils the lesser of two hahahahaha.
Scott: Darwin who was in that movie oh my god.
Rym: oh.
Scott: the guy who operated on himself pick a who took a bullet out of his own gut.
Rym: the guy who wasn't really Darwin.
Scott: the guy who was Darwin.
Rym: yeah he's a Jonah that one alright in another in another stupid quiz fashion.
Rym: this is not open to anyone who knows us personally.
Rym: what movie were we just talking about?
Scott: oh it's so freaking easy.
Rym: you never know you guys.
Rym: well I was up here recording some or doing stuff with the podcast or fiddling around.
Rym: I remember you were all sitting downstairs and you came up and you're like there's a trade in this book.
Rym: he's a Jonah you know what that's from.
Rym: and I said fuck it I'll ruin it never mind forget the contest.
Rym: I said master and commander yeah and you guys said what.
Rym: how'd you know that?
Scott: I didn't know.
Scott: I just like the burning wheel book has a lot of references to things and I didn't know what any of them were mostly.
Scott: and but he's a Jonah that one I don't remember that from the movie at all.
Scott: and then we had like there's another one.
Rym: and yeah white gold wielder.
Scott: yeah yes the thing Evan had read the sci-fi the fantasy book that went with that and he knew exactly what the hell it was and no one else knew.
Scott: cuz no one else had read those books.
Rym: yeah at least I can say sometime coming up we're gonna do a burning wheel episode like we said we do since we're actually going to put together a game game of it sometime soon at least within the next month.
Rym: oh and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Scott: make sure you visit them.
Scott: you can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537. GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience but unlike those other talk shows it's actually recorded at night.