Rym: It's Tuesday May 16th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We continue worst week with video game consoles the worst of the worst.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So today I went on my final business trip as my IBM employment.
Scott: Is there any other work left to do for IBM at all?
Rym: Uh, most of my only thing I think I've left to do is to sit there and answer questions for the next couple of days At work while people go.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: How do we support this thing?
Rym: You built two years ago, and I say I'm not going to teach you how to use Linux.
Scott: So you have what two or three days of employment left?
Rym: Yes, then I have a new employment on Monday and I There's no sign of me losing my current job anytime soon.
Scott: Yet with you have more work to do in the two days you have left that I have to do at all.
Rym: Yeah, something like that.
Rym: I don't have to do anything.
Rym: I'm not actually going to do anything.
Rym: I'm going to sit in my office and dick around on my computer and Answer any questions people have for the next two weeks.
Rym: two days.
Scott: So you will be doing more than me in the next two days.
Scott: That's correct.
Rym: Possibly days three days.
Rym: I might say more words than you.
Scott: I might be saying the words TLDP Over and I'll definitely be saying very few words because I'll probably be alone in this middle of nowhere office.
Rym: You know if I'm alone in an office, I tend to talk to myself for saying I Yes, I don't do that I do.
Rym: I sit on the computer and I type Wow I just be on the phone talking to people all day.
Scott: You know, they got their free Skype by good.
Rym: Yeah, we got to start interviewing people start prank calling people something I used to prank call people all the time in high school when dial pad appeared.
Rym: Oh, yeah Yeah dial pad when it appeared.
Rym: This was a long time ago and not many people had broadband.
Rym: It was a website and you could go to this website and on the website call any real phone number for free and talk to It as though you had a phone.
Rym: It was used almost Exclusively for prank calls for a couple months and then it died.
Scott: and now we have Skype which can now do the same thing Until the end of the year, where are the prank calls?
Scott: What happened?
Rym: I don't know if prank calls happen so much anymore.
Rym: I think it's a dying art.
Scott: I'm gonna go onto the internet and find a website that tells me a bunch of funny prank calls I can do and then I'm.
Rym: I think the problem is punk kids today aren't as creative.
Rym: I mean the most recent prank call I remember is you kick my dog.
Scott: Yeah, you kick my dog.
Rym: I say you kick my dog.
Rym: You come to my house you stand in my front yard and you kick my dog.
Scott: We should.
Scott: My favorite was always hello.
Scott: Hello, is your refrigerator running?
Rym: Uh, yeah better go and catch that.
Rym: That's right.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Excuse me Do you have Prince Albert in a can?
Rym: All right We got some actual news.
Rym: But before that I got a. it's a news but not really a news spinny leak.
Rym: lady Loytuma, I talked about it yesterday.
Rym: I made it my thing in the day.
Rym: There's a crazy thread in the forums.
Rym: I Would like to note that I went about trying to purchase the album.
Rym: two places I looked at it was sold out or not available and One of the places which seems to be a primary seller of their CDs Has an update talking about how the popularity of this album has exploded in the United States Due to an internet phenomenon bond some.
Rym: and then there's like something on YouTube something something.
Scott: Yeah, they seems they figured out what the hell was going on.
Rym: They know about spinny leak Awesome.
Rym: I find that just amazing and hilarious and great.
Scott: All I can say is this if you want to have a musical group and You want to start a band with your friends and you want your band?
Scott: To make a lot of money and get really popular What you do is some part of one of your songs has to be humorous or interesting or unique.
Scott: That's the hard part or very easily looped Yes Then take that part of one of your songs or one of your entire songs and make a viral internet flash with that song.
Scott: People will start wondering who did the music?
Scott: they'll find out that it's you and they'll all buy your album.
Rym: now.
Rym: bear in mind That a lot of people try to make things like this and if it's obvious that you tried to make it viral it'll fail.
Scott: Yeah There are a lot of freaking videos on the internet with a lot of freaking songs and only some of them Succeeds such as all your bass.
Scott: Numa Numa Numa Numa Numa.
Scott: Hey those Russian chicks.
Rym: Oh Saw social awesome, uh No, the lesbian one.
Rym: Yeah, the song was saw social awesome.
Scott: Uh, what was their name again?
Rym: Uh, tattoo.
Scott: That's the one.
Rym: Yeah, the fake lesbians.
Rym: Yes, their music was meh, but because they were supposedly lesbians They were very popular partly because penny arcade they didn't even have to make a flash.
Scott: They just used their normal music video, which is hot lesbian action.
Rym: Yes, it was.
Rym: Unfortunately, the rest of their videos were not yeah unfortunately.
Scott: So If that's you know, that's the way to get popular I say go for it.
Scott: If especially if your music isn't that great you can still make a quick buck.
Rym: Yeah though I got to say I'm gonna probably get all of loich and was albums because I found some more of their songs other than Levins polka and I like their music a lot.
Rym: All right, I think I like rush.
Rym: I I think I really like Finnish folk music now and I found a whole bunch of other bands and I can't find torrents any This crap.
Rym: so I think I'm gonna be the one who bites the bullet buys it all and then makes torrents.
Scott: Yep, so don't go buy these albums.
Scott: rimmel by them and then everyone else in the whole world will download them.
Rym: You know, what's scary?
Rym: There are like ten torrents on pirates Bay.
Rym: Well linked to on pirates Bay For Levins polka the song from spinny leak, but no other song by Lloyd.
Rym: too much is that one?
Scott: Because people don't care about the other songs.
Scott: They just want the one.
Scott: so they do.
Rym: That's why iTunes is kicking out, you know the snow You know how many threads out there are people saying why isn't loitering on iTunes?
Rym: I want their songs.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: Yeah, but as soon as someone buys one or two other Lloyd's in the songs They probably won't like them as much and they won't buy any more.
Rym: Yeah, people might be turned off by the fact that some of their music is instrumental.
Rym: Oh It's good though.
Rym: It's like nice ambient.
Scott: Cool.
Scott: Yeah, this one is an instrumental all.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think there's any.
Rym: it's acapella.
Rym: Yeah, because there's the one guy who all he seems to do is go.
Rym: Hey boy Hey boy.
Rym: Hey boy.
Rym: Oh Love it up.
Rym: Dump it up.
Rym: Dump.
Rym: Okay So in the video game news Well, actually in the podcast news Scott's breathing into the microphone really loudly.
Rym: but in video game news, I Actually did not notice this.
Rym: first one of my friends scooped me and then we both scooped Scott because he happened to be at Home with his parents and missed it.
Rym: on Sunday I was pointed out to me by a good friend Scott Johnson that there's a new Phoenix right game for the DS coming out.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: Oh my god gonna bite as soon as it comes out.
Rym: Oh my god It was on other sites before.
Rym: it was on kotaku Which is funny because kotaku is like the biggest that they like Phoenix right more than they should.
Scott: Oh they do.
Rym: indeed and it's hard to like.
Scott: the Phoenix right came out.
Scott: for months They were throwing Phoenix right references jokes and images into like an article per day.
Scott: Just go to kotaku and go find out when Phoenix right came out.
Scott: go to their page and you'll see there are disproportionate number of Articles about the game or referencing the game.
Rym: now the link I give has a bunch of screenshots Which they know exactly what we want to see.
Rym: because if you look through the screenshots They you'll notice things like.
Rym: you'll see some text whatever but then you realize who's saying the text and oh Yep, yep, yep a character.
Scott: I suggest you play the current Phoenix right before you play this one.
Rym: Yes, but I think the title of this game says it all.
Rym: the title of the game is Phoenix right ace attorney justice for all.
Scott: Yes, just you know the site that we're linking to is planet GameCube which They sometimes have reviews and stuff.
Scott: That's actually Content created by them, but mostly what they do is Take Nintendo press releases and third-party press releases and they go to the press websites where you can get you know The press images and all that stuff and they just paste it right up there as soon as it comes out.
Rym: I also hear that they have a lot of ads on their site.
Scott: they do but I blocked them all.
Rym: Yeah, me too.
Rym: The site looks really nice if you run adblock.
Scott: Yeah, the site does look really nice.
Scott: You run adblock.
Scott: Okay, I got some non-video game news, but it's pretty big bastard.
Scott: Apple released today the MacBook after releasing the MacBook Pro, I Think the MacBook Pro actually got some updates like a shinier screen and such.
Scott: What's new in this MacBook?
Scott: Well, obviously the Intel processor.
Scott: it's Dual core.
Scott: That comes with that little Apple remote-controlled.
Scott: it looks like an iPod shuffle.
Rym: Oh, I like that thing.
Scott: Yeah, it's got front row.
Scott: It's 13 inches.
Scott: it's got a 1280 by 800 screen.
Scott: It's pretty powerful.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: 512 megs of RAM, but you can get up to two gigs if you want 60 gig hard drive, but you can get up to like a hundred and something if you want.
Rym: Oh get to.
Rym: the important part is black.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: No, you can get a black MacBook Pro.
Rym: now They're there.
Scott: Okay, your options are when buying a MacBook for a regular MacBook You have three options.
Scott: number one.
Scott: Do you get the shitty?
Scott: 1.83 gigahertz MacBook?
Scott: that's gonna be white no matter what.
Scott: Yeah shitty.
Scott: if you get the two gigahertz MacBook Which is the one you should buy because the only one worth getting you have a choice between white and black.
Scott: However, if you get black the only limitation is that you your hard drive is gonna be at least 80 gigs.
Scott: You can get a white two gigahertz with a 60 your hard drive.
Rym: So they're definitely pulling this whole.
Rym: Yes The black ones are better.
Rym: So if you see someone with a black one, it's got more.
Scott: Well, someone could have a white one with more but if you have a black one, it meets the minimum Qual.
Rym: you know, it's like an old MMOs where if you had a black cowl or a black shirt It was like goddamn that guy's got black stuff.
Scott: Well, that was puzzle pirate specifically with no It was.
Rym: it was also very specific to the realm Okay, where black clothing was incredibly rare and expensive and if you got a hold of a vial of black dye or a black Baldrick it was like it would go for millions Mm-hmm.
Scott: Yeah So yeah If you carry around your black MacBook people will know that you're more badass and rich than the people with the white MacBooks.
Scott: I Compared this thing to some other Laptops and it's actually a pretty good deal Especially since it comes with you know, the OS X and the I life in the front row.
Rym: And yeah, I mean these things are good laptops, but they're also the boot camp.
Rym: They're viable desktop replacements Mm-hmm.
Rym: I mean, they're that powerful.
Scott: You're not gonna be playing any awesome game.
Scott: Well, actually it's pretty wicked fast with the dual core, but the video card is an Intel's 950 graphics card with 64 megs of you know shared RAM.
Scott: So you're not gonna be playing.
Scott: you could probably play some normal games on it But don't expect to install windows of boot camp and then install DirectX and then play.
Scott: the awesome is new games.
Scott: You know, you could but you might not be able to play oblivion, but you could probably old oblivion And you could.
Scott: you probably might not have the greatest experience playing, you know, super half-life 2 But you could probably play counter-strike and half-life 1 very nicely.
Rym: now I find it incredibly interesting that I saw this news reported all over the place.
Rym: I mean I saw it on the o'farrick and everywhere most people who talk about the new MacBook stuff.
Rym: The primary thing they said was black ones Like.
Rym: that's the news.
Rym: people reported not the specs not anything else Just the fact the fact that it has a camera in it.
Rym: No, no, they did.
Rym: Oh, it's black and that was the news.
Rym: Yeah, but no one cares about anything else.
Scott: Those are just Mac people who are pinned by Mac.
Rym: Yeah, but here's the thing my head right now.
Rym: I'm thinking ooh black.
Scott: well, see that's what they do is let's Think about this.
Rym: Nintendo does the same thing.
Rym: Look, of course game boy put out a boy with a color to it.
Scott: Yeah, what you do is you put out one product and you don't have a lot of variation.
Scott: So that way when you do have variation, it's a big deal.
Scott: If you just released a hundred colors at once people wouldn't go Red ooh green.
Scott: they'd be like I can get any color I want and they take it for granted.
Scott: if you put out only white ones Then all the people who want it for what it is right away get the white ones and then You put out red ones and people are like red.
Scott: Whoa And then people get red ones and then you then you make the special edition ones.
Scott: Yeah, then the colors have some sort of meaning to them like oh you got the the red one.
Scott: Holy crap.
Rym: Well, what we had a friend of ours up visiting and he already had a gameboy micro and he bought another one because it had A different skin.
Scott: Whoa, that's yeah, right.
Scott: I forgot about that.
Rym: Yeah, we made fun of him for about an hour.
Rym: Yeah, we're like, what are you doing?
Scott: Talk about throwing money away.
Rym: I was like, can I I'll buy your old one?
Rym: He's like.
Rym: no, I bought this so I can have two.
Scott: Yeah, yeah That's pissing money away.
Scott: No one should buy two macbooks to have a white one in a black one.
Scott: only buy a macbook if you need a laptop and the macbook suits your needs and The price is right for you.
Rym: My level of faith in humanity states currently that at least one person will buy one of each just for that purpose.
Scott: Probably yeah and buy whichever color you like.
Scott: better don't buy one because it's a certain color.
Scott: That's just stupid.
Scott: You're just an apples tool if you do that.
Rym: So things of the day Just remember you can go to frontroadcrew.com and the links to the things of the day will be right there because usually they're things We want to talk about but they're also things we want you to see.
Scott: Yeah, things of the day kind of need to be seen.
Scott: they can't just be talked about by us.
Scott: you know what the best is actually if you listen at a computer and We talk about the thing of the day while you look at it unless it's a spinny leak because then you'll be hypnotized.
Scott: Yeah hypnotism not so good when listening to a podcast Alright, so for people who know my political views.
Rym: I I really like Al Gore.
Rym: as a person.
Rym: I'm not gonna get into policy or anything.
Rym: We're not on my thing of the day while it involves all these things.
Rym: I'm not here to talk about politics.
Rym: I'm not here to argue either way on environmentalism or global warming or anything.
Scott: goddamn dirty hippies.
Rym: All I want to say is that this is probably the most fear-mongering Movie trailer I've ever seen in my life.
Scott: I agree.
Rym: I mean, this is beyond the the spin of Fahrenheit 9/11.
Rym: This is like I'd say it's pretty equal.
Rym: The trailer is like you will all die.
Rym: You are all going to die.
Rym: Everyone is going to die.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: We're all going to die.
Scott: Oh my god I think Al Gore is at this point is just saying let's fight fire with fire.
Rym: if they're gonna fear monger terrorists We're gonna fear monger global warming which I really think that's true because Al Gore is a smart, dude.
Rym: I don't know exactly what Al Gore's deal is but after the 2000 election he you know, he grew a beard and he was kind of quiet for a while and Then he kind of took off his mask of unoffensive unassuming liberal Democrat guy who never wanted to say anything that can anger anyone ever and he turned into Fire brand.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: This is the situation.
Rym: This country's in horrible environmental environmentalism blah.
Rym: And he's given some awesome speeches.
Rym: I mean in this trailer There's a funny bit where he introduces himself is like hi.
Rym: I'm Al Gore.
Rym: I used to be the next president of the United States haha Pined.
Rym: but watch this movie trailer.
Rym: I defy you to find anything more fear mongering than that.
Rym: that is also a trailer for a major motion picture.
Scott: Any disaster movie?
Rym: Yeah, but those don't monger fear those monger the liking or enjoying or watching a fear.
Rym: Oh Okay, this movie is like you're going to die not what?
Rym: if something happened and we all died in this independence day?
Rym: That was more root aliens root aliens.
Rym: Let's drag your ass through the desert.
Rym: That glass bulletproof Yes, sir.
Scott: Oh, no, sir way to ruin it.
Scott: Yeah, I messed it up.
Rym: Yeah, I like Independence Day, even though it's stupid.
Scott: Well Smith is just so funny when he drags the aliens through the desert.
Rym: It is the best all right, so you got a thing of the day right I sure do?
Scott: everyone knows about dance dance revolution?
Scott: Oh, yeah, do you know about?
Rym: Step mania step mania everyone knows about.
Scott: I think step mania is DDR for the computer But it's free.
Rym: You can make your own songs.
Rym: You can get illegal versions of all the songs from DDR.
Rym: I don't know where you can actually get these songs.
Rym: DDR Brazil Brazil DDR Brazil but Spain huh, I don't actually remember.
Rym: okay doesn't matter.
Rym: anyone who has step mania knows where to get it.
Scott: That's for sure.
Scott: So yeah, it's basically DDR for your computer, which you can turn into a real DDR machine without paying Konami any money.
Scott: so Red octane who makes in the groove and the DDR pads and guitar hero and all that stuff go guitar hero.
Scott: They make it our hero.
Scott: Someone said hey if we could make step mania.
Scott: Why don't we make free tar hero?
Scott: and This guy Anton streak.
Scott: I guess is his name because that's his domain name Has made a program called free tar hero.
Scott: It's not actually out yet It's gonna be actually two programs also one program is the song editor Which you take an mp3 or any other song and you make the notes to it?
Scott: and The other piece of software is the game that will allow you to play the things you make in the editor.
Scott: so Right now the only thing on this site is a video of how the editor works.
Scott: and I have to say Compared to all the things that let you edit DDR arrows.
Scott: This is incredible.
Rym: The video will get you really excited about this game.
Rym: Yeah, I am excited.
Rym: I want to make songs.
Scott: see now what this does for me is I was thinking maybe I'll buy a Ps2 to get the guitar hero and some racing games, you know, but now I'm thinking hey screw that shit.
Scott: I'll get free tar hero a guitar from red octane for the PC and then I'll get a 360 and we and we'll be set All right.
Rym: Yeah The best part about this video is the selection of songs they use to show the capabilities of the editor is Perhaps the perfect collection of songs to showcase how awesome this game could be.
Scott: It's not 100% perfect, but it's a damn good selection.
Rym: Yeah, I don't think it could be a hundred percent perfect.
Rym: How long would it have to be?
Scott: But there was no Led Zeppelin.
Scott: adding one Led Zeppelin song would have improved it greatly.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, probably but that's it.
Scott: Yeah, free tar hero.
Scott: Look forward to it.
Scott: free guitar hero.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: So continuing with worst week.
Scott: It is video game day So we're not gonna talk about the worst video games because we'll be here forever.
Scott: ET custard's ready to custard's revenge.
Scott: ET custard's revenge.
Rym: custard's revenge Gameplay wise was significantly better than ET.
Scott: the extraterrestrial ET was a bad game, but it was not a hundred percent bad.
Scott: It was ninety nine point nine percent customers.
Rym: revenge had some gameplay.
Rym: You had to dodge those answers.
Scott: avenge.
Scott: It might as well be a hundred percent bad.
Scott: No, it was about raping a Native American woman.
Scott: Oh giant breasts and she's all pixelated Atari stuff.
Rym: But here's the thing.
Scott: All right, it doesn't get right than that.
Scott: So you got.
Scott: you're saying that a te Telefono la casa is worse now.
Rym: They gotta hear me anything.
Scott: women with a naked Custer there's dodging arrows.
Rym: Now.
Rym: You got to hear me out here.
Rym: Custer's revenge is not that bad a game.
Rym: in the same way that from a pure ideological standpoint I agree with some of what the South was doing in the Civil War Because if the Civil War is just about states rights woo go south.
Rym: The problem was the Civil War was also about slavery.
Rym: so boo South Custer's revenge.
Rym: the game is a typical semi crappy Atari game, but it's not the bottom of the barrel.
Rym: However, it is skinned with probably the most offensive thing that has ever been put in a video game ever.
Rym: Oh Rendition I'll make the text adventure.
Rym: you get on that 3d one.
Rym: All right You know what.
Rym: if we did that we would probably get a whole bunch of traffic to the site.
Scott: We probably would All right, I think I'd put it on my site not the GeekNights say yeah But we definitely had to say something about.
Rym: this.
Rym: is a front row crew production.
Scott: Yeah, we would we don't.
Scott: we don't even say This is a front row crew production when it is.
Rym: So we decided to not talk about video games.
Rym: we're just talking about consoles and hardware.
Rym: Otherwise, we'd be here all night.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Now.
Rym: I got a long list in no particular order chronological order semi Chronological order.
Rym: I kinda was real fast and loose with that All right.
Rym: And also I might just forget or skip around.
Rym: and I'd like to note again that we're trying to be somewhat objective here.
Rym: We're not talking about things that we dislike.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: This is worst week Not Rym and Scott heat week because it was Rym and Scott heat week.
Scott: We would probably talk about Sony.
Rym: Yeah Sony Yeah Yeah, like.
Scott: but it's not heat week.
Scott: It's worst week.
Scott: So it's not things we hate It's things that are terrible because everyone they're basically useless.
Rym: like the best example here just to show the difference here Is that the game gear which is one thing we're going to talk about.
Rym: I love the game gear.
Rym: I own a game gear.
Rym: I if I could find the game gear that I own would probably still play it occasionally But it's terrible.
Rym: It was an awesome piece of technology.
Rym: That was still a miserable failure and thus deserves to be on the worst list is a better example.
Scott: I really don't like Chrysler Sebring convertibles because I just don't like them but it's a car.
Rym: What did one like hit you when you were a kid?
Scott: I don't know I just don't like them but It seems like a car that pretends to be a sports fast car when really is just a normal shitty car like a Landry.
Scott: That isn't an evolution kind of but at least those look cool.
Scott: But the Ford Pinto is a piece of shit.
Scott: Everyone knows it.
Scott: There's no there's no butts about it.
Scott: It's just terrible.
Scott: So a Ford Pinto will make it into worst week.
Rym: It was a Plymouth Horizon Exactly.
Scott: It's not a joy to ride But the Sebring will only make it into Rimm and Scott hate week and not worst week.
Rym: So we're going to start with probably one of the most infamous old-school failures at video gaming the Philips CDI.
Scott: Oh, man, that thing was just terrific.
Scott: I want one so bad It had so many great games and this interesting roller controller.
Scott: Oh, it was fit.
Scott: Oh, man.
Scott: Why is that in worst week?
Rym: Yeah, I mean it had that connect for game and all those Zelda games.
Scott: Oh, yeah Those all the games that were things of the day a while ago the videos on YouTube of the openings and endings that were hilarious.
Scott: Yeah, the Philips CDI came out of a long complicated clusterfuck between Nintendo Sony and Phillips When they were trying to make CD-ROM attachments for the SNES and they came up with a standard called the CDI standard.
Scott: Yes, they never had never really worked out Right and what ended up happening was Phillips just busted out on their own and came out with the CDI.
Rym: Yeah But they had an agreement because of this whole clusterfuck with Nintendo To be able to use Nintendo characters and Nintendo franchises in their games for a little while.
Rym: So Nintendo was contractually obligated to let them make these horrible Zelda games.
Rym: Luckily the thing was an abysmal failure because no one in their right mind would buy it.
Rym: It was very expensive.
Rym: It had terrible games.
Rym: The first games that came out for were just board games that you played on your TV.
Scott: Yeah, according to that we have this handy chart here that came out recently showing adjusted for inflation the Costs of every important console at release in the u.s.
Rym: We'll be referring to this a lot today.
Scott: the CDI cost the equivalent of $400 when it came out.
Rym: Yeah, $400.
Rym: That's an Xbox 360.
Rym: It sure is the CDI was just shit.
Scott: That's the best Xbox 360.
Rym: It had terrible load times.
Rym: The games were crap the the system barely worked at lots of problems making them function and they broke down all the time.
Rym: They were a complete failure on the market.
Rym: Phillips tried to re-engineer them to sell them as like business kiosks and stuff and that failed.
Rym: and the whole abysmal failure was Discontinued and forgotten.
Scott: It was supposed to be all cool because CDs are big in those days and everyone just wanted CDs CDs But it didn't actually get you anything.
Scott: It just sucked.
Rym: Yeah laser discs were more popular than the Phillips CDI.
Rym: That says a lot.
Scott: So CDI one of the worst consoles ever.
Rym: now that was a case of bad technology for a high price.
Rym: There's really no redeeming factor not one.
Scott: I can't think of a single reason anyone would want a Phillips CDI unless By some miracle there was actually maybe one or two good games using the roller controller Which is the giant yellow yellow ball that you would spin around.
Rym: Now we could go on to another.
Rym: here's a whole different list of worse.
Rym: These are all lumped together because they all failed for the same reason the game gear the Lynx the turbo graphics Portable what was that called?
Rym: I forget I don't remember the Sega Nomad.
Scott: Yeah Well, the Sega Nomad slightly different than the others, but in general they all have the same problem.
Scott: There are portable systems that weren't very portable.
Rym: They were incredibly badass in terms of technology.
Rym: The game gear is similar in size to the PSP only about three times thicker and heavier.
Rym: Yeah, but back in the day when it came out I mean the Game Boy had that lime green screen that you couldn't see for shit.
Rym: It was a crap.
Rym: Oh system.
Rym: The game gear was a full-color backlit LCD.
Scott: You could get a TV tuner for it.
Scott: It took four double-a batteries and it drained right away it.
Rym: No, it took six double-a batteries.
Scott: All right six nevermind.
Rym: Sorry It lasted about three hours on those batteries Mmm, but I mean the system was hot too.
Rym: Yeah, it was but the system was extremely powerful Extremely badass and it wasn't that expensive.
Rym: It was very expensive, but it could have been worse.
Scott: It was cheap enough for a lot of people actually had game gears.
Scott: The problem was is that the games released for the game gear weren't portable style games Thing with the turbo graphics 16 portable it was.
Scott: they weren't portable games.
Scott: They were console games games that were designed to be played on your TV sitting on the couch.
Scott: Only they let you take them around with you and that doesn't work too.
Rym: Well, yep Well, it was basically a portable console as opposed to a portable.
Rym: Yep I mean I use my game gear only in the car where I knew I wouldn't be interrupted because if I started playing a game It was basically a Sega game.
Rym: I had to play my whole thing and I couldn't save my game or anything for quite some time.
Rym: I remember having races between my battery and finding a save point.
Scott: if you notice the game boy the original game boy Which didn't suck at all?
Rym: Well, it's like it kind of sucked technologically technologically speaking.
Scott: but the reason that the games didn't suck and the reason the game boy won in the end is because of the kind of games it had were games like Kirby's pinball which you could just play and then turn off Yoshi to play and turn off Tetris play and turn off.
Rym: I mean consider this the.
Rym: the original game boy is one of the highest selling video game things ever.
Scott: If you take the game boy the game boy pocket the game boy color and the game boy advance Which are all really the game boy Just you know I mean the game boy advance really isn't any different than the game boy and the game boy color Any more than the DS light is different from the DS.
Scott: It's just plus plus.
Scott: They're really all the same platform.
Scott: The game boy is the number one video game in the world period.
Rym: I mean The original game boy.
Rym: probably outsold the game gear the links the turbo graphics thing and all those other Things that came out combined by by an order of magnitude at least and the game boy pocket sold insane.
Scott: I think everyone replaced their game boys the game boy pockets.
Scott: I actually was still playing their game boys.
Rym: I didn't because I had my game gear and I had those eight games.
Scott: And then when the game boy color came out a lot of people bought that but not so many.
Scott: But then when the game boy advance came out that sold more than the original.
Scott: that sold more than anything.
Rym: Now the Lynx was worse than the game gear in that it was more powerful and better and cost more.
Scott: It also came out earlier.
Rym: I mean the game it came with.
Rym: it was blue something.
Scott: It was this like flight sim fighting game that I remember the TV commercial that showed a kid in the school bathroom playing it.
Scott: Wasn't that the TV commercial?
Rym: I Brings a bell.
Scott: That's what I remember.
Scott: You're flying.
Scott: it might not be right, but I remember the flight sim game.
Scott: So that's definitely real.
Rym: I played a Lynx and it was pretty badass But the thing was hellishly expensive.
Rym: the games were few and far between and it just disappeared off the shelves.
Scott: Yeah, I remember seeing TV commercials for the Lynx and I think I saw it in a Toys R Us once But I never knew anyone who had one.
Scott: I never knew anyone who played one.
Scott: I And it disappeared and the commercials went away and that was that I mean at least the game flash in the pen.
Rym: The game gear was marketed heavily and it was fairly popular.
Rym: it If you at least if you look at it the game gear is very similar in terms of the sales and demographics to the PSP.
Scott: Yeah, it was set.
Scott: it sold second most when compared to the game boy But it had a lot of fancy fancy awesome game and it did sell quite a bit.
Rym: I mean the game gear did very well early on.
Scott: a lot of people have game gears, but it just died out.
Scott: It couldn't maintain.
Rym: And we're not.
Rym: I'm not really ragging on the PSP I'm just saying that there's a trend that that type of system does not die completely.
Scott: But it will be is definitely on a level above these things so far.
Scott: Who knows maybe ten years from now the PSP will be in worst week.
Scott: Maybe not but right now it's not.
Scott: but game gear is and the PSP looks to be the same thing.
Rym: It is my my opinion my belief that the PSP is going to fall the same way that the aimed ear gear did.
Rym: It's not a Lynx It's not a total failure because there are games for it and people seem to like it.
Rym: But there were games for the game gear and people seem to like it.
Rym: This console itself was just not a sustainable market.
Rym: Yep Now back to well, we didn't even met.
Rym: we'd said the Sega Nomad that was like the worst offender in terms of games.
Rym: Well, it's just it just played Sega games.
Scott: Well, the Sega Nomad.
Scott: what they tried to do is that the Genesis was kind of flailing.
Scott: So they came out the Sega Nomad, which is a portable Sega Genesis.
Scott: What do you do to take Sega Genesis games?
Scott: you stick it into the Nomad and you can play them in your car Point.
Rym: the first Sega Genesis games are big.
Scott: Yeah, this thing the Genesis games would stick out of it big-time - it was real big and heavy and black and Three as I was talking before about portable games.
Scott: Well now you're taking it a step further.
Scott: You're playing the console games themselves with you wherever you go.
Rym: Those games are not conducive to popping off a five-minute game and stopping not at all.
Scott: And considering you even lost the two-player of any you know any hope?
Rym: yep, and that thing ate batteries like a motherfucker.
Rym: Yeah, it ate the batteries the game gears the worst offender there.
Scott: Not too many people bought it.
Rym: I think it's slightly boosted the Genesis and then it disappeared though a little trick if anyone still has a game gear You know, it takes six batteries.
Rym: I'll find a link to a picture or something, but two of those batteries Power, it's one or two of them power the backlight and the rest of them power the system.
Rym: Yep, those two batteries died long before everything else.
Rym: So if you rotated your batteries around you could get a lot more life out of them.
Scott: or you could buy two Wicked awesome batteries and put them in those holes and then use normal shit batteries in the rest of the holes.
Rym: or I saw some People at jury-rigged little extenders where they put three batteries there for a total of seven batteries.
Rym: Mmm, that seemed to do the trick.
Scott: my friend hit is he bought these third-party grips.
Scott: They were actually little black things that you stuck.
Scott: They were like battery packs, but And grips and you stuck them into the battery slots and you plugged it into the wall and it charged up the battery packs And it would last a bit longer than just normal batteries.
Rym: I had this big black thing that would hang from the bottom and it looked like a telephone receiver, but it did the same thing.
Scott: Yeah, it's just what you need on an already humongous black system is yeah that thing weighed over a pound with all the batteries on It.
Scott: yeah I mean the original Gameboy was huge and it wasn't until the Gameboy Pocket where they made the screen bigger and it only used Two triple-a batteries or three triple-a batteries.
Scott: It was it was real.
Scott: It was a huge improvement.
Scott: if you want to talk about improvements You think the SP was so much better than the GBA or the DS light is so much better than the DS.
Scott: Compare the Gameboy Pocket to the Gameboy.
Scott: Yeah, that's the biggest leap ever.
Rym: I mean it.
Rym: I didn't realize it till I went to the Nintendo store and saw an original Gameboy again.
Rym: Those things were huge and clunky and that screen was really really really tiny.
Scott: Yeah, and my brother had was like he got a Gameboy Pocket and Pokemon when it came out when the Gameboy was revived for in The Pokemon days got.
Scott: that thing is thin.
Scott: It's small.
Scott: The screen is big and awesome.
Scott: It takes very few batteries triple-a batteries and it lasts forever.
Scott: and it plays all original Gameboy games.
Rym: Yeah, God, I remember I had this big magnifying glass light thing that I'd stick on my Gameboy.
Scott: Oh, yeah, people had those things.
Scott: Yeah, they were funny.
Rym: I'd one for the game here too.
Rym: that just made it badass, but it was heavy.
Scott: So yeah, it's already heavy.
Scott: So why not throw some more shit on there?
Rym: now, you notice we didn't love the engage in with all this.
Rym: We're gonna talk about that later that that failed for a completely different set of reasons.
Rym: Awesome Now we got the 3do to move away from portables for a bit.
Scott: Okay Let's talk about the 3do cuz it's a special case.
Scott: First of all, according to the chart that I mentioned earlier that says the real prices of consoles The 3do is the most expensive console ever at the equivalent of seven hundred dollars.
Rym: It's slightly more expensive than the current PlayStation 3 adjusted for inflation Yep.
Scott: Now the thing with the 3do is it wasn't just one console.
Scott: What it was is a standard for consoles.
Scott: so if you wanted to and You were an electronics company You could make a 3do console as long as it met the following standards and had the following chips and all that.
Scott: So, I think there was like a 3do 3do and a Panasonic 3do and you could choose which 3do you wanted.
Scott: So you had different people competing to see who could make the best 3do console, but they all played any 3do game Just fine.
Rym: It was crazy powerful and awesome.
Scott: It was wicked powerful and there were some crazy games for it that no one remembers But one of them was start.
Scott: There was a star control version of star control 2 for the 3do.
Rym: I mean this is back when Arcades were popular partly because the games in the arcades were so amazing looking compared to games at home.
Scott: Yeah, if you went to the arcade and played Ninja Turtles 2, that was the shit.
Scott: But then if you played Ninja Turtles 2 arcade version for the NES, it was the same game, but it didn't compare at all Yep, and there were a lot of reasons for that.
Rym: The 3do was like having an arcade in your house.
Scott: The Neo Geo was like having an arcade.
Scott: Yeah, that was the point of the Neo Geo Which I'll talk about but the 3do is just Wow.
Rym: Now the problem was it was so expensive that no one bought it and there weren't any game.
Scott: I can't even remember a goddamn game for it besides star control 2 and I don't remember it because it was a 3do game.
Scott: I remember it because it's star control fucking 2.
Rym: Yeah, there was a kid I knew who lied all the time about how he had a 3do but we knew he didn't.
Scott: I Remember it because I subscribed to game pro from when I was in middle school up until just recently and I'm trying.
Scott: I'm gonna sell The magazines on eBay at some point.
Scott: Yeah, if anyone's interested Yeah, if you want like 10 or 11 years worth of game pro magazines from 95 through the present I subscribe before 95.
Scott: But in those days, they didn't have flat bindings.
Scott: So those magazines died and got thrown out.
Rym: My me and my brother have a. we share a copy of every Nintendo power from 1 until like 300.
Scott: My brother has Nintendo power, I think from like 96 to 2,000 or something like that.
Rym: I have the original covers that were banned because they were scary to little kids.
Scott: Yep Anyway, I remember seeing all these consoles in the game pro magazines the 3do and all this shit, but Never made it anywhere.
Rym: Yeah, they had failed.
Rym: simply the technology.
Rym: Well, the technology was good as technology tends to be it was just so expensive and unwieldy that no it couldn't happen.
Rym: It was a miserable failure.
Rym: It's one of the worst.
Rym: Yep Now here's a pisser.
Rym: Remember the virtual boy.
Rym: Oh god.
Scott: That's the only time I think Nintendo put out a console that just bombed.
Rym: It was like the gameboy.
Rym: color wasn't the best It wasn't a big winner But it wasn't a complete blowout like the bird now boy when the early rumors came about the virtual boy Originally was like it's gonna be a full color VR thing because back then VR was big.
Scott: Yeah, you gotta realize that You know before the days of 3d graphics and all that people were looking for virtual reality.
Scott: That was the next big thing was goggles and motion sensors power glove the activator which we'll talk about later.
Scott: Yep, I mean VR was like a lot of stuff later.
Rym: Yeah, remember that show VR five your VR troopers.
Rym: God.
Rym: Yeah, VR was the buzzword back then.
Rym: it was the thing.
Rym: So Nintendo was gonna capitalize on that and make this full color immersive Virtual reality console and they wouldn't correct their mistake until 2006 with the Wii.
Rym: Yeah, so then as time went on Nintendo seemed to realize that alright We can't make this color because then maybe one person could afford it.
Rym: Yep, so they made it red and black.
Scott: I remember I played a virtual boy in the store Toys R Us of course in those days and I played Mario Tennis.
Scott: It was I think that was the first Mario Tennis.
Rym: It might have been I think it was cuz.
Scott: this was an old console it was and It was just a pain in the ass to play and the depth really fucked with my head.
Rym: See, I like.
Rym: I liked playing it like it was really fun and it looked really cool.
Rym: But after about ten minutes my eyes would hurt and I get a headache.
Scott: The problem was you had to like lean over to get your head into it.
Scott: It was not comfortable to get to any sitting position.
Rym: It was this big red goggly thing that was heavy and plastic and you had to put it on a tripod and then lean into It.
Rym: you couldn't wear it.
Scott: the leaning into it was what hurt your back in your neck.
Rym: The controller was actually kind of good.
Scott: the controller I think was the first one to have the grips.
Scott: Like, you know today the GameCube controller the PlayStation control the Xbox controller they all have a piece of plastic that just comes down on the left and the right that you grab your extra fingers around to hold on to the controller.
Scott: the virtual boy Was the first one that I remember.
Scott: that had that where all your extra fingers grabbed on to this thing instead of floating around In the middle of nowhere, but the virtual boy was painful stupid terrible One of the worst things ever.
Rym: Nintendo realized this right away and it basically just died.
Rym: Yeah, like no question Nintendo was like, alright fuck this.
Scott: No one bought it.
Scott: No one wanted it.
Scott: Everything sucked.
Scott: They put it out on the shelves and then it was gone.
Rym: I have a friend back in high school who still has his virtual boy.
Scott: Yeah having a virtual boy see the virtual boy taught me one thing whenever a new console comes out if There's a chance of it dying or you're not sure about it Especially if it's a Nintendo console just get it because at the best you have something that's gonna be awesome And at the worst like let's say the Wii completely bombs.
Scott: No one buys a Wii except you and me.
Scott: We'll be the only dudes with the Wii's.
Scott: it'll be cool like being the only dude who has a virtual boy.
Rym: Yeah, that's why we bought the DS early on cuz we weren't sure.
Rym: I I was really.
Scott: I was only 75%.
Scott: Sure, the DS is gonna kick ass and I was.
Scott: I was a hundred percent sure it had potential But I was still cautious that people wouldn't take advantage of the potential and it would suck.
Rym: Yeah, I was 50/50.
Rym: I was like wow, there's a good chance.
Scott: This is gonna fail, but I bought it Anyway, and I said it worst this will be virtual boy too and I'll have one and I'll be awesome.
Rym: Yeah, but oh my god, it didn't did not.
Rym: All right, um Atari back.
Rym: I mean it used to be like they're the 8-bit systems than NES the Sega and then saying a master system the 16-bit systems came out and right near the middle of their life cycle people were thinking All right, when's 32-bit coming?
Rym: because kids we really didn't understand what that meant.
Scott: We didn't know what that meant at all.
Rym: Their powers.
Scott: more bits meant better looking video games.
Scott: So better sounding video games.
Rym: So we were hearing the rumors of the 32-bit consoles, you know, like the PlayStation stuff like that.
Rym: Rumors rumors rumors not like not even real like the barest ass rumors.
Rym: then Atari was like we're gonna have a 64-bit console and everyone said what?
Scott: What whoa, whoa, there is status doubled the number two times.
Scott: Holy shit.
Rym: Yeah 64-bit Oh my god.
Rym: And there were like tiny reviews like tiny screenshots from development things and like the buzz was crazy.
Rym: I
Scott: remember I was at a summer camp at day camp and I had read this news in the video game magazine And I went in and I said, you know, Atari's coming out with this 64-bit video game system called the Jaguar
Rym: Jaguar Jaguar
Scott: the Jaguar and the kids are like you're lying.
Scott: Here's making shit up blah blah blah, but no I was right.
Rym: haha.
Scott: The thing is the Jaguar sucked.
Rym: not only did it suck it wasn't really 64-bit Not really.
Rym: This is right about when we all learned what bits meant because we've someone smarter than us You know.
Rym: older kids who knew better would say things like it's not really 64-bit It's just two 32-bit chips blah blah blah blah blah blah blah blah.
Rym: and my brain said wait a minute research research.
Rym: hey That's what bits are.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I Learned about all the MMC chips in the different Nintendo games and why you couldn't go backwards in Mario 1 stuff like that.
Rym: Jaguar was a terrible failure and it died.
Scott: Let's see.
Scott: What was terrible at the Jaguar number one?
Scott: useless games number two There was some weird CD attachment thing.
Scott: That was just useless.
Rym: number three.
Rym: It was horribly expensive.
Scott: There were three is hardly sensitive number four.
Scott: It was real powerful, but the games weren't 3d or anything.
Scott: It didn't provide anything.
Scott: the 16-bit systems didn't provide.
Rym: Yep, like number four the controller The controller it wasn't the worst controller ever.
Scott: What do you thought?
Scott: Do you remember the controller?
Rym: All right, I submit to you the fucking Intellivision to control.
Scott: No, look what did the Jaguar controller have?
Rym: All right The Intellivision 2 had a puck that didn't work and broke and instead of buttons it had four Depressions on the side of it.
Rym: you had to jam your fingernail in to make work The Jaguar at the top of it.
Scott: It was this big square thing bigger than a Dreamcast controller but it was kind of flat and at the top there was like an arrow thing and some button things, but at the Majority of the controller was taken up by one button for I think every letter of the alphabet if I remember correctly It was insane.
Rym: It was this monstrosity Like you.
Rym: look at it and think what is that?
Scott: What the fuck do I need those buttons for?
Scott: am I supposed to push all those buttons while I play a game?
Rym: That's bigger than my game gear.
Scott: What the hell?
Scott: It sucked.
Rym: Also the Super Nintendo and the Sega Genesis were still going strong.
Scott: Yeah, so the Jaguar tried to come out to start the next generation while the 16-bit was still going strong.
Scott: bad move.
Scott: You got to wait until everyone knows.
Scott: you wait until the current generation starts to wane and then you start the new one.
Scott: That's the only reason that they keep coming out with new consoles.
Scott: They would be perfectly content to put out one console and just keep selling games for it forever.
Scott: The reason they sell new consoles is because people lose interest and that when you come out with a new console Then the interest resurges they and you know, then it wanes and then you're releasing new console every four or five years.
Rym: Yep Plus games.
Rym: just you run out of potential in certain types of games because you've done everything that console can do other than just make More of the same.
Rym: Yep Alright now the Jaguar was terrible.
Rym: the Sega 32x Sega CD all that Sega shit after.
Rym: Basically Sega after the Genesis went nowhere Okay.
Scott: Well, there's the Sega Genesis is just fine.
Scott: It's very popular around the world.
Rym: The master system really didn't do well.
Scott: master system didn't do so well in America, but it did.
Scott: Okay, you know, it wasn't junk.
Scott: It was definitely wasn't junk.
Scott: like the Jaguar the virtual boy.
Rym: Nintendo was number one.
Rym: Sega was a trailing number two, but it was there and they were making money.
Rym: Yep, the Genesis.
Rym: they were much closer, but the Super Nintendo was still dominated far and away.
Rym: Not really Well, not counting foreign sales outside of America.
Scott: in Japan in the 16-bit days the SNES and the Genesis were just like right on.
Rym: I think the NES had a longer staying power.
Scott: It did have a slightly longer staying power because what happened was the Sega Genesis.
Scott: They decided they're gonna do the Sega CD now.
Scott: the Sega CD wasn't a standalone console.
Scott: It was a thing you added on to the Genesis to play CD games and the CD games are still 16-bit games.
Scott: They just had so much storage on the disc that they could have CD quality audio and videos and that sort of shit.
Rym: now What did they do with this amazing potential?
Scott: They made crap-ass shit game.
Rym: They put FMV's and movies.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: I think only good game for the Sega CD as far as I'm concerned is Sonic CD.
Rym: Remember that sewer rats game?
Rym: Yep, or there was the Sherlock Holmes sewer shark.
Rym: sewer shark That's it or the Sherlock Holmes Jurassic Park.
Rym: as far as I could tell it was just movies of a guy who looked like Sherlock.
Scott: Yeah now the Sega CD originally was like more money than the say the Genesis itself and it was this giant thing bigger than a normal CD player that you Put under your Genesis.
Scott: It was crazy.
Rym: It was also expensive.
Scott: Then they came out with a better version of the Sega CD where you put your Genesis on it And it would.
Scott: the part that took the CDs was kind of to the right side of the Genesis and it was a lot better.
Scott: then They came out the 32 X. now the 32 X was the thing you put in the cartridge slot of the Genesis and then you But 32 X cartridges into it.
Rym: now think about all that for a minute.
Rym: Does that sound complicated?
Rym: because it was.
Scott: it was people.
Scott: no one bought the 32 X. there were no games for it That were memorable or useful.
Scott: Supposedly if you had one it would improve the goodness of your Sega Genesis games that you put into it.
Scott: But I don't know about that.
Scott: I think that's not work shit.
Scott: Yeah So Sega CD 32 X games where if you had all three things the Genesis to see Sega CD in a 32 X all hooked Up into one monster system that you could play these games and no one played those.
Rym: Yeah, those games sold great.
Rym: I can't name one.
Scott: there was a thing you could buy that was a Sega Genesis and a Sega CD combined into one device and then you could stick A 32 X into that.
Rym: that came out like the end of the life cycle.
Scott: That was the end and the Sega Genesis died.
Scott: now the 32 X and the Sega CD were yes Those are the worst.
Scott: the genesis was not the word.
Rym: I never knew anyone who owned any of them.
Rym: I only played them at Funko Land.
Scott: I know people who had the Sega Genesis and I knew someone who had the Genesis.
Scott: but no no Sega CD No one guy who had the Sega CD and no one had the 32 X. absolutely no one.
Rym: now the Sega Saturn Just to mention it was really badass and it failed for mostly.
Scott: Sega Saturn failed a lot in this country But it didn't fail in Japan and there are quite a few awesome games for the Sega Saturn that I want to play.
Scott: But I guess because it's too difficult to get the equipment.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: We are the games are in Japanese.
Rym: We only mentioned the Sega Saturn because it is not on our worst list.
Rym: It is only worst because we didn't get to have it.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: If only the Sega Saturn had somehow Come out with the only reason the PlayStation or the Saturn could survive You know against the n64 or even the SNES You know was because a Final Fantasy 7.
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: I know we say this a lot but really Nintendo and Sony had this and square there was this huge clusterfuck and The the higher-ups of Nintendo and square had a fight like angry at each other over the technology and the direction of the games and Nintendo's refusal to switch away from cartridges and They jump ship from Nintendo to Sony and that was like that.
Rym: That was the linchpin in the video game industry.
Scott: if it wasn't for Final Fantasy 7 the PlayStation 1 would have died The Sega Saturn would have died.
Scott: the n64 would have been the only thing there was.
Rym: Yep, Freddy if you were too young to remember this, you know now like when the Xbox when?
Rym: when the Xbox was first announced When it was so told that Microsoft was making a console the world of nerds who heard this laugh their asses off and just oh My god, how could this be?
Rym: This is the stupidest thing ever and when the Xbox came out it did terribly.
Scott: They lost I think about four billion dollars in the Xbox.
Rym: It did so terrible.
Rym: now They're okay.
Rym: Yeah, because while no one bought it Microsoft had so much money.
Rym: They just kept pumping money and pumping research and pumping games and pumping everything into it to keep it afloat until it took off.
Rym: Sony succeeded because of Final Fantasy.
Rym: Yep But when Sony when it was announced that Sony was making a console before we knew any of this Final Fantasy stuff It was treated by the gaming community the same way that Microsoft was.
Rym: when they announced the Xbox People said Sony can't make games.
Rym: What the hell.
Rym: who could beat Sega and Nintendo?
Scott: Yeah, when I first saw the PlayStation in those game pro magazines, it looked to me like 3do2.
Scott: I was like up here comes more 3do type shit.
Scott: the Sega Saturn at least kind of made sense You know, even though it died.
Scott: Yeah, a lot of people rooted for the Sega Saturn Yep, but in the n64, I was actually kind of about it Especially the weird-looking controller.
Scott: that didn't seem to find an advantage.
Scott: actually until you had the 3d game.
Rym: What really got me there was that right around n64 is when PC gaming it kind of exploded.
Scott: Yeah, that's also true.
Rym: That was like I would consider that the golden age of PC gaming there was 96 yeah, like that whole air.
Rym: basically my high school consisted of only PC games and Original SNES NES games.
Scott: the 64 actually came out the year after the PlayStation in the Saturn.
Scott: It was sort of a response, you know more than a also ran.
Scott: Yeah, so if the PlayStation didn't have Final Fantasy 7 then you know Who knows maybe the SNES would have gone even longer or the n64 would have been different or who knows?
Rym: That was also really the point at which Nintendo went from being this crazy like Monopoly on gaming to just a profitable game company.
Scott: Yep, and the PC gaming really did take a lot away from the consoles in the late 90s.
Rym: Yeah Well, we do a whole show on that.
Scott: Those are the days when there was Windows 95 starting with Windows 95 PC gaming got huge.
Scott: Yeah, well, that's when like OpenGL and all those sorts of things and people, you know games like met courier to Half-Life 1 I Counter-strike quake to wake to wait - was like huge quake one Doom it was.
Scott: it was earlier.
Scott: That was like 94 95 Yeah, but yeah in the late DOS days in the early Windows 95 98 days Grand Theft Auto 1.
Rym: for the Windows 95 I mean gaming really splintered and the whole market was civilization - this was a period when console gaming a lot of people were Thinking that maybe it was going to die and be replaced by PC gaming.
Scott: and then Final Fantasy playstation 1 All that kind of it was really Final Fantasy 7 on the PlayStation and Goldeneye.
Scott: They carried the consoles over it, you know to The current generation which is now ending.
Rym: Yep, because the current generation is really when PC gaming.
Rym: We're not gonna have this argument again with all of our list.
Rym: Well, not all of our listeners But a few loud members of our listening audience started to fade away again.
Rym: PC gaming started dying and console gaming is taking off crazy again.
Rym: Yep now we've talked for a long time.
Rym: So we're gonna try to be brief on the rest of our list.
Rym: we've got a lot of worse here because they're game consoles are something that are really.
Scott: they either win big or they fail miserably because you have to sell hardware at a loss and Then you have to sell expensive razor blade games.
Scott: Yep, and with that business model if you manage to sell people enough people the console at a loss then you win But if you don't then you just lost a giant pile of money and you fail.
Rym: there's very little middle ground.
Rym: I mean the game gear was middle ground because the game gear did okay, but it did didn't.
Scott: it didn't you either?
Scott: You can do it, but you have to keep it going so rare.
Rym: if you're in that middle ground You're like a crazy anomaly in the gaming industry.
Scott: Releasing a new game console is like one of the worst business decisions you can do.
Rym: Yeah, except Nintendo, which they're really the only company now that makes a profit on their consoles even early on.
Scott: Well, I think what they do is when they make the console they think about, you know We will not possibly do anything to not profit.
Scott: Yeah Nintendo to not profit No one would have to buy this at all.
Rym: Nintendo is one of the most profitable percentage wise corporations in the world In terms of expenditures versus not.
Rym: it's yeah, not total money no, but not by far God, you know Hello Burton in Blackwater, but yeah, Nintendo is insanely profitable.
Rym: So all these people who keep saying oh Nintendo is dying.
Rym: Nintendo is dying I mean especially in the n64 like the late n64.
Rym: days before the GameCube came out a lot of people kept saying Nintendo was dying not Noticing that Nintendo was raking in gobs and gobs of cash.
Scott: Yep I mean if Rym has a giant company that says sells a billion widgets for a dot and he makes a dollar profit on each One he's got a billion dollars.
Scott: That's awesome.
Scott: Let's say, you know, I have a company and I sell a hundred thousand widgets But I get a hundred dollars profit on each one because I'm awesome with my profit margins.
Scott: Well, I'm not.
Scott: I might not be as big a company as Rym but goddamn if I ain't making a shit ton of money.
Rym: Yep, Nintendo's in no danger.
Scott: Not at all.
Rym: In fact, I'll note that on the news that this is just an aside when the Microsoft guy said that you should buy a Wii Nintendo stock rose almost 6%.
Scott: Yep, it like Nintendo stock is going up because the Wii line.
Scott: Yes, and all the Wii news.
Scott: and yeah All right.
Scott: So let's talk about worst video game.
Scott: All right.
Scott: All right, so Gizmondo, all right The gizmondo wasn't really a serious thing.
Scott: What it was is Stefan Eriksson and some other European mafia dudes.
Rym: Yeah, really mafia.
Rym: We're not kidding.
Rym: Yeah, really?
Scott: They made up this portable gaming console and some of it was interesting.
Scott: They said it was gonna have a GPS and that it would have some online Features and other stuff and that got me kind of interested.
Scott: like on I'd like to play some GPS enabled games.
Scott: The problem was is their idea was to have two versions of the gizmondo one That was ludicrously expensive like as expensive as an xbox 360 Or the other version which was a little bit expensive like a couple hundred bucks that would have Advertisements while you played great.
Rym: Just about yeah.
Scott: And there were no games for it and it was all really just a big scam for them to make up giant pile of mafia Money.
Rym: and then he crashed his Ferrari and then it was all found out about the mafia.
Scott: Yeah, and the gizmondo died almost immediately.
Scott: It was hilarious.
Scott: the end now This was very recently too like within the past year.
Rym: now, there's another similar situation with the phantom.
Scott: Oh You're gonna talk about the phantom real briefly.
Rym: The Phantom was a concept.
Rym: was what Infinium?
Rym: Infinium?
Scott: Yes Infinium Labs.
Rym: they said a long time ago that they were gonna make this console.
Scott: that was gonna blow the industry away and The idea of the phantom was that you would buy PC games put them in the phantom and they would just work without dealing with PC game bullshit.
Rym: now it basically became apparent over the years because over the years that no phantom was ever made or released.
Scott: They just kept saying it was coming and they had pieces of plastic in the shape of a console that they said was the phantom But there was nothing inside the.
Rym: it is my opinion.
Rym: I'm saying this only because I do not want to get sued because I do not have actual evidence on me That the phantom was like the gizmondo a scam to get money from venture capitalists and nothing more.
Scott: That's what it seems like and if it wasn't then they just really really suck.
Rym: Yeah, it's either evil or incompetence.
Rym: There's no middle ground there or incompetent evil.
Rym: Yeah, which once again, they should cancel each other out, but they don't.
Scott: Yeah One good thing did come out of the phantom, which was the keyboard that was easy to use while sitting on the couch Which it didn't actually come out yet.
Scott: and we're still waiting because they're supposedly going to release that whether the phantom ever actually exists or not.
Scott: So we're waiting for it and we want it because a keyboard from the couch is what I need but strangely it was delayed.
Scott: Oh, really?
Scott: At least there was a picture of it and someone else can make something similar.
Rym: All right game.com.
Scott: The game.com was a handheld system made by tiger who made all those little tiger LCD games Which I think we're terrible, but I seem to like.
Scott: I like and they're okay.
Scott: And what it was?
Scott: you'd put cartridges in it to play games a lot like the game boy But I had higher resolution in the game boy.
Scott: The screen was actually black and white.
Scott: It had Duke Nukem and I think another FPS game and you know the games.
Scott: they didn't stand up because well There was really no publicity.
Rym: I had actually never heard of this until Scott mentioned it while we were coming up with what our worst.
Scott: Now one of the features of this thing that actually had me thinking about it for a little bit was that it had internet Abilities.
Scott: you could put your high scores online and you could check your email with it and all kinds of stuff.
Scott: The problem was you know, he got it online.
Scott: you plugged it into a modem and then It could only go on the internet with text and you had to pay for this online Service and like no one paid for it was just okay.
Rym: I think it's obvious why that failed.
Scott: Yeah Go read about the game.com G-a-m-e-dot-c-o-m and it's hilarious.
Scott: who even thought of that and why?
Scott: you know.
Scott: in those days It seemed kind of cool, but nowadays.
Rym: Oh, man All right We're gonna run through some non console but console accessory stuff real quick.
Rym: just because they have to be worth mention They have to be mentioned.
Rym: the power glove was so bad.
Scott: It's so bad.
Rym: He touched my boob.
Rym: If the power glove looked really cool the ads made it look awesome and wearing it made you feel really cool Until you tried to use it.
Rym: It didn't work.
Scott: It didn't work at all.
Scott: I think the pat the the Wii technology is actually just updated working power glove technology.
Rym: Yeah, Nintendo seemed to have this problem back then, you know Virtual Boy power glove of trying to do something before the technology Existed brought to work properly at a price people could afford and now they learn that lesson.
Scott: But at least you can see that Nintendo has always been trying to do something new and different.
Rym: Yeah, because they they also came out with the you force.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, that wasn't Nintendo.
Scott: That was a third party.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but it was for the Nintendo.
Rym: Oh, yeah Didn't work.
Scott: No you force didn't work at all.
Scott: You force is like this Helmet thing with a targeting reticle that went over your eyeball.
Rym: No, that was something else.
Scott: Oh was it you force?
Rym: was this?
Rym: it looked like a laptop that you opened and you could move your hands in front of it To control games.
Rym: Oh It was for Nintendo.
Rym: Oh, I don't know.
Rym: I'm pretty sure Nintendo made it, huh?
Scott: Cuz like yeah, I know you're thinking about.
Rym: I forget what it's called, but I just looked at a picture of it.
Rym: It was just as bad cuz.
Rym: it didn't work.
Rym: You could say like fire fire fire.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: That was that one Yeah, and it didn't work at all.
Rym: It was crap.
Scott: now Sega had some other bad purples the menacer which is his gun.
Scott: It was a light gun basically and you could had three parts and you could reconfigure the light gun to be like a rifle a pistol And a thing with the scope.
Scott: it was in response to the super scope.
Scott: The super scope wasn't the worst.
Scott: the menacer was the worst because there are really no games that use the menacer.
Rym: Yeah, there weren't many games with the super scope either No, but they both.
Scott: scope actually wasn't the worst.
Rym: like the manager the super scope was good technology.
Rym: It was a good thing.
Rym: Mostly it just it wasn't.
Rym: really.
Rym: that wasn't the type of gaming that was gonna be popular then and no one really made a good Game for it.
Scott: Nope, but the menacer was just terrible and useless.
Scott: and the Sega activator?
Scott: God The Sega activator.
Rym: what it could have been so cool.
Scott: It could have been done.
Scott: What it was was an octagon.
Scott: Yes an octagon octagonal bodies Octagonal bunnies, okay.
Scott: So you take this big plastic octagon and you put it on the floor kind of like a para para pad.
Scott: Well para para flowers.
Scott: Yeah, and each side of the octagon has a little sensor.
Scott: So when you wave your hand over that area in the sky, you know You just stand in the middle of the octagon and you wave your body parts and you you know You you over these sensors on the eight sides of the octagon and each side of the octagon was mapped to a different button on the Sega Genesis, so that was ABC up down left right and Start that's eight.
Rym: Now you'd think you could do cool things with this, you know fighting games But no one made a fighting game that used it in an intuitive or fun way.
Scott: Oh, no, they were fighting games that used it.
Rym: No that used it in an intuitive and fun.
Scott: Well, it couldn't be used an intuitive and fun way because it was neither intuitive nor fun.
Scott: Oh See the commercials and the ads made it looked like you would stand inside this thing and actually fight like you would do kung fu Standing inside the octagon and the fighting guy on the screen would do the kung fu that you did.
Rym: Yeah, the ads were real deceptive in reality.
Scott: You just kind of waved your arms and legs over the edges of it.
Scott: You know to put in the same case real inaccurate it did.
Rym: it just didn't really work.
Scott: It didn't work nearly as well as a pair of flower does.
Scott: it was useless and silly and a waste of money.
Scott: I mean it seems like a lot of times in the early video game days People just made stuff that to fool kids into buying something that was useless and shitty and nowadays No one really does that anymore.
Rym: course kids were easily fooled.
Rym: I remember lawsuits and problems because this is kind of an aside.
Scott: It's true, but we don't get fooled again.
Rym: Fool me once.
Rym: All right, but back way back there was the game.
Rym: clue, you know the silly American board game clue with a little flip-ups.
Rym: Yeah, or not?
Rym: clue.
Rym: Why am I thinking clue guess who guess who I?
Rym: Don't know why I have a beard.
Rym: does your guy wear glasses.
Scott: I think you have a woman.
Rym: now when they Advertise this game it showed the characters in the board talking which was obviously just.
Rym: you know a funny thing.
Rym: in the ad A lot of kids thought the game really talked and their parents sued when the game didn't talk.
Rym: So they had to change the ad.
Rym: yep, so back then?
Rym: well kids are probably just as gullible today But back then it seems like the gaming industry tried to market to those kids specifically to fool them.
Scott: a Lot of things are just fooling kids into thinking that some Crapass electronic gizmo was so amazing when it wasn't like talking battleship.
Scott: we had electronic like one of the old electronic talking battleships and When it worked which I think we only played it when it worked once it was okay But it wasn't nearly like the commercial said.
Scott: it was just bad.
Rym: Yeah Plus battleships kind of a broken game.
Rym: Yeah It's all it is is implement the perfect the most optimal search algorithm.
Rym: Mm-hmm Oh, we were both implementing it.
Rym: now the game comes down to the random placement.
Scott: Yep So it's all about the placement of the ships and secretly moving the ships to pull your opponent and cheating.
Rym: Yeah, until Rym says wait a minute.
Rym: I have a white peg on before you ass fucker.
Scott: Yeah, that's right.
Scott: You always see what you drew.
Scott: you do in battleship.
Scott: is you move the ship?
Scott: That's only two spots and you always put it somewhere.
Rym: No You know what you do when you're gonna cheat.
Rym: you put white pegs on your board where the other guy shot.
Rym: that way you know exactly where you can cheat to.
Rym: I Do that anyway, ah, you know most people didn't because there wasn't any reason to unless you're cheating.
Scott: No, I did it anyway.
Scott: so I knew where everyone.
Scott: I had the whole layout on my board and what I also did is I would take the ship that Was only two spots and I would figure out the other person search algorithm and I'd put the ship.
Scott: That was only two spots in the place.
Scott: They were least likely to go after next.
Rym: Yeah, my search algorithm was fairly complex, but the game was stupid.
Rym: It's we're not gonna put it on our worst games.
Rym: Maybe we'll do a battleship.
Scott: It's not a worst game.
Rym: Yeah, we're gonna our worst board games.
Rym: It's just hellas.
Scott: Yeah, well there's other worst board games that we can talk about those some other time.
Scott: We're only talking about the worst game consoles and peripherals.
Rym: Yep, and I think we're pretty much done here.
Scott: Didn't you want to yell about the Atari?
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: I just noticed at the top of my list.
Rym: I missed it real briefly.
Rym: I had an Atari 2600 and I still have an Atari 7800.
Scott: We had the Atari 2600 and then it died and then we didn't have video games till the NES.
Rym: now The 7800 is just the advancement of the 2600.
Rym: It was fully backward compatible, but there were also games for it.
Scott: 7800 could play every 2600 game but could also play special 7200 games.
Scott: It was 7800.
Rym: It was actually very powerful.
Rym: the 7800 could make games or play games about the level of the first non MMC Nintendo games.
Rym: Yeah Like gyromite you could probably play Yeah Or the games like this for the brother fighting game in the streets in the early Challenge urban challenge the early sports games.
Scott: you could play those in an Atari 7800 probably.
Scott: Yeah, you did some.
Scott: really Donkey Kong is perfect because it was exactly the same on both systems.
Rym: Yeah, the NES was actually a really really regular Mario Brothers.
Rym: Yeah, right now regular Mario Brothers was an MMC chip.
Scott: Oh Was it really?
Scott: Yeah, because it was on the 7800.
Scott: It was almost perfect.
Rym: Why it's when where I'm pretty sure it was.
Rym: Oh, no, the Mario Brothers.
Rym: I was thinking you said Super Mario.
Scott: No, I said a regular Mario Brothers.
Rym: the Mario Brothers in the Atari was good, but it wasn't perfect.
Rym: It had a lot of Issues made it different from the real game.
Scott: Yeah, it was still good enough.
Rym: Yeah, but yeah, I was off.
Rym: I thought you said Super Nintendo.
Scott: Oh hell no.
Rym: Yeah but the problem was that you couldn't extend the 7800 the Nintendo.
Rym: you could put chips in the cartridges to do more because the Nintendo itself was really really really weak.
Scott: An actual NES doesn't have a lot of stuff in it But you could put stuff in the cartridges to make it more off high-end NES games like Mario 3. almost everything was happening in the cartridge and that was part of the reason why the NES lasted so long was because the cartridges, you know Mario 3 was.
Scott: It seemed like if you look at Mario 3 and Super Mario Brothers 1 and you say that was the best the console could do At that time it's like they switched to a whole new console, but no it was the same thing And that's why the NES lasted like eight years.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Whereas nowadays You can't you have CDs and things you can't put something in the CD to make the console better.
Scott: You know, that's it.
Scott: You see this console is the console.
Scott: It doesn't get more powerful.
Scott: You can't make the game is better over time.
Scott: So the consoles don't last more than four years now.
Rym: the 2600 7800 was a clear progression and they didn't do great and they lost money.
Rym: But that's due to a number of reasons that weren't all Atari's fault.
Rym: The 5200 came between the two and it was the bastard child that was completely different from both of them.
Rym: It was a terrible console.
Rym: It had some good games, but it was just.
Rym: it Epitomizes everything that was wrong with the gaming industry back in that day.
Rym: It was a miserable miserable failure.
Scott: Yeah, go look it up.
Scott: It's just bad.
Rym: Yeah, I don't really sucked.
Scott: It was useless.
Scott: The controller was weird.
Rym: Yeah, there's not much I can say about it just terrible.
Rym: I wanted one when I was a kid just because I heard about it I didn't know what it was and it sounded kind of mystical and cool because no one had heard of it.
Scott: All I really knew is that we had an Atari the wood panels 2600 and it didn't work.
Scott: and I wanted it to work and our friend had a different looking Atari and He had the same game.
Scott: So I think you might add a 7800 but I didn't know the numbers and what different things were.
Rym: 7800 sitting right there.
Rym: We can go look at it.
Scott: I know what it looks like now, but it back in the kiddie days I didn't know the Atari said numbers.
Scott: I said, oh he has an Atari that looks different, you know.
Scott: Yeah it's like the difference between the Intellivision and the Intellivision 2 and I didn't know it in any s was until I went over my cousin's house and he's like Hey I got this thing and we had to wait for the dads to give up the only TV.
Scott: Now he turned it on and Super Mario Brothers was there and I was like, oh, what is this?
Scott: And I you know, I didn't really get it and I died in the first goomba like everyone else.
Scott: and And then we played a little bit and then that was that and you know then later I Yeah, but I think we've talked about everything.
Rym: We've hated about console gaming in the last couple decades.
Scott: It's not everything we hated It's the worst.
Rym: Yeah, but I noticed that we hated everything here.
Rym: That was also a worst except the game gear and the Saturn.
Scott: it's because smart people hate the worst shit Like the worst shit, you're not really a smart dude or you're just really weird.
Rym: though I did really like the game here.
Rym: I can't pretend I didn't.
Scott: I kind of like the game.
Rym: crystal warriors is a great game.
Rym: It's apparently it's very similar to Fire Emblem.
Rym: It's actually a lot like Advance Wars.
Scott: I would play the game gear at my friend's house who had one and I have to sit there plugged into the wall playing it.
Scott: It wasn't a really poorly wars for it was really the only shmoop I ever liked and I remember playing Aladdin for it and a Sonic game.
Scott: and the Sonic game was okay.
Scott: God the Sonic game for it was good But it was hard and it wasn't anything near anywhere near as good as the Sonic 2 & 3 for the Sega Genesis Which are amazing.
Rym: Yeah, the Sega the Sega game gear Sonic game.
Rym: I think it was called Sonic 2.
Scott: I think it was called Sonic 2, but it wasn't really Sonic 2.
Scott: It was just another Sonic game.
Rym: That thing was hard as hell.
Rym: It sure was I never.
Scott: Sonic games are hard.
Scott: Sonic 2 is easy because I've mastered it.
Scott: Yeah, Sonic 1 is a little bit harder.
Scott: Sonic 3 Like the first few levels are easy, but then it gets hard at Sonic and Knuckles is wicked hard.
Rym: I'm not Dan.
Rym: We got to stop.
Rym: We've gone on a long time.
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: tomorrow the worst anime manga and comic.
Scott: Well, let's just do worst anime tomorrow.
Rym: Yeah, we'll get into comics.
Rym: Well, no, I'm not gonna talk about the worst comics.
Scott: Yeah, well during tomorrow the worst anime Odine Legend of Len me.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Okay, let's go Keep some surprises and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.