Rym: It's Wednesday May 24th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We preview to anime or on high school host club and rec.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So we were coming back from the store today and Scott tried to make fun of me and my mother.
Rym: You thought I was gonna open with the thing about me getting a patent, but no I'm starting with this.
Rym: He said you're gonna open with before yeah, and then this happened, so I have to start with this.
Scott: So your mom?
Rym: So But Scott bought like two apples, and they fell out of his bag, and they're rolling around in the back.
Rym: So when I unloaded the car I said Scott your apples fell out, and they were rolling around in the back and Scott says to me.
Rym: He says to me what exactly did you say?
Scott: I said Me and my mom were doing last night?
Scott: Yeah, rollin referring to the rolling around in the back.
Scott: now obviously the my was the slip of the tongue And I meant to say that your mom and not my mom, but it was funny nonetheless.
Scott: Yeah, in fact if I would have said that's what me and your mom were doing last night.
Scott: It wouldn't have been funny.
Scott: We just got like yeah, yeah, but because I accidentally said my we were bestowed with much laughter, and it was well worth it.
Scott: So hooray for accidentally being more funny.
Rym: Yeah in somewhat more relevant news You know for all of you know I quit IBM one week ago, and I've been working at a new awesome job like crazy Awesome job.
Rym: I'll have so many days.
Rym: Yeah, and now I'm going on vacation To an amazement.
Rym: so one anyone who's going to be in North Carolina for an amazement this weekend.
Rym: I'm going to be there doing at least one panel, and I'll probably doing security and wandering around.
Rym: you can't miss me.
Scott: He'll make himself known.
Scott: you can see his picture on our forum at front row.
Rym: crew calm Yeah, but well what wasn't that crepey guy who was like hey, let's want to see room without his shirt on.
Rym: How about you without your shirt on yeah?
Scott: Yeah?
Scott: I didn't turn Skype on today.
Rym: Yeah, I wonder why I'm gonna.
Scott: I'm gonna figure out a way where I can talk to intelligent people on Skype.
Rym: until then no But I left IBM on good terms.
Rym: I mean aside for the fact that I'm no longer supporting all the crap I built for them over the years there I like all the people that I worked with at least and they have my email address.
Rym: Well they emailed me and apparently I really can't talk about the details but one of the things I did while I was working at IBM they feel is patent worthy and They're trying to get a patent on it and IBM is good at that sort of thing.
Rym: so like they needed all my information So it'll be on the patent.
Rym: yeah So I may or may not be getting my first patent Far sooner than when I was gonna try to get to patents as part of a show on how the patent system is broken.
Scott: Yeah Completely useless pet.
Rym: I can't say what the patents about.
Rym: Other than that it is not something that I would consider patent worthy.
Scott: Yeah, it shouldn't be patentable.
Scott: But because the patent system is broken you can and because IBM is basically just as a patent machine They could just get patents that don't mean anything all over the place.
Rym: now I guess I'm fine with it because I'll put on my resume that I have a patent through IBM.
Rym: Yeah, hell, I'd be able to try to hire me back with that because they're real big on patents over there.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think you'd go back there though.
Rym: Hey if they offered me double what I'm paid right now I'd go back.
Rym: probably I'd still give my current work like eight months notice or something.
Scott: well tomorrow at work I'm supposedly gonna do actual work.
Rym: No bullshit.
Scott: No It's not bullshit.
Scott: the people from the New York office are coming and we're getting a t1 Verizon's coming and we're gonna do stuff.
Rym: Are you gonna be setting any of that up or you're just gonna sit there while they all set it up?
Rym: I'll probably do something.
Rym: Do you know how to deal with t1 stuffers?
Rym: Verizon gonna handle all that?
Scott: I guess Verizon's gonna do the telephony end of it.
Rym: Well, usually they'll give you a router.
Rym: No it whatever.
Rym: I imagine they're going to handle it all.
Scott: yeah, whatever Stuff to do we're gonna do a whole bunch of this stuff like rearranging all the furniture.
Rym: Yeah, so you're gonna get some people there meaning you can't just run around the office naked.
Scott: or there's been one person there for a while But it's not very exciting.
Scott: Now all the people you know important people good people are coming.
Scott: So any of the work continues?
Rym: yeah, I doubt it somehow.
Scott: yeah, I don't know.
Scott: I'm gonna ask for more work also.
Rym: I mean I'm doing more work at my new job now where I'm learning how to do the work Then I've ever done in my life and even that is really not much.
Rym: if I push myself I could probably do it all over a course of four or five hours every day.
Rym: I'm really convinced that no job is actually 9 to 5 worth of work.
Scott: You know what is if you work for your damn self?
Rym: Yeah, yeah Maybe we should just eventually work for our damn selves though at least for now now get this.
Rym: this is a cool thing.
Rym: the one Thing I always complained about in work was that they generally want you there for a full eight hours every day plus your lunch plus whatever and a lot of times they want you to work overtime and If you work more efficiently like they really don't let you just leave early.
Rym: The way my work works is basically I have to put in seven and a half hours worth of logged work Per day, and that's really the only requirement if I get all my work done somehow And I can somehow do that leaving early every day.
Rym: They don't seem to mind Awesome, so I think I'm gonna try real hard to get all my work done real quick and real well.
Scott: here go for it.
Scott: Yeah, we'll see how it happens.
Rym: It's a big difference between salary and hourly.
Rym: I'll tell you what yeah, there is.
Scott: So these are awesome But they're also not awesome.
Rym: Yeah, well I Generally am not going to work overtime, so yeah, yep Alright, yeah, but in actual news.
Rym: This is not tech news really.
Rym: I only bring it up because for those of you who are paying attention I tried for one week to always drive the speed limit no matter what you failed.
Rym: I stopped doing it after two days because I was almost killed.
Rym: I was almost run off the road by a tractor trailer on Monday and on Friday when I tried to drive to work people were passing me in the median.
Scott: I think you mixed your Friday and Monday, but that's fun.
Rym: No, I'm talking about my commutes.
Rym: I'm not talking about what happened Friday or what happened today.
Scott: No, I think you said Friday.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Scott: What do you switch Friday and Monday?
Scott: did I yes?
Scott: You said Monday first, and then you said Friday.
Rym: I meant to say Monday first.
Rym: okay as in this previous Monday I was starting now and going backwards through time.
Rym: Ah all right Because one of those events happened on one of those days and what happened on the other day, okay, okay?
Rym: Anyway, I almost died and it wasn't worth it if I went 55 on the taconic.
Rym: I would probably not be here now.
Rym: Mm-hmm I mean those traffickers going faster than I was comfortable going.
Rym: and for people who know how fast I Drive.
Rym: That's scary Like real scary, that's really scary.
Rym: So I was speeding whatever.
Rym: But the reason I bring it up Is that Hillary Clinton who I've been kind of 50/50 on in terms of her political views for a while Yeah, similar here like oh, she's doing this.
Scott: She's doing that.
Rym: Video games all the bad stuff.
Rym: She does is very obviously pandering to the idiot vote.
Rym: Yeah, like I see her trying things and like saying oh I'm going to push for this and then failing on purpose because she does a lot of things that aren't visible.
Scott: like did you know?
Scott: She's on the Banking Committee in the Senate.
Scott: Nothing she does concerning banking is made public or pronounced very loudly because no one knows or cares.
Rym: No one knows or cares except for banks, but when she says something about video games, there's a brouhaha.
Scott: Yeah, so anything she does where there's a brouhaha is always something stupid and I'm 90% of the time against it.
Rym: Yeah, and most of the time I'm pretty sure she's against it, too I can't tell and it doesn't matter.
Scott: but as long as she's saying it That's how she's gonna vote and that whether she's actually against it or not doesn't matter now.
Rym: today She did something that I have mixed feelings about but I Think this is pretty much the last nail in the coffin of.
Rym: she cannot be nominated by the Democrats to run in 2008 For anything she wants.
Rym: Well, she could probably stay in the Senate.
Rym: You know how hard it is to get kicked out of the Senate?
Scott: Yeah, but she's the New York Senate.
Scott: so I can vote for the other guy.
Rym: you can no one else will.
Rym: that's fine.
Rym: Besides the other guy is probably a Republican.
Scott: I'm gonna vote for the third guy.
Rym: There's no third guy.
Scott: Tommy G party.
Rym: Nah, yeah, they're kind of cool.
Rym: I guess they're.
Scott: they're not great But they're better than the other schmucks.
Rym: Yeah, there's really no political party I like.
Rym: I mean the libertarians are the closest thing to what I want except they're a little batshit.
Scott: They're crazy bad.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, I really don't like the way our schools are in this country And I have a lot of beef with the public education system.
Scott: But the answer is not to abolish it and the answer is not to put a bunch of money into it or take a bunch Of money out.
Scott: Yeah, the answer is to change it dramatically to something new.
Rym: like the right-wingers want You know a police state and the libertarians want no police and neither one of those is going to work.
Rym: Nope, the left-wingers want communism.
Rym: That's not going to work.
Scott: I but the Democrats want something else.
Scott: They want a whole.
Scott: They want the same police.
Scott: you've got now only really inefficient.
Rym: I mean while the Republicans want the same police We've got now only costing less.
Rym: Yeah, but actually costing more but doing more.
Rym: Or well, really they want doing more and costing more.
Scott: Yeah Well, the Republicans say they want costing less they want doing more But they actually end up paying more because they want the doing more than they want the paying less.
Scott: They just say the paying less.
Rym: It's really scary to me that now when I think back to the days of Newt Gingrich Republicans, I think back fondly.
Scott: Yeah If I would have told you that like, you know, I mean when Clinton was in office I mean like I wasn't like all this is terrible, but you know, I wasn't like hooray for Bill Clinton.
Rym: Hooray I was like I was but that's a whole other story.
Rym: It's all our story.
Scott: I was just like all right this guy, you know, whoever was the president I always was like and president sucks no matter who it was, you know.
Scott: But now if you would have told me now I would have been like goddamn whatever amendment number that was Let's throw it out.
Rym: Yeah, throw it out cuz then Bush will run again against Clinton and Clinton win.
Rym: Yeah, I Really?
Scott: It's really only two people ever to run for president FDR and Clinton who could just win win win win win every time.
Scott: Well, I guess maybe JFK but JFK could have.
Scott: he died.
Rym: I still love that one Photoshop where it shows Fox News then it shows the JFK assassination and the Fox News scroller says John F Kennedy dead of apparent suicide Just to make fun of Fox News cuz they've been in the news lately.
Rym: Yeah, anyway my news All right, Hillary Clinton's new thing.
Rym: Is that to save money on gas costs and to save lives, but that's secondary to it.
Rym: She thinks that we should go back to the 55 mile an hour speed limit.
Rym: now new Whatever your feelings are on speed limits.
Rym: I can tell you with certainty that there is only one demographic of voters who will approve of this people over the age of 65 and Even some of them.
Scott: I have one grandma who goes slow and one grandma who goes fast?
Scott: Yeah So the grandma who goes fast isn't gonna like it only the slow Grandmas and grandpas are gonna like.
Scott: and oh and those people who don't want swings on the playground?
Scott: Oh, yeah, those people don't like speed limits either.
Rym: Well, I they like speed limits.
Rym: They like them a lot.
Scott: I mean, yeah, they don't like high speed limits.
Scott: They like low ones.
Rym: Now on FARC I saw in fact, I'm gonna link to the FARC article on this because I know it won't go away I saw perhaps the most perfect awesome rebuttal to the argument that the speed limit is too high ever.
Rym: It shows a picture of a United States freeway from 1957 or 58.
Rym: I was waiting for that and It shows the speed limit sign and the speed limit sign says minimum speed 40 maximum speed 80 and the caption above this picture says This is from back or no.
Rym: It says if cars that had drum brakes really powerful v8 engines No airbags no crumple zones No seat belts crap headlights crap tires and large heavy steel frames and no suspension of any reasonable ability can go 80 dot dot dot.
Rym: I agree, yeah cars are a lot safer now and Studies show like numerous.
Rym: numerous studies show that lowering the speed limit to 55 greatly increased the accident and fatality rate.
Rym: States that have raised their speed limit since then have seen dramatic decreases in accidents and deaths on the roads.
Scott: Because what had on a day on a highway?
Scott: we're talking about highways here not other roads because rural roads are death traps, basically Statistically speaking.
Rym: Yep, and if your road is outside houses or schools or real like hospital nun zones 25 miles an hour is perfectly reasonable.
Rym: And if you speed there you're an asshat.
Rym: That's not what we're talking about.
Scott: Yeah, we're talking about roads with many lanes like interstates that are mostly straight and you know roads like.
Scott: What's a good example of a road that's not an interstate that's real big like the merit Parkway.
Rym: Yeah, however, not the taconic Parkway.
Rym: Yeah, that's the speed limit of the taconic Parkway should stay at 55.
Scott: There's because there's a kind of part.
Scott: we could be 65.
Scott: There's people on it drive with 90.
Scott: God.
Rym: Well, there's one section where should be about 45. it goes Like this crazy winding yeah.
Scott: Yeah, but you know you get different parts of the road.
Scott: That's that's okay.
Scott: on a major interstate road You know people the danger doesn't come from going fast or going slow.
Scott: The danger comes from people driving different speeds from each other.
Scott: So if everyone drove 90 it would be safer than if some people drove 70 and some people drove 55. now if somehow magically everyone drove 55 it would be just as safe.
Scott: It wouldn't matter.
Scott: The thing is a lot of cars.
Scott: It's just not reasonable to stay going 55 Especially when you're trying to get somewhere.
Rym: I mean people's like.
Rym: I remember driver's ed.
Rym: a lot of people I remember Scott told me this story where they would basically tell kids Yeah, speeding doesn't get you there any faster.
Scott: Yes, it does.
Rym: I've caught about.
Rym: I've probably saved several weeks worth of lifetime By speeding on every road trip I've ever been on.
Scott: think about this if I go on route 90, right?
Scott: It's like a six hour trip to Rochester.
Scott: following the speed limit I can make it a four and a half hour trip by stepping on the gas.
Scott: Yeah, I'm going 80 or 90 that's an hour and a half and if I go round trip Three hours of saved time by speeding It's just completely unreasonable for me to go.
Scott: the speed limit of 55 slash 65 the entire way.
Scott: Not only that, but I wouldn't.
Scott: it's just stupid.
Rym: Now.
Rym: of course people will still drive somewhat slower in some cases but you just have to have the European style of driving where you stay to the right in a two-lane road you stay to the Right and if you're going faster than everyone you go to the left and if someone comes behind you in the left lane you get Out of their way.
Rym: Mm-hmm and a three-lane road you cruise in the middle.
Rym: The right lane is for trucks and merging the left lane is for speeding.
Rym: Yep in a four-lane road You follow the pattern there.
Rym: Yep Yeah, this 50 regardless 55 mile an hour thing's not gonna fly.
Rym: the vast majority of Americans don't like speed limits.
Scott: the other thing is that truck drivers want to get places as fast as Possible because that means they can do more jobs in less time and get paid more money and live better lives.
Scott: Yep In fact, if only limits go down they get mad pissed off.
Rym: the last time this happened when the u.s Instituted its 55 mile an hour nationwide speed limit deal back in what the 70s.
Rym: Mm-hmm The truckers unions got together and they put roadblocks rolling roadblocks on almost every freeway in the country driving exactly 55 and it caused mass chaos.
Scott: Yep Imagine if two tractor trailers were on every two-lane interstate in every direction all going exact Exactly the speed limit that there's lines of cars for miles and miles all rolling slowly at 55 Taking hours and hours to get where they're going bumper to bumper.
Rym: This is why I think the speed limits are set too low and stupid Because we're now in a situation where if you follow the law to the letter you are more of a danger than if you break It yep.
Scott: Now you might say oh, you're only a danger because there's other people on the road going fast.
Scott: Well Yeah This.
Scott: the speed limits on roads Should be determined by safety and not by making money.
Rym: And also it doesn't remove liability for people who cause accidents because weather and conditions change the road.
Rym: So if you're going too fast Like say the speed limits 90 on a road and you're going 90 and it's snowing or you're going 90 and you're driving stupidly And you cause an accident Investigators if the accident is big enough can tell what caused the accident by Investigators.
Scott: they can go to a scene of an accident and they know exactly what the hell happened.
Scott: It's a fucking science.
Scott: one of those guys came to my math class once and he's like look at this.
Scott: I went to this crime scene.
Scott: I saw a car embedded in this other car at this angle.
Scott: the car crumpled this much.
Scott: It was this kind of car with these kind of tires that were this worn There was this much tread visible on the street, etc.
Scott: Etc.
Scott: Here's my math.
Scott: Here's my little computer model I used with this little software in the detective office at the police station.
Scott: Here's a video of the accident that no one saw in the middle of the night.
Rym: Now my idea is very simple raise the speed limits to I forget the term But it's the
Scott: 85% 85%
Rym: the 80 so 85 percentile speed limit wherein you have engineers study roads watch the average speed of traffic and Generally with few exceptions the only exceptions being odd non apparent dangers like a road that's windier than it looks or a road that has Blind corners that aren't obvious or things like that.
Scott: There's always crazy exceptions.
Scott: Everyone knows.
Rym: Yeah, but engineers find those and mark them private separately.
Rym: Yes,
Scott: they do usually with big yellow signs with arrows on them
Rym: But in general the safest speed for traffic to go is the speed that currently about 85% of drivers will go if there's no speed Limit,
Scott: yep so let's say there's no speed limit on a road only crazy ricers and people with Ferraris and Corvettes are gonna go like 120 150 or as fast as their car can go and you can
Rym: pull those people over anyway for being reckless and Dangering.
Scott: well.
Scott: and the other thing is if someone's driving a Ferrari and they're driving it properly It's pretty safe for them to go 150 if the road is, you know, straight and flat.
Rym: Yeah, of course most roads in the u.s.
Rym: Really can't handle 150.
Scott: Yeah, especially considering the other cars in the way, but if it's a super like 10-lane road, it's mostly empty.
Scott: Sure, go for it like an Autobahn type road plus.
Rym: I mean all the the stage that have raised the speed limit.
Rym: It's shown that if the speed limit is 55 people tend to drive 65. if the speed limit 65 that tend to drive 75.
Rym: If the speed limit 75 people tend to drive 75 because most people don't want to go faster than that.
Scott: I mean the fastest that I would ever go.
Scott: and like a normal trip to work I mean when I'm going on super long-distance trips on extra empty roads that are real long and straight I'll go 90 or 100 for quite a bit not the whole time because you can't stay at 90 or 100.
Scott: It's not really if you're gonna turn at all.
Scott: It's not really safe or comfortable and you have to constantly, you know control the driving.
Rym: Yeah, you can't just zone out like you do when you're going 55.
Scott: Yeah, but if I go down, you know to work the fastest my car ever gets to is 80 You know and the roads 55. but most people are going 70 because it the road is really a 70 75 kind of road.
Scott: That's I feel perfectly safe.
Scott: driving 75, you know, I don't have to put a lot of energy into it I can zone out is no risk of really hitting anyone because everyone the left lanes go in that speed.
Scott: It's all good.
Scott: Well, I guess we kind of did our show on speeding You know because we're gonna do some other cool stuff in a real show on speeding.
Rym: Yeah Interviews and we've been collecting articles and scientific studies for the past several months.
Rym: Hmm.
Scott: Okay, so I haven't news.
Scott: It's anime related an animated.
Rym: Oh, yeah, it's anime day.
Scott: Hey, so Tokyo pop they make that ball that manga.
Scott: They used to make the good manga, but now this makes the good manga signature.
Scott: Yeah signature series All right.
Scott: Anyway, Tokyo pop used to put out DVDs.
Scott: They have initial D marblade boy GTO reign the Conqueror some other shows But then it didn't work out so well, you know why?
Scott: because Tokyo pop always screwed them up.
Rym: Ah Initial D.
Scott: If you don't know there's a big debacle about Tokyo pops initial D DVD releases in America.
Rym: It's pry in some that one of the worst things ever done to an anime other than possibly warriors of the wind.
Scott: Yeah, so what they did is normally when you put a DVD out in America you translate it you make a dub you make some subtitles you put it on DVD a few episodes per disc and You put some extras on there.
Scott: you make some DVD menus and you sell it.
Scott: It's pretty simple.
Scott: Tokyo pop thought it was a good idea to take initial D and remix it.
Scott: what they did is They dubbed it.
Scott: They changed the characters names.
Scott: They changed the amazing superhero beat music to this rap music They hired someone to make.
Scott: that's terrible.
Scott: It's terrible like not just because it's rap music.
Scott: I like a lot of hip-hop music.
Scott: This is bad music.
Scott: bad.
Rym: Your music's bad and you should feel bad exactly.
Scott: and all the racing scenes They did.
Scott: they basically took 1980s video editors and did like split screens and like wacky color changes and all sorts of quote tricked out effects.
Scott: So if you buy initial D on DVD from Tokyo pop You'll notice that when you boot the DVD up the menu says tricked out or standard watch Standard tricked out is an abomination to say the least.
Rym: They also edited the tricked-out version the Americanized version and took out various scenes that were inappropriate for whatever reason Scenes that were very important like Papa.
Scott: Yep so Tokyo pop really wasn't any good at releasing DVDs.
Scott: So it's not a wonder why they stopped putting out DVDs.
Scott: They stuck to their manga which made them a ton of money.
Scott: good business move.
Scott: What Tokyo pop is now done is they have sold their existing DVD titles to Funimation.
Scott: who knows how to make DVDs?
Scott: So Funimation is going to over the course of the future release GTO marmalade boy initial D, etc.
Scott: Tokyo pops previous DVD titles New DVDs that will be rebranded reprised You know reach a changed in basically every way to make them correct Hopefully.
Scott: and the first one they're gonna put out is Street Fury remixed on June 27th.
Scott: So I guess Tokyo pop wasn't making any money off their DVDs anymore.
Scott: They sold them all to Funimation.
Scott: now Funimation is gonna make money that you know Tokyo pop should have made before if they did things, right, huh?
Scott: So that's if you're a fan of initial D and you already bought the DVDs like me.
Rym: Oh, well buy them again.
Scott: Yeah Probably I'm gonna try to see if I can.
Scott: if they do release better DVDs than the ones I have now.
Scott: I'll see if I can sell all of mine to buy the newer ones at like a low price.
Scott: Hopefully that'll work.
Scott: If not, I'll just keep what I got.
Scott: Yeah, I don't have to watch the tricked-out version.
Rym: I'm not about to rush out and buy that super new awesome crazy version of Ava.
Rym: No, I just bought the Platinum Edition.
Scott: Yeah, who cares about the limited ultra super extra plus edition with the t-shirts and it comes with a jacket?
Scott: yeah leather jacket I don't know.
Scott: It's crazy.
Rym: It's two hundred and fifty dollars I could buy.
Scott: what a PSP For 50 bucks more.
Scott: you go buy the low-end Xbox 360 for what?
Rym: $350 more.
Rym: I could buy the crappy ps3.
Scott: we could buy Mario soccer and Mario baseball and have a hundred and fifty dollars left over for what?
Rym: $550 more I could buy.
Rym: and a PlayStation 3 in Europe.
Rym: Yeah All right.
Rym: All right.
Rym: enough making fun of Sony for 250.
Scott: We could buy a we a we or a box of Ava.
Rym: So once again my thing of the day is old old old.
Scott: I guess you're just not good at finding things of the day anymore.
Scott: So you're digging up the old dregs from before the GeekNights existed.
Rym: I think it's more that in my previous job I was mostly doing development work meaning I sat in front of a computer all day with a Fark RSS feed and I knew what Was going on every second.
Rym: now.
Rym: I'm out doing stuff.
Rym: doing stuff means I'm not sitting in front of a computer trolling for links for GeekNights.
Scott: so what's gonna happen when eventually you run out of old things of the day to drag up and You know what?
Rym: when I'm
Scott: not things of the day
Rym: when I'm not tired and getting ready for a convention and busy and I have To check the internet when I get home from work
Scott: True
Rym: or when I actually fall into a routine at work, I can take a five-minute break to check the internet.
Scott: True also.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It's all good.
Rym: I'm not giving up GeekNights just cuz I have a job.
Scott: We've had a job the whole time.
Scott: We've had.
Scott: Why would a different job all of a sudden mean a different story unless we got some sort of night jobs?
Rym: Actually, one of our friends on Kate made fun of my away aim away message today Because it's always like working for the man or something like that.
Rym: And she said Rym you are the man.
Rym: You're a white guy young who makes a lot of money.
Rym: You're the man you're working for yourself.
Scott: Yeah, that's true.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I am the man.
Scott: I am also the man.
Rym: We got to keep everyone else down.
Scott: We should just change it instead of GeekNights to the man nights the man nights with the men.
Rym: That kind of sounds like some sort of homoerotic porn pie.
Scott: just realized that.
Scott: yeah, yeah.
Scott: So first I make a joke about my mom and then I make a joke about us being gay.
Rym: father rapers.
Scott: Okay, you're supposed to say mother rapers and then I'm supposed to say father.
Scott: That's how the joke goes.
Rym: I just wanted to say father rapers father rapers It's fun to say that.
Rym: yeah father rapers.
Scott: Why he says it.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, okay Thing of the day think of it.
Rym: I got a thing because that's what the music was.
Rym: So my thing of the day is I We've talked about the Radis call off and on.
Rym: we've never talked about him in any sort of Informative capacity.
Scott: Well, let's do so.
Rym: the Radis call episode 1 appeared a long fuck time ago like late 90s like late high school for last millennia Back when stick death was awesome.
Scott: Stick death is my thing of the day for tomorrow.
Scott: Oh my god.
Rym: when you when flash was flash and director was director Back when if someone made a flash animation a million everyone in the world would watch it because it was awesome And there were like six of them on the internet and everyone used shockwave and flash was insane.
Scott: You had to wait for it to load shockwave calm Back when games like Pico's adventure Or Lenny loose jocks.
Rym: Oh my god pushin Brown pushin Brown I Mean.
Rym: this is back in the time of the internet when you used ICQ or AOL instant messenger.
Rym: And if you used ICQ and use Netscape three gold random people would message you and you talk to them because they were cool.
Scott: Is anyone using the internet in the 90s had to be cool?
Scott: Yeah, everyone stupid people in those days using it.
Rym: I mean back then not even all the AOLers were really on the internet.
Scott: yet No fully and half the AOLers are cool now.
Scott: anyone using AOL still these days is just stupid.
Rym: So this guy Joe sparks made radis skull and devil doll.
Scott: now This is pretty much the premier flash animation.
Scott: We wouldn't have things like homestar runner if we didn't have radis skull.
Rym: now It was just this one silly contrived kind of goonie But yet awesome because it was the 90s flash thing about the radis skull.
Rym: who will kill you all?
Scott: It was a short cartoon where a giant floating skull floats up and a little tiny double comes and they're like hey I am the radis skull blah blah blah.
Rym: and it was just silly and over-the-top.
Scott: and they did a rap.
Rym: It was really popular and later the song was pretty good.
Rym: Yeah, it's that kind of rap that I really like.
Rym: You know Beastie Boys kind of deal.
Scott: It's not like the Beastie Boys.
Rym: No, it's like some of the Beastie Boys.
Scott: No, not really.
Scott: No, yeah.
Scott: No.
Scott: Yeah, but it's much better than the initial D rap.
Scott: God Much much better.
Scott: They should have hired Joe sparks to do it.
Rym: So he kept making episodes and they got better and better.
Scott: Yeah episode two is particularly good with the Halloween II.
Scott: Yeah, and so is the episode the rock heart episode in which there is some cg's in the background.
Scott: I guess it's all technically CG, but 3d cg's and radis skull has an awesome dream.
Rym: Oh my god radis skulls dream was probably the funniest thing to come out of the early days of the internet.
Scott: It doesn't help that the song in the rock heart episode is also probably the best song.
Rym: Yeah, it's a good song of its own merit Yep, and the lyrics are very clever.
Rym: Yes any person has my favorite line and all of radis skull But the head off a dove in the tunnel of love.
Scott: That's a good one.
Scott: There's also the.
Rym: We laugh just thinking about the radis skull.
Scott: yeah, it was.
Scott: it was like Huh?
Rym: It was like I don't have a heart or any other body parts.
Rym: That's the.
Rym: I don't understand love.
Scott: Yeah, cuz he's just a giant floating skull and he's saying I have a heart or any other body parts And the little devil's like but I do Because he's actually has a whole body.
Scott: I'll warn you this angel thing.
Rym: Well, I want two little bits of trivia one bit of trivia.
Rym: Is that the the devil doll?
Rym: when he's dancing every time he yells or something his face like sort of Slowly morphs back into him smiling again.
Rym: That was a mistake that Joe sparks didn't correct and then he realized it and it looked good.
Rym: So we kept it.
Rym: Yep, and - if you don't find this amusing one, you're a punk kid and Yep - just watch this and try to pretend that none of those memes you've seen have existed yet.
Rym: I mean, this is the early days of awesome internet things before all the other things that they existed.
Scott: There was radis skull.
Rym: This is internet protoculture.
Scott: This was I think this is pre all your base I believe so it could have been because it was that early, you know.
Rym: Well, I'll have to verify that later to find out I'm not entirely sure.
Scott: so I'm not gonna commit either way Yeah, but I think this is either pre all your base or right around the same damn time.
Rym: Yeah, this is old shit man old shit and you can get all the mp3s at the site.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: The other thing about you have to know about radis skull is that they don't finish the story because of a stupid Copyright thing that we're not gonna get into.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Joe sparks has an official website You can visit to find out more about his other things and radis skull and you can also purchase The radis skull book which contains the script of the final episode as well as some radis skull comics And I'm still waiting for the book to come from Amazon.
Scott: Maybe I should go check on that.
Rym: Yeah cuz the plight actually grows a plot and the plots about as clever as a show about a giant floating skull who wraps can be And the wraps in every episode are awesomes cuz the radis skull likes to kick it.
Scott: Yeah Okay, I have another anime thing great.
Scott: The anime thing of the day is this girl's website.
Scott: I'm pretty sure it's a girl's website only.
Scott: girls draw like gum gum gum pins and stickers.
Scott: now if you've ever been to a anime convention in artist alley many people sell pins and stickers and these are often hot buys because Number one, they're cheap and people are poor.
Scott: number two They're cute and people like cute things.
Scott: and number three there you can use them right away.
Scott: people love to buy stuff They can use right away.
Rym: I have a sticker or pin or button or something on every con badge with few exceptions I've ever gotten.
Rym: that's how I remember which con was which yep.
Scott: every Otakon I go to I buy some sort of stickers in the artist alley and put them in my little con badge holder or Some sort of pin and put it on the lanyard or something like that.
Scott: Well, this girl gum gum is one of the best drawing of cute characters I've ever seen.
Scott: It's not the best but it's up there.
Rym: Yeah I mean a lot of her.
Rym: once you look at a lot of her art at all kind of looks the same as I'm sorry That's end to be of course.
Rym: I just particularly like her little picture of foo from.
Scott: She's the only one I've ever seen turn Tetsuo from Akira with his blobby arm full of you know nastiness into something cute.
Scott: So that's a big plus.
Scott: Now at this site you can buy of course pins and stickers.
Scott: So if you've never been to an anime convention artist alley or if you really really like pins and stickers from anime and video games And you don't go to conventions You can't get them or whatever your situation may be.
Scott: if you want to buy pins and stickers containing cute characters from anime and video games Go to this website Now.
Scott: really cheap and awesome.
Rym: We weren't paid to shill or anything because we're actually going to do an episode soon on shilling because we've been getting Emails from people who want us to shill their dreck on GeekNights.
Scott: We will not shill your dreck on GeekNights unless a you pay us a great deal of money.
Scott: But even then we will tell people that we were paid a great deal of money and that we are shilling you because of it.
Scott: Yeah, or be your stuff is legitimately good And then we want to shill it anyway Whether you told us to or not now to major retailers and/or video game Manufacturers and creators.
Rym: if you send us things to review we will review them thoroughly And honestly, I thoroughly is my word.
Rym: I'm sticking to it.
Scott: My word is honestly.
Scott: So I will accept free things and basically sending us free things is a way to guarantee that we will review them in some way.
Scott: So if you're of the mind that all press is good press send free shit to Scott.
Rym: That was the most diplomatic way to say that.
Rym: yep If you are of the mind wait a minute, I've got it, this is a slightly Obscure inside joke, but I'm sure Scott will get it.
Rym: I am confident that this box contains cell phones.
Scott: How much laughter we gonna put in the show.
Rym: I'm not gonna You know, I've noticed the most radio guys tend to just leave all that in.
Rym: plus we don't edit the show anymore, so whatever All right.
Scott: So If you send us free things we will review them But we will review them honestly and give our honest opinions of whatever you send us.
Scott: So if your stuff sucks You might not want to send it to us and if your stuff is awesome and you know that we'll say awesome things about it Sending it might be a good idea because then our audience will buy it
Rym: though I know that if I was just told this by a podcast I listen to I would send them a small box with poo in It
Scott: of course
Rym: because that's the obvious thing you do to someone who asks you to send them thing.
Scott: We can do an episode on poo.
Rym: I could do an episode on poo.
Rym: Let me tell you what.
Scott: yeah You were like a poop report reading fiend.
Rym: for like a year poop report was a great website.
Rym: I don't know if it's still up there, but that would to go check.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Are you checking?
Rym: yep?
Rym: All right poop report is gonna be a thing of the day sometime in the future.
Scott: Spoop report calm right I think.
Rym: so there it is still there with the brown background still there.
Rym: They review toilet paper among other things.
Rym: Alright alright, so it's anime day whoo.
Rym: It's not monkey Tuesday for us.
Scott: No.
Scott: It's not okay.
Scott: It's not even Tuesday.
Scott: It's Wednesday.
Scott: Yeah, I only heard monkey Tuesday on Wednesday.
Rym: cuz I get those shows a day late Yep, and I no longer hear him on the radio because I'm not driving at 2 o'clock.
Rym: Yeah, or whenever that show was.
Scott: you have an iPod yet.
Scott: Yeah, I'm getting one soon alright, so We're gonna review two anime for you today.
Scott: preview.
Rym: well pre That's right cuz you've only seen one episode of each one And I think they're both good enough to where we're going to talk about them again.
Rym: Are we?
Scott: Planning on watching much.
Rym: I'm gonna watch both of them to the end.
Scott: alright good for you.
Scott: alright I think that these shows were of the variety where once you've seen one episode.
Scott: You've pretty much seen most of the show.
Rym: I Don't know about one of them because the second one we're gonna talk about is alright Yeah, but one more so than the other.
Rym: yeah what they both have the potential.
Rym: But if the potential is not realized the shows will be only met.
Rym: yep, but alright It's worth it to watch the first episode of both of these shows yes, and it'll probably be worth it to watch more.
Rym: But if you're hedging your bets wait until we talk about it later after I watch it is who knows if I can't guarantee the Whole show is worth it.
Rym: now the first one is our on.
Scott: hi Well, it's our on high school host club.
Scott: now when you first see this show Just looking at the title you say the alarm bells go off.
Scott: Yeah, we it's yeah, we.
Scott: oh my god everything.
Scott: everything is pink and purple and Sparkly and every care and flowery with pretty boys and pretty girls in a pretty school for rich kids.
Rym: yeah We owe we owe we owe we like you can't imagine like imagine, Utah Where's you know someone standing there, and then rose blossoms go by multiply that by a million and?
Scott: Somehow despite all this the show actually isn't yaoi.
Rym: Not only is it not yaoi.
Rym: It is hilarious.
Scott: It is pretty funny.
Scott: It's the funniest show I've seen in quite a while.
Rym: and the first episode.
Rym: We can't even spoil the first episode because there is a humorous thing that happens in it With the light bulbs.
Scott: Oh, I want to make a reference to another show to say what it's like But then I think that might spoil it.
Rym: yeah, that's why this is a preview.
Rym: We really try to avoid ruining anything unless the show's crap.
Rym: There was no key rape in this show.
Scott: Let me say this without trying to spoil the first we're trying not to spoil the first episode.
Scott: Imagine if there's a show and you know in a Hitchcock movie the twist comes at the end, right?
Scott: But in some shows the twist is the whole show and it's there from the beginning like if there's a show about a Car that can actually talk and then that's your example.
Scott: It's the best I could think of without spoiling.
Scott: okay now There's two ways to do that.
Scott: It's at the end You can be like surprised the car was doing all the talking or for the whole show You say the car can talk the whole time.
Scott: This is one of those shows where there's a gimmicky twist thing that is revealed in the first episode And it lasts throughout the show and therefore I think it's gonna wear off Because the gimmick is only.
Rym: I mean the gimmick was hilarious, but it was only one part of all that was going on.
Scott: It's true, but I don't know if the rest of it maybe if it was only like a 13 episode show it'd be perfect.
Scott: I don't know how many episodes it is.
Rym: Yeah, cuz I worry it'll fall into honey or a dango syndrome.
Rym: Yeah, honey or a dango was awesome And I watched a lot of.
Scott: it is pretty awesome But it's a manga and anime and a live-action and a movie.
Scott: I think.
Rym: yeah I think so But as the show goes on it gets less and less awesome in my opinion and more and more just.
Rym: alright god damn it end.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, I saw this before.
Rym: oh she likes the guy.
Rym: oh Yeah, like it just doesn't go anywhere.
Rym: our on has the potential to be really funny and stay funny.
Rym: It depends on how they execute it.
Scott: if they can keep making every episode as good as the first one instead of just sort of Slowly moving the plot along while making the same jokes over and over.
Scott: It'll be an awesome hilarious show.
Rym: It makes fun of Shonen eyeshows shoujo anime and fangirls Simultaneously Yep, sure does.
Rym: and it has a scene that is perhaps the most perfect representation of a maximized fangirl.
Rym: The world has ever seen this boy?
Rym: I think it's.
Rym: I forget exactly which character to involve but a boy was being real cute and possibly Almost shown in IE with another boy and these two girls are sitting there next to him Just kind of talking and watching Mm-hmm and they do something like really like the kind of thing that sets a fangirl off like crazily and It pans over to other characters talking.
Rym: but in the background you see these two girls and they're leaning toward each other with their hands like clasped in front of their necks like II and They're.
Rym: they have these huge like XD smiles and their heads turn bright red and they're rolling back and forth on their necks going.
Scott: Yep Yeah, so the show is about this rich rich school where rich rich kids go.
Scott: They have a host club which is where a host club is if you don't know is the thing that's common in yaoi shows And I don't know if it actually exists in Japan.
Scott: Although I'm sure it does Where a bunch of guys get together and will host ladies.
Rym: It's that simple.
Scott: yeah, so ladies will go to the host club and say I would like to be hosted by that member of the host club and then that member of the host club will host them in sort of a Geisha but with genders reverse sort of way.
Rym: So this poor kid accidentally runs afoul of the host club and ends up join.
Scott: poor kid is looking around the rich school because he goes there and ends up stumbling in into the host club room.
Scott: and things happen when he stumbles in there and They forced him to join the host club.
Rym: It makes fun of every stereotype.
Rym: like there's the typical bishonen guy and it shows him like talking about how he does his bishonen poses.
Rym: He's like I posed like this and then like this and I stand by the flowers.
Scott: and then there's the real the tiny kid for The girls who like little boys who's actually a senior in high school.
Scott: Yeah And then there's the the tall dark quiet guy.
Rym: There's the two twin brothers who pretend to be all Shown and I yaoi.
Rym: so they get the girls.
Scott: Yep, it's just they got them all the whole run-of-the-mill and they make jokes about each and every one.
Rym: It is hilarious.
Rym: Trust us watch this show at least one episode.
Rym: you'll laugh your ass even if you start.
Scott: if you're a guy and you watch the first few seconds of the show and you start to Feel really girly and you don't want to continue Continue it's worth it.
Rym: We're not kidding.
Rym: We'll tell you if a show is bad.
Scott: Here's the thing.
Scott: If you're not really big on anime, this is not a show for you.
Scott: This is a show for people who are already anime fans because it's like an anime parody.
Scott: Yeah, the same way the Holy Grail isn't as funny if you don't know about King Arthur.
Scott: Yeah, this is not as funny if you don't know anime because it's making fun of anime.
Rym: Yeah, like if you've never seen any anime.
Rym: Excel saga or Combustible campus guard s guard dress just seems stupid because you don't get it.
Rym: Yeah, why is this weird?
Scott: You will only.
Scott: this is show first here for anime fans.
Scott: You want to be a super anime fan, but if you're any kind of anime fan at all this show will make you pee your pants.
Scott: So watch it with as many anime fans in the room as possible.
Rym: Yes, if there is an anime club near you showing it go see it with them.
Scott: Yep I think the Metro anime club in New York City is showing it.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah I think they're already on episode like three or four or something.
Rym: Now the other show that we watched.
Rym: actually we watched a whole bunch of shows and they were all For the most part above the line of watching at least a little bit more which was amazing after all the crap we've seen Yep, but we'll continue to watch some of them.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: The other show that we're gonna talk about today.
Scott: However is Rick R EC as in recording but only wreck.
Rym: now it looks from the opener like a yippie showjoey Semi romantic comedy.
Scott: That's what I thought.
Scott: I thought it was gonna be a yippy it be girly show based on the opener.
Rym: It is actually a fairly serious and realistic Romantic comedy.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Now in the opener you see like a tree with a cat head and you're like, alright there's the cute creature for the show.
Scott: and But then you see a picture sort of like koto cha but a little grown-up.
Scott: Yeah, that's what it looked like from the opener.
Rym: now They show a picture in the opener of Audrey Hepburn from Roman holiday.
Rym: Mm-hmm I didn't get that in the first go around and the first episode one the characters watch Roman holiday in the theater Mm-hmm, then the basic basic basic plot and scenes from Roman holiday reoccur in the show.
Rym: Like the show parallels Roman holiday in the way that an English teacher would shit would say.
Rym: that show parodies that movie.
Rym: Yeah And it doesn't really well and the show is really just kind of.
Rym: I guess it's it's more classy Normal humor as opposed to you know XD or on high anime humor.
Scott: Yeah, so Roman holiday If you don't know is this movie about the supporter who goes to Rome because there's a princess visiting there who's gonna do some sort of speech thing.
Scott: and Somehow he ends up with the princess in his bedroom And he's like hotel and he doesn't know she's the princess.
Scott: and then halfway through the movie He finds out she is.
Scott: and then at the end of the movie she finds out he is and it's it's really good and really Old.
Rym: yeah, it's one of my favorite movies.
Rym: I really like it.
Scott: It's one of my favorite movies, but it's a good movie and everyone should see it Especially before you see this anime.
Scott: if you don't watch if you don't haven't seen Roman holiday And you watch a wreck at least from the first episode you won't know what's going on.
Scott: But it seems like it carries on to the second episode as well even though we haven't seen it.
Rym: yep I have really high hopes for the show.
Scott: I Don't have the highest hopes.
Scott: I'm just kind of average like good.
Rym: It just seems like a generic good Romantic comedy.
Rym: yep, I don't want to keep calling it that but that's what it is and that's Yeah, there's a guy you know he has a job.
Rym: Remember when the boyfriend for the other girl appears.
Scott: Yeah, that was funny.
Scott: So the guy is waiting for a girl outside a movie theater.
Scott: instead this other girl shows up.
Scott: Who's the main character?
Scott: I think she's the main character.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: She's trying to become another.
Scott: hit her the guy.
Scott: She's trying to become a say you yeah she's trying to become a voice actor and Instead of you know going with the girl he was waiting for He goes with this wreck girl.
Scott: Her name is wreck.
Rym: They don't.
Rym: actually it's funny because they don't actually tell each other their names until a certain scene.
Scott: That's right because it's kind of like Roman holiday.
Scott: yeah, they don't know who each other are.
Scott: so he goes to see the movie with this girl instead and Then I had his way out of the movie.
Scott: He sees the girl He was waiting for and then he sees this gigantic guy pick her up instead of him.
Scott: Oh So he ends up going with this girl and having a good time Even though he's a little bit older than she is, but it's fine.
Rym: She's like 20 or something Yep, and then they go home, and then the plot is that all right?
Rym: they live near each other.
Rym: And then he's woken up by fire alarms and her apartment building is burned down or houses burned down.
Scott: so he takes her in and They hit it off.
Rym: And there was a moment where one of our friends Adam was saying he's like Please tell me this doesn't turn into porn.
Rym: please tell me this doesn't turn into porn and it doesn't turn into porn.
Scott: It turns into Roman holiday.
Rym: yep But it's very it's more.
Rym: It doesn't dance around the issue.
Rym: I mean these are two adults and They do what adults do.
Scott: yeah, it's sort of a an open parody like space balls is the Star Wars.
Scott: It's like we are parodying this show, but it's not so much a parody as in.
Scott: they're Twisting it to make it humorous and wacky so much as that.
Scott: there I don't want to say homage because that's not really what it is, but it's.
Rym: I guess they're using it as Semi basis for what's going on?
Rym: Yeah, like it's a nice thing you can because you can reference things, but not have to actually do them.
Rym: But by referencing them you pull in all that stuff from the movie without having to do anything.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Yep yep You can do a lot less stuff in your show just by saying Think about Roman holiday right now, and then you don't do anything in the show because people just thought about it.
Scott: If you haven't seen Roman holiday, though You're probably not gonna get anything out of this show cuz you won't know what the hell's going on.
Rym: Yeah, of course if you haven't seen Roman holiday.
Rym: You're a terrible person.
Scott: I didn't see it till recently.
Rym: I know I couldn't believe that I put it in Netflix and put it to the top of the queue when I found out Scott Hadn't seen it.
Rym: you hadn't seen Something.
Rym: ah the sting there you go.
Scott: Yeah Someone makes an anime about the sting.
Rym: then you know I'll go see the sting.
Scott: you should see the sting right now.
Scott: It's awesome.
Scott: I can watch it like a hundred times.
Rym: Yeah, I said like you know you know what else you said.
Rym: you said in case you don't know I think five times Course.
Rym: I think I finally started to get over my basically blah blah blah blah blah blah basically blah blah blah.
Scott: It's fine.
Scott: I had a teacher once who always said in essence in essence.
Rym: I had one teacher who said quintessential Every opportunity.
Scott: Wow I had another tough one.
Rym: I had another okay guy.
Rym: Okay except he He wouldn't stop saying okay until someone said like acknowledge him in some way.
Rym: One time the class was like no one would say he'd be like okay, okay, and some were like yeah And you go and you keep taught teaching.
Rym: one day No one said anything, and he stood up the front of the room going okay, okay?
Rym: Okay, okay Okay, and then he started teaching.
Rym: It was like his brain was broken for a second.
Scott: How do people get jobs teaching?
Rym: I don't know - ah?
Scott: So we're gonna talk any more about these two anime.
Rym: I don't think we really can without either ruining something or talking more than one episode worth of watching can warrant.
Scott: I Guess yeah, so or on high school host club and rec are both recommended shows.
Scott: rec amended They're not super highly.
Scott: oh my god, this is amazing.
Scott: recommended They're just great shows.
Rym: they're definitely must watch the first episode of shows Absolutely if nothing else.
Scott: watch the first episode if you like it continue to watch and then if you really like it watch to the End.
Scott: but of course my guess is that each show?
Scott: Doesn't have 26 episodes worth of stuff in them.
Scott: unless they come up with something to add in Like if rec follows Roman holiday, and when the Roman holiday runs out picks another old movie.
Scott: That would be awesome That would be awesome, but if they stick with just Roman holiday They've got ten episodes is a little even stretching it a little bit Unless they just break away from Roman holiday into a show.
Scott: that could do that too, but the show has to be good Yeah Which it has the potential to be.
Rym: but we really can't say without seeing more of it.
Scott: and our on high school host club if They come up with new jokes And without becoming monotonous can go on for quite a while as long as they can continue to make jokes but More than 13 episodes, I don't think there's that many jokes in existence
Rym: to use our favorite phrase.
Rym: I am cautiously optimistic And now once again, I'm leaving.
Rym: I will be back Monday evening, so I will be on next Monday's GeekNights, but I will not be here tomorrow.
Scott: So whether I make a GeekNights tomorrow Depends on whether I make a GeekNights tomorrow.
Rym: Yeah, we were gonna record it.
Scott: You know it'll be an all Scott GeekNights.
Rym: Yep, I've learned that doing an all Rym GeekNights is not easy or trivial.
Rym: No, it's not because you feel I mean here.
Rym: We're basically just talking to each other.
Rym: We act the same way on the show that we acting we have friends over.
Scott: When you're just talking on your own to no one It's hard to come up with stuff to say besides Stuff that you would say in a crazy rant or a blog post, but then it's not really appropriate for a podcast.
Scott: You're just talking to yourself.
Scott: Plus when you record those kind of things is much better to write down than to say.
Rym: the worst thing is when you're recording yourself There's the desire and opportunity to self-edit to go back through and clean up everything.
Scott: Well, I wouldn't do that.
Rym: Yeah, but there's the.
Rym: there's the temptation.
Scott: I don't really have the temptation it because the laziness completely eliminates it.
Rym: Ah, I think my laziness is almost overcome by my desire to sound cool.
Scott: Oh, I don't really care about sounding cool.
Rym: I Know good job.
Rym: I Just got a tape a goddamn pop filter to your face someday, that's no good.
Rym: All right, I think we're done.
Rym: That's it for tonight's show and if anyone complains about the fact that there may not be a GeekNights tomorrow You can die in a fire.
Rym: We've done like God we.
Rym: this is episode 115. we have done 116 times about 45 minutes worth of content and Pretty consistently.
Scott: I think we've only missed shows when there are conventions and things and then we always make up for it by having awesome Convention recap shows.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I'll definitely have interviews from an amazement Whoo-hoo, and just you wait until Otakon.
Scott: we're gonna have a week's worth of coverage about that I two damn weeks of yeah, like the pre Otakon week.
Scott: What do we expect to see it Otakon?
Scott: Well, I don't know.
Scott: What do you know?
Scott: what do we expect to do it over at Otakon?
Scott: Is the week after Otakon I'm tired.
Scott: What happened to a gun, oh my god, I don't remember.
Scott: And Otakon isn't even like e3 is like a stuff to know.
Scott: Otakon is just us hanging out.
Scott: Yeah, I have a show about us hanging out for three days.
Scott: Oh Wow, how are we gonna do our shows from the shore?
Rym: Uh, There might be I don't know.
Rym: We'll figure something out.
Rym: What might happen is, you know We'll go to an internet cafe and upload mini bits that whole week.
Scott: Maybe it will still be able to get.
Scott: oh, no, maybe you can still get wireless out the window.
Scott: Who knows?
Rym: Yeah, apparently the loo-ray is gonna be gone.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah well We'll figure it won't burn that bridge after we cross it.
Scott: We will.
Scott: there might there.
Scott: in August there might be a week without GeekNights and then the best week of GeekNights You've ever heard immediately following it.
Rym: Yeah, they'll be like two episodes a night Or something crazy.
Scott: Well, there will be like a whole.
Scott: the geek fables bin will be full and fresh and steaming.
Rym: You realize we could probably do a week just on stories from the previous Otakons.
Scott: Oh, yeah That'll be the week the weeks leading up to Otakon.
Rym: So starting in July This is gonna be great.
Scott: cuz we've been to four Otakons, right?
Rym: Uh, yeah Cuz I didn't.
Scott: we already use up one Otakon as a geek fable.
Rym: We used up the first one, but we didn't tell the whole story.
Rym: We just told the story of how some of our for our former Acquaintances were kind of dumb and they made our Otakon less fun.
Rym: All right, remember the hotel room fiasco and the driving fiasco?
Scott: Yeah, we told that.
Scott: so that's that's the important stuff from that Otakon.
Rym: Yeah other than the oh my god You know experiencing Otakon for the first time you which isn't really.
Scott: Yeah, there's not much to say but that we haven't already said.
Rym: we have the story from last year when our friend Conrad who's a huge Anime fan, but had never been to an Otakon or any big con saw the Otakon dealer's room.
Rym: But that all for another day, yes right now Scott go sleep and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: If you like our podcast, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206 GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.