Rym: It's Wednesday August 9th, and this is a GeekNights special tonight.
Rym: We tell a tale of fanboys.
Rym: So as it should be apparent to everyone who's been listening all week.
Rym: This is yet another GeekNights special.
Rym: We are out of town as part of Otakon and the week of fun that follows it every year.
Scott: Yeah By the time you're listening to this Otakon will be over and we will be far away on a beach or something And we won't be able to record anything.
Rym: So yeah, yes Hence we thought we'd do these short specials to one fill out the feed while we're gone and two.
Rym: so you guys don't forget We exist.
Scott: if this is the first time you're listening to GeekNights.
Scott: This is not normal GeekNights.
Rym: Not at all.
Rym: This is a very special GeekNights.
Rym: Hence is a GeekNights special.
Rym: if you want to know what the show is all about I suggest you look for any episode that doesn't have the word special in the title.
Scott: That would be a good idea.
Rym: There are about a hundred and sixty of them.
Scott: Who knows how many?
Scott: I Think we should just stop using episode numbers and use the numbers that we use on the.
Scott: we don't use episode numbers Anyway, I know but like stop counting the episodes just actually say episode.
Scott: Oh six.
Rym: Oh, whatever We just say what day the episode is.
Rym: Anyway, we've never said what the episode number was ever.
Scott: I think we did like.
Rym: no we didn't.
Scott: we've never introduced the show that way not introduced the show that way but talking about it That way at all Okay.
Rym: Yeah, the only one who's ever done that is you maybe.
Rym: Anyway, since it's anime day our special will involve a story from the days when we used to run the RIT anime club.
Scott: scary days.
Rym: well, they were good days, but one time we were at this convention and Some people from case Western who they also also have a fairly large anime club, you know We met him and they're talking to our club people.
Rym: and after a while they realized wait a minute.
Rym: You're the RIT anime people.
Rym: We have a warning for you.
Rym: And they were dead serious like the tone because cease to become jovial.
Rym: and they were dead serious.
Rym: They said we've got this guy and his name is Steve.
Scott: and we said whoa We have Steve's.
Scott: yeah know all about Steve's.
Rym: we know everything there is to know about guys named Steve and anime clubs.
Rym: In fact, we had two of them and they said no this guy And they couldn't really even describe him.
Rym: They just said he's going to RIT next year and we said, oh great We'll have three Steve.
Rym: and then they said we felt the need to warn you about this guy And we totally blew these guys off.
Scott: Yeah, we're like, okay if you know if this isn't just complete BS either.
Scott: Okay, we have two Steve's already a third Steve isn't you know, whatever we if we can handle the two We got we can handle a third one.
Rym: now to back up a bit the whole thing about Steve's there were we know a bunch Of people named Steve and one of which is good.
Rym: Yeah, one of which is a very good friend of ours.
Rym: There are a couple other Steve's we know who are general.
Rym: Okay people.
Rym: Mm-hmm, but in the anime club, it seemed that a Greater number of people than is statistically probable who were named Steve were also fanboys of the highest order as in Bonboys as in my favorite anime is the baby Anime Like to watch it all night.
Scott: I sit in my room with no friends.
Rym: Yeah, one of them actually used to follow us around describing hentai to us.
Rym: Yeah, like you think we're kidding.
Rym: But no, no, you just follow us around like yeah, he told me remember one day I was trying to eat my brunch at Gracie's and he starts telling me about this Disembodlement porn that he'd been looking at the previous night and I was like, ah Something I need to do and I got up to leave and I hadn't even finished my food and he's like, oh, what are you?
Rym: Up to I'll follow and I was like Something you can't come along to do.
Scott: Eventually, we got rid of that Steve by saying no one likes you.
Rym: go well no No, we got rid of him because Pete who is not a spineless coward told him.
Rym: No one likes you.
Rym: Please go away.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, the rest of us just stood there.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: That's the story for another time.
Rym: I don't know if we actually told that one or not either.
Rym: Yeah, it doesn't matter But all of these Steve's were fanboy fanboy fanboy.
Rym: We were used to running this huge club and run.
Rym: dealing with fanboys was just the power and cars were par for the course.
Rym: We were used to it.
Rym: then Club starts up the next year and lo and behold.
Rym: There's a new member and his name is Steve.
Scott: Oh and They weren't lying.
Rym: He's wearing this bicycle helmet, which he wore all the time as far as I could tell and This guy was a scruffy looking fanboy, but whatever a lot of people in the anime club were kind of scruffy looking.
Rym: Then he opened his goddamn mouth.
Scott: Got damn is not even close to the correct words that need to be used to describe his mouth.
Rym: I mean there were people before us like before the front row crew took over this club.
Rym: the crew before that They all had like.
Rym: there was God boy and fanboy and art boy and fanboy was a slightly derogatory term But it wasn't a bad word.
Rym: like calling someone a fanboy wasn't a terrible offense.
Rym: We felt that this word did not do this person justice not at all.
Rym: So we did not call him fanboy.
Rym: We called him Fanboy with with a huge emphasis.
Rym: I mean that was his name as far as the entire.
Scott: if you just say fanboy That's not.
Scott: no that's not him.
Scott: That's some other word fanboy.
Scott: That's the correct way to say his name.
Scott: this dude motherfucking insane Holy shit, and there's stories of him doing crazy shit outside of anime club, too.
Rym: Yeah, like banging his head against the wall in the lab and freaking out lab attendants and screaming and yelling.
Scott: He was a CS student and see the way CS.
Scott: a lot of CS projects go at RIT is they have a date and then They have like a minimum due date.
Scott: And if you don't get the minimum requirement in by the minimum date Then you don't pass the class and all this stuff and you have to submit your project Electronically and this computer tests your program to make sure it works properly and all this stuff.
Scott: So, you know, he was having trouble with his project.
Scott: He was probably gonna fail.
Scott: I don't know if he did or not But you know, he was in this lab full of people working on their projects and you know And obviously he had some sort of social Disorder.
Scott: Yes, it's called being a fun boy Yeah, and he was like getting up and screaming and you know The little the.
Scott: there was like some girl who is running the lab at the time and you know She's just a person who watches the computer lab, you know and hands you your piece of paper after you print it out and you know Restarts the computer if you have trouble.
Rym: that was the most sought-after job in all of RIT.
Rym: Nothing, except your homework and you got paid.
Scott: I mean she knows something about computer science because you know, it's a CS lab but She's not just gonna she's not supposed to tell the guy how to do his project or anything like that and this guy's like screaming and yelling and he's going crazy and he's hitting things and he hits his head against the wall.
Scott: and Crazy guy.
Rym: now at the anime club He was generally just disruptive and bothersome and he yelled a lot.
Rym: I talked a lot and he talked about hentai and things we didn't want to hear about.
Scott: Yeah, the general rule at anime club was you know, you're not supposed to talk during the show But if you have something incredibly clever to yell out, right then it's all good.
Scott: And the way you can tell this is you yell something out and if everyone laughs that was good.
Scott: if people groan That was bad.
Scott: if people don't say anything that's also bad and it's generally sort of a one-strike deal.
Scott: You know if you if you say funny things all the time and you don't do it too often to be annoying then You know, you got a free pass.
Scott: This guy everything he said was a groan Absolutely everything.
Rym: He just yelled stuff out.
Rym: at any anime we showed like two girls would see each other and he'd be like Oh boy, Yuri time.
Scott: Yeah, and Generally as soon as you get one groan you're supposed to shut up forever forever and ever and ever.
Scott: Yeah, I mean didn't shut up.
Rym: the primary means of punishment in the club were simply social ostracizing Ostracizing.
Rym: Yep Ostracification There's not really a word that we wanted to use there.
Scott: I Guess there isn't no ostracization, I guess That's what he was.
Scott: He was ostracized.
Rym: Yeah, that didn't stop him.
Rym: That didn't stop him.
Scott: no, he would just come up to you and try to talk about things that you didn't care about and Scary scary anime stuff and yep, like I'd be ready to start the the anime club meeting, you know, yell my classic.
Rym: Hi everybody.
Rym: Hi Rym.
Rym: Welcome to anime club blah blah blah blah.
Rym: He would just kind of be standing in front of me at the front of the room and he you know The other couple hundred people are sitting down and he's just kind of standing right in front of me in my way And I'm like, could you please sit down so I can start the meeting?
Rym: now also as Fanboys do he often would work up a sweat and then there were oh, yeah, that was the same dude.
Rym: Yeah, it was the same dude.
Rym: So there'd be odors associated with the sweat.
Rym: and okay Yeah, well we I'll start the first and Scott can finish what actually happened here.
Rym: All right We had a very strict policy on smell.
Rym: if you smell bad a member of our Administration would take you aside and tell you that you smell bad that you need to go home and shower or you're gonna be kicked Out of the club.
Scott: It's not kicked out of the club.
Scott: I thought out of the meeting.
Rym: if you kept doing it you would be barred from the club.
Rym: We never had to bar anyone.
Scott: It's basically He has a crowded room full of people watching something on a screen or a crowded room full of people playing games or dancing.
Scott: If you were giving off an odor and the people around you were disturbed we said, all right You have to leave the room and you can't come back and say you no longer give off an odor.
Rym: now We had those hundreds of pounds of soap that we had Commandeered from RIT at one point.
Scott: basically you're out of college so they get all sorts of free shit to give out to students all the time.
Scott: and somehow we ended up with 44 pound boxes of zest soap.
Scott: now it was shitty soap zest rainforest, whatever.
Rym: This is crap soap, but they were all individually wrapped.
Rym: and think 44 pounds per box.
Rym: I took a box for me.
Rym: Scott took a box for him.
Rym: Our friend Pete took a box for him.
Scott: So that was no.
Rym: Pete took two boxes.
Rym: I think Diddy.
Scott: So 8860 76 boxes of pounds of soap.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: I mean we couldn't almost 200 pounds of soap.
Rym: We couldn't even carry it back to the dorms.
Rym: We stashed it under some stairs in the liberal arts building and we wrote like some bullshit on them like I put a piece of paper on him and I wrote like temporary storage care of and I made up a name and then I put a number on it and I figured that would look official enough To.
Rym: people would leave it alone and they did.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Hey, no one took any soap out of it besides us.
Rym: Yeah, every time I needed soap.
Rym: I just stopped by there open one up take whatever soap I needed.
Scott: Yeah, so We had this soap and one of the boxes belong to the anime club.
Scott: and if someone gave off an odor You know, we try.
Scott: we said hey we can use this soap really discreetly, you know Just kind of hand someone a soap and that's like.
Scott: now they know that they smell.
Scott: they have to go without saying you smell And everyone around here as you say it now, what would a normal human being do when given a bar of soap?
Scott: They would go.
Rym: Oh And leave shower and come back hopefully with the soap or some other kind of soap.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: What did fanboy do?
Scott: Well, he took the soap and he rubbed it in his underarms.
Scott: immediately a dry bar of soap.
Rym: and Then he said thanks We were we were dumbfounded.
Scott: This is not a. was he a homeless person before going to college.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I have no idea what his deal was.
Rym: I never will know I'll probably never see him again.
Scott: Yeah, thankfully very thankfully.
Rym: I mean he really was probably the the epitome of all.
Rym: that is fun boy.
Scott: Yeah, as soon as we had him the other Steve's were like, okay cool.
Scott: Yeah, you know talk about hentai whatever.
Scott: You're not rubbing soap under your arm.
Rym: Yeah, luckily I mean smell is a problem apparently with a lot of anime clubs, but we really kind of had it under control.
Scott: Yeah, well, it's cuz he recognized the problem.
Scott: a lot of other anime clubs and conventions where smells a problem They kind of ignore it or they don't recognize it.
Rym: I think a lot of those cons because they were run by people who also gave off those smells.
Scott: Yeah, but you know by bringing the problem out into the open.
Scott: We really were able to manage it.
Rym: Yeah, plus honestly, nothing will make a fanboy shower faster than public humiliation.
Rym: So in closing I urge you if you're at Otakon or any other big anime convention and a dude smells like an open sewer full of cheese tell him that openly Loudly and the people if you're playing DDR, it's inevitable.
Scott: You're going to smell that's okay.
Scott: That's okay.
Scott: It's just when you're done playing DDR go back to your hotel.
Scott: Take a shower and come back.
Rym: Yeah, I swear to God.
Rym: if you play DDR for two hours and then you're sitting next to me at the cosplay I'm going to kill you.
Scott: And also some people are fat.
Scott: well you shouldn't be but you know.
Scott: if you're fat and if you sweat a lot and smell a lot and you're waiting in line for two hours in the heat of Baltimore or wherever else your Convention may be and thus you sweat and smell after you get your badge go take a shower.
Rym: If you don't and you're sitting next to me at the cosplay, I will kill you.
Scott: I'll publicly humiliate you as well Which might be worse than killing considering there's tens of thousands of people there.
Rym: All right Hooray, we finished a very short episode with little effort and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott special Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: If you like our podcast, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to geeknight@gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.