Rym: It's Tuesday January 17th, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We nominally talk about Mario and Luigi partners in time and Ultima quest of the avatar But we also spend more time than you think arguing about the latest Supreme Court decision in Gonzalez vs.
Rym: Oregon.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So you might have noticed today that I screwed up the forums a little bit and there might have been some downtime or whatever.
Rym: Yeah, everyone lost their avatars.
Scott: Well, only people who uploaded avatars lost them.
Scott: people who had their avatars on another website did not lose them.
Rym: I don't think anyone has their avatar on another site.
Scott: I think one person did actually but that it does.
Scott: that's not the point.
Scott: The point is there was a Potential security threat to the forum.
Scott: So I attempted to upgrade it to a newer version and in the process I accidentally overwrote the images directory which had all the little icons in it.
Scott: Yeah So, oops, my bad Nothing else is hurt.
Scott: Just go re-upload your avatars and everything will be back to normal.
Rym: Yep I mean we did it for your own good because basically we built another site on the same host for another group out there.
Rym: we talked about a little bit and we put the same kind of blog and forum over there and I was logged into that forum Testing it and then I go log into the GeekNights forum and I discover that I am in fact logged into the GeekNights forum as Someone else one of our fine listeners.
Scott: Yes the whale shark Yeah, so there was basically a sort of.
Scott: they usually call it a cross site scripting attack But it's not really cross site because it was the same site with the same piece of software running two times.
Rym: It was like a cross hash cookie PHP session exploit.
Scott: I don't know what it was But it wasn't the guy.
Scott: I wrote to the people who make the forum and they said it was really a configuration error.
Scott: That isn't an issue anymore with the newer newer newer version that we're not gonna use yet because it's still beta But we'll use that version when it's no longer beta.
Scott: The point is is that it's solved now.
Rym: I mean basically all I could have done is someone could have logged in as you but no one knew about it and we fixed It before anyone found out.
Scott: Yep So it's all good.
Scott: Re-upload your avatars and if you're not in the forum go there because I put a secret there.
Rym: You didn't put shit.
Scott: Oh, really?
Scott: Yeah, really now this secrets there.
Rym: what secrets?
Rym: I was just there a second ago secrets to make people go there.
Rym: Yeah, so it means you're gonna add a secret after the show while I'm doing post-production.
Scott: No, I already added a secret, but I'll add it something more obvious later.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: So anyway, we actually have a lot a bit of a non geek news But it's a topic that we're real riled up about.
Rym: so we figured we'd talk about it Since people seem to like here in our opinions and or us yelling at each other yelling.
Rym: But as you're all probably aware the Supreme Court ruled today in Gonzalez vs.
Rym: Oregon that and this is the majority opinion that the DEA and the Attorney General's ban of assisted suicide a Federal mandate Violated the Constitution in the sense that it overrode an Oregon state law saying that assisted suicide is okay and the doctors can do it if they follow a procedure and the patient wants them to.
Scott: In other words, it was a vote in favor of states rights.
Rym: yes in favor of states rights in favor of a right to die in favor of limiting the power of the executive branch and It was just really a really interesting ruling and I guess we'll try to explain why.
Scott: for those of you who aren't big SCOTUS followers, yeah, so what's really cool about this is That it was six to three, I think right?
Rym: Yep So even if someone like when O'Connor steps down and Scalito probably gets in It wouldn't have changed the result because he's almost definitely gonna dissent on this opinion.
Scott: The next thing that it's important to note is the three people who voted against.
Scott: it were Roberts Scalia and Thomas Thomas.
Rym: Now those three claim to be conservative.
Scott: they say they're conservatives yet.
Scott: They voted against states rights.
Scott: Now if that's not the opposite of conservative, I don't know what is.
Rym: I mean basically a little background on this case.
Rym: I think it was in 1996 or 97 that Oregon passed a law saying that if someone's terminally ill and Doctors verify that there is no way to help them.
Rym: They're in pain.
Scott: I think they had to be like going definitely going to die within six months.
Rym: Yeah, exactly.
Rym: Yeah Like a doctor has to say this person will be dead within six months.
Rym: They're in pain blah blah blah and a psychologist to evaluate the person and all these rules to make sure that this isn't abused.
Rym: Then a person can go through all this and request a doctor to painlessly end their life.
Rym: It was called the dying with dignity act.
Scott: Actually, it's even.
Scott: it's even less than that.
Scott: The doctor doesn't even end your life.
Scott: The doctor will prescribe to you pain-killing medication and You have to go get that prescription filled and then take enough of it to kill yourself.
Rym: In fact, if you're too weak, if you're too weak to do it, they'll set up a device that'll do it But you have to make the final call and push the button.
Scott: Yeah, so it's like the doctor doesn't even do it.
Scott: The doctor just sort of it's like someone saying alright You're not allowed to buy a gun.
Scott: So I'm gonna write a piece of paper that says you're allowed to buy a gun and You can shoot yourself with it if you want to.
Rym: I know what it was called the dying with dignity act and regardless of your feelings on right to die or suicide Even though we're very opinionated about it.
Rym: The fact remains that this was voted into law by the majority of voters.
Rym: I believe it was a referendum in Oregon and most people in the state agreed with it.
Rym: so doctors started doing this and Back then a bunch of Republican senators like Orrin Hatch that bastard Got together and decided that they didn't like this.
Rym: they didn't like the fact that people could kill themselves legally.
Scott: Why don't you mind your own business and then to do with you?
Rym: So they went over to Janet Reno and told her to intervene and Janet Reno gave him the finger and said that's the stupidest thing Ever.
Rym: it'd be unconstitutional.
Rym: Leave me alone Mm-hmm, so Nothing could happen.
Scott: Yeah, that's forward.
Scott: and a side note I want to point out that pretty much almost everything in Oregon is a referendum Which means the people actually vote on all their lot most of their laws.
Rym: Yeah, it's not a really cool place.
Rym: I didn't really know much about it until recently.
Scott: Yeah, like an election day they get like these huge books full of stuff and they have to go through and fill out all this Crap, like yes.
Scott: No, maybe yes.
Scott: No, maybe it's really cool there as opposed to other places where your state government does Whatever you don't know.
Rym: I mean, it's a mixed bag because sometimes people don't really know what's best.
Scott: But at least the people of Oregon know exactly what they're getting into Mm-hmm, and this is something that they definitely voted for in a vast majority.
Rym: so fast forward to recently Bush is now president and Gonzalez slash Ashcroft our attorneys general and such.
Rym: now There's a clause in the the controlled substances act Which is that it's basically the thing that they use that and the commerce clause to make drugs illegal federally.
Rym: So things like marijuana and all that
Scott: cocaine
Rym: and the drugs that were used by doctors To administer this death to people who requested it were scheduled to drugs Meaning that they're illegal unless prescribed by a doctor and the legal way to prescribe them is to go through the CSA.
Rym: Now Ashcroft said oh well considering that the CSA says all these blah blah blah.
Rym: If you actually give people these drugs to kill themselves killing themselves is not a valid use of that drug and therefore what that doctor is doing is illegal and Irrespective of state laws making it legal It is now a federal crime to do so and they started trying to get all the doctors in Oregon thrown in jail.
Scott: Alright, so the the exact phrase in question was legitimate medical purpose.
Scott: So they were saying that because suicide was about as far as you can get from.
Scott: well Let me quote the guy.
Scott: if the term legitimate medical purposes is any meaning It surely excludes the prescription of drugs to produce death.
Rym: Now this coming from a supposedly conservative Supreme Court justice Who did or I?
Rym: was that Ashcroft or wasn't one of the justices?
Rym: was that the dissenting opinion?
Scott: I think it.
Scott: Scalia said that.
Rym: oh now Scalia is very conservative.
Rym: He says very pro states rights.
Rym: yet Now he's saying that because he's arbitrarily against something states don't have the right to do it.
Rym: Mm-hmm Yeah, I'm not too fond of that.
Scott: Yeah, man, those lefties.
Scott: Those are the activist judges.
Scott: Let me tell you Yeah, all right, so basically their argument if we're voting against it was that because Killing someone or killing yourself is not a legitimate medical purpose that you couldn't prescribe the illegal drugs for.
Scott: you know this Something that's not a legitimate medical purpose.
Scott: So what this really?
Scott: the decision?
Scott: since we voted, you know, the those guys lost and the good guys won.
Scott: Was that now?
Scott: The definition of legitimate medical purpose is expanded to things like killing yourself.
Scott: We now could include, you know drugs that they don't want.
Rym: see it's actually this ruling is very complicated And I could do a whole podcast on just the majority opinion here.
Rym: But to try to sum up as briefly as I can Basically, what what they ruled is that?
Rym: One the state's obvious if you read the CSA.
Rym: that is intended to prevent illicit drug use specifically abusable drugs for in and to and To eliminate the abuse of these drugs to better society as in getting rid of heroin addicts and crackheads.
Rym: And in addition to that They also decided that one states rights.
Rym: the state has the right to do this and the Attorney General Does not actually write the CSA he merely administers it.
Rym: he parrots it.
Rym: They even use the word parroting.
Rym: the phrase parroting an anti parrot cannon appear fairly often around all these decisions here.
Rym: if an anti parrot cannon existed But basically because it's not he didn't write it and he didn't use it He's just prescribing it the Attorney General has no right to interpret it.
Rym: it is the court's job to interpret it and the only way to possibly use this as a means of Preventing people from killing themselves is to interpret it as to say that it does not include killing oneself.
Rym: Mm-hmm, so and they make like five or six other points and they actually call Ashcroft out directly Basically making fun of him for making a decision on a subject that he knows almost nothing about and has no credentials in.
Rym: Well, they they really ride him in this decision.
Scott: You know, I can see like if the Surgeon General did something like this then it would be like, alright, okay You know, we actually have a real thing going on here But the Attorney General a lawyer getting involved in the doctor department.
Scott: That makes a whole lot of sense.
Rym: I mean, wow Yeah now there's also another really interesting possible.
Rym: well to really ramifications of this is One.
Rym: you may not realize it but Roe vs Wade might weigh very heavily into this decision because this decision among other things says that states Individually have the right to decide whether or not a medical practice is Allowable and that the federal government cannot do so.
Rym: now It's possible that that would actually undermine Roe vs.
Rym: Wade which said that states cannot regulate the right to an abortion.
Rym: Mm-hmm, which not to get into that I disagree with Roe vs Wade in terms of the way it was decided, but I definitely agree with the right of a woman to have an abortion.
Scott: Yeah, but see what they're saying is because remember it's about a legitimate medical purpose.
Scott: So now what we can say is if killing yourself is a legitimate medical purpose by could a doctor for can prescribe medicine Then kill it, you know now we open the door is killing a baby is a legitimate medical purpose And the woman and you're allowed doctors allowed to do it.
Rym: or by the same token that a state could make abortion illegal Despite Roe vs.
Rym: Wade and this would be precedent for it.
Rym: Mm-hmm And it's we.
Rym: there's really no way to say which way it would go.
Rym: It's gonna depend a lot on if Scalito actually gets entered into the Supreme Court because basically he's going to vote on the side of the administration no matter what.
Rym: Yeah, he's pretty much that is.
Scott: but even if he was there right now, it's still pretty cool that it'd be five and four.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: now the other possible unintended consequence of this is that it really kind of guts the CSA in its in the way that it can regulate the use of drugs because a couple of states have legalized medical marijuana recently and Every time they've done.
Rym: So the federal government has said up up up CSA commerce act commerce clause It's still against federal law, even though it doesn't cross state boundaries.
Rym: We're gonna come in and arrest you.
Rym: Anyway, we're gonna send federal marshals.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So This basically says that the state has the right to regulate that and not the federal government.
Scott: Yes, there's rights.
Rym: So there are only two things keeping a state from legalizing drugs right now the CSA and the Commerce Clause.
Rym: Now the CSA was gutted because of this decision.
Rym: It really can't be used as justification for having federal laws that make substances illegal anymore.
Rym: However, it does not get rid of the Commerce Clause, which Alright, well if I wrap this up because you don't want a commerce clause is the line in the Constitution That says Congress is allowed to make laws like the CSA.
Scott: Yeah, so Congress can make another law anytime they feel like and There's not much you can do about it.
Rym: What the Commerce Clause does is it says that the federal government can regulate interstate commerce Not intra only commerce between two states or between a state and a foreign power or between the federal government and a foreign power But whatever.
Rym: now The thing is the Commerce Clause is very broad and for the last pretty much since the Civil War They've used the Commerce Clause to regulate internal state matters And the rationale is that even though it's entirely within a state it can affect other states Which in my opinion is horseshit.
Scott: It is I agree that it's horseshit, but there's really not much you can do about it.
Scott: now It's sort of like well, they decided Roe vs.
Scott: Wade.
Scott: There's not much you can do about it.
Scott: now They decided the Commerce Clause for hundreds of years to pretty much be anything.
Scott: the federal government completely controls anything even close to commerce and Congress can make any law at once Pertaining to anything even close to commerce and there's not much you can do about it.
Rym: See this all goes back to the Civil War Because I mean a lot of people down south and a lot of historians don't call it the Civil War.
Rym: They call it the war of northern aggression.
Rym: Now I used to make fun of that a lot.
Rym: Ah the war northern aggression, but Imagine if slavery hadn't been an issue in the Civil War.
Rym: Then if you look at it It's a bunch of states who have decided that they don't like the federal government and that they want to rule themselves Breaking away and the federal government sending troops in and killing countless people And having a huge war and raising cities to the ground in order to force them to remain a part of a union that they'd Have not want nothing to do with
Scott: Yep, but then you think about it You throw the slavery in there and all of a sudden it becomes a bunch of slave drivers.
Rym: and then this heroic country going to say hey if you want to keep you know, I hate it when an ideology or We're basically when an ideology gets clouded by an issue.
Rym: I'm with the south Ideologically.
Rym: the problem is they use that ideology to do to make an issue of something stupid.
Rym: They wanted slaves, which is not cool.
Scott: Yeah But at the same time they could have wanted something good.
Scott: It could have been like hey We want our state's rights so that we can have video games because there's a federal law outlawing video games You know and that's a good thing.
Scott: states rights are good Because it was associated with slavery.
Scott: people think it's bad, but there's nothing wrong with it.
Scott: It's great.
Rym: Yeah There's only something wrong with slavery.
Scott: Mm-hmm a lot wrong with slavery.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah But that's enough constitutional talk.
Rym: I'll try to a whole show on it sometime because we talk about geekery a lot But we're very politically motivated and we're very loud about it and we could probably do an entire separate four day a week.
Rym: Just on politics.
Scott: there there are different kinds of geeks.
Scott: they're political geeks out there.
Rym: that works.
Rym: if we ever run out of technology Let's just turn Mondays into.
Scott: I don't think we're gonna run into technology.
Rym: Hey, maybe there's some sort of Luddite revolution.
Scott: Then we'll definitely keep going on about technology to get rid of those Luddites.
Rym: So we had one more news bit and we'll probably kind of gloss over it because we've gone a while already.
Scott: Okay, so you might have read today.
Scott: well you might know what I think about World of Warcraft.
Rym: not so great Yeah, today's real-life comics pretty much described what I think about World of Warcraft.
Scott: Yeah Yesterday's rest doesn't matter.
Scott: Basically, what's been happening in World of Warcraft is there's lots of gold farmers.
Rym: These are people who are basically hired.
Rym: or they do it to make money and they play the game Grinding Lee to make gold and then sell it on eBay or they sell it on other various websites.
Scott: Actually, there are various gold farmers and power levelers that were advertising in PC gamer and they would advertise in their monthly With like big expensive ads and PC gamer.
Scott: the editors got together and they went to.
Scott: you know The company that actually takes care of the ads because you know video game editors don't actually You know take care of the stuff on that level.
Scott: They're below that.
Scott: and they said you have to stop putting these ads for gold farmers and power levels in our magazine.
Scott: and they did.
Scott: They gave up all that money to say that's bad and we're gonna get rid of it.
Rym: And there's been an unexpected consequence of all this in World of Warcraft.
Rym: Now there is a huge amount of discrimination against anyone who doesn't speak English because what the the common Stereotype is that the gold farmers are Chinese people which is kind of true.
Scott: Yeah The thing is.
Scott: is that sure?
Scott: most of the gold farmers are Chinese?
Scott: There's some non-chinese gold farmers, but most of them are.
Rym: but you know what?
Rym: most of the Chinese are not gold farmers.
Rym: Yeah They're a pro.
Scott: They're like a one and a half million people playing World of Warcraft in China and a very small percentage of them are gold farmers.
Rym: It's just like spam.
Rym: I mean most spam in the world comes out of Russia and China.
Scott: The most email from Russia and China is not spam.
Scott: Yep, because there's just so much email I'll draw a Venn diagram for you sometime.
Rym: Understand what we should have some sort of like.
Rym: live Oh Akaki to go with the podcast so we can have little diagrams and draw things.
Scott: Yeah, let's not so.
Scott: Now there's a problem where what's happening is People start a group and they want people to join and they say hey before you can join our group.
Scott: We don't know.
Scott: you Type two or three sentences in perfect English, you know.
Scott: they ask them a couple questions and expect them to answer in English and if the grammar is broken or Anything like that then they say oh you're just a gold farmer go away now.
Rym: This is the point at which I call shenanigans on this possibly apocryphal tale Because I don't think there's anyone in World of Warcraft who uses proper grammar.
Scott: I can name a few people but I know those people well.
Rym: actually Scott you had some trouble with grammar the other day didn't know How an adverb works?
Scott: I know an adverb works.
Rym: You didn't seem to realize that adverbs can also modify other other adverbs and in fact cannot also modify adjectives.
Scott: Well, it's like a thing.
Scott: I know it's like I use adverbs correctly when I speak and when I write.
Scott: I just you know don't know the The rules like.
Scott: I guess I can quote you and yesterday It's like I can play D&D and I can roll a d20 and I can tell you if I hit or not.
Scott: But I can't tell you.
Scott: you know, there was like a base attack bonus and a deflection.
Scott: God knows what other talk is in that book.
Rym: So you are you are right.
Rym: good Yeah, yeah.
Rym: Yeah We Argue about grammar a lot.
Rym: We don't really argue Scott just things.
Scott: It's not really much to argue about grammar.
Scott: This is right wrong?
Scott: Yeah, you look it up and you say up.
Scott: There's the right answer.
Scott: That's yeah.
Rym: No, there was the point when you denied the fact that sometimes is or somewhat was an adverb.
Scott: But I didn't know it was an adverb.
Rym: it didn't what you think it was.
Scott: What do you think?
Scott: it didn't seem very adverb like.
Scott: but then I looked at dictionary and I was wrong.
Scott: So what do you want?
Rym: Yeah, I mean, what did you think it modified?
Rym: Somewhat what?
Scott: Well, I guess it could modify An adjective.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Yep, hence Yeah, all right.
Scott: It's not an ad adjective But I figure you know an adjective.
Scott: I thought an adjective could modify an adjective.
Scott: You ever do one of those.
Scott: name that tune kind of thing.
Scott: So they play a song and you got to say what it is and who sung it.
Rym: name that beard name that beard.
Scott: More like name that tune.
Scott: But anyway, it's a PBS of all places put up a nice little flash game where 18 questions, I think Yeah, 18. and they play sound effects from old old old video games.
Scott: we're talking Atari and Intellivision 2 an arcade old Atari era arcade machines.
Scott: and Then they ask you which game it was and they'll usually give you three choices and then also give you like a cryptic sentence is a hint on some of them and I got a 15 out of 18, but that's because I didn't look at the hints and a couple of them threw me off.
Rym: Yep, I didn't look at the hints either.
Rym: I only got a 13 but two of them were bullshit.
Scott: I gotta say which ones are bullshit.
Rym: Oh the berserk one wasn't so much bullshit It was always and I got that one, right?
Rym: He cuz I. I'm actually really really good at the Atari version, but I didn't know there was an arcade version of berserk.
Scott: It's an arcade version of everything Mmm all the Atari game.
Rym: I defy you to find an arcade version of snap fucking foo.
Scott: Look, yeah, there might be.
Scott: Mame has so many freaking roms man.
Scott: It's yeah.
Scott: But anyway, if you want to test your old-school Atari knowledges head on over to my thing of the day and You'll see how you stand up.
Rym: It's quite cool, dude.
Rym: Yeah, some of them are real obvious and real awesome.
Rym: So my thing this is in a foreign policy magazine, which I actually used to read Because I used to be able to like.
Rym: the thing is in my high school We had the Lexis Nexus for free and we also had subscriptions to pretty much every magazine Ever RIT had.
Scott: that I didn't take advantage of until way later though.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, but the internet provided much much more.
Rym: Yes, it did.
Rym: But I used to say just have time when I was bored in high school So I go to the library and just read like all these various magazines I was a big fan of the Atlantic Monthly - mm-hmm.
Rym: But basically this is a nice online bit and they think they have more in the magazine, but it's a photo journal of Bangladeshi scrap workers.
Scott: Bangladesh isn't that like one of the poorest countries that are?
Rym: is yes Bangladesh is one of the poorest countries that has ever existed.
Scott: I mean I remember a thing from a Bangladesh guy and this is back in the days when they actually talked about first world second world third world instead of developing and developed nations and The guy was like, yeah, Bangladesh is like the fourth world nation.
Scott: It's so bad and so poor.
Rym: so Bangladesh also has what pretty much the largest beach in the world and it's also used as the largest docking or dry docking facility in the world.
Rym: and You know super tankers and by super tanker I mean the giant giant giant oil tankers that are.
Rym: they're the biggest things on the ocean.
Rym: They're bigger than a super aircraft carriers and they carry oil around.
Rym: They wear out pretty kit quick and when they get decommissioned more than half of them in the world end up in Bangladesh Where and I kid you not about 200,000 peasants with their bare hands tear them apart to scrap and that is the primary industry there.
Rym: This accounts for almost all the steel that Bangladesh has.
Scott: That's a lot of steel though.
Scott: These pictures are and they get it for free.
Rym: They don't get it for free.
Rym: You'd look at these pictures.
Rym: These people do something that I I mean money-wise.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I couldn't imagine people actually doing this.
Rym: I mean they show this super tanker and then they show it gone Because these people have just ripped every piece of steel off of it and carried it away on their backs.
Rym: Wow these pictures are Worth looking at.
Scott: I mean some of the things I can understand like oh, they took the fire extinguisher They took you know, the stair railing.
Scott: they took the chairs You know that that kind of stuff.
Scott: the doors.
Scott: you can take the hinges off and take the door but like Eventually you get to pieces that are just big heavy pieces of metal bolted together and welded together.
Scott: You can't really take them especially not without Extremely powerful tools yet.
Rym: This supplies 80% of Bangladesh's steel this industry.
Rym: Well, yeah, these are some very sad looking people.
Scott: I'd be pretty sad if I was hanging out in a tank.
Rym: I mean, I guess the only Glimmer I can see in this is that if nothing else it proves the tenacity of mankind to survive no matter what.
Rym: Mmm, look at what these people do to survive and people here think they got it bad.
Scott: It's like the power goes out.
Rym: Yeah, or their blog gets spammed.
Rym: So today's video game day and since we've gone long that's fine.
Rym: We have one and a half games to talk about.
Scott: Yeah, totally awesome.
Rym: So we're gonna talk today about Mario Luigi partners in time which Scott just beat and Then I'm gonna rant about Ultima for until he stops me I thought it was - no no no - is God We'll talk about.
Rym: don't even get me into Ultima.
Rym: Anyway, I'm gonna get into Ultima, but not just yet.
Scott: So Mario Luigi partners in time.
Scott: I just beat it on the train today and I Like the Superstar Saga a little bit better than the partners in time.
Scott: But the partners in time was worth playing.
Scott: if I would have known that it wasn't as good as Superstar Saga I might have wanted to pay like five dollars less, but whatever It was still pretty hilarious.
Scott: You know, there's a lot of funny jokes here and there and The you can all.
Scott: the one thing I didn't like about it was that you never really They had a future world in a past world and I thought that would be the cool mechanic that you know.
Scott: Like Metroid Prime 2 has.
Scott: we're like, oh you're in the future.
Scott: in the past You know the puzzles crossover like that, but not really.
Scott: It's just the past is where all the game is and the future is just the happy princess castle town where you do You know normal town stuff.
Scott: That was it.
Scott: Uh-huh, you know and Superstar Saga the old the Gameboy one had more of like this exploring type of thing where you'd go different places and Try to find stuff.
Scott: This one was like very linear.
Scott: You can always turn around like When a level was real big like a third of the way through it.
Scott: They would give you like a little pipe to get back to the beginning in case you wanted to go back to the.
Scott: you know The town castle to freshen up, you know get some more mushrooms and whatever.
Scott: But other than that, it was like a straight through game.
Rym: I don't know if I like that.
Rym: I'm getting kind of tired of that kind of linear gameplay.
Scott: Yeah one thing though at the end I don't want to give away the end, but I will say that there were three bosses.
Scott: There was a square boss and a cube boss.
Scott: Wow, yeah and there were this.
Scott: there was a flurry of save spots at the end and Once I figured out what they were doing with these save spots.
Scott: I actually thought it was pretty nice.
Scott: It was.
Scott: you know, you know, there are always things that happen in games over and over again and everyone's annoyed by them and No one ever seems to correct them no matter how many years they annoy us for.
Scott: and in this game They corrected one of those things right before The the point of no return.
Scott: right.
Scott: there was a normal save spot.
Scott: then Like I was about to go in this door and there's this little suitcase character who is part of the plot But whatever and you're always carrying him around with you and he comes out and he says This is the point at which you will not be able to turn back.
Scott: You know, the bosses are ahead.
Scott: Sit, you know you better save and then he forces you to save.
Scott: he like blocks the paths.
Rym: Wow Final Fantasy 4 could have freaking use that because I'm at the end on the GBA version and For all of you remember the end of that game.
Rym: Basically, there's a final save spot and then if you want to go fight You know Zemus and all the crazy stuff at the end You have to walk for like two or three minutes and then you have to go through a couple minutes of plot and dialogue And all this crap before you can fight him and then you die in two seconds You have to do it again.
Rym: You have to go through so much to fight him every time you lose.
Scott: Then I go through and there is yet another save spot and I save.
Scott: and you know And I fight the first boss and then after the first boss I hit the save spot and he says Do you want to go back before you save the princess?
Scott: You know, I guess I kind of get beat that come on.
Scott: Everyone saves a princess in Mario.
Rym: Now the princess dies.
Scott: Yeah, the princess totally dies.
Scott: He says do you want to go back?
Scott: So when you whenever you hit this save spot You can actually use it to teleport back and fight that boss again and go back into the game Where the boss is unbeaten.
Scott: All right.
Scott: so you can do that or you can just save and continue and fight the next boss and After that boss is yet another save spot Which will let you teleport back in time to before you beat the bosses.
Scott: and then is if you know you go and there's this The third boss and there's yet another save spot that will let you teleport back or save.
Scott: So it's like I have the game saved at the end of the game after I've beaten the whole thing.
Scott: There's nothing left to beat at all.
Scott: But if I go and hit that save spot I can go back into the game.
Scott: You know before I beat the final bosses, that's kind of cool It's really.
Scott: it was very handy once I realized what the hell they were doing.
Rym: It's like oh you've made the end less painful Thank you, yep now it's fun to just go back and fiddle with things when you're bored a year from now.
Scott: Yeah, there's not much to fiddle with though.
Scott: Honestly in this game I mean I pretty much cleaned out every single area for every secret I needed and Like I leveled up all the characters like level 31 and I didn't ever actually level up.
Scott: I just went through the game straight and Because they pretty much mastered the use of all of the bros items You know and you only don't really need to use all the bros items like the chomp ones.
Scott: I never used some of the items.
Scott: they were just Harder to use than like the red shells and they didn't do as much damage.
Scott: so I never had a reason to use them.
Scott: and I still beat the living crap out of the final bosses doing like a zillion damage because I've Bothered to collect enough beans and get good badges.
Scott: and collecting beans was a lot more fun than some of the other tasks being animals.
Scott: Yeah, the bean collecting was actually more advanced.
Scott: in the gameboy one, you know, it feels like they kind of like Like it's a good game because Mario and Luigi Mario RPG type game.
Scott: But this one feels a little more like like they hurried up to get it out, you know.
Scott: And they didn't you know make the fullness what they could have.
Scott: They just said oh we'll use a B X and Y and the DS and you know, we'll be all good You know.
Scott: whereas with the Superstar Saga and thousand-year door paper Mario They really made like paper door the paper Mario.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: That's like the amazing.
Rym: Yeah, cuz I I'm real liria games like this in general, but paper Mario is calling to me And if I ever have free time, I'm just gonna sit down and beat that game like bang.
Scott: Yeah, so For partners in time if You're like a huge fan of the you know the Mario and you like paper Mario's and Mario RPGs You should get it cuz it's not the greatest of those but it's still great enough to warrant playing.
Scott: But if you're if that's not your thing, then this is not the one to play.
Scott: you're better off playing the gameboy one or Paper Mario on the GameCube.
Rym: paper Mario on the GameCube looks just fantastic.
Scott: It's totally and it's much bigger and more interesting.
Rym: and there's a goomba girl.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know what it is about this goomba girl.
Rym: It's cute.
Scott: She's real cute.
Rym: So this podcast kind of went long as they tend to do when we're real opinionated.
Rym: But a real quick and nice aside.
Rym: Ultima for the quest of the Avatar.
Rym: Now this was an NES game and I just have a question to the world as anyone actually played All these Ultima games and are any of them actually playable?
Rym: They're all just these terrible monstrosities and I could never play any of them for more than about 10 seconds without just getting pissed off And stopping I just tried to play what three of them?
Scott: Yeah on the NES downstairs all the computer ROM NES emulator downstairs and all three of them.
Scott: well Some of them seemed like they had interesting components to them.
Scott: All three of them were just completely unplayable terrible games that I just ah It is painful to even try to do anything like talking to people was hard.
Rym: I Mean, there's one Ultima game that I've ever played that didn't suck as much And that was Ultima for the Avatar because it looks it's the only one that looks like a real NES game like it works like a console game, of course, it came out for the PC too.
Rym: And if you play that version well I'm sorry It's a completely different game.
Rym: play the NES version.
Rym: It's probably the best Ultima game ever created.
Scott: You know, I have a feeling though that like Ultima on the PC was something different.
Rym: cuz in now I played several of them on the PC.
Rym: They're terrible game.
Rym: Really?
Scott: Yeah, cuz whenever I hear people talk about Ultima in a good light, they seem to always be talking about PC games.
Scott: I never you know when they're talking about.
Rym: well, they all.
Scott: any s is like something else.
Rym: They all came out on the PC Mm-hmm and Ultima zero.
Rym: the first one is just this piss-poor like semi 3d dungeon crawl thing and There was no plot at all.
Rym: Really.
Scott: Is that one of those ones of the first-person perspective?
Scott: kind of any drag items Like into like the arm slot the chest slot.
Rym: It's not that sophisticated.
Scott: Oh, I like those what that's like dungeon master That those are great or dungeon hack.
Rym: I used to play.
Rym: Mm-hmm But basically all the Ultima's were on the PC and they were all just these plotting.
Rym: Terrible arbitrarily difficult games like some Nintendo games are arbitrary.
Rym: You know pick the right warp area throw the holy water on the right brick.
Rym: But just to give you a sample because Ultima 4 in my opinion is the best of these games and it's actually a really good game except for the fact that part of the plot is that you have to find like these seven runes and these seven stones all these different items.
Rym: and Here's an example of the locations of these items.
Rym: one of these runes is if you go to a certain town called pause which is south of another town and you go into the town and you walk over to where the stables are and Then you walk like two spaces to the left and three spaces up and then you hit a and search You'll find this critical plot item that you need to win the game.
Scott: Is there like a character in the game who says hey look search the stable to find the item or anything like that?
Rym: Barely, you'll find a guy on the other side of the world completely unrelated who will say like there's something special in that town.
Rym: There's someone else in another side of the world who would say something like something something stables.
Rym: That's probably the easiest.
Scott: is there any sort of connection between them at all?
Rym: God Let me put it this way.
Rym: That's probably the easiest one to find.
Rym: great I mean like that.
Rym: you can has magic in the game, right?
Rym: But not only do you have magic points, but you have spell components like ten different kinds of spell components.
Rym: Some are cheap some are expensive.
Rym: You've only some cities have them for sale.
Rym: They only have certain ones for sale.
Rym: and To learn a new spell you have to learn which components to use as in literally you have to remember based on people you talk to that it's Mandrake ash and Something else to cast this spell.
Scott: in order to know how to cast the spell I would just write them all down in a piece of paper.
Rym: Yeah, you have to use a piece of paper.
Rym: You can't win this game.
Rym: You have to write down gobs of information and memorize things and memorize that certain colors go with certain virtues that go with certain symbols that go with certain stones.
Rym: and It's just this.
Rym: I Hate this game so much yet.
Rym: I played it constantly because I I was convinced that there was something to it.
Rym: Mm-hmm of course now.
Rym: I know better because I read game facts, and I found out that there's nothing to it Really nothing at all.
Rym: now the game just kind of a and when you finally beat it It's just arbitrary and crap and the endings kind of blah.
Scott: the ending is blah If usually games like that have a crazy exciting ending.
Rym: no in fact I won't link to it because I don't want to spoil it.
Rym: But if you google around you'll find a site that has pictures of the entire end of the game.
Rym: It's just some text.
Scott: That's it basically.
Rym: Wow, I mean the ultimate games form this giant epic overarching plot and the continuity is Ridiculous.
Rym: like you'll be a party who kills a guy this evil guy named mundane in a previous ultimate game.
Rym: And then an ultimate for if you remember it because the world's always the same.
Rym: Where the skull of mundane is you can go get it, and it's as powerful artifact And in fact you have to get it to beat the game.
Scott: Oh I get it.
Scott: yeah That's kind of cool.
Rym: It'd be cool.
Rym: If the games didn't suck ass.
Rym: Yeah, I guess what I'm looking for.
Rym: cuz I'm done ranting I could rant forever.
Rym: Is there anyone out there listen to GeekNights who actually played and liked any Ultima game ever?
Rym: cuz I want to talk to you.
Rym: I got some questions.
Scott: Yeah, also If you can beat any levels in the silver surfer for the NES I'd like to hear from you also.
Rym: We should just have a tournament with anyone who listens to GeekNights.
Rym: She's close enough to us.
Rym: you get a stopwatch timer.
Rym: whoever lasts the longest wins.
Scott: No, I knew a kid way back in the day who actually had the cartridge.
Scott: He could beat a few levels of that game.
Scott: It was scary.
Scott: On the on a cartridge no less no saving and loading business.
Rym: All right, so we're done.
Rym: this podcast went long.
Rym: my final bit is simply that we recorded a new closer and Tell us what you think.
Rym: it's just information about the podcast like it was last time we added the phone number to it Yeah number that Scott said incorrectly a couple podcasts ago.
Scott: Yeah, that was just a little confusing.
Scott: The correct phone number is in the closer.
Rym: Call it leave us messages, and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Scott: make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is accorded with absolutely no studio and no audience But unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.