Rym: It's Thursday June 29th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We answer your questions on the ask Rym and Scott show.
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: Okay, so we just got done recording two hours of audio for someone else's podcast.
Scott: yep And now we're immediately recording our own podcast, but if you want to listen to us on someone else's show Namely the geek speak podcast, but with Ian Levenstein just go to speak.
Scott: geek speak calm speak.
Scott: geek Speak calm.
Scott: and his latest episode, which I don't know when he's gonna put it up about anime and anime conventions And all that sort of stuff Includes us for the entire duration.
Scott: and if you just can't get enough listening to us talk about the same old stuff over and over Again, you should go listen to that.
Rym: Yeah, you have interviews us and half.
Rym: We just kind of talk about an anime next and anime cons in general.
Scott: Yeah, it shows a pretty good show and if you're into geeky things And you just can't get enough podcasting as four nights a week is enough for you add him to your little podcast Subscribe you bit.
Rym: Yeah, also we finally started making our promos which sometime over the next week I'm going to edit and put up which means you might start hearing promos from all the shows.
Scott: We like all the crap.
Rym: Yeah, we've done how many episodes we never did a promo I know isn't it crazy?
Rym: it's about time.
Scott: It also might mean there might be an influx of a bunch of new people who hear our promo on other shows.
Rym: Yeah, unlike the previous.
Rym: I don't know like five influxes.
Scott: We've had I know right We're just waiting for the one big influx where like our listenership quintuples.
Rym: If anything that might be.
Rym: once we do our live show at Otakon, it might be yep.
Rym: But anyway, as we promised today, we're going to be doing our.
Rym: the listeners interview us episode At least the first of these.
Rym: we might do it again sometime Mm-hmm.
Scott: This is very easy to do when we get a whole bunch of more listeners.
Scott: You know they have a whole enough new questions to ask us.
Rym: Thus we'll be kind of quick on the news and things of the day mostly because one we want to fit as many of these Questions in as we can.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: We're probably gonna do all of them.
Scott: If not most of them.
Rym: Yep, and two I kind of want to get to sleep because we're basically recording two and a half Times the number of pot the amount of podcast we usually record tonight.
Scott: Yeah, we're going it.
Scott: We're doing a podcast a whole shit ton of it.
Scott: going to sleep waking up going to work going to the beach.
Scott: That's our schedule right now.
Scott: Okay So, let's see.
Scott: start with the news.
Scott: This is a quick news.
Scott: There's a guy named mark pilgrim who's been a crazy Mac user.
Scott: He's had using Mac since 1984 when I was two.
Rym: He has a Mac tattoo.
Scott: Yeah He's a Mac Apple tattoo on his right bicep and he's owned 50 Macs at least.
Scott: He is switching to Ubuntu after becoming fed up with proprietary Mac file formats and the increasing use of DRM Technologies in the Mac OS.
Scott: why didn't this guy talk and do this before we bought a Mac?
Rym: I want to try and get him on the show Bailey.
Scott: that might be a good idea.
Rym: I would like to talk to him because I want to see what he has to say because honestly though I haven't used the Mac very thoroughly like.
Rym: I haven't used it as my Daily computer for all my normal stuff, but I used it a lot for non podcasting And I liked it except for the podcasting bit, but I didn't put it to heavy use.
Rym: I'm really curious what this guy has to say.
Scott: I don't know how much he's into the podcasting So, I don't know how much insight.
Rym: Well, no, I mean I want to ask him about everything else.
Scott: Yeah, everything else.
Scott: This guy seems like a good choice.
Scott: Maybe we should send him an email.
Rym: If anything, I'd like to get an email response that we could read.
Scott: that would be cool, too.
Rym: Cuz I realize you know listening to anime world order which I want to plug again.
Rym: We even we plugged anime world order on the other podcast that we were talking on God.
Scott: Yeah, just keep it.
Scott: It's like we don't even plug people anymore.
Scott: But you know, I mean we are not shills.
Scott: We do not plug people, you know out of because we want them to be promoted.
Scott: We're not plug people because someone paid us or told us to.
Scott: yeah, like when we say we mentioned something else It's because we're mentioning it.
Scott: we just do it so often.
Rym: Yeah And like if we ever play a promo or anything You can we can guarantee to you that we would only ever play a promo if it was a show we actually do or would Listen to.
Scott: yeah, you know what it is.
Scott: It's like if I mentioned the Simpsons.
Scott: people don't go all your shilling the Simpsons because it's a popular thing.
Scott: You don't shill it you just refer to it.
Scott: But when you refer to something very unpopular and amateur like a podcast it comes off as a promotion.
Rym: you see Plus also while we were just on this podcast We sent a long audio feedback to anime world order and they sent us a long email response Which I then responded to with a longer email response response.
Scott: And then I did a little uh, you know additional punch with a tiny email.
Scott: Yep, relatively tiny email.
Rym: Yeah, only because as Scott said the beginning of his email Rym was very thorough.
Scott: He was indeed.
Rym: Okay So you'll be able to hear us on at least two other podcasts in the near future.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: But anyway, uh, that's it.
Rym: Let's do some news.
Scott: We did the news.
Scott: My news was this guy who?
Rym: Alright, right.
Rym: Yeah, we're going kind of quick here.
Scott: We want to get to the questions, which is the fun part.
Rym: Yep, you know, I don't have a news.
Rym: I'll just note that the Supreme Court of the United States Basically just told the administration President Bush that they can't keep doing this Guantanamo Bay thing.
Scott: Oh That was obvious.
Rym: Yeah, but it really you know what.
Scott: you can just go out on the street and ask any guy and they'll tell You that that's obvious.
Rym: what surprised me was the way the Supreme Court ruled on it and also the fact that Roberts who was appointed by Bush and I really was leery of him and his leanings and how how Loyal he would be to the administration versus how loyal he would be to his judicial ethics.
Rym: And he actually bowed out of this decision because he sat on the lower court's ruling Mm-hmm, and I just I I have a little bit more respect for this guy as a result.
Scott: Yeah, I was leery of him too at first but as time goes on I'm less worried about him.
Scott: Yeah, but well it remains to be seen.
Rym: still I'm more leery of skeletal.
Scott: Yes, but you know, what do you want?
Rym: Yeah, but I'll just note that this is actually probably very important news But the consequences and ramifications will not come out for many weeks or months.
Scott: That's always the problem with things.
Rym: Well mainly because the Supreme Court has no enforcement power.
Rym: I mean a long time.
Scott: Don't they have marshals?
Rym: They have federal marshals, but it doesn't quite work the way you might think it would work.
Rym: I mean if anyone isn't really familiar with American history, there is a point where Andrew Jackson who?
Rym: I honestly have a very low opinion of this man, though I have a high opinion of the fact that I have a high opinion of his Testicles, yeah, I have a low opinion of his ideas.
Rym: Yeah, it's like he did.
Rym: he was really good at doing things, but the things he did were bad.
Scott: Yeah, it's like someone who's you know knows how to get the job done and has the balls to just do the job But at the same time what his the job he tries to do is stupid.
Rym: Well to make a long story short He wanted to wipe out the Native Americans in an area and he wanted to do something with like this National bank business all sorts of bad stuff.
Rym: well It was real bad bad stuff or at least things that weren't really so constitutional.
Rym: Yeah, and the Supreme Court.
Rym: and John Marshall the head of the Supreme Court said the best Supreme Court justice ever.
Rym: He said no, you can't do that.
Rym: It is unconstitutional.
Rym: the Supreme Court ruled.
Rym: I think almost unanimously and Andrew Jackson said the famous words John Marshall has made his decision.
Rym: Let's see him and force it.
Scott: yep, and the only way he can do that is with US marshals of course back Then he couldn't.
Rym: so Jackson just marched the army out and killed all the Indians.
Scott: Yep, it was a dark day in American history very dark, and now he's on the $20 bill.
Scott: Andrew Jackson.
Rym: Yeah, funny how that works.
Rym: Abraham Lincoln's on money.
Rym: He was kind of a cock.
Rym: Thomas Jefferson got dicked with a $2 bill.
Scott: Yeah, Thomas Jefferson is like no money.
Rym: What the hell Ben Franklin's okay?
Scott: Yeah, he's on the hundred.
Scott: That's that's cool.
Rym: He's on the big bill.
Rym: Yep course then we got like grant.
Rym: What a grant ever do?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: didn't they have $50 bills before grant?
Scott: who was on it?
Scott: Then I don't know they should take grant off and put on Teddy Roosevelt.
Rym: Yeah, Teddy Roosevelt's the man.
Rym: Yeah, no he should be on something weird like the three dollar at 80 cent.
Scott: They should be on the 50.
Scott: I'm telling you the 50 just sings.
Scott: Teddy to me All right things of the day What you got all right.
Rym: uh I didn't really have anything good for today And I thought about just skipping things of the day and getting right to the questions.
Rym: But Scott had a decent thing of the day, so I came up with something I almost made my thing of the day the picture of Lisa and James's new baby bunnies because they're adorable even though you can only see a tiny ball of fur.
Scott: Yeah, they're just indistinguishable balls of fuzz.
Rym: so I'll make that my thing of the day once.
Rym: They're more recognizable as bunnies.
Rym: But instead I was poking around in the internet.
Rym: I actually searched for Hitler in Google video just to see if anything funny would come up And I saw something that looked like it was gonna be funny like someone voiced over Hitler funnily.
Rym: But it just petered out and wasn't.
Rym: and then I found the entirety of one of my favorite Monty Python sketches ever mr.
Rym: Hilta, that's an excellent sketch yes, and I mr..
Scott: Hilta escape.
Rym: Hi, Kay.
Rym: That's a map of Stalingrad.
Scott: You got the wrong map.
Rym: I Was never head of the Gestapo.
Rym: yeah, it's just.
Rym: it's really.
Rym: you've never seen.
Rym: I mean a lot.
Rym: everyone's seen the Monty Python movies.
Rym: I know a lot of people who have never actually seen Monty Python's Flying Circus.
Rym: whoa If any of you out there have never seen any Monty Python's Flying Circus not just the movies But Flying Circus.
Rym: watch my thing of the day.
Rym: It's got Japanese subtitles in case someone wants that.
Rym: but it's just.
Rym: it's hilarious.
Rym: I can't really say anything.
Scott: Japanese not Chinese.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: I'm sure because I saw hiragana.
Scott: Okay, my thing day is an awesome really quick video.
Scott: You know those firecrackers.
Scott: they were.
Scott: there's a string and you light the string and it goes through the firecrackers And they snap off in rapid succession as the fuse burns.
Scott: You know it's like crack crack crack crack crack crack crack crack crack crack crack in a line.
Rym: Yep, like sometimes.
Rym: I'd tear those apart to get a bunch of individual fire.
Scott: Yeah, you usually take get a big roll of it, and you tear it up.
Scott: You know it's like sets of like 20. you light it you throw it And then it cracks 20 times in a row.
Scott: you know that sort of thing.
Scott: some guys took a roll of 16,000 of these things and they rolled it up real tight and they let the end of it dangle about a foot down off the.
Scott: you know the rest of the roll and they lit it and Ran away, and it starts to go as you expect.
Scott: you know crack crack crack crack crack crack crack crack crack crack crack crack crack crack.
Scott: And as it gets closer to the actual roll not only does it go around the spiral But it actually starts.
Scott: you know each firecracker sets off all the adjacent ones and there is 16,000 of them and it gets crazy And I must say it is perhaps one of the greatest firecracker displays of our time It's.
Rym: I didn't really expect it.
Rym: I thought it was just gonna Peter around and be a normal dumb video and It's it's amazing.
Rym: It's inferno.
Scott: Yeah, that's basically the only words I can use to describe it.
Rym: But anyway as we promised today is the ask Rym and Scott episode.
Scott: Hooray, this is gonna be fun a lot of fun.
Scott: We should do that.
Scott: wish you could do it more often, but people run out of interesting questions.
Rym: Yep, even though I gotta make fun of a few people's questions because they weren't the best questions Well, we'll do it.
Rym: as the questions come yep And I think we're just gonna take them in a semi random order.
Rym: and this will be an interesting thing because usually for anyone Who's noticed we don't really like when we get listener feedback?
Rym: We tend to just say what like what the gist of what they said was and then talk about it.
Rym: but every other radio show and Podcast out there actually reads the text of the emails they get or they get more voicemails and feedbacks Which I'm thinking about getting a pay for voicemail service.
Scott: That doesn't suck like the one we had.
Rym: that failed that's broken But the phone number is still in our closing music.
Rym: So we hope you're not calling it.
Scott: Yeah But yeah, we're.
Scott: I'm thinking about paying for a real voicemail service Maybe with a cool phone number like something something something geek or something like that.
Rym: Of course, you can always just email us feedback at GeekNights at front row.
Scott: crew calm Yeah, but some people don't know how to make an mp3.
Rym: I am I am you know who you are.
Rym: Yeah So we're just gonna handle these in kind of random order.
Scott: and Well, no particular order not random ordering.
Scott: if we don't answer your question or we didn't get to it or whatever We're sorry, just say so in the forums or via email and we will send you either an email response or a forum response Or we'll make fun of you or make fun of you.
Rym: Alright, so I guess Scott you can start just pick one the pick one.
Scott: Hey, yeah, I'm gonna start at the top of the list because it's easier.
Scott: All right, your opinion on Joan and Vasquez and his works also your thoughts in the AMV hell series.
Scott: Well, this isn't a question.
Scott: So if this were jeopardy you would have just failed because there are no question marks now For anyone doesn't know who mr.
Rym: Vasquez is this is the creative genius behind invader-zim Johnny the homicidal maniac At all at alia.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: I enjoy invader-zim as much as I enjoy other cartoons Sort of like Rocco's modern life and rest in peace, which is pretty good.
Rym: I was very much a fan of the especially the early episodes of invader-zim.
Scott: Yep I didn't really see more than the early episodes and Johnny the homicidal maniac.
Scott: what little of it Was moderately enjoyable But parts of it were also not enjoyable.
Scott: It really depended.
Rym: Yeah, I enjoy it partly because I've never met any.
Rym: with rare exception.
Rym: I've never met anyone who was a fan of Johnny and who wasn't and somehow cool.
Rym: Yep I mean like you walked on you just just you yell squee at an anime con and almost anyone who yells squee back is A cool guy.
Scott: Yep or a girl.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, so you don't know Vasquez not the most amazing most perfect favorite awesome guy in the world But he's not bad.
Scott: He's a good dude.
Scott: That's good stuff.
Scott: AMV hell series.
Scott: I had heard of the AMV hell series and never actually watched it.
Scott: I watched AMV held your number one on YouTube and it wasn't so exciting.
Scott: It was like a bunch of really short.
Scott: It's like someone came up with a bunch of AMV ideas, but couldn't actually be bothered to make real AMVs.
Scott: so they kind of made like these 10-second AMVs that just embodied the idea they came up with strung them all together and While they were comedic they weren't comedic enough to actually get me to go even ha once.
Scott: so Lame I call this fan crap.
Rym: I I guess things like this are a lot more fun to us.
Rym: before we became jaded old men We've been to a million anime.
Scott: Yeah, you had showed me this five years ago I would have pissed my pants.
Scott: But because I've seen so much anime and so many music videos and been to so many cons This looks like fan crap to me.
Rym: So yeah, my advice to you is if you're not jaded or you don't know what this is At least go check it out once at a con because it is good.
Rym: It is well executed is well done.
Rym: It is just not our bag anymore.
Scott: Nope doesn't doesn't Get us stirred up, but it gets the normal anime fan stirred up.
Rym: All right.
Rym: now there's a question I'm gonna mention but skip now.
Rym: hasbro asked us in the forums about how we feel about the fact that anime cons have kind of become generic geek cons and just the whole all this stuff about anime culture and Everything and all I'd really like to say is that we answered this question in excruciating detail on Anime world order and very shortly they're going to be playing an episode where they respond to that and they'll play it.
Scott: Yeah, who knows if it'll be next week or the week after but if you just listen to their show We they said some things about it two shows ago and on their most recent show and then we just responded with a flurry As we already said flurry of voice MP3s and emails and I'm sure it will come up on there, you know coming up shows
Rym: we will definitely keep you appraised Okay.
Rym: Now since I skipped one, I'm gonna actually pick a real question.
Rym: Okay, I'm going right down the line.
Rym: We had a question from classic bra in the forums something you wanted to ask us How important is your relationship to each other to the overall show?
Rym: Do you think that the show was more about you guys or the things you talk about?
Scott: I Think the show isn't about us.
Scott: Well, sometimes it's about us with the geek fables type things and Sometimes it is about the things we talk about because well, you know, because we're doing lame stuff but what the show I think is really about is our Perspective on the things we talk about.
Scott: it's us plus the things equals the show.
Rym: I mean, I guess honestly, I really think we could have done geek.
Rym: No We could have done a podcast about Just about any topic in the world and it would have been generally the same quality unless it was a topic We didn't know anything about.
Scott: it would be the same flavor.
Rym: Yeah, you get the same.
Rym: You know us yelling at each other in the same jokes and most people who listen they get the informative stuff and they like our Opinions, but most people seem to listen because they think we're funny.
Scott: Yeah, we we don't intentionally try to make jokes And actually I was in the laundromat and Letterman was on last night and it was really painful to watch that.
Scott: I mean, there's a laugh track and an applause track and it's so Scripted and written and he's trying to be funny and it's not funny at all At least not to me.
Rym: and meanwhile the two of us when we would hang out.
Rym: I mean the reason we do GeekNights The reason we wanted to do this was that back at RIT Like we had our group of friends the front row crew and we were cool.
Rym: But as we started meeting new people and they'd come over and visit Scott and I'd be yelling at each other or like me Scott Alex and Pete and Katsu would be yelling at each other just doing What we do normally and these people who didn't know us or who had just met us would just sit there laughing hysterically And just basically providing a laugh track to us.
Scott: Yeah, it really only worked if they were geeky people though non geeky people didn't get it.
Scott: They would just be like what the hell you talking about, but geeky people would just laugh.
Scott: Yeah, apparently our natural way of talking and way of living is hilarious to other geeks therefore GeekNights.
Rym: Yep, and in terms of how important is our relationship to each other?
Rym: It's we can talk about this from a bunch of the questions, but we're very good friends.
Rym: I mean the front row crew as a whole all of us myself Scott Alex Katsu Pete, I don't want to list everyone but you're all out there.
Rym: We really all consider each other blood family.
Rym: Yeah, we are very close.
Scott: Well, not blood family the the non blood.
Rym: Well, we considered each other family But I say that many of us consider it as thick and as important as blood.
Scott: the world is a filial.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Yes And as I mean if we weren't friends, we couldn't do this.
Rym: But at the same time Scott and I argue a lot.
Rym: You have never heard us argue fully on the show because we don't want to subject you to that.
Rym: Yes, the patent thing was it kept going for almost an hour after I cut it off.
Rym: Yeah, you have no idea and it got to degenerate it to.
Rym: you're stupid.
Rym: No, you're stupid.
Rym: You're a horrible person.
Rym: I've lost all respect for you.
Scott: Everything comes down to that.
Rym: You can go to hell.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, I should just move out.
Rym: Yeah, fuck the podcast.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think we never said let's move out.
Rym: But we've said like I should just move away the socks or I hate you and We don't care.
Rym: like.
Rym: we've all had arguments like that.
Scott: But it's like on South Park.
Scott: the kids always make fun of each other, but they're.
Scott: you know Cartman still hangs out with them.
Rym: Yep, but no matter how angry we are at it well the angry isn't the word no matter how heated the argument we have is we can hit record in the middle of that and It disappears and we just do a show and you wouldn't even know that we were arguing a second earlier.
Rym: Yep, like literally we've had shows was like Scott you're a pig fucker and I hate you.
Rym: click it's time for things of the day.
Scott: All right Okay.
Rym: All right, you want to pick one?
Scott: Let's just.
Scott: I'm gonna do the next three because two of them are kind of quick.
Rym: All right, you knew kremlians.
Scott: Yeah, okay kremlian your thoughts on freezing time and the moral nature of it.
Scott: Yes, you know the inside joke We had where I once to use freezing time as an example in an argument where I was trying to demonstrate no harm No foul.
Scott: Yes, that's enough of that.
Scott: All I can say to that is no harm.
Scott: No foul the end Thane of Cod.
Scott: or here's a question.
Scott: Where's the freakin burning wheel episode?
Scott: I know you're not a pair of shit talkers.
Scott: Thank you for you know Continuing our definition of the word shit talkers.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: In fact, we're very glad that you don't think we're shit talkers.
Scott: Yes, and when our vocabulary is spread among the masses that pleases us greatly.
Scott: So when is it going to happen?
Scott: Well, it's gonna happen two times number one when we get Luke Crane on the horn and two when we actually play a lot More burning wheel because we honestly we like it a lot and we have the books.
Scott: We haven't played it a lot as much not as nearly as much as we want to.
Scott: so we need more burning wheel Experience and we need to talk with the man himself and you will get more burning wheel episode and you want to do it.
Rym: Yes, once we get Luke Crane on the show, which he kind of said he was interested in the last time we talked to him I think that'll be one hell of an episode.
Scott: That would be one hell of an episode.
Scott: and the third question what two subject subjects should I pick for next year film in history?
Scott: the Holocaust American Century the Hollywood industry Australian politics the politics of third world states?
Scott: well My picks.
Scott: if I was having to choose between those any two I would do the Hollywood industry because I would be able to argue with people in the class every day about the evil MPAA.
Scott: and Maybe I would also pick.
Scott: I might pick the Holocaust in case of the Holocaust denier.
Scott: That would make the class a lot of fun.
Rym: Yeah, I wouldn't make the Holocaust just because I know so much about it.
Scott: Yeah, I do.
Scott: I also do know a lot about the Holocaust and American Century also looks good because pretty much everything interesting happened between 1900 and 2000.
Rym: Yeah, they definitely don't mean between 1700 and 1800.
Scott: Yeah, so that will leave a great deal of great class discussions to have.
Rym: so in the very least Let's say this you probably don't want to take the politics of third world states.
Rym: the politics of third world states are Horrible and tedious and you just you'll lose a lot of the respect you have for fellow man.
Scott: Yep, and while film in history you know that could be good because actually the one film class I ever took is one of the greatest classes ever took at RIT and I would take that class again if I could film in history.
Scott: I don't know how exciting that one sounds.
Scott: I took fine art film art.
Scott: So whatever.
Rym: Yeah, it's really hard to say do what you like.
Rym: personally I'd look for something completely different from all of these.
Rym: I assume you have to pick something from this list.
Scott: Yeah, so there you go.
Scott: Okay, your turn.
Rym: All right I'm gonna skip a bit because I want to get the good questions now or at least one really good question.
Rym: I think it's great.
Rym: Colin asked us again in the forums.
Rym: You've been graduated from college and been in the real world for a while now.
Rym: What have you had to learn during this time that you wish someone would have told you when you were younger.
Rym: I think your younger listeners would greatly benefit from this topic and we actually talked about this a bit on geek speak Just a little while ago Part one.
Rym: the main thing is that I have to say that These aren't things that I wish someone had told me because I already figured these things out.
Rym: I went through college knowing that my grades didn't matter.
Rym: I went through high school knowing that nothing I did mattered.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't go through middle school knowing that the things didn't matter.
Rym: Yeah, me either.
Scott: if I see if I went back to tell myself something by late high school I had it figured out.
Scott: so it would have to be me telling my early high school self or my middle or elementary school self something and Mostly it would be grades don't matter.
Scott: Here's how to get ladies.
Rym: don't bother going to the prom just go to a party somewhere else.
Scott: anime conventions exist.
Scott: I could have been going to them a lot earlier.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Here's how to get anime.
Scott: You know all that sort of stuff that I just you know.
Scott: Get me into geekery sooner.
Scott: get myself to play settlers of Catan sooner to play German board games sooner to see anime sooner.
Scott: That's the kind of stuff that I would do.
Rym: but thus we'll just make this more of a. what advice would we give to younger?
Rym: People out there now and very quickly one your grades in middle school and high school to a great degree mean Absolutely, nothing.
Scott: unless you want to go to Harvard or MIT or so or Cal CMU you do not need great grades.
Rym: you were much better off taking AP classes, which will save you money in college or Once you graduate high school going off and just trying to make it somewhere and don't even bother with college.
Scott: Yeah, I am becoming more and more a fan, you know Penn Jillette.
Scott: I think you know.
Scott: at first I thought he was crazy when he said no college and I'm beginning to think that maybe I used to think everyone needed to go to college or you'd be a loser.
Scott: But now I'm beginning to think maybe you don't a lot more.
Scott: if you look at the list of successful people and they you know The history of the world or important people a lot of them just didn't go to college or even high school.
Scott: So you really got to think about what you want to do with your life?
Scott: And if college is something that's right for you and something you want to spend four or more years of your life doing.
Rym: Yep, I mean there you can get a lot out of college.
Rym: We're not saying that you shouldn't go.
Rym: I mean going to college has made our lives Wonderful mainly because the college we went to and the people we met have pretty much sealed our fate for the rest of our lives.
Rym: I mean we have the front row crew.
Rym: We're big in the anime culture.
Rym: we have all these things going for us because of the people we met and the things we did in college and College is an experience that Really can't be paralleled in terms of just the lifestyle and the living and the fun.
Scott: But at the same time Bill Gates dropped out of college and I don't think I don't know if Steve Jobs or Wozniak even went to.
Scott: I have to go check on.
Rym: I guess don't go to college because you think you have to.
Rym: don't go to college Because you want to get an education alone.
Rym: if you just want an education you can teach yourself.
Rym: You can find someone to teach you.
Rym: you can go to a community college.
Scott: You can get a job and learn on the job.
Rym: You go to college to meet people.
Rym: you go to college for the networking.
Rym: you go to college to be social in the real world.
Scott: You go to college because you want to do something that requires college like be a doctor or a dentist or something like that.
Rym: If you don't know what you want to do unless you have money just coming out of your ass don't go to college.
Rym: Yep, until you know what you want to do if you decide you want to be a lawyer Go to college.
Scott: you need to go to college to be a lawyer.
Rym: all right unless you're just crazy and you pass the bar.
Scott: Yeah, you could just self-study and pass the bar all right.
Scott: What are your favorite board games at each player number?
Scott: your favorite light medium and heavy games?
Scott: all right player numbers?
Scott: What do you say to player to player it?
Rym: There's really no good to player game.
Scott: well I haven't found a game.
Scott: That's excellent to player.
Scott: like.
Scott: there are some good two-player games and some bad ones.
Scott: I haven't found a game.
Scott: That's like an amazing two-player game.
Scott: I love to play.
Scott: I guess the only ones I can really pick would be lost.
Scott: cities is kind of good and San Juan played two players, okay, I enjoy a Stratego.
Rym: I enjoy Attica two-player.
Rym: I like Stratego two-player.
Rym: I really liked st.
Scott: Petersburg to player until we solved it.
Rym: We solved the game and also we discovered the game is broken.
Rym: yep three players, Puerto Rico hands down, Puerto Rico Is one probably in my eyes the most perfect board game ever constructed yep?
Rym: I can't think of any game that has even come close to the Citizen Kane of board games.
Rym: yes Not my favorite game anymore But especially the three-player version of Puerto Rico is just this perfect perfect game.
Scott: most people seem to like the four and five But I think it's because we played the three players so much that we're we really like that more.
Scott: Yeah, four player Tigris and Euphrates hands down.
Rym: Tigris and Euphrates is just an amazing game.
Scott: Yep, four player five player.
Rym: I would say I'm on Ray, but that's just because I haven't played Calus enough.
Scott: I think yeah, but see the thing is I would say Calus more for the six player.
Rym: Yeah It's hard to see.
Rym: it's hard to say at that point because games that have more than four tend to have many more than four.
Scott: Yeah, I'm on Ray is good five player, but there are also you know there are games that we haven't played that you know.
Scott: might Trump over these things.
Rym: you know it's hard to say what our favorite game is just because we like so many games And we like them all for different reasons.
Scott: yep light medium and heavy games.
Scott: What's light that we like?
Scott: Carcassonne is kind of light.
Rym: yeah, I would say it's light only because I've solved it.
Scott: Yeah, maybe that maybe Carcassonne is medium light could be Stratego.
Rym: It's I mean it's hard.
Rym: basically the way I categorize games are trivial normal and difficult As opposed to light.
Rym: medium heavy yeah difficult is like Tigers and Euphrates.
Rym: so Carcassonne isn't trivial.
Scott: It's medium.
Rym: Yeah, we don't really play trivial games.
Scott: No we played Timbuktu once yeah, but that's not it's not.
Scott: Yeah, that's debatable whether it's trivial.
Scott: I would say it's not trivial to everyone.
Rym: It's trivial.
Rym: it's something like Candyland is trivial to everyone yeah, but I would consider to a German board game or a game like Timbuktu is trivial if you're reasonably intelligent.
Rym: Deductive yeah, yeah, yeah Okay, and you understand game theory.
Scott: Yeah, heavy games.
Scott: I guess if you consider Tigris and Euphrates and Kayla's heavy then there you have it.
Scott: We like the German games.
Rym: Yes Alright, I'm gonna jump around today.
Scott: You guys planning any to chibi?
Scott: usa says you guys planning any trips to Florida.
Rym: Are you gonna do two now?
Scott: Yeah alright, so Yeah My grandma lives in Florida and haven't visited in a while, so I might visit her soon Maybe in the winter.
Rym: who knows all right you did too, so I'm gonna do two all right.
Rym: I'll start off with a Rayleth in the forums asked us quote.
Rym: What are you guys going to do when the zombies attack?
Rym: and it's funny.
Scott: You should ask that because we have you know how some people in their buildings or houses have a plan of fire escape.
Scott: We have a plan of zombie attack for every situation that we are ever in.
Rym: whenever we're bored at a convention or at Wildwood, New Jersey wherever we happen to be we just debate what we would do and it did like.
Rym: well If they're fast zombies that only infect with a bite we do this But if they're slow zombies that lunge we do this.
Scott: and if the zombies are they aimless zombies Or they come after you eat the brain zombies.
Rym: Yeah, are they 28 days later zombies or dawn of the dead zombies?
Scott: Yeah, it depends on a lot of things.
Scott: zombies eat my neighbor zombies.
Scott: yep, and For every situation we've got a plan that usually involves motor vehicles.
Scott: Different forms of transportation.
Rym: trains are very good for zombie attacks guns explosives chainsaws knives Chopping malls, it's not Dan everyone says the baseball bat a good bokto will serve just as well.
Rym: indeed In fact better because you can poke it through the eye.
Rym: yep, but anyway We're not gonna give you all the plans.
Rym: But suffice to say if when the zombies come we're ready.
Rym: if you come out to the geek house We can probably protect you, but we probably won't be able to feed you unless you can fend for yourself.
Rym: We'll just eat you.
Scott: oh Yeah, come to the geek house in the zombie attack.
Rym: Yeah Send more paramedics.
Scott: Great I'm a vegetarian zombie.
Scott: It's an old joke great.
Rym: I'm gonna do another one here Fantasos in the forums as this question and I bring this up only because this is an issue that we know quite a bit about And I'm surprised someone even noticed that we talked about this.
Rym: This question has occurred to me every morning when I'm getting ready, but I keep forgetting to ask it.
Rym: While ago, I don't know one of you made a passing remark about how deodorant was good, but antiperspirant was bad.
Rym: It was completely tangential, and it wasn't coming on further.
Rym: What's wrong with antiperspirant?
Rym: Is the only people I've ever heard talk about this?
Rym: or crazy hippies or some sort of Randy ness?
Rym: All right point the first.
Scott: I like how he said Randy ness.
Scott: yes We're spreading the vocabulary of GeekNights even farther, and that was a great paraphrasing Rym.
Rym: Yeah, I'm proud of that.
Rym: I think I do a good job at that.
Rym: You know what I'm Maggie with paraphrasing skills.
Scott: Oh god someone else's vocabulary spreads to you, and then comes back to uh Okay, okay.
Rym: now point the first.
Rym: your body wants to sweat.
Rym: There is probably a reason it is trying to sweat.
Scott: sweating is good.
Scott: It's like your natural coolant system.
Scott: You know what happens if you take the coolant system out of a computer or your car it catches fire.
Scott: You want to sweat.
Scott: that is your number one coolant system.
Scott: you need to use it if you prevent sweating.
Scott: It's like taking the heat sink off your CPU.
Scott: very bad very very bad.
Scott: now number two And this is more a cosmetic thing the vast majority of antiperspirants in the United States pretty much all the ones that work all the Ones that don't use this method are the bullshit hippie sea salt Crystal crap.
Scott: that is just hippie crap.
Scott: that doesn't work now.
Rym: They contain one of three chemical compounds Aluminum chloride or aluminium.
Rym: for those aluminium aluminium aluminium Chlorhydrate or aluminium zirconia notice the common ingredient in and all those now Aluminum is a wonderful metal.
Rym: There is evidence both ways there.
Rym: there have been some tiny links between aluminum exposure in quantity and Alzheimer's disease But I'll say right now those are not in any way statistically verifiable.
Scott: The reason that antiperspirant is bad and the reason that aluminum is an ingredient is the way antiperspirant works.
Scott: There are aluminum shards in the antiperspirant that clog your pores.
Scott: now if you don't mind Aluminum shards clogging your pores be my guest and use antiperspirant personally.
Scott: I don't like to You know destroy all the pores in my armpits with shards of aluminum.
Rym: Yeah, I mean quite literally.
Rym: this aluminum reacts with your sweat and things in your sweat to form a jealous kind of plug in the Sweat gland that swells up and it it actually can damage the sweat glands indeed And that's what it's trying to do because it doesn't want you to perspire.
Rym: Using antiperspirants too much can cause you in the end to sweat more or to get to the point where if you don't wear any Perspirant you'll sweat up more than you humanly should and it's bad or you can destroy everything so you won't sweat.
Scott: that's dangerous.
Rym: Now two About three I guess all these aluminum compounds will stain clothing.
Rym: So if you have ever ruined a shirt because you got these yellow stains in the pits that is because of your antiperspirant.
Rym: No human excretion unless you have a disease will cause that.
Rym: well pee Well human excretion from the sweat gland there you go unless you have a disease or unless you didn't shower.
Rym: if you've ever gotten sweat Stains that is caused by any perspirants.
Rym: yep And if you have a problem with odor down there one trim the hair a little bit.
Rym: Having less hair in the armpits means less surface area which means less order to shower down there.
Scott: three Deodorant that isn't any perspirant.
Rym: Yes, however Hippies with their crystals.
Rym: No that doesn't work.
Scott: No go to the store and There there aren't many of them, but there are brands of deodorant that are not antiperspirant.
Rym: They're actually kind of sparse now in the u.s..
Scott: Because bars yeah the ones with baking soda are good.
Scott: So we're the one I even know baking soda doesn't really get rid of I know, but they're still good.
Scott: Well, they feel they do the function.
Scott: Yeah, they feel the rising even though baking soda doesn't deodorize.
Rym: I've actually had a problem where I if I find a deodorant.
Rym: I like I will use it forever Yeah, and and then they'll cancel it four times in my life.
Rym: I found a deodorant.
Rym: I like.
Rym: I use it.
Rym: It smells nice It works.
Scott: I'm on my third.
Scott: I'm on my fourth variety.
Scott: if you count the one antiperspirant I used at the beginning they keep getting canceled.
Rym: Yeah, I used to use antiperspirant when I was young and you know what I sweated more.
Rym: So I put more antiperspirant on and then I sweated more.
Scott: yep I started using ban which was just a roll on whatever.
Scott: then I switched to Mitchum and then when I learned about the aluminum shards I switched to a Standard deodorant speed stick that was green and now I'm using this bluish green degree, which is actually pretty good.
Scott: I like it all right.
Rym: I want to do one more question because this one will be real short.
Rym: Amethyst home away asked us in the forums what separates you from other podcasts?
Rym: We're good we do a lot.
Rym: We do a lot more Podcasting than other podcasts not to sound I guess conceited, but I think we run a much more professional shop.
Scott: Other podcasts seem to really be into the whole Podcasting thing and we're just kind of doing our own thing not caring about.
Scott: you know the you know the quote official Podcast community and all that stuff that's going on in there.
Scott: I just stopped paying attention to all that crap.
Rym: Yep, I mean half of what we say is what we would have said to each other anyway if the mics weren't here.
Scott: yep I can't.
Rym: really it's a hard question to answer any more than that yeah, especially since I really I'm real I like self promoting like when I'm talking myself up to be on a panel or I'm interviewing for a job.
Rym: I really feel icky self promoting for any other purpose.
Rym: Yep, okay.
Scott: Let's see what question we got here.
Scott: Oh The where's the one about a billion dollars?
Rym: It's right under that one is it?
Rym: yeah, bald matrix Let me fight.
Scott: I think I lost it all right.
Scott: I'll read Oh, what would you guys do if you had a billion dollars?
Rym: Scott can answer this first?
Scott: I know exactly what I would do if I had a billion dollars.
Scott: I would buy exactly one thing that costs a billion dollars.
Scott: that one thing is the cable vision corporation in New York City.
Scott: If you buy the cable vision corporation here is what you get.
Scott: are you ready for this list of things you get?
Scott: Number one you get optimum online optimum voice optimum TV.
Scott: That's gonna.
Scott: Make you a lot of money and Think of the bandwidth baby.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: number two you get Madison Square Garden the most famous sporting arena in the world.
Scott: Number three you get the New York Knicks.
Scott: number four you get the New York Rangers.
Scott: It's two sports teams baby and the best hockey my favorite hockey team not the best They don't.
Scott: they did okay this season not that great.
Scott: They got to the playoffs and then they went poop.
Scott: But that's not the point.
Scott: the point is the cable vision corporation is Worth about a billion dollars.
Scott: the last time I checked I remember there was some newspaper thing about it years ago.
Scott: It could be worth more than a billion dollars now but I don't care.
Scott: it's not the point.
Scott: if I own cable vision not only would the Profits coming in from such an ownership be able to buy anything else I would need but Just about anything that I could think to buy I could get and I would also own an arena where I could have awesome conventions in New York City property.
Scott: they own a lot of property in New York City that I could live in and sports teams and TV and Internet and I would make the.
Scott: I would be able to use Cable vision in the ISP of optimum line to push my ISP agenda and do things like Fight for net neutrality and all that other good stuff and geeks I could hook them up with.
Scott: my awesome optimum line is penis and I could do a great service for geekery as well as living a life of luxury and then You know retire with a life of philanthropy.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I think Scott's answer is real good So I won't bother answering because it's somewhat similar in what I would do.
Rym: I can say that everyone I'm good friends with would be very well off for the rest of their lives.
Scott: Well, duh, if I was the owner cable vision, they would be all well off.
Scott: It would be great.
Scott: No one would need to work anymore.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Now here's a question that was emailed to us by Joe from New York.
Rym: Why did the two of you live together?
Rym: rent issues close pals?
Rym: I've been wondering about this for a while now, but I never got around to actually emailing you.
Rym: Well, there's a funny story about that.
Rym: Now when we were at RIT where the front row crew which was myself and Scott Alex our friend Pete our friend katsu and then a bunch of other people that were around but all of us were the ones who?
Rym: Were trying to kind of go into housing together Because at RIT they have this housing lottery and we wanted to get.
Rym: it was myself Greg Alex and Scott who decided the four of us are going to get an apartment together and We got in the lottery and we were standing in line and there was a one Two-bedroom four person apartment left in all of RIT and We were up next and as we're walking in the lady walked out and she crossed it off because the people before us had taken It
Scott: and we figured that we were gonna have to suck it up and go to live in River Hole which River Knoll
Rym: It's a hellhole.
Scott: It sucks, but we were like fine.
Scott: It was better than the dorm So we were gonna take it.
Rym: So the four of us are walking over and then someone from across the room yells No one wants these two one-bedroom apartments in colony.
Scott: No, I think it was.
Scott: we said we'll take the River Knoll and they're like, wow, no one wants these in colony.
Scott: We're like we do.
Rym: Yep, and what they were is actually it turned out they're all of all the apartments in RIT.
Rym: There are only six of these and they are the best possible apartment you can get because in terms of square footage per person and price because they're one or two occupancy and There are pretty much as large as the three and four person apartments.
Scott: They're just missing one bedroom.
Scott: They only have one bedroom instead of two.
Rym: so the four of us are standing there and we're like, let's do this.
Rym: We can just live right next to each other and it'll be awesome.
Rym: It'll have more space.
Rym: and then everyone looks everyone.
Rym: and then Greg at the time asked the important question Who's going to live with Scott?
Rym: Everyone stood there for a minute and no one said anything.
Rym: and finally I said Alright, I think I can deal with him because I'm real I'm real thick-headed thins thick-skulled when it comes to that sort of thing and History was decided in a minute.
Scott: It's like a few seconds.
Scott: Yeah If it had turned any other way, who knows what things would be like now?
Rym: now Despite the fact that Scott and I live together all through college Effectively all of our friends lived with us because they were just in our apartment all the time.
Rym: Most of the time our apartment was like the center of our of everyone's social lives.
Rym: It was indeed which was funny because it was very small Small for that.
Rym: many people like we'd have 15 like like 10 people over.
Rym: that was too much and it was just a bunch.
Rym: Everyone would sit and not move because he couldn't do anything and we'd all just kind of yell and talk and it was a good Time.
Rym: we have a lot of stories from that apartment we do.
Rym: so.
Rym: I moved away Oh for a while for six months to work for IBM in Poughkeepsie and I got a condo there and Scott just lived in the apartment by himself.
Rym: I kept paying rent.
Rym: So technically I still had the apartment.
Rym: I left all my stuff there.
Rym: Then we all moved away for the summer.
Rym: We all moved back.
Rym: I went back to RIT at the end of that year of RIT.
Rym: I moved back to the mid Hudson Valley to work for IBM again.
Scott: Is he graduated?
Rym: Well, no, I didn't.
Scott: Oh, that's right.
Scott: I
Rym: just left RIT and I stepped down from all my positions like the anime club and I moved away to work for IBM and I eventually I lived in a whole bunch of places in the mid Hudson Valley and then Scott graduated and I eventually did graduate remotely and he went to live with his parents for a while and got a job and I was working at IBM and Eventually, I found I decided, you know, we need to get out place somewhere and I hey Scott, let's move in together.
Rym: You know rent in half Not living with your parents me not living in a crappy studio apartment in Fishkill.
Scott: Yeah, I couldn't live with my parents anymore.
Scott: My job was in New York City.
Scott: he found a place that was you know, I could take the trains in New York City to go to my job and Also, he could drive to his work.
Scott: And so we said okay half rent not living with parents not living in a tiny ass shithole Apartment box piece of crap.
Scott: We're good.
Rym: Also the fact that the whole front row crew is.
Rym: we realized we were all going to graduate had decided We all need to move in together somewhere.
Rym: We all need to take over a city and Scott and I were the first ones to.
Rym: well Pete actually had a geek house in Albany, but it failed.
Rym: Yeah, it did completely broke apart but we were the first ones to Go out and set up a geek house.
Rym: and now bit by bit all of our awesome friends in the front row crew are moving Out actually near us and we're all kind of coming back together.
Scott: Yep, it helps being one train ride away from the city where people can get plenty of jobs.
Rym: Yeah, also as you can tell from the show we do get along.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Okay, very to popular speculation.
Rym: We are not homosexual lovers.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Scott: Let's I'm gonna read a bunch of really quick ones ready.
Scott: All right your opinions on emos and their emo ness.
Rym: All right, the word emo is stupid.
Scott: from chemical base.
Rym: Emo is a term that appeared somewhat recently, but it's not a new concept.
Rym: teenagers have been this way since the dawn of time.
Rym: Nothing has changed there.
Rym: Why is there a new word for something that has always been around?
Scott: It's just some trendy bullshit.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: I just ignore and don't care about the whole emo thing.
Scott: I don't really like their music.
Scott: I don't like them.
Scott: They don't bother me.
Scott: I don't bother them.
Rym: It's all good I just don't.
Rym: I mean when I was in middle school people like that They were called the angst definite article angst Mm-hmm, and there's been all these terms over the years.
Rym: and someday emo will fall away and people call them something else.
Rym: It's it's nothing special.
Rym: it's not anything to even bother having an opinion about in my opinion.
Scott: Yep All right, Emma this Tomoe I asked where do babies come from women's vaginas?
Scott: Kremlin asks, how about Rym actually tell us his hidden screen names.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Okay, stop asking inside joke questions.
Rym: Yes The.
Rym: the deal there very briefly is that I went by a lot of screen names over the years and a long time ago I kind of I kind of dated a girl and she made a website that was about me and It's gone now, so you couldn't find it even if you look for it and there's really no like.
Rym: honestly You'd think there'd be a funny story there, but it's really not.
Rym: and if I told you more details, it would be less amusing.
Scott: Kremlin asks, how about what Scott's rat last relationship experience with a mysterious woman?
Scott: Stop asking inside joke questions again.
Rym: Granted that's a funny story.
Scott: It's the thing about that story is the truth is pretty tame and unfunny except for when I got you.
Scott: Yes, but yeah, but the The story around it that isn't true is much more interesting.
Scott: Yeah, and that'll wait for geek fable.
Rym: Yes, suffice to say Scott mayor may not have dated and/or slept with an international terrorist.
Scott: I didn't but the story is that I did so that's a much better story than a reality.
Rym: Though going back to Kremlin's question I'll tell you this my first handle the first name I ever used on the great white internet in God, I had like prodigy was Origins.
Rym: Mm-hmm, because I was sitting there and I was thinking I need a handle I'm about to go onto the internet for the first time ever.
Rym: I was really excited I was really young and I looked around the room and we had this huge book on evolution this Giant book on like evolution and evolutionary theory and it was called origins.
Rym: something something something something something.
Rym: So I made that my handle and I used that for many years.
Scott: My first one was taser which I stole from an old DOS game where you couldn't type a name.
Scott: You had to pick one of the pre-made names and I always picked taser.
Scott: cuz that let you be the green guy.
Scott: So my AOL name was taser three one four six.
Scott: Oh and then eventually why three one four six?
Scott: Oh, that was the number it gave me Back in the dial-up days.
Scott: and then I played a mod on AOL called gemstone three and I got the name I use.
Scott: now No one else uses it.
Scott: It's my name.
Rym: Haha a preachy.
Scott: Yeah, however, it has no official pronunciation.
Scott: Our Bach asks, what size boobs do you like?
Scott: only the female variety?
Scott: Thanks.
Rym: I like my boobs.
Scott: Okay, I think the female variety.
Scott: Thanks.
Scott: So Rym admits he's a female.
Scott: Um, I like.
Scott: You know the size.
Scott: the gigantic boobs really are just kind of.
Scott: I don't like him so much, you know.
Scott: But at the same time the ultra flatness is also kind of no good, you know, I mean I do like boobs.
Scott: Yeah, I think my fate the best boobs for me are the ones that are they're spherical.
Scott: now I know they're not naturally spherical that there's a bra that makes them look spherical.
Scott: But when there's like two perfect softballs with a tight shirt, that's good.
Scott: I like that.
Rym: now to me I really I like the aesthetic of like the 1920s flapper body type.
Rym: I like like small kind of close to the chest like very pert breasts.
Rym: I just I really I like that.
Rym: I like I like the whole frapper body type flapper.
Rym: I can't really.
Rym: yeah flapper.
Rym: I was thinking about frapper maps.
Rym: Yeah, but I really I can't say any more without embarrassing either Emily or people I know.
Rym: so I'm just going to leave it at that.
Scott: Ninja Ned asked as a recent high school graduate.
Scott: I was wondering what you think is the best way to prepare for college.
Scott: You already talked about deciding if you if college is even right for you.
Scott: But if you have decided college is right for you and you want to prepare.
Scott: first You should figure out.
Scott: you should make sure you got your shit down know how to register for classes Know your way around the school meet people at the school join clubs at the school.
Scott: Make sure you don't forget any things, you know, you bring your mini fridge and all your college stuff.
Scott: Make sure you call your roommate a few times before you go to college if they assigned you a dorm roommate.
Rym: more importantly Because all the material stuff you'll figure out I Am fairly certain that once you get to college and meet real people and normal people you're you're going to lose touch with almost everyone you knew in high school and You should.
Rym: yes There are rare exceptions where you will still be good friends with someone from your high school Once you get to college.
Rym: Don't try to cling to high school.
Rym: the people who try to cling to their hometown tend to have a lot of trouble with college.
Rym: Yep, all right I'm gonna go with one now.
Rym: now baltimatrix has a question or a bunch of questions in a row and we'll just hit them all.
Rym: These are kind of random one.
Rym: which superpower would you take?
Rym: the ability to fly or the ability to turn invisible?
Rym: and then he has a note with all the You know provides those About whether yeah, like you can't fly into space your clothes turn invisible with you that sort of thing.
Rym: Yep I Would take the ability to fly.
Rym: I've been fascinated with flight my whole life.
Rym: I'd love nothing more than to have some sort of genetic thing where they can inject me and I'd have giant feathered wings.
Rym: But that's just me.
Scott: I would if only I had flying and invisibility.
Scott: I would all I would take invisibility but if I had my choice, I would take teleportation.
Scott: Well, it's because the flying for me.
Scott: I could get the flying experience by skydiving.
Scott: The flying really is about the transportation and flying isn't really any better than walking or running or driving.
Rym: Yes airplanes one, you know quickly I could get to my work.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: But at the same time teleportation is really what I would want.
Scott: but invisibility versus the slightly faster transportation of flying.
Scott: Invisibility has all kinds of great uses sneaking into places sneaking out of places Stealing shit.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: All right bender Yeah See, I guess if if it was the choice between these two while I could do more with invisibility I choose flying just cuz I've been fascinated with it my whole life.
Rym: I I would law.
Rym: I just couldn't imagine the feeling of just like jumping off of an embankment and flying away.
Scott: We'll just go skydiving then.
Rym: Yeah, actually I plan to sometime in the future.
Rym: Yeah, I've been bungee jumping.
Rym: It's amazing, but just flight I think is neat.
Rym: now if I had the choice of any super ability I would want the ability to cast spells and be some sort of mage.
Scott: That's so cheating.
Scott: why cuz?
Scott: then you could teleport and fly and turn invisible.
Rym: I've been the ability to transform my body because then I could turn into a snake to hide but I can also grow myself wings and fly Right.
Rym: I can pick superpowers.
Rym: All right, and this question I think is interesting If - if you never went into computers, what course of study would you have taken?
Rym: I personally almost I really considered going into music instead of into computing and It was really the money and the fact that RIT had a good internet connection that swayed me.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I might have done something like electrical engineering or mechanical engineering or microelectronic engineering now if I.
Rym: but
Scott: I also might have done something more artsy like Writing or something or something like that
Rym: if I knew then what I know now, I might have tried to go into radio If I knew then what I knew now and I could somehow have still had the RIT experience But yet gotten my education elsewhere.
Rym: I would have taken that scholarship to Oxford and I would have gotten a law degree.
Scott: It does really matter and this relates to his last question if I knew early enough, I would be a race car driver.
Scott: Yeah Because you would have told me when I was in like elementary school that there were go-karts I could drive and that's how to become a race car driver.
Scott: I would be Probably racing f1 right now or be close to it.
Rym: Yep I mean to me the college I went to mattered more than the degree I got.
Rym: So I went into computing because that was the degree that RIT offered.
Rym: that was good.
Scott: Yeah, I pretty much was gonna do computer science no matter where I went but everywhere offered computer science even the state school.
Scott: So it was just you know, a matter of picking the college and RIT was the one.
Rym: Yep I didn't even decide on IT until I got to RIT.
Scott: Yeah I wasn't sure if I was gonna do IT or CS a hundred percent.
Scott: as soon as I realized there were alternatives to CS I was deciding between IT and computer engineering.
Rym: Yep, which I'm glad I didn't go into.
Rym: Yeah though.
Rym: actually I'm considering now getting a law degree and I've been looking at a lot of online or night classes and in that in The years to come I may become a lawyer in some fashion.
Scott: Yeah, while I wouldn't want to be a lawyer, I would want to be a judge.
Rym: I want to be a lawyer as a Leaping stone into politics and into all sorts of industries that I currently don't have access.
Scott: Yeah, being a judge or a detective would have been cool.
Rym: Three this question is kind of mad, but if money was no object, what car would you purchase?
Scott: well that all depends.
Scott: see it depends if you're asking for a day-to-day car or a race car a tank kind of car.
Rym: if From a pure game theory perspective.
Rym: I should pick an Enzo Ferrari or an f1 car sell it get the money buy the car I actually want and then have a pile of money.
Scott: Well money is no object.
Rym: So yeah, but maybe money is no object only for buying a car.
Rym: Maybe I could turn that yeah money and all.
Scott: if I wanted to get the best car I would get a 2004 f1 Ferrari the one that Michael Schumacher drove to win the championship because that is probably the fastest best f1 Car there is?
Rym: yeah But I say we're Fernando Alonso's current car.
Rym: if we could just if we were just buying a car and money didn't really matter like we Could finance any car we wanted to make it a more reasonable question.
Scott: the car for everyday use?
Rym: Yeah, just like if I could just walk out and buy a car right now the way I just went and bought that Mac I'd either buy like a z3 or a Miata.
Scott: I would either get a Nissan Skyline GTR or I would get a Ferrari the current one the 355 the one that's out now spider because it's yeah too cool.
Scott: I was GTR man because you don't see GTRs on the road.
Scott: They're not street-legal in the US, but god damn.
Rym: yep I just like really little zoomy cars.
Scott: For how much wood can a woodchuck check?
Scott: it can chuck less than Chuck Norris can check.
Rym: yep My alternate answer is that's a stupid question.
Rym: You're a stupid person for asking it.
Scott: five rally or f1 and why?
Scott: well It's not really a matter of or it's a matter of which one right now.
Rym: I like them both for their own merits.
Rym: I like f1 more now because it's more accessible to me, and it's easier to watch and I enjoy watching it a lot.
Scott: Yep, rally is more about drivers skill and crazy downhill racing But the technical stuff.
Scott: and rally isn't that interesting.
Scott: f1 I'm really interested in the technical side of it.
Scott: So it really grabs my interest and also the driver Personalities and and all that sort of thing.
Scott: if rally was more accessible.
Scott: I would watch that too But it really isn't and I don't really have time to watch another racing sport, so Yeah, all right now.
Rym: They had asked and I think this is a very good question Quoting I submit to you that real life is just like a very complex German board game.
Rym: Clearly both Rym and Scott are outstanding gamers.
Rym: Therefore those gaming skills should transfer to real life enabling them to acquire much power and wealth in the real life game.
Rym: So the question and it's the one that plagues Mensa members ever it doesn't plague Mensa members everywhere That's the members.
Rym: I have my opinions on Mensa, but that's a whole lot.
Scott: That's another who have like that.
Rym: why aren't Rym and Scott rich and powerful in real life, okay?
Scott: Let's start by saying Okay, you might be able to say that life is German board game But there's a problem and a German board game.
Scott: everyone starts on equal footing and has the same opportunities with minimal randomness.
Rym: a better way to phrase the question would be life can be viewed from the Perspective of game theory?
Scott: yes, but the thing is is that life as a game?
Scott: Isn't as?
Scott: even as a German board game everyone starts out on different footings.
Scott: some people might start out as the president's son some people Start out homeless in the ghetto.
Scott: so there you go.
Scott: We started out in the suburban America, which is sort of middle-of-the-road.
Scott: Secondly there's a lot of randomness in life.
Scott: shit just happens.
Scott: I mean I could just go down to a casino bet my entire everything I own on black on the casino and possibly double my wealth on a roulette wheel.
Scott: This you know, but that's an example of sort of a game of chance in your life, but there's other chance in real life.
Scott: I mean some.
Scott: I might find a bar of gold in the backyard.
Rym: You might just trip on the streets of New York City fall on a spike and die.
Scott: you might step on an electrified manhole and die.
Scott: It's like imagine if you're playing a board game And there's a deck of cards and everyone draws the cards and some cards say you win some cards say you lose.
Scott: They say all kinds of things.
Scott: it doesn't really matter how good you are at games If there's that much randomness as there is in the real world.
Rym: now three Game theory has been plagued by this problem for as long as it's existed.
Rym: and the problem is that game theory in general the the equations assume that Everyone involved is acting to one to a common goal to a similar utility.
Rym: But in the real world people have very different utility.
Rym: utility is what you want out of the game.
Rym: Some people want to be happy.
Rym: Some people want money.
Rym: Some people want power.
Rym: Some people want sex.
Rym: Some people want to just take drugs and die.
Rym: There's.
Rym: there's so many different things people want that everyone's playing a different game to right along these lines.
Rym: It assumes that people act rationally in order to achieve their goals and that they learn from their mistakes.
Rym: and the problem with this is that Not to disparage humankind but sociology is showed empirically that as a herd humans act against their own best interests and will often act contrary to their own goals for No reason at all.
Scott: people who a lot of you will just don't know what they want and people who do know what they want Often don't know how to get it or Fail to or do know how to get it and fail to do what they know they got to do out of laziness or who?
Scott: Knows what?
Scott: so it's really hard especially because there's some German board games.
Scott: You can affect other players and there's someone you can't.
Scott: in life Anyone can pretty much affect anyone in almost any way depending on how well they're currently doing at the game.
Rym: It's a game of Tigers and Euphrates where everyone has a million catastrophes.
Scott: Yeah, so it's really hard to win in a game because there are a lot of things I know I could do to get ahead right now.
Scott: But I also know that if I did those things people would throw catastrophes at me and I'd be worse off than when I started.
Rym: Now also, here's our second half of the answer Which is the more this is part you actually wanted to hear because we went on about game theory and all that.
Rym: This is a life is a game Where you I mean let's consider a game like Carcassonne or Timbuktu.
Rym: if you play you could play the game optimally.
Rym: Yeah, meaning no matter what's going on.
Rym: You were playing the best game you can play with the pieces you've got.
Rym: despite that you might still lose because if other people have better pieces or Everyone's playing optimally and the game just comes down to chance.
Rym: You could finish a game that you lost and know that is the best I could have done in any circumstances Mm-hmm.
Rym: And secondly, we actually honestly are More rich and more powerful than the vast majority of humans have ever been.
Rym: that is that is not a conceded statement.
Rym: The vast majority of humanity throughout all of history and today has lived in utter squalor and filth compared to what we do.
Rym: We have a podcast that people listen to.
Rym: we have a six-figure income.
Rym: We live in a wonderful free country.
Rym: for the most part We.
Rym: we have luxuries that are unheard of to most people humans who have ever existed.
Scott: think about this.
Scott: I can send a message and To publish it to everyone in the world.
Scott: Most people who are alive today can't do that.
Scott: Do you understand how much power we have right now?
Scott: It's insane.
Scott: We have more power in our little dinky house without a basement because an old lady living down there than most humans have ever had.
Rym: I mean the fact that I can right now talk to my girlfriend Emily who's in Nagoya Japan just on a whim and yet there are people in Africa who can't get a message to the neighboring village and
Scott: On the same token I could go down, you know, evilly I'm not gonna say I would do this because I'd probably go to jail but you know It is possible that we have the ability to make bombs and blow lots of things up.
Scott: We're not going to nor would we but there we have a lot of power to do many things.
Scott: There are a lot of cards in our hands that we're not playing.
Rym: for various reasons Like for example Palestine just as an example, they have no actual military power.
Rym: They have no normal conventional way to exert force upon on people.
Rym: They have very little technology.
Rym: They would normally be irrelevant.
Rym: However Individual determined people can very very greatly affect the world if they so choose.
Rym: I'm not agreeing with what a suicide bomber does but being a suicide bomber is a very powerful thing.
Scott: people can have a large effect on the giant game board that is the world.
Scott: and You know, we just think about what we can do and we do the best we can Considering our laziness and desires
Rym: and I really think in terms of how what life has handed us and what we've done we are about we're doing as well and being as powerful and as influential and as rich as We can be without violating our own morals and ethical codes
Scott: or without taking unnecessarily crazy risks.
Scott: I mean there are crazy risks we could take to like suddenly shoot to the top, but it's just not worth the risk.
Scott: Yeah, and there are things I could do to be much more powerful that I just don't feel ethically okay with doing Yep, or there are things that we could do to become much more powerful But then other things would happen as a side effect that I don't want.
Scott: so I have to go about it a different way.
Rym: So to answer your question I think we are actually doing very well and we are applying game theory to our lives both consciously and unconsciously to great effect.
Scott: alright What is on?
Scott: Lindsay says what aren't you guys good at?
Scott: there must be something?
Rym: Alright, neither one of us can draw for a shit.
Rym: I can draw stick figures I can't even do that.
Scott: I tried to learn to draw once with this little how to draw manga book and I kind of stopped pretty quickly because I was Terrible.
Rym: Yeah, neither one of us can sing at all can't sing.
Rym: I mean I can almost Kind of sing one Bob Seger song because he only uses like three notes and even that is pretty piss poor.
Scott: I can't really rollers.
Scott: skate Rym can but I really I am kind of terrible at roller skate.
Scott: I just roll the blade.
Rym: I'm a. I haven't rollerbladed recently just because there's no real good sidewalks around here, but I was a super avid rollerblader.
Rym: I can't roller skate at all But I can rollerblade like you wouldn't believe and I can't really do any sort of skating or bleeding.
Rym: Yeah, though if you want to learn yeah, I could.
Scott: I've never skied so I don't know how I'm good at it But I probably won't ski.
Rym: you should skings really fun.
Scott: No, it's super dangerous.
Rym: I'll teach you it's really not hard It's not that dangerous.
Scott: I think I'm gonna stay away from the super dangerous.
Rym: It's not dangerous.
Scott: Yeah, it is.
Rym: It's only dangerous if you do the crazy skiing that I never really did to any great extent.
Scott: Yeah, it's not worth it.
Scott: What else aren't we good at?
Rym: Well, you played the guitar a little bit, but you're not very music.
Scott: No I played guitar in fifth grade and then I played the clarinet in sixth seventh eighth and ninth grade and I haven't played music since.
Scott: Like I can read music You know if I if you gave me like a music book and an instrument and within like a day I could be back to.
Scott: You know average, but I'm not super musical But I'd say I'm better than most people when it comes to music.
Rym: This will sound weird and please let me finish before you yell at me.
Rym: I'm not good at lying now.
Rym: what I mean by that?
Rym: What I mean by that is that I am very good at telling stories.
Rym: I'm very good at exaggerating.
Rym: I'm very good at taking an otherwise mundane event and turning it into an amazing story However, which Scott says is lying.
Rym: However, what I cannot do at all and it bothers me because I'd want to and I think I have good ideas sometimes But I just can't pull it off is I can't come up with a story from nothing.
Rym: Like if there's any grain of.
Rym: if I ever tell a story no matter how outlandish it may seem There is a grain of truth in there somewhere because I need that grain of truth.
Rym: if there's no truth to it at all I just can't do it.
Rym: I can't tell the story.
Rym: I can't make up the lie.
Rym: I just can't do it.
Scott: Yeah, I have a lot of trouble if I try to write fiction Maybe it's cuz.
Scott: no I haven't figured out how it's done But I can't really just come up with a good story out of nothing I end up either stealing a bunch of parts of existing stories I know or writing nonfiction or who knows but I really can't write fiction very well
Rym: There are a lot of
Scott: other things.
Scott: I'm not good at like.
Scott: I'm not good at dentistry.
Scott: I'm not good at surgery.
Rym: Although I probably could be but I would just boggle as much as I like to play around with electronics.
Rym: I'm not that good at soldering and while I can passively solder something I often burn myself and I often make really poor joy.
Scott: I don't burn myself and I can solder in a way that works, but I also make pretty poor Solders, you know big blobs instead of nice little dots.
Scott: Yeah I think if someone showed me the right method and I practiced for an hour, I'd be down.
Scott: though There are plenty other things that we're not good at.
Rym: Yeah, we just we're not gonna list everything in the world that we're not good at.
Scott: I'm generally good at crafts and not good at arts.
Scott: It's like painting.
Scott: No good putting together something or making a little tiny race car.
Scott: Very good.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Let's see what other questions.
Rym: we're running low.
Rym: We've done most of them.
Rym: All right, here's an interesting one by thorn and I. we can't go into great detail on this because most of you don't care To paraphrase.
Rym: this probably isn't a good question for the show, but it seemed a good place to ask You mentioned a few times you've been to penguin con.
Rym: when were you there?
Rym: Did you board game there?
Rym: I might have met you depending on which one you went to To make an actual question.
Rym: What do you think of penguin con?
Rym: What do you think of these unified cons?
Rym: You know where there's more than one thing at it.
Rym: Would you go again?
Scott: We went to penguin con 2.0.
Scott: I believe the one where Neil Gaiman and Steve Jackson and who else was there?
Rym: Rob MALDA.
Scott: Rob MALDA was there.
Scott: It was a cool Mozilla guy was there.
Rym: It was an amazing amazing con.
Rym: at least we had a lot of fun But I had a lot of fun at that and honestly we probably would have gone back every year because Novi Michigan is only about four hours from rock.
Scott: Yeah, it doesn't see.
Scott: I've looked at the websites for future penguin cons, but they didn't seem to have the guests line up But I still probably would have gone back in future years.
Rym: The only reason we don't go is that instead of being four hours away Novi is now nine hours away.
Scott: That con was closer.
Scott: We would have kept going to it, but it's not.
Rym: in fact if jetblue flew to Detroit We might have been inclined to go but it's not.
Rym: it's actually very expensive to fly to Detroit from where we are Because not many people do so now.
Scott: in the future We might go to a penguin con.
Scott: if you know, they turn out to be that much.
Rym: Awesome If penguin con will pay our way will be guests.
Scott: Oh as we should send a letter to penguin con asking, you know Actually could we could kill a bunch of birds in one stone?
Rym: I could go visit my family and then we could do a show and yep.
Scott: But yeah we will tell the story of what happened to that penguin con in a geek fables episode in the future because There are many tales from that penguin con because it was really that awesome.
Rym: All right.
Rym: We've only got two or three more questions left here.
Rym: Cool There's a couple more on the forums, but they came kind of late and they weren't too interesting So I just kind of skipped him.
Scott: All right, it's all you.
Rym: All right, there's two more questions here.
Rym: Well, this question is good because I think we can talk about it a lot.
Rym: And then I saved the best question for last because I think it's really cool that this guy listens to us.
Rym: Mm-hmm one Balta matrix asked what do you guys do to prepare or to do a panel at cons?
Rym: I asked because I'm thinking of doing a panel at a con in 2007.
Rym: I will say right now that I Personally don't prepare at all for any public speaking.
Rym: I ever do see me.
Scott: When I was learning public speaking in my last year of high school I learned the lesson that if I prepare it's wicked awesome And if I don't prepare it's not wicked awesome.
Scott: But my preparations Over time have required less and less and less and after doing this podcast it really I can just write the Sparsest of notes like in two seconds and I'm good to go and even then I don't even need that most of the time.
Rym: Yep, I mean, I guess I didn't go through that with the podcast just because I've done a lot of extemporaneous speaking in my life.
Rym: I mean I gave speeches in high school.
Scott: Well, see I always I had the speaking skill and it came out when I prepared.
Scott: like remember when we were freshmen I ran for anime club.
Rym: Yeah, you almost won.
Scott: Yeah, see cuz they I had.
Scott: I was using my public speaking skills for my last year of high school And then I hadn't.
Scott: they gave her.
Scott: it's like a muscle.
Scott: I didn't flex.
Rym: Yeah, I mean my only point is that I started earlier than you.
Rym: That's the only reason that I cuz I went through the same thing I used to prepare and as I did it so much.
Rym: She's got to the point where give me literally you could come up to us like we could have a panel the anything panel.
Rym: we could sit there and Random people could walk up and say you must do this panel on X and I think we could pull off a damn good panel.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much no matter what X was unless it was something so complicated that we had no knowledge of whatsoever like a very specific physics topic like Super string theory something something something then we wouldn't know what to talk about but we could look it up on Wikipedia real quick.
Rym: I mean like.
Rym: I took a lot of public speaking and communications classes at university as well And I even entered in some public speaking contests and I really didn't prepare it all Like at all.
Rym: the most I would ever carry with me is if say I had to cite something I had to talk about something very specific.
Rym: I might have one index card with just the name like the actual citation because I'm not gonna remember that.
Scott: Yeah, like who said the quote or what book it's from on what page?
Rym: but we literally will sit down at a panel.
Rym: Well me because I got hasn't actually done a panel yet.
Rym: This is his first one.
Scott: But well, that's my second panel at a car at an anime kind of oh, yeah an anime con.
Rym: But I've done I've done God 15 or 20.
Rym: I just sit down and go.
Rym: I really don't even sketch anything out at all.
Rym: Uh, I don't recommend you do that unless you were very comfortable in your extemporaneous speaking skills.
Rym: I don't really have any good advice as to how to prepare because I we don't.
Scott: Yeah Alright, I'll read the last question.
Rym: Alright, cuz I think I like this question.
Scott: This is from Robert and he said I'm gonna read the whole thing.
Scott: Alright, I love your show.
Scott: I have been listening for about five months.
Scott: That was an excellent use of semicolon by the way.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: It is a lost art.
Scott: I try to listen every day, but I'm not an anime fan.
Scott: I like comics but not anime.
Scott: So some Wednesdays, I only listen to the beginning.
Scott: That's cool.
Scott: I'm in the military and I recently was shipped overseas.
Scott: There was a time where I was not able to log on to iTunes for over three weeks in the travel here before I got My first chance to download your new episodes and 12 episodes downloaded at once and it took a very long time.
Scott: But I had to spend the next few days doing things where I'm able to keep my iPad with me.
Scott: So I listen to all those episodes in the span of three days.
Scott: Oh, you started out with such a great semicolon and then you had what can only be called a run-on sentence.
Rym: Yeah, I think I'll forgive that because the semicolon was so well placed.
Scott: My question is something I've been wondering What is your view of the military?
Scott: and my other question is what is y'all's favorite TV show shows?
Rym: Alright now one I would just like to say.
Rym: this is a topic we could do a whole episode on our views of the military.
Rym: In the US military is in general Use of force in the world when it's justified when it isn't a recruitment.
Rym: everything about the military.
Scott: yet to summarize as long as there are groups of people in the world who have Military forces of some sort.
Scott: it is required for other groups even good groups to have their own defensive military forces of some sort if they wish to be secure in their persons.
Rym: and as Libertarian as I am I very much believe that there are times when force is necessary and/or justified.
Scott: Yes, I'm not going to talk about you know many specific times when force is and is not justified but I will say this as long as your military is voluntary and as long as it is not political and As long as it is used in a justifiable way It is a good military.
Rym: now to be more specific because I think you were thinking more along the lines of our views of the US military or the People in it and I will say that I have nothing but the utmost respect for anyone who has joined the military.
Rym: I see it as a great way for people who don't have other opportunities to better themselves to better themselves.
Rym: I see it as a career for people who for a great number of reasons are involved in it.
Rym: I actually know a lot of people are in the Navy and Really we have nothing but respect for you guys.
Rym: Mm-hmm I very much disagree with how the government of this country is using you guys But that is not your fault.
Scott: Yep, and what it all comes down to is Because we've had problems with this issue before.
Scott: if there was a draft tomorrow for the Iraq War We would run away.
Rym: In fact, we were almost attacked by someone because we stated this fact.
Scott: if there was a draft tomorrow for World War two We wouldn't need to be drafted because he would sign up.
Rym: Yep, that really kind of sums up how we feel about the military.
Rym: I very much believe that there are things worth fighting for.
Rym: Yep, and I would fight for those things.
Rym: It pains me that our military which is one of the few militaries in the history of the world That has remained mostly non-political I mean so many countries have a military and then as soon as something happened
Scott: as a military dictator
Rym: Yep or the military intervenes in politics and the fact that the military and the people in the military Will follow orders and do what they're told to do Even if they disagree with it is in my eyes just an amazing thing
Scott: Yep, even though sometimes I say to myself dang if those military people just you know, didn't do the things They knew were wrong.
Scott: I mean there is a line that a military can cross, you know You violate some Geneva Conventions or anything like that, you know There is a line at which a military shouldn't just do whatever it's told but on the whole as a one single unit military.
Scott: not you know only doing what the Rest of the government tells it to do as opposed to telling the government what it wants to do.
Rym: Yes, it's a good thing because I mean theoretically we're a democracy in America Which means that the military only acts if the people feel the need for it to act.
Rym: So theoretically the military only acts when such action is justified and thus they should always follow orders because you know That is that is what a democracy is.
Rym: I have my views about the politics surrounding that in current America.
Rym: But all of that aside I have two examples of what I feel are problem.
Rym: I mean these these are two men are my heroes and I don't even remember their names.
Scott: on the Canadian guy I'm gonna find the Canadian guy right now.
Rym: All right, you find that I'll talk about the other guy.
Rym: I forget his name too, but maybe we'll look that up.
Rym: I believe it was in Vietnam.
Rym: there was a group of American soldiers who were about to just massacre a bunch of civilians and There was a man in a gunboat or a gun helicopter and he saw what was about to happen and he ordered his men to train their guns from the helicopter on these American soldiers and Ordered them despite the fact that what he was doing was it was justified under a whole bunch of military Statutes and things but it was also disobeying orders from a superior.
Rym: He ordered these men to stand down or be fired upon and He saved these people's lives and then he was then ostracized from the military.
Rym: and there's this whole story.
Rym: I think we'll do an episode on it someday.
Rym: That man is a hero as far as I'm concerned.
Rym: and There's also the case of Rwanda where the UN general who was there Scott's looking up his name Defied the orders of the UN.
Rym: the UN told him to leave to take his troops and leave Rwanda and leave these people to die and He refused the order and he was threatened and as a result him and his men Sabotage their own equipment so that they would be forced to stay in Rwanda and protect everyone they could.
Scott: the guy's name is Lieutenant General Romeo Alain.
Scott: Diado.
Scott: I think it's French.
Scott: I can't pronounce that properly.
Scott: He's actually a Canadian senator now, and he is a living hero.
Rym: Yes, and I just I don't know.
Rym: I mean we really got on a bunch of tangents with that.
Rym: Yes, we very much respect the military and what it does we're.
Rym: I'm very glad that it exists.
Rym: I'm very glad that it fights for us.
Rym: I wish it would be used in a more responsible way by the people who have the power to do so.
Scott: Yes, I my ideal military would act only defensively like it would be walking around the streets in the United States.
Scott: It would be on the coast of the United States And if anyone tried to get in and screw with us Then they would go and into action and they wouldn't be in other countries screwing around Unless there was evil there to root out such as Rwanda Darfur etc.
Scott: Etc.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: I'm very I very much am a proponent of peacekeeping missions.
Rym: I just wish they would actually be engaged properly as in send enough troops and Actually do what needs to be done to prevent people from fighting so that you can help people.
Rym: Yep, I mean so many times UN peacekeepers are sent somewhere and they're given such terrible Orders like you were not.
Rym: are such terrible parameters of conflict?
Rym: or what's the terms of engagement like yes protect these people But you're not allowed to fire your guns or just it's laughable.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And one last thing I read the Wikipedia about this guy that the hero general from Canada Diarrhea, I think Dallaire I don't know is widely known for having served as a force commander of Una Mir the ill-fated United Nations Peacekeeping force for Rwanda between 93 and 94 and we're trying to stop a war of genocide that was being waged by Hutu extremists against Tutsis and Hutu moderates.
Scott: Guy single-handedly with a very small force tried to stop a genocide.
Scott: That's what a military is for
Rym: Yep, and the fact that being in a military like that puts you in a position P puts people normal normal humans I mean people in the military Aren't any different from us except that a lot of them are younger in fact
Scott: and trained in the military ways.
Rym: Yeah, but I mean we could have joined the military.
Rym: We could have been forced to join the military by economic or whatever situations Yeah, but I mean they're people just like us.
Rym: and yet you're in a position to do such good Mm-hmm and also such bad Yep, and I just have faith that the military of this country will in the end be used only for good.
Scott: Hopefully.
Rym: Yeah, hopefully I also have the feeling that if our military was ever used in a such an egregious way I mean the Iraq War is terrible.
Rym: But if things got bad enough I would not only hope for but expect that members of the military would do the same things that Mr.
Rym: Rwanda or the person from Vietnam did.
Rym: Yep, because I really just like say all hell broke loose and the US government tried to deploy the military against US citizens Like say there was chaos in the country anarchy or an armed revolution.
Rym: I Couldn't imagine or fathom American soldiers firing on American citizens.
Rym: nope, and I just don't think that could ever happen because I have that much faith in our military.
Scott: and If they did start firing on us, I don't know whose side I'd be on.
Scott: it would depend on the revolution.
Scott: Yeah, so yeah.
Scott: Yeah, we asked What is y'all's favorite TV show shows?
Rym: All right, that's a real easy Futurama Family Guy Simpsons Firefly.
Rym: yes, I don't like Firefly but like we're not gonna talk about anime just TV TV shows.
Scott: Yep, I think the thing is that people have to know is that we don't watch television.
Rym: However, there are TV shows we like South Park.
Rym: Yeah, we'll watch them on DVD because I just can't stand the advertising.
Scott: We have a television in our house.
Scott: There are video game systems and now a Mac Mini plugged into that television.
Scott: However, we do not get any channels via broadcast or cable.
Scott: we do not pay for that and we don't get any channels at all.
Scott: We don't watch live television.
Scott: All the television we watch is either downloaded off the internet or DVDs Etc.
Scott: Oh, we watch f1 races.
Scott: Yeah, we would watch hockey games.
Scott: Yeah, and there's that show on ESPN.
Scott: pardon the interruption that I would watch But now I just get an audio version of it on podcast for free.
Scott: So I don't.
Rym: yeah I would watch The Daily Show if I could just for free.
Scott: I'll watch The Daily Show.
Scott: Maybe the Colbert Report.
Rym: You can't be a bear.
Scott: What else would we watch?
Scott: That's that's pretty much it.
Rym: Well, like Battlestar Galactica, I'd probably watching.
Scott: Yeah, most of what I miss from television is live sports.
Scott: That's pretty much it.
Scott: Yeah, and there aren't that many live sports.
Scott: I would watch.
Scott: I would much just hockey and racing.
Rym: I would like to be watching new South Park's because I actually have a lot of respect for Trey Parker.
Rym: and what's the other guy's name?
Rym: That's stone and I like the show.
Rym: The show has really changed.
Rym: for anyone who didn't who watched the first few seasons and said oh This is just kids swearing and gave it up.
Rym: I think it's a very intelligent show.
Scott: Yep Okay, any more questions?
Rym: Actually, there's one more.
Rym: I didn't print it because it came late But it was amethyst home away again who asked why we hate advertising so much.
Rym: Now well proud to be proud to be brief because the episodes been long.
Rym: very briefly one Advertising itself is okay because people advertise things that you get the word out.
Rym: The problem I have is that Advertising has become a business model in and of itself whereby people will give out content for free attach ads to it and somehow think that this is a viable economic model and I really don't think that it in any way can continue within the next decade.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I have a lot of reasons for that that I wouldn't really like to get into in detail here because it would take a while.
Scott: Yeah really just the main problem I have with advertising is that it's so.
Scott: Most of it at least is not well intentioned, you know, I mean, there's nothing wrong with saying You know, even though I feel bad even doing what I would consider legitimate advertising, you know saying I have a podcast.
Scott: Please listen to it.
Scott: but You know when you go out there and you make you know You word things in a way in which you know that the average person will think you said this but technically you only said That and you're not actually lying.
Scott: So you can't be caught with false advertising.
Scott: But really you're lying to get people to spend money on something and instead of letting your product speak for itself It's all about marketing and brand rather than physical goods and services and just the intrusiveness of ads.
Rym: I mean advertisers do horrible things on the internet and I'll say right now I never ever ever see ads on the internet.
Rym: I block them all.
Rym: yeah I've talked to people we've known who believe that what I am doing is theft and I say to them Even if I saw the ad I would at best ignore it and at worst would note the product and vowed never to buy it.
Scott: So in fact, you're getting helped by me blocking your ads.
Rym: case in point the x10 camera.
Rym: It's actually a really cool thing.
Rym: It was there's.
Scott: it was a cool thing.
Rym: It was a good.
Rym: now logic tech makes webcams But when it came out it was this really cool piece of technology.
Rym: But their advertising was so ubiquitous and so annoying that I even though I wanted one chose not to buy one Specifically because I dislike their advertising practices on the streets of New York.
Scott: There are those people.
Scott: you'll see them every single day.
Scott: they hand out little pieces of paper with menus or come eat at this place or come see this show or Anything like that.
Scott: if someone's handing out a piece of paper, not only do I not take it But I look and note what the piece of paper is for and I never go there.
Scott: wherever they're advertising I don't go because I disprove disapprove of their advertising method.
Rym: Alright, I think that about wraps it up.
Scott: Alright, there's actually a couple questions that just spots on the forums I want to answer.
Rym: Alright, let's be quick about it.
Scott: Eson Lindsey says when are you going to do shows?
Scott: and all the things you said you'll do a show on when we remember What we said, yeah, so if you guys remember what we said, please remind us and we'll do a show on it.
Scott: Well, maybe we should make a remind us thread.
Scott: and one last question, which I think actually be interesting.
Scott: amethyst.
Scott: Oh my ass Which part of your body do you value the most now?
Rym: I know what Scott's gonna say.
Rym: No No, I know you're going to say it but then you'll say haha just kidding.
Rym: But seriously, no now now not.
Rym: Oh, okay.
Rym: You were gonna say the penis.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, that's the obvious funny answer.
Scott: So the penis.
Rym: Alright anyway It's Hard to say.
Rym: I mean, I don't want to say my brain because I don't know if my brain matters or not.
Rym: Um, I I'd want to say my legs because they get me around once in my eyes like spirit.
Rym: I I can't.
Rym: there's no part of my body that I dislike except my appendix.
Scott: I Don't like says which part of your which one part do you value the most?
Scott: not which one do you dislike?
Rym: Yeah, but I can't.
Rym: I value them all equally.
Rym: I mean if I lost my sense of smell I would be devastated.
Rym: if I lost my sense of sight Equally devastated.
Scott: see that's the thing is I don't think that if I lost smell and sight they would be equally devastating devastating both.
Scott: But there are two parts of my body that I think are tied for first place where if I lost those it would be worse Than losing any other single part of my body and those are my eyes and my hands.
Rym: I honestly Even though it would be a greater inconvenience to my life and it would ruin much of what I want to do with my life.
Rym: I would I think I would rather lose my sight than my hearing because I love music so much that I Probably couldn't continue living without music yet.
Scott: I could continue living without hearing is like one like Tiny tiny fraction of a millimeter below seeing and hands on the scale.
Scott: But I mean, you know, of course brain because without the brain I couldn't do anything at all.
Scott: But that's you know, that's not the point of the question.
Rym: Actually, I would I don't want to say my penis but in general
Scott: the the penis ranks
Rym: highly it does but the the the ability the erogenous zones of my body in general that I I'm generally a very odd, I guess I feel weird using words like this, especially on a show like this, but a Sensuous kind of sexual person.
Rym: I'm very Yeah, I think there's no delicate way to put it.
Rym: I am a Randy dude.
Scott: Yeah, I think discounting the brain I think the ranking is hands and eyes Then ears, you know mouth tongue the whole head area and then you know the arms and the legs.
Scott: I guess if you count hands don't need to put the arms with them.
Rym: I know cuz they could just graph the hand on the Shoulder.
Rym: I guess it's bones knees and bone knees into.
Scott: yeah Because I mean that's really as a human being the opposing thumbs and the fingers that are.
Scott: you know?
Scott: What's the word?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I'm done.
Rym: Yeah, I don't have anything more to say without hands.
Scott: I really can't do anything I can't make things I can't interact with things in an efficient manner.
Scott: you get a hook hand Yeah, but while a hook is cool I do not discount the quality of a hook.
Scott: like if I lost one hand and got a hook I might be okay with that But losing both hands, uh-uh.
Scott: No good two hooks doesn't cut it.
Scott: And you know if I lost one eye maybe but two eyes not a chance.
Scott: So there you go hands and eyes.
Rym: All right, we've now answered all the questions except for Kremlin's inside joke questions.
Scott: well he can take those inside joke questions and cram them up.
Rym: his inside joke though I will say he did remind me of a story that I totally forgotten about.
Rym: well his mom yeah The the whole spygirl thing which I will tell that story because there's a lot of funny.
Scott: It looks like we've just primed a bunch of geek fables today.
Rym: Yeah, and Actually, I'm thank you all for submitting your questions.
Rym: We're glad we could answer them.
Scott: if you want any follow-up bits I'll go into the forums obviously and in the future when we have a whole bunch more listeners we'll probably run this again if we think we can get enough new and previously unanswered questions.
Rym: Yeah, and that's really all we've got.
Rym: it's late.
Rym: We've done like four hours worth of podcasting.
Scott: today I'm going to bed and tomorrow.
Scott: I'm going to the beach.
Rym: Yeah I got to pack my bags the beach, and I got all.
Rym: I got a lot of stuff to do And I put you in the beach.
Rym: you kind of do that for two minutes.
Rym: You must sit in the beach.
Scott: I sit in the beach.
Scott: you get this sunburn in the cancer.
Rym: Yeah, bring that sunscreen.
Scott: I'm bringing that sunscreen.
Scott: Oh like you never seen before I'm not going to dole it out to you other people as generously as we did in the past.
Rym: you have to dole it out To me because I subsidize your you not you.
Scott: I'm talking about the other people there.
Rym: Oh, they can go to hell.
Rym: they can die in a tie in a fire dying a malignant.
Scott: I'll provide them sunscreen.
Scott: Maybe once but or maybe a little bit, but you got to bring your own bottle.
Scott: people you know I'm done sunscreens too expensive now that we can't use the My clocks was the chemical.
Rym: Oh, I don't remember the chemical.
Scott: That's better than whatever we have.
Scott: Alright, yeah episode over though though little warning.
Rym: there may or may not be an episode Monday Depending on if I am forced to drive back to beacon to go to work on Monday or not.
Rym: if I drive back I'll do a Monday show.
Rym: if I don't drive back.
Rym: There's no Monday show and we'll have a GeekNights special again.
Rym: And Tuesday, we'll have a special episode Which is it's the 4th of July monkey Tuesday?
Rym: And We'll have to celebrate that.
Rym: I don't want to rip off Penn Jillette or anything But that's an occasion that we really have to celebrate.
Rym: we do indeed And That was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Scott: make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com, and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.