Scott: It's Thursday November 9th.
Scott: I'm Scott and I'm Rym and this is GeekNights tonight.
Scott: we discuss bathing and showering.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: It took me not one not two, but three hours to get to work today.
Rym: Oh, man.
Scott: I got to work Today faster than ever before.
Rym: yeah, well because you don't really go into a heavily populated area.
Scott: now I go from heavily populated area to a less populated area.
Rym: See I would have been okay because the only issue really was that the sawmill River flooded after the torrential downpour the other day Which meant that the primary road I take to work was also flooded.
Rym: of course They closed the road without telling anyone there weren't signs or anything.
Rym: the road was just closed and no one knew what to do.
Scott: What about the workers in the sawmill?
Scott: did they have any trouble with their logs getting cut up for?
Scott: Soggy or anything?
Rym: you know?
Rym: the sawmill River is like four feet wide right now.
Scott: I'm being silly Actually being a sawmill there when there used to be you know 200 years ago.
Rym: Yeah, yeah That that was part of my joke though The thing is I would it would have been okay that only added about an hour to my commute.
Rym: So where did this magical mystical third hour come from idiots?
Rym: Completely unrelated to that on the way to work some jackass Just hit someone else and spun out and blocked the entire taconic Parkway for an hour.
Scott: Oh, I never would have thought that would happen.
Rym: and then later today I was driving around for work going to different places, and I saw three completely independent major accidents.
Rym: Yeah, there seems to have been a sudden increase at least anecdotally from my perspective in major accidents on roads on which I travel.
Scott: Yeah, just this was it.
Rym: this more saw a nun yelling at a guy after she caught him off and got hit.
Scott: Yeah, I think there was an accident on 52 this morning right in front of the Sunoco station, huh?
Scott: It was either this morning or yesterday morning.
Scott: It's morning, so I don't really remember too.
Rym: Well really you really don't know.
Scott: I don't know if it's today or yesterday.
Rym: What did you eat for dinner yesterday?
Rym: I Rest my chicken and potato all right.
Rym: what we have the night before Pasta with sauce on.
Rym: uh-huh you sure that wasn't the day before that and then we just crowned that other night I'm sure.
Rym: are you sure?
Rym: I'm pretty sure Captain Alzheimer of the USS something know.
Scott: if I had Alzheimer I'd be like what am I doing there?
Scott: What's his microphone here for?
Scott: What's this again?
Scott: talking stick?
Rym: yeah, but anyway the interesting part about the whole what's your name, Sonny?
Rym: was that I was coming in and the road was closed directly in front of me, and there was a traffic light and You could.
Rym: basically the only thing you can do here is turn left, so the light is red.
Rym: I cannot legally turn left even though there's no oncoming traffic.
Rym: the lady behind me starts getting super pissed off that I'm not turning left now.
Rym: Normally, I probably would have just run the red light.
Rym: But if you look where I could have turned left onto the other road Traffic had filled that road all the way up to where I was.
Rym: I would have run the red light and driven five feet.
Rym: Not only was this lady honking continuously, but she started whining and yelling at me through her window come on Come on, just go just go come on come on come on come on Have not gone until she stopped?
Rym: yeah, I did better than that.
Rym: I got out of my car turn around and took a picture of her.
Rym: yeah she got super pissed then and she ran around me and cut me off and made that left turn and Sat there blocking the road, and she couldn't get in And then I just pulled up behind her when the light turned green and followed her for the next.
Rym: you know ten miles of this Trip.
Rym: just kind of you know Sinking in the fact that she didn't really get anywhere other than frustrated by trying to make that red light.
Rym: Why are people so to paraphrase Penn Jillette goddamn stupid?
Scott: Because they didn't get an education.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: no she's obviously well-dressed.
Rym: She was on her way to a white-collar job somewhere.
Rym: She probably makes within $20,000 of what I make.
Scott: Probably I don't know.
Rym: she was driving a really nice car.
Rym: well not a nice car.
Rym: She was driving a pseudo nice car.
Rym: She had some Lexus.
Scott: Yeah, car that's you know bit high on the prestige for people who care about that sort of thing.
Scott: But everyone else goes wow look at that guy just trying to look good, but doesn't actually know shit about cars.
Rym: I don't think I've ever known anyone that I was friends with who owned a Lexus on purpose.
Scott: Yeah, I can't think.
Scott: is there anyone who owns a Lexus because they think it's a good car and a good value for the money And they don't buy it because it's some sort of prestige icon sort of thing?
Rym: See it's kind of like we were talking about the Escalade or the h2 Hummer the other day And how.
Rym: basically these sorts of cars are really just the equivalent of the old yellow badges from Nazi Germany only instead of Jewish.
Rym: They mean stupid.
Scott: Yeah, basically.
Scott: Hey someone made a purchasing decision because they're trying to Impress other idiots who care about consumerism and whatever.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It's sort of like.
Scott: you know it's sort of weird.
Scott: I I could really see this contrast in my childhood because I was from New York like originally.
Scott: well you Don't say you're from that yard.
Scott: I lived there for like a whole year, but then I was in Connecticut.
Rym: What you can't remember a single thing from that year can you I?
Scott: Remember a couple things.
Rym: what?
Rym: what do you remember from the ages of zero to one?
Scott: When my mom would bring me to that little park next to the the apartment there
Rym: Are you sure you remember that is you're not just making it up because I remember distinctly being bitten by a dog But my parents swear that it didn't happen when I was really really young.
Scott: I'm not saying it happened I'm just saying that's what I remember.
Scott: I remember a lot of things and my mom says I went to the park.
Scott: so but the point is is I had a bunch of relatives in New York So I was hanging out with New York people in Connecticut people all Jews all had a bunch of money, right?
Scott: But the New York Jews like for their bar and bought mitzvahs they would put on the big show.
Scott: You know they would all be all showy with lots of jewelry and lots of fans.
Scott: You know Yeah, jewelry all the all the Jewish ladies in New York were like loaded with jewelry.
Scott: You know everyone really cared about.
Scott: you know this sort of.
Scott: I have expensive things So I'm better than you all showing off.
Scott: and all the Connecticut people.
Scott: while they had just as much money Usually even more they weren't so showy.
Scott: you know they were much more utilitarian.
Rym: I've pretty much lived my life exactly the same way regardless of how much money.
Rym: I've had.
Scott: yeah pretty much.
Rym: I mean the only difference is on the bottom end of the scale of rims economic well-being.
Rym: It got to the point where if it weren't for the charity of some friends.
Rym: I probably would have starved to death, but I Don't think you would have died.
Rym: No.
Rym: I wouldn't have died, but it would have sucked.
Scott: Yeah, you might have to eat bad gruel from the homeless shelter.
Rym: It sucked anyway.
Rym: I mean there were many days in the pretty much right before I went on co-op and made you know like $20,000 which was a lot when you're in college, and you don't have any expenses other than ramen Ramen.
Rym: and I remember there were days where I'd wake up and I'd eat anything I could find in the house Which usually wasn't much?
Rym: We'd have like one egg so I'd cook it and maybe a moldy English muffin that I toast real good.
Rym: and then he Or actually we had a freezer full of ice cream mochi which lasted about one morning.
Rym: I'd be on campus I'd be hungry, and I couldn't afford to buy any food so I'd be hungry until night.
Rym: then I'd come home and eat some ramen Alright, so what's the news say?
Rym: I only get into the news cuz my news is totally uninteresting.
Scott: whatever we got to do a show alright.
Rym: so the thing I actually want to talk about and my news are kind of related.
Rym: they involve the Pagan holiday that Christianity co-opted and turned into the birth of their Savior Jesus Mm-hmm you know aka Christmas yep the yule festival and all that yep.
Rym: now for a long time bit by bit stores have been not Saying things like Merry Christmas.
Rym: They've been replacing everything with holiday sales and holiday stuff in order to avoid offending people.
Rym: and now Walmart The stalwart defenders of everything wonderful that they are decided that they are going to stand up against this tide of Something by doing the opposite thing and they're gonna start saying Merry Christmas again.
Rym: God damn it.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: I don't like either one.
Scott: I don't like Christmas because I don't like religion, and I don't like political correctness.
Scott: so no matter what decision They make I hate them either way.
Scott: I basically hate everyone.
Rym: I don't celebrate Christmas.
Rym: I haven't pretty much.
Scott: You know what I would support them if they just didn't do anything for the holidays.
Scott: They just ran their store as normal didn't change their store into Christmas consumer Hell you know around the beginning of November just kept doing business.
Rym: Try the middle of October.
Scott: I know I know, but they just ignored the holidays completely.
Scott: Then that is the only way to avoid my ire.
Rym: Well, it's really not easy to avoid your iris.
Rym: God.
Rym: No.
Scott: No it is not.
Scott: my iris is a Giant blanket covering the entire world.
Rym: you can't avoid ten hours.
Rym: Oh, no you can't Hey Scott, but where were you originally born?
Scott: Mount Ireland?
Scott: No, Ireland.
Rym: Okay, anyway, but you see I don't care.
Rym: either way I call it Christmas because I grew up in a family that celebrated Christmas in a 100% secular way.
Rym: I also went to a Catholic school when I was very young where we'd have to go to church occasionally and pretend we believed in.
Rym: But Christmas was really more just the time when the whole family got together And I always viewed it as such.
Rym: and while I've never celebrated it as a religious holiday Until I went to college.
Rym: I always celebrated it as a family holiday.
Rym: Then I went to college and I couldn't exactly travel around so often anymore to my family.
Rym: half my family moved to Arizona And then I moved to downstate, New York and last year my Christmas celebrations consisted of talking about our podcast that we were starting Dealing with the fact that Scott set off the burglar alarm on our house And we couldn't turn it off during which time it called 9-1-1 and the police came.
Scott: now I think the next-door neighbor lady called 9-1-1.
Rym: Yeah, it also called in I'm pretty sure cuz I cut a phone line.
Rym: Yeah, who knows I cut a phone line and a bunch of power cables to it all right.
Scott: Yeah I think we ate at a Chinese buffet.
Rym: Yeah, we ate at a mediocre Chinese buffet.
Rym: That was the extent of my Christmas.
Rym: Yeah, that's pretty typical The previous Christmas where I decided I was gonna fly home to Detroit and see my grandparents and my dad my brother and then Every single flight I was on was canceled for reasons ranging from mechanical failure to workers striking to a blizzard.
Rym: and I end up spending an entire day all of Christmas at Newark Airport drinking free liquor getting drunk and being bored playing my DS.
Rym: Awesome that was an awesome Christmas.
Rym: Then I got sick, and I went home And I played more DS while I was laying in bed sick in my studio apartment all alone in Fishkill.
Rym: That was the best Christmas ever then.
Rym: the dinosaurs can't be worse.
Scott: I spent a Christmas once.
Scott: I was in Rochester.
Scott: I didn't leave Rochester.
Scott: I was living in colony.
Scott: No one was there.
Scott: I think I went to China Gate alone.
Rym: I remember that I felt bad for you cuz I went out to do something on Christmas.
Rym: Then I came back and you were still there.
Rym: yeah Hey, was that the year we went to Niagara Falls for New Year's?
Scott: it might have been whatever.
Scott: it doesn't matter.
Scott: It's not worse than saying in an airport all day or being sick in a in a box all day Yeah, I was in colony.
Scott: I had an OC 3. no one else was clogging up the network.
Scott: I had good food.
Scott: I had money.
Scott: I was warm.
Scott: It was good times.
Rym: the best part was when they canceled my last flight, and I went up to the people I'm like all right fuckers, and I pretty much said it exactly those terms I want my money back.
Rym: They gave me my money back, and then I said I want a ride home.
Rym: And they said we're not giving you a ride home.
Rym: And then I said you drove my ass from Stewart Airport an hour and a half to here.
Rym: I don't have a car here.
Rym: What do you want me to do?
Rym: Pay me a cab.
Rym: and they got pissed.
Rym: But then they gave me an unlimited taxi voucher and I got in a cab at Newark And I said take me to Stewart Airport, and he said what?
Rym: And I handed him this thing and it was like a hundred and forty bucks by the end.
Scott: I didn't care and the guy like the taxi guy actually drove that far.
Rym: Yeah, not only did he drive that far, but I talked to him the whole time about how shitty my Christmas was man.
Scott: His Christmas even shitter.
Scott: He's like man.
Scott: I spent my Christmas in this fucking cab driving really really far away talking to this loser.
Scott: All right my news Stefan Erickson.
Scott: oh yeah, he's gonna join the ranks of Sony and What's his name Jack Thompson.
Scott: in being in the news often?
Rym: Yeah except Jack Thompson?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: They're different levels of absurdity.
Rym: this guy is absurd for awesome reasons.
Scott: Well, not really, but yeah this I think this guy actually give me the last time He's in the news because this this is the king.
Rym: no no no I guarantee He'll be in news one more time, and that'll be when he gets shaved.
Scott: it could be All Right.
Scott: this is like the conclusion to this epic tale, so there's a guy named Stefan Erickson, and he's a bad Corrupt mafia dude from Sweden all right.
Scott: And he decides to pull this big scam and make a video game system called the Gizmondo Which actually had a few interesting ideas and that it was a portable thing with the GPS and there'd be some GPS games.
Scott: But no it was just.
Scott: everyone knew was gonna fail.
Scott: It was ridiculed.
Scott: It was crappy.
Scott: No one had any expectations for it.
Rym: It was kind of like the that other fake console that didn't come.
Scott: It's basically a big scam where he ripped off a bunch of investors Or you know the ps3 right.
Scott: so this is the guy who he basically ran away to the u.s.
Scott: He brought with him a Mercedes like Frickin McLaren or whatever our race car yeah, and an Enzo Ferrari of which there are only 400.
Rym: well now there's 399.
Scott: I think it's actually 398. someone else crashed one.
Scott: Oh good job yeah, and those are like.
Scott: that's like a million dollar ultra-rare amazing car.
Scott: and He got drunk, and he crashed the Enzo.
Scott: and then weird shit happened.
Rym: We like that.
Rym: they started saying that someone else was yeah.
Scott: He was like said someone else named Dietrich was driving, but Dietrich was never found.
Scott: yeah, and like these guys were posing as Homeland security officers and all kinds of weird shit Someone tried to steal some of the wreckage of the car.
Scott: Yeah, he had a gun that was property of some Sheriff's like assistant like a deputy sheriff in his house.
Scott: It was just all fucked up, but now they got him and he pleaded no contest to a bunch of charges.
Rym: now I like the idea of pleading no contest.
Rym: you're basically saying I May or may not have done whatever you're accusing me of but I'm not gonna fight it.
Rym: that doesn't mean I'm saying I did it.
Rym: It just means I'm gonna accept whatever punishment.
Rym: I'm not actually admitting to anything.
Scott: yeah Yeah, that's fine.
Rym: No one cool ever pleads no contest.
Scott: So you play no contest.
Scott: And he's going to jail for I think three years, and he's paying a lot of money and fines and after the three years He's gonna be deported back to Sweden where they'll probably put him in jail again because he's an evil mafia, dude awesome.
Scott: Yeah, he's a drunken bad guy, and he ruined a perfectly awesome car.
Scott: I could have had that car.
Rym: No, you couldn't have.
Scott: yeah I could have.
Rym: I think you would have trouble with that car.
Rym: Well that that car would have spelled bad news all around for you.
Scott: What kind of bad news would have dispelled?
Rym: you would have died within five minutes of turning on that car?
Scott: I would have just brought it over to Watkins Glen.
Scott: I wouldn't have died over there.
Rym: Yeah, you would have Right into the wall.
Scott: there is a. I guess there is a wall.
Scott: I wouldn't go into it.
Rym: if you go in any direction long enough you hit a wall or an ocean Probably a wall dude.
Scott: I should have had it totally modded.
Scott: So it'd be one of those car boats like the Enzo car boat should have totally had it modded.
Rym: you didn't have it.
Rym: That's that's quite a. it's like if I'd had that Enzo I would have totally I should have.
Rym: I did have that Enzo, and I should have done blah to it.
Rym: That's right, okay I said enough news for you.
Scott: I think it's gonna cover the news again.
Rym: things of the day.
Scott: How many things of the day?
Scott: two two two not three?
Rym: No?
Rym: We don't have a third person here.
Scott: Oh, no I Guess that guy over there was just faking it.
Rym: what?
Scott: Right things of the day.
Rym: There's no guy over there, or is there?
Rym: no no there isn't are you sure?
Rym: There's just a one-up mushroom.
Scott: That's what it is the mushroom, okay?
Scott: All right I'm just trying to be randomly crazy, but it didn't work.
Rym: No it didn't work at all.
Rym: you suck That was that was pretty piss-poor.
Rym: I'm sorry.
Rym: I'm really sorry because it could have been funny.
Rym: I don't know maybe if I'd done something different like pretended.
Rym: There was a guy in the room with me.
Scott: No, it's not necessary.
Rym: Well.
Rym: I guess there is a guy in the room cuz you know we've got we've got teller from Penn and Yeah, yeah, actually isn't funny.
Rym: actually I thought the joke would have been funny except that I don't listen to the radio and Apparently according to Penn Gillette every radio show he's ever been on ever Has thought it'd be clever to act like teller was there too even when he wasn't.
Rym: yeah like every guy ever thought They were being clever and none of them were.
Rym: well No, I guess they all were independently.
Rym: they all discovered it independently kind of like how two people discover the light bulb at the same time.
Scott: All right, what's your thing of the day?
Rym: my thing of the day is this flash game called?
Rym: Orbit.
Scott: I played it.
Scott: It's good.
Rym: It's fun.
Rym: I played it for about five minutes And I could have played it longer if I had.
Rym: you know no life and nothing better to do.
Rym: It's one of those games that you just play a little bit.
Rym: It's not as fun as that drag sand around and then put oil in it and set it on fire.
Scott: That's not really a game.
Scott: That's more of a sandbox.
Rym: Sandboxes are games.
Rym: games are sandboxes.
Scott: I guess not really kind of.
Rym: yeah.
Rym: I made races between two trees to see which one would flourish.
Scott: well That's that's.
Scott: you created a game within the sandbox.
Rym: Yeah, the game was making a game.
Scott: I guess it doesn't have to be yeah.
Rym: anyway It's a little fun game.
Rym: where you take a comet you give it a little bit of velocity And there's a bunch of planets on the board and your goal is to make it orbit or generally avoid these planets for as long As possible.
Rym: the planets thereby well during which are exerting gravity upon your little comet.
Scott: a lot of it is trial and error You know try a vector doesn't work.
Scott: try a vector doesn't work.
Scott: try a vector.
Rym: we it worked though I thought I was all smooth because the first time I played it the first three levels one I got the bonus skip a level bonus because I was so awesome.
Rym: kind of by luck mostly by luck but to entirely by luck.
Rym: I Wanted my comment to do really like cool things like go between two planets and a figure eight kind of thing and I Pulled that off a lot a whole bunch of times, and I thought I figured this out.
Rym: then I realized that now It was totally random.
Rym: there was no amount of skill involved in that whatsoever.
Scott: Yeah, you tried to find a lagrange point, and it you totally didn't find one.
Rym: well as we determined the lagrange point was between two Pixels.
Rym: so fuck that game.
Scott: yeah All right.
Scott: my thing today is video from the Wii factory Where they make Or at least where they package the Wiis and where they also package the Wiimotes and the Zeldas.
Scott: It's pretty impressive.
Scott: if you look at the rate at which they make Wiis and Zeldas It's literally.
Rym: it's like we are we are we are we?
Rym: Zelda Zelda Zelda Zelda Zelda Zelda Zelda Zelda.
Scott: well, it's more like Zelda Zelda Zelda.
Scott: It's like a Zelda a second.
Scott: alright if I did the math They got ten days until this thing is out in stores.
Scott: if they continue to keep this factory running and they actually are Manufacturing things at the rate at which you see them manufactured in the video They're gonna make 800,000 plus more Wiis between now and when it comes out.
Rym: I just like I mean you see this line this conveyor belt And there's so many Wiis coming off of it at such a rate, and then you know I kind of picture What's the ps3 line looking like.
Scott: it's probably like the s3?
Rym: Broken ps3.
Rym: a ps3 missing apart Just like an empty box is a ps2.
Scott: I Really a gamecube.
Rym: they're making what not like 200,000 ps3s.
Rym: they make that many Wiis in like a day or two in a few days.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, at least if the rate of this factory in the video is to be assumed I'm sure there's like issues getting enough chips.
Scott: You know eventually this factory is gonna run out of chips and they'll have to wait for another shipment.
Scott: Maybe who knows.
Rym: cuz I'll say when I worked at IBM, and you know the factory pretty much was going at full steam 24/7 all the time nothing ever really got hold held up because there weren't enough of a chip because they plan that shit out.
Rym: I mean you plan I could go and actually I could go into really cool detail about how factories plan.
Rym: You know the way They'll figure out their inventory and how to track things through the factory in different pads.
Rym: yeah all the fun stuff I learned at IBM that is in no way applicable to any job.
Rym: I'll ever want to have again.
Scott: Yeah, but this video might not even be the factory.
Scott: it might just be the packaging and warehouse because that's the only parts you Actually see.
Scott: like you see people taking wiimotes that are already made and packaging them.
Rym: you see all the minimum wage workers Drop in that's.
Scott: this is the hilarious part of the video.
Scott: is the minimum wage workers?
Scott: Because this is one guy who has the saddest job in the world and his face is so sad.
Scott: all he does is Weaves in cardboard boxes come down a conveyor belt and the conveyor belt is wide enough for two We boxes side by side.
Scott: But the weeboxes come down one at a time and now they could easily make some sort of little Mechanism to put the weeboxes side by side in rows of two in a two by two instead of one by one.
Scott: This guy is using his hands to move the wee boxes to make them two by two Instead of one by one.
Rym: see now.
Rym: That's a big thing in factories.
Rym: Oh well first off this guy looks really Really sad.
Scott: he is so sad like I just feel bad looking at him like oh, man Where did your life go wrong?
Rym: Well it harkens back to when I had that factory job working for what I think was Pillsbury.
Rym: Yeah, well I say I had a factory job.
Rym: I worked there for exactly eight hours.
Rym: Total it's one shift and my job.
Rym: This is what I was really poor at RIT And I took a whole bunch of temp jobs.
Rym: I was a Jewish caterer a bunch of times which was actually kind of fun Yeah, but I had to stand there, and there's this giant machine that was making a cinnamon apple pie.
Rym: It's like frozen apple pies like full-size pies that would be put up by Pillsbury.
Rym: at a rate It was literally pie pie pie pie pie pie pie pie pie pie pie pie pie pie pie pie pie.
Scott: And it was that's quite a bunch of pies for a full eight hours.
Rym: Just pies.
Scott: are people eating pies at that rate?
Scott: That's insane I don't even know.
Rym: but it was literally was like all these different shoots at the end and all these people ready to box them.
Rym: So the pot one pie would come down one slot and be the pie pie pie pie pie.
Rym: down all these different slots and by The time it got back to the first slot the first guy had just boxed one of the pies Man.
Rym: like if anyone fucked up at all they blow a whistle the whole thing would stop.
Rym: They'd yell at someone and then it would start again.
Rym: My job was that there were.
Rym: there were these tins.
Rym: you know the pie tins.
Rym: I would load up thousands and thousands of them like by ripping them out of boxes stacking them up Carry them over and dump them in the top of this hopper.
Rym: That was my hopper that was my entire job, I got a hopper Hopper.
Rym: hey Jerry Yeah, so for eight hours one day with a half-hour break for lunch and two 15-minute union mandated breaks for whatever.
Rym: I carried Pie tins and dropped him in a hopper.
Rym: Wow yeah factory jobs suck.
Rym: anytime I see a factory job it reminds me not to complain about my job at all.
Scott: You know the thing is for someone out there for a lot of people out there They probably could have fun with a factory job.
Rym: Oh, yeah, cuz once you get used to that you can just hang out with the people in the factory and all the Really really poor people working in this Pillsbury factory because they were making Like the bare minimum wage at this place, and I think I was making ten cents above that because I was a contractor.
Rym: Yeah for that one day, but they really seem to enjoy themselves running around yelling at each other.
Rym: They had this whole kind of camaraderie thing going.
Scott: yeah, I mean just today.
Scott: I was listening to Like.
Scott: it was.
Scott: it was a pot.
Scott: It wasn't really a podcast.
Scott: it was a recording of a radio show, but they podcasted it of My band Doug Rushkoff and someone's interviewing about his book his newest book about.
Scott: You know think inside the box instead of outside the box.
Scott: I forget what the book's called.
Scott: I have the book.
Scott: I want it from him.
Scott: He signed it.
Scott: I haven't read it yet.
Rym: Yeah You wrote that essay.
Scott: I didn't write an essay.
Scott: it was just I. it was a little contest.
Scott: I answered a question, but anyway The he was talking about that.
Scott: there was a guy who was a trash man But he really enjoyed being a trash man And he optimized his trash truck so much and the way he picks up trash That the Union got pissed because he was doing it is making his route too quickly.
Scott: See I'm not gonna get out of rent here, but you could think the rant we would make about that is obvious.
Rym: Yeah, so I think it can.
Rym: I mean Otakon has the same problem pretty much every a lot of things I run into more and more.
Rym: I'm running into Union problems, and I don't like it.
Scott: No.
Scott: I don't all right Yeah, so yeah this Wii factory pretty cool with all the Wii's and all the Zelda games.
Scott: Minimum wage workers hilarious.
Rym: I hope that guy at least gets a Wii.
Rym: Yeah, that guy looked like he looked different from all the other people.
Rym: I think he made a little bit more money.
Rym: Okay, cuz there was only.
Rym: he was the only guy doing his job, but there was a gaggle of people doing the other jobs.
Scott: I don't know, but they weren't making much plus.
Rym: his badge I think was a different color was like yellowish, but that might have just been your monitor who knows okay?
Rym: Yeah, so You kind of picked our topic for today, so I think you can introduce this okay?
Rym: Cuz I had a different idea about what to talk about.
Scott: no idea what to talk about today.
Scott: So suddenly we came up with the idea of talking about showering and bathing in an entirely non-sexual way.
Scott: yes But cuz you know apparently there's a lot of geeks out there who don't know how to shower and bathe properly.
Scott: however and also Even if you do know how to shower and bathe properly and you do so there are many hilarious Anecdotes that can go along with such a simple everyday task.
Rym: Yeah, I think back to an episode of Seinfeld where Kramer was talking about how it takes him forever to get ready like in the Morning like they're gonna go somewhere, and they're like Kramer.
Rym: Just go take a shower.
Rym: We'll go when he's like What I need like two hours, and they're like what and it turns out that Kramer Just didn't actually know how to shower.
Rym: so he asked Jerry for help and they get in the bathtub With or the the shower with bath bathing suits on and Jerry shows him how to shower like Don't wash each part of the body and rinse it wash the whole body then rinse the whole body And it was actually a really funny episode.
Scott: Yeah, there's many other things talk about too like water pressure and Hard water and soft water.
Scott: remember the episode where they had the hair was on.
Rym: Seinfeld actually talks about this topic quite a bit Because it's a really important topic in New York City.
Scott: Yeah, I guess it is low flow.
Rym: I don't like this one bit Plus.
Rym: we got that new technology to talk about.
Scott: I think that's how we came up with the idea for this episode.
Rym: Yeah, even though I wanted to talk about bad professors and teachers But we we Scott decided and I kind of agree now that we should probably think on that because I got to make sure I Remember I'd
Scott: have to go through it grade by grade writing down teachers and what they did.
Rym: well I had a lot of nuns as teachers.
Rym: oh And one of them was a millionaire gave up her fortune really wow and you know what she didn't look very happy.
Scott: Okay So Showering and bathing.
Scott: how do you take a shower?
Rym: well Scott?
Rym: And I have very different shower procedures in ways that the more I've lived with him the more I've learned that we're very different in that way.
Rym: one aside from all that I have very long hair so Showering is a 15-minute deal for me, and then another half hour at least worth of dealing with my hair.
Scott: Yeah, and sometimes you don't even deal with the hair.
Rym: Oh, yeah, if I need to take a quick shower I wash all of my body except the hair.
Scott: Yeah, I shampoo every time.
Rym: see I can't because once my hair gets wet I either have to do stuff to it or put on a hat.
Rym: yeah Plus if I want a shower at night, and I get my hair wet I can't really go to bed with wet hair, and I can't quickly dry my hair.
Rym: It takes a long time for my hair to dry mmm.
Scott: Yeah, see I just shampoo every time.
Scott: the thing is my showers Can either be like one-minute affairs in which I clean myself in the shortest amount of time possible Or they can be like five to ten minute affairs where I wake up in the morning in the shower Or they could be longer where I spend a lot of time just relaxing in the hot water going.
Rym: ah Yeah, I've often taken very long showers just for the fun of it.
Rym: Yeah But I mean if the only consolation I guess I could ever have if I got cancer and I had to go through Chemotherapy was that if I lost all my hair, and I ended up being bald Showering I could wake up an hour later and still make it to work on time I could.
Rym: I could shave and shower inside of five minutes.
Scott: See like I kind of want to be bald for the comfort.
Scott: the only reason I don't I'll shave your head.
Scott: Yeah, I'll shave your head is because then there would be problems in the hair.
Scott: grew back.
Rym: No, you just keep shaving it.
Rym: What if you look like Yasu?
Scott: I don't think I look like Yasu.
Rym: You could probably pull it off if you shaved all the hair from the neck up and your dark sunglasses and smoked black cigarettes.
Rym: No, it's not gonna happen, and we're awesome, and we're in a rock band.
Scott: I'm awesome, but I'm not in a rock band.
Scott: Okay, so my shower procedure is pretty simple.
Rym: I didn't actually tell my shower procedure.
Rym: I guess you can do yours.
Scott: Mine's real simple, so I'll go first right yeah, cuz captain doesn't use a washcloth.
Scott: Just hey I use a sponge.
Rym: Yeah, that's a recent development for most of your life.
Rym: apparently you just take a bar of soap and rub it all over your body.
Rym: What's wrong with that?
Rym: It's not how you shower.
Scott: That's how they shower.
Scott: and all the commercials on TV.
Rym: You know what.
Rym: that's not how humans shower.
Rym: Why not supposed to shower that way.
Rym: Why not doesn't it work so well?
Scott: It works just fine.
Scott: I'm very clean.
Rym: see I was the opposite tech in that I Rarely use soap My whole life.
Rym: I never really use soap.
Rym: when I showered you know what I smell just fine.
Scott: Anyway, I get in the shower.
Scott: I turn on the bathtub part, and then I turn on the shower part But I sure to aim it away from me, so I don't get wet right away.
Scott: I got to make sure the temperature is just right.
Scott: you know cuz sometimes you turn the water on right away And it'll be the first time the showers been turned on in the morning.
Scott: So it'll be cold cold cold cold warm warm warm warm.
Rym: the worst is when you're taking a shower in an unfamiliar bathroom.
Rym: Okay, cuz every bathroom has its own little like mystery of how it works like the spots where it is and the thresholds and How hot the hot water is now cold.
Scott: the cold water is and the worst is if you can't Like it used to turn the shower on then it blasts you.
Scott: I always jump even though I know it's coming and that's why I have to have the handheld one so I can aim it away for myself.
Rym: The worst is you know like some are real loose.
Rym: You know like you turn the thing half a turn and the temperature barely changes.
Rym: And then there's some where you just kind of tap the top it with your pinky, and it's 10 degrees hotter.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, cuz it also doesn't help that our house.
Rym: We have a somewhat small water heater.
Rym: It's a mini water heater so in order to have and also the water heater is hooked in with our heat because we have gas Heat that heats water and pumps it through radiators all around the house.
Rym: modern good radiators, not old shitty steam radiators.
Scott: Yeah, it's a it's an okay system.
Rym: Yeah, it's actually a really good system.
Rym: It saves us a lot of money in the winter yep, but as a result our hot water is Just shy of boiling.
Rym: you can just use our tap to cook ramen.
Rym: Probably our tap will scald you if you just turn on our hot water and get it on your skin.
Rym: It is dangerous.
Scott: Yeah, I like that way.
Rym: I like it that way too because we've never run out of hot water.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, so I get in the shower.
Scott: I get I get all you know.
Scott: I let the warm water heat me up.
Scott: It feels good.
Scott: I get my hair wet, but I what hair I have at the time.
Scott: And then I get some shampoo, and I go Rinse it out and then depending on what kind of a rush I'm in if I'm not in a rush I take out my sponge and I put some soap on it and then I go Shoo-shoo-shoo-shoo-shoo.
Rym: See I'm glad that you have added the sponge to your repertoire.
Scott: I don't know what the sponge feels nice But I don't see how it.
Scott: you know that much different because it scrapes your skin it exfoliates it pulls off Just a bunch of womanly whatnot?
Rym: no Yeah, are you saying that exfoliation doesn't actually happen.
Scott: No.
Scott: I'm saying is it's all a bunch of BS crap.
Scott: They used to sell shit at the bed bath and whatever Scott you can exfoliate with your hands and water anyway.
Scott: So and then if I'm in a rush though I just take a bar of soap and I rub it on myself, and then I run away.
Rym: that doesn't work.
Scott: It works just fine, and then you know I'll.
Scott: You know I'll take the.
Scott: if I have a shower massaging thing that I can take off the hook which I do.
Rym: I don't want to hear about what you do with that.
Scott: Just clean down.
Scott: see you gotta have one of those cuz.
Scott: how else can you clean down under where the shower can't hit you know?
Scott: I don't understand like you go it.
Scott: They just have a shower head mounted on the wall.
Scott: There's no way to get that to hit you in the taint Like stand upside down in the shower.
Rym: actually what I've done on numerous occasions is I'm actually kind of flexible for the kind Considering that I'm a 24 or 25 year old.
Rym: I'm 24 right?
Rym: yeah, yeah 24 year old.
Rym: You're gonna be 25 real soon.
Rym: Yeah I am but I can pretty much lift my leg high enough and stand at an angle to wash my tank.
Scott: No, I don't die if I can't get water to blast into the taint.
Rym: I'll just I'll kind of go like this.
Rym: I'm doing it right now.
Rym: Oh I'm wearing clothes, but see you can't do this shit.
Scott: I could do that shit You couldn't but I don't want to do that.
Rym: what I'll do is I'll do what I just did.
Scott: I'll just take soap and rub it down there, and then I'll cup water with my hands and splash it or I'll get down like this.
Scott: That's no good.
Rym: It works really well.
Scott: another option is to just you know get the sponge and rub it down there.
Scott: Or you know I could turn the tub on and then like get down into the the tub Blaster like just lay down in the shower, but that's kind of gross if the shower isn't clean which it's kind of dirty in there.
Scott: Yeah, so the tub part is still really clean.
Scott: No.
Rym: It's not.
Rym: there's stuff growing down there again.
Scott: It's nothing growing on.
Rym: There's a big stain.
Scott: No it's.
Scott: it's better than it ever has been it's not.
Scott: it's right back to the way.
Scott: Oh, it's not.
Rym: yes.
Scott: It is.
Scott: It's not.
Rym: I'll bring in two objective witnesses tomorrow.
Scott: Yeah, whatever.
Scott: Anyway, yeah, so I just cleaned my hair.
Scott: I cleaned the rest of my body.
Scott: I make sure I clean my feet like in between the toes behind the ears and all that.
Rym: That's something that bothers me because while you've had a couple of fungus on your feet your feet are pretty good.
Rym: They don't smell bad usually.
Scott: they don't Smell bad if I'm wearing sneakers all day and running around and sweating in my socks And then at the end of the day I go.
Rym: ah But I saw statistics a while ago that apparently like 80% of Americans have Moderate to serious fungus problems on their feet and their toenails.
Scott: whoa look at my.
Scott: my toenails look clean clear white.
Scott: Yeah, it's white and pink.
Scott: those the only colors.
Rym: Yeah, I go step further And I'm dead serious.
Rym: my feet almost never smell at all and numerous people have pointed this out to me Like they just never smell like anything.
Rym: Hmm, I blame mostly the fact that I'm always barefoot and I wash my feet But I can't understand how so many people have such disgusting feet.
Rym: wash them Yeah, that's all.
Scott: you get soap on the feet rub them a little bit get soap between the toes And then take your handheld shower massager and blast your feet so that they get all the shit off.
Rym: Well, I think that one of the other big keys is to not really paint your toenails.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know why.
Scott: I don't understand why women do that.
Scott: I don't want to turn the topic of the show into toenail painting, but do you think toenail painting is attractive?
Rym: I am mostly indifferent.
Scott: That's what I'm saying is that most guys are completely indifferent to toenail painting like they don't care if they're painted or not.
Scott: There's a few guys.
Scott: I'm sure that have like a toenail painting fetish, but most guys that I know are indifferent.
Scott: Yeah, women insist on doing it some paying a lot of money for pedicures.
Scott: You know what though?
Rym: a lot of awesome women don't.
Scott: yeah, pedicure is a lot different from painting And I know but I like that usually pedicure followed by nail painting and all kinds of craziness.
Rym: actually I should go get a pedicure.
Scott: I mean, I don't even like hand fingernails, you know, see I'm just generally.
Rym: I Generally dislike makeup.
Rym: I like yeah made on makeup.
Rym: Granted makeup is cool.
Rym: You know, like if you're going to a formal ball like a fancy party It's cool to get all dressed like we're gonna be on TV or on stage.
Rym: I have worn makeup on a several occasions.
Scott: Wow, I know I know you're gay.
Rym: No, but way back when the RIT Anime Club.
Rym: I was pretty much I was guaranteed to be president.
Rym: I've been on the eboard everyone knew me everyone loved me But I was actually living way out of town during the elections So I couldn't give a speech or anything and it didn't matter because I was running unopposed.
Rym: But then someone decided to run against me.
Rym: So I there was no danger of me losing but I had to give a little speech and videotape it and mail it back to Rochester so they could show it to the club where I basically said All right, everyone vote for me and I actually put on some makeup.
Rym: So I'd look better because my camera was kind of shitty and the light was really shitty and I recorded it once and I looked Kind of a bit shit.
Rym: So I powdered my face and then I put on a little bit and I looked a lot better and then I did it take Two.
Scott: So what's your shower methodology?
Scott: Mr.
Scott: Fancy pants.
Rym: All right.
Rym: All right fancy pants.
Rym: now I've been all right, so I get in the shower.
Rym: Well first I lay in my room and I do as many sit-ups as I can until I shower because then I get all sweaty And it wakes me up real quick.
Rym: So I don't wake up in the shower All right, and then, you know, I go into the shower.
Rym: I set up.
Scott: I wake up in the shower.
Rym: I Usually brush my teeth first before I get in the shower.
Rym: Huh?
Rym: That way I'm done with it.
Rym: I was out of the way.
Rym: It's done that taste that you wake up with in the morning is already gone.
Scott: Mmm, see in the shower.
Scott: I let like because they blast pretty hard.
Scott: I'm all about high water pressure So I blast.
Scott: I let the shower blast into my mouth and then I brush the teeth, you know Cuz all that fungus growing in that nasty busted old showerhead?
Scott: no, it's not fungus growing in there.
Rym: Uh, yeah there is it's fine It's there.
Rym: There's a lot of mold and other things growing.
Rym: Whatever.
Rym: I'll show it to you.
Rym: You want me to show it to you?
Rym: Do you believe it's there but you five bucks is there?
Scott: It's not gonna hurt you?
Rym: not probably not but I'd rather just brush my teeth.
Rym: Anyway, and then you know while I'm brushing my teeth about halfway through I turn on the tub on hot.
Rym: That way all the cold water in the pipe gets rushed out like a bum.
Scott: So my problem is I go in and I pee and I flush and then I jump in the shower right away And now I got away.
Rym: Oh, see I just pee in the shower.
Scott: I don't do that.
Rym: I always pee in the shower.
Rym: If I shower I probably pee.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I'll make the Seinfeld argument the George Costanza argument.
Rym: It's all tubes.
Scott: so, you know what the thing is is If I go into the bathroom to shower I have an urge to pee like if I go in I pee then I just walk out of the bathroom and walk back in Immediately like I'm gonna shower.
Scott: I'll have to pee again no matter what really and like a one drop of pee will come out and then I can get in the Shower.
Scott: Wow, it's like my body knows when I go into a bathroom and the pee sensor just turns on automatically How it works, but it must be some connection there like entering a bathroom gotta pee.
Rym: See I pretty much just I saw the hot waters going and then I finished brushing my teeth and right about then is when the scalding Water comes out.
Scott: It's like if I was running away from the police and they chased me into a bathroom.
Scott: I'd have to pee Huh?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right continue.
Rym: See I wonder though if you had that urge and the police could you would you just pee your pants?
Scott: I might be the police Because I guess if I'm in a bathroom, it's probably a dead end.
Scott: So it's time to give up.
Scott: but if I'm gonna give up I'm gonna pee on the police.
Rym: I cannot pee my pants.
Rym: Furthermore I cannot like I could.
Scott: if I and just sat there and held it in forever And I was in a car on a long trip and there's nowhere to stop It would.
Scott: I would eventually no longer be able to hold it after a long period of time or if I've got punched in the gut Of course that would immediately spill it out.
Rym: But no there were a couple times where I'd be driving in a long road trip and I'd have a large empty water bottle or Something and I'm making good time.
Rym: I don't want to stop.
Rym: So I'd try to pee into something and I found that I simply could not Bring my body to open that little orifice and let my dragon drain When I was in a car or in any place other than a place for peeing.
Rym: Now a tree is a place for peeing.
Rym: pretty much any open space is a place for peeing.
Rym: Yeah, but if I'm sitting down and a car can't pee I've never tried it.
Rym: It's actually it takes a little bit more logistical planning.
Scott: did I imagine the hardest part would be continuing to drive safely?
Rym: No, really easy actually because it was Canada.
Rym: It was a straight flat.
Scott: That'll do it with cruise control.
Rym: Like there wasn't even a chance of deer.
Rym: It's just nothing.
Rym: I mean, maybe I'll run into a Tim Hortons.
Scott: How do you shower?
Rym: Oh, yeah showers.
Rym: So I get that water pretty much one step away from burning me to death and I stand there for a good five minutes.
Rym: just.
Scott: Yeah, I love that.
Scott: it's like the best feeling except for drinking orange juice, which is a better feeling.
Rym: and of course see sometimes I'll drink orange juice and do all that before I get in the shower.
Scott: Oh, no, I can't do that.
Rym: I'll run downstairs I'll drink a giant glass of orange juice.
Rym: Then I'll come up.
Scott: No, I can't do.
Scott: I gotta drink it right before I leave the house All right, so
Rym: then I'll be in the shower hot water and I you know rub my body down relax a bit And then I take the shampoo of which I have three different kinds that I thought that I alternate
Scott: whatever.
Scott: It's all the same shit.
Rym: No, it's not.
Rym: cuz I actually in about two and a half seasons out of the air I'll get dandruff.
Rym: so I use Selsun blue once or twice a week because that is like Fucking dandruff death right there.
Rym: that kills all the dandruff.
Rym: all the tea gel kills the dandruff but that gives you cancer also Yeah, because it contains I forget what it can do coal tar Whatever it's called Selsun blue actually works better than that stuff.
Rym: Anyway, yeah according to several stuff.
Scott: Well, it depends on there's different causes of dandruff.
Scott: It depends.
Rym: Well, the most common cause of dandruff is a fungus.
Scott: Yeah, so if you got the fungus one the Selsun blue works great.
Rym: If you have the other kinds you should go to a doctor because you've got problems.
Rym: Yeah, but yeah, so I use the Selsun once or twice a week.
Rym: I use head and shoulders most other days and about once a week I use this other shampoo just to wash it just to kind of balance it out.
Rym: and also see I say that but it's mostly Just because that's my travel shampoo and it's a big thing.
Rym: So I just kind of use it occasionally cuz.
Scott: yeah I forgot to mention what soaps and shampoos I owe.
Rym: you can get to that later.
Rym: All right, cuz you wanted to know how I shower.
Rym: Okay, cuz and that's how I know you're gay Asking Rym how we showers.
Rym: this was all just some elaborate scheme to get me to describe myself in the shower.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: anyway We're gonna run out of time.
Rym: yes got continued.
Scott: Okay proceed.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So then I shampoo my hair with whatever shampoo I'm gonna use and I leave it in for like five minutes.
Rym: Well that's going on and take a washcloth and I rub my whole body down.
Rym: Real well.
Rym: most specifically To paraphrase phrase George Carlin armpits asshole crotch armpits asshole crotch and then tea.
Rym: Well, I don't wash my teeth in the shower.
Scott: I know but that's those are the important bits.
Rym: Yes armpits asshole crash and teeth and for the vast majority of my showers for my whole life.
Rym: I didn't use any soap.
Rym: I just rub myself down with really hot water and a clean washcloth.
Rym: Now lately, I'll use shampoo because it acts more as kind of a fragrance and I smell nice for the rest of the day as opposed to smelling like nothing.
Rym: and also lately because I've been exercising a lot and I've been doing anaerobic exercise since I'm lifting weights now and I found that when I lift weights, my sweat is a quite a bit more foul than when I do anything else.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: It seems to be the way it rolls.
Rym: So if I lift weight, I get some smelly sweat So I use soap then to make sure that all goes away.
Rym: But if I go running I smell normal I just happen to be sweaty.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Then I rinse all that off of me Then I rinse out the shampoo then I dick around for a while.
Rym: Enjoy the hot water some more.
Rym: rub myself down again.
Rym: You know, I enjoy my showers rubbing yourself down not in that way.
Rym: I can't really masturbate in the morning if that's what you're getting at.
Scott: No, I can't do it in the morning either.
Rym: Yeah, cuz it's there.
Rym: It's ready to go.
Scott: Well, no, it's like if it is a morning wood and you go for it.
Scott: It doesn't work.
Scott: I mean it works, but it doesn't work in a good way.
Rym: It just sucks.
Scott: Yeah morning wood is not useful.
Rym: No, it's useful.
Scott: Well, it's useful for pleasuring women, but not for pleasuring yourself.
Rym: So anyway, yeah Then I load up on the conditioner.
Rym: I use like eight different kinds.
Rym: Okay, not like all at once like I'll use one until it runs out.
Rym: then I buy a different one till it runs out.
Rym: I buy different till it runs out.
Rym: I have this kind of random cycle where I buy whatever one smelled nice at the time.
Scott: That's usually my judgment is which one smells.
Rym: so recently.
Rym: I bought some suave conditioner for men and it totally sucks.
Rym: Alright, it's just it's terrible conditioner.
Rym: It seems to be this wave.
Scott: Yeah, it is not like the world's wave.
Rym: Then I leave that in for a while and I enjoy the hot water again at that point usually wash my face and start Soaking my stubble in preparation for the shave.
Scott: Oh, yeah, if I'm gonna shave I totally just stand with my face like getting blasted by hot hot water from the shower for like a whole minute.
Rym: But and then I jump out and shave and then here's the trick I set it to cool or coldish water and I rinse my hair Mm-hmm real.
Rym: and then I do this occasionally because it's it's a really awesome adrenaline rush.
Rym: I'll just turn that full-on cold water and stand under it.
Scott: Yeah If you need to wake up Like in the morning the best thing to do I only do this like if I'm super sleepy and I have to wake up real Quick is you just go in there you stand in the nice warm water and just take the knob and you go Cold normal like
Rym: wait what?
Rym: No, no.
Rym: No, you're a goddamn pansy.
Rym: if that's what you do You stand there in the water on hot and you deliberately put your hand on the dial Jerk it all the way to cold and don't move your ass.
Scott: You know in like five seconds later.
Scott: You're like fuck.
Rym: In fact, you know what I have never not yelled fuck when I've done Because I don't do it often because I think this will feel really good after I get over what I've just done to myself but without fail.
Scott: Shit see the thing is it's so much worse if you're if you have it done hot and then cold and then hot as Opposed to if you just turned it cold in the first place.
Scott: you ever done that experiment where you have like a bucket of warm Water and a bucket of cold water like go do this If you're if you're curious take two buckets.
Scott: fill one bucket with perfectly lukewarm tap water Like room temperature water.
Scott: take another bucket and put cold water with a bunch of ice in it like freaking freezing cold water, right?
Scott: Put your hand in the warm water.
Scott: it will feel warm.
Scott: then put that same hand in the ice water.
Scott: It will feel freezing cold.
Scott: now take your other hand that you didn't use yet and put it in the ice cold water.
Scott: It'll be cold but not as cold as it felt with the other hand a minute ago.
Scott: Now take that hand and put it in the perfectly lukewarm water.
Scott: It will feel hot like ow your temperature sensors are all relative They're not absolute, you know, which can get you into trouble sometimes.
Scott: But in the shower, you said it's a hot and then cold.
Rym: Oh, man, though I gotta say it's weird cuz in the summer like I'll often take a cool shower.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but even then I have to start with a hot shower.
Rym: Yeah, I can't start with cold water unless it's a hundred degrees and I'm in the Sun.
Scott: Well, the thing is if it's a hundred degrees and you're in the Sun the water is actually heating up.
Scott: So you need the cool water.
Scott: Yeah All right.
Scott: So what do what shampoos do I use?
Rym: Yeah, we'll wrap this up.
Rym: We've got a while.
Scott: So most recently I've been using all this suave like for men Shampoos and soaps and things but I think they discontinued most of them.
Scott: I was buying them because they were cheap And they smelled okay, they smelled kind of manly.
Scott: But now I think most recently I bought like suave completely normal shampoo that smells like apples Which is cool because I like apples, huh?
Scott: And when I need a bar of soap, I always get coast and if coast is not available I get Irish spring.
Rym: See it's weird because I actually really prefer lavender or lilac.
Rym: I really like anything that has lilac smell.
Scott: Yeah, cuz they're a woman.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: Yeah, I just get apples or maybe like strawberries or melons.
Rym: Yeah, and apples and strawberries are so much more manly captain man fruit.
Scott: Yeah, root is more manly than flowers, I don't know.
Rym: lilacs are awesome.
Scott: they're not manly.
Rym: yeah, they are.
Rym: they're so manly.
Rym: Yeah to use my favorite phrase it's like two Vikings having sex.
Scott: Yeah, all right.
Scott: Are we done talking about showers?
Rym: I think we're done talking about this.
Rym: Hopefully next time we'll do.
Rym: I don't know my idea where we're talking about bad professors.
Scott: Yeah, all I need to do is spend like a half hour Maybe not even a half hour just like a few minutes to think about all the teachers have had throughout the years.
Rym: See I haven't had so many bad teachers.
Rym: I've just had really really mediocre teachers.
Scott: Yeah, I haven't had anyone who was evil like.
Scott: I've had some teachers who were like good, but there was a bad aspect I dropped out of like four classes.
Rym: just cuz I didn't like the cut of the teachers.
Scott: jib We're done.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio Via audio.
Scott: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Scott: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.