Rym: It's Thursday February 2nd, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We wax poetic about the toys of our youth.
Scott: Let's do this, so I'm getting this new car.
Scott: tomorrow at 4 p.m.. I have to go pick it up and I had to go through the ordeal of buying insurance.
Rym: Now for any of you who don't know our views on car insurance and the laws Surrounding it in this country this country being the United States for all of our foreign listeners ah It's kind of a scam.
Rym: It's kind of a bullshit.
Scott: Yeah, I mean you're basically Betting that you're gonna crash or your car is gonna get stolen or get messed up somehow.
Scott: now not only do I not think that's gonna happen and I I don't want to bet that it is gonna happen.
Scott: in fact if I could bet that it wasn't gonna happen I would do so and This is really a problem because the government says you must bet that it will happen.
Rym: well It depends on the state.
Rym: some states don't require car insurance.
Scott: Oh really well.
Rym: Yeah, so those no state We want to live in great New York and Michigan actually have some of the strictest laws.
Rym: They do.
Rym: we happen to live in New York.
Scott: Yeah, so because I'm financing this car.
Scott: I need a pile of insurance.
Scott: now I'm gonna explain some details because I don't think everyone listening knows everything there is to know about car insurance.
Rym: But we do now.
Scott: we do now.
Scott: so first I do the smart thing that a smart person like me does and I call every single major car insurance provider my current provider And my company also acts as an insurance agency.
Scott: at least one part of it does.
Scott: so I called them to.
Scott: The lowest quote was from my current provider in Connecticut.
Scott: So they told me 629 for six months or something like that, which is great Considering I'm financing the car and I'm not 25 yet.
Scott: That's like a crazy price.
Scott: So after I call everyone else and everyone else gives me a higher price including the famous infamous Geico I called all state and I said alright.
Scott: Give me that price.
Scott: then they did a. It wasn't a credit check.
Scott: They called it a Financial stability check now.
Rym: This is the point at which I think you could have pressed and gotten some sort of contents for that.
Rym: Anyway, go on doesn't matter.
Scott: So they changed the quote from six something to 1,100 and something.
Scott: and I'm like, yeah, I'm totally not buying that now and The reason I didn't press was because obviously this this girl didn't actually, you know She's an insurance agent Which means she's not an actuary.
Scott: the actuaries of the people who figure out how much the insurance cost.
Scott: the agent is just a sales Person.
Scott: they basically type in my information into a computer which gives them a number between 1 and 16.
Scott: They type that number into a box and then it tells them how much money.
Scott: to tell me they don't know crap.
Scott: So pressing I figured really wouldn't get me anyway like Phoenix Wright press.
Rym: Yeah, so thing is the way.
Rym: they must have done some sort of credit check.
Rym: I would assume that they did some sort of credit.
Scott: Yeah, but the thing is this girl didn't do anything.
Scott: She all she did.
Rym: it was a matter though If the company gave you a higher price as a result of anything involving a credit check.
Rym: by law They have to inform you that.
Rym: that's why they did it and they have to provide you with a free credit report.
Scott: Well, they say she said he did.
Scott: she did it because of the number that came out when she did this financial stability.
Rym: I would have pressed I would have been on the phone with every manager.
Rym: They'd send me to Whatever.
Scott: so the next lowest was of course the infamous Geico.
Scott: So I called them up and I said I want the insurance at this price.
Scott: you said so.
Scott: they said okay and That was that.
Scott: now I'm a big fan of and a big pusher of companies making their businesses run smoothly with computers.
Rym: That means you write stuff.
Scott: Yeah, so Geico actually had something really slick.
Scott: progressive also had it where basically I Went to their website and did a whole bunch of quotes before I called them on the phone, you know and Their computers are so smart that it combined all those quotes in the database So that when I called them and told them who I was they're like, oh I see you did some quotes on the internet there And I'm like, yep.
Scott: So what happened was the first time I called Geico in the middle of a quote the shitty shitty phones at work cut out.
Scott: I had to call back.
Scott: So the guy loaded up the quote that I was working on with that person or at least so he says.
Scott: and Then the third time that I called was the time that I got the policy.
Scott: Then I get a phone call on the way home from Geico because they have to communicate with the dealer because the dealer can't give Me the car unless he knows I have insurance and he has to get the insurance card for me and all that kind of stuff.
Scott: So They call me and they're like, yeah, I got your dealer on the line.
Scott: I'm like, yeah, you got my dealer on the line.
Scott: what's going on?
Scott: And they said we have to change your policy.
Scott: I'm like why?
Scott: Because the car that they think that I have is not the car I have.
Scott: they thought I was getting a 2005 Mazda 6, but I'm getting a 2006 Mazda 3 Outstanding because I'm pretty sure they loaded up a quote saved online that I just did to you know.
Scott: Check out you're lucky.
Rym: They didn't get the GTI instead.
Scott: Yeah, but if they did that then I would have called someone else first because the price would have been different Because it would have been a much higher price of the GTI than for the either of the Mazdas because it's a crazy fast Car.
Scott: but anyway, so I said, okay fine and that because it made my insurance lower.
Scott: Mazda 3 is a lot cheaper insurance than the 6 so I was fine with that.
Scott: Then they call me back later the same thing again, and I'm like, huh?
Scott: What the hell's going on?
Scott: and they say I chose a thousand dollar deductible.
Scott: That means if anything happens where I need to actually collect insurance.
Scott: I have to pay $1,000.
Rym: Now I have $1,000 deductible in my car, which I'm still paying off.
Scott: Yeah And that basically what it does for you is let's say I crashed the car and it takes $500 worth of damage.
Scott: I have to pay all of it because it's less than $1,000.
Scott: Let's say I crashed the car and it takes $2,000 worth of damage.
Scott: I pay a thousand and the insurance pays a thousand totaling the two thousand, right if I took a $500 deductible and there were two thousand dollars worth of damage I would pay five hundred and the insurance company would pay fifteen hundred.
Rym: now bear in mind that we live in a what's called a No fault state.
Rym: now if you live in a no-fault insurance state everything's weird because basically your insurance covers you and the other person's insurance covers them.
Rym: and Whenever there's an accident if you have full insurance, it doesn't matter whose fault it was Whatever the insurance just all pays out no matter what
Scott: Mm-hmm
Rym: in Contented states which is the kind of state I prefer if you cause an accident You are responsible for all of the damages resulting.
Scott: That's the way.
Rym: you don't have insurance that covers it.
Rym: You're kind of fucked.
Scott: Justice is the way it should be.
Scott: which is that way?
Scott: the Rym just said.
Rym: I think no fault Sure insurance should exist.
Rym: as in if you want no fault insurance.
Rym: You should be able to pay for it and have it.
Scott: Oh, yeah, if you want to fix an a damage that someone else did to your car You're free to do so.
Scott: but at the same time if someone else damages my car I'm free to make them fix it because they did it if I can prove they did it.
Rym: Yeah, the problem with no fault states is that they don't let you go after the people who cause accidents so easily.
Scott: Yeah, it sucks.
Scott: So the thing here is that I'm financing the car which basically means I don't technically own it.
Scott: It's just collateral on this loan that I'm paying off to this bank.
Rym: It's a lot like a mortgage.
Scott: Yeah, so they decide how much they could force me to get whatever insurance they want me to get and for some reason They're forcing me to get the $500 deductible instead of the 1,000.
Scott: I Don't know why.
Scott: That makes no sense.
Scott: Why would they care?
Rym: but Yeah, if I were you I would have called the bank up and been like, hey, I don't have the bank's phone number I would have found it out.
Scott: I could have found it out, but I think they were closed at that hour.
Scott: The thing is is like If I get a thousand dollar deductible, it makes my insurance payments a lot less.
Scott: So I'm wasting a lot less of my money on nothing.
Scott: So I kind of want it and I'm sure that after like I'm 25.
Scott: I'll be fine.
Rym: So whatever I mean, I just I hate the idea of having to have car insurance.
Rym: if someone else causes an accident It's their dumbass fault and they should pay for the damages to me.
Rym: And if they don't cause an accident Well, it's my dumbass fault and I should be forced to pay for it.
Scott: yeah, and if I think that I'm gonna cause an accident, I'm free to bet on insurance and gamble my money and Possibly pay out.
Scott: if I do cause an accident also, and if I don't want insurance and I cause an accident That's my own damn fault for not getting insurance and betting wrong.
Scott: and now I should be forced to pay out.
Rym: Even worse if I had all the money that I've put into car insurance over the years It'd be enough to put a down payment on a new car or cover any kind of damage.
Rym: I might have caused to myself.
Scott: Yeah, I know and think about if I had taken that money from the insurance.
Scott: right.
Scott: I'm putting in what $700 to insurance the next six months.
Scott: $700 in a savings account.
Scott: we get three percent interest three percent.
Rym: What kind of crap Bank are you going to?
Scott: That's what you get about as the average for a savings account these days.
Rym: I get that on my checking account.
Scott: No, you don't.
Rym: Well, I do on the account that has a dollar in it.
Rym: I'm not one that has a dollar in it.
Rym: I haven't switched fully over to that bank yet.
Scott: There's not much interest rates on normal savings accounts aren't so great these days.
Scott: Yeah, you know three and four percent range.
Rym: Yeah, I go to a credit union man.
Scott: it's not the set the normal savings account, but anyway, the point is is $700 a month.
Scott: I'm gonna have the car for five years assuming that just stays the same.
Scott: 700 times 2 is 14 times 5.
Scott: It's 22 thousand plus seven thousand dollars.
Scott: four percent interest.
Rym: Congratulations that you're good at math.
Scott: Yeah, the point is mad.
Scott: money's yo enough to buy cars and Computers and gadgets and instead it goes to nothing.
Scott: It's crap.
Rym: But at least you'll have the car tomorrow and we might be driving out to Rochester with a bunch of our friends for a weekend of Buying board games and playing them.
Rym: Hooray playing multiple eight-player eight-way Bomberman slash Mario Kart's.
Scott: We definitely need to buy some board games and play them.
Rym: Yeah I got to say the gaming stores where we live are not up to come up to par and I think I'm just gonna have a Little like gamegasm when I get back to Rochester.
Scott: Yeah, I think I'll buy two or three games.
Scott: Maybe if they have what I want.
Rym: So in the news for all of you who listened to yesterday's episode, we talked about the controversy surrounding Otakon's possible artists alley policy.
Rym: Well, we're not the only ones talking about it and like we kind of mentioned There's a giant flaming shitstorm going on all over the Internet at least the anime Internet.
Rym: yeah, the Internet we care about the like the geekly anime whatever Internet and Otakon.
Rym: today Jim Vowles the head of Otakon 2006 released an official statement regarding this.
Rym: it's on the website.
Rym: I'm not gonna read the whole thing But basically he says that Otakon is not not in capital letters Implementing nor is it ever seriously considered a total ban on fan arts.
Rym: our initial posting on the subject Was clearly confused by some people blah blah blah and we apologize.
Scott: All right, it was confusing.
Scott: now, I Guess you could say it was confusing but Have you read it?
Rym: I mean I could see because it wall this.
Rym: the original announcement was posted under a thread entitled Official changes to artist alley policy and while it was posted by the head of the artists alley for Otakon There was language in the specific Clause they talked about.
Rym: that does say something to the effect of the above will be reworded depending on blah blah blah Whatever the lawyers tell us.
Rym: So, alright, if that had been it I would have been alright, obviously it was just a misunderstanding.
Rym: They should have waited whatever.
Rym: but The he says here that Otakon never seriously considered banning all fan art.
Rym: Yet if you read all the posts by the head of the artist alley in the Otakon forum since the announcement she made She very much says that fan art is going to be banned.
Rym: She doesn't use the word fan art.
Rym: She says you can't use that word, which I agree with because it's not a legal term.
Rym: But she you can.
Rym: there are many quotes for she very specifically outlines What is and is not allowed and what is not allowed is everything?
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So obviously the there is a difference of opinion between the head of artists alley and the rest of Otakon and I think even though it looks like We're gonna turn out so that artists alley isn't ruined or anything Which is good not gonna argue that it looks like Otakon is gonna have to.
Scott: Just you know, they did a PR stumble for no reason.
Rym: Yeah I mean even if this policy went into effect and they were going to do it I can't believe that Otakon would not have expected an insane Possibly irrational backlash from anything like this.
Scott: to think that's the problem is Otakon.
Scott: It doesn't look like this was a movement of Otakon itself.
Scott: It looks like this was all the artists alley person.
Rym: Well, actually it was.
Rym: she admits to this in two separate posts in the forums.
Scott: See, that's the.
Scott: you can't have that you I mean, there's one thing we have absolutely no democracy And there's another and we have too much democracy, right?
Scott: Which is would be all the members decide how Otakon is wrong.
Rym: I disagree because when I ran the anime club at RIT back in the day Basically every member of the executive board was in charge of a certain aspect of the club.
Rym: you know the treasurer the facilities coordinator whatever and Unless the board voted as a group to overrule someone which was a rare event.
Rym: a member of an eboard member was free to do whatever they wanted with their domain and Otakon seems to run the same way which in many ways works.
Rym: the head of the artists alley is fully in charge of the artist Alley, unless the rest of the board as far as I can gather here comes together and says alright No, we're overruling you.
Rym: I agree.
Scott: but here's the problem.
Scott: this artists alley person has stepped out of their role as head of artists alley and stepped into the Role of who should be the PR man,
Rym: maybe I mean other than again This is her own forum And if she's running the artists alley I say she could use the forum to post of whatever she wants about the artists alley as long as she's willing to take care of the Possible PR consequences.
Scott: Yeah, I just don't think that that's an intelligent way to run things.
Scott: if you were so public that and you have So many people who you can upset or piss off or make blunders about You should either have a PR guy where everything goes through that person or You should you know Be real smart when you say things.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, I guess if I were in charge of releasing like say Otakon was doing this policy.
Rym: I was in charge of releasing it.
Rym: I would have gotten together with whoever was involved and come up with answers to every possible question I could think of and then made a big announcement about on the Otakon site and Along with all of the information like a fact and all the whole webpage dedicated to this change.
Rym: that would diffuse the Immediate reactionary backlash that we've seen happen here.
Scott: limit here.
Scott: take an example of a company that does PR well take Microsoft right.
Scott: anything that Microsoft ever says is either said by Bill Gates Steve Ballmer or an official press release an Official PR people I guess but they don't say much.
Scott: they just kind of say these things that have already been written.
Scott: I listened to an interview with one guy today.
Scott: He just kept saying the same thing over and over again And if they asked him to say anything that wasn't already something he knew how to say.
Scott: He just dodged it entirely and said something generic.
Scott: You know and that's if you're you know.
Scott: That's the only way to be unless you're one of those completely wide-open companies where people see all of your internal communications Like you know something like Linux where the kernel mailing list is all the communication and it's wide open.
Rym: Yeah, you're not wanted right now.
Rym: You could just subscribe to that and know exactly what's going on with the link.
Scott: I need to subscribe.
Scott: you can just go look at it.
Scott: Oh, yeah, browse it.
Scott: But yeah If you're not completely open so that no one has any Misunderstandings about what you're doing because they can see everything and it's completely transparent You need to be like all those real corporations that keep everything complete secret and make no official statements and no comments except for official PR and You know it.
Scott: when you have such a loose kind of non Super strict thing like Otakon that is as big as Otakon sometimes these things happen.
Rym: I mean at least I really think artist Ally's gonna be okay because at the end of the statement by Jim Vowels he says Until then then being when the policy is released officially We respectfully request that Responsible media and opinion shapers assist us in putting the rumors to rest and hold further questions on this matter Until after the actual final policy has been announced.
Scott: I just want to ask if he was here.
Scott: I just asked him.
Scott: so you're accusing your own artist Ally head of spreading rumors.
Scott: Is that what you're saying?
Scott: and you probably say yeah, I
Rym: Mean, I'm not sure I I mean, I don't know the staff I don't know what's actually going on behind the scenes but it from my experience with similar events and similar types of organizations, my best guess is that the the decision to announce it was made by the head of the artist Ally and it was probably a mistake.
Rym: and now the president and everyone else are working damage control and Dealing with the consequences and they're probably rewriting the policy to be either be the same But then explain it or just rewriting it or scrapping it and I guess we'll just see what happens.
Rym: Yeah, you can't really comment anymore until Otakon actually releases the final policy.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Yeah, but people got to work on their PR skills.
Scott: No matter what the policy is.
Scott: That's all I'm saying.
Rym: Don't piss people off and remember that people are real easy to piss off on the internet.
Rym: Yeah I mean Every time someone's name is posted anywhere like Fark or slashdot and there's someone that people don't like like a DRM guy or a spam Guy their email accounts done.
Rym: just mobs of flaming flaming flaming flamers with trollish tendencies.
Rym: Just attack them.
Scott: Yeah Don't be those guys.
Scott: So Speaking of PR and making announcements.
Scott: I just mentioned a little minute ago Bill Gates.
Scott: Well, he actually did make an announcement today.
Scott: you said Where's the quote?
Scott: The ability to really withhold information no longer exists.
Scott: You may be able to take a very visible website and say that something shouldn't be there But if there is a desire by the population to know something it is going to get out.
Scott: He's basically saying that governments trying to censor the internet are dumb and they they're not going to succeed at all.
Scott: They have no chance.
Rym: That's part of why I think Google seems to be cooperating with China a lot in that they'll block whatever China requests.
Rym: But I'll note that all over the internet.
Rym: it's obvious how trivial it is to even using Google get around those blocks anyway.
Scott: Yeah, but look at this.
Scott: the way I see this is Goo, everyone's looking at Google now saying they're all evil with China, right and they actually the stock dropped a whole bunch.
Scott: now Microsoft which is a competitor somewhat to Google is Taking the other side against Google the side that's supposedly good, you know by Bill Gates saying this maybe he'll get you know.
Rym: Yeah, this is definitely a good PR move on the side of Microsoft.
Scott: Yeah, gonna little boost a little Microsoft stock, you know if it goes down when you you know Try to censor things.
Scott: It'll go up when you say you can't censor things.
Scott: It makes sense though.
Rym: Honestly the stock drop from what I've been reading has a lot more to do with the fact that the stock Skyrocketed and was worth more than it should have been worth.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: Yeah, it was and that the mic Google has twice in recent memory as in within the last month or so Ignored or Congress about various issues.
Scott: Mm-hmm Yeah, that'll always make your stock go down even if you're right.
Scott: But as soon as it's a good bet to do that sort of thing if you think you're gonna win Because when you beat Congress your stock goes crazy through the roof.
Scott: I think Google's a stock drop was pretty well deserved.
Scott: after the little Google video sort of fiasco thing What the hell is the?
Rym: what archive of American television?
Scott: No, no, no, but yeah, we that is terrible.
Rym: What the hell is that?
Scott: yeah, no, but the point is is that Google video came out in recent weeks with the ability to buy episodes of shows on Like NBC shows.
Scott: I think yeah, but it's real in my way kind of annoying Yeah, and basically what happened is at first they didn't do it too Well, they tried to do too much of a simplified Google design.
Scott: You tried to do too much with it so they weren't selling any shows so they changed it to what it is now But they're still not really selling.
Scott: like iTunes is so already the networks that were selling their shows on Google video We're like screw that we're gonna sell it on our own website and in other places too because Google video really
Rym: you know What that's fine in that I wouldn't buy these shows from anyone anywhere.
Scott: Yeah, me either because they're terrible shows.
Scott: I think that's something else people have to realize is that the shows that were being sold on iTunes Were shows that internet people actually wanted to buy.
Scott: well the shows that look like they're being sold on Google video Were shows that like people who don't even know how to use a computer.
Scott: You know are gonna buy.
Rym: So every now and then if I'm in a laundromat and the TV will be on I can't turn it off and I see what's On American TV these days, and it's painful.
Rym: It's painful to watch.
Rym: I can't deal with it.
Scott: Yeah, but the point is is that even Google has admitted that Google video really hasn't lived up in terms of its You know selling of legitimate content.
Rym: Yeah, but in terms of finding videos of explosions or cute kittens?
Scott: Yeah in terms of finding all the funny videos on the internet Google video is the the shit.
Rym: It's all though.
Rym: now there seems to be this trend of a video getting popular.
Rym: That is in no way funny.
Rym: Yeah, what was the one we saw in popular recently?
Rym: was it was a Google video of a kid sitting there like eating some pudding Or yogurt or something?
Rym: it was something slimy and that was it.
Rym: it was like 20 seconds long because you know what it's the people Who?
Scott: Haven't seen all this shit on the internet?
Scott: Imagine if you were brand new to the internet.
Scott: you were an internet virgin and someone brought you up and showed you that video.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: It's a kid eating pudding on the internet.
Rym: What the hell all those face.
Scott: It's.
Scott: you know the never-ending September of Google video.
Rym: You know.
Rym: if any of you out there don't know what the never-ending September is just don't say anything because it'll make me feel old.
Scott: Go to the Wikipedia for never-ending September.
Scott: I'm sure there has to be one.
Rym: I'm sure there is.
Rym: I haven't looked But yeah, that'll.
Scott: that'll tell you what we're talking about.
Scott: So we like hockey ice hockey.
Scott: You know who you are.
Scott: There's a goalie from I think Finland.
Scott: his name is Kari Lettenen.
Scott: I'm pretty sure that's the correct pronunciation And I don't know how good a goalie is.
Scott: I think must be pretty good being in the NHL and playing for the Atlanta Thrashers.
Scott: But you know goalies always have fancy helmets right?
Scott: you know with a bumblebee or a tiger on them or something else cool You know There's a lot of space to work with.
Scott: so they nest they like to paint something nice.
Scott: well Kari Lettenen is apparently a huge gamer like Hardcore and on his helmet.
Scott: He has two characters from Final Fantasy 10, Yuna and Riku.
Scott: Yeah, so if that's not cool I Don't know what to say.
Rym: the link has a nice close-up shot of him wearing this helmet, and it's very obvious.
Rym: There's no way.
Rym: This is something else.
Scott: No.
Scott: No don't it is not even a question.
Scott: if you ask him He'll probably just be like yep.
Scott: That's it.
Rym: So a company called Floran X active in Israel has supposedly come up with a way to Use electricity and a chemical to change the composition of the outer layer of the enamel of your teeth to make them highly resistant to bacteria and acid.
Scott: So wait wait wait.
Rym: you're basically Electroplating your teeth kind of what they do now this I haven't.
Rym: there's no scientific journal on this.
Rym: This is just a kind of a press release thing, but it looks semi legitimate as Far as I know.
Rym: we'll see we'll see, but I think this is legit.
Rym: Basically they use a gel and an electronic electric signal and what they'll do is it'll carry of Fluoride ions into your enamel which will replace the hydroxide ions that are currently there Which is kind of what fluoride does to a smaller scale when you drink fluoridated water.
Scott: So they're basically forcing the fluoride into the teeth.
Rym: basically yeah changes the composition of the mineral layer of that surrounds the teeth and makes them almost invulnerable and You get the treatment every five years.
Rym: you're pretty much immune to cavities except for the ones that are like under your gums.
Scott: so You're electroplating your teeth with fluoride.
Rym: basically they don't have much more about it.
Rym: I'm curious to see how this develops.
Scott: You know if it was if it worked, and it didn't have any nasty side effects like I don't know tooth pain or Tooth pain.
Scott: I have adamantium teeth or perhaps tooth pain, then I would go for it doesn't look like it hurts.
Rym: They kind of done it to some people.
Rym: Really apparently people have been trying to come up with a way to do this exact thing.
Scott: for decades They never thought of electroplating teeth with fluoride.
Rym: They've always thought of it.
Rym: There was never able to do it.
Rym: It's not really electroplating.
Scott: It's the same principle.
Scott: I think it sounds like the same principle.
Rym: I mean they didn't give us any very good technical details on it.
Rym: But the militaries of the world have been contending with the issue of troops getting terrible teeth for forever.
Scott: well Because you lose you can't really brush your teeth in the desert.
Scott: You know it sucks.
Rym: Not only that but soldiers tend to be nervous so their mouth gets dry and when they're out when your mouth is dry That's prime breeding ground for bacteria.
Scott: Yeah, saliva is the is the cleaner of teeth more than anything.
Rym: I mean that's what causes a meth mouth and people who use crystal meth.
Rym: they they'd get dehydrated and then their teeth just rot.
Rym: Mm-hmm and also a lot of our troops recently are in the desert, but that's dry air which doesn't contribute very well.
Rym: No, so there's been a lot of strides in research and tooth care in the military, and this is another one.
Rym: It looks like the Israeli military is gonna jump all over this once.
Rym: It's proven.
Scott: Well.
Scott: You know what if it works out I'll have to do a scientific study of biting power in People who had you in biting.
Scott: what the hell if it gives me more ability to bite.
Rym: It's all good I'm not much ability to bite you actually have.
Scott: What's the purpose of teeth to chew and what is chewing?
Rym: Chewing is not simply a form of biting repeatedly.
Scott: chewing is a rapid and repeated biting Hence.
Rym: anything that improves my functionality of my teeth without you know doing any bad to me is Okay, see I'd be with you if you were say eating meat off of a cow, but you're eating meat off of a plate.
Scott: You know sometimes that meats hard to chew.
Scott: You chew it and chew it and chew it and you make meat gum also.
Rym: now I think I learned the secret.
Scott: you think you learn the secret.
Scott: have you actually performed the secret?
Rym: You realize that I cook meats other than stir-fry and my non stir-fry meats are quite delectable.
Scott: my non stir-fry meats are also Delectable.
Rym: you eat almost no meats.
Scott: I eat plenty of meats.
Rym: Yeah, you won't eat any pork derivative whatsoever bacon.
Rym: You won't eat other than bacon.
Rym: You'll eat bacon.
Rym: You won't eat any of my Sausages or cabasas, I don't like sausages.
Rym: you ever had a beef cabasa.
Rym: No, oh, well, how do you know you don't like it?
Scott: I just don't like most wiener meats This one.
Rym: How do you know it doesn't taste completely different?
Scott: because I know you don't know.
Scott: I do know you know.
Rym: Yeah, I never had it.
Rym: You don't know I know.
Rym: provide me some evidence.
Scott: It's not a provable thing so I guess science can't go there.
Scott: There's no way to prove it or disprove it.
Rym: so anyway Today we thought we'd talk about the toys of our youth.
Scott: Yeah Our shows of our youth is pretty popular and we stopped at what.
Scott: when did we?
Scott: what show did we stop on?
Rym: I don't remember.
Scott: we did the shows of like our early youth like the Sesame Street's right and After that we watched more shows, but all those shows are really just toys Animated.
Scott: so I figured since that was a good episode that people seem to like we would just do toys of our youth Which is sort of also the sequel to shows of our youth because it covers the same things like I don't know.
Rym: transformers yeah mask Voltron Thundercats Thundercats Ninja Turtles Ninja Turtles a lot of Ninja Turtles GI Joe.
Rym: I didn't have so many Joes at all, but I'm just saying what I had though at army men.
Scott: I had a little green army I had so many army men matchbox cars.
Rym: Oh, I was.
Scott: What is also see what's the difference between matchbox cars and Hot Wheels, I don't know But I didn't.
Rym: so I have no idea.
Scott: I think one is made by Mattel and another one is made by some other company.
Rym: all I know is I think I had both.
Rym: I just had a whole pile of them.
Scott: Yeah, I just I bought what cars look cool.
Scott: I didn't care if they were matchbox or Hot Wheels or Oh micro machines.
Rym: Yeah, I was about to say cuz matchbox cars were awesome But there wasn't so much non car stuff to go with it.
Scott: well because the micro machines all what they would do.
Scott: Know the Hot Wheels and matchbox cars.
Scott: what they would do is you get these ramps and you would always send them down the ramp.
Scott: Yeah Or you'd push them around a track or there would be a thing with a spinny rubber bit that would.
Scott: that would shoot them out.
Scott: Yeah, we make them do a jump.
Scott: Oh the car wash.
Scott: There's a car wash for them.
Rym: Yeah I had.
Scott: that didn't actually work, so I didn't work so well But that was a popular toy that I knew people who had it, but I had it and it was awesome.
Scott: Anyway, yeah, but Micro machines had like cities you could drive around and it had.
Rym: Remember waffle blocks?
Rym: No, oh wow waffle blocks were these big.
Rym: they were about a foot by a foot and they were just big flat Squarish objects and they pieced together and you could make large structures with them.
Rym: No, like large enough to make a boat and then sit in it or make a giant cube and put yourself in it Stairway higher than your mom would like you to and then fall off of it.
Scott: Well, we usually did is at my friend's house.
Scott: He had these basically what were cardboard bricks.
Scott: It was just a cardboard.
Rym: Oh, yeah, we had those two.
Scott: It was just a cardboard rectangle basically that folded.
Scott: It was a these a cardboard that folded into a rectangular Thing and it the outside of it was painted to look like a brick.
Scott: and you said a whole mess of them because they were Cheap as crap.
Rym: We throw them at each other.
Scott: Yeah, you just we just made stuff out of them.
Scott: and then you usually took one of those little Fisher price cars that was powered by your feet, you know, not the power wheels which are cool But you know the little indoor ones had like the yellow roof with the little.
Rym: oh, yeah Yeah, I had one of those.
Rym: it was red with a yellow roof.
Rym: Yeah It's like a little funny car steering wheel didn't even do anything.
Scott: steering wheel doesn't do anything.
Scott: You just you Flintstones it, you know.
Scott: You just push your legs in the ground to go and you drive that right through the brick wall.
Scott: And that was the like the funnest thing in the world.
Rym: I always put my brother in it and push him through the brick wall.
Scott: Yeah, that was good.
Scott: pushing pushing help to make it go fast.
Rym: Well the box where I guess a step more sophisticated I'll look online.
Rym: You'll see him.
Rym: But basically there were these mini waffle blocks.
Rym: I don't know if they were called something else But the road pieces that came with them because they little road pieces you can make a lot of houses and stuff out of them Were exactly two lanes for micro machines Really?
Rym: Thus I would always build like the micro machine city with all my micro gene sets and Then I'd build like the suburbs with these things.
Rym: It was high quality.
Scott: Yeah, that was always a problem when like toy you wanted toys to play with each other, but they were incompatible somehow like Thundercats and Lego man really didn't go together.
Scott: Well because Lion.
Scott: Oh, it was like really tall and the Lego men were kind of small.
Rym: Yep, but then you get those crazy by chance.
Rym: a toy works better with a different thing than you'd expect and that's when when fun Happens.
Rym: Yeah, my best story involving that is alright.
Rym: I had masked toys.
Rym: and say what you will about the show.
Rym: masked toys were frickin awesome.
Rym: They were much higher quality than transformers.
Rym: They were just cars that transformed into things usually into bigger flying things with missiles coming out of them.
Scott: Yeah, not into robots with heads But no.
Rym: and they also had little guys that sat in him and it could stay in him while they transform.
Rym: But the guys were like four inches tall five inches tall and they had masks that you could put on them.
Rym: yeah, it's called mask and The coolest thing was that the technodrome from the Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles set.
Rym: The turtles didn't really fit in it.
Rym: I had the technodrome and I had all the turtles toys and the turtles were just really kind of big and ungainly in there.
Rym: you Couldn't even play with it.
Scott: Yeah, I had the.
Scott: I think we already talked about this.
Scott: I had the Thundercats layer the cats layer.
Rym: Yeah I didn't know.
Scott: Thundercats guys only kind of fit in it like there was certain parts where they were meant to fit in But you couldn't really move them around in there and play with them.
Rym: See the mask bases were really high quality.
Rym: They were huge in there and you could.
Rym: they had little chairs and stuff made all just like hanging out.
Rym: But the technodrome.
Rym: I basically turned that into my masked men's Death Star and they'd roam around wreaking havoc upon the Lego man.
Scott: I never had the technodrome.
Scott: I don't know anyone at the technodrome.
Rym: technodrome was probably one of the highest quality little toys I remember from that era.
Scott: I know you had the Ninja Turtles sewer, which was excellent.
Rym: I had that as well.
Rym: It had the spiky ball.
Rym: Yeah drop into the pipe.
Scott: That was exactly the toy.
Rym: My problem was I had one foot soldier and then four turtles and Casey Jones and April and then splinter and the shredder.
Scott: Yeah, my brother was really the one who got all the Ninja Turtles toys But it was cool because I was still playing with them or whatever.
Rym: Actually, I think they're.
Rym: technically they were.
Rym: my mask was mine and the turtles were my brothers.
Rym: Yeah, we both played with them both all the time.
Scott: Oh, yeah, it was just whatever but I think the kid down the street I'd like three foot soldiers and we had one or two and another kid had a couple.
Scott: so we ended up with enough.
Scott: But it wasn't like, you know, if I was gonna play Star Wars, I would need at least 50 stormtroopers or something.
Rym: You know has bugged me though about the Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles.
Rym: the turtles themselves were high quality and so were their sets Except for the turtles on motorcycles thing, which I don't get.
Rym: this trend of take a character and put them on a motorcycle I don't get it either.
Rym: We saw a Darth Vader one I mean.
Scott: when you looked at the Ninja Turtles figures we had we have one of every guy.
Scott: normally we had splinter Casey Jones April shredder bebop rocksteady right all the normal characters.
Scott: then we had like Donatello the fireman and I didn't have any of those.
Scott: we had Michelangelo like the skateboarder and we had All kinds of crazy stuff.
Scott: actually Donatello the fireman was one of the best quality toys.
Rym: But what always pissed me off about the turtles was that they were high quality.
Rym: How come the weapons that came with them were these flimsy?
Rym: Tiny brown plastic unpainted little pieces of crap.
Scott: I agree.
Scott: They always got lost.
Rym: I lost all of them within about a minute.
Scott: There is nothing worse than a toy which a does not stand up on its own in any position Ah, and B cannot hold its weapons properly.
Rym: I mean I'm okay with like a big thing that shoots a tiny little missile that you'll lose.
Rym: Cuz kids are smart and they won't shoot them, you know behind the couch.
Rym: We know better.
Rym: Ah Yeah, yeah, but if there's nowhere to actually put that little missile and it just sits there hmm The worst that also is when you want to like share weapons between toys Like never worked.
Scott: a he-man figure is about the same size as a Ninja Turtles figure which is about the same size Is I don't know Robocop Thundercat.
Rym: I had all the Robocop toys Don't you flip their backs and they have caps in them?
Scott: I guess anyway, you know all action figures are about the same size.
Scott: but if you could get you know Leonardo to hold the sword of omens or if you could get He-man to hold it like Donatello's stick.
Rym: I Didn't know you were into that sort of thing.
Scott: But if you can get that to happen the winner is you.
Rym: No, I think the winner is a Donatello.
Rym: Maybe You Know actually for in terms of guys that held guns The Robocop toys.
Rym: if you ignore the gimmick of the fact that you put a roll of caps in their back And then you could flick it and they would shoot meaning they'd make a lot of noise and piss your parents off.
Rym: God, my parents.
Rym: I hated me.
Rym: I think that was.
Scott: the purpose of most toys is to piss parents.
Scott: It was like hey kids This your parents off in the store to make them buy you this and then piss them off with it and make them regret it.
Rym: But the characters came with their little guns were high-quality and well done and they fit into their hands and didn't fall out.
Rym: And also my parents were smart this time as was in the Ninja Turtles and they bought me a million of the bad guys and Then I had Robocop and he killed them all Really?
Scott: I figured I would make Robocop lose.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I liked Robocop.
Rym: I looked up to him as a kid.
Scott: Oh, you should have gotten the Terminator to kick his ass.
Rym: I didn't have any Terminator - I didn't have any Terminators either You know.
Rym: thinking back though, I can't recall many of the scenarios I put my various action guys into.
Scott: I Can recall a few of the scenario?
Rym: I just I remember most of what I was doing as just like I'd have two characters and I like I got hold Donatello with this thing and then he hit another guy with it and then I'd like make that guy fall down.
Scott: I would usually try.
Scott: you know how nerds will sometimes argue like aha if there was a fight between a Hypothetical battle between this fictional thing and this fictional thing What would happen?
Scott: right?
Scott: and I would be all I would try to like figure it out Like I'd be like, all right He tries to punch him but he can do this and then he would try to hit him with the sword up But he can do this and then he tries to And then it eventually somewhat I'd be like up Oh, that is the winner.
Rym: and then I would make like a little tournament or something I always did like the good guys Ganging up to get the bad guys Especially with the mask figures because the good guys and the bad guys each had their own base.
Rym: I gave the bad guys the technodrome and the good guys had like Boulder Mountain and there always be infighting in the good guys.
Rym: and Then what like one guy would always like try to be the hero and get killed and then everyone else would be like, oh And then they'd fight back and mmm It took some priming but it's all starting to come back to me.
Scott: You played with more toys and just action figures though, right?
Scott: I think we had slot cars are always cool.
Rym: Oh, I had two different sets of slot cars and actually I had model trains like old-school model.
Scott: I had one model train.
Scott: I actually had two.
Scott: one of them was all fancy like a bullet train with lights and shit and that was a piece of crap.
Scott: It didn't work.
Scott: Then I got a real train where he screwed tracks down to a piece of wood a giant oval Yeah, and then put the train on it with the fake smoke and everything and I only used it a few times But I had it.
Rym: Well I had from when my parents were kids I had this old like three-track electric train set that was old and metal and heavy and difficult to use.
Scott: Mine weren't that difficult to use
Rym: but the things I had more fun with I don't know what they're called at all but they were Really really really realistic trains and these little snap together tracks and a million things to go with him and they weren't powered at all Like you had to do everything manually with your hands
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I don't remember any more than that.
Rym: I don't know what they were called or anything, but they were awesome.
Scott: Yeah, there were quite a few toys that I remember having and not remembering exactly what they were Like not so much action figures, but other things Like what was that thing?
Scott: That was like a ball with a disc.
Scott: It looked like the planet Saturn but you would stand on it.
Scott: Oh and then you jump and then you jumped and you held.
Scott: you grabbed the ball with your feet and you just keep jumping And then you could do stuff.
Rym: I remember seeing that when it first appeared on TV and thinking it was the stupidest thing ever I didn't understand the point of it But my friend had and I remember trying like that jump rope thing where you put it around one leg.
Scott: Oh, that's skip it skip.
Scott: It's actually fun.
Rym: No skip.
Rym: It's not fun.
Scott: Skip it is fun.
Scott: The thing about skip it though that sucks.
Scott: It's it's supposed to count the number of times you skip didn't work.
Scott: No that part totally sucks.
Scott: it doesn't do that for shit because the way it does that is you're supposed to roll the end the weighted end of the Skip it on the ground and every time it spins around It'll count one, you know.
Scott: So usually you would get it swinging up in the air and it wouldn't touch the ground and then it wouldn't count.
Scott: So the count was worthless.
Rym: I remember moon shoes.
Scott: Oh god, I saw those on TV and I said that's a gimmick I'm not buying it.
Rym: They came out and they were quite quickly recalled for the fact that kids frickin busted their heads open with them.
Scott: Yeah, well, there was that other Nickelodeon stuff the slime or the goop.
Scott: It wasn't goop.
Scott: It wasn't the actual slime.
Rym: It was like this other stuff, you know, my brother actually got slimed at Nickelodeon.
Scott: Yeah, so did a bunch of people.
Scott: It's pretty common I mean, let's like think what they bring in a hundred people in there at a time and they do it like a hundred times a day.
Rym: Yeah, but it's cool.
Rym: They got a little certificate like I've been slimed with the real slime.
Scott: It's just applesauce and green food coloring.
Rym: I've heard that he didn't try to eat it.
Scott: Yeah, they try to give it.
Rym: all I remember is they let him take a shower and they wash his clothes But they didn't dry his underwear all the way and he was pissed off for the rest of the day.
Scott: bastards.
Scott: I Would totally be pissed off and demand they dry my underwear all the way.
Scott: But did he have to stand there naked while they dried his clothes, oh no, they him a robe or something?
Rym: I don't remember.
Rym: That was a long time ago.
Scott: He's taking the robe.
Scott: Go away with the official Nickelodeon robe The one cool.
Rym: So I remember.
Rym: I don't know what these were called either but they were like these I beams and such and you could make like a skeletal building structure or a tower or something.
Rym: and Then they had other devices that you could use to demolish them Mm-hmm.
Rym: They were fairly high quality.
Rym: Once again, I don't remember what they were called.
Scott: I had constructs which were like Is another building toy and you would have basically sticks and little connecty bits and the connecty bits like.
Rym: What like connects?
Rym: no like tinker toys.
Scott: It's sort of like connects in that it sticks that connect at the end.
Scott: But constructs have a different connecting mechanism and everything is nice and square and and uh-huh You could build a really strong stuff with it really easily and it was good for like Spaceships and spacemen and that sort of thing.
Rym: I've noticed I don't really see connects or Tinker toys around so much anymore.
Scott: I see you can get a basic set of Lincoln logs.
Scott: still Lincoln logs.
Scott: actually I Had a lot of fun with Lincoln logs.
Rym: I'm a giant freaking Enormous amazing structures with Lincoln law.
Scott: I didn't have it.
Scott: I never had enough Lincoln logs.
Scott: All I could make was a cabin.
Rym: Well, I had enough.
Rym: I actually made like and a four large Cabins that would be level like a flat roof and then there'd be other cabins on top that had like multiple towers.
Scott: I didn't have enough Lincoln logs for that.
Rym: I Once saw my brother and I tried to make the tallest structure we could make.
Rym: I think it was two or three hundred Lincoln log units tall in the end and then it fell over and we almost cried If you want to make something big the key do blows man.
Rym: Oh god do blows.
Rym: I had do blows all over the place.
Scott: We had a giant thing of do blows.
Scott: But when we got into Lego not Legos Lego, you know what it's Legos.
Rym: Yeah, let him sue me.
Rym: I'll bring it.
Scott: Yeah, go to Legos calm and you'll see what we're talking about.
Scott: Legos calm www.legos.com.
Scott: if you go to le go calm you'll get something different.
Rym: but Lego pretty much Dominated my childhood in way other than Nintendo and Atari in ways that I can't even begin to describe.
Scott: Yes, I think we should keep Lego for it's a separate episode because I agree so big we'll do a whole episode on Lego.
Rym: Yeah, Legos.
Scott: I think nerf might also take a separate episode.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Oh, I felt so gypped.
Rym: So the nerf bow and arrow, I'll just tell this story.
Rym: Remember the nerf bow and arrow which you don't see the original nerf bow and arrow anymore for sale Which bothers me because it was probably the best nerf toy ever made.
Scott: Probably maybe the ball Zuka stands up there.
Rym: ball Zuka was quality and the arrow storm was awesome.
Rym: Yeah, the arrow storm was just the ball Zuka of the arrows, but yes Yeah See what I did is I modified my arrow storm to shoot the little orange ones from a later gun called like the razor bag Or so one day one that the suction cup there.
Scott: Yeah, cuz there's a cup darts bolts and our little arrows and big arrows.
Scott: That's those are the nerf weapons.
Rym: Yeah, wait bolts.
Rym: Those are the black ones, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I remember I had the black ones.
Scott: I use the one that's the sidearm.
Scott: It has three black Yes, and you pump it to shoot each one you with the power of air.
Scott: But then there was the suction pistol that you could cock it and have it ready to fire, dude We had like the suction like SMG rifle You'd put a suction dart in the front and pull the whole giant spring-loaded contraption And it would lock.
Scott: and then you when you pulled the trigger it shot a single suction cup dart like freaking hard like BAM Pulled this spring back like six inches.
Scott: It was crazy.
Rym: All right, you know what?
Rym: Yeah, we're gonna do a whole show on nerf, too.
Rym: Yeah, but finish my anecdote.
Rym: Oh my god They sold out when the nerf bow and arrow came out for those of you who are too young to know it sold out immediately.
Rym: Parents were fighting with each other like I know what toy we're talking about next.
Rym: Oh, yeah Oh god, like parents fought with each other and there were lawsuits and oh my god, and my parents only found one and Me and my brother.
Rym: there were two of us and they knew that they couldn't arm one of us and leave the other one out hanging Mm-hmm.
Rym: So apparently they decided for whatever reason they gave my brother the nerf bow and arrow and I got this knockoff Robin Hood bow and arrow and it shot.
Rym: actually the arrows that shot were harder and they felt like higher quality But it was an actual bow and arrow.
Rym: as in you pull the string back and let go and those arrows flew Maybe half the distance.
Rym: the nerf bow and arrow did.
Scott: my brother pooned me in a royal way Yeah, but at least the foam darts didn't hurt Yeah, so speaking of toys that are Weaponry based that sell out The super soaker.
Rym: Oh my god That was for once again for those of you who were too young when the super soaker appeared That was a revolution.
Scott: Think about this.
Scott: water fights to that day were simply balloons, which is still the deadliest weapon on the field.
Scott: Yes, right?
Scott: The little tiny squirt guns which were fun when there wasn't anything bigger on the field.
Scott: or those one-shot bazookas Yeah, where you fill it up in the pool and then you pull it back with you know And you squeeze all the water out in this one-shot bazooka thing.
Rym: now I always carried three squirt guns on me.
Rym: back in the day I had my bazooka which was full and strapped around my back just ready to go Mm-hmm.
Rym: I had a. I had a normal like sidearm rifle II thing.
Rym: That was a normal crap squirt gun, you know the clear plastic ones.
Rym: and then I had one that took batteries.
Rym: It was an SMG that took a little.
Scott: those always sucked.
Rym: Oh, it sucked ass.
Rym: it fired like ten shots and it was done and it by these tiny tiny wussy shots.
Scott: But it made a fun noise.
Scott: Those are more fun as toys to play with without the water.
Rym: Actually mine broke almost right away and then I used it as a normal toy.
Scott: Yeah, but don't forget the garden hose.
Rym: No, the garden hose was always like banned.
Scott: No We always had the garden hose is out there and people would get it and then become the king And everyone else wouldn't just run away far out of range.
Scott: They would try to get.
Rym: I remember some kids didn't get it.
Rym: like some kids would like shoot me in the chest.
Rym: It depend on what kind of fighting we were playing.
Rym: Sometimes we play.
Rym: Oh you were hit you're out blah blah blah.
Rym: But a lot of times kids were like shoot me in the chest and I shoot them in the eye and I won.
Scott: So one day I because when you were a little kid you always looked in a little Toys R Us circular in the newspaper on Sunday Whatever you saw the Super Soaker in there.
Scott: It was yellow and green.
Scott: You might know it as the Super Soaker 50.
Scott: It was the original Super Soaker.
Scott: There was nothing before this and it had this green little Barrel.
Scott: What do you want to get?
Rym: jar cylinder?
Scott: I guess cylinder tank tank.
Rym: There you go And you pumped it up and It pressurized and I didn't get what the big deal was because I saw that I saw a picture of it.
Scott: I said that's a water gun.
Scott: That's the silliest looking water gun I ever seen but a piece of junk.
Scott: It's just a gimmick.
Scott: then I saw it on TV and I was like It's just a gimmick.
Scott: then as soon as one kid on the block got one everyone ran to the toy store immediately.
Rym: because I guess the revolution was until that point the I mean Basically the only dominating weapon on the field other than water balloons Which are kind of rare because our parents would always make us pick up the leavings afterward.
Scott: Yeah No one ever actually bought water balloons.
Rym: So every now and then someone I had a friend who had a water balloon slingshot some kid would go somewhere and he'd get the ones That look like grenades.
Rym: Those were terrible.
Rym: They were you gotta get normal balloons fill them up and drop them on someone.
Rym: Yep but I mean you pull the trigger and it'd be one little squirt and it would barely go anywhere and you had to keep pulling and Pulling and pulling and pulling and the bazooka was great, but you had one shot and then you were done.
Scott: You couldn't actually get anyone wet.
Rym: the super soaker was a bazooka that just kept firing for as long as you held that trigger down.
Scott: You can just hold it down to this.
Scott: constant stream of water came out.
Scott: It wasn't the biggest stream of water, but you could pump keep I would think I'm thinking until the release valve went.
Rym: Yeah, and I'd know all right.
Rym: I'm at maximum capacity.
Scott: It built mad arm strength and little kids.
Rym: Let me tell you though I got to say I remember many moments where like my opponent wouldn't would not be pumping up continuously throughout the battle and He'd start to slack in and then I'd have more range than him.
Rym: and that was the end.
Scott: Yeah, remember it was called the super soaker 50 because it shot up to 50 feet.
Scott: Well, uh, then the super soaker 100 came out, you know Let me tell you the story about the super soaker 100. see we went to the store to get a super soaker 50 for me to compete with the neighborhood kids with their 50s and The toy works which is the store at the Times.
Rym: Mmm, that's why I had an onion on my belt.
Scott: Yep, of course.
Scott: It was a white onion, whatever.
Scott: They were sold out of 50s, of course, of course makes angry in the Turlet.
Scott: All right, that's just two three Three references in like a minute.
Scott: Okay They were sold out of 50s.
Scott: while we were standing in the store in the morning a shipment of super soakers came in.
Scott: all of them were a hundreds and It wasn't too difficult to get my mom to buy me the hundred because there were no fifties.
Rym: now before Scott describes his Dominance of the battlefield that ensued from having this this brand new weapon I mean this is like in civilization too when you get gunpowder and all your well.
Rym: No, no, no, the super soaker 50 was gunpowder versus non gunpowder, you know Musketeers versus Knights kenigits.
Rym: as Scott says the super soaker hundred was when you got riflemen.
Scott: the super soaker 100 had The first water gun ever with the reserve pressurization tank.
Rym: So you'd pump it up and it would fill both of your tanks with pressure.
Scott: Well, no what?
Scott: that's not what it would do at all.
Rym: Actually now it would because if you pumped it wrong, you could see the bubbles coming into the reserve tank.
Scott: No, no No, that's when you're pumping it right.
Scott: you see the way it worked is.
Scott: there was the front tank Which is just where you stored all your water.
Scott: All right, and but normally the super soaker 50 Pressurizes that main tank Right and then you release the pressure from it until it kind of loses its stuff and that's it.
Scott: and because it's so big And it has all your water in it.
Scott: It's not really, you know, it doesn't work.
Scott: It's like a direct system.
Rym: Well, it has two main problems one when you refuel, you know put water back in While you're filling your thing up you're done You have no way to protect yourself.
Rym: and two once you fill it in you have to then pump it up before you can shoot.
Scott: Yeah, now I remember holding down the trigger and pumping simultaneously super circle 100 behind the main tank of water Which is bigger than the tank of water on the super soaker 50 was a small like ball.
Scott: It was like the size of a baseball.
Scott: It was another tank and you never open that tank.
Scott: it stayed closed all the time.
Scott: You didn't open it You didn't do anything to it now.
Scott: when you pumped it would take water From a reservoir from the main tank.
Scott: All right and put it into that little ball.
Scott: now the little ball was already filled with air also from your pumping and The ball also had a much thicker plastic than the main water reservoir tank.
Scott: So basically you would fill this little ball up with water and air to the point of it exploding.
Rym: Yeah And the thing is the super soakers you couldn't actually make them explode.
Rym: now that I'm older and I realize there's a rubber hose that went through it where the water and everything came out and the trigger Released a. basically there's a pin like constricting the flow so nothing could get out.
Scott: It was like when you kink the garden hose bite, you know, and when you pull the trigger it unkinks the garden hose.
Rym: Yep But if you put too much pressure It would leak out a little bit through the kink and then it would like maintain a solid steady not blow up and kill a kid Pressure.
Scott: Yeah, but if you somehow modify the trigger to keep that kink there no matter what pressure comes out, you know, you can Destroy yourself.
Rym: Yeah, you'll die.
Scott: Yeah, but anyway you had this reserve tank that you would fill with water and pressure and when you released it Not only was it more powerful than the 50 not only did it shoot farther with more water for a greater amount of time But you could take the main tank off because it wasn't pressurized at all Fill it up with water again while you were shooting the water out of the reserve tank.
Scott: So whatever all the kids are gathered around the hose to refill you just shoot them up.
Rym: and then I saw they started selling Extra tanks.
Rym: Yeah, they came in a little like backpack thing and you could have a two extra backup tanks on you.
Scott: There was even one super soaker that they eventually had.
Rym: It was like the 200 or I don't know what it was.
Scott: It had the quick replacement tanks that you didn't have to screw in.
Scott: you could just snap them in and out and you could fill them by jamming them In the into this attachment at the end of the garden hose.
Scott: so at the end of the garden hose is a little like launch pad and you would stick the end of the bottle in there and It would fill it up real quick and you can just pull bottles out of your gun and throw them away and stick new ones In like click click.
Scott: it was like, you know Almost as fast as switching like magazines in an assault rifle.
Rym: Of course.
Rym: this arms race of super soakers eventually met its end with the final one that I cared about.
Rym: I I be any super soaker beyond this one was when I didn't play with super soakers anymore Mm-hmm.
Rym: It was a backpack filled with like multiple gallons of water and A giant gun and they were connected and you pumped it up like a super soaker and it was the most dangerous thing in the world Except for the fact that the kid wearing it and I remember the kid named Dave my neighborhood whose parents got it for him He couldn't even move in the thing.
Rym: It weighed so much.
Scott: See, I remember that one, but no one actually got that.
Scott: there was the.
Scott: let's see which other ones Do I remember.
Scott: there was the one that had two barrels and it was like two super soaker hundreds attached to each other But with the XP technology.
Scott: remember they had these super You know XP was.
Rym: it just emptied your tank.
Scott: Well, it emptied your tank and basically the barrels were twice as wide.
Scott: So your spray was more powerful and got people more wet.
Scott: It was extra wetness is what it was, but it also emptied your tank a little faster.
Scott: So whatever.
Scott: But then came the.
Scott: my brother had the biggest XP super soaker.
Scott: It was basically this it looked like a giant laser rifle for Makira And it emptied in about four or five full power shots Maybe even three if you if you pumped it up real all the way and had like a pressure meter and everything.
Scott: But the when it shot it shot about Had to be at least a liter of water in a blast Like a half an inch wide.
Scott: and then of course came the whatever that giant was.
Scott: We saw a freshman year of college.
Scott: That was like two giant the monster XXL.
Scott: That was it.
Rym: See that was the point when I had moved on from water gun fights to pranking people.
Rym: Yeah, and instead of having a water fight We had a water balloon slingshot and we would launch water balloons at our friend's house like around the corner and down the street.
Scott: Yeah went by the time the monster came out super soakers were done.
Scott: That was it.
Scott: It was too much.
Rym: of course in that same era nerf which we'll do another show on had many water fight enabled nerf weapons.
Rym: There were a lot of arrows that had a sponge on the end that you could dip in water and held a lot of water.
Rym: Surprisingly and if you hit someone with it, they were just talking wet.
Rym: it was So.
Scott: when I was real little my favorite toy was a glow worm.
Rym: I was a big fan of my light.
Rym: bright.
Scott: Light brights good.
Scott: That's where you put the pegs in the thing that lights up.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, that goes with Etch-a-sketch and magnet oodle.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: No magnet oodle was awesome.
Rym: Ours wore out.
Rym: from years.
Scott: ours wore out.
Scott: magnet oodle seemed to always wear out.
Scott: You keep buying new ones.
Rym: It's like a piece of crap - I used to manually play a little Sim City on mine.
Rym: I draw everything bit by bit as I built it up.
Scott: Oh, wow.
Rym: Yeah, I was a geeky little kid.
Scott: Yeah, that's crazy.
Rym: Actually a game that I played a lot as a child was hero quest.
Rym: Mmm, I blame that for a lot of my interest in role-playing games today because my dad got hero quest and he would be the master for me and my little brother and We played through that whole game and eventually we kicked Evil's ass and it was over.
Rym: Mm-hmm All I remember is that I swear to you.
Rym: my little brother cheated stole the game.
Rym: Read the book found out where that Boris's or borax whatever armor was.
Rym: because when we got to the level and we knew from the clues from the old man that the Armor was somewhere there He friggin runs right to the room.
Rym: He was in and gets it.
Scott: Yeah, he read the book.
Rym: Yeah, he denies it to this day.
Rym: But god damn it.
Rym: I was the barbarian I needed that arm only he'll deny it today.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: He was now if he had spells.
Rym: What does he need armor for?
Rym: Mm-hmm Of course I had an axe so I got him.
Scott: then he just chopped him up and took the armor.
Rym: No, actually, no, I didn't know was No, the board games.
Scott: I played I was a little kid were like dino bones.
Scott: God candy land candy land all that stuff.
Rym: I like monopoly a lot when I was a little kid.
Scott: Yeah, me too I like.
Scott: I guess I like that stuff when I was little but not anymore.
Rym: Actually, one of my favorite games was don't break the ice don't break.
Scott: The ice is a good game.
Rym: cooties Didn't?
Rym: I actually never played cooties?
Scott: And I don't remember how to play cooties.
Scott: I think I might have played it once but it's in the same series as don't break the ice don't spill the beans.
Scott: No the beans, which is I don't know how to play that but it had a pair of pants that you filled with beans.
Rym: Yeah, there's also ants in the pants.
Scott: Oh, maybe I'm confusing those two games.
Rym: Yeah I don't know what you're talking about.
Rym: pants filled with beans I guess I confused.
Scott: don't spill the beans and ants in the pants And just beans in the pants.
Scott: Don't spill the ants, I don't know.
Rym: we had this memory game.
Rym: I forgot it was called but it was like remembering things.
Rym: game and my little brother.
Rym: I don't know what it was, but he would kick our entire family's ass no matter what was it called?
Scott: Memory might have been because there was a board game called memory.
Rym: Will you go around?
Rym: you have to remember like it's like the card games and like mario 3.
Scott: Yeah, exactly Yeah, that's all.
Scott: the game was was that with pictures on cards.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Oh, what about pop goes perfection?
Scott: That game you said the timer you to put all the pieces in the holes and then push the stop button.
Rym: I had the versus one.
Rym: Oh, you have two people and they're rare images of each other and it had the best game mechanic ever.
Rym: well other than you know Tigers and Euphrates game mechanics, but basically if You know in perfection if you don't make it in time it like pops up and scares the shit out of you.
Rym: Mm-hmm this one when you finish well one there was a timer and if it ran out it pops it up on both of you.
Rym: But as soon as you finish you had a button you get hit on your side a big spacebar and it popped the other guy.
Scott: Yes, of course, you could pop the other guy right away and you know what.
Rym: then they'd hit you.
Scott: Yeah, that goes to Simon - ah Simon.
Scott: I never got Simon.
Scott: I was played at other people's houses, but it I got over real quick.
Rym: Yeah, my friend Joe Oglesby had.
Rym: I didn't actually have it.
Rym: I was pretty good at it.
Rym: I liked it.
Scott: It was okay, but it's not a toy that you can play with for a long time.
Rym: He had this toy.
Rym: It was an afterburner type game.
Rym: It was a video game But it's one of those.
Rym: you buy a VHS tape and you play it And then you have this thing the light gun that you like pointed the screen and you have to shoot the tail Jets of planes going by and had some sort of pseudo optical reader on it.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and he thought it was awesome But it was kind of dumb.
Scott: Yeah, I never liked any of those VHS games.
Scott: Of course what I did like that we only played once ever was actually really dumb.
Scott: It's one of those the game where you have the little football man.
Scott: you set them up and then it vibrates.
Rym: Oh my brother wanted that for most of his life like.
Rym: he'd see it on TV and he'd see it in the Sears catalog and he'd be like I want it.
Rym: it's the best thing ever.
Rym: and Finally one day my parents got it for like for Christmas.
Rym: There's a big deal.
Rym: We set it up and we ran it and then he he was the most crestfallen kid I've ever seen Mm-hmm.
Rym: It just.
Rym: it was like wait a minute.
Scott: They just Move around randomly, you know something you want to hear something real scary.
Scott: My family actually.
Scott: we played that once Which is me and my brother and my dad versus my uncle and my cousins.
Scott: We actually played like a whole football came out on that thing.
Scott: It was great.
Scott: We like did a little we passed and we made plays and it was great.
Rym: See we were really big into you know, spinny hockey.
Rym: Oh, yeah, we had one of those.
Rym: we played it often.
Rym: That's why I'm so good at it.
Scott: Oh, we didn't have one of those we had.
Scott: we also had we had knock hockey.
Scott: Knock hockey was the shit.
Scott: Ah And I should probably try to get a knock hockey table.
Scott: they're hard to get now.
Rym: we had actually no kids.
Scott: they're getting one.
Rym: We had a bumper pool table when I was real young which wasn't.
Rym: I wasn't old enough to use it But then we got a real pool table.
Scott: Nope It seemed like everyone we knew had one except us and we had a foosball table.
Rym: No, but I was never good at foosball.
Rym: My little brother was a frickin foosball prodigy.
Rym: No, I remember when I was little and indignant I never would play against him because he'd always beat me and he'd always get mad because I wouldn't play against him.
Scott: It was also a crossfire.
Rym: Crossfire was the most awesome game.
Scott: Oh my I mean you just put these two little basically these metal marbles and his playing field.
Scott: and There were two metal marbles crossfire crossfire.
Scott: One metal marble had a plastic chainsaw around it and the other one was a triangle.
Rym: the other one had a plastic triangle and that One was a lot harder to move.
Scott: Yeah, one guy was the triangle and one guy was the chainsaw.
Scott: And what you tried to do was you had this gun that would shoot the metal marbles from your side to the other guy's Side and you could take marbles from your side and put them in your gun to reload.
Rym: the gun would jam easily.
Scott: You had to be mad skilled yeah, so you would shoot these metal marbles at the triangle and the chainsaw trying to push them to the other guy's side and It was fun a lot of fun.
Rym: See well, my brother and I played a different because we couldn't agree because no one ever wanted to be the chainsaw.
Rym: so we just played as Both of them shoot them both in either direction and the first one person to have any one of them fall into their side loses.
Scott: Oh, just go everyone just go for the chainsaw and screw the triangle.
Rym: No, cuz I'd edge the triangle over there bit by bit and it was actually it worked out pretty well.
Scott: Now the thing in that game those once it's too close.
Scott: You can't get it out of there without touching it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah The big problems I always had with the game was one My parents never let me play it because if you've never seen this game first of all Firing an individual BB made a loud clacking noise.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Scott: This game was like click click click click click.
Scott: No, it was like bang bang bang bang bang bang bang bang bang bang.
Rym: We're just crazy screaming noise pieces of plastic wailing against each other and kids yelling and screaming - you would shoot maybe I don't know.
Rym: a hundred thousand of these BB's over the course of one game Mm-hmm, and it was really hard to pull the trigger and I would get blisters early.
Scott: Maybe yours is broken.
Rym: I was hard to pull the trigger unless you wore it like wore it out.
Scott: Well, we never had that problem.
Scott: Maybe it was a different version to the game.
Rym: I might have been cuz all the force all.
Rym: they didn't have a spring or anything.
Rym: It shot the ball by having you pull the trigger against resistance which then pushed the BB out.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: That's what it did.
Rym: Oh Well, there's also that game.
Rym: I figured it was called where you had the ships that you put on a big mat on the floor like a big cardboard board And then you eat.
Rym: each side you had a submarine.
Rym: you flicked little red discs at the other guy's fleet.
Scott: I don't remember that at all.
Rym: It's a really good game except that it also gave me blisters, huh?
Scott: Now I'm remembering things like chutes and ladders.
Scott: That was a good game.
Rym: Not really.
Scott: It was good.
Scott: when you're a little kid It's better than Candyland.
Rym: We always like payday cuz it involved real money.
Rym: It was like it seemed like it was edutainment.
Scott: I remember seeing the board for that game and I see seeing the box but I don't know what that game was.
Rym: It was us now paying our bills.
Rym: Wow, but for a kid who doesn't pay bills, it was awesome.
Scott: Yeah, what else do we have?
Scott: We had free.
Scott: parking was actually a really good game with a monopoly theme.
Scott: That had nothing to do with monopoly except the theme.
Rym: Wait, was that the dice game?
Scott: No, I had nothing to do with dice whatsoever.
Scott: You had a parking meter and you didn't want it to go expire and you'd keep filling the meter.
Scott: But you could also get officer Jones to go get people.
Scott: There's an officer Jones card.
Scott: I think I have the game.
Scott: We'll play it.
Scott: Aha It'll be alright.
Scott: I'm sure it's not the greatest game but Millborn I was about to say Millborn saw the same genre.
Rym: I had a knockoff shareware version on the computer called Miles bones.
Scott: Yeah, we had the real deal.
Rym: It's all right game.
Rym: now that I I'm more versed in German.
Rym: this I'm not so much of a fan of it.
Scott: Yeah, I guess these games really only have nostalgia Factors, you know the old kitty game member of volcano run or whatever it was called?
Rym: No, it was a gimmicky game.
Rym: It was probably the first of the gimmicky games.
Rym: That was really market.
Rym: I thought dizzy-dizzy dinosaur was the first gimmick, you know, this game came out before that.
Scott: I thought mousetrap came out in the 50s.
Rym: Yeah, mousetrap was the first one.
Rym: But this game like stormed the world as a gimmick.
Rym: All right you move guys around on a volcano but huh if the volcano erupts you take a little volcano ball and put at the top and Decide where it comes out and then it rolls along and knocks guys over.
Scott: Oh Remember now.
Scott: Yeah, it reminds me the agro Craig and all the agro Craig.
Scott: anyone doesn't know what that is.
Rym: Shut up Don't make me feel old.
Scott: the Dizzy-dizzy dinosaur was the one where you would move around the board but occasionally you would turn on this little dinosaur and he would spin around and Bump into you and if he bumped into your guy you had to go back to the beginning or something, right?
Rym: Yeah, I don't remember eggs around.
Scott: you're trying to move eggs around the map without getting dizzy-dizzy dinosaur to hit you.
Rym: I remember this alligator dentist.
Rym: We had to pull teeth.
Scott: I remember the alligator dentist.
Scott: I saw the commercials.
Scott: They didn't buy that piece of crap.
Rym: Yeah, I don't think we actually owned it.
Rym: I think one of her little cousins owned it and we had to play it with him.
Scott: The worst Hanukkah ever was when My mom was like, oh I got a good prod I got a good present for the last day right.
Scott: and then on the second last day I'm like, I was looking at the toy catalog and I was like, it's mr.
Scott: Bucket, isn't it?
Scott: It's a toy for everybody.
Scott: You got mr.
Scott: Bucket because you thought it's cute, but it's not and it's gonna be no fun.
Rym: the hell's a mr.
Scott: Bucket, this is the worst thing ever.
Scott: I don't know why my mom thought it was gonna be a good idea.
Scott: It's his bucket right and okay the bucket has.
Scott: It's a robotic bucket and it moves around with wheels on the floor right and it has a mouth with a and the mouth has a hole in it and He has two hands above his head that go like this to keep you from putting things in the bucket.
Scott: Oh god, I saw commercials for that and he opens and closes his eyes all the time.
Scott: now He spits out these balls and you have a shovel and you have to pick up the balls with a shovel and put him In the bucket.
Scott: and if you get all your balls in the bucket, then you win.
Scott: so basically, it's just everyone runs around the room picking up balls and putting them in the bucket and After about two times, it's not fun anymore.
Scott: It's just dumb.
Rym: Wow Yeah, yeah way to go mom Alright, you know what?
Rym: We've talked about this a long time.
Rym: We could talk about it a long time more but stay tuned.
Rym: We'll do a show whenever we get to it on Lego.
Rym: Yeah, like we'll do a separate one on nerf there.
Rym: And that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.