Scott: It's Monday July 31st, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Scott: We go over a list of our favorite Firefox extensions.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Well for anyone who's been living under a rock and hasn't actually been listening to us recently We're going to Otakon this weekend woohoo.
Rym: Now Otakon is probably the highlight of our year for the front row crew every year.
Rym: It is also our largest gathering.
Scott: next year It might be different because we were probably gonna go to other places perhaps Vegas perhaps yerp.
Rym: Well the thing is it's more that no matter what any of us do the front row crew always comes together every year at Otakon and then everyone who can swing it we go to the beach and Or other fun places for what we call the week of fun directly after a week
Scott: of awesome.
Rym: Oh, yes the week of awesome That's right.
Rym: You know what they've been calling it the week of fun and the internal secret front row crew forums lately heathens.
Rym: Yeah, I got to get on that because I realized mr.. Perry doesn't have access to that stuff.
Rym: no, cuz I the other day one of our friend see we have a forum just for you know like our private stuff and There was a point at which someone.
Rym: I'm not gonna say who made a typo, and I was like god.
Rym: Why isn't?
Rym: mr.
Rym: Perry had fixed this.
Rym: it's been here forever, then I realized oh, oh he can't see that cuz he's.
Scott: he's not in the front row crew anyway.
Rym: Now that means that Thursday morning, we're going to Baltimore, so there's going to be no episode on Thursday.
Rym: Oh sucks to be a Thursday only listener, and we're going to be out of town all next week Meaning instead of having normal GeekNights We're going to have GeekNights specials every day of the week that we're going to upload.
Rym: actually they were uploaded yesterday.
Rym: Oh They're already ready to go.
Scott: the illusion has been destroyed.
Rym: Yeah Considering in every one of them.
Rym: We basically say something to the effect of burn out here.
Scott: now The specials are going to be basically short episodes by us except for the Monday special.
Rym: Yeah, Monday something really cool is.
Scott: Monday is extra special.
Scott: so you being a Monday GeekNights listener you Probably want to listen to next Monday because it's going to be very interesting.
Scott: I'm very interested to hear what it is.
Rym: I'm excited.
Scott: What can I say very excited?
Scott: We'll let it stay a surprise.
Rym: Yes, though also bear in mind that we I have appeared on Movies.
Rym: you should see a podcast we both enjoy.
Scott: Yeah, that that's all we're going to say about that.
Rym: Yes their episode about city of God.
Rym: We had some things to say about city of God.
Scott: I Think we also did another episode a long time ago attack the gas station Which if you were listening to GeekNights back then you already knew about.
Rym: Yeah, I see in regards to hate mail last week you were still a slow talker.
Rym: yes low talking I don't know.
Scott: I don't know either.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Anyway, it is Monday, you know science tech sci-fi day all those things.
Rym: We've got some newses like we always do.
Rym: no geek backs.
Rym: No geek backs.
Scott: No, there's probably gonna be a shit ton of geek back type action coming after Otakon.
Scott: Oh good God, so two weeks from now will be the geek back times.
Scott: now.
Scott: No geek back
Rym: and don't be surprised if today or tomorrow we go a little bit short just because basically Otakon has gotten to the point where it takes us an entire the entire week before Otakon to prepare for Otakon and Then the entire two weeks after Otakon to recover from Otakon.
Scott: So this week is gonna be oh no Thursday episode He already said but in fact Wednesday is going to be nothing more than the Otakon pregame.
Rym: It will be the beginning of our Otakon coverage exactly.
Rym: So without further ado my news.
Rym: I'm not gonna go over the details of this because similar stories to this one have been cropping up all over the place in the past several years and it's an issue that is Really starting to bother me and it's somewhat technologically related.
Rym: So I got an excuse now.
Rym: at Penn State not too long ago very recently in fact, there was something going on.
Rym: some police were doing something.
Rym: a Kid walked out of his parents house and saw these police doing something.
Rym: So he opened his cell phone and took a picture a few minutes later.
Rym: The police came over Arrested his ass took him to jail.
Rym: They're charging him with other than this law about taking pictures of police, which is clearly unconstitutional.
Rym: they also, you know obstruction of justice and interfering with investigation and all sorts of bullshit charges If that judge actually or lawyer jury or whoever actually convicts him on those charges.
Scott: That's heinous.
Rym: at least at least the ACLU is all about this.
Scott: Yeah, there are a bunch of crazies in the ACLU and they often fight for crazy things But for sure, this is something that they're in the right on.
Scott: Yeah, they are in the right quite often They came.
Scott: I don't think I've ever disagreed with them fighting for something because even though I've wanted to once or twice They were on the side of a court case and I was like, what are you doing?
Rym: well, I disagree with a lot of the people they defend.
Rym: ah But I agree with the principles they stand for fully.
Scott: yeah see that but the times that That I was saying what are you doing?
Scott: It was actually people that I kind of was on there.
Scott: So hey, yeah, it was just I was like, yeah, they broke the law.
Scott: But what can you do?
Rym: But the ACLU made a statement right away and they basically said that this is crap.
Scott: And yeah, I've heard of you know people getting you know By police officers for taking pictures or told by security cards to move along.
Scott: You know all right, sir.
Rym: I'm gonna need to ask you to move along.
Scott: Yeah But I've never actually seen anyone go this far to arrest someone on the spot and charge them with all these extra Stupid excessive charges.
Rym: now this story would have angered me greatly as it stands but there have been four or five almost identical stories over the past several months.
Rym: and No, this was just the last straw for me.
Rym: This is just.
Rym: I urge all of you if you see a police officer in public to take his picture.
Scott: So here's the thing.
Scott: if you go look at my flicker You'll see one day when I was walking to I think I told this story on an early episode of the mugger Yeah, the purse snatcher.
Scott: I was why I would live.
Scott: I worked in the city at the time and I was walking to my office from the train station And I heard some girl scream and I couldn't believe it.
Scott: There was a freaking purse snatcher and I went oh shits.
Scott: and of course the first instinct is go Catch him and beat him up because someone else, you know, but they beat me to it.
Scott: So I said what do I do now?
Scott: Uh, I know I'll take a picture.
Scott: So I took a picture of the purse snatcher a couple of them.
Scott: They're on my flicker You can find them and the cop was just like yeah, whatever
Rym: I get the impression that the only police officers who have a problem with you taking are
Scott: the ones who do things wrong
Rym: Yes or the ones who really shouldn't be police officers
Scott: or the ones who were poorly trained or their noobs or Perhaps they've done other things wrong.
Rym: and yeah I mean people have commented that it seems as though I generally take a very adversarial position on the police.
Rym: I mean on FARC I once posted an extensive guide on how to avoid the police if you were on a bicycle Mm-hmm.
Rym: due to some personal experience the statute of limitations is over almost over on but I digress.
Rym: I have also generally encouraged people to not speak to the police unless they have a warrant or they're arresting you and I guess or unless you're gonna be friendly with them like hey, man, what's up?
Rym: Yeah, which I've done often.
Scott: I mean, hey, can I can you tell me how to find this train station?
Rym: actually the police and Beacon are really cool Partly because they really don't go after stupid traffic laws and they actually seem to only exist to protect people.
Scott: Yeah, well the beacon, you know beacon has some not-so-nice people in it true and some uncouth individuals.
Scott: So the police mostly have their hands full with those types.
Scott: So people like us you're just like whatever.
Scott: Hey, how's it going?
Rym: Plus there's no major road going through beacon that would require that would be able to generate ticket revenue on any reasonable basis.
Rym: Oh 52, I guess no cuz not know so many people go through.
Rym: fish kill is where they get everyone in the road.
Rym: We live on me now because no one drives through beacon 90 maybe now cuz no one goes through that far.
Scott: No, whatever.
Rym: Yeah, plus there's nowhere on that road for a cop to sit.
Scott: They could do it on the beacon bridge.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, I don't think they have the authority to do so.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I'm pretty sure they don't because that's because I saw that that bridge is.
Rym: I don't know what the deal is, but there's a federal thing that you can't take pictures from or of the bridge next to our House.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: is it?
Scott: we could a state cop do it possibly but I guess it might have to be some weird River type maybe the Port Authority.
Scott: No, they're in New York City thing.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Yeah, it's it's just in general.
Rym: I. my theory on police is very simply that 99% of police give the 1% a bad name but the 1% are the ones doing the most stuff.
Rym: cuz 99% of them are just sitting around like Andy Griffith show I just it's at the point in this country where I'm actually always and I'm dead serious.
Rym: I am more afraid of being accosted Harassed or molested by police officers in this country than I am about any criminals any terrorists anyone else in the world?
Rym: Yeah, yeah because actually police bother me on a fairly regular basis mostly because I do things that probably stand out to them.
Rym: I mean I'll be on my bike in the middle of the night or I'll be out for a walk like in the middle of a snow Storm at night.
Rym: Usually I'm just out at night and police are like, what are you doing?
Rym: Yeah to which I say officer unless you're arresting me.
Rym: I would like to go on my way and not say another word to you Mm-hmm.
Rym: Well do what we've said it before and I'll say it again.
Rym: We'll do a whole show on how to deal with the police someday.
Scott: Okay, so GPL three draft number two is out.
Scott: and for the non lawyers including myself and Rym I have read some Journalists describe what it says.
Rym: Well first the GPL the GNU general public license is a license you can use to just basically anything you create ever is For the most usually software.
Rym: Well anything in general though is copyrighted by default.
Rym: There's a copy Okay, and no one has the right to use what you created except in certain commonly accepted Ways fair use and eventually public domain without your permission.
Rym: Now the GPL and similar things like Creative Commons are Ways are easy ways that are already written and tested by lawyers So that the legalese is already in there where you can say the thing I just created is released under this license meaning you all out there can use it for all these purposes.
Rym: You don't have to bother me about it and it's perfectly legal.
Scott: Mm-hmm Well, sometimes the license says you have to tell me about it.
Rym: Well, yeah, you can change.
Rym: you can do whatever you want.
Rym: You can alter the license But in general it's a way to allow other people to use what you have created While not giving up all of your rights to what you just created.
Scott: Yeah So I mean you could just put something in the public domain right away Or you could say I want to keep like one of the rights that I have but I want to give the rest of them Plus the.
Rym: the one thing about public domain is that once something is in the public domain You could like say I wrote a book and I put it in the public domain.
Rym: Scott could take the book say he wrote it and there's nothing wrong with that.
Rym: public domain means 100% public right?
Scott: Well, the GPL is bit is licensed that Linux uses.
Scott: It's the license that most Linux software uses and The gist of what it says.
Scott: the main point of it that way is that this this software is open source.
Scott: You can sell it you can copy it you can share it with friends you can modify it.
Scott: if you choose to modify it it that modification also has to be open source and That's what it says.
Scott: GP cart.
Scott: right now Linux and everything else uses GPL version 2.
Scott: GPL version 3 has two important changes.
Scott: The first important change has to do with DRM and DRM is that stuff that makes you not able to copy iTunes files and play them on non iPods.
Rym: Yeah, DRM is such a terrible misnomer.
Rym: I mean, it's called digital rights management when really it's more like digital Digital copyright restriction blah blah blah.
Scott: Yeah, the point of it is is that GPL version 3?
Scott: Says you basically can't do DRM with a GPL software.
Scott: now in so many words That's so wrong because I generalized it so much.
Scott: but to give a specific example ready Let's say I'm TiVo and I use Linux on my TiVo.
Scott: now, of course, I have to open source that software.
Scott: That's a given.
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: Let's say I make it that I only want people to run this particular version of software on TiVo's.
Scott: So I put something in the hardware and I put something in the software that is Technologically similar to DRM.
Scott: that way people can't run other software on their TiVo's They can only run the TiVo software on the TiVo's.
Scott: GPL version 2 allows that just fine.
Scott: GPL version 3 does not and therefore the people who make GPL version 3 which include Richard Stallman in the new Whatever the free software foundation disagree with Linus Torvalds who says he was on the side of TiVo.
Rym: Linus is the one who maintains the Linux kernel Yeah and He says that GPL version 3 sucks.
Scott: Linux is gonna keep using number 2 and the people from the free software foundation are all like.
Rym: Now I'm fairly ambivalent because on one hand I see where RMS at all are coming from because they are basically of the mind that DRM is an evil and This will prevent people who want to use this evil from also using open source thus limiting their options and making it harder for People to use DRM and DRM encrypted software.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: But at the same time Linus is arguing that by doing so you're preventing people who would all Otherwise use open source software from using it because you're not allowing them to use it for their purpose
Scott: Mm-hmm,
Rym: and they both have valid points and I think that people should use whichever version of the GPL they want to.
Scott: here's the problem.
Scott: the free software foundation recommends that when you right now if you were to say release a piece of software and you wanted to do it under the GPL and you followed the FSF recommendations exactly they recommend the use that you license your software as GPL version 2 or greater.
Scott: Linus had the foresight to license Linux as GPL version 2 Period.
Scott: a lot of people have licensed it as GPL version 2 or greater.
Scott: That's problem.
Rym: Well, the thing is if it's 2 or greater Then that means that generally if you use something that is licensed under that you can choose which of the two you want.
Rym: and since The later one is more restrictive.
Rym: There's really no problem I think unless it says unless it very specifically says or greater in the sense that the newest version is always the one this Is licensed on.
Scott: I think this is the second one, although I'm not a hundred percent sure.
Rym: See, I don't think so.
Rym: But even if that were the case, it's still your thing.
Rym: It might be 2 and greater like GeekNights, right GeekNights is released under the Creative Commons license with a few.
Rym: We've got a whole thing about it.
Scott: but
Rym: if we wanted to change that we could change it just like that and Anything that anyone
Scott: here's the thing
Rym: thing that has already been released is already can already be used under the old license But it could also be used under the new license if we said so because we have full rights to whatever we want.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Anyway, these another problem with the GPL version 3 and it has to do with patents.
Scott: and What it all comes down to is that Sure, the FSF guys they who make the GPL want there to be less software patents.
Scott: So it doesn't exactly say this.
Scott: but in so many words if you want to make something patentable You can't you know patent open source software with GPL version 3.
Rym: now take everything I just said and apply it to this because it's the same issue.
Scott: Yeah, in fact HP has said yeah, we don't like this GPL version 3 because we want to make open source stuff but we want to put our patented stuff in there also.
Rym: and see now the thing is I Generally err on the side of freedom But at the same time the people doing all of these software patents and DRM are in my eyes to a certain extent evil.
Scott: yeah, it's like the GPL guys writing the GPL.
Scott: they want to Help stop these evil things that we recognize are bad things.
Scott: DRM and software patents bad and bad however By the problem is is that if governments legislate software patents and DRM, that's bad.
Scott: But at the same time if they put DRM or software patents in the license Even though they're on the side of good.
Scott: That's also bad for other reasons.
Scott: the best thing that people could possibly do with DRM and Software patents is nothing.
Rym: now bear in mind that when we say I'm not saying that we're against copyright There's a whole different argument very specifically.
Rym: It's DRM.
Rym: That is the evil.
Rym: Mm-hmm because DRM basically creates a situation wherein Information that was created and exists can be locked down Destroyed and lost forever at the whims of the people who created it while I'm of the mind that information that is created Should never be allowed to be destroyed.
Scott: Yeah, imagine if George Lucas made Star Wars in the time of DRM.
Scott: He would basically with a wave of his hand eliminate every single copy of the the original First three episodes four or five and six and we wouldn't have you know, the copies that we have today.
Rym: Yeah I mean look quite literally if the DRM vision of the future of computing came through and this has happened back Then George Lucas could have snapped his fingers and no one would ever again be able to see The scene where Han Solo shoots first.
Rym: and in fact, there would be no way to prove that Han Solo did in fact shoot first.
Scott: Absolutely.
Scott: No way.
Scott: that is why DRM is bad.
Rym: or what if the government decided that they were gonna use DRM to protect all their voting Records and then on a whim they could just delete the voting records or change the voting records and there's no way for anyone to Ever prove otherwise.
Rym: Yeah, no one could.
Scott: Nowadays, you can technically Freedom of Information Act and all this stuff But you know that none of that will help you if they've just deleted all the evidence and it's not there anymore.
Rym: Yeah, because there are currently legal Restrictions on getting information to disseminating information.
Rym: DRM is another step with physical permanent restrictions Mm-hmm, not good.
Rym: and in regards to patents, which is a whole other issue I think I can say with certainty that the official position of GeekNights is that software patents are bollocks.
Scott: They are indeed.
Rym: How can you patent a large number that may or may not be prime?
Scott: Yeah I mean If you saw a lot of this problem with software patents is it's sort of like patenting screws.
Scott: if you patent the screw Then no one can make a machine with a screw in it without paying you money.
Rym: And in fact, I am under no obligation to let you even though say I invented the screw and I patented it I don't have to let you use my screw or anything.
Rym: Yeah, you'd have to invent some sort of other mechanical Device or bit to make our machines and we're not gonna get into it now because this is a new is not a thing of The day.
Rym: but I can tell you with but with the full backing of my professional education and career That if software patents had existed and what had been used during the early years of computing Software and technology related to computing would not have progressed even a quarter as far as it has.
Rym: you wouldn't be podcasting right now Mostly because mp3s where mp3s were probably never because none of none of what we have now would have happened.
Scott: Nothing things of the day Thingy thingy thingy.
Rym: Well, why do you always do that?
Rym: Well, what is that from you?
Rym: just say that or I don't know Thingy thingy thing.
Scott: It's like you say things of the day and then I just have an urge to say something.
Scott: So What do you want?
Rym: Where could he be?
Scott: That's fishy fishy fishy.
Rym: Well, no, no, no, it's thing of the day.
Rym: thing of the day.
Scott: What is your thing of the day?
Rym: My thing of the day is something pretty awesome that Lisa actually sent me a link to and it's on a live journal Which I bristle at because I don't like live journal, but at the same time This is the most awesome Cthulhu doll I've ever seen.
Rym: it is made entirely out of leather and it is a sight to behold.
Rym: I highly recommend you click on this link.
Rym: And if you don't know what Cthulhu is, I Think you're a lost cause.
Rym: Okay, that's all I got.
Rym: I'm quick.
Scott: okay, my thing of the day is actually technological which is good for a Monday Boom.
Scott:  now this I'm gonna actually do a somewhat technical explanation But for the non-technical of you, I will give a one sentence Some summary at the end.
Rym: Yeah, were you gonna say summation?
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Why didn't you?
Scott: I don't know All right.
Scott: So this guy had problems with his neighbors accessing his wireless network.
Scott: So he modified his DHCP servers configuration to put them all the people on the open wireless network with different Mac addresses onto a separate sub network.
Scott: then using IP tables He rerouted all incoming traffic Going to the untrusted Separate subnet through a squid proxy server on the squid proxy server.
Scott: He wrote a redirection script that combined with image magic would flip all images coming down over the internet.
Scott: So to summarize that when his neighbors used his wireless network to browse the web all Pictures were upside down, but everything else was fine.
Rym: Yep, that is beautiful.
Rym: That is an absolutely beautiful thing and I don't know what I can say.
Scott: He was also able to do other things because you know image magic is a command-line program that can pretty much modify an image Any way you want.
Scott: he made all the images blurry.
Scott: He could monochrome all the images.
Rym: now think about some Luddite dude.
Rym: He can.
Scott: he can negative all the images to make them crazy colors about some dude who doesn't know much about tech.
Rym: but he's got his laptop and he's connected to this wireless and all the pictures on his internets are blurry and He can't figure out why.
Rym: he's probably getting really agitated.
Scott: and they're all.
Scott: it's only on in web pages and any images that come From the internet.
Scott: it basically filters all gif paying JPEG images coming from the internet and flips them upside down.
Scott: That's just beautiful Fantastic, I think we should do something like that.
Rym: Yeah plus remember kids having a wireless access point Always gives you an excuse to not get gotten by the RIAA and the MPAA Because there's no way they can prove that it was you downloading or uploading dick.
Rym: Yep, the more, you know.
Scott: Yeah, this is a lot more interesting for someone who understands the technology behind it because you see how clever he was in the way He did it.
Rym: Yes Mad props very mad props.
Rym: Now anyway today being Monday in tech day We decided we were going to talk a bit about Firefox extensions the ones we use the ones that are good and the ones that are crap All the ones I don't use a crap.
Rym: Yes All right I don't use nearly as many as Scott.
Scott: So, you know, I have a lot of them that I use very little but I have them because that one time they're gonna be useful.
Scott: Wham there they are.
Scott: Well the one that comes with Firefox the DOM inspector, which is wonderful It's only really good if you're a web developer who's doing a lot of JavaScript type stuff.
Rym: Yeah, but my most used extensions are very easily and simply the delicious one Which lets me right click on a page and add it to delicious and do all the delicious stuff.
Scott: Yeah, I use the official delicious extension, which you know, I only use it for one thing.
Scott: I'm at a web page.
Scott: I want to add it to my delicious.
Scott: I push the delicious button thing Much easier than copying the URL going to delicious opening it pasting it.
Scott: I Just push one button and I'm all good.
Rym: Yep I like it mostly because I use it to keep track of all the things I've seen during the week that I'm going to talk About on GeekNights.
Scott: That's what I use it for.
Rym: So if you really want to be ahead of the game, you could watch my own people are ahead of the game.
Rym: Well, yeah I know some people try to guess at what my thing of the day is based on what I've put in my delicious recently.
Scott: Mmm, I tag all my things of the day with the tag thing of the day But you never know which one I'm gonna use.
Scott: or maybe I'll use something that isn't tagged.
Rym: Sometimes I do sometimes I don't sometimes I take things GeekNights.
Rym: Sometimes I don't.
Rym: I guess it depends on how sure I am That I'm going to use it.
Scott: Yeah, it's like I'd like to go through my delicious and sort of make all the tags uniform again, but nah screw them.
Rym: Oh god, my tags have diverged so much.
Rym: my tags are just so crazy and out there I mean, I have a. I looked and I saw that the majority of tags I have were only ever used once.
Rym: Wow Yeah, me.me also I think the one thing I do is I do tag a lot of my things with FARC.
Rym: So any FARC tag is usually prevalent in delicious.
Rym: for me, you know sad scary amusing asinine.
Scott: All right All right up more Firefox extensions.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Well, that was a nice segue.
Rym: I was gonna do until you ruined it.
Rym: Oh now my favorite and most used extension other than adblock which we'll talk about in a minute is FARC.
Rym: it which is simple and beautiful.
Rym: see on FARC now in in terms of levels of Technology and Interestingness involved in creating places for people to discuss things on the internet FARC is pretty much only one step above chaos.
Rym: I Mean that the bottom FARC us at the bottom is 4chan 4chan I can't follow.
Rym: I have never seen a coherent conversation in 4chan.
Rym: I don't think it's for coherent conversation But I have never seen a single post that looked like it in any way was related to any other post other than the fact that occasionally there would be a picture of something pornographic.
Rym: that was appeared to be related to the previous picture of something pornographic.
Rym: But the next step above that is FARC now slashed out is moderated and dig has you know?
Rym: moderate you can dig people up and down FARC.
Rym: the only moderation is if you post something illegal You will be deleted.
Rym: other and they block out a few words that would get you you know if you were in work.
Rym: other than that if you post something it appears and It's just it's a string of guys name what he posted guys name what he posted and that's it.
Rym: and It's a fine art to be able to read all the different simultaneous Conversations that are going on in FARC because there's absolutely no way to separate them.
Scott: Yeah, if they had some threading in there, it would make it easier to read But I think it would also destroy the whole that is FARC.
Rym: Yes, it would because it's really it's a skill And I put far more points into it than I should have.
Rym: Yes But FARC it is a beautiful extension that you highlight because a lot of times you want to reply to someone and there's an etiquette Where if you want to reply to what someone said you take their name you put it in bold then you would enter twice.
Rym: Then you take whatever you wanted to quote from them.
Rym: you put in italics.
Rym: you would enter twice again.
Rym: Then you respond.
Rym: that way you go into the thread and you want to see anyone responded to you.
Rym: I hit you know Slash or control F or whatever you use and I type my name and then I look for instances of my name in order to See if anyone responded to me.
Rym: FARC it automates this.
Rym: if you highlight text anywhere on FARC and you right-click it adds FARC it and you click on that.
Rym: it creates all the HTML and everything and you're.
Rym: all you have to do now is type your Posts and then hit enter.
Scott: Aha, so it adds features to FARC that should be in the FARC website itself, but you just use an extension instead.
Rym: Well, the thing is FARC gets so much traffic that I don't think it would be economically feasible to add any sort of anything to FARC other than the static text you get.
Scott: I think that they could add a quote button without hurting themselves.
Rym: They don't even have HTML buttons.
Rym: If you don't know.
Rym: if you don't know HTML, you're just fucked on FARC.
Scott: Alright, let's see.
Scott: Let's talk about adblock.
Rym: Alright adblock is the single most important extension in the world.
Scott: Yeah, well, there are actually two extensions is adblock and adblock plus.
Scott: as far as I'm concerned They're equivalent.
Scott: However, a lot of people adblock plus does have more features and a lot of people prefer it.
Scott: I personally don't care which whichever I use whichever one suits my whim.
Scott: Yeah, but some people say adblock plus all the way and some people say adblock plus sucks adblock all the way.
Scott: I don't care.
Scott: No, they're the same.
Rym: before we talk about the filter set G adblock by itself All it is is say you see an ad you right-click on the ad and you say adblock.
Rym: it opens a little dialog and it shows you the URL of the ad and you can tie.
Rym: you can Cut it short or add wildcards do whatever you want to do.
Rym: You're basically creating a rule that says any image that follows this rule will not be shown to me ever again.
Scott: So for example, let's say your favorite website is Rym and Scott.com.
Scott: and Rym and Scott.com have a bunch of advertising images and they keep them at.
Scott: Rym and Scott.com slash ads slash Name of the ad gift.
Scott: you make a rule.
Scott: That's Rym and Scott.com slash ads slash star.
Scott: That way any images that are at Rym and Scott.com slash ads you won't see them ever.
Scott: They just won't be visible to you.
Rym: It also has two options.
Rym: You can tell it to either Download the ads but don't show them to me or don't download them at all.
Rym: and both are valid.
Rym: because in the first case if You pick the don't download them, especially you have a slow connection.
Rym: It saves you a lot of speed and bandwidth.
Scott: Yeah, dial up people that's very key is to use adblock with the don't download the ads.
Rym: also if you're at work or something It cuts down on the number of weird domains.
Rym: Your browser may be hitting while you're at work when you should be working.
Scott: Yeah, cuz you know, you might visit Rym and Scott.com but it gets an advertisement from Penn Island.
Scott: Yeah, Penn Island.com.
Scott: and then And it downloads.
Scott: and you know, you might not see the ad.
Scott: but if it downloaded the people watching what you do at work We'll see that you went to Penn Island net or calm or whatever, but you might not have wanted to go to.
Scott: You didn't want to go to Penn Island, it's not a good place.
Scott: Oh, it's not Unless you know you're into that sort of thing.
Rym: Yeah, if you really like pens.
Rym: Yeah islands.
Rym: Yeah Now the benefit of using it the other way is that some sites usually terrible sites You wouldn't want to go to anyway.
Rym: Try to set up some logic where if the dads don't get downloaded it makes sure you can't see the content either.
Rym: This way one you can rip off all the advertisers who I think are dumb for trying to advertise the internet in the first place By.
Rym: they'll think you downloaded the ad.
Rym: they'll think you saw the ad but you didn't know.
Rym: and two if they're checking to see if you saw the ad as far as they're concerned you did and there's no way for Them to know otherwise.
Scott: the other advantage of this method is Sometimes you'll block an ad but it's not really an ad.
Scott: Like for some website might use some pictures for its navigation and you'll accidentally add block all of them.
Scott: Well now you've downloaded them You can just click a couple times and they'll appear instead of having to go and download them.
Rym: Yeah, or you know refresh the page after adding a rule or removing a rule.
Scott: Yeah, so that that's also helpful.
Rym: Now the only drawback is that you have to do it manually which I prefer to do for a number of reasons.
Scott: I prefer not to do it manually because I'm lazy.
Rym: yes, also, I dislike seeing advertisements so much on the internet mostly because they annoy me.
Rym: and It's got to the point where I use such a broad brush.
Rym: Like if I see an ad I blocked the whole domain that ad came from.
Rym: with rare exceptions I Mean I most sites I see.
Rym: now I block almost every picture on them all those every news site.
Rym: I just see the text.
Scott: see.
Scott: I used to do stuff like that but then eventually a lot of sites became unnavigatable and then my rules became unmanageable and it just wasn't worth the time and effort anymore.
Rym: see to me Unnavigable sites.
Rym: don't bother me because I rarely ever navigate a site unless it's a site that I go to regularly in which case it's In my ad block whitelist or it usually doesn't have bad ads.
Rym: if I go to a new site For example, I will only ever get to a news site from Google News or from Fark or from slash out or from some guys Blog and I'll only go to the one page.
Rym: They took me to.
Scott: it's usually the blogs though that I had the problem on.
Rym: See, I don't navigate the blogs either though I only I'll only ever get to a blog if I get to it from Fark or slash time.
Scott: See what it is is not a common occurrence But you know once in a every week or two I like I'll find a podcast which is a blog Basically, and I'll try to go look at his old episodes and then it won't work and I'll be screwed.
Rym: This may sound evil but for my for my perspective if I can't navigate a site Because my ad blocker your site is so much like an advertisement that my site my ad blocker blocks you.
Rym: I don't care what you have on your site.
Scott: All right Anyway, so how does Scott do it?
Scott: If Rym does it manually and Scott does it automatically?
Scott: How does Scott do it automatically?
Scott: Well with another extension the ad block filter set dot G Updater all this is.
Scott: It's basically an extension.
Scott: You don't have to look at or do anything with you install it you click OK and you're done what it does in.
Scott: If you have ad block or ad block plus already installed which you have to have in order for the filter set G updater to Work it will automatically manage and update your set of rules for blocking ads to block Most of the ads on the internet.
Scott: Well, very rarely blocking things that are not ads.
Rym: now I will note that I'm Phil just said geez great and I use it at work actually in addition to adding things manually.
Rym: But I don't use it at home and Scott used it but way back.
Rym: we played a game for a while called Kingdom of Loathing Mm-hmm, which is a really funny awesome game.
Rym: You've never heard of it.
Rym: I highly recommend you play it until you get sick of it, which won't take long.
Rym: I guarantee but it's really fun.
Scott: Yeah, it's worth it for the humor and then it's not worth it anymore.
Rym: then it becomes a waste of time because then you might understand why we mispronounce certain words like Zmabi and lick.
Rym: Yes also Now anyway, the game had really funny graphics because the game is stick figures.
Rym: Everything is poorly drawn.
Rym: stick figures Scott because he was using the filter set G It thought that all of these pictures were ads and blocked many of them.
Rym: Thus Scott had missed much of the humor of Kingdom of Loathing.
Scott: I did indeed miss many of the pictures.
Rym: I saw many pictures But I also missed many of them which interestingly enough is proof to me that the pictures added something to the game because Scott Scott and I started the game at about the same time.
Rym: I started one day after he did.
Rym: He stopped playing about two weeks before I stopped playing And I think the only reason I played two weeks more is because the pictures were that entertaining.
Rym: they were two weeks worth of entertainment Maybe.
Rym: I think that's it.
Rym: It could be See honestly though.
Rym: There aren't really many other extensions I use.
Scott: I use a lot, but all of them see are pretty small.
Scott: But the biggest one and the newest one that is the most important is the Google browser sync Which I've been using the hell out of lately the Google browser sync.
Scott: what it does is you and let's say you have a laptop and a desktop and a work and a computer at work three computers Now five five five computer now three computers now you want to have the same bookmarks on all those computers.
Scott: You want to have the same cookies on all those computers you want to have.
Scott: you know?
Scott: Cuz like sometimes you log into a forum at home and then you want to go read the forum on your laptop But you won't be logged in.
Scott: so you log in on the laptop and then you go back to the desktop and you're not logged in anymore over there, it's annoying.
Scott: and You know some people save their passwords for website in Firefox and some people, you know, you'll visit a website at home You'll be at work.
Scott: you want to look in your history to figure out what website you visited your history.
Scott: Also, you know you want on all your computers the Google browser sync what it does when you close your web browser Takes your history your save passwords your cookies, you know all that stuff.
Scott: You can choose which ones you want.
Scott: You can actually say just do my history.
Scott: Just do my cookies.
Scott: Just do my cookies and my bookmarks, you know, and it will take all those things and send them to Google encrypted.
Scott: So Google isn't looking at them, you know.
Scott: as a privacy thing, you know, it's really encrypted.
Scott: I checked and You know, they just hold on to them for you at Google and then you visit another.
Scott: you go home You know from work after adding a bookmark you open Firefox at home.
Scott: It goes to Google gets your bookmarks your history and all that stuff and updates it on your home computer.
Scott: That way all your firefoxes and all your computers will have the same bookmarks the same history the same everything and it will all stay Together and be cool.
Scott: The only problem with this extension is that it takes longer to start up and shut down Firefox because it's talking to Google.
Scott: other than that.
Scott: It's perfect and amazing and holy crap.
Rym: I haven't used it yet, but no one's really said anything bad about it as far as I can see.
Scott: Yep Let's see.
Scott: What other others go down the list because a lot of these are quick nothings.
Scott: This flash block flash block All it does is it blocks all flash.
Scott: all flash is blocked unless you click on it.
Rym: Now.
Rym: that's great because 99% of flash on the internet is ads or crap.
Scott: Yeah The only problem with flash block is that sometimes a website will use flash for navigation in which like the viz website is particularly bad.
Scott: So you have to say, you know, it's a flash block.
Scott: allow the viz.com website to use flash.
Scott: You know allow this website to use flash.
Rym: now to me the flash It's mostly redundant because ad block for me blocks by default flash from any domain that even looks like it's an ad domain.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is that when ad block blocks flash, it makes it completely disappear.
Scott: flash block is Sometimes we visit a website and the flash will just start playing and you wanted to.
Scott: you know You have it in some hidden tab and you want to watch it later and then it starts spewing audio out and it's annoying.
Scott: You know, like I'll open up ten tabs.
Scott: two of them have videos in them.
Scott: now I have to go find the tabs with the videos.
Scott: stop them.
Scott: This makes it so the flash won't start playing and true click on it.
Scott: That's why I use flash block not to block the flash from my view but to prevent it from automatically playing right away.
Rym: Now also bear in mind that if your website requires flash for navigating you've got problems and you shouldn't be on the internet.
Scott: You definitely shouldn't be doing that.
Scott: I mean you can make what if someone went to your website with links or if they were blind or if they were using an old Netscape 2 or 3?
Rym: I mean in general.
Rym: I mean you can make cool websites with flash.
Rym: But you have to just remember that whenever you use flash you were greatly limiting your possible audience.
Rym: You're also making it far more difficult for search engines to index your content and thus making it harder for people to find you.
Scott: Yep, another extension to use is sage.
Scott: It's just an RSS reader that goes in the sidebar on the left.
Scott: You know where the bookmark sidebar and the history sidebar are.
Scott: I mean It's a little bit more efficient for reading things like blogs that you read every day than the Firefox live bookmarks are But it's not that much better.
Scott: I just like it.
Scott: It's it's up to you.
Rym: Yeah, I've actually got that at work because the Firefox live bookmarks thing is kind of meh.
Scott: It's a little bit meh and the sage is a lot.
Rym: I think part of the problem is that RSS to me is mostly meh except in the context of podcasting.
Scott: Whatever bug me not bug me not is huge.
Scott: You know, yes, you know how you go to New York Times or some other news website?
Scott: And they say you must log in to read this story.
Scott: Well, you don't want to go and actually register.
Scott: It takes too damn long.
Scott: It's not you don't want to give them your information now.
Rym: in the old days Slash dot 2000 is a username and slash dot slash dot 2000 is a password almost always worked on every site.
Scott: Yep, but now those news websites clear out these fake passwords and usernames that everyone shares.
Scott: So what you have to do is use bug me not.
Scott: bug me Not is a database of names and passwords for news websites and other websites and you can just add things to it all the time.
Scott: Yeah, you can go and let's say you make a name and a password for some website.
Scott: You can just go put it on bug me not and then other people can use bug me not To get that name and password and log in to that website.
Scott: So let's say you go to New York Times com and it says please log in you just right-click in the username box where you would normally type in your username and click bug me not and it will go to the bug me not.
Scott: database.
Scott: get a name and A password and type it in for you and you just click login and you're all good to go.
Rym: now I'll note also that there are many pay or restricted access sites that for whatever reason People have put usernames and passwords in for.
Rym: so if you ever find a site that won't let you in and The Google cache also won't let you in.
Rym: try bug me not.
Rym: I once got into total FARC for a few minutes with it.
Scott: Yeah, I once got into experts exchange for a few minutes.
Scott: Yeah, and Porn sites man, you know, it works occasionally very rarely It's it's not.
Rym: it got I think by occasionally you mean every night from 7 and 715.
Scott: no, no, but no, I wouldn't waste your time Willie's time I wouldn't.
Scott: I wouldn't waste your time trying to every porn site in the universe to see if you can log in with bug me.
Scott: Not because that's probably not worth it But if you happen to end up at a porn site that says please log in it doesn't hurt to click click bug me not.
Rym: Now there are a million things like save tabs when you close or things that the Firefox I mean the Google browser sync.
Scott: does that?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, there were a lot of extensions that Originally were extensions and then eventually things that are obviously useful.
Rym: It can just be added into Firefox every time.
Scott: Yeah, Firefox 2.0 is gonna have a spell checker making the spell check extensions useless and it's gonna have I think the tab saving when you crash.
Rym: so Yeah things that used to be extensions are now gonna be in Firefox though I got to say a crash because I had for various reasons the computer I do GeekNights on.
Rym: I Haven't updated anything on it in over a year With few rare exceptions because the computer is honest last legs.
Rym: Anyway, it's stable and working and is behind a firewall and I'm not going to risk screwing up The only computer I have that is set up to do GeekNights until I have a new computer.
Rym: So this computer is basically in its end-of-life steady-state cycle.
Rym: as a result I have an old version of Firefox an old version of flash and occasionally flash will cause Firefox to crash.
Scott: that happens to me, too Now with my new Firefox great less often than it used to the way to flash 9.
Rym: That'll solve every.
Scott: flash 9 for Linux will solve everything.
Rym: but now I have the same flash problems in OS X. So no one gets naughty.
Rym: only windows does flash work fully.
Scott: Yeah, it's macro meet Adobe's fault.
Scott: Sorry Yeah, it does nothing to do with Firefox or Windows or any operating system.
Rym: but I was writing a post somewhere and I was kind of writing it on the fly and the post was kind of meant like it wasn't my usual it wasn't to my usual standard of posting and Then Firefox crash and it was a long post and I lost it and I was pissed.
Rym: But then I realized that it forced me to rewrite it and I rewrote it much better than it would have been.
Rym: so the Firefox Crash made a small amount of content that I added to the world slightly better.
Scott: Mm-hmm All right, let me just run down the rest of these real quick cuz I don't I feel bad if I left any of them out Especially for those extension creators out there.
Rym: Yeah, by the way mad props to everyone whose extension we've talked about.
Scott: Yeah, IE tab.
Scott: This is a Windows only extension and you know Sometimes you visit a website and it doesn't work without IE IE tab.
Scott: Just you click a button and it opens in another tab.
Scott: But that tab even though it's in Firefox is actually IE and it works perfectly.
Scott: So it's really great.
Scott: instead of having to go open up Internet Explorer copy the URL blah blah blah blah blah.
Scott: This just works.
Scott: Web developer what this does is it adds a whole mess of buttons to the top of Firefox?
Scott: That let you do various things which are very useful.
Scott: if you're a web developer like you can turn the CSS off You can edit the CSS in real time You can disable Java disable JavaScript change the resolution all sorts of crazy stuff.
Scott: So you can.
Scott: if you're making websites, that's an essential tool.
Scott: You can't be without it.
Scott: Here's a little tiny one colorzilla.
Scott: Sometimes you'd be at a website and there's a color in an image or in the text and you say wow That's a nice color.
Scott: What the hell color is that?
Scott: You just click this little eyedropper in the bottom left of Firefox.
Scott: you click on the color and colorzilla It tells you what color it is.
Rym: I forgot that existed until just now.
Scott: Yeah, it's the greatest thing.
Rym: I gotta get that again because I got it way back when you told me about it the first time and it was badass.
Scott: I hardly ever use it, but you know that two times that I use it.
Scott: It's worth having this little tiny extension.
Rym: You know when it's really great.
Rym: When you want to make an avatar for a forum somewhere and you want your avatars background to match the background of the forum Because they don't.
Rym: let you use transparent ping bastards which a lot of sites don't best.
Rym: It's a lot of sites.
Rym: make you use JPEG or gif bastards.
Scott: Okay, anyway Linky.
Scott: now linky is a thing that lets you do a whole bunch of different stuff with links But I really only use one feature of it text.
Scott: No.
Rym: Oh, that's the only thing I used it for.
Scott: Okay, I use it for open selected links in tabs.
Rym: Oh, yeah that too.
Scott: Let's say you go to slashdot and there's a. there's an article and the article has like six links in it and you go geez And you would have to click six times to open up six tabs one with each of the articles.
Scott: with linky You can just select the whole art.
Scott: the whole little slashdot thing You know is a big Highlight the whole thing and click two times and it'll open up all the links in the highlighted area in new tabs.
Scott: That's it saves so many clicks.
Scott: It's crazy.
Scott: Here's one that not a lot of people know about which is pretty clever.
Scott: It's FXIF and it allows you to view the EXIF data in images.
Scott: now friend who doesn't know?
Scott: EXIF is sort of like ID3 for pictures.
Scott: if you go on flickr and you start looking at the EXIF of different photos you'll see You know who what camera took the pictures who took them maybe what time they were taken all sorts of information.
Scott: So It's really funny to go to like a news website and you look at the EXIF.
Scott: Or you go to a blog and you look at the EXIF on their images and you go Aha, and occasionally it's very very interesting most of the time.
Scott: It's just boring Yeah, but you know when there's a picture roaming around the internet you can say where did that come from?
Scott: Aha, that's where it came from.
Scott: I know what that is.
Rym: I see what you did there.
Scott: Yeah, so like if you found the original goatse you can see who took it.
Scott: maybe yeah Reload every.
Scott: now, sometimes you visit a website that doesn't update on its own But you know, you're like.
Scott: maybe it says like in 10 minutes the grand opening and you know You want to watch and wait you're waiting on a website for something to happen.
Scott: You can say reload this tab every 10 seconds and Reload every allows you to do that.
Scott: It's not useful often, but sometimes very very useful.
Scott: a Lot better than sitting around going reload reload, you know when I use that last e3.
Rym: Yeah, I haven't used it since.
Scott: that's when I used it on e3 because there was a. that was that website with all the e3 news.
Scott: I uninstalled it after e3 and I said reload this every minute and then every time there was new e3 news I went there.
Scott: it is Screen grab.
Scott: this is actually pretty useful because what it does?
Scott: it allows you to take a screenshot of just the website you're on.
Scott: So, you know how sometimes you want to take a screenshot of a website you take a screenshot of the Firefox window.
Scott: Then you to cut the website out or maybe the website is so long You'd have to take a screenshot of the website scroll down take another screenshot paste them together.
Rym: I hate doing that so much.
Scott: screen grab allows you to just take the screenshot of the whole website in one click.
Scott: but there it is perfect.
Scott: and The last extension I have is dig this which is just like delicious, but it digs.
Scott: That's all it does is it is one button to go to your dig and a button to dig something great.
Scott: I don't think we have any meta bits for today simply because we're mostly preparing for Otakon Yep, so if any of those Firefox extensions dry strike your fancy go install them from add-ons not my zilla org Yep.
Rym: and if once again if you're interested in seeing Scott and I live either go to Otakon or Don't see us live until the next con we go to and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Scott: make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.