Rym: It's Tuesday June 13th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We reminisce about counter-strike.
Rym: Let's do this today in white Plains.
Rym: I discovered an abomination unto man Really?
Rym: I wanted to go to a mall down there and I drove and I parked far away because I was doing some other stuff.
Rym: and then I walked over to the mall and I Realized that I didn't see the entrance.
Rym: So I started walking around the mall and I walked all the way around it twice and then it came to me that no Long walk to walk around a mall twice.
Rym: Yeah, it was.
Rym: I had some free time But it turns out that there is absolutely no pedestrian entrance to this mall Whatsoever.
Scott: Oh, is there like a giant cement concrete wall surrounding the whole thing?
Rym: No, it was.
Rym: just imagine a mall with no exits.
Scott: I mean so to the building itself or to the parking lots around it.
Rym: There's no parking lots around it.
Rym: There's a big parking garage in it.
Scott: Okay, and you couldn't walk into that parking garage?
Rym: No, there's only four cars.
Scott: So the only way to get into this mall would be to park in the parking garage Yes, and then walk into the mall.
Rym: there were lots of emergency exits But they were very formidable and industrial looking and there were absolutely no ways in.
Scott: also so into the building itself.
Rym: you mean Into them if there's no way in anywhere.
Rym: I think it's a pretty simple concept Huh?
Rym: There was no way in unless you drove.
Scott: so it's a building sitting in the middle of what a field.
Rym: No, it's in white plain surrounded by hundreds of other buildings, okay, so it's bordered by roads and a parking garage.
Rym: Well, the parking garage is in it.
Scott: Okay, as I said and the only door to get in.
Rym: Well, there's no doors There's just elevators in the parking garage that go to the mall parts.
Scott: Oh, it's one of those now.
Scott: I get it.
Scott: I've seen those before.
Scott: Okay, the way you're describing I thought maybe it was like like why?
Rym: what could you possibly be imagining?
Rym: This is like when you thought up was away from the Sun.
Scott: well because and I think about a mall a mall is a you Know is is separated.
Scott: It has a big field of parking lots all around.
Rym: what a lot of malls don't.
Scott: this isn't some mega mall.
Scott: This is you know, this is a building in the middle of a city.
Rym: Well, no, it's.
Rym: oh, it's a mega mall.
Rym: It's absolutely huge.
Rym: Yeah, but it's not in fact, it's bigger than the mall in Rochester I think in terms of the amount of space in it.
Scott: Well, the ball in Rochester is tiny but the you know It doesn't have the same structure as the the usual mall.
Rym: whatever you seem to have trouble with Imagining architecture as we learned in that D&D.
Scott: It's not like.
Scott: you described it very well.
Scott: You said it as a mall with no entrances, which it was a descriptive because that's all that.
Rym: That's the operative part of the story.
Rym: It was a mall with no entrances.
Rym: That was behind of the cars.
Scott: get in.
Rym: Well, there's an entrance for the car and I said specifically pedestrian entrances.
Scott: Yeah, why didn't you walk in where the cars went in?
Rym: They wouldn't let me.
Rym: there's a guy there and he said this is for cars only.
Rym: you can't walk in.
Rym: Okay, I Walked through a loading dock and a urine-soaked hallway and got into the mall.
Scott: Wow Wow, that's kind of crazy.
Rym: But for my news in that mall, I bought the cheapest Mac mini money can buy.
Rym: Hooray And an iPod.
Scott: All right, everyone.
Scott: It's time to tell Rym.
Scott: we convinced him to buy something Expensive for you know what he needed.
Rym: I was probably going to buy it anyway.
Rym: Yeah, I tried to buy it before but you can't ship Apple things to yourself without signatures before.
Scott: Yeah before meaning yesterday meaning after we were convincing you.
Rym: now I like it and I'm gonna use it mostly for podcasting once I figure out garage band and all that.
Rym: But long term at least for my initial uses.
Rym: I really couldn't use a Mac as my primary desktop.
Scott: Well, we'll talk about that next Monday.
Scott: Yep, because that's not what today's about.
Scott: today's about two games.
Rym: Well, weren't you gonna do your news?
Scott: yep to gaming news.
Scott: Okay, my gaming news.
Scott: So there's this guy and he decided to make a World of Warcraft strategy guide and that kind of reminds me I had a friend who?
Scott: bought himself a Super Nintendo by making Mortal Kombat strategy guides back in the olden days and selling them in school.
Scott: And then he got in trouble for it because you're not allowed to sell stuff in school.
Rym: We used to just play poker straight up in school.
Rym: Yeah for money.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So anyway, this guy wrote a World of Warcraft strategy guide and you know Regardless of what you think about gold farming.
Scott: It was a gold farming guide Whatever.
Scott: That's not the point of the story.
Scott: the point of the story was that he was selling it for $15 as a PDF on eBay, you know by now 15 bucks and Blizzard came down on him like a ton of bricks and he said screw you.
Scott: and he kept trying to make new eBay accounts.
Scott: He didn't take it like most people take it in the ass And he kept fighting it and fighting it and fighting it and eventually without even having to go to court Blizzard just gave up and they agreed just recently to Let him go about his business as long as a. he leaves the disclaimer that was already in the book in the book
Rym: Saying that he's not affiliated with World of Warcraft or Blizzard and
Scott: that he's not using any copyrighted materials of World of Warcraft or Blizzard
Rym: Even though he could use a significant number of copyrighted materials per fair use especially since it is a guide
Scott: Yep, but he's not using any.
Scott: He also has to not publish any sort of cheats and hacks or links to cheats and hacks in the book Which I don't think he was.
Rym: but even if he did that's not illegal.
Scott: No, it's not.
Rym: They can't they really can't go after him for that.
Scott: But he did now he you know to basically keep Blizzard from fighting against him and pestering him.
Scott: He made that agreement with them.
Scott: So now it's a contract I guess.
Scott: Yeah We'll see but the point of this story is if someone comes after you like an evil company for something that you know is perfectly Legal don't take it if you fight back if they realize that they're wrong.
Scott: They pretty much have to give in to you.
Rym: Not always.
Rym: they could just sue you and win if they have good lawyers and you can't afford one.
Scott: Yeah, but when it's in the problem is when it's an open and shut case like this The lawyers are like, alright don't we don't want to go to court But I don't want to sound like idiots when they go there.
Rym: But then again, is it so open and shut?
Rym: because I mean if they have lawyers and money They could probably talk about implied contracts and EULA's and talk their way into a conviction to something.
Scott: I don't think so.
Rym: We see it happen a lot.
Scott: Yeah, but not when it's something so obvious.
Scott: It's like god.
Rym: Yeah, we'll see.
Scott: Plus hey, you know the.
Scott: If it was something so obvious that I knew I could win I would go out and get like the best lawyers I could but they usually won't work for free for something like that.
Scott: Yeah, but if I know I'm gonna win I won't care why because you still have to pay the lawyer?
Scott: Yeah, and I'll get the lawyers to counter sue to get their money.
Rym: It doesn't always work.
Rym: So well, I think it'll work.
Rym: Maybe you should ask my lawyer about that.
Scott: How'd you go ask your lawyer?
Scott: Cuz I can't ask your lawyer.
Rym: Oh, you can ask him through me.
Rym: You can just call him Whatever.
Rym: Yeah, I got a bother him soon.
Rym: I got some questions.
Scott: You got any news action.
Rym: I had my news about a Mac Scott took forever doing his laundry and it's real late.
Rym: My laundry was done at like 10.
Scott: Yeah, my law I just started mine later because you know, we can only have one washing machine.
Rym: Yeah, I don't think it helped that your laundry was sitting idle for quite some time.
Scott: while you dick There's only sitting around idle for like five minutes.
Rym: Yeah, whatever.
Scott: Yeah Just Cuz you can't wait for me to do.
Scott: I said I'd had three loads and you're like.
Scott: you said you had two loads.
Rym: You listen what I talk now cuz you talk wrong.
Rym: I should have recorded it.
Rym: I said anyway, it's late So we're gonna do a short episode.
Rym: Things of the day.
Rym: I actually found something kind of cool.
Rym: There's this video of a plane a passenger plane a big jetliner landing at an airport.
Rym: I don't know what Airport.
Rym: and There's this really really strong crosswind and as the planes coming down it kind of turns sideways and Hovers there using its engines to hold itself into the wind and slowly lowers itself and then turns back around.
Rym: and Lance It's crazy.
Scott: It's pretty crazy.
Scott: You got to wonder what the pilots doing there.
Rym: I imagine he's either real lucky or real skilled.
Scott: I Mean if that plane would have not turned back in the right direction Whoo, it looks like there's some water there.
Scott: they would have ended up in.
Rym: yeah But I don't think there's any other way to land over there.
Rym: I I have this feeling that that sort of thing is a common occurrence and the pilot just knew what to do.
Scott: Here's a hint don't build airports places like that.
Rym: Yeah, you know, I've heard that actually Hong Kong Airport is a lot like that because there was nowhere else to put one.
Scott: Oh, well, yeah, you got no choice.
Rym: But and actually I heard on NPR today that experts said if New York, New Jersey don't build another Airport real soon The state's screwed.
Rym: Really JFK is already running at full capacity and LaGuardia is at about 95 right?
Scott: No, because it JFK There's the old TWA terminal.
Rym: Yeah, you know what they're unused.
Rym: There's this huge thing on NPR this morning where they talked about how JFK and LaGuardia can't handle the air load into the New York City anymore at all and How if we don't build a new airport then within ten years there will not be a way.
Scott: I'll have to go check that out because Because what I've been to JFK and they have terminals that are sitting there abandoned that they could use Yeah, apparently they can't or something or they can't.
Scott: there's not enough Runway and not a terminal.
Rym: I think it's just.
Rym: there's not enough capacity there for the expected load.
Rym: Could be since New York City is one of the few cities where the economy is in the upswing and crime is going down.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: All right.
Scott: My thing of the day is actually game related.
Scott: Holy crap.
Scott: Really?
Scott: Yep This is a guy named flying omelet and he made a website with his top 50 favorite video game ending songs Extravaganza part one.
Rym: All right, what's number one?
Scott: Number one, I believe is an RPG Named.
Scott: it's an RPG heavy list, by the way.
Rym: Well RPGs tend to have the best music.
Scott: Yes, some of them number one.
Scott: Final Fantasy 6.
Scott: Final Fantasy 4.
Rym: Final Fantasy 4. at a great 3 chrono trigger.
Scott: number 4 is the first is the one of the only non RPGs in the top of the list Panzer Dragoon saga.
Scott: and You know number 5 is Metroid 6 earthbound, you know, the list is pretty Expected but some of them with the real good part of this list is number one.
Scott: He's got an mp3 for pretty much every song in the whole thing.
Scott: he's got MIDI's for a whole lot of them and Some of them are games you never even heard of.
Scott: like.
Scott: What's the crazy one?
Scott: I never heard of Hyperzone.
Scott: you ever heard of hyperzone?
Rym: never I don't really care to either.
Scott: How about skyblazer?
Rym: I've heard of that.
Rym: I've heard that before.
Rym: I don't know what the game is, but I've heard the word skyblazer.
Scott: Yeah Megaman 2 and 3 were on the list, but they were pretty low.
Scott: but considering the top 50 I'll let it slide a little bit.
Rym: Yeah, Megaman 2 didn't have the greatest ending music.
Scott: Megaman 2 had excellent ending music.
Rym: you talking about a good music.
Rym: the ending song wasn't that special.
Scott: Number 49 is Drakken, which is one of those games.
Rym: It's impossible God Drakken I could do a whole show about how bad that game was.
Scott: Yeah There's a lot of bad games on this list that I for some reason or another this guy thinks they have good ending music.
Rym: I definitely agree with the guys top three at least.
Scott: I don't say they're the numb.
Rym: Do you remember the ending song to Final Fantasy 4?
Scott: Yeah, you know.
Scott: and while ending songs.
Rym: Oh, oh do you how'd it go?
Rym: But I thought you said you remembered.
Scott: I do but I can't sing it.
Scott: Oh Yeah, when something like this, let me push the button on the computer here, right?
Scott: Anyway, yeah, you know while RPGs have you know, usually the good epic music There are plenty of musics in other Genres of video game music that are better, you know It's sort of like it's picking Final Fantasy 6 and 4 and krona trigger.
Scott: It's sort of like you're picking the same song three times now.
Rym: Final Fantasy 6 is ending.
Scott: song was vastly different from fours Yeah, but it's the same kind of song.
Rym: What do you mean?
Rym: the same kind of song?
Scott: It's like if I made a list of best Songs ever period and I chose all like rock songs for the top 25.
Scott: It's like, okay, seriously You know, it's like picking best video game songs ever and choosing mostly RPGs.
Rym: Well, I think it's partly that RPG music tends to be more classical and more complex in nature.
Scott: Yep, that's true, which generally but that doesn't make it necessarily better than other music.
Scott: Well, it depends on what criteria is using for better and I think yeah the guys criteria I have to let him slide also is that it's his top 50 favorites.
Scott: So this is this guy's favorites.
Scott: He's not claiming that these are the best ones.
Rym: Well, I at least agree with him.
Scott: Yeah, I slight I would take his top 50 and just put him in a different order probably.
Scott: So because Rym is all tired and wussy and yeah, Scott's tired, too I'm not tired.
Rym: We got to get this done.
Rym: It's late and I want to play with my max amor.
Scott: Yeah, you're late.
Scott: It's late.
Scott: You want to play with the Mac and I don't care anyway.
Scott: Today we're gonna talk about something real easy to talk about real old not that old.
Scott: It's still being played today.
Rym: I haven't though.
Rym: I haven't personally played it in over a year me either but that's besides the point hasn't changed very much.
Scott: We're gonna talk about the classic perhaps number one FPS ever in existence multiplayer FPS Counter-strike.
Rym: I mean for anyone who doesn't really realize it counter-strike was the number one FPS in terms of number of players for pretty much the entirety of the time we were in college pretty much from the end of the quake 2 era Until the World of Warcraft era when people just started the FPS has started dropping out of favor.
Scott: even so counter-strike is still played by thousands and thousands of people around the world at to this day is Perhaps the most popular multiplayer online game ever to exist and it is doubtful whether it will ever be beaten
Rym: Other than lineage possibly in terms of raw numbers, but that is
Scott: World of Warcraft.
Scott: is beaten lineage in numbers now?
Rym: Oh now it is.
Scott: Yeah So, but this is you know counter-strike is a game where there were always around the world Thousands perhaps tens of thousands people playing it constantly no matter where you live.
Rym: There were low ping servers near you that were full all the time and it's been going on For how long since since about the year?
Rym: 1999.
Scott: so seven years give or take something like that.
Rym: It really really took off the summer of 2000.
Scott: Yeah, that's that's when it lost and then it took off again.
Rym: I forget which beta came out, but there was one I think was 1.3 Something.
Scott: 1.3 wasn't beta.
Rym: Yeah, that was one point.
Scott: Oh was non.
Rym: 1.0 was non beta and one of those versions Shortly after there is when the game exploded crazy like it.
Scott: at one point one was an explosion and beta 7 was an explosion.
Rym: Yeah, beta 7 is the one I think I was thinking of.
Scott: yeah, so let's talk about how we started playing counter-strike.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Well that thing is I tried it first before Scott, but Scott played it before I did.
Rym: It's kind of weird, but I'd heard of this counter-strike and so I think it was can or someone told me to play it and I got it and I played it and I died right away and then I died again and the game was just frustrating and difficult and I quit immediately.
Scott: and that was it For me in high school, we only had dial-up modem so I couldn't play too many online games besides Diablo 2 else would never play again.
Scott: And I had half-life 1 which I beat and I really like half-life 1 And I wanted to play some multiplayer games.
Scott: and So when I got to college, I played Team Fortress classic mostly the hunted type Which is where you which is sort of like counter-strike with a VIP You know, you got to get this VIP to the to the garage so he's safe But the other guys are trying to snipe him.
Scott: It's it's actually the only decent Team Fortress scenario.
Scott: anyway in CS1 lab the lab instructor was like, oh you got to play counter-strike.
Scott: Yeah, when you die, you don't come back.
Scott: and I was like, well that sucks.
Scott: I'm gonna die and then sit around doing nothing.
Scott: I'll just turn the game off or you know quit and go find another game to play.
Scott: and what's the point of that?
Scott: Now I had heard of counter-strike, but I didn't really Know that it was a free half-life mod.
Scott: I thought it was some game and that's all I knew is there was a game named counter-strike that I didn't want to play.
Rym: See at least cuz I had a cable modem Early early on like me and my friend Ken got cable modems when they were still kind of being rolled out in the country.
Rym: So we were playing for every freaking mod quake 1 and quake 2 online pretty all through high school.
Rym: Mm-hmm counter-strike was just another one and Honestly when I first played it, I thought this is like a crappy version of action quake.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: So then, you know, someone told me that counter-strike was actually a free half-life mod.
Scott: So, of course, I'm gonna try it because I'll try it once why not free.
Scott: Hey So I tried it and then whoa There's counter-strike from there on till tribes 2 and then counter-strike again and then natural selection and then counter-strike again.
Rym: Yep, cuz Scott tells me not too long because this is when we we knew and this is the crew would all come together But we were still freshmen at RIT So we weren't really the front row crew fully yet.
Rym: and I still have all the chat logs from back then when I used ICQ.
Rym: Oh, those were good days.
Scott: Nah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I see you as the bomb.
Rym: Javert does more and better Yeah, but Javert wasn't around back then.
Scott: Yeah, it was.
Scott: it was just not as good as it is now.
Rym: It was not around in a form that I would have used.
Scott: No No one that you you don't use anything.
Rym: But Scott messaged me.
Rym: one is I'm playing counter-strike and it's great and I remember thinking I remember trying that game.
Rym: It was just a slow version of action quake.
Rym: No, I don't know why I would play that half-life one was crap Mmm, because the back then Quake 2 was still really big for the mods and the quake 2 mods were just about to die.
Scott: It's like as counter-strike gained in popularity quake 2 dropped off a cliff.
Rym: Yep, because before counter-strike took off I mean action quake and weapons factory and even like mega TF for quake 1 were still super super super popular Relatively, I mean if you compare it to the popular of games now.
Scott: It was.
Scott: it was there a popular relative to the time when you see when an FPS gaming wasn't Super crazy huge and not in broadband wasn't widespread.
Scott: Yeah, the pills games were wicked more popular than any other game.
Rym: Yeah, the people who had broadband were pretty much guaranteed to be in that culture of you know mod FPS quake 2 style gaming.
Scott: Yeah, if graphic in game development had gone slower and network speeds had gone faster Then quake 2 would be now And we all had broadband and it would be the number one game.
Rym: Yep And we could do a whole show about the progression of like the quake 2 era.
Scott: I think we already did a show about FPS is.
Scott: so yeah, we'd let's stick to the counter-strike.
Rym: but I tried the game again and I started getting it and I started liking it and I played it pretty much continuously until Natural selection.
Rym: I was discovered by me and then I went back to it and then tribes 2 came out and tribes 2 came out Before natural selection.
Rym: try well long before.
Rym: I don't really remember the chronology.
Rym: All I remember is when tribes 2 came out.
Rym: We stopped playing counter-strike pretty much until tribes 2 died.
Scott: Yeah, that's how it went.
Scott: Tribes - it's like counter-strike was this game.
Scott: You could always go back to because there are people always playing it.
Scott: Yeah, like every other FPS that came out, you know was just a dent in Counter-strike, you know unreal would come out and a few counter-strike people would go to unreal and then some of them would come back And every time a new big FPS came out counter-strike would go down a little bit and then go back up a little bit less Than that.
Scott: So, you know after it reaches peak it's been declining but It's still there with still thousands of players.
Rym: Yep I still I'll still bet that it's probably one of the most played FPS is still oh Absolutely, if not the most played.
Scott: just think about all those FPS.
Scott: is that put a dent in counter-strike over the years are now mostly dead.
Rym: Yep, I mean the.
Rym: the only real survivor that I know of is natural selection, which is hanging on.
Scott: There's that battlefield.
Scott: people play then.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It's a good game.
Rym: I'm just.
Scott: some people playing unreal some people play sin and some people play quake.
Rym: for yeah Not so many people play the newer quakes.
Rym: Yeah, like quake 3 was a flash in the pan.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: There's a bunch of.
Scott: well Quick, there's.
Scott: we'll talk about quick three another time.
Rym: Yeah, we could do a whole show on the reason anomaly.
Scott: Yeah, but there are a lot of half-life mods that have a small following.
Scott: you can always get a game as Sven co-op if you want or Science and industry.
Scott: Yeah, none of them, you know, maybe a hundred players at most.
Scott: that would be insane.
Rym: You can't just do with counter-strike with these games what you can do with counter-strike.
Rym: log on There's a server.
Rym: just click on the top server and play.
Scott: Yeah, and there's people there and they're good Mm-hmm, or they're punk kids punk kids All right, now we're not gonna talk about counter-strike cheating yeah, but the culture of counter-strike.
Rym: a lot of people pointed to it as the End-all or the bottom of the internet.
Scott: and that's just not true because the bottom of the internet is like style project and F Net and style project and fortune and fortune.
Scott: That's the bottom.
Rym: but people always make jokes about about the Terribleness of the people in counter-strike.
Rym: and there were a lot of assholes playing counter-strike, but they're mostly just 12 year olds.
Scott: They weren't assholes.
Scott: They're just there like every other 12 year old.
Rym: I think it's that so many people played counter-strike that Every server it was like a million different countries and depending on where you played there any every walk of life was represented in counter-strike.
Scott: Well every teenage male walk of life.
Scott: that is true.
Rym: true though.
Scott: I'd a few females here and there.
Rym: Yeah, I knew some pretty badass females at that game.
Rym: Oh, there are plenty of badass ones but but like I remember the people who complained the most about counter-strike were the people who never played it or Played some other obscure mod Like say the people who still played action quake long after counter-strike at one.
Rym: Those people had a very close-knit community where everyone knew everyone.
Rym: So when they get into counter-strike and not only does no one recognize or fear their clan tag but no one recognizes them or talks to them and there are people speaking strange lingos like stfu nub nub Jew I Think around back bomb number two.
Scott: Oh my god Go go go.
Scott: Okay, that's the end of the counter-strike radio jokes.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah fire hole.
Rym: now bear in mind that this is before I mean when counter-strike was super popular.
Rym: There wasn't the voice chat built in.
Scott: Yeah, all you could do is say the built-in things.
Rym: some people would use things like team speak But some people consider that cheating.
Scott: Yeah There's a lot of dead speak going on.
Scott: So they didn't want anyone to use any out-of-game chat Things.
Scott: while you play counter-strike, I have to admit Scott and I were the masters of oh We were totally the masters because we'd be in the same room playing cat for anyone doesn't know the way counter-strike works.
Scott: Let's do a short description.
Rym: We should we should.
Scott: so there's two teams the terrorists and the counter-terrorists.
Scott: There's three scenarios the DE Demolition scenario the CS counter-strike scenario and the a s the long-forgotten Assault scenario.
Rym: Well, no as was assassinate assassinate.
Scott: a scenario ultra long lost Escape es scenario.
Rym: Oh escape.
Scott: now, let's talk about the ultra long lost never to be played again.
Rym: escape scenario It was a really cool idea, but it didn't work.
Rym: Well, the reason it didn't work is that back when that was around and even that even today It's hard to make maps in half-life.
Rym: Oh real hard you because you have to make the map by modeling it, but you also have to program the map.
Rym: Yeah, it's basically you're writing code really the map making tools.
Scott: while they're better now than they were ass They're really not easy to use at all.
Rym: Plus some people like one map.
Rym: I think it was docks.
Rym: I don't remember all the details because I didn't really care but the map was a terrible terrible terrible map.
Rym: It just didn't work.
Rym: It was not a dead guy.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Rym: But then the guy the kid the punk kid who made the map killed himself not long after making the mat.
Rym: so all the servers kept playing the map and talking about awesome.
Rym: the map was as a tribute to this kid and While it's horrible the kid died.
Rym: the map he made was terrible.
Rym: There's no reason that we should have to subject ourselves to that and in fact I got banned from a server for saying that that map sucks because the admin was like a kid died for this map.
Scott: Okay, yeah Yes, yes is an escape map.
Scott: This is where the terrorists are in a prison of some sort and they have to escape Which means they all have to get to some other place on the map before the counter-terrorists kill them all.
Rym: They usually don't start with weapons.
Scott: Yes, it really sucked.
Scott: It was a good idea and if it was executed properly would make a really fun game but it was never executed properly and Everyone would go change the map or servers would just take the map out of the rotation and that would be it
Rym: Yep,
Scott: and then they took the maps out of counter-strike all together.
Rym: Now as was probably my favorite Was also my favorite there were only a few maps where it actually worked.
Rym: Yep, now the whole thing is.
Rym: one guy was the VIP.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: He was a counter-terrorist.
Rym: Yeah I think he was giving a. he was given a pistol and he had a whole bunch of body armor on and he was a Person.
Rym: his only goal was to escape to the helicopter Yep, and it really suck.
Rym: as if you were a counter-terrorist you would be randomly selected to be the VIP Which sometimes it was like you could tell because it always kind of randomly picked.
Rym: but there if you were good and you kept surviving It tended to keep picking you
Scott: kinda yeah yeah, but but it really sucked because it threw this big kink in the game where if whoever got picked to be the VIP suck Your game was basically screwed no matter how good the rest of the CT's were.
Rym: or by the same token Sometimes you really didn't like say the terrorists are just owning you and every round they just gun the guy down.
Rym: Suddenly you're the VIP.
Rym: You have no weapons.
Rym: You've got a little pistol.
Rym: You got to worry about all your friends and then here come the terrorists to gun you down.
Rym: Yeah, you're running away high corners.
Scott: my situation it was usually I was a counter-terrorist.
Scott: we'd lose lose lose.
Scott: I would be the VIP and I would go my patented VIP oil rig guaranteed escape route.
Rym: Yeah every single time My what was the snow one?
Rym: That was my favorite.
Rym: Yeah, Tundra was my favorite assassinate man.
Scott: No, it's all about oil rig.
Scott: Anyway, then comes the CS.
Scott: the CS and the DE maps are pretty much most of the maps.
Scott: Yep, CS is counter-strike.
Scott: This is where the.
Scott: there are some hostages which are not actual players.
Scott: They're just kind of standing there.
Rym: Yeah, they used to be tricks you could do with them.
Rym: we'll talk about.
Scott: yeah, they're in some part of the map and The counter-terrorists need to rescue these hostages.
Scott: so they need to go to where the hostages are touch the hostages then go to Back to where the counter-terrorists started and then the hostages are rescued.
Scott: So you have to go into the enemy base and out and the terrorists all they have to do is prevent the counter-terrorists from rescuing.
Rym: Now for the long job the game was set up where to grab a hostage.
Rym: You basically run up to him and use him and then he'll follow you around like a dude.
Rym: Mm-hmm now terrorists could do this, too.
Rym: so Smart terrorists would grab one hostage and hide him somewhere or they grab all the hostages and stash him in a closet somewhere and guard That yep.
Scott: No, you couldn't kill the hostages because then you would lose your money, which we'll talk about later.
Scott: Yeah, you're killing the hostages no matter what team you are on screwed you.
Scott: So unless you were desperate you wouldn't kill all the hostages.
Scott: a lot of times hostages got gunned down just in a firefight But that was a because a terrorist would sit near the hostages waiting for the counter-terrorists to come and rescue them And then the counter-terrorists would show up.
Scott: There'd be a billion bullets everywhere and some you know hostages get killed.
Scott: It just happens Yeah, anyway, and then there's the DE map.
Scott: DE is demolitions.
Scott: This is where there are two one or more bomb spots Usually two sometimes three and the terrorists want to blow up any of these bomb spots.
Scott: if they blow up just one of them They win.
Scott: one guy randomly selected on the terrorist team has a bomb The only bomb and he has to bring that bomb to one of the bomb spots set it up Which takes like five seconds then wait around for it to explode and hope that a counter-terrorist doesn't come and defuse it.
Scott: now If you die before you plant the bomb someone else on your team can pick it up and go do the job.
Scott: If the bomb is defused it's over because you only have one bomb.
Scott: and once you plant the bomb You can't pick it up and bring it somewhere else.
Scott: It's you planted it.
Scott: That's where it's gonna be until it either explodes or is defused.
Scott: Yep You could also always win any game of counter-strike by killing the other team to a point.
Rym: if the terrorists plant the bomb and then They all get killed but the bomb still goes off terrorists win the terrorists still win.
Rym: That's right.
Scott: terrorists win suicide terrorist bombers.
Rym: I was just thinking of some natural selection things, but I'll talk about those another day.
Rym: Yes another.
Scott: the thing that made counter-strike real popular were two things.
Scott: number one in Any route counter-strike is played in rounds you play until someone wins then you do it again then do it again Then you change the map.
Rym: there's short rounds.
Rym: Yeah the game itself You know, there are games like SWAT.
Rym: there are games that involve terrorism counterterrorism action.
Rym: Basically, the premise of counter-strike is that the round begins the moment that negotiations broke down.
Scott: Yep So it's the.
Scott: you know, the terrorists made some demands.
Scott: the counter-terrorists didn't agree to the demands.
Scott: and then you know You go click.
Scott: they said the counter-terrorists decided to go in or the terrorists decided.
Scott: All right We're gonna go plant this bomb.
Scott: fuck those guys.
Scott: They didn't meet our demands.
Scott: and then as soon as the game says let's go team.
Scott: That's the minute that you know, you decided that you're gonna go do the job.
Rym: Yeah, you make your dynamic entry a big firefight.
Rym: someone comes out on top.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: There's a time limit.
Rym: you have an objective.
Rym: It's not just kill other people like most FPS is were.
Scott: Yes, the one problem in counter-strike is that if you don't end up with good players, they won't try for the objective.
Scott: They'll just try to camp or kill all the other players and they won't help you plant the bomb.
Scott: many a time I would go with the bomb or and plant it on my own or rescue the hostages all on my own.
Rym: Well, everyone else is fighting somewhere else and if Scott and I were on a team and our team sucked It just didn't matter.
Rym: we could handle it.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: As long as the other team wasn't really really good I mean, I don't want to brag.
Rym: Well, I love bragging but Scott and I were Extremely badass at counter-strike.
Scott: I don't know how badass we are now now Counter-strike source where we mostly played the older counter-strike.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean when we played when we played we were pretty good.
Rym: I mean we the to one of us joining a team could pretty much turn the tide.
Scott: I would say most of the time that we lost it was because of a cheater.
Rym: Yeah, I would honestly agree with that.
Rym: I mean We're just really freaking good at that game.
Scott: But also many times when we won it was because the cheater was on our team.
Rym: You want to know why we were so good.
Rym: We wasted countless hours when we refresh whenever we weren't Class.
Scott: you're playing counter-strike until nighttime when we did something else instead.
Rym: Yeah, because we'd all get together and play D&D and battle tech and stuff at night But during the day between classes we just played counter-strike.
Scott: Yeah, what else are you gonna do for that short amount of time?
Rym: five rounds of CS duh, and you know, what's amazing?
Rym: Pretty much everyone else did too.
Rym: Yeah walking walking around the dorms at RIT at any given daylight hour.
Scott: All you could hear in any room was either ticketing Or Those are the two things you heard at RIT dorms.
Rym: Sometimes you heard both.
Rym: Oh, you know one roommates playing doesn't notice.
Scott: the other roommates The two gimmicks they're not really gimmicks they're the gate.
Scott: They're the gameplay aspects that make counter-strike unique and awesome.
Rym: Yeah the gimmicks.
Scott: Yes One of them is that when you die you don't respawn.
Scott: now if you've ever played quake the second you die You push a button and now you're in the game again immediately.
Scott: I know just keep playing and playing and playing until you get enough kills and the game's over and Counter-strike.
Scott: when you die you're out for the rest of the round until one of the team's wins.
Scott: You can just float around doing nothing usually watching what's going on.
Scott: Well early on you could watch what was going on and now you can too.
Scott: I remember in one version They added the black screen of death.
Rym: Yeah, you couldn't see or at least you could only see what your teammates could see.
Rym: Yeah, because otherwise here's the scenario.
Rym: it is now which Scott and I did occasionally just for fun.
Rym: Usually when we were on opposite teams, like I was a terrorist and he was a counter terrorist But then say he died because one of us shot him.
Rym: He would then tell me where the last guys were just different in the round quicker But alright, so we're on the same team.
Rym: Let's say in a tournament whatever and I die.
Rym: What's to stop me from floating around and then calling Scott on his cell phone and telling him?
Rym: Yeah, the last terrorist is hiding behind the box at the far end of bombsite.
Scott: be yep and That was known as ghosting and it's kind of cheating but not really.
Rym: Yeah, it's pretty much cheating.
Rym: Yeah, the thing is no one ever did it in a real match And if you did you were just kind of an asshole.
Scott: no one did it in a real match.
Scott: No but anyway The second thing about counter-strike was the weapons.
Scott: The way it worked is when you started a game of counter-strike you had what like eight hundred bucks.
Rym: Yeah, eight hundred dollars not really hundred dollars.
Scott: eight hundred dollars in the game and with those eight hundred dollars You could buy Weapons and different weapons cost different amounts of money and you had to pay for ammo and you had to pay for armor.
Rym: you had to pay for grenades and the weapons were Varied enough to where you really felt good buying a different weapon and the weapons were all modeled after real weapons.
Rym: now They weren't realistic in a literal sense.
Scott: Not yet.
Scott: A military fanboy would be pissed off.
Scott: However, I compared to quake or doom or wolfenstein.
Scott: these things are awesome.
Rym: They were extremely realistic from a minor pseudo military fanboy perspective exactly.
Rym: You know the kids.
Rym: you like the kids.
Rym: you hear any.
Rym: you hear them all the time online talking about the merits of the stair versus the m4 carbine Carbine.
Rym: a lot of people say carbine whatever.
Rym: anyway those kids they eat it up.
Rym: kids love talking about desert eagles.
Scott: They are So usually in the first round of counter-strike on a prop on a server.
Scott: that didn't you know?
Scott: cuz servers could say you could start With more money, but most of them didn't.
Scott: it would be the pistol round because you could only afford pistols.
Scott: now everyone starts No matter what you get this shit pistol.
Scott: And the other thing is different teams have different weapons.
Scott: the counter terrorists have in my opinion much better weapons But they're more expensive.
Scott: They are more.
Rym: terrorists get all the AKs and Mac 10.
Scott: Terrorists get AK-47s Mac 10s and SIGs while I mean terrorists get those and counter-terrorists get Augs, and I remember when they added the p90 p9.
Rym: there's both.
Scott: people got that or the five seven pistol the five seven pistol the and then the terrorists have the The elites.
Rym: Yeah, the elites Oh elites.
Rym: That was the dumbest thing ever the best pistol.
Scott: Oh my god I went through a phase where I would try to elite all I could.
Scott: I always kept my elites And then I would whip them out whenever I had a chance.
Rym: I have for some reason.
Rym: I love using the normal shotgun.
Rym: Really pump shotgun.
Rym: it was terrible.
Rym: I usually died, but there was nothing more satisfying better than using the noob cannon.
Rym: There's nothing more satisfying in the world than standing there and a terrorist war runs around the corner And he stops and he's about to shoot you and you turn and you put one Shotgun blast into him and he flies over and falls dead.
Scott: Yeah, his friends and you gotta reload and pump and someone kills you.
Rym: Yeah Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, no the the super shotgun the Benelli in counter-strike is known as the noob cannon.
Scott: Some people who don't know might call some other guns the noob cannon.
Scott: They're idiots.
Scott: The noob cannon is the Benelli shotgun.
Scott: The thing about the Benelli shotgun is an automatic shotgun.
Scott: It's real you could fire it like how many times it was But it was like doo doo doo doo doo doo doo Until you ran out of shells and you could fire like eight times I think before you had to reload.
Scott: now reloading took a while because you had to go click Click click as you filled it with shotgun shells But you could interrupt the loading process to shoot which most other guns you couldn't yep.
Scott: So you'd be like, you know, you would start with a full loadout, you know And you'd go you'd see a guy and you go doo doo doo doo.
Rym: now The reason a lot of people call it the noob cannon is that in in close quarters I mean someone skilled could deal with it and team tactics could definitely take it out.
Rym: It wasn't the best weapon.
Rym: It was however the best weapon for someone who had absolutely no skill and they probably kill someone.
Scott: yeah, if you have absolutely no accuracy in your aiming and You need to kill someone and do a lot of damage Your best bet is to use the noob cannon.
Scott: you get a bunch of guys in front of you You push the button as fast as you can and you're likely to deal out a lot of damage.
Scott: It's like the real world if you had an auto shotgun and you're in a room full of I don't know five-year-olds If you had an auto shotgun and you in a room full of Navy SEALs You would still hose them until and they would kill you.
Scott: maybe like, you know five after you shot a bunch of shells.
Scott: Yep, you could get plenty of shots off if you knew what you're doing.
Scott: You can't miss a target with an automatic shotgun, especially not like across the room maybe across the field but not across the room.
Scott: and counter-strike had a lot of rooms and not so many fields because of the half-life engine didn't really allow For outdoors so much.
Scott: Yep, half-life 2 engine fixes that.
Rym: now We actually at one point decided to run a counter-strike server on.
Rym: well How slow was that piece of crap computer we had?
Scott: it was a piece of shit, man I think it was in my old Pentium 3 450 or no, it was even slower.
Scott: It was a Pentium 200.
Rym: I think it was a Pentium 200.
Rym: It might have been a 233.
Rym: It was old and shitty.
Rym: We were we just we really wanted to run a counter-strike server, but we didn't have money or extra computers Mm-hmm.
Rym: So we took this crap old computer.
Rym: We put counter-strike on it.
Rym: we discovered that as long as less than seven people were on the server the ping was okay if More than seven people were on or if the map was actually a real map as opposed to icy world Which is the only map we could run.
Scott: Yeah, the icy world if you don't know is the smallest tiniest map.
Rym: It's also a map with no objective.
Rym: It's one of the FY maps which unofficially stands for fuck you.
Rym: Yeah, and all those maps are is kill the other guys And it's real small and you can.
Scott: this is weapons lying on the ground at the start of the map.
Scott: So all you would do is you would start pick up a weapon and go and then it would be over in five seconds.
Scott: Yeah And that's why our server was able to run it because it was the simplest map.
Rym: now when we made the server Servers that ran those maps weren't that common yet.
Rym: So our server was in high demand and full Constantly despite the fact people wanted to play icy world.
Scott: Our server was always full and we had a good.
Scott: was a 10 on 10 going on or was an 8 on 8?
Scott: It was a good number for icy world.
Scott: I remember that.
Rym: Yeah, the problem was if any if all those people connected the servers ping got real bad.
Scott: No, I remember we set the limit to like the max the server could handle.
Rym: Yeah point which wasn't so much.
Scott: It was good enough.
Rym: We had.
Rym: we often kick people off so we could play.
Scott: that's true.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: It's because we couldn't setting up all the stuff that lets you reserve slots is a pain in the ass.
Rym: Yeah, setting up setting up any sort of Counter-Strike server was an incredibly painful process.
Scott: It's less painful now Thanks to steam But it's still to set the mods on the server to make the server do fancy things is still sucky Mostly because it's that was from the previous generation of mods.
Rym: I mean playing the old quake 2 mods.
Rym: Try yeah, all of you kids now who played these new games, you know, like Counter-Strike source and natural selection Go find a copy of quake 2 and try to even figure out how to shoot in some of those mods for quake 2.
Rym: Yeah, those games you would have to write your own scripts to do anything.
Rym: Yep, those games were nuts.
Rym: You really have it easy these days but the servers for a lot of the early half-life 1 mods and Counter-Strike Were about that level of pain in the assness.
Scott: the other problem But really was even when things were easy to do which they often were they were poorly Redocumented and the websites for the software were hard to find because there really weren't official websites for any of these things.
Scott: Yeah, they were all other websites You know distributing them and he was all.
Scott: it was very hard to find out exactly the latest and greatest Information and the complete information was like a big secret.
Rym: PC gaming is a lot easier now Thanks to the Xbox 360 mostly.
Scott: Yeah and steam But yeah, so counter-strike Good memories.
Rym: Yeah I mean when I think back that game It's weird to think that I have so many fond memories from such a simple stupid game, but I played it constantly.
Scott: Yep Let's think of some good counter-strike memories.
Rym: Oh, I remember this one time.
Rym: It was in Kabul and Not Kabul as in Iraq But Kabul as in this place full of cobblestones and I was a terrorist with an ak-47 And I'm walking.
Rym: then Scott was on the server.
Rym: I think he was dead.
Rym: He was watching and I was walking around and For some reason like this is just random because I would just shoot my gun around a lot because I like doing that and I just kind of flipped around and fired a shot off in the distance and then it I saw a headshot from Shazar and I'd gotten someone and then they kicked me off the server for cheating.
Rym: Holy crap I don't know what the odds of that were.
Scott: I Had a similar situation on this map.
Scott: I forget the name of it.
Scott: Actually, it was it's.
Scott: it was like the Spanish castle or something and it was water and you would run into the castle.
Scott: I don't really remember.
Rym: I remember that map and there was a.
Scott: I think there was a sundial somewhere.
Rym: Yes Yes, I don't know what it was called.
Rym: Not many servers ran it, but I love that map.
Scott: Yeah, and I think we had the bomb planted or I was looking for the bomb.
Scott: I remember I was a terrorist.
Scott: I wanted to plant the bomb and I was walking around And I had a desert eagle and that was about it.
Scott: I had used up everything else and this guy's coming down the stairs and I pretty much turn and fire one shot and his he just falls over dead and I'm like, holy crap And the guy was like lucky shot and I'm like, yup that was.
Rym: I've had a lot of moments where it was real dicey like my whole team gets killed and I'm on my own and I got like a pistol and the bomb and Somehow I'd weasel my way through.
Rym: everyone plant the bomb kill a bunch of people go on a rampage.
Scott: I have a lot of great moments where My favorite thing to do in counter-strike is to take a clever path through the map.
Scott: like an Aztec I would always take the secret stairs, even though it's not so secret anymore.
Scott: No, but and in Assault oil rig I would always go my secret back way.
Scott: We're basically no one would be where I was until I made my mad dash for the helicopter you know.
Scott: and Oh, there was also good one in Vegas.
Scott: I would take the back way also.
Scott: That was a good map one time.
Rym: This isn't anything awesome.
Rym: I did I was playing in I was office and I was the last counter-terrorist alive and the last terrorist was also alive.
Rym: who's one versus one?
Rym: and I know that everyone else in the map was watching us because our little fight was going on for a while.
Rym: We were stalking each other around.
Rym: It was unlimited time server.
Rym: So I was stalking, you know, very carefully.
Rym: I had my m4 silenced and I'm poking around and poking around and I Was walking silently and he was walking silently and for minutes and minutes.
Rym: We couldn't find each other.
Rym: So finally I'm walking very slowly and For a while and then I get this feeling and I I turn around and he's standing right there With a knife and he's been standing there and I didn't know what to do.
Rym: I would I almost.
Rym: I jumped out of my chair like yeah and then he stabbed me to death.
Rym: and Then the voice chat turned on for me for all the dead people and all I heard was them laughing their asses off as they Explained to me that he'd been following me like that for over a minute.
Rym: Yeah And the fact that I was so dumbstruck I couldn't even shoot him.
Rym: Yeah, it's a good yeah, like I literally I was like, yeah and I stood up a little bit and it was too late.
Scott: Yeah encounters like you always want to look all over the place real quick all the time.
Scott: Yep You never most of the time when you and you need dying counter-strike.
Scott: It's you shot in the back.
Scott: Usually when you you know, you're facing someone the odds of a firefight is pretty much just random But when you just get killed right out, it's in the back of the head.
Rym: Yep I mean playing against people who were a good as we were good.
Rym: it was really just a tactical game of strategy and teamwork.
Rym: and What kind of plan the counter-terrorists would put together to do blah or what route we would take or how we would do it?
Rym: Or what kind of like wave we would move in?
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Strategies would be things like, you know all right, one guy has the para and let's loose and everyone else runs down the tunnel or Everyone go everyone rush left.
Scott: every absolutely everyone on the team go left because if you're on the defensive team usually want to have some guys at all.
Scott: the different ways that the way the maps are constructed is that you know, the Terrorists start in one area and the counter-terrorists start in another area and there are multiple paths To get from one area to the other and one team is gonna be pushing and one team is gonna be blocking.
Scott: Based on if it's DE the terrorists push and on CS the counter-terrorists push.
Scott: So the defenders usually want to cover all the different entrances because if they leave one Unguarded then there's a chance that all the offensive to the team will just go through that door.
Scott: No one will be there to stop them and they'll win a game over.
Scott: The offensive team wants to have all of their team go to one entrance.
Scott: that way Even there even if there's a few guards at that entrance They'll be able to kill him and still have a whole team.
Scott: They're ready to go.
Scott: So, you know this strategy would be like rush left brush middle rush, right?
Scott: You know stuff.
Rym: but even then I mean good teams.
Rym: you had the the actual mechanics of all right.
Rym: Like.
Rym: well, they'll run in and this guy will sweep to the left and this other guy runs straight forward Not looking at anyone.
Rym: the next two people walk in and throw flashes in this direction.
Scott: plans like that Yep, and then would also be you know defensive strategies that you know.
Scott: you.
Scott: way I described it You think the offense would always win?
Scott: But the defense could do things like throw flash grenades as soon as they saw anyone walk through the entrance.
Scott: Then that would be a signal to all the other defenders to get over there as well as completely screwing up the offense.
Scott: Then that you know, they could throw some smoke in there, you know kill the guys at a choke point.
Scott: So even though they're in a big group, they have to walk through the door one at a time.
Scott: They all get killed as they walk through the door.
Rym: of course a lot of times we play it on servers with people who weren't so good and At that point it became I am Rym aka Rambo.
Rym: I walk around with an mp5 killing everyone.
Scott: I see no one can stop me except for the one guy who just stopped you.
Scott: Yeah, you killed a whole bunch of guys.
Rym: Yeah Cuz no matter how good you were One guy could not often take on the entire enemy team.
Rym: you could take out most of them But then it really depends on the on the skill of the other team.
Scott: they had to be pretty bad to completely lose to you, but in terms of I Could hardly ever kill many guys on the other team if I killed more than four guys in a round.
Scott: That was crazy.
Scott: And in fact three guys is a damn good round.
Scott: help two guys is a good round You know, but often I would win on my own by completing the objective.
Scott: I would go in alone with the bomb I would go around the back way all alone with the terrorists and the hostages and rescue them.
Scott: Yeah, rescue the terrorists.
Scott: I'd rescue the hostages all alone, but trying to fight the other team alone was What do you how do you say?
Rym: I don't know how you say what are you trying to?
Scott: fruitless?
Scott: Silly, what's the other word for silly?
Scott: Silly a waste of time.
Scott: Feudal.
Scott: it was futile That's the word.
Rym: that's the one futile rare.
Scott: Yes, trying to fight the other team on your own was futile But I think that's enough rambling.
Rym: we killed enough time and now I can finish playing with my brand new shiny Mac mini and then Go to bed and next Monday Rym.
Rym: We'll talk about the Mac Yep, because I'm not switching to OS X but I am adding OS X to my repertoire of computing and I will have many Insights both pro and con to the experiences.
Rym: I've had.
Scott: also if anyone's interested I just I switch from gen 2 to Ubuntu today.
Rym: Yeah captain gen 2 is just switched.
Scott: Well, we'll talk about that next Monday.
Scott: Also, we'll talk about the two switches.
Rym: Monday will be switch day.
Rym: Yes, there you go and don't forget the how computers work thing.
Rym: any feedback would be appreciated.
Rym: We tried to slow it down for you guys.
Scott: Yeah, obviously cuz Monday's gonna be switch day that'll be delayed.
Scott: episode 3 will be delayed another week on that.
Scott: and What's tomorrow?
Rym: tomorrow's easy?
Rym: We're gonna cover.
Rym: I'm gonna talk about the mocha Arts Festival and then next Wednesday We're going to talk about anime next Which we're going to this weekend.
Scott: We just haven't reviewed any anime.
Scott: Have we?
Scott: no we've got a pile of great animal That makes all the anime podcast happy because we're not stealing their thunder.
Rym: Oh, we'll get back to stealing it right quick.
Rym: Okay, actually, you know what?
Rym: tomorrow on anime day, I think while we won't review them We will give you the list of all the good shows we're watching right now.
Rym: So you can't really that many now.
Rym: there aren't so many but they're good and there's enough that are good And that way you'll know what we're gonna what we're gonna talk about once we get around to it.
Rym: Okay, and That was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is accorded with absolutely no studio and no audience But unlike those other talk shows it's actually recorded at night.