Scott: It's Tuesday, April 25th, and this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight, we talk about the amazing board game, Kalus.
Scott: Kalus.
Scott: Let's do this!
Rym: So now that it's spring, I'm actually really seriously looking into buying a motorcycle.
Scott: Oh, really?
Rym: Yeah, considering that most of the jobs I've been looking at either aren't actually easily commutable to buy a train, or for various reasons I would need my car there, I really think in general it'd be nice to have a motorcycle to get to work every day.
Scott: Yeah, unless, you know, the weather's bad, or you die.
Rym: Yeah, I mean my dad used to motorcycle a lot, and Emily's sister likes motorcycles, and honestly I'm not too, I don't know, full of ego to go to class and ask for help because I have no idea how to ride a motorcycle.
Rym: I'll be taking all the relevant classes.
Rym: Of course, but wearing all of the relevant armors on my bits.
Scott: Yeah, but even people with much skill in motorcycle, you know, it's like the number of motorcycle accidents when you look at, like, you know, it's always this sketchy thing when people argue about this, like, oh, they're dangerous or not dangerous, because you look at it, and it seems to be the total number of motorcycle accidents is much rarer than car accidents, but also motorcycles are much rarer than cars.
Rym: Yeah, I'm not too worried.
Rym: I mean, I guess in the end it would be so much cheaper than driving with the gas prices, what they are, that it's worth the tiny risk to my life.
Scott: Yeah, but the thing is when there's a motorcycle accident, it's like, oh no, it's, but when there's a car accident, it's like, most, some of the time, you're just like, eh, whatever.
Scott: Even, you know, you're alive, but the car, that's another story.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, they said there was a meeting in the city.
Scott: I was actually gonna get work to do, and right before I got on the train, email, oh, no meeting.
Rym: So why'd you even get on the train?
Scott: Because I had this new hard drive for my work laptop, and I went to the city, because then I could get the Windows CDs and all that jazz.
Rym: You know, I could have just given you a Windows CD.
Scott: Yeah, get one for my work, because it's my work's laptop.
Scott: I'm not gonna use...
Rym: Why not?
Rym: The CD is a CD.
Rym: What matters is the key, which you can get from your current legal installation from work.
Scott: Oh, okay, hold on.
Scott: There's a key on the bottom of this laptop.
Scott: You see that?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Doesn't fucking work.
Rym: Um, is it for the right version of the operating system?
Scott: It says right on there, Windows XP Professional.
Rym: One or two, two to you.
Rym: Are you sure it's not a bulk or OEM license that sometimes does require a different CD?
Scott: I have a feeling it is.
Rym: Well, good job.
Rym: I could have gotten you that CD, too.
Scott: Doesn't matter, 'cause I needed some other work softwares, which I don't have.
Rym: Alright, good game.
Rym: So you went down to the city to pick up a CD.
Scott: Well, and also, I'd just like to say that Windows sucks ass.
Scott: Anyone who still thinks, like, "Okay, what does Windows have going for
Scott: it?".
Scott: Gaming.
Scott: Well, that, and it has a bajillion drivers for all the hardware in the universe, right?
Rym: Uh, also support for, uh, this little bit that I bought to recorded cons that doesn't work in Linux.
Scott: That's not something going for Windows.
Scott: That's something against that little bit.
Rym: Yeah, I point out that there's no such thing as a little bit like this that works in Linux, as far as I know.
Scott: There are.
Scott: They're just, uh, you know...
Rym: Expensive.
Scott: 'Cause, you know, quality.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: Besides gaming.
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: The point is, is that people are always like, "Oh, it's really hard to get Linux to work on a laptop.
Scott: It doesn't support all this
Scott: stuff."
Scott: And, "Oh, Windows just works great on
Scott: laptops.".
Scott: Well, I tried to install Windows on a laptop today, and it didn't have a goddamn driver.
Scott: Didn't have a driver for the network card.
Scott: I had to go get it.
Rym: Yeah, you know what?
Rym: I'll point out that you have an IBM ThinkPad, and usually when they install the OS on an IBM ThinkPad, they install it from the recovery disk, and it comes with everything already.
Scott: Yeah, well, screw that.
Rym: Yeah, well, that's what you get for using Windows.
Rym: It's not my problem.
Scott: I'm just, you know, it's not me that wants to use Windows.
Scott: It's the work that forces me to use it.
Scott: Part of the reason I got the bigger hard drive is so I can throw some other OSes on the other area.
Rym: Wait, so, uh, why does the work force you to use the Windows?
Scott: Because the work isn't so smart.
Rym: So, uh, there's the work has a... So there's some applications that, uh, you need to use Windows for, and thus that's another...
Scott: None that I do!
Scott: I don't know how to use shit.
Rym: Well, apparently you have to.
Rym: Otherwise, you wouldn't need Windows.
Scott: I don't need to use shit.
Scott: They need to use Windows.
Scott: They want to be able to, you know, do their Windows thing to my computer.
Rym: All right, so then as a result, you have to use Windows in order to have a job.
Scott: Well, it's my work's computers, not my computer.
Rym: All right, all right.
Scott: But it sucks.
Rym: Because you realize most people who use Windows are forced to use Windows for various reasons.
Scott: Yeah, but the point I'm making here is that, you know, one of the things that is often touted is the, you know, good part of using Windows is that all the hardware is easily supported and such.
Scott: Uh, it's not true.
Scott: It's just a bunch of shit.
Scott: I could put a live CD from any Linux distribution in here and it just works.
Rym: God damn.
Rym: Uh, on a lot of laptops that isn't the case, and a lot of times the wireless won't work.
Scott: Yeah, those laptops suck.
Rym: Yeah, you seem to think everything sucks.
Scott: Yeah, everything does.
Scott: Most things suck.
Rym: Nah, I take a more optimistic approach.
Rym: Only many things suck, not most things.
Scott: Most things suck.
Scott: Nah.
Scott: Meh.
Scott: Yeah, most things suck.
Rym: Eh, puppies.
Scott: They suck.
Rym: What's wrong with you?
Rym: Uh, Firefly.
Scott: Serenity.
Scott: Sucks.
Scott: It's the same damn thing.
Rym: No, no, Serenity was the movie.
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: It's the same shit.
Rym: Star Trek.
Scott: All of it sucks.
Rym: Star Trek's awesome.
Scott: It sucks.
Rym: What about, uh, Star Wars?
Scott: Doesn't suck.
Rym: Episode one.
Scott: Sucks.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Anyway, uh, all right, E.T.
Rym: the extraterrestrial, the movie.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: The game.
Scott: It's not the worst thing ever.
Rym: Um, yes it is.
Scott: No, it's not.
Rym: I submit that Custer's Revenge had more redeeming gameplay than
Rym: E.T.,
Rym: the extraterrestrial for the Atari 2600.
Scott: I don't know about that, but I do know that E.T.
Rym: for the 2600, while there was a big fiasco surrounding it of cartridges in a dump- You pilot a blob into pits to pick up other blobs that you then return to a larger blob.
Rym: The control scheme consists of hitting a button repeatedly and hoping something happens.
Scott: Isn't that most games?
Scott: Yes, it is.
Rym: Custer's Revenge had more redeeming gameplay.
Rym: It was also more straightforward.
Rym: You had to dodge those arrows and do your thing.
Rym: None of this falling in pits, FBI agents dragging your ass around.
Scott: Yes, there was more to it in E.T No, there wasn't.
Rym: Fall in a pit.
Rym: Nothing here.
Rym: Fly out.
Rym: Fall in another pit.
Rym: Oh, a dead flower.
Rym: I bring it back to life.
Rym: Fall in a pit.
Rym: Oh, a blob.
Rym: I'll touch it.
Rym: Oh, now I have a status thing.
Rym: Oh, the G-Man came and took it away.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, in video game news, we all remember Infineon, who- or Infinium.
Rym: Not Infineon, Infinium.
Scott: Infineon makes chips.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And they have a racetrack.
Rym: Infinium made- well, said they made the Phantom Gaming Console, which was supposed to be a competitor to the PS2 and the GameCube and the Xbox.
Rym: It was also supposed to be a competitor to every console ever.
Rym: It was supposed to be- basically, it was touted as the most awesome, amazing, perfect console ever.
Rym: It'll bring a revolution to the gaming industry.
Rym: It'll be everything you could ever hope for.
Scott: I thought they were just saying it was going to be a console that played PC games.
Scott: I thought that's what they were saying.
Rym: Well, at first, but they kept getting more and more like, "This is big.
Rym: Ooh, it can do this.
Rym: It can do
Rym: this.".
Rym: The specs they- when they announced it, the specs they gave, which were very vague, were well beyond what you could afford to put into a little console.
Rym: And regardless, they never actually made the Phantom Console.
Rym: They faced bankruptcy, and there was all sorts of shenanigans going on with the fact that the company really kind of didn't actually exist.
Rym: Well, then they straightened themselves out, and they claimed to have a real product, the Phantom Latboard.
Rym: Now, I note that the console, the one that never existed, was called the Phantom.
Rym: Now, this Latboard, which we've seen pictures of, is also called the Phantom.
Rym: And it seems like a cool idea.
Rym: It's a little thing you put on your lap, and it has a keyboard in it and a spot for a mouse, and is basically a way to use a computer in the living room easily without a table.
Rym: Cool idea.
Rym: This was the only product this company has ever produced or claimed they were going to produce and had any evidence of having a prototype that I've ever seen.
Rym: And, uh, things were going well.
Rym: Until it was announced, recently, that this product, like the Phantom Console, has now been mysteriously delayed.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Hmm.
Scott: See, this is the only good thing to come out of the Phantom, was this cool little lap keyboard thing.
Scott: The fact that it's not coming is, uh, being sad, actually.
Rym: I submit that other things came out of the Phantom Console.
Rym: For one, about seven Penny Arcade comics that were hilarious.
Rym: A media shitstorm.
Rym: Lots of lolling.
Scott: Yeah, that, you know, there's a lot of things like that that came out of Jack Thompson.
Scott: That doesn't mean I still wanted to be around.
Rym: Oh, I want Jack Thompson to be around.
Rym: I can't wait for my next thing of the day to be Jack Thompson.
Scott: Uh, I, I really can get it.
Scott: Uh, I've had enough with Jack.
Rym: I don't know what next.
Rym: He'd have to sue me for me to talk about him again.
Rym: Maybe I'll start talking about the people over at Avinium.
Scott: Maybe, of course, uh, they really don't care.
Scott: I mean, they're just done.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: All right, so there's some rumors going around.
Rym: There's some rumors going around.
Scott: First of all, on May 9th, write that on your calendar.
Scott: May 9th.
Scott: That's the date of the Nintendo Super Press Conference at E3.
Rym: Now, I'm not gonna try to sound like a Nintendo fanboy here, and I'd say there's a small chance that this is going to be one of those moments that years from now we'll remember, and fellow geeks will ask each other, "Where were you when it was
Rym: announced?".
Scott: I don't think it'll be quite that amazing.
Rym: Hence, I gave some fairly meager odds on it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It depends on what they announce.
Rym: If it's just the rumor that you're about to tell me, I'm not so excited.
Scott: No, no, no, but on that day, they're going to basically give the full story on the revolution.
Scott: There will be nothing left hidden after May 9th.
Scott: That all will be out in the open.
Scott: Probably the release date, the price, the feature set, some launch titles.
Scott: Everything will be way out in the open.
Scott: And everyone will go,
Scott: "Woo-hoo!".
Rym: Meanwhile, Sony, whose PS3 was supposed to be released already, has nothing for E3.
Scott: Yeah, well, we're not worried about that right now.
Scott: What we're worried about is the latest rumor is that one of the things that we will learn about the revolution on May 9th could possibly be, according to sources...
Rym: Wow, I think that was enough disclaimers.
Rym: Yeah, okay.
Scott: You know the little nunchuck thing attached to the revolution controller?
Rym: Has the little directional pad on it.
Scott: Has an analog stick on it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And a button under it.
Scott: Or two buttons under it, or something like that.
Scott: You know, you don't have to use it with the revolution controller, but you should if you're going to play like a Metroid or something.
Scott: You move with that and you aim with the other one.
Scott: Anyway, supposedly, that will also be motion sensitive.
Scott: Not as motion sensitive as the revolution controller itself, but motion sensitive nonetheless, adding yet another axis of control.
Rym: So, uh, boxing games.
Rym: Drumming games.
Rym: Boxing games.
Scott: Anything that requires two hands.
Scott: Two hands shooting.
Rym: Ah.
Scott: Um, throwing two knives.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Rym: Yeah, you know, I also heard a rumor that the revolution is going to have a holographic 3D projector, it will fetch your mail, and fell at you regularly.
Scott: Oh really?
Rym: Yeah, really.
Scott: I had to get me some of that.
Rym: Yeah, basically, there's a lot of rumors and we really can't say anything until E3.
Rym: Which, by the way, GeekNights is not going to.
Rym: For a number of reasons.
Scott: We're not allowed in, et cetera, et cetera, et cetera.
Rym: Yeah, even though it's not hard to get into E3.
Scott: Supposedly they're making it harder this year.
Rym: Good.
Scott: We'll see what happens.
Rym: Hey, maybe one of us will win that contest.
Scott: Yeah, that would be awesome.
Scott: So, anyone who calls themselves a worthwhile geek these days knows about the DDRs and the guitar heroes.
Rym: Dance Dance Revolution.
Scott: Yeah, not double data rate or anything else that DDR stands for, because it stands for a lot of shit.
Rym: Now, there's a guy named DJ 8-Ball, who back in the day was well known as one of the best awesome DDR freestyle Funkmaster dancers ever.
Scott: Yeah, he was pretty good at DDR.
Scott: I mean, he probably, I don't know if he was good enough to get super perfects on every song ever.
Rym: Well, no, he did the freestyle.
Scott: Yeah, but he could do DDR and look really cool while doing DDR.
Scott: Like, if you took away the pads, he'd be really dancing, for real.
Rym: Well, this guy is reminiscent of that, except for one key difference.
Scott: He has one leg.
Rym: Really?
Scott: Really.
Scott: So, this guy is up on this DDR machine doing a somewhat difficult song on a somewhat difficult setting, and he has two crutches and one leg, and he does it rather well.
Rym: Yeah, the video is really kind of cool to see.
Scott: Like, most people who are missing a leg or something like that, you know, it's like most of them seem to just kind of get by, you know, and try to at least bring their lives back to what they would be if they didn't have a handicap.
Scott: But, you know, it's a rare guy like this that makes his life better than what it would be, you know.
Rym: Well, at least his life in regards to DDR.
Scott: Well, it doesn't look like his life's too bad.
Scott: He looks like he can get around pretty good.
Rym: Eh?
Rym: Well.
Scott: Well.
Rym: Mr.
Rym: Perry would be pissed.
Rym: You're lucky he's not here.
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: All right.
Scott: He could drown in a well for all I care.
Rym: So, why not die in a fire?
Scott: Well, because I wanted to use the word well.
Rym: Yeah, but die in a fire is the thing.
Rym: It's the thing going around.
Scott: It's not well.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So, so this has been making the rounds, but I want to talk about it, partly because some of my friends had a rather poor showing on it, and two, because it's something I can put in the forum and we can all have fun with it like we did with that nerd geek dork test a while ago.
Scott: Yeah, because there's two answers.
Scott: We don't know and we want someone to tell us what they are.
Rym: It's a simple little 8-bit test where it shows you a sprite from an 8-bit Nintendo video game and you have to say what game it is.
Rym: I got all but two of them.
Rym: Now, keep in mind that the rules in terms of us and GeekNights on a quiz like this is you can't think for more than like 10 seconds on one and you can't like Google it.
Rym: So, just right off the top of your head, which ones can you get?
Rym: I think there's 10 of them on the list.
Rym: 10 or 12.
Scott: Something like that.
Rym: I got all but two.
Rym: Scott got all but I think five.
Scott: I think it's almost like four.
Rym: Nah, you missed.
Scott: Some of them I should have had.
Scott: It was bullshit.
Rym: Yeah, I should have had, but you know what?
Scott: I give myself half credit for those.
Scott: No.
Scott: I get half credit on the Dr.
Scott: Mario and the...
Rym: Well, don't say anything because that'll ruin it for the people out there who haven't done it yet.
Scott: They don't know which one's Dr.
Scott: Mario.
Rym: It's obvious because there's only one of them.
Rym: it could be.
Scott: No, because they're not old school.
Rym: Besides Scott, it's obvious.
Rym: Besides, even then, that's the one you didn't get.
Scott: I knew it.
Scott: I just didn't know it.
Rym: Whatever.
Rym: We'll blow it away.
Rym: Scott didn't get the ninja from Final Fantasy I.
Scott: Oh, come on.
Scott: It was such a trick.
Rym: No, it wasn't.
Rym: It was.
Rym: He didn't get Dr.
Rym: Mario, one of the bugs.
Scott: It wasn't one of the bugs.
Scott: It was the weird guy.
Rym: He didn't get... No, that is the big representation of the bugs that it puts under the little magnifying glass.
Scott: No, the bugs, that's the different bug guy.
Scott: I'll show you later.
Rym: You also didn't get the eggplant wizard.
Scott: I never got very far in that game.
Scott: I didn't know what the hell the eggplant wizard was.
Scott: I recognized it as something familiar.
Rym: But he's even in Captain N. I mean, what the hell?
Scott: I never really watched Captain N that much.
Rym: Of course, our friend Scott Johnson, who was complaining earlier that he doesn't talk to us enough because he listens to GeekNights instead.
Scott: Oh, he's probably listening to this right now, which could be a different time depending on who you are and when you're listening.
Rym: You got less right than Scott did, I hear.
Scott: That's what I remember.
Scott: I had to go look at the aim logs, but I'm pretty sure you had a poor showing when I sent you the link this morning.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, almost as poor as Scott, but you got a little bit more poor.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty poor.
Rym: Anyway, yeah.
Scott: Now we know which Scott is more Scott and which one is not.
Rym: Except originally you were Scott Prime and he was Scott.
Scott: Prime, even better.
Scott: Optimus Prime.
Rym: Whatever.
Rym: So anyway, it's a gaming day and we picked up a while ago a board game called Kalis, which has been much hyped.
Scott: Well, a lot of people are arguing about whether it's hype or not.
Scott: The point is, is that a lot of there's been a lot of buzz and discussion and people saying good things about this game and, you know, encouraging others to play it and saying how great it is and all that stuff.
Scott: The word of mouth.
Rym: Well, we got the game and we've played it.
Rym: And as you read the forums, no, I'm mostly undefeated at it.
Scott: I haven't exactly played it that many times.
Rym: Five times.
Scott: Different configurations.
Scott: It's not very many.
Rym: Yeah, you're just bitter.
Rym: But anyway, the game is actually really good.
Scott: It's a pretty good game, yeah.
Rym: It is a hard board game.
Rym: I mean hard like Puerto Rico.
Rym: Hard as in solid, luckless, and just brains bashing against each other for an hour.
Scott: Yeah, if you want to play a nice light board game, you know, it's nice and easy.
Scott: Just about anyone can get into it, have a lot of fun.
Scott: This is not the game.
Rym: Yeah, you probably want to pick up Carcassonne.
Scott: Yeah, or something else.
Scott: Because Kalis is a lot of pain.
Rym: Kalis is one of those rare games where when you finish a game of it, you have not a headache, but definitely this feeling of mental exhaustion.
Rym: Like you have spent a part of your brain that now needs to recover.
Scott: I don't feel it that bad.
Scott: Maybe that's because I'm not trying so hard.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, so the game, the premise of the game is that King Phillip the Fair.
Rym: Who is a creepy looking dude, by the way.
Scott: At least if you consider the picture on the front of the box to be a picture of him, he's ugly.
Rym: He is not fair.
Scott: No, he is not.
Scott: So he's building a castle in France.
Scott: Ho ho ho ho, the castle.
Rym: Yeah, Scott is very multicultural.
Scott: And you are a laborer.
Scott: Oh, you're not a laborer.
Scott: You're like a build master guy.
Rym: Yeah, like an artisan or something.
Scott: You're something like that.
Scott: And you helped to build his castle.
Scott: And everyone else is of course also the same thing as you.
Scott: So you're competing to see who can build the most of the castle and gain the most favor from the king.
Scott: Because if the king likes you the most, then that's good for you.
Rym: Now it's not a victory point game, it's a prestige point game.
Scott: Yeah, they're victory points, but they call them prestige points because you're competing for prestige of the best castle builder guy.
Rym: Yeah, we'll probably just say victory points, but we might slip back and forth.
Rym: Just so we don't confuse with anyone.
Scott: And the other part of it, the reason it's called Calus, is because you're building this castle next to, in, or near the town of Calus.
Scott: Calus is a little shit village.
Scott: Like, it's got a half horse town.
Rym: Even though it's got six buildings in it, plus an inn and a stable and a jousting field.
Scott: That's not much.
Scott: Oh, those buildings, the jousting field, those are things the king built while he sits there and waits for the castle people.
Scott: Those aren't part of the town of Calus.
Rym: Aha!
Rym: See, this is probably the first time--.
Scott: That's why the bridge is there.
Rym: This is probably the first time you've ever paid attention to the flavor text of a game.
Scott: Well, I think it's kind of important for this game.
Scott: Not really.
Scott: Because in other games, you could replace the flavor, but in this game, it's sort of like, if you're going to put a different flavor in, because the flavor is somewhat tied into the game itself, you need to make it match.
Rym: You know?
Rym: Yeah, the theme actually plays into it pretty well.
Rym: Like, if you think of the game in terms of the theme, a lot of the rules make sense.
Rym: As opposed to some other games we've played.
Rym: Like, Tigris and Euphrates is pretty much just, yeah, I'm throwing down red tiles.
Scott: Yeah, you could change the theme in Tigris and Euphrates to anything you want.
Scott: Just replace red, green, blue, and black with anything.
Rym: We don't even remember what the tiles you're supposed to be representing.
Scott: Hemples, harvesty farms.
Rym: Yeah, markets and fishers.
Scott: Something like that.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Scott: It's red, green, blue, and black.
Scott: Anyway, the point is Calus.
Scott: The town of Calus, the village, or should I say, that's on the other side of the bridge from the castle, has like six buildings in it.
Scott: And after that, it's pretty much nothing.
Scott: I mean, there's a gold mine somewhere, and there's a couple other buildings, but they suck.
Scott: Well, they don't suck, but they're not really part of the town yet.
Scott: And what you do is while you're trying to build the castle and curry favors from the king in order to get prestige, you also have to use the people of the town of Calus to work for you.
Rym: Now the basic game is simply, there are a multitude of ways to gather a multitude of resources.
Rym: You want to convert resources as efficiently as possible into prestige points over the course of the game.
Scott: Yep, I mean, you get money, you get cubes of different colors, and you get buildings.
Rym: You get gold, which is a special cube.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: What else do you get?
Rym: That's really it.
Rym: I mean, you get favors from the king.
Scott: You get favors from the king.
Rym: Which just turn into other things.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: You can manipulate the provost and indirectly the bailiff.
Rym: Which are just two mechanics we'll talk about.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And you can screw with other players.
Scott: Kinda indirectly screw with other players.
Scott: Depending on what you want to do.
Rym: Now basically all the game is, is you go around one by one, you have a bunch of workers, six right?
Scott: Six workers, yep.
Rym: And you pay a gold to put a worker somewhere on a building, and then the building doesn't get activated.
Rym: You're just saying I'm putting a worker in that building.
Scott: You basically pay the workers to go out and do work.
Scott: But they don't do the work yet.
Scott: You have to pay them to go out there and then we'll see if they do work or not.
Rym: Now there's a nice mechanic here where it costs you say one gold to put one out.
Rym: Now at any time, instead of putting a worker out, you can pass and say I'm done.
Scott: If you can't, if you can't put a worker out, you have to pass.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Now once you pass, that's fine.
Rym: Everyone else can still put workers out, but now it costs two.
Rym: And then if someone else passes up, now it costs three.
Scott: So what that mechanic does is it says, all right, everyone's going to put out the same number, pretty much the same number of workers each turn.
Scott: And if you want to put out more workers than the other people, then you're going to have to pay up extra monies to put out more workers than the other people.
Scott: And also, there's an advantage to being the last guy to pass.
Scott: But being the last guy to pass might mean you have to put out more workers, even though you might put them on a building you don't want to use and pay extra money.
Scott: So, ooh.
Rym: Also, there's an incentive to pass first because you get one gold.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Just bing.
Scott: If you're really, one gold can be a big difference.
Scott: It can also be nothing.
Scott: But passing first gets you the one gold, you know, since passing first really doesn't help you in any other way.
Rym: So you keep going around until everyone's passed, and then you start at the castle and go down the road in order, just building, building, building.
Rym: And each building that has a worker in it, you then activate it and do whatever the building does until you hit the end.
Rym: Then you do all the other stuff for the turn, and then the turn starts over.
Rym: And that's the whole game.
Scott: So you just go down the road and it'll be like, there'll be a building, and someone put a worker in it.
Scott: You can't have two workers in this.
Scott: Well, some buildings can have two workers, but 90% of the buildings can have one worker.
Scott: So if I put a worker in this building, no one else puts a worker in that building this turn.
Scott: So you go down the road, you get to the building that says three money on it.
Scott: I have a worker there.
Scott: I get three money.
Scott: Go down the road some more, you see a building that says purple cube.
Scott: Rym has a worker in that building, he gets a purple cube.
Rym: That's really, that's the main part of the game.
Scott: Yep, that's, that's pretty much 90% of the rules.
Rym: Now you get all these goods and stuff, and buildings, the game starts with a few buildings on the board that aren't owned by anyone.
Rym: You can build more buildings, and the buildings that are built are far superior to the buildings already on the board.
Scott: Infinitely superior.
Rym: Now when you build a building, it's your building.
Rym: You get points for putting it out, and you put your little housey on it.
Rym: Now the benefits of you building a building, aside from getting the points, is that one, no matter how many people have passed, it always costs you only one money to go on one of your own buildings.
Scott: So you want to kind of not put workers in your own buildings right away, because that way, if other people pass, then you can put a worker in your own building, pass later, and still not pay more money.
Rym: Now two, if anyone else puts a worker in your building, they can still use the building.
Rym: But you get a victory point.
Scott: Prestige point.
Rym: Victory point.
Scott: Awesome.
Scott: Yeah, so if you build a nice building, then other people might use it, and thus give you a point.
Scott: However, sometimes they'll probably get more than a point from using your building.
Scott: So then you want to use your building right away, but then you lose the advantage of waiting until people pass to use your building, and whoa.
Rym: But if you have a lot of popular buildings, the victory points you get from other people using it really adds up over time.
Scott: If you have two or three popular buildings, you're not going to want to use all three of those in the same turn.
Scott: So maybe you'll put one of your guys in one of them right away, because you need it this turn.
Scott: Then you'll ignore the other ones.
Scott: Someone else will put a guy in one of them, giving you a point.
Scott: And then after other people pass, you decide you want to stick around a little while, you'll put a guy in your third building.
Scott: You can get a big advantage that way.
Scott: Not to mention the fact you get a lot of points just for building them.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Now that's all well and good.
Rym: There are a whole bunch of ways to get points there.
Rym: Some buildings turn cubes into victory points, or money into gold, and then another building turns gold into victory points, and all sorts of things.
Rym: And you get points for building them.
Rym: The primary way, or at least the main way, to get victory points is by actually building the castle, you know, the point of the game.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So the castle has like three pieces.
Scott: The dungeon, the wall, and the tower.
Rym: And these are just the three phases of the game, basically.
Scott: Yeah, it's like in the first phase of the game, you build the dungeon.
Scott: Now the dungeon's real small, but if you build a piece of the dungeon, you can get a lot of points for it.
Scott: And you can also get a lot of favors if you build more dungeon than other people, or a significant portion of the dungeon.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I'm not going to go into the rules on that.
Rym: Yeah, and the favors are cool, but we'll talk about them later.
Rym: They're a whole separate mechanic.
Scott: Then the walls are the same thing, except the walls are bigger than the dungeon, and therefore it's easier to get a piece of the wall.
Scott: But you can get more favors for building a significant portion of the wall, and it's the same rules, just slightly different.
Scott: And the tower is the same thing yet again.
Scott: And once the tower is finished, the game is over.
Rym: Now the way you build in the castle is you make batches.
Rym: And a ba- I mean, there's a whole bunch of different- there's a cloth- the cubes are cloth, gold, which is special, food, wood, and stone.
Rym: A batch for the king consists of one food and two cubes of any other color, as long as they're different.
Scott: Yeah, so a food is stone is stone is not a batch.
Scott: A food is stone and a wood is a batch.
Scott: A food, a gold, and a cloth is a batch.
Scott: A food, a wood, and a cloth is a batch.
Scott: A stone, a wood, and a cloth is not a batch, because it doesn't have a food in it.
Rym: Now one of the buildings you can put a worker on is the castle.
Scott: And then- Yeah, if you want to submit batches to the castle, you have to put your- one of your workers in the castle.
Rym: Any number of people can be in the castle, though.
Rym: Everyone on the board could be in the castle.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: You can always go to the castle if you want to.
Scott: No one can block you out.
Scott: But going in the castle before everyone else has an advantage in that if you tie for most batches, whoever went in earlier wins and gets a favor.
Rym: But at the same time, going last is an advantage, because then you know what everyone else put in, and you know exactly how many you need to put in to beat everyone.
Scott: Yeah, but the advantage of that is you just don't go in if you can't beat everyone, and you wait till next turn when you have more.
Rym: Yep, but then it depends on if you have a whole bunch of batches, and you know you can beat everyone anyway.
Rym: You go last, beat whoever went in by one, and keep the rest of your batches.
Scott: Yep, yep.
Rym: It's all- you really have to think a lot in this game about those sorts of things.
Rym: Like, there's always an advantage to doing one thing, but a similar advantage in the opposite end for doing the other thing.
Scott: It just depends on what you have, and the timing, and the order in which things execute.
Rym: Now, there's a funny little mechanic in the batches.
Rym: If you put a guy in the castle, and then for whatever reason you don't put a batch in, you lose victory points.
Rym: Straight up.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: you went up to the king, and you said, "King, I have brought you pieces of the castle,".
Scott: and he goes, "Oh, really?
Scott: I don't see
Scott: anything.".
Rym: And then you go, "I got
Rym: nothing.".
Scott: And then the king hates you, and you suck.
Rym: And you can ignore the castle, but once the part that they're building is scored, you know, when it finishes, and scoring, you don't get extra points, you usually get favors from the king.
Rym: Anyone who doesn't have any batches in each section loses even more points.
Scott: Yeah, so if you don't build any part of the dungeon, you lose some points, but not that many, but it still sucks.
Rym: Yeah, and the losses increase.
Scott: If you don't build any part of the wall... Now, the wall's a lot bigger than the dungeon, so it's hard to get shut out of the wall.
Scott: I mean, you'd really have to suck to build nothing in the wall at all.
Scott: If you build no part of the wall, you lose even more points.
Scott: The tower... I don't know how you couldn't possibly build a piece of the tower, but if you really suck, and you don't build any part of the giant, giant tower, you lose a shit ton of points.
Scott: You're basically lost the game.
Rym: Now, aside from all that, we mentioned the provost and the bailiff.
Rym: The bailiff is basically just the march of time.
Rym: He moves inerringly toward the end of the board, and a phase can change, like the dungeon phase, it'll change when the whole dungeon is built, or when the bailiff gets past the dungeon area on the board and hits the wall area.
Rym: Either one of those conditions triggers the scoring of the dungeon.
Scott: I think it's when the bailiff touches the end of the dungeon area, not the beginning of the wall area, but whatever.
Rym: And when he touches the end part, where the tower is, that's the end of the game.
Scott: Yeah, yep, that's the end.
Rym: And the provost is a really cool guy.
Scott: He's a really cool guy.
Scott: Now, the provost does two things.
Scott: Number one is people move him around.
Scott: Like, there's a building that you can use that allows you to bribe the provost, and well, it basically means you move him around for free, a whole bunch.
Scott: And there's the bridge.
Scott: Everyone goes on the bridge when you pass, but whoever passed first pays zero, one, two, or three money to move the provost.
Scott: zero, one, two, or three spaces accordingly.
Rym: Now, there aren't that many spaces on the board, and if you have a game with five people, that's up to 18 spaces he could move, depending on how people move him.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And then, of course, the guy who passed second can move the provost third, fourth, fifth, so whoever is the last person to pass on placing workers gets to move the provost last, which is a huge advantage, which means you can shut people out with him.
Rym: Now, you may be wondering, why would I want to move the provost?
Rym: What is the mechanic here?
Scott: Well, the first thing is that the provost is moved to a position on the board after the bailiff, then the bailiff will march forward two spaces that turn.
Scott: If the provost is on the same space as the bailiff, or before the bailiff, the bailiff will only move forward one space that turn.
Scott: That's a big deal, because you can make the game move really quick.
Scott: I mean, if you keep moving the provost forward every turn, you'll finish the dungeon in three turns, which means people have three turns to get a batch in, or they're screwed.
Scott: So, there's something big with that.
Rym: Now, two, the board is a line.
Rym: It just goes a windy line.
Scott: Yeah, they make it windy to fit on a board.
Scott: It could be a straight line, it wouldn't make a difference.
Rym: And it gets built in order, and things get activated in order.
Rym: Anything that is beyond whatever square the provost is sitting on doesn't get activated, and if you put a worker on one of those buildings, well, fuck you.
Scott: Yeah, so let's say there's a building that gives you a wood cube, and then a building that gives you a stone cube, and when we're putting workers out, you put a worker on the stone cube building.
Scott: The provost gets moved all the way back to the wood cube building.
Scott: The stone cube building never gets activated.
Scott: Your worker is sitting on it, you paid to put the worker there, but you're never going to get that stone cube, because the provost won't let the buildings behind him, or in front of him, depending on your point of view, get activated.
Rym: See, now you might have been wondering earlier, why would you go into the castle if you didn't have a batch?
Rym: Well, you might have been expecting a batch, but then the provost cocked you.
Scott: Yeah, I put my guy out to get a food cube, because I got plenty of other cubes, and if I can get every food cube I get, it's pretty much a batch, because I have so many other cubes.
Scott: Well, the provost moves before the building that gives me food cubes, and I already put my guy in the castle, and now I'm in big trouble.
Rym: Yep, so there's a lot to think about in this game, and a lot of ways to manipulate and scheme.
Rym: I mean, it looks like in a five player game, there will often be semi-formal alliances, where, like, say I go on the go- like, we're near the gold gets there, we get close to the gold, and I put a guy on the gold.
Rym: No one wants me to have gold, and they're going to try to push the provost past the gold so I won't get it, but I want to push it beyond the gold so I'll get it.
Rym: Someone else might say, "Eh, Rym's trying to get the
Rym: gold.".
Rym: I'm going to put all my workers around that area in the other buildings that are close to the guy.
Rym: That way, I know Rym will fight to keep his gold, which will protect my workers, too.
Rym: And then Scott will say, "Oh, those two fuckers are winning.
Rym: Everyone else, we gotta keep the provost from getting out
Rym: there.".
Scott: Yeah, I generally assume that any building within three spaces of the provost is a dangerous area, but if someone else puts a guy way out there in the dangerous area, I'll be willing to put a guy one or two spaces behind their guy where I normally wouldn't feel safe putting him, you know, with the knowledge that, hey, that guy is also going to move the provost away, you know?
Scott: And, of course, there's a chance that he could still be shut out.
Scott: and I still get my building far away and we both win.
Rym: Yep, I usually seem to play very conservatively with the provost, but I have, on occasion, gone balls out and gone right up to the edge.
Scott: Yeah, I also try to be real conservative and I only go for the edge either when I really want a building and I also have a lot of money to move the provost a lot and I have the building that lets me move the provost a lot, you know?
Scott: Like, if there's a building near the edge that you want, go to the building that lets you move the provost
Rym: a lot
Scott: first and if you get that building, then after everyone else takes their turn, you'll see, oh, okay, you know, if they put guys way out near the end, then don't put your guy way out near the end, just use that building to screw them.
Rym: Yep, putting a guy there early in the round makes, it's a big deterrent for anyone else going near the edge until you put your guys down.
Rym: Yeah, until you claim a spot.
Scott: And then if no one else puts their guy near the edge for you to screw them, then put your guy near the edge where he'll be perfectly safe.
Rym: Unless everyone gangs up on you.
Scott: Unless everyone gangs up on you, but all, it depends a lot on the number of players, like, the number of players really changes this game.
Scott: in a four player game that's three whole spaces.
Scott: the provost can't move that he could have moved in a five player game.
Rym: In addition to there's so much more contention for good buildings and favors.
Scott: Yeah, there aren't any more buildings in a more player game, there's still the same number of buildings out there, but now there's a whole lot more workers going out.
Rym: Now there's only one more mechanic in the whole game.
Rym: The game's actually, it looks really complex, and it is really complex in terms of the paths to victory, but the game itself is actually very simple.
Scott: Yeah, when I tried to figure out how to play the game I was pretty confused, but then once you learn the symbols on the board, and the symbols are really self explanatory, but once you learn all the symbols, it's sort of like learning a little picturized language, once you learn them all, you know exactly how to play this game perfectly.
Rym: Like oh, that building costs one food and one stone, it produces blah blah blah, it gives me blah victory points.
Scott: It's just, you have to know what the symbols mean, and what they mean in different contexts, so if I see that symbol here it means this, but if I see the same symbol over there it means that.
Rym: Now the only other mechanic are the favors of the king.
Scott: Ah, the favors of the king.
Rym: And they're cool, basically there's four tracks.
Rym: Victory points, money, cubes, and building buildings.
Rym: These four tracks, you have a marker on each one, and it's increasing returns.
Rym: The further to the right you get on these tracks, the greater the reward is.
Rym: And every time you get a favor, you pick one of those tracks, advance your little marker, and take any of the favors in that row that you are on or that are to the left of you.
Scott: So basically the king comes to you and he says, "You have done a good job, I favor
Scott: you.".
Scott: And you can say, "Alright king, I would like some money," or, "I would like some victory points," or, "I would like a cube," or, "I would like to build a building, can you help me
Scott: out?".
Scott: And you know, you pick one of the four.
Scott: And depending on how many times the king is giving you a favor and you've picked the same thing, you can do it better and better.
Scott: So the first time you ask for a cube it gives you a feud cube, but like the sixth time you ask for a cube, you get a gold cube.
Rym: And the victory points are just one, two, three, four, five.
Scott: And the money I think is three, four, five, six, seven?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And then the building buildings, this is one kind of kicker in the game.
Rym: You can't just build buildings.
Scott: Nope.
Rym: You can't do any action in this game without putting a worker on a building somewhere.
Rym: So there is a building that says, "You can build a wood type
Rym: building.".
Rym: There is one wood type building, only one, that says, "Ah, this building lets you build stone type
Rym: buildings.".
Rym: There is a building that lets you build the green type buildings, the residences.
Rym: And there is a building that lets you turn residences into blue buildings or prestige buildings.
Scott: Those are basically, those buildings don't do much, but they give you a whole lot of points when you build them.
Rym: Those are the big buildings.
Scott: The stone and the wood buildings do a whole lot of stuff.
Scott: The stone buildings do more than the wood buildings.
Scott: They're like super buildings.
Scott: And the green buildings don't do anything because they're all the same, but they increase the income you get each turn.
Scott: So if you have a couple of them, you get a lot of money.
Rym: And they give you a place to build blue buildings, which can only be built on top of other buildings you own.
Scott: Green ones.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: That are yours, yeah.
Scott: The green buildings also can only be built on top of buildings you already own or the pink buildings that start out in the game.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: A common strategy I've had is to build all the buildings that make stone and then build a residence over the pink building that makes stone, thus having a monopoly on stone.
Scott: Yeah, you eliminate the competition that the board presents right at the beginning.
Scott: That's a good strategy.
Scott: But yeah.
Rym: Now the building a building favor is big because one, you can now build a building without needing those cards, those buildings.
Scott: Yeah, so let's say that the thing that lets people build stone buildings isn't on the board, but you get enough favors to build a stone building without that building that's usually on the board.
Scott: So now you're building stone buildings and no one else can.
Rym: Plus those favors also let you build them at a discount.
Scott: Yeah, you don't have to actually use a stone cube to build a stone building if you use the favors.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Now, I mean, that favor sounds really powerful, but it's mitigated by the fact that the first space on that track is nothing.
Rym: So taking the first favor there doesn't do anything for you.
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: The game is insanely well balanced with the possible exception of this one expansion building that turns gold into victory points at some sick rate.
Scott: Yeah, there was this... In the game, there's pretty much a building for everything.
Scott: I mean, there's a building that lets you turn money into gold.
Scott: There's a building that lets you turn money into cubes, cubes into money.
Rym: There are a lot of combos where you can take one cube and shunt it through three buildings and end up with four cubes instead, things like that.
Scott: Yeah, I like to, what I do is turn a cube into a pile of money and then turn some of that money back into like two cubes.
Scott: So like turn one cube into like some money and some cubes.
Scott: It's a good move.
Scott: Anyway, this one building that was, it's not even in the instruction book.
Scott: It was given out as an expansion at Essen, which is the German super gaming convention that I'd like to go to one day.
Scott: They just threw it into the second printing of the game, which is what I have, without, you know, making mention of it at all.
Scott: And what it does is allows you, I think, to turn gold into a sick number of victory points.
Rym: Like the game we played at Gaming for Hope, it was a five player game.
Rym: I had run away with the game.
Rym: I was a full halfway around the board from everyone else.
Rym: There was nothing they could do about it until one guy who was, he was pretty much at the leader of the loser pack, built that building and started chunking gold into it.
Rym: And he almost caught up to me.
Rym: Like suddenly the game turned around completely for that one guy.
Scott: Yeah, the gold cubes are sort of special in that number one, they're harder to get than any of the other cubes.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: And two, they only have a few uses.
Scott: Number one, you can use them as like where you would normally use a cube as like a batch or convert it into money.
Scott: But that's kind of silly because gold has special powers.
Scott: So using it for those purposes is kind of a waste.
Rym: Unless, you know, you need an emergency batch.
Scott: Yeah, like I would rather sacrifice the gold than get the minus two points for not having a batch.
Scott: But anyway, what you primarily use gold for is number one, all the blue buildings require gold, the ones that you build on top of the green buildings.
Scott: So those blue buildings can give you a shit ton of points when you build them.
Rym: So I once recently built the biggest one.
Rym: It would cost like three gold and five stone and it's worth like 25 victory points or something.
Scott: It's insane, but you know, that's what gold is good for.
Scott: Also, at the end of the game, every gold cube you have gets you three points.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Basically the game, when it ends, everything you have, there's a conversion directly into points.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Like every four cubes you have that aren't gold, you get a point.
Scott: Every three money you have left at the end of the game is a point.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So you can use those as the, all right, is there any way before this game's end, game ends, I can turn what I've got into victory points more efficiently than that right there because that's the final value.
Scott: That's really the whole point of the game is to collect those resources and then convert them into victory points more efficiently than you would if you're holding on to them.
Scott: Like think about when you're playing the game, I'm going to about to spend three money.
Scott: Is that going to end up getting me more than one prestige point?
Scott: If no, that's probably not a good way to spend the three money because if you just held on to that money till the end of the game, you'd get one point.
Scott: So, you know, it's the same thing with cubes.
Scott: I'm about to do something with four cubes.
Scott: Am I going to get more than one point for that?
Scott: If not, it's probably a bad idea.
Scott: Same thing with the gold.
Scott: If you're going to turn gold into less than three points, you're probably wasting the gold.
Rym: Now the game is very, I mean, you know, I've talked a lot in various times about how some games are strategic and some games are tactical.
Rym: As in some games, you can plan ahead and you can have like a plan, like I'm going to go for this and this and this and do this.
Rym: And some, yeah.
Scott: And they, yeah, strategic game is, it's not because you could do that in any game.
Scott: You could always come up with a plan.
Scott: The point is in a strategic game, the plan you come up with beforehand is matters.
Scott: Like if you go into, like Stratego is a game of strategy.
Scott: Your plan is how you set up your dudes.
Rym: Yep, because it's all pre-planned.
Rym: And there are very few actual tactical decisions to make in Stratego because it's usually fairly obvious what you should do for a given situation.
Scott: Yeah, you just look at what the board is and you see what you've got and you know which guys, the other guy has moved and you know where some bombs are and your move is pretty obvious.
Scott: It's all about pre-planning.
Scott: Pre-planning matters the most in a strategic game.
Rym: Then there's a game like Tigers and Euphrates, which is, leans much more heavily toward tactics.
Scott: Yeah, you can go into Tigris and Euphrates saying, I'm going to do this and this and this with a bunch of these cubes, but, or these tiles, not cubes.
Rym: Well, you get cubes.
Scott: You get cubes.
Scott: But that doesn't really matter.
Scott: What matters is the decisions you make on the fly in the game.
Scott: No matter pre-planning is going to help you win.
Rym: Because you can plan all you want, but you have to really be able to take tactical advantage of a situation like, Oh, he just fucked up and put this tile here.
Rym: That means I can do this.
Rym: My whole strategy just changed.
Scott: Yeah, it's not, you can't plan for that.
Scott: You just kind of see how things go each and every turn.
Scott: And every time you take an action, you have to consider the situation on the fly and make the right move.
Rym: Kalis really seems to be a healthy balance of the two.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: It's like, I mean, there's zero randomness other than the initial setup of the board and the initial turn order.
Rym: Yeah, but that's it.
Rym: Yeah, that's it.
Rym: The game is, is so precise and there's so little luck and randomness that basically you have the tactical considerations of everything that happens to me is caused by another player.
Rym: I have to anticipate their actions and react.
Scott: I think the randomness in the game isn't, it's not gameplay related.
Scott: What it is, is to make it so the game isn't the same game every time.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Because if the game were set up the same way every time, then they'd be like, I'd be in the situation where, all right, I go first and the board's this way.
Rym: So I do this no matter what, if I go first every time I ever play Kalis.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It's like battle tech.
Scott: The different map doesn't make the game random, even though battle tech's a random game.
Rym: I mean, there's, there's no randomness at all in Kalis.
Scott: It's like Kalis, there's six buildings that start out on the board, but they start in a random order.
Scott: So how many possible starting positions is that?
Rym: Six times six.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So there's 36, basically you get 36 maps.
Rym: It's six factorial.
Scott: Oh, that's right.
Scott: So there is six factorial "maps" in quotes in Kalis.
Rym: Yeah, but everyone knows the map and the starting order right as the game begins.
Rym: So at that point you can immediately, one, formulate your strategy, knowing exactly how the game is going to go.
Scott: If you see like a certain building is really close to the bridge, then that building is never going to get provosted early on, which means the game is going to lean in this way, which means this is what you kind of want to lean, do.
Rym: But at the other, on the other hand, there are a lot of other players with their own strategies and they're going to try to do their thing.
Rym: And you have to take advantage of them and not be taken advantage of.
Scott: So on any individual turn, you'll see like, okay, he has this many cubes and he's got his worker there and he has that many money and he put his worker there.
Scott: That means if I go for that, then I'm going to get fucked.
Scott: But if I go for that, then I can fuck them.
Scott: Let me go for that.
Rym: It's just, it's one of those rare games.
Rym: I can't think of many games that have a very good balance of the two.
Rym: Most games really lean to one or the other.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Now, the only negative thing I can really say about this game is that at first glance, it looked like there were going to be many different ways to achieve victory points.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Many paths to victory.
Rym: And I still think that's true.
Scott: There are.
Scott: However, I kind of got this feeling at first that, you know, the castle seems to be like the main way, it always seems to be a main way of getting points in any game.
Scott: Like in Alhambra, the main way of getting points is most of a color in the scoring round.
Rym: Puerto Rico, it's shipping things.
Scott: Yeah, but there's also other ways to get points.
Scott: Like in Puerto Rico, you can also get points, you know, from doing other things like big buildings and other stuff.
Scott: And in Alhambra, you can get points for having the longest wall, you know, that there are other ways to get points that are secondary or perhaps tertiary.
Scott: Well, it looked to me when I first started reading the instructions of Kalis that they're, you know, going for the castle, which is the main way of getting points.
Scott: You know, there is a way to just go through the game with not completely ignoring, but largely ignoring the castle and using the other mechanisms of point getting like building buildings and getting gold and all that and coming out way ahead.
Rym: Meanwhile, I heard the rules of the game and immediately thought, I'm going to hammer that castle relentlessly every time I play this game as hard and as fast as I can.
Scott: And it was slightly disappointing that it seems that you really can't ignore the castle all that much.
Rym: You see, I'll note that I really think you can mostly ignore the castle in a many player game.
Scott: Yeah, see, I think I was the line where you can't ignore the castle below the line.
Scott: It's like you have to do the minimum effort in the castle, which makes sense because the whole game is building the castle.
Scott: I know, I know.
Rym: If you're just a gold trader, why don't you go play Gold Traders of Kalis?
Scott: Because maybe I can trade so much gold that the king will go, whoa, you got so much gold, I don't give a shit about those guys building my castle.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: You kind of can with that one gold building.
Scott: You can, but you know, it's not the point I'm trying to make.
Rym: Yeah, I think the point is it's mostly that we play the two player game a bunch of times and we played the three player game once.
Rym: And in those small player games, you can put so much into the castle because there's so little competition that the castle is really the primary means to get victory points.
Scott: I mean, putting one batch in the castle, even with the tower, gets you what, three points?
Scott: Getting a favor gets you an average three points.
Scott: So, you know, getting a gold gets you three points.
Rym: But in the five player game, there's a lot more competition in the castle.
Scott: Huge competition in the castle.
Rym: You can either go all out for the castle or hang with the castle and go all out on like gold or all out on money.
Scott: In a more player game, you really can't go all out on the castle because there are just so many people trying to have to get their batches in that there's no room to get enough points in the castle.
Scott: All you'll do by maxing out the castle is end the game faster.
Scott: Though, you need to get the castle and points elsewhere in a more player game.
Rym: Yes, though in the one five player game we played, I won by ignoring everything but the castle, only doing the castle, and trying to end the game as fast as possible so that no one could even start all their other victory point generation schemes.
Scott: Yeah, I really don't know how... See, the problem is that a lot of the games we played are with inexperienced players.
Scott: I really want to see what'll happen if we play with like five Kalis masters or five well-learned Kalis players.
Rym: Yeah, it's like with Puerto Rico.
Rym: When we first played Puerto Rico, it was like we played... None of us knew how to play and there were obvious paths to victory.
Rym: and "Oh, he's got the harbor captain blah blah blah, he
Rym: wins.".
Rym: And then as we got good at the game, it got to the point where crazier and crazier strategies kept emerging.
Rym: And it ended up, we basically discovered that in a three player game, the factory is pretty much the way to go to win.
Rym: Depending on the situation, but...
Scott: At least for now.
Rym: Yeah, in three player games too.
Rym: Five player Puerto Rico is totally different.
Scott: That threw me off once because I was playing a perfect three player game and I forgot there were four players at once.
Rym: And meanwhile, I realized that and bought a warehouse, which was key.
Scott: Yeah, that was a crazy game because I felt like I was doing great in this one game of Puerto Rico, but then I forgot there was a fourth player and then my game fell apart.
Scott: If it would have been a three player game, I would have won.
Rym: Yeah, but that's one thing we miss from RIT is that our, you know, the front row crew, the people we run with are for the very... They're largely very good rote gamers.
Rym: They're very good at German games.
Rym: And when we get a game, we all progress at largely the same rate.
Rym: And we, I don't know, we're good.
Rym: What can I say?
Rym: We've ended up playing a lot of games with people who aren't so good lately just because of where we live and what free time we have.
Scott: And even like our crew, you know, we play the games with them and then we play the games with just us or with other people.
Scott: So our skill level gets way ahead of theirs because the number of plays they have under their belt is significantly lower than the number of plays we have.
Rym: Yeah, so yeah, geeks move out here and we'll play board games.
Scott: Lots of board games.
Rym: But I guess I really like Kalis.
Rym: I think it's a great game.
Scott: Yeah, really good game.
Scott: Glad I bought it.
Scott: It lives up to... I could see why everyone was talking about it.
Scott: I don't know if it's a T&E, but for the time being, it's going to get more play, I think.
Rym: Yeah, it's a long ways out to Lodacon, but we'll probably bring it and...
Scott: Absolutely bring it.
Rym: Well, I don't know if we'll have time to play with any of our fans out there since we as the crew want to play this game, but we can at least show you the game.
Scott: Yeah, you can stand around and watch and talk to us.
Scott: There'll be plenty of time for talking to you.
Scott: I don't know if there'll be an hour for a Kalis game.
Rym: Yeah, though I do point out that there's the Thursday at the con.
Scott: Oh, that's true, but we're usually spending that in the hot tub.
Rym: We could play some games in the hot tub.
Scott: Not Kalis.
Scott: Unless you want to make inflatable waterproof Kalis.
Rym: That would be awesome.
Scott: Hit a little king's castle floating in the hot tub, throwing cubes at it.
Rym: But anyway, since I brought up Odacon, don't forget that tomorrow, Anime Day, we're going to be bringing you our actual coverage of Toracon 2006.
Rym: And for anyone who doesn't listen to all the Days of GeekNights, yesterday we played the live show we did at Toracon.
Scott: Yeah, which didn't really have anything to do with anime, which is why we ended up deciding to play it yesterday.
Scott: Also because we were really tired and we didn't want to do a show yesterday.
Rym: We actually, little secret for anyone who's still listening, we recorded the news yesterday twice.
Rym: We recorded it, we were so tired it was crap, we just re-recorded it.
Scott: Yep, and it was a little bit better.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, but I think we'll be good today, we'll be good tomorrow.
Scott: Well, we were good today.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: We got a lot for tomorrow.
Rym: We'll figure out what we're going to do Thursday at some point.
Scott: Oh great, it'll probably be ass.
Rym: And that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: If you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums, make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to geeknights@gmail.com.
Scott: And if you want, you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight, Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other talk shows, it's actually recorded at night.