Rym: It's Monday April 10th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We talk about home networking and a bunch of other meta bits.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So as I've mentioned several times in the past I like to edit Wikipedia articles.
Rym: now I don't usually write like entirely new content.
Rym: I usually go through and fix you know Terrible grammar or people who just don't know what they're talking about or people who say that indigo children are real.
Rym: Yeah, that's like my pet article.
Rym: I keep going back there and fixing it.
Rym: But anyway, I never had an account on Wikipedia.
Rym: I just decided that I would always just do it anonymously and I didn't really care like I never participate in the talk pages or anything.
Rym: I just edit and The other day I was at work and I was doing something that didn't require my input and I was waiting for it to finish.
Rym: so I'm sitting there and I decided to go check on some Wikipedia and I found an article that had a fairly glaring typo in it.
Rym: so I go and I try to change it and I submit and Then a message pops up at the top when I reload the page saying something about an edit.
Rym: I made recently as bad and I look and In my history page, which is basically if you don't log into Wikipedia Logging in is actually more anonymous than not logging in because if you log in you have a username.
Rym: if you don't log in it tracks you by IP address and The IP address that I connect to Wikipedia from work with is shared by a lot of people through a net.
Rym: and I discovered that countless Indians in IBM have been writing countless Terrible articles about countless Indian things all over Wikipedia.
Rym: They've been just like writing stuff like writing an article that has nothing in it Making new articles that are empty or just full of gibberish like all over the place to the point that the IP address I was using is being watched.
Scott: really people from who work at IBM who are from in the country of India I say writing bad articles on on Wikipedia and in great number or is this one guy?
Rym: I think it's a bunch of guys because the topics were wide and varied over a long period of time.
Rym: Maybe it's one guy who just like is writing about everything Indian over time Possibly but I I wish I could show you guys the page that shows my history.
Rym: I really don't want to give away all the IP address I connect from but Suffice to say there are numerous and it's not like people are writing bad things like making up stuff about Pakistan or like just lying About India.
Rym: It's like broken articles with bad HTML or bad wiki code.
Scott: Wow So why does he keep doing it?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: All I know is I stopped editing Wikipedia from work because I don't want my awesome edits to be intermingled with this guy's IP address.
Scott: That's the trouble of net which we will discuss in this episode, yep I'm actually considering getting an account on Wikipedia.
Rym: now I'm waiting whether or not I'm going to get an account like just with a crazy strings I don't know who I am or if I'll just use Rym and then you guys could see what I actually do on there.
Scott: Yeah, do that?
Scott: you pick some crazy name and then if someone ever complains about it, you know, like anything you write Just pick a new crazy name.
Scott: Ah, just keep picking different crazy names.
Rym: People who complain are the Inigo children people.
Rym: well good they can shove it because I think they've noticed that it's always me.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway you had some medivids - didn't you?
Scott: yes Everyone who is listening to eat nights.
Scott: I'm gonna probably have to say this every day this week just for the people who listen to only one day Even though we learned there aren't so many of you.
Scott: No, not it.
Scott: Well, that's another good thing.
Scott: You reminded me of the first thing.
Scott: everybody here who is listening to eat nights go right now Or the next time you're sitting in the computer.
Scott: Go to front row crew calm and on the right side of the page.
Scott: There is a poll.
Scott: Answer this poll.
Scott: We want to know and the poll will probably change every few weeks or so, so Repeatedly go to front row crew calm many many times.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: I imagine the polls will eventually include controversial topics that will then rant about.
Scott: Yes, but for now there are things that we need to know to make the podcast better for you.
Rym: So yep, mostly because it's difficult to track stats.
Scott: Yes So if you want the podcast to improve go and vote in the polls on the side of the page.
Rym: Well, how could it improve?
Rym: It's perfect.
Rym: I mean no one ever complains ever.
Scott: Maybe people should complain by sending email to us.
Scott: Nights at front row crew calm.
Rym: In fact tonight's episode is proof that we do in fact read the email.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Anyway so the forum Our forum is a little different and a little more advanced and a little less advanced in some ways than PHPBB and VBUL and then all those other forums.
Rym: Yep I will say that most of the people who use it seem to really like it once they get the hang of it.
Scott: Yeah, our forum runs on lusimo vanilla software, which is wicked almost web 2.0.
Scott: Awesome forums of crazy.
Rym: You can say lusimo, but you don't say Ubuntu Ubuntu Ubuntu.
Scott: All right anyway The way this forum works is instead of just joining you apply for membership and then within like a few hours I noticed that you applied for membership and I click approve and you get an email saying You are welcome to the forums.
Scott: come back and sign in.
Scott: Well, it seems that some people have some sort of bad spam filter that will filter out Completely not spam, you know because some people are dumb with email they use like hotmail or stupid shit like that.
Scott: So to the following people you have been approved and you have accounts on our forum Come sign in and talk with us many times because it should just work.
Rym: We didn't deny you or anything.
Scott: Yeah, and to all those people who like do have accounts and have logged in at least once bookmark the forum and keep coming back and to anyone doesn't have an account in the forum come and apply and if you don't get An email within like eight hours saying you have been approved membership Just send us an email and I will tell you if I approved you so far.
Scott: I have not rejected anybody.
Scott: Yep, it's basically.
Scott: I'm only gonna reject you if you're obviously someone who's gonna spam the forum or something.
Rym: and don't worry.
Rym: Mr Period does not have the power to deny you.
Scott: No, he doesn't.
Scott: So yeah, these are the people right now.
Scott: ace bellarm Colin Burkett see dac rule 427 The Roach digital monkey fuzzy Ed spirit fiend Z-mang 86 or Z-man g86.
Scott: I don't know the reviewer Manda, but M&D are in little square brackets and there's someone who's obviously really really trying to get into the forums.
Scott: first He tried to sign in as like flammer guy.
Scott: Then he tried to get another account as the flaming geek and I think he thinks he was rejected because he hasn't been back.
Scott: But I approved both of those accounts.
Scott: pick one of them sign in and I'll delete the other one.
Scott: you were approved You're not rejected.
Scott: come back.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And for anyone who joined the forums like early early on a long time ago when we first started and thought hey There's no one here and never came back.
Rym: There's a lot of people in there.
Rym: In fact, someone just someone on their own started a new flame war.
Scott: Yeah, there is a talking in the forum Pretty much on the hour.
Scott: So if more people come they'll be talking on the half-hour perhaps on the 10-minute and It'd be cool.
Rym: So anyway in the news we have only one news today because we got some audio feedback from our GeekNights resident scientist Peter Olson.
Rym: hooray Now first off the news.
Rym: we didn't.
Rym: I mean there was a lot of news over the weekend.
Rym: We could talk about any number of things and I think we're going to spread about over the week because they're all fairly Relevant or important.
Rym: but this one isn't really a news per se just a topic that's been coming up more and more lately.
Scott: black hats That means those Hackers that aren't cool you.
Scott: they don't want to be your friend They want to spam you and zombie you and all those other bad things see.
Rym: a long time ago It used to be that hackers were the good guys who messed with technology and they
Scott: still are the good guys
Rym: And this is the old terminology the way I mean There are some people who really have a bug up their butt about this and hackers were the good guys.
Rym: They mess with technology.
Rym: They protect you from crackers.
Rym: crackers were the guys who broke into things and did evil and The terms all got mixed up and then new terms came out now.
Rym: It's a white hat as in the good guys.
Rym: Black hat as in the bad guys.
Rym: red hat is in that crappy Linux distribution and ass hat.
Scott: You forgot gray hat those guys who are like good guys, but then they're also bad guys.
Rym: Yeah, you can make up your own hats but black hat is very well-defined and it basically means people on the internet or Alvar networks or in some way evil Usually spammers.
Rym: Yeah, that's pretty much the primary thing spyware dudes And there's been a lot of news about attacks and extortion and DD OS's and things cropping up again.
Rym: Yeah, this really hasn't been an issue for a long time and it's starting to come back.
Scott: Well, the primary attack vector seems to be get a bunch of Windows machines and put a virus on them which is not too hard to do and Connect them with some sort of IRC bot thing So that you go to an IRC channel and you type in some secret commands there and the bots You know all those thousands of window machines talk back to you in that IRC channel and you can control them and make them do Your bidding, you know, you can say all you Windows machines that I have collected DDS that guy
Rym: OS stands for
Scott: Denial absurd distributed
Rym: Distributed denial of service.
Rym: It's like say you got a thousand pcs under your control and you tell them all to ping one, dude until he goes down.
Scott: imagine if there was like a guy who had a grocery store and you basically Brainwashed a million people on the street and you said hey grocery store guy either you give me all your money or I'm gonna fill Your grocery store with a million of these zombie people I brainwashed and no one's gonna be able to shop in your store ever again.
Rym: It's a decent analogy and that's pretty much what happens.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It's more common than you'd think a lot of times.
Scott: what happens is the people who are threatened or Blackmailed or whatever you extorted.
Scott: they won't say they were extorted because well, you know If they do the guy will just send the zombies anyway.
Rym: Yep, plus I mean there's been a lot a lot of talk about banks and financial institutions lately and about course This is kind of an old problem how they won't let on.
Rym: if they get compromised They'll just pay the guy because the police aren't gonna track him down and if they admit that they got hacked That's the end of that bank.
Scott: Yeah, if a banks like yeah, we were hacked by this guy and he took a zillion dollars No one's gonna put their money in that bank anymore.
Rym: Everyone's gonna be like, well, I'll put my money That and every hacker in the world is get well cracker in the world is gonna attack that bank.
Scott: Yep Oh, really?
Scott: Your your bank was hacked a and successfully and you paid the guy off, huh?
Scott: Oh, you know what?
Scott: I Won't even bother hacking you.
Scott: I'm just gonna call you up and say I hacked you and ask for money.
Rym: now There was a time I don't think many of our listeners are old enough to remember but the the early middling days of IRC When IRC was like the primary mode of cool internet guy communication.
Rym: now IRC is a cesspool but and that it was a summer.
Scott: It's okay, but not much.
Rym: Yeah, it's mostly a cesspool.
Scott: mostly There is a few places that are like, you know cordoned off or like.
Scott: there's an open source area.
Scott: That's kind of okay Yeah, and there's some like, you know specialized geek channels here and there but a lot of comics.
Scott: Most of it is just blah.
Rym: Yeah, and back then there was this rise of script kitty Horrible assholes who would just?
Rym: they basically had gang turf wars in IRC over channels and they'd fight each other with these botnets and scripts and everything and it got really bad.
Rym: and then as technology improved and a Lot of normal people who don't know about that sort of thing flooded the internet and IRC died the problem disappeared or at least retreated to the fringes of the internet and If the news is to be believed it's coming back.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: now, I'm of two minds on this because one I haven't been attacked at all.
Scott: Like we won't be we're running Linux.
Scott: It's kind of a very very difficult to attack us.
Rym: But - I just I wonder because when you see these articles I almost get the feeling that they're being written by people who are being paid by various anti spyware or Antivirus companies or firewall companies who want people to be afraid so that they'll buy their products.
Scott: I Agree, especially since Microsoft seems to actually be upping the security a little bit and as time goes on sure, there is still a hajillion Windows machines out there being compromised, but It's not because people don't have anything available them to secure themselves.
Scott: It's because people are stupid.
Scott: So as Used to be everyone was vulnerable even us, you know using Windows to play games or something.
Scott: We'd be out in the open and fucked.
Rym: But now the only people out in the open and fucked are the people are stupid and it's decreasing daily because honestly one thing that's Really prevented attacks on most normal people out there is war routers and net which we're going to talk about today.
Rym: Hooray, if you're behind a router and the routers running that so your computer is not directly connected to the internet with a bare IP You're safe from 90% of the non user initiated attacks that are out there.
Scott: Yeah The only way someone can get you then is if they trick you with something stupid like you visit a website with ie that's got a thing on it or you Download an email attachment or you click on a phishing scam or something like that.
Rym: Yep But I just I want to warn people that even though I think a lot of this Blackhat resurgence is overhyped and possibly false The internet if you go at it like a direct connection to the internet is basically the Wild West.
Rym: It is just that it is filled with the sea of dangerous things.
Scott: there are these things.
Scott: this is pieces of software.
Scott: not gonna explain too much of this because you can try to do a whole episode.
Scott: and called honeypots and think of a honeypot is like this you um Let's say that it was pirate town and you had a treasure chest, but the church just had didn't really have treasure in it.
Scott: It just looked like it had treasure in it.
Scott: Yeah, whenever a pirate came to get the treasure There was a little man inside the church just to write down which pirate came to check the treasure and what he tried to do.
Rym: So after a month, you've got a list of all the pirates.
Scott: Yeah, you got a list of all the pirates.
Scott: You got a list of the techniques pirates are using to steal treasure.
Scott: You got all kinds of information on pirates.
Scott: So people put these honeypots out there and on the internet and try to see who tries to hack it.
Rym: Millions and millions and millions.
Scott: Yeah, we're talking Insane like within days you'll get crazy hacking attempts.
Scott: Just I don't know where.
Scott: Successful ones who knows but just packing attempts come all the time to random brand new computers.
Scott: They've never been on the internet before.
Scott: guys We'll just discover these computers and hack them when we move back into RIT.
Rym: in our apartment Scott Ed was building a new Windows XP.
Scott: Well, that was cuz.
Scott: I did it at a bad time.
Scott: It was there was a worm going around.
Rym: Yeah, but even then it's still pretty dangerous out there.
Scott: It's real dangerous.
Rym: Of course either running Linux or being behind a firewall saves you from 99% of that or both.
Scott: Yeah, both is very good.
Rym: But anyway that aside the other we don't have another news today instead.
Rym: We have the audio feedback.
Rym: Like I said now, I believe was last Thursday.
Rym: We talked a lot about evolution and various Quote-unquote missing links that have been discovered recently seems to be the hot topic of the past year.
Rym: So yep, and Peter had something interesting and enlightening to say about that.
Guest: Hooray Hey guys, it's Pete.
Guest: Just thought I'd chime in about the topic of evolution since it's come up this past Thursday and it's been in the news quite a bit this past week and shed some light on it.
Guest: do a little explaining and Just generally kind of expound a bit on evolution.
Guest: I guess I'll start by defining it.
Guest: evolution the word as in the phenomenon of Evolution is defined as changes in the allele frequencies of a population over time.
Guest: That's the modern definition.
Guest: It used to be a lot simpler.
Guest: simpler just, you know changes in organisms that sort of thing.
Guest: But it's very specifically changes in allele frequencies.
Guest: Alleles are basically settings of genes.
Guest: You know genes are the unit of inheritance.
Guest: That's how characteristics get passed from one organism to its successive generation.
Guest: and Allele of a gene is sort of like a setting basically of that gene like an option for that gene.
Guest: Good example is eye color.
Guest: if you have one gene that controls the eye color you will have several alleles of that gene.
Guest: Each instance of the eye color will be its own allele.
Guest: So you have like a blue allele or a red allele Or green allele or something like that.
Guest: So changes in the allele frequencies of a population over time really just means sort of changes in the proportion of the proportion of How often a given characteristic is expressed in a population.
Guest: if something becomes More dominant while something else becomes less dominant.
Guest: Well, that's that's a form of evolution and it's in a population of organisms this is key to note population, which is not necessarily a species as a whole and just refers to a Subset of a species.
Guest: It's typically Geographically located.
Guest: something like that.
Guest: The way evolution works the theory of evolution Describes the mechanisms by which it occurs And we have quite a bit of information as to that, you know genetic inheritance and mutations and all this stuff.
Guest: It's important to note that the way evolution works is by making several successive small changes Over a period of time.
Guest: that eventually adds up to larger changes.
Guest: It's actually a quote from Darwin about how you could Show his theory wrong and if it would be demonstrated that any complex organ existed Which cannot possibly have been formed by numerous successive slight modifications My theory would absolutely break down
Scott: which is true
Guest: if you could have something that would not have evolved by this this Successive changes.
Guest: and it's it's a blow to evolution.
Guest: there That's.
Guest: there's basically how it operates.
Guest: a lot of people separate micro evolution and macro evolution.
Guest: This is something I'll clear up for your benefit.
Guest: Micro evolution usually refers to evolution in microorganisms small like bacteria and such.
Guest: Macro evolution is evolution as it applies to large animals and such.
Guest: they're the same process exactly the same 100% same process.
Guest: the reason that people separate it out is because you can actually see evolution And observe it very readily in microorganisms.
Guest: That's because they have very quick generation times.
Guest: in 24 hours You can increase the population of a culture of E. Coli by several orders of magnitude just overnight.
Guest: You can't exactly increase the population of elephants by several orders of magnitude overnight.
Guest: That's kind of why you don't see great sweeping.
Guest: You know you won't see changes coming about that quickly in organisms that have long gestation periods that sort of thing Because obviously the only way these traits are arise will arise is with Reproduction and such.
Guest: that's how genes get carried forward and expressed And that's that's that.
Guest: so the the idea of evolution think the idea that that organisms change over time has been around since about the mid 1700s and basically the idea arose from observing like the fossil record and Doing studies of animals and such and what scientists found is that there's a lot of Ancestor species a lot of stuff they observed and you know fossils from a long time ago.
Guest: These organs are these structures are analogs of these structures exist in creatures today and they said I wonder why that is.
Guest: and the from that evolution kind of came about and Basically we've had tons of evidence that that changes actually occur and that we have shared Characteristics and shared structures and common ancestry for some time.
Guest: as I said Studying structures of past organisms very specifically if you study if you were to look at say the skeleton of a fish.
Guest: you'll notice it has some structures that look very similar to the things you would see in a human.
Guest: it has like a definable ribcage in the spine and stuff and Actually fish have a structure known as gill arches.
Guest: They're kind of like these basically rib like things that are used to support the gills themselves.
Guest: Humans actually have that structure in them.
Guest: It's it's up in the neck region I believe it's kind of those those cartilaginous rings Around your trachea.
Guest: Those are um, those are gill arches.
Guest: That's exactly what they are.
Guest: They don't do anything for you because you know, you don't have gills, but that's exactly what they are.
Guest: There's a species of fish and forget what it is off the bat, but it basically has a shoulder for its front flippers.
Guest: it's kind of this round nub to which a fin is attached and That structure was carried through to tetrapods and such.
Guest: That's actually in the one animal.
Guest: that Rym mentioned on Thursday the link between seagoing creatures and land-based creatures.
Guest: It's kind of what it is.
Guest: It's like this fish like thing with some limbs to it basically or limb like things.
Guest: Well, really your arm is just a heavily modified fin.
Guest: that's all it really is and the shoulder structure has been around for some time and Skeletons and such to see these very similar structures.
Guest: I mentioned the appendix on the forums.
Guest: The appendix is a vestigial structure in humans But it actually has function in some species today and it had function in previous herbivorous species progenitor organisms.
Guest: But it's this thing.
Guest: We've just had kicking around for all this time.
Guest: So evolution that's you know, just how evolution occurs.
Guest: you start with one thing you modify it a little bit and it gets passed on The link.
Guest: these these links that have been recently found they always talk about missing links and such are Really great to have like the link between homo erectus and homo sapiens.
Guest: It's great to have But for most scientists, it's not really like necessary evidence that we've been digging for forever.
Guest: We just keep digging for more evidence to further solidify our theories, but it's been a pretty solid theory for some time.
Guest: You know, we've known that that links like that have existed.
Guest: We even have living organisms that are kind of links themselves the lungfish for example.
Guest: that's that's a great link between a Seagoing creatures and and current land-based creatures.
Guest: can you know jump from pond to pond if it has to and when a pond dries up and can bury itself Mud keeps up moist and breathe air.
Guest: It's an air-breathing fish has limb like fins.
Guest: So really these discoveries that Rym is brought up while they're uh, they're nifty and such Scientists haven't had a problem believing that evolution is occurring.
Guest: It's really only the creationists and other people like that that really seem to have a problem with it despite all scientific evidence that's been shown at them and It's probably gonna stay that way for a while.
Guest: every time some discovery like this is made most people just basically move the goalposts.
Guest: They say well You can't you can't you know, you don't have a species in between these two now And then you won't have a species in between those two and etc, etc.
Guest: But the theory itself the concept that evolution occurs has been set in science for some time.
Guest: I mean, it's widely accepted and the Being studied and we have a pretty good working of working understanding of that.
Guest: So, uh, don't be too thrown off by Anything you might read any time.
Guest: the media says we were missing link discovered.
Guest: Just remember that there really aren't missing links.
Guest: There are just links.
Guest: We've known about them for some time.
Guest: So, uh, that's it and Yeah, I'm out.
Rym: So that aside.
Rym: What is your thing of the day?
Scott: Oh, that's right We can't get enough of Chuck Norris, can we?
Scott: god damn it god damn god damn.
Scott: I got another check Norris thing of the day and there's not a god damn thing you can do about it.
Scott: This Chuck Norris thing of the day is brought to you by Soul Calibur 3.
Scott: Oh, really?
Scott: Oh, yeah, really cuz.
Scott: in Soul Calibur 3 Apparently you have the ability to create brand new characters that look like you want and fight like you want and all that good stuff.
Scott: so someone had the Foresight to create Chuck Norris.
Rym: now Chuck Norris seems to only have one move.
Scott: Oh, I wonder what move it could be.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: All I know is that if you watch the video you will see that Chuck Norris can defeat any opponent with one Swiftly placed roundhouse kick to the face.
Scott: really does he have any other moves?
Rym: I don't think so.
Scott: No, how much damage did it do?
Scott: all of it all of it.
Rym: you say yes all of it.
Scott: Ah well, you know what if I was Wanting to have any chance of surviving the pending Chuck Norris apocalypse I would watch this video because it's really the only thing you can do to Prepare yourself for the impending roundhouse doom.
Rym: just remember if you can see Chuck Norris he can see you.
Scott: if you cannot see Chuck Norris were seconds from death and If anyone tries to play with Chuck Norris in a Soul Calibur 3 tournament, I'll just forfeit right away.
Rym: This is not fair All right, so along the line we have two video game things today here now.
Rym: mine though I guess I mean Scott's was Chuck Norris related and mine is actually more baseball related.
Scott: Baseball just started like days ago.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, basically someone took the game six of the 1986 World Series between The Mets and the Red Sox and they reenacted it in NES RBI baseball.
Scott: well, they reenacted the last inning.
Rym: now for anyone who doesn't know it looks like they reenacted the entire game.
Scott: Oh, really?
Scott: Yeah, just skip to the left.
Rym: I skipped all around.
Scott: Oh, wow.
Scott: It's long.
Scott: Okay, because for anyone who doesn't know basically at the very last thing in this game if the Red Sox had won this game They would have won the World Series in 1986 and the curse would have been defeated then instead of two years ago.
Scott: So, you know who won already?
Scott: I guess I spoiled it.
Scott: The only reason I know this is because I'm a Mets fan.
Scott: if it was any other World Series I would have known dick about it.
Rym: Yeah, all these guys did is they took the radio Commentary from the game.
Scott: I think it was the TV commentary doesn't matter.
Rym: They're usually similar Yeah, and they took RBI baseball and they reenacted the game play for play.
Rym: That's it yeah, and it's it's kind of fascinating to watch.
Scott: and the scary part is they must have like Saved state and redid each thing until they got exactly the ball hit, you know the way they wanted to.
Rym: yeah Because it's pretty much dead on.
Scott: it's really dead on except for one thing.
Scott: This is how close it is.
Scott: The only difference was in the ninth inning the guy the first baseman makes like an error and the ball goes by him.
Scott: Instead of that the ball like was in front of him instead of behind him.
Scott: Yeah, that's how.
Scott: that's how accurate this is.
Scott: so if you've never Experienced the Insane tension that this amazing.
Scott: This is was a pretty good game of baseball.
Scott: I mean in terms of games of baseball in history This is a pretty good one to watch.
Scott: So this is a pretty entertaining way to watch it if you've never seen it.
Rym: Yep Now anyway moving on to our main bit.
Rym: I believe we actually got the idea for this from some reader feedback.
Scott: Yeah, someone finally listened to us and emailed us Like I've been telling you to do I don't know how many times this episode Because this is the Scott tells everyone to do feedback episodes.
Rym: So here is proof that if you email us we read it.
Rym: We don't always respond, but we read it.
Scott: Yep this more.
Scott: I just responded.
Scott: actually this today I got an email from Greg Carpenter.
Scott: Hey Greg, what's up?
Scott: Yo, he gave us some ideas for some Monday episodes some of which were good and some of which were not so good, but Anyway, there's a. we're gonna do two of them today one Because one of them is actually a good one and the other one will take us five seconds.
Scott: So he figured why the hell not?
Scott: All right.
Rym: So Scott, why don't you ask us the question that he asked?
Scott: Well, he didn't ask a question.
Scott: He just gives ideas for Monday idea Monday shows.
Scott: So the first idea for Monday shows I want to talk about was what certifications do you recommend people get now?
Scott: if you don't know a certification is Like this a-plus and Cisco and MS whatever MSCE.
Scott: what it is is if you're a computer or IT professional You can go pay money to study this thing and take a test and when if you pass the test You get like this little badge of honor that you can put on your resume and your business card and all that.
Scott: You can say I am a Microsoft certified computer engineer or I am a Cisco certified blah blah blah One.
Rym: they cost a lot of money to.
Rym: the tests aren't really that difficult.
Rym: They're just annoying.
Rym: and Three the only companies that care about them are companies that you probably don't want to work for.
Scott: yeah, basically if you're going to be working for a smart person someone who knows about Computers and is not a giant evil company or a giant pile of stupid crap You don't need a certification.
Scott: In fact, those people smart people would look and say wow, you have a bunch of certifications You must be stupid as shit.
Rym: Yep, I mean basically if you have a degree as in a Bachelor of Science in computer technology or IT or information technology computer Science anything like that.
Rym: You're pretty much golden.
Rym: Anyway, if you don't have a degree Certifications are better than nothing.
Rym: if you have a degree they're useless.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if you have a chance to get one for relatively little money and little time spent like if there's someone giving out like free tests or Certification test five bucks or
Rym: your company says hey take the certification and we'll promote you and we'll pay for all the time You spend learning it.
Scott: Yeah, go for it, but Getting certifications to like try to boost your resume.
Scott: It's not a good idea.
Rym: Yeah, in fact, even if you have certifications, I'd put them on your resume But I wouldn't put them in any sort of place of honor and I wouldn't bring them up while I was at the interview Unless someone asked about them in which case I'd be perfectly honest.
Scott: I would say oh those certifications Yeah, I just took that one cuz someone paid for it.
Scott: And yeah, that one was really easy.
Scott: Whatever Yeah, or if the company you're applying for is dumb Yeah if basically if I was hiring someone and you came in and introduced yourself as As I am a someone someone certified I'd be like, all right, you're done.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much Okay, that's all I got to say on certifications.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So we killed a show and now we can do another show on home networking.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Oh, well first I forgot to mention the movie guys.
Scott: All right, right This is probably the last time you mentioned them.
Scott: unless we interact with them again, which I'm sure we will I'm sure we will.
Rym: they're cool.
Scott: Yeah, so remember last week.
Scott: You might not have listened to the episode but The guy rich from our forum who also does a podcast of his own called movies.
Scott: You should see where they talk about movies that you should see.
Scott: there are a bunch of middle-aged British people And you said middle-aged again.
Rym: She's gonna freaking kill you.
Scott: I know isn't that great?
Rym: See I'm okay I agree with her now.
Rym: It's not 32 isn't middle-aged?
Rym: because the count of Monte Cristo was badass.
Rym: He was like 40 something.
Scott: Yeah, I think your people live to like 80 90 these days.
Scott: So 40 45 is middle-aged.
Rym: Mathematically speaking I get my line.
Rym: old is older than me.
Scott: Yeah, so we're.
Scott: I'm gonna be 24 in less than a month.
Scott: So if you're 30 something you're old to me.
Scott: You might be young to my mom who's like 50 something but you're old to me.
Rym: so yeah I think I'm pretty much the line because of the inner group of the front row crew.
Rym: I'm the oldest one of this generation and then I mean we have our friends like Scott Johnson's a little older and Collins like a thousand.
Scott: he's like 10 billion.
Scott: But the way I see it, you know if my mom is 50 something she's old and I'm 20 something and I'm young.
Scott: if you're 30 Something you're in the middle middle age.
Scott: Anyway, all right that that was a tangent and a tangent of attention.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: All right back to the back to the point.
Scott: We did a guest spot on their movies podcast where we talked about a attack the gas station, which is awesome.
Rym: Yes, you should see it.
Rym: It's a movie.
Rym: You should see.
Scott: yes attack the gas station is a movie everyone should see especially if you're a geek and If anyone he is here because you know, they listen to movies you should see and they told you to come listen to us.
Scott: Well, that's awesome.
Scott: but Now, you know, we works both ways.
Scott: if you listen to us and you like movies go listen to movies.
Scott: You should see if you can go to simply syndicated comm slash movies.
Scott: You should see that HTML plus.
Rym: It's very good that we know of these people and they're cool because now we are much less inclined to do our Thursday cop-out Which is if it's Thursday, and we don't want to do a show.
Rym: We'll just talk about a movie we've seen.
Rym: Yeah, now we probably won't do that.
Scott: Yep, I mean we were gonna do probably do at some point and attack the gas station episode, but now we don't have to.
Scott: yeah So there you go.
Rym: Plus their commentary was slightly more erudite than what we would say about attack the gas station.
Scott: Yes, but I was surprised they did not know what mise en scene means which is the first thing I learned in the only film Class I've ever taken and they didn't even pronounce it correctly yet.
Scott: They think they should be able to have a movie podcast.
Rym: Oh, you're bringing out the smack talk.
Scott: Well, no, actually they they recognize in their podcast that who are we to have a movie podcast?
Scott: And of course, who are we to have a?
Scott: oh wait no, we are professionals at GeekNights, yeah.
Scott: So, yes, we are the ones to have a geeky podcast being professional geeks of the highest alpha geek character.
Rym: Yeah, we'll stand by that too If anyone wants to.
Scott: uh, if anyone wants to challenge us to like a geek duel to see you know Who is geekier and more intelligent and all that?
Scott: Unless you're like some crazy super geek unless you have a webcomic that gets more than 1 million readers per day Yeah, but then we'll only bow to you in certain areas.
Scott: Like if Gabe came up to us, we would only bow to his art geekness.
Scott: We would not bow to anything else.
Rym: His video game geek is something to be feared.
Scott: Oh, it is true.
Scott: His video game geek is feared, but I don't know.
Scott: It's probably equal to my only does have more hours But he plays a lot of crap games.
Scott: see it comes down to that sort of thing.
Scott: Yeah, but we could probably beat 90% of geeks in any geek category not to be you know Full of hubris or anything.
Scott: if we ever have our own Convention the gax if you will Then We will have to have the geek megathon where people will have to challenge us to like ten tests of geek skill And I'm sure they're all losing the board game round.
Scott: So it doesn't matter.
Scott: Anyway, right our episode is on home networking.
Rym: Yeah, if you've listened through all that just because you wanted to get to the home networking part I'm sorry, but it's Monday and Mondays tend to have a lot of cruft.
Scott: Yeah We're gonna.
Scott: basically what we do is we have the cruft on Monday and then we summarize the cruft Tuesday Wednesday and Thursday into smaller bits.
Scott: Sorry Monday guys.
Rym: Yep, but today is home networking day and one because we got the Question in the feedback email and two because it worked today.
Rym: I was asked some fairly mundane questions about home networking by my office mate the cool Korean guy.
Scott: You seem to get that asked quite a bit or at least you say you do well because one.
Rym: While I do system administration and like a lot of Linux and server stuff Where I work at IBM and pretty much all the jobs I've had I went to school for networking.
Rym: I concentrated in like networking Architecture and like high-level awesome cool routing stuff and I've never actually done that for money.
Scott: I was just about to say how often have you used that now?
Rym: I mean I I am capable on my own of fully planning out Architecting and wiring like all the way down to pulling the cables if I have to like an entire office building.
Rym: But now I don't do any of that.
Rym: I admin frickin Linux servers and databases and crap.
Scott: Yeah, it does seem to be a common question now Like if someone has something wrong with their you know computer or they find out you're a computer guy.
Scott: One of the first things I seem to get asked all the time is I just bought a wireless router.
Scott: How do I make it go or that sort of thing?
Rym: Now I could go on and on about tech support for people who aren't Technological and we're gonna do a whole episode on that someday because I have thousands of anecdotes.
Scott: Oh my god millions.
Rym: The only thing I'll say now is that you don't ask your dentist friend to rip your tooth out at a party.
Rym: Don't ask me to fix your router at a party.
Rym: I'll charge you the same amount the dentist charges exactly.
Rym: But anyway, even though I end up helping people anyway, because it's usually not that difficult and cuz it doesn't require materials like a dentist Usually I've had people ask me to like wire their house.
Rym: Oh and that requires a lot of equipment.
Scott: I just give you two middle fingers, right?
Rym: But home networking Anyone who's considering building home network who has a home network and doesn't know if it's good or it has problems The best thing I can tell you right now is that it's a good time to be alive.
Rym: networking unless you need to do something interesting is Incredibly simple.
Scott: nowadays most devices that you buy are literally just plug it in and it works Especially if you got Windows or a Mac and if you have Linux you already smart enough.
Rym: You don't need to know about whatever and even if you don't I mean leaving like Ubuntu just freakin works.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, but I'm gonna talk mostly about the actual infrastructure of a home network, you know cable modem routers wireless Switches and hubs and why?
Rym: one of them is spawn of Satan and one of them is the holiest of Holies.
Scott: the holiest of Holies.
Rym: I really like switches wires.
Rym: Yeah, what kind of wires?
Rym: all the cable II crap network cards because I mean It's really simple to me and people who have studied this sort of thing.
Rym: But while it's simple just plug the stuff in and make it work.
Rym: It's not trivial.
Rym: You have to know something.
Rym: So hopefully I can shed some light on this topic.
Rym: Now one I'm gonna assume you have broadband.
Rym: if you don't have broadband you don't have a home network.
Scott: Yeah, if you have dial-up, um What the hell?
Scott: How are you downloading podcasts?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Wow, you must be really freaking dedicated got them.
Rym: We did have one guy download our podcast dial-up a couple times really.
Rym: Yeah a guy at work who doesn't have broadband.
Scott: Holy shit.
Rym: Yeah, Wow He said he'd ever he'd listen again if we ever got James Randi on the show.
Scott: She'd give him a CD Instead of you know, it's not a bad idea DVD man, whatever.
Rym: Anyway home networking so broadband.
Rym: I'm also not going to talk about the different types of internet connections or broadband because it doesn't matter.
Rym: we could do a whole separate Episode on that and it's actually complicated.
Rym: But you've got some sort of networking some sort of DSL modem or cable modem or something And there's a little cat5 cable that comes out of it.
Scott: a cat5 cable looks like a phone cable But it's bigger and has eight little wires in it.
Rym: Now the only other thing I want to say before I get started is that if you have any sort of USB Network thing if you plug into any networking equipment with a USB cable That's bad and you should probably not do it that way.
Rym: You should listen to me and do it the way.
Rym: I'm about to say
Scott: Yeah If you'll have a cable modem or a DSL or something and it's connected to your computer with a wire That is similar to the one your mouse and your keyboard and your printer and your scanner use and it's not doesn't look like a phone Cable, that's bad.
Rym: I just had this horrible image of someone using like ps2 or AT connections.
Scott: a USB has this little three Simply with an arrow and a god.
Scott: if you don't know what USB is go to Wikipedia and type in USB.
Rym: You know what USB is.
Rym: stop listening to GeekNights.
Scott: Yeah, I mean come on these GeekNights Mondays.
Rym: Yeah, all right, so It's a. I mean I could talk about so much.
Rym: It's so simple.
Rym: quite literally if you have one computer We'll start with that.
Rym: If you have one computer and you wanna hook it up to the internet You have your cable modem.
Rym: now, you're gonna want to plug a network cable a normal network cable.
Rym: Don't worry about any special you just need a normal network cable.
Rym: Anything you buy in the store will work.
Rym: as long as it does not say crossover Mm-hmm You plug it into the hole in there in the cable modem or DSL modem and then you plug it into the uplink hole on Your router.
Rym: if you don't have a router Buy a router.
Rym: if you yeah.
Scott: Well, you should buy a router.
Scott: I recommend the Linksys WRT 54 G. that is probably the best router you can buy for home network.
Rym: Yeah, and it's not like we're paid to shill or anything.
Rym: Everyone agrees on the internet.
Rym: It's it's the best router.
Scott: It's actually because links is used Linux for the software of the router and it's all open source.
Scott: and there's a million Firmwares.
Scott: and this router is just awesome.
Rym: It's also really cheap.
Scott: It's really cheap.
Scott: It does everything you need.
Scott: It's perfect.
Scott: They sell it everywhere.
Scott: It just get it.
Scott: it's easy it works.
Rym: Alright now you have the router.
Rym: you've bought the cable modem into the uplink port of the router.
Rym: It'll say uplink on it and then you plug your PC into one of the other ports on the router doesn't matter which one and Everything will probably just work if it doesn't just work.
Scott: Your links is router comes to directions read those directions and do what they say.
Scott: usually involves putting in a CD and pushing two buttons.
Rym: Yep Now what I'm gonna keep doing is I'm gonna explain just kind of describe all the different Setups and then I'll go and explain what each of the things is and how it works on a very broad level.
Rym: Now if you say you have two computers This is when it gets a little tricky because at this point you're going to need something else.
Rym: now You can just plug two computers into the router and that'll work fine.
Rym: however, the router Has a switch in it if you use a normal router just because that makes things easier.
Rym: However, the switch is usually using logic in the router or it's somehow Taxing the router.
Rym: you're basically putting more stress on the router and as a result your connection might be a little slower.
Rym: But if you don't care, it doesn't matter.
Rym: you can plug as many computers into your router as it has holes.
Scott: Yeah, well except of course for the one hole that goes to the cable modem or DSL modem.
Scott: Yep The thing is is it won't make it that much slower unless you plan on having everyone do something Bit torrent at the same time.
Scott: It's not gonna hurt you.
Rym: Don't worry about it.
Rym: Now if you have a bunch of computers in your house, you're gonna want some switches.
Rym: Now the setup here is very simple.
Rym: again cable modem to your router.
Rym: Then one cable from your router to the switch in the uplink part of the switch.
Scott: So in the you have the.
Scott: the kid modem still goes to the uplink on the router.
Scott: but then you take a cable from any of the normal computer holes on the router to the uplink on the switch and then Plug every computer you have into all the other ports on that switch.
Rym: Mm-hmm, if you have too many computers plug another switch into that switch or plug another switch into the router.
Rym: Yep, the key here is that you can basically just keep expanding your network as much as you want as long as you use switches Mm-hmm.
Rym: Not many people sell hubs anymore, but don't buy a hub make sure it says the word 10 100. it might say a thousand switch.
Rym: you also wanted to say full duplex.
Rym: if you buy a link sis You can't go wrong.
Rym: In fact, I would recommend buying link sis for everything in your house.
Rym: They pretty much make the best home networking equipment at the best price.
Scott: Yeah, I mean sometimes you can get a cheap net gear thing, but that's like big and metal and it.
Scott: you know It can scratch furniture and whatever.
Rym: But what I just said, that's it.
Rym: That's basically all you have to do to have a home network.
Rym: now You might wonder well, right?
Rym: Why are you gonna talk about it or rib?
Rym: My network doesn't work.
Rym: Here's where the fun parts come in.
Rym: Now a router the links.
Rym: this router that you've got between you and the cable modem Does a lot of things you might not realize and you might have to set some of these up again.
Rym: There are instructions that came with your router.
Rym: It's very simple to do.
Rym: I'm not going to explain the commands you type or whatever.
Rym: What the router does is you get an IP address?
Rym: I assume you know what an IP address is from your internet provider.
Rym: They give it to you via a protocol called DHCP dynamic host configuration protocol.
Rym: usually yeah 99% of the time again your ISP will also give you instructions as to how you'll get your IP address.
Rym: follow their instructions.
Rym: Yep, now you'll get an IP address and that is your IP to the world.
Rym: That is your address.
Rym: as far as the internet is concerned when you talk to someone else It goes from that IP address.
Rym: when someone talks to you if they ever dial in that IP address It goes to your computer.
Scott: if you have five computers as far as the Internet's concerned All those five computers are sharing that one IP it.
Scott: Well.
Rym: I'm getting to that because as far as the internet concern is concerned There's only one computer.
Rym: There's no sharing.
Rym: That's true.
Rym: now That's fine.
Rym: If you have one computer now if you have two computers And you want them both to be on the internet at the same time that's not going to work.
Rym: You only have one IP address and until recently your only option was to buy another IP address From your internet service provider.
Scott: that sucked ass.
Rym: you can still do it actually yep And sometimes it's useful but it usually cost quite a bit of money and it sucks ass.
Rym: and then you needed a switch or something so you could all plug into the cable modem and Depending if you know that you need an IP address for something then you know about.
Rym: don't bother listening to the rest of this.
Rym: you Know what you're doing, but if you have no idea what I'm talking about right now It's good to be alive.
Rym: like I said before Nowadays instead of having to buy one IP address for every computer you have you buy the router that Scott just mentioned and you plug it in just like I said and The router will do something called network address translation or net.
Rym: now technically what it does is port address translation But I've never talked to an actual network professional who uses those terms.
Rym: they use net to mean everything.
Scott: it has Pat.
Scott: Way to go Pat now.
Rym: basically what it does is Computers have ports on IP addresses, so you connect to a website.
Rym: You know you type in www.whatever.com.
Rym: the DNS resolves that name to a IP number an IP address and then you connect to that computer on Port 80 because Port 80 is the port that everyone agreed is where web pages will come from and There's a different port for every protocol.
Rym: And then there's thousands and thousands and thousands of high or they're called ephemeral ports that you just use whenever you need to use a port for something.
Rym: Anytime you ever connect to another computer you do it on one of their ports from one of your ports.
Rym: Now this is very handy that there's so many of them because you only have one IP address to the outside world.
Rym: But that IP address has a whole bunch of ports 65,000 something.
Scott: yeah, yeah 65,535.
Rym: give or take Unsigned integer yeah.
Rym: Now what it'll do and I'm gonna explain this as non technically as I can.
Rym: you have you have your IP address to the Internet Inside of your network.
Rym: all of your computers have other IP addresses that usually your router will just give to you.
Rym: You don't have to worry about it Because basically you can set your router up to do the DHCP thing that I said earlier.
Rym: read the instructions for your router.
Rym: So you'll have for say you have four computers.
Rym: You'll have four IP addresses that are internal to your network using special IP addresses that only exist inside of little networks like yours.
Rym: These addresses are special in that they're not routable on the Internet.
Rym: Nothing on the Internet can ever route these special IP numbers.
Rym: so your network is basically completely on its own.
Rym: now say 10 dot 10 dot 10 dot 10 dot 1 is the IP address of your first computer and You want to connect to slash dot?
Rym: So you're the right.
Rym: it'll go to the router and the router will perform a translation on it And it'll so say it comes out of port a thousand on your computer.
Rym: your computer Just picks that port and it connects to the net.
Rym: it goes to the router.
Rym: The router will say all right ten dot ten dot ten dot one wants to connect to slash dot on port 80.
Rym: I will send this thing to slash dot on port 80 from me from my port.
Rym: Now every time something comes back to the router from the outside internet on port 9,000 it knows all right.
Rym: anything coming on port 9,000 is supposed to go back to computer ten dot ten dot ten dot one Because he's the one I gave that port to.
Rym: I hope that made sense.
Rym: basically, it'll divvy up ports and it'll take.
Rym: it'll basically take care of the traffic that's going in and out and it'll on its Own know which of your computers the traffic from the outside needs to go to.
Rym: That way all of your computers can share one IP address on the internet.
Rym: Yep, every router does this.
Scott: I don't know, but if you decide that you want to have 70,000 computers on your network all visit a web page at the same time.
Scott: You're not going to do with that little router.
Rym: Yeah, well if you've got that many you really need some Cisco hardware.
Rym: Yeah, you need something else even though our link.
Scott: This is Cisco links is technically is Cisco.
Rym: That is correct Yep, so when I say Cisco hardware, I mean routers bigger than my computer exactly now net I mean almost all of you out there are probably using net and there are a lot of Problems that people have with the internet that they don't realize.
Rym: like they'll wonder why bit torrent is slow on their computer but it's fine for all their friends.
Rym: or If I'm playing a game on half like a half-life game on Steam How come John in the other room can't connect?
Rym: but as soon as I disconnect he can stuff like that.
Rym: And it all comes down to the fact that port address translation is not perfect.
Rym: the main thing is if a request comes in if someone tries to connect to you and There's not a connection already established by the net in the router The router doesn't know what to do with that packet.
Rym: So it drops it.
Rym: So if you're running a game or something like bit torrents a good example Your bit torrent needs to be able to receive connections from the outside world Meaning a random person will connect to your IP address on a certain port and say hey, I'm here to do some bit torrent with you.
Rym: I'm gonna give you some files and seed woohoo now Because you don't know that guy's gonna connect to you and you haven't connected to him before it comes in.
Rym: on whatever port you've got Set up for bit torrent and Your router doesn't know who that port belongs to which your for computer should he send it to?
Rym: he can't send it to everyone.
Rym: That's dangerous.
Rym: So he just drops it.
Rym: Yep So if you've ever if you have bit torrent and I know a lot of people use a serious I'll use that as an example and you only get the yellow smiley faces.
Rym: You never get the green smiley face ever.
Rym: That's your problem.
Rym: it means that you can still use bit torrent but you can't ever get an unsolicited connection from someone else to you and The way around.
Rym: this is called port forwarding or port tunneling.
Rym: I Can't really tell you how to do it because it's another thing.
Rym: You'll have to read the manual for your router or search on the internet.
Rym: It's very simple.
Rym: All it does is you'll be able to specify.
Rym: Hey anything that comes in on port whatever to the router Automatically goes to that same port on whatever computer I specify.
Scott: So in other words, let's say I want to run a game server and the game server runs on port 6969.
Scott: I tell the router hey if anyone comes around to this router and they want to talk to port 6969 You tell them to go to that computer over there because that is the game server.
Scott: Yeah, the problem with this is if another computer wants to use port 6969.
Scott: Well, you can't do that.
Scott: Really?
Rym: Yep Now it I want to get into the details of that because technically it could but not it's really complicated.
Scott: That's the part you don't need to know.
Scott: Yeah That's the part I need to know because I'm the one who sets all this crap up for you'll never have that problem if you Ever run two game servers put one on six nine six nine and one on six nine seven.
Scott: Oh, yep You'll be just fine now 65,000 to choose from.
Scott: you can't go wrong.
Rym: Now the best advice I can give right here in terms of problems with Nat and Pat and all that sort of thing is that Here's a list of the applications that tend to be affected by this sort of thing.
Rym: So if you have if you're running something like this and you have trouble Involving connecting to people or getting connections or slow connections or what have you it's probably a nat issue.
Rym: Google around on port forwarding and port tunneling and fig and then you'll be able to fix it.
Rym: a lot of voice over IP stuff like Skype bit torrent II things any sort of peer-to-peer application Instant messenger file transfers tend to be hit by this a lot.
Rym: Oh, yeah certain kinds of FTP servers actually get hit by this.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know how many of you know, but FTP everyone uses FTP right.
Rym: there's two kinds of FTP Passive mode and active mode.
Rym: I'm not even gonna explain the differences But sometimes FTP doesn't work.
Rym: And if it doesn't a firewall or a net is probably the reason.
Rym: Mm-hmm and games game servers and even a lot of game clients steam in particular has a lot of trouble with ports.
Scott: anything that Any program where it's like you don't really know what port stuff is using.
Scott: but if there's a program that says I use port this number or You know, which port number do you want to use?
Scott: because it asks you for a number?
Scott: Those are the programs to watch out for other programs.
Scott: They don't really care what port they use.
Scott: They'll just do it.
Rym: Yep, and Generally, it's programs that in any way act as a server.
Rym: any program that wants someone else to be able to connect to you Unsolicited from the outside needs some sort of tunnel through the net to work.
Scott: Yep, so with a net you can go to every computer out on the internet and say hey, what's doing?
Scott: Hey, what's doing?
Scott: But if anyone wants to come to you and say hey, how you guys doing over here?
Scott: That's when the net gets in the way.
Scott: so if you want people on the internet to be able to come over to you and talk to you without you going and Inviting them or talking to them first.
Scott: That's where the net gets in the way.
Rym: Yep, if anything else if you know, you have a problem like this find some geek and say hey I'm having trouble with my net.
Rym: That way he'll probably be able to help you instead of saying hey my game server doesn't work.
Scott: Then they really don't know what your talk could be.
Scott: You're just stupid.
Scott: You don't set up a game server.
Rym: Yeah, plus as a geek I will say that the more effort and due diligence a person puts in before they come to me for help the more likely I Am to help them.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Like if someone says my internets down, I'll punch them.
Rym: But if someone says my internets down I tried rebooting my router.
Rym: I tried unplugging everything and plugging it back in.
Rym: I tried doing that IP release renew thing You told me about and it still doesn't work.
Rym: Then I'll probably help.
Scott: Yep One more cool thing.
Scott: I've talked a lot about hamachi all over the place.
Scott: I'm probably a good place to tell people what hamachi does Yep.
Rym: Now one if you're using Linux you might have you have to do some kernel things to get it working sometimes.
Scott: So yeah, if you don't have the tunnel kernel module, whatever but ignore that I'm not only gonna talk about it on the home networking level.
Rym: Yeah, not windows.
Rym: It's so trivial to use.
Rym: I could cry.
Scott: Yes, so there's a thing called a virtual private network a VPN.
Scott: people have talked about it.
Scott: you might have heard it.
Rym: Yep, your router might actually have stuff to do it built in.
Scott: or your writer.
Scott: your routers usually don't have stuff to do it But what they usually have is a thing that allows it to happen.
Scott: Yeah, you have the other tools that make it go.
Rym: you can even buy special VPN boxes.
Rym: That'll do it all for you.
Scott: You can buy hardware things that do it.
Scott: You can buy all kinds of software that does it.
Scott: There are a million ways to do it.
Scott: But hamachi I say is the best way because it is free and perfect.
Rym: now anyway Well, remember how I said that.
Rym: would you have your private network behind the net?
Rym: You have your own special IP addresses that no one else can see and they're secret and not routable.
Rym: This basically lets you even if you're out on the internet connect to your little private numbered Network all by itself as though you were there physically.
Scott: So here's an example in our house.
Scott: I have a web server.
Scott: You can't visit this web server.
Scott: It has web pages on it, but you can't visit it.
Rym: In fact, it has prototypes of GeekNights it does.
Scott: if you were to find out the IP address of our cable modem and Visit it with your web browser.
Scott: You would get nothing because the web server is hidden behind the network and you're coming around asking for stuff and We didn't forward the port.
Scott: if I forwarded the port and I said hey router if anyone comes looking on port 80 Send them to the web server on port 80 then you would be able to see what was going on.
Scott: Now if you use hamachi, this is really cool or any other VPN if you can get one to work.
Scott: But hamachi I already said is the best.
Scott: What it does is there's some hamachi server out on the internet somewhere and you say hey hamachi server blah blah blah.
Scott: It talks a bunch of mystic crap.
Scott: It's all magic that we don't understand.
Scott: We don't care.
Scott: Yeah, you don't care.
Rym: Yeah, we understand it mostly.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And what happens is you turn hamachi on and all of a sudden like magic your computer is now somehow Not really, but essentially Inside our network.
Scott: It's as if you plug your computer into our router.
Scott: But no you're far away on the other side of the world and don't be scared by hamachi.
Rym: It's really really really simple to use and as far as we can tell and as far as a lot of experts can tell it's Really really really secure.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: The only problem with it is is now you're exposing all your ports to our network.
Rym: So if you come on to our network with you know through hamachi Then it's just like your computers in the next room and I could do all sorts of things to you.
Scott: So you want to be nice and tight before you hamachi with some strange people and if you're gonna use hamachi So you can get into your own.
Scott: that's what I use it for.
Scott: So when I'm out and about the world I can get into the home network and do things on all the computers in the house From far away.
Scott: if you were gonna do that make sure that you know Your computer is in your house.
Scott: If anyone accidentally busts into your hamachi and comes inside your house you they don't have much to do.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Now there are software solutions to this too.
Rym: I mean this is hamachi is a software solution Yeah, but I mean there are other like direct software solutions of take control of a computer screen scraper type things.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, yeah VNC was popular VNC PC anywhere, but yeah We're not really gonna talk about those because hamachi in my opinion makes most of them obsolete.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I mean if you use hamachi Linux and xdmcp or hamachi and windows remote desktop I don't think anyone who's still listening know what knows what that is.
Scott: windows remote desktop.
Rym: No, the other one Xdmcp.
Scott: anyone who uses Linux knows it.
Rym: Yeah, anyone who uses Linux probably isn't still listening to this episode.
Scott: Yeah, but the people use windows using remote desktop and terminal services.
Scott: use those combined with hamachi and you're set.
Rym: Yep Now in terms of the home network and we talked about how to get to your network from the outside and about kind of how It works and the troubles Wired and wireless and moving the wires around is probably the last big thing.
Scott: Oh, we gotta talk about wireless.
Rym: Yeah, because anything else you can just read your manual.
Rym: I mean seriously most of the information that I didn't say.
Rym: I didn't say it because it's right there in the frickin manual for whatever You just bought.
Rym: now There are crossover cables and there are straight through cables on Networking.
Rym: if you can find any geek near you to make the cables for you ask them to and pay whatever they ask you to Pay because network cables literally cost me about two cents a yard to make.
Scott: Network cables at Staples are a ripoff.
Scott: network cables at Home Depot are great because what you do at Home Depot is you buy like a Mile of network cable in a giant spool and then you put the little plastic caps on the end of it and you cut it.
Scott: In fact if you don't have the skill or the tools to cut it and put the plastic bits on the ends of the cables Properly then you need someone else to do and the tools are actually kind of expensive.
Scott: if you want ones that work Yeah, but once you get one tool, you don't need any more.
Scott: Yep
Rym: now there's actually a funny story about that because I bought a giant like thousand foot spool of network cable back at RIT and I stuck it under my desk and One day I was sitting on slash dot and Scott was sitting next to me on his computer on slash dot and the new poll Appeared and it was how much cable is under your desk?
Rym: I remember that now they obviously meant like all the cables connecting all your crap together.
Rym: and I'm sitting there and I'm thinking and I I'm like.
Rym: I got about 10 15 meters of cable and I said this out loud.
Rym: Scott looks at me.
Rym: He's like a Rym.
Rym: look at your feet and I look down and my feet are resting on this thousand foot spool of cable.
Scott: Yep I still have it.
Scott: We haven't used it all yet.
Scott: Have we?
Rym: we're down to the last like 50 feet.
Rym: I'm gonna buy another one.
Rym: All right now Get the cable.
Rym: somehow.
Rym: if you get a geek to make him make him.
Rym: if you want to learn how to make them yourself It's pretty easy to do so on the internet.
Rym: I'm not going to explain it here.
Rym: Maybe I'll show someone.
Scott: if we ever do a video Google and type in how to make cat5 had a crimp cat5 cable how to make network cables You'll find it pretty easily.
Scott: You just have to remember the order of the colors.
Scott: That's the tricky part.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It's Green green and white red red and white orange brown brown bottom fucking now white and orange orange white and green blue white and Blue green white and brown brown.
Scott: Yeah that one.
Rym: That's the B one.
Scott: I knew it was green and white and brown and shit.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: All right, which which colors are used and which ones aren't?
Scott: Every other one.
Rym: now Orange white and orange green white and green are used.
Rym: Nothing else is used in a standard Ethernet.
Rym: Well power over Ethernet the others get you some yeah or in like the old way to do gigabit over cat3 and all sorts of crazy, yeah, they're just a.
Scott: here's a geeky fact that you may not know.
Scott: a Network cable has eight wires in it.
Rym: Only four of them are actually used and each wire is not actually a wire used on itself.
Rym: It's a wire that is used in pair with another wire.
Scott: so instead of the uses two wires to make one base of its magic and for the wires aren't used at all.
Rym: and Well except in special circumstances that you'll never run into.
Scott: for now at least you'll never run into.
Scott: However, if someone gives you a network cable and only has four wires in it.
Rym: Don't worry However, it is mandated by the standard that all eight wires be there for various reasons.
Rym: So if you get a cable that only has four in it, that means whoever made it skimped their ass off.
Scott: Yeah, and you should probably just you know use it.
Scott: It'll work but replace it when you have time.
Rym: Yeah, cuz that means it's a cheap cable keeps super cheap crap.
Rym: Now when it comes to buying cable one regardless you want straight through cables.
Rym: No normal person will ever Actually need a crossover cable.
Rym: a
Scott: crossover cable is like if you want to plug two computers together Directly and do something stupid or
Rym: if you want to plug a computer directly to the Ethernet adapter on a real giant like in the closet router Mm-hmm because the rotten I mean the router that a router is basically a computer.
Rym: So if you want to connect to a router directly you have to use a crossover cable In fact, if you want to be really cool.
Scott: You don't need to buy a router.
Scott: just buy a computer and put a bunch of network cards in it and then Linux on it.
Rym: Even if I mean IP changed IP tables, I could do a whole episode.
Rym: how to set that?
Scott: is it?
Scott: there's a Linux distribution called IP cop.
Scott: Yeah, you install that it turns your computer into a router slash firewall.
Rym: It's really good.
Scott: It's really good.
Scott: It's really easy, but you have to know about networking to make use of it and you have to sacrifice an entire computer.
Scott: Yeah, and you have to have a whole bunch of network cards in that computer.
Rym: But basically the routers that you buy from Linksys actually have a switch in them and then the routers like inside and you never Connect directly to the router.
Rym: So you don't need a crossover cable in that situation.
Rym: In fact, like I said, you'll never need a crossover cable unless you connect two computers together.
Rym: All the other situations are things you'll never run into.
Rym: so you want straight through to.
Rym: you want category five type E cat 5e cat 6 cat 7 cat 8.
Scott: some of them are real.
Scott: some of them are fake.
Scott: ignore them.
Scott: They're trying to get your money.
Rym: Yeah I mean if the if the cost is the same or almost the same.
Rym: you might as well get cat 6 because it'll run gigabit more reliably.
Rym: But you're probably not even gonna run gigabit to begin with because basically there's cat 3 and there's cat 5.
Rym: Those are the two standards.
Rym: right now cat 3 is obsolete.
Rym: There are two speeds that are used commonly in Ethernet 10 base T and 100 base T. the standard is rapidly becoming 100 base.
Rym: You need at least cat 5 to run 100 base.
Rym: You do not need more than cat 5 to run 100 base.
Scott: if you have cat a billion It'll still run at a hundred.
Scott: It won't go any faster.
Rym: Yep, and while gigabit, you know 1000 base T is coming out and it's becoming more and more accepted If you don't know you have a reason to get it.
Rym: You don't have a reason to get it.
Rym: as of now.
Rym: that might change rapidly But right now you don't really.
Scott: the only reason to ever have gigabit is if you're doing crazy things on your network because to fill That 100 is insane.
Scott: Like you would have to do forwarding of 3d applications over the network to use the all of the hundred.
Scott: and In fact, if you're doing that you should probably get the thousand.
Scott: but other than that a thousand is just a waste of your time.
Rym: Now if you're going to run cable like actually run it through your walls I'm gonna have to do a whole nother episode on that because there's all sorts of fire codes and safety and all sorts of Stuff that you'd have to worry about.
Scott: call a professional.
Rym: Yep, like me or an electrician if you're interested I could do an episode on how to do that because I know how to do that very well.
Rym: I've run cable in walls before but the only thing I'll say right now is that if Anything else if you don't remember anything if you're ever gonna run cable inside your walls There are two basic grades of cable to worry about.
Rym: if you buy a spool somewhere There's plenum grade and there's riser grade.
Rym: Riser grade is what you plug your computer into.
Rym: that's what you see across the ceiling in a computer lab somewhere.
Rym: That's what you see laying on the floor.
Rym: The only difference is that plenum grade will not give off toxic gases if it catches fire Yep, so if you're running wires through your house in the walls, you must use plenum grade.
Rym: I cannot stress this enough.
Rym: It is dangerous to use anything else because it does not meet fire code and you can get in trouble.
Rym: Yep, also you could die.
Rym: not really.
Rym: it's not really that dangerous but it's bad.
Rym: It's as dangerous.
Scott: It's bad enough that someone to make a law about it.
Rym: It's about as dangerous as semi shoddy electrical work would be.
Rym: There's also shielded and unshielded.
Rym: You need unshielded.
Rym: You don't need shielded unless you're doing something interesting like Magnets or running it through a wall where there's power or all sorts of things.
Rym: If I do when we do our stuff on how computers work our big series that's coming up.
Rym: I'll go into great detail about the cables.
Scott: Yeah, just if you're doing wiring between computers and the router all over your house.
Scott: Try to keep it simple.
Scott: You know if you can find a way to just go through one wall do that.
Scott: if you can find a way to go around The edge of the room do that.
Scott: try not to go in the walls.
Scott: It's a lot easier and it leaves you a lot more options.
Rym: if you want to move stuff around Yeah If you're going through the walls You basically have to plan that from the start and you'll basically want to build a wiring closet and all sorts of fun stuff.
Scott: Yeah, or get a house that's already wired and then put your computer near all the jacks in the walls.
Rym: now the basic advice I'll give for running wires You have a lot of computers is that you want to have your big old switch in a central location and run all the cables To that.
Rym: the only exception is if say the cable modem comes in upstairs like in our house And you've got two computers up there.
Rym: They plug in directly to it, but then downstairs You've got three more computers.
Rym: instead of running three cables down there You know all over the stairs or whatever run one and put a switch on the end of it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Yep Yep, other than that.
Rym: I mean wiring is pretty simple unless you want to do it all fancy-like.
Rym: Now the other option if you don't want to run wires is wireless wireless rule.
Rym: now if you have a laptop It'll just work.
Rym: don't worry about it.
Rym: If you have a PC and you want to put a wireless thing in it I'll warn you that wireless network cards for PCs are expensive and they suck most of them.
Rym: Yep Now the other option there is.
Rym: you can buy a wireless bridge which will basically you put one end of it upstairs Where your connection comes in plugged into your router or sometimes the router will do it you put the other end Downstairs and a wire comes out of it or if there's a switch on it and basically it acts like a wireless wire between those Two points.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: A lot of them use 802.11 a. Whoo Now I'm not gonna go into great detail about wireless in general other than a. here's a few basic things to keep in mind.
Rym: One the things that block wireless signals are one water two metal.
Scott: No, I'd paint bad.
Scott: Yep, plumbing bad plumbing.
Rym: Not so bad.
Rym: It's a little bad plumbing will cause other problems yeah, but the main thing that blocks it really is meshes of metal and Also old buildings tend to have a lot of steel reinforced whatnots inside of them which will block signals even more.
Scott: if your wire if Your windows have chicken wire You're not gonna get your wireless to your neighbor's house unless you open the window and yet the router in the window.
Scott: if you want To know why Google for the words Faraday cage Yep, and if you don't know how to spell Faraday Google will tell you now.
Rym: basically the advice there Is that the older your house is or the older your apartment is the more likely your walls are to block your signal?
Rym: To You want to put the wireless access point with the little rabbit ears or whatever in a somewhat central location?
Scott: The farther away you are from that the less likely your wireless will be to work.
Scott: three Oh if you want to do it if you want to be in your bedroom with your laptop in your living room Put the wireless between the bedroom and living room somewhere.
Rym: three secure your wireless access point.
Rym: There will be instructions in your router.
Rym: There are also instructions online.
Rym: if you don't know what I'm talking about in the very least Google for WEP WEP.
Rym: learn how to turn it on and turn it on.
Scott: in fact use WPA instead of WEP wherever possible.
Scott: Yes, you have a Nintendo DS then use WEP because Nintendo DS doesn't support WPA.
Rym: Yeah, but at least use WEP because that works fairly well.
Scott: It'll keep most a million ways to break it, but random idiots won't be able to break it.
Rym: And you're much more worried about random idiots than you are about hackers because a hacker will get in anyway.
Scott: Yeah, there's not much you can do about the hacker.
Scott: You know WPA can stop them from getting in by the wireless way But there's so many other ways You know.
Rym: But I guess my last bit here because we have gone on fairly long about this is that if you're setting up wireless there Are three types of wireless networking that exists now that you will run into.
Rym: there's 802.11 a Which is old.
Rym: it's somewhat obsolete now.
Rym: It uses a lot of power And it's generally only used for point-to-point links or wireless bridges like I talked about just a little while ago.
Rym: You probably won't even see that there's 802.b and 802.g.
Rym: B is the older one.
Rym: G is the newer one.
Rym: G is fully backward compatible with B. B is not always forward compatible with G Mm-hmm.
Rym: so and there are access points that will do B G or both.
Rym: When in doubt get the higher one because a G router will work just fine with your B laptop But your and your G laptop will work just fine with your B router.
Rym: But your B laptop will not work with your G only router Which usually those things aren't very common anymore.
Scott: G routers don't.
Scott: G only routers don't really exist.
Scott: Yeah, I've seen them, but yeah the thing you really have to know is that you know B or G will work.
Scott: But ideally you want a G router and G computer to get maximum speed.
Scott: yes You know if either end is B. It'll work, but it'll be the slower.
Scott: It'll always default to B Which is slower.
Scott: G is faster.
Rym: you want G now with B and in general you're going to have at some point when you set This up, and you'll follow the instructions.
Rym: It'll ask you what channel you want to use.
Rym: I'm not going to explain why but your options are 1 6 or 11.
Scott: I like 11.
Rym: don't pick anything else.
Rym: if you're having trouble Find out if any of your neighbors have wireless access points and set it to a different channel.
Scott: if your neighbor uses one your other Neighbor uses six.
Scott: eleven is the way to go.
Scott: yep I get three neighbors.
Rym: If you really want to know Google around or ask me and I'll explain in the forums Why you pick one six or eleven.
Rym: yeah?
Rym: It's kind of complicated.
Scott: don't pick two three four five seven eight nine ten.
Scott: well But don't don't pick them.
Scott: They're bad.
Rym: But in general wireless networking like wired networking.
Rym: in this modern day with links this stuff tends to just work.
Scott: Yep, and once you have the wireless part working your computer will act just like every other computer That's plugged in with a wire only its wireless, and you can walk around with it.
Rym: Yep I mean that should be it for today.
Rym: This was a very very brief and cursory overview.
Scott: Oh, there's one last thing to know about wireless.
Scott: if you have a wireless access point It's G right and you're a bunch of friends over and everyone has a G laptop But one guy has a B laptop.
Scott: it'll work, but now everyone is gonna be brought down to be.
Scott: So if you have like ten friends and one guy has B because he sucks Don't let him on your network cuz you're gonna slow everyone else down.
Rym: But basically if you're interested in all the nitty-gritty because I actually found it difficult to talk about this without going into insane detail We're starting up at some point soon our long ongoing series on how computers work.
Rym: on fundamental exact details.
Scott: We're gonna start with the lowest possible level Electricity and go up to the highest possible level playing 3d games of surround sound on the crowd.
Rym: Oh, and part of that is going to be a very long tedious section on networking Maybe more than one section on networking.
Rym: So if you have any very specific questions, you can ask me.
Rym: but just know that at some point in the future I'm going to do a fairly detailed show where I won't have to keep stopping myself to think of a simpler way to explain something.
Scott: I mean, we'll probably do like a whole episode on email and a whole episode on web and a whole episode on all kinds of Stuff.
Rym: Yep our RAM as someone asked about in the forums.
Scott: Yep We'll probably do memory twice because one time we'll talk about memory on the hardware level and then we'll talk about Memory usage when we talk about operating systems.
Rym: Yep If there's one thing you want to take away about memory as a nice little tidbit before we go One of the things that makes Linux so good compared to Windows is that Linux handles memory really really well.
Scott: Yeah, Linux isn't stupid when it comes to RAM.
Scott: I mean Linux will say, huh?
Scott: He's got this much RAM and he said this much swap space.
Scott: All right He needs to use this much for all the programs he's running and he uses.
Scott: so it uses the exact amount like It doesn't get out of control, you know Windows.
Rym: They'll just freakin use some of your RAM.
Rym: It'll leave some to never be used.
Rym: I've seen systems that act like they have no RAM, but they got you know 400 megabytes free.
Scott: Yep, and then Linux if it says you have a bunch of free RAM will say, huh?
Scott: Well, you know what I can use that free RAM to make the computer faster.
Scott: Oh, no, he needs some of the RAM.
Scott: Well forget this making the computer faster.
Scott: We're gonna use it.
Rym: Yep stuff like that.
Scott: so we're gonna start doing a very long awesome series on computers and Hopefully, you know when we start doing it people will send us some feedback like for each episode and then in the next part We can answer the previous parts feedback.
Rym: Yep, because we're gonna try to be really accessible here I'm.
Scott: my goal is that my like mom should be able to understand how a computer works if she listens to all of it.
Rym: And that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.