Rym: It's Monday December 4th.
Scott: I'm Rym and I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We talk a bit about the old days of internet video.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So we're back after yet another exciting weekend here in geek house land.
Scott: Well It's the weekend of hey, everyone came over and messed up our house.
Rym: They didn't mess it up nearly so bad as they have in days past.
Scott: I think is they usually do.
Scott: It's
Rym: partly because the last several times people have come over we have bit by bit called them out on the messes They make and now some of them are taking it upon themselves to start to clean up some of the messes or to avoid making them though Despite the fact that we provided an infinite number of plastic cups and plastic plates These people used an inordinate number of non plastic dishes.
Scott: I don't know what the hell's up with that.
Scott: I mean it didn't.
Scott: well that it's guys didn't get used too much But the they did use a lot of plastic cups, but many glass cups who were dirty.
Rym: Here's what I don't get.
Rym: we had what like a 10 11 people in the house.
Rym: Yeah, there were like 40 plastic cups out and they were almost all used.
Scott: what the hell What is.
Scott: some people just take one plastic cup and that's it and use it over and over.
Scott: I mean if you change beverages I can understand.
Rym: I was about to say maybe 30 should be used not 40.
Scott: And that's if everyone drinks Three different beverages and remember this including me.
Rym: it's not like that was the whole weekend.
Rym: most people showed up Saturday afternoon evening.
Rym: Yeah, in fact only Jess was here Friday, and she used a glass glass because I poured a drink into it.
Scott: Yeah, we accounted for the glass.
Scott: glasses turns out like five to six or maybe even ten.
Scott: glasses were used by people We don't know.
Rym: yep But a couple of that like I think Wyatt asked if he could drink his beer out of an actual glass Instead of out of a plastic cup and that was perfectly.
Scott: we accounted for a few of them, but not all of them.
Rym: Yeah, most of them were unaccounted for though the house was significantly less trash than usual.
Scott: Yeah, it's less trash than it has been in the past, but at the same time it hasn't been trashed recently.
Scott: So it was kind of like this hasn't happened in a while.
Rym: Well the living room was half trash before anyone got there just from your wii stuff that you finally cleaned up.
Scott: Well the wii stuff isn't trash.
Scott: It's you know just controllers.
Rym: Until right before everyone came the living room was strewn with wii boxes and gamecube and Controllers all over the place and dead batteries laying everywhere.
Scott: They weren't dead battery saying ever.
Scott: there are two dead batteries.
Scott: that rolled off the little thing on.
Rym: I picked up four four batteries individual battery.
Scott: Maybe some of them fell out of the battery bay on Wednesday and those the trash is was in the wii bag.
Scott: That from the Wii store, and it's still there.
Scott: cuz I didn't throw that bag out.
Rym: Yeah, yeah Yeah, I actually you know it's kind of related.
Rym: It's tech day science day.
Rym: I worked Saturday morning Which is something I almost would never do.
Scott: I only did I would never work Saturday.
Rym: Well, I did it cuz I wanted a day off that I hadn't put in for and they were kind of yeah We why you in that day, so I was like alright I'll work that Saturday if you give me an extra vacation day and give me that day off and Feed me and blah blah blah.
Rym: and they agreed to it mm-hmm Basically a four-day weekend, that's all right.
Rym: Yeah, even though you know four or five o'clock rolls around, and I'm like all right I gotta go.
Rym: you schedule me for eight hours today And my time is up and the person there got kind of mad.
Rym: No, you have to stay till the jobs done, and I'm not that kind of person, so I totally didn't stay awesome.
Scott: Yeah, I would definitely not work Saturday.
Scott: Well unless they paid me a shit ton of monies and I was actually doing something And I wouldn't stay a minute longer than I had.
Scott: oh no no no I'd be like here.
Scott: I am at exactly the time.
Scott: I'm supposed to get here.
Rym: well There have been other times.
Rym: They've tried to get me to work at night or on a weekend.
Rym: They always say hey, are you free tomorrow night, and I'll say no.
Rym: Or hey, what are you doing?
Rym: Are you gonna be around Saturday?
Rym: We kind of need some be like I have plans.
Rym: I Wonder what they'll notice when they realize that I always have plans and to when they realize that I'm not lying.
Rym: I really do always have plans.
Scott: Yeah, I mean what's up with those people who like get pressured into stuff by like a Harold and Harold and Kumar?
Scott: yeah exactly I mean there are people like you know what it is.
Rym: people are afraid of being fired.
Rym: Yet I've realized that as long as you're good enough at your job to where you're not.
Rym: a total fuck-up.
Rym: Your company's not going to fire you unless they wanted to fire you anyway.
Rym: if you work harder No one's going to notice and no one's going to care.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I do nothing and no one seems to care.
Scott: So if you are the type of person who actually does work at work all day The only way you're gonna get fired is if there's layoffs or anything like that.
Rym: Yeah I hate to say it But you know what matters a lot more than being good at your job being cool or personable or just generally having people in management like you and you know what else.
Scott: if Firing scares you that probably means you don't have enough skills to get another job easily.
Scott: if I was fired today I could have a new job next week that paid probably more than the job I have now.
Scott: yeah, so firing is not something I fear, but you're kind of hoping for it.
Scott: Yeah, kinda, so if you are afraid of being think about your job right now If you have a job are you afraid of being fired?
Scott: if so you should be building your skills in your spare time Because you were in fucking trouble all right.
Rym: Yeah, we should get onto the news.
Rym: Maybe we'll do an episode someday.
Scott: on sounds like a good episode So we didn't say it.
Scott: One more thing is we play D&D for the first time in a long time on Sunday, and we'll talk about it tomorrow.
Rym: Yeah Tomorrow is gonna be kind of a big show just because of the fact that we haven't talked about Role-playing games much since the burning wheel interview with Luke crane or the Luke crane interview about burning wheel however you want to phrase that.
Rym: But having played D&D again after a multi-year hiatus We got quite a bit to say about Dungeons & Dragons And I think we're going to do a whole bunch of episodes on it in the near future Possibly at least one tomorrow.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, we had a geek back.
Rym: We're gonna hold off on it.
Rym: Just cuz I forgot about it until just now.
Rym: Alright, I don't want to pull it up on the computer.
Scott: I pull it up when it's relevant.
Rym: Yeah, it'll never be relevant.
Rym: Okay, yeah, all right.
Rym: so in the British Isles in you know Britain and all that which one?
Rym: Albion?
Rym: okay, so in Albion.
Rym: They have recently discovered a Roman casket an ancient Roman coffin with an ancient Roman body that is missing its head.
Rym: Yeah, they talk a bit about why they think the heads missing, but it was on a stake out by the river.
Scott: now They're ward off pirates.
Rym: Yes, the pirates that came to Britain the Roman pirates.
Rym: well I mean there were the Vikings and then the Normans and all the Roman pirates the Roman pirates.
Rym: Okay for those of you who know me I've been on a bit of a Roman history kick lately a bit of a cake More like a freaking boot to the with a rocket on it.
Rym: I am a kind of person who have something.
Rym: I generally my life.
Rym: I go about it in kind of an aimless fashion.
Rym: I have long-term goals like rule the world become president have a podcast And I have short-term goals like eat this sandwich walk over there drink a soda.
Rym: the in-between the in-between is totally dependent upon the situations in which I find myself and I tend to take a fancy to something.
Rym: if I take a fancy to something I'll get really into it really quick And I'll probably forget about it really quick as well.
Rym: like a while ago Emily was learning Korean and I was trying to learn Korean - and I was really getting into it.
Rym: I learned Hangul and I was learning like I could or I could go to a restaurant and order things and I was doing okay like Early early basic beginner stuff, but I was doing alright.
Rym: Since then I've totally forgotten Hangul.
Rym: Yeah, yeah like a hundred percent.
Rym: I can't I don't remember any of it.
Rym: I vaguely remember how it's structured.
Scott: How about when you were reading all those?
Scott: Horatio hornblower thing.
Rym: No, the only reason that ended is because I finished all of them.
Rym: That was a fancy that never ended.
Rym: I like her as your hornblower more than anything.
Rym: However, I am more than Rome.
Rym: The the thing is with Horatio is that the books ended and the only outlet I have for my aggression now would be the Fan fiction archive a site that I'm not going to visit again.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: Are you sure?
Rym: Yes, I'm sure I don't want to know Really goes to the Horatio hornblower fanfiction archive about how Horatio saved the furries.
Rym: Anyway But I ever since I started listening to my favorite podcast and also one of the first podcasts I ever listened to 12 Byzantine emperors consider this a plug.
Rym: the guy doesn't have a promo or anything But it is seriously the best podcast out there.
Rym: Agree but it's what would you say is the best podcast out there other than GeekNights the best podcast there is anywhere.
Scott: Yeah I mean you can't say if it's not one that I had if it's what I don't listen to that would probably be dishonest It wouldn't it?
Scott: Yeah, probably It's a tough call.
Rym: what's your favorite non GeekNights podcast?
Scott: It's also a tough girl.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, we should probably do a show on that.
Rym: We'll just do shows on everything.
Rym: but no 12 Byzantine emperors is an absolutely amazing podcast.
Scott: It is amazing.
Scott: It's not the best.
Rym: and also I didn't know much about Byzantine history pretty much.
Scott: I hate no shit
Rym: from the time when Rome you know, like 476 a when Rome falls in popular history and everyone kind of ignored all the history after that other than like the Middle Ages crap and like Europe until suddenly the Renaissance and I really got off on that.
Rym: I really thought it was cool and I've been Voraciously finding any Roman and Byzantine history I can.
Rym: so when I saw this article now Yeah back on topic here.
Rym: The article isn't that special in and of itself in that.
Rym: Oh, we found something Roman in Britain.
Rym: Well, the Romans colonize Britain and had stuff there for a long time.
Rym: You can't.
Rym: you can just throw a spit and you'll hit something Roman in Britain.
Rym: Well Albion, but the interesting thing is they found this body in a place where they didn't think Romans ever had permanent settlements.
Scott: Maybe it wasn't a permanent settlement.
Scott: It was like the guy died.
Scott: They dropped him off.
Scott: They moved on.
Rym: Uh, no, no No It's more that there more and more evidence comes out that the Roman Empire was in many ways Even larger and more advanced than we realize.
Rym: and I guess my point here in this article is simply that Roman history as you might have learned in school or if you'll get if you read big coffee table books is interesting but a lot of it's kind of made up and They discover totally new things all the time.
Rym: We're still learning about Rome.
Rym: There is no definitive answer as to just about anything involving that Empire.
Scott: I think the problem with history is that there's just so much information even if you don't include the information we don't know yet.
Scott: There's so much information that we do know and I mean we could just spend all 12 grades of school teaching people about like one part of history and not finish it.
Rym: So when you leave stuff out it gets distorted greatly, you know Well also that we don't have a lot so we have to make things up and fill in the gaps.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, but at least we make it something up that makes sense or is entertaining or interesting.
Rym: Yeah like the time I slow I'd slain all the Dinosaurs living in the center of the earth just saving Dave and Joel's fast karate for the gentleman from certain doom.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Yeah I hate playing promos, but I want to promote other podcasts, but I'm done playing promos.
Rym: I just think they sound dumb.
Rym: I'm sorry.
Rym: All right, so I'm just gonna name podcast periodically that I like awesome.
Scott: So there's a big deal now, you know the whole Microsoft novel deal that went down and people Are all going and this is gonna be like SEO round two and and blah blah blah blah blah.
Rym: Yeah, Microsoft and these people basically made some deals the patents this suing that etc.
Rym: It said it opens up the Linux community to a lot more bullshit than they're willing to deal with right now.
Scott: Yeah so the latest Blow in this round is that novel?
Scott: Let's see novel put out a press release that says Novell boots open office and Microsoft Office Interoperability.
Scott: novel to support open XML format to advanced document interoperability.
Scott: So open office org, which is the Office suite of choice for open source peoples and that is free You can download from open office org for any operating system uses a format called open document format.
Scott: It's an XML format And it's wide open.
Scott: if you wanted to make a piece of software that reads and writes open document format files It's pretty damn easy because this documentation that says this is how the files work.
Scott: Here it is Microsoft doesn't have open documents.
Scott: They have doc files and The latest version of doc files are the open XML format.
Scott: We notice the word open Which is not very open because there is no document that at least no document that is available to everyone that says This is how these files work 100%.
Scott: I mean this.
Scott: there's some documents that tell you a little bit how they work, but you cannot easily or legally really create a Program that can read and write Microsoft Office open XML format files like you can with open office files.
Scott: This is a big deal for many reasons.
Scott: It's one of the reasons that Massachusetts is State of Massachusetts is thinking about moving to open document format and Many governments around the world.
Scott: because if you don't use open document format or another opened up or another format which is truly open Then you're basically beholden to Microsoft as the only people who can provide software that can read your important The
Rym: reason Microsoft never embraces any of these open formats is simply that not many people would continue to use Microsoft Office Suites with their crazy high price tags if they weren't forced to by the fact that other people use them.
Scott: Yeah, it's like oh that guy over there made a document file.
Scott: The only program that can possibly read that file Properly, I mean there are ways to read it.
Scott: There's plenty of little converters and things, you know.
Scott: But the only thing that can read it properly and edit it properly is open off is Microsoft Office.
Scott: Jillian dollar.
Rym: there have been lawsuits and such where like say a state agency requires if you do something online You have to send a doc file.
Rym: now think about that for a minute.
Rym: That means that in order to do the thing with the government that they're they're offering you have to purchase a third-party piece of software that is unrelated to the government in any way and You must do that in order to interface with your government the government you're paying for with your tax dollars.
Scott: It's exactly the same as if you were driving down the road and you wanted to make a right turn and it's a government public Road that your tax dollars paid for and they said no.
Scott: No, only Ford cars can drive on this road.
Scott: Yeah It's a perfect analogy.
Scott: if you don't agree, you don't understand technology.
Scott: Anyway, what's happening here is Novell.
Scott: that first of all, you're gonna see the headlines all say Novell forking open office.
Scott: That's not true.
Scott: Novell forked open office org a while ago and If you use SUSE Linux the default open office actually like says Novell on it Because they did.
Scott: they forked it a while ago.
Scott: and the real open office, you know Since they they tend to take a lot of thick because the way the GPL works is you know If you write code into GPL software Then you you have to release it and people take it back.
Scott: And so the real open office looks at that one and uses it for their Linux build.
Scott: a lot.
Scott: Well, Novell has said all right.
Scott: This is what we're gonna do.
Scott: first We're gonna make a little plug-in interface for the R fork of open office.
Scott: All right They're gonna make a little plug-in interface and that plug-in interface will be open source as it is legally required to be.
Scott: Then we're gonna release a few plugins and you can put in that plug-in interface that will let you open and convert Microsoft Office open XML files really easily.
Scott: Alright, you can do that too, you know, but they're not gonna open source the converters but they don't have to because of the way it works.
Scott: see a lot of people are like Oh, there's gonna be lawsuits and patents and all this and this is what they're worried about.
Scott: No, what they're really doing is this Microsoft realized that Vista is not really going to be the biggest hit in the universe.
Scott: So what they've done is they're saying alright the basic reasons that Linux can't make it on the corporate desktop is a lot of it Not being interoperable with Microsoft and its products that have already dominated the corporate desktop.
Scott: So what they've done is they basically bought out Novell.
Scott: they're gonna make SUSE Linux which is the Linux that Novell sort of owns kinda and They're gonna make it interoperable basically eliminating every other Linux's chance of Desktop movement in the corporate zone.
Rym: Yeah, luckily not that many people use any stuff anyway right now.
Rym: I mean a lot of companies are moving toward Ubuntu.
Rym: Ubuntu just because it's so easy and it just works.
Scott: Yeah, but those are only companies where there are smart people.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, but things will change over time.
Rym: Maybe.
Rym: look France is moving toward Linux.
Rym: I don't think they're gonna use any of this Novell business.
Scott: yeah, the thing is, you know, if you're a company and You know, you want to move to Linux and then you say hey this Linux over here This one works can read all my old documents and that one can't.
Scott: which one am I gonna use?
Scott: Oh I'm actually still tied into Microsoft.
Scott: I just think I'm cool because I'm using Linux now You know, it's really not the greatest thing in the world.
Rym: Yeah There's really no easy answer except for people to actually stand up to Microsoft and say they're not gonna use their proprietary Document standards, which I don't.
Rym: I haven't used Docs in forever.
Scott: Yeah me either but it seems like Obviously all the open source community people even the people who are less crazy like ourselves are going up.
Scott: fuck sues is done.
Scott: Yeah, novella's done anything they do is basically like and a dragon's bane and we're not going near it.
Scott: You gotta stay far away in spade.
Rym: Yeah, that would imply that we're dragons.
Scott: Well, you know if you're awesome enough to use open-source software and know about Linux, you might be awesome.
Rym: dragon Man, I got to stop playing with this keyboard when I should be doing the show.
Scott: I'll just like cut the power wire on it.
Scott: Then you won't be able to do anything.
Rym: You know, I didn't even look.
Rym: I wonder if the power wire is the right one for the other compressor.
Rym: The company is still out of stock.
Scott: Oh, wow.
Scott: Did you check recently?
Rym: I called him a week ago.
Rym: They're like, yeah We don't have any.
Scott: it doesn't look like it's the right one because that Transformer is real big and the one for that compressor was real small.
Rym: true true.
Rym: Yeah, I just thought of it suddenly.
Rym: But I can make such cheesy music with this thing.
Rym: It's so fantastic.
Scott: It's like the ultimate 80s box for sure.
Scott: I mean if you just if you had one of these in someone's house in the 80s They wouldn't need to buy any cassette tapes, man If only we could have the consumer tech like this a decade early.
Scott: Oh, so today we'd have the keyboard that makes 2000s music just perfectly like a push a button in like record company tech.
Rym: because seriously some of those Accompaniments and instruments built into this keyboard wouldn't sound out of place at all in an 80s movie soundtrack like straight up.
Rym: Yeah, I think I've heard these songs in movies before.
Scott: Yeah, I mean seriously we could somehow get a keyboard that you know.
Scott: We bring it to like a club push the buttons and all of a sudden we're the best DJ in the world.
Rym: Yeah, anyway things of the day oh shit.
Rym: so A while ago.
Rym: We had a thing of the day about a stupid criminal who kept falling through the roof and all sorts of hilarious hijinks.
Rym: I was going to use as my thing of the day the Benny Hill remix of that but instead I Have to use this this wonderful gem of a criminal who?
Rym: Broke into some dudes house naked in the middle of the night and fell asleep on the couch.
Scott: Well, it's unknown what you went through that too quickly.
Scott: You gotta like tell that one.
Rym: Well, I gotta tell it slow.
Rym: I got a good pendulum still All right.
Scott: Well, the other thing is we don't know if he was naked before he broke in or after.
Rym: You know, it's tough to say.
Rym: The actual story here is this guy comes home late at night.
Rym: He's 330 a.m.
Rym: His windows been broken.
Rym: So he goes into his house all suspicious like there's a naked black man laying there sound asleep on the couch.
Scott: Well, it's a black man broke into a black man's house.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, and he's laying there except for he's got like a sheet Kind of over his genitals.
Scott: I think the The guy who owns the house put that there.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: It's not entirely clear But I think I'll admit the guy who filmed this.
Rym: I mean, it's probably not staged but I wouldn't wake the guy up with a camera.
Rym: I would just wait for the police to show up.
Scott: Well, the police showed up like 10 seconds later.
Rym: I mean, yeah But he films himself kind basically going.
Rym: you got to see this.
Rym: and then he goes into his house and he films this guy Just naked in his sleep and then for whatever reason he decides to wake the guy up Well, he kicks him which is what I would have done first.
Rym: I would have kicked him squat in his naked ass nuts and the guy wakes up and is suitably indignant though suitably Dazed and confused at first.
Scott: Yeah The only thing I can like with the the guy who owns the house I can tell what he's saying mostly fuck you what the fuck you do to my house.
Rym: best I can tell the.
Scott: the guy who broke in says No, the best I can tell is when the guy kicks him awake.
Scott: He's like you broke into my house guys Like how you know day?
Scott: That's what I think he says.
Scott: it's up for.
Scott: it's up for debate there's there's nothing there.
Rym: This guy is about on the level of the guy who broke into that convenience store.
Scott: Yeah, the funniest part of the video is after the guy, you know kicks the intruder enough that he's down on the ground The cops show up and the cop the cop just walks in.
Scott: he's like what's going on here?
Scott: The guy says look I broke in my house and he arrests him right there.
Rym: Yep and the great thing is the guy like he's kind of.
Rym: he beats the guy up a little bit starts kicking him the robber and The robber is looking at him with the look of I'm gonna take you down right when the cop walks in.
Scott: Yeah, and at least he doesn't fight the cop.
Scott: He just liked it.
Scott: He just goes down.
Rym: It's pretty funny, I don't know if if I came home and there was a naked guy laying on the couch I would probably just call the police and wait outside and if he came to try to leave the house I hit him with a bat or something.
Scott: Yeah I would pretty much just stand there with a video camera watching him.
Scott: so I get a video of the police arresting him.
Rym: I just take a picture.
Rym: I never would have thought to video it.
Scott: Well, it's because you don't have a camera?
Scott: Yeah, we do not not a useful one.
Rym: We have a camcorder.
Rym: Anyway, that camcorder cost over $3,000.
Rym: Yeah in 1986.
Scott: so I would definitely video it if I had the equipment.
Scott: But I wouldn't like wake him up before the cops got there.
Scott: if he did wake up before the cops got there I'd be just I would have a bat and I just go wham And he'd be on the.
Scott: I think is I wouldn't want to make a mess.
Scott: Like I try to hit him in the nuts I don't want like his head bleeding all over my carpet or any.
Rym: but you don't want nut all over your carpet either.
Scott: There won't be nut.
Scott: if you hit a guy in the nuts of the baseball pad I'll just send his nuts flying into his stomach.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: I would do I'd probably go into the closet where I got that old sword and I just stand there looking real Fucked up and menacing with it.
Scott: But yeah, you don't want to actually poke him low cuz they even more blood.
Rym: Yeah, but you know what?
Scott: The trick is there's a naked guy in your couch has already made a mess by being naked on your couch.
Scott: No, he's got his naked hobo slime on your couch.
Rym: the couch is forfeit.
Scott: So you don't want to do any more damage by getting blood everywhere cuz it'll all stay in the couch.
Scott: You spear him with the sword into the couch like a pushpin But then the blood might leak onto the carpet under the couch.
Rym: Not our couch.
Rym: Our couch is sturdy.
Rym: It'll hold it in.
Scott: I don't know about that.
Scott: Anyway, my thing it is is pretty short and I'm not gonna read the whole thing, even though I could easily Just get it, you know how to read.
Scott: yeah, I do know how to.
Scott: well, it's very short.
Scott: It's like it wouldn't take too long.
Scott: I do know how to read.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: I am literate.
Scott: Hooked on phonics works for me.
Rym: That was really lame.
Scott: You suck.
Rym: No one makes hooked on phonics jokes anymore.
Scott: Now they do.
Rym: Yeah, 1996 called.
Rym: they want their joke back and you know what SNL called me.
Rym: They want that joke back to me.
Scott: So This is a little webpage that describes the intelligent design sort.
Scott: now If you're not a programmer, you might not know what a sort is pretty much.
Scott: Let's say you have a bunch of stuff and you got to put it in order, right?
Scott: So I've got the numbers one two and three and I've got them just sitting there.
Scott: I got to put them in order.
Scott: There are many different ways to program to write a program that does that.
Scott: there's a bubble sort.
Rym: That was the first one I was gonna say.
Scott: Yeah, there's a quick sort.
Scott: There's all sorts of different sorts And all sorts of sorts.
Scott: Yes the intelligent design sort is obviously not an actual sort but a bit of comedy that combines the quote theory of intelligent design with the Principle of a sorting algorithm and it is quite hilarious.
Rym: Fairly, well done.
Rym: Good show.
Scott: Good show.
Scott: So here's your thing of the day, right?
Rym: So being lazy as we tend to be on Mondays, we were gonna talk about, you know codex and all that.
Rym: We've said we're gonna talk about that before video on to internet and we realized not to sound like crotches old men that many Of you out there are spoiled young kids with the YouTube and your Google video Who have no idea the trouble that people used to have to go through to see any sort of moving content on to internet?
Scott: So hopefully I mean when YouTube finally existed and finally worked properly.
Scott: It was like Whoa.
Scott: Finally it is here.
Scott: You have no you can't understand what we went through before we had this modern technology.
Scott: This is ten years of anticipation So hopefully this will give you some appreciation of those who came before.
Rym: See we grew up when the internet was the wild wild west where most people wait even before the internet.
Scott: Let's talk about the video.
Rym: Well, I was gonna say there the internet was around but most people who had internet didn't actually have internet.
Rym: they had like prodigy or something and Seeing a moving thing on the internet in a website was this unfathomable Dream, but seeing a video on your computer was already unfathomable.
Scott: I mean people would have something on their computer like Microsoft and Carta or some sort of other CD based Encyclopedia and there might be some short video clips on there.
Scott: But they were like two seconds long and the resolution was crap like in those days I remember watching like a short clip from Star Wars and in Carta.
Scott: I had a multimedia like a Pentium one and go Yeah, but my for guys saw that if you saw it now you you probably be like you can't even tell it Star Wars.
Scott: It was that shitty my 486.
Rym: I got one of those encyclopedias with it and it had these like 15 second clips and the resolution was like 50 by 50 Something like that.
Rym: Yeah, and I would sit there for hours Pouring over the the WAV files and the MIDI files and the Movie files that were 50 by 50 just in utter shock.
Rym: Ah and wonderment.
Scott: Yeah, I mean we had much better videos to watch on our VHS tapes, but somehow when it was on the computer It was amazing.
Scott: I don't know why.
Rym: you know what it is.
Rym: It's kind of like back in the day when if a video game talked to you in English You just wet your pants.
Scott: I guess yeah, but you know, yeah Talks to you in English all the time.
Rym: Yeah But like the first time I played TIE fighter and x-wing and the people talked to me I freaked out and I'm like dad look at this.
Rym: Look at this.
Rym: Darth Vader just said something Holy crap, and I didn't know what to do.
Scott: and obviously, you know what he said?
Rym: I'll say I'll put it this way my parents where This is the diplomatic mission My dad was Understandably unimpressed.
Rym: I don't think that anyone other than me and my friends my age and my little brother was impressed by this.
Rym: No, I don't know what it was.
Rym: It's just seeing like watching a crappy video on the computer.
Rym: was this magical thing, but watching a tape was just old head Yeah, and in those days the videos were a VI or MOV.
Scott: It was pretty much QuickTime and Windows Media Player.
Rym: Yeah, I mean MPEG video was around pretty early But no one could play them.
Rym: you couldn't just play it in a computer.
Rym: computers didn't have media playing things.
Rym: You had to get a special MPEG player and most of them cost money.
Scott: It was it was a chip on a card and you stuck it in your computer and ran a wire from the card To your video card.
Scott: and then that that was actually way beyond the days of just plain old a VI.
Scott: Yeah, that was.
Scott: it was that I was like the first thing after a VI came around.
Rym: It was the same thing when DVD came around.
Rym: well early computers couldn't decode MPEG - you had to have a DVD decoder card in your computer.
Scott: Yeah, cuz I mean the way it works is.
Scott: We had a VI and a VI was uncompressed.
Scott: But you know, they might have just made compressed the you know, the video to make it shittier and lower quality.
Scott: But the video it file itself required less processor to play.
Scott: I mean it was basically reading JPEGs or bitmaps and just displaying them quickly one after the other, you know And these files are big and you couldn't really do much with them.
Rym: Yeah, I mean you would die like if you wanted to get a video.
Rym: I remember I downloaded a five second clip from Les Miserables and it took like an hour and it was super Awesome by super awesome.
Rym: I mean it was tiny and shitty and skipped.
Scott: Yep, but if you wanted to play an MPEG, which is actually a compressed video file That means not only did you have your CPU have to play the video file.
Scott: It also had to Decompress the video file simultaneously.
Scott: That was a lot of work and the processors of the day were not capable of doing it.
Scott: I mean you think about what you have today with like the MPEG 4s and the divixes and the xvids.
Scott: if you try to play an x-vid on like a Pentium 3 the thing will be like Because it doesn't have enough power to Decode the x-vid into playable video as fast as it's supposed to be played.
Scott: I mean it decodes one frame of the videos slower than the speed at which you need to watch one frame.
Rym: I mean pretty much video on computers was confined to animation from a game or CD content that was low quality and crap.
Rym: I mean, we're not talking about streaming.
Scott: the mere idea of streaming video was ludicrous like Inconceivable and impossible because the fastest modem you could have was like a 14 4 or 28 8 and that was way Crazy by those times.
Scott: Yeah, I remember by 28 8 56 K was even crazier and that didn't come for years.
Rym: I mean I had a 2400 baud modem and then we upgraded and I got a 336.
Scott: there was at least a year where 33 6 was it?
Scott: Yeah, that was it.
Scott: And even when 56 K's came out they were like not every place supported 56 K. So it was like thirty three six slash 56 K.
Rym: Yeah the first real revolution.
Rym: I mean.
Rym: actually I did download an AVI.
Rym: I still have it to this day.
Rym: It's the first large video I ever downloaded from the internet.
Rym: It's in the same directory as the first mp3 I ever downloaded or played other than Winnie.
Rym: Winnie.
Scott: Winnie It really whips the llama's ass.
Scott: Yeah now there were a lot of.
Scott: you could get a video sometimes on a CD romp.
Scott: That was pretty much the best way to get a video.
Scott: Yeah, because it was faster than downloading anything is you just got six hundred and forty megabytes, right?
Rym: Except there weren't.
Rym: no one was making videos.
Rym: So the only videos you get were things in like the Encarta encyclopedia that your parents bought you.
Scott: Well, for example, we had a game that came with our PC was undersea adventure.
Scott: It was just a little educational aquarium game.
Scott: But there were all these little videos with Jacques Cousteau and he would say stuff I remember pouring through like FMV's and video games AVI files on CD roms and they were all short and low quality and amazing somehow.
Rym: Yeah, I remember when I had xcom mission UFO and I pulled the AVI file out of it and I made it action God a macromedia action presentation and I put the video in it and I thought I was so cool.
Scott: Mmm, yeah Monty Python in the.
Scott: oh, yeah the Monty Python games had the Monty Python game for Windows 3.1 and I had a lot of 100 by 100 pixel.
Scott: it had a lot of incredibly low resolution skit videos That were all cut short and they were all on the CD ROM.
Scott: So whenever you're gonna watch one you had to wait for it to read the CD ROM and then play it and then oh man Those are the days so fast forward to the middle of 56k era and the beginning For many people of the cable modem era.
Rym: DSL was kind of a pipe dream back then.
Rym: I mean your options were.
Rym: really if you lived in one of the places where they were testing cable modems You could get a cable modem.
Rym: I was actually very lucky and that one of the first cable modem deployments was in the area where I lived and I had a Cable doesn't seem to understand like his time when the cable modems are coming in.
Scott: It was actually when most everyone had 56k modems.
Rym: Yeah I mean I got me and my friends in high school and like early high school we're at the point where we were playing games with low pings and We couldn't fathom people having a ping higher than like a hundred.
Scott: cable modems weren't widely available in most areas like 2000 even like yeah 99 2000.
Rym: They were expensive.
Scott: they were really expensive, you know.
Scott: and DSL it was sort of like depending on where you lived.
Scott: It was either the DSL or cable, you know If you lived really close to the phone company DSL was coming in if you live if you have her in a place where your Cable company was really good.
Scott: You got lots of cable.
Rym: Yeah, cable modems kind of bridged the gap because before then the really cool uber people had isdn lines Still a hajillion down.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: so then cable modems started appearing and early on the reason cable modems were so awesome is they didn't really pay attention to the Bandwidth.
Rym: you used it all.
Rym: it was free and open and fair game.
Rym: Whatever you could get you could get and most people didn't even have computers where I lived.
Scott: So it's not like they expected anyone to have more than one computer or a computer powerful enough to use lots of bandwidth.
Rym: I also don't think they expected me and my friends and all the other geeks in the area to Saturate that cable modem network immediately.
Scott: Yeah go napster.
Rym: Yeah, but right around that time Real media appeared and they put forth something called real media appeared like in Way earlier.
Rym: That's when I had a cable modem.
Scott: Oh, wow.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Yeah, they appeared I think when I still had a 14-4 modem.
Rym: there were most of high school.
Rym: I had a cable modem.
Rym: Yeah Anyway, yeah until it went to shit when we were seniors because then everyone got a cable modem and it was still unrestricted bandwidth access.
Rym: so pings Skyrocketed and throughput fell apart and everything went to shit.
Rym: and then I moved.
Rym: I didn't care anymore.
Rym: Yeah, but no right around that time when I had a cable modem not that it mattered for this Real media appeared and a lot of old-timers will still call any kind of real file a real audio file a real audio player Because that's all they made back then Real audio.
Rym: It was a big horrible bloated application and it would stream an Incredibly low quality audio to your computer live semi live.
Rym: It buffered for like a minute and they would play a minute and ten second clip.
Scott: I got it.
Scott: I got it All right, apparently I looked it up just now.
Scott: the first version of real player came out in 95 and it was real audio player which I remember that because what it could do is you would go and get internet radio and it would take audio and Compress it horrendously.
Scott: It would basically sound like mostly static and but you could listen to live or semi live Streaming audio on your computer.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Now then I didn't even have a cable modem yet.
Rym: That was the 33-6 mode.
Scott: I didn't use that thing until like God 97 it must have been when I tried to do that.
Rym: see I Remember a lot of websites appear that had a bunch of real audio clips that were cool and I used to the ones I always looked at.
Rym: a lot were stuff about musicals.
Rym: there be clips from musicals and They would be terrible and shitty.
Scott: Yeah, I mean remember there were no mp3s Yeah, and then there was the other player which eventually they came out with real player, which is just real player.
Scott: Yeah, I could do video and yeah do.
Scott: then it was like real player g2 which worked better with Intel processors.
Rym: Remember that yeah, and there were all sorts of basically real.
Rym: the company was a collection of idiots and assholes Pretty much from the start.
Scott: Yeah, they were real jukebox.
Rym: They were universally reviled.
Rym: They were one of the earliest, you know Companies with really bad bloatware spyware and all that sort of stuff.
Scott: They cleaned up their egg mostly lately Yeah, and but now they've sort of no longer have a use for them.
Rym: No, really, they're no worse than any other company out there nowadays.
Rym: They don't really deserve any particular hatred or anything not anymore people our age Remember what they were and can't forgive them.
Scott: No, they pretty much started a lot of this stuff.
Rym: Yeah, I mean they were one of the first applications that would have the checkbox.
Rym: Like would you like to receive email from us?
Rym: Would you like to subscribe to blah?
Rym: Would you like to install the special handy super duper toolbar?
Rym: and the thing is It would show a list of all the things you can install they'd all be unchecked.
Rym: So you'd click OK, but the list had a scroll bar and if you scroll down you'd see that there were like 40 options under the five at the top that weren't checked and all the Ones underneath it you couldn't see were checked.
Scott: Yeah, I default when I'm making that up.
Scott: That's absolutely true.
Rym: It was Those those people I I hated them.
Rym: So and I remember the CEO of real would always say horrible things.
Rym: He wasn't one of the earliest proponents of DRM.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, like the thing about real was back in the day They actually had an innovative and important technology and that when you had low bandwidth and a shitty processor Real audio and real video made it possible to watch or listen to audio and video streaming from the internet.
Scott: in My 14-4 modem I could watch CNN news in like this tiny little window And it was minutes upon minutes of video that I could watch any just by clicking on it.
Scott: And it was crazy and like you would update all the time Like I could open up real player and watch the news like it updated five times a day and that was insane
Rym: Yep, and then there was the point at which MPEG video started getting you know Computers are fast enough and there were ways to play it for free and you didn't need hardware anymore.
Rym: And then a lot of sites hosting anime music videos or hosting, you know Just various videos of not really not a lot of pirated stuff.
Rym: for a long time It was mostly fan created stuff and cool stuff people had filmed and like news.
Scott: Well, that was even way later.
Scott: Actually the thing that happened after real player is if you started to use Napster.
Scott: Napster mostly did mp3s, but the open nap protocol that came around in like the wake of Napster.
Scott: I don't know enough about it But it's basically people were able to run servers that did the same thing.
Rym: that really kind of peaked and then died Like during our freshman year of college.
Scott: it did.
Scott: Well, no, it was actually around for a long time.
Scott: We just didn't get into it until in college, but a lot of people were using Napster like things like around the year 2099 2001, you know in the in the peak of Napster to trade videos.
Rym: also see in those days I that stuff all that old peer-to-peer thing wasn't quite flesh out yet.
Rym: And I even remember when Napster came out I laughed at all my friends like why would you use that?
Rym: just go to the mp3?
Scott: Sites exactly.
Scott: It's like so many people were just using the regular Napster to do mp3s But there were a lot of savvy people who would get what.
Scott: was that program?
Scott: something Gator?
Scott: Not not the bad Gator.
Scott: the spyware one a different one and you could like it.
Scott: was it nap Gator?
Scott: nap?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: You see I didn't do any of that.
Rym: I had a bunch of websites I went to that had regular.
Rym: I mean, you know There's wares community today and the wares community back then which was actually a long time ago used to be very different Though in a lot of ways is still very much the same.
Rym: just different punk kids different punk kid ideals Yeah, but the people who were in the know or the people who were lucky I was one of the lucky ones.
Rym: I didn't actually know any of these people but I ended up with the passwords to a whole bunch of FTP sites that had all sorts of wares and all sorts of like anime videos and all sorts of just fun stuff in there.
Rym: So I never saw the reason for peer-to-peer.
Rym: Why would I waste my precious upstream bandwidth helping people?
Scott: Anyway, the next thing to happen was pretty much mpeg-4 and divics.
Scott: That was like the smash that is created the environment We have today.
Rym: Yeah, that was the Industrial Revolution of video on the internet.
Scott: Basically what happened is they came up with this mpeg-4 which was hey we can compress the video a lot.
Scott: Still have it look good with our fancy algorithms.
Scott: You need a better CPU and if you download about 200 megabytes of video you can get like a half hour of Really good looking shit.
Rym: And of course the rest was history.
Scott: Yeah, you know we kill.
Rym: honestly There's been a lot of trend until YouTube and Google video.
Rym: The trend was away from streaming stuff because people would rather just download it.
Scott: Yeah, I mean you could get really high quality stuff.
Scott: All you had to do was download it with.
Scott: you know, your favorite peer-to-peer thing Which you know, there were a lot of them over time and the codex kept improving.
Scott: you kept getting better and better looking video with less and less download time.
Scott: and
Rym: Yeah, and streaming really just came back with YouTube and Google video Which the two single-handedly brought back the idea of that streaming video Could be popular and good and also the fact that bandwidth increased to the point to where it was feasible for the majority of cool People to be able to do it.
Scott: Yeah I mean flash vid.
Scott: it's kind of weird though because people are getting higher and higher quality stuff in less and less space.
Scott: Right flat YouTube and flash video is basically like yeah, we don't care what it looks like anymore.
Scott: We spent all that effort making these awesome codex and honing these algorithms.
Scott: now Toss them out the window.
Scott: who needs?
Rym: because YouTube and Google video are like watching something on TV.
Rym: You do it for the content.
Rym: if you want the quality You go to wherever you go to get that sort of thing.
Rym: and get that sort of thing and burn it to a CD And put it in your stack of a thousand fan subs that you're never gonna watch, but you can say you own.
Scott: Yeah It's good to see that You know.
Scott: like while that a lot of fan subs do end up on YouTube and some people watch them there maybe because it's easier for them there's still the Large community and very popular group of people who you know, they want to watch a whole show.
Scott: They're not gonna freakin watch it on YouTube in three or four parts of five minutes each.
Rym: You'd be surprised how many young and there are a lot of.
Scott: there are a lot of people who do that But there is still plenty of people who go and they use the bit Torrance and they download their favorite show in HD or whatever.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah HD anime HD Anime or you know much higher resolution.
Scott: It only doesn't take up that much space, you know it doesn't take too long to download.
Scott: on bit Torrance if you're watching something popular and Goddamn, is it good to have that compared to what?
Scott: Avi's on a CD that are 50 by 50 and yeah 30 seconds long.
Rym: go to an FTP site.
Rym: We have to upload 500 megabytes before you're allowed to download 10 megabytes.
Rym: So I uploaded 500 megabytes of garbage from a looping garbage file.
Scott: I made think about that.
Scott: think about that Back in the day.
Scott: you had to have a CD Right and you could fit on it.
Scott: Maybe a few minutes of incredibly low-resolution crap video.
Scott: Nowadays, I can fit like three or four Very good-looking episodes of an anime or any other TV show on a CD that just blow your mind.
Scott: The difference was the CPU and not the storage space.
Scott: Well, this is a CD.
Scott: now is a CD then?
Rym: Yep, because they could have had those algorithms then too But you'd look at them and no computer of the time could possibly decode that in any reasonable fashion.
Scott: Yeah You would have to basically leave your computer running overnight and then maybe like a few more like days days later.
Scott: It would play it, you know, you couldn't do it at the same time decoding and watching.
Scott: That's how fast your computers are.
Scott: It's insane.
Rym: But yeah I guess hopefully we offered a little bit of perspective and Sometime in the future.
Rym: We'll probably end this series by talking about the current state of it.
Rym: You know the codex that are popular now how to get them all that stuff.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at frontrowcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.