Rym: It's Thursday August 17th, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We talk about hacking but not the kind of hacking you might expect for tonight.
Rym: We hacked the Wildwood, New Jersey boardwalk.
Rym: Let's do this Well GeekNights fans.
Rym: You're in luck.
Rym: today is prop.
Rym: well tonight is probably the last episode where I will not have a pop filter.
Scott: It's also going to be one hell of an entertaining episode if we know what people have liked in the past.
Rym: Yes, because we've done not one, but two stupid things.
Rym: oh Yeah, oh my god.
Rym: Oh my god, but before that because all of you You know really really seem to like it We have to do the news and the thing of the day and all that other stuff.
Rym: but bear in mind That at every moment while we are speaking about these other mundane real-world issues We are just trying to hold back the torrent of awesome that is about to follow.
Scott: We are barely containing the Absolutely hysterical and crazy main bit for this episode.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: It's kind of weird because the main bit for this episode is in the same style as the things that people have greatly enjoyed in The past.
Scott: however all of those times in the past when people have greatly enjoyed an episode We said this episode is going to suck.
Scott: and now we're saying this episode is going to rock.
Scott: So let's see what happens.
Rym: in the very least even if the episode might end up being mad for whatever reason The things we did will speak for themselves.
Rym: They are the kinds of things that if we were not the ones doing them They would be things of the day.
Scott: They would be.
Rym: indeed now I believe Scott wanted to do a whole bunch of meta bits since we do have a Not a shit ton, but a good deal of new listeners from Otakon.
Scott: Oh, all right.
Scott: So for anyone out there GeekNights is a podcast.
Rym: Yeah, yeah.
Scott: Yeah, and we do four episodes a week.
Scott: So if you happen to subscribe to GeekNights Thursdays, guess what?
Scott: There are also GeekNights Mondays Tuesdays and Wednesdays And Let's see.
Scott: What else do you have to tell them?
Scott: We have a forum.
Scott: That's really awesome.
Rym: Yeah, the forum has people who may or may not actually even listen to the show at this point.
Scott: Yeah, and if you go there, they're cool people talking about stuff.
Scott: also surprisingly the forum comes up near the top on Google for a whole lot of really interesting search queries and Also, we have a frapper map if you go to front row crew calm, which is our website front row crew calm.
Scott: In the bottom right there's a little frapper link and if you click on it It brings you to this Google map and on the Google map You can put a pin on the map to show where you are And that way we can see where all the listeners are and it's pretty cool when for anyone to look at.
Rym: But anyway, that's probably a good and not a good enough amount of that for now since somewhat soon As soon as we get new microphones and everything and we finish updating the website We're going to redo the closer and put all of that updated information in there.
Rym: So we never have to say this again when we get new listeners.
Scott: Hooray.
Rym: So without further ado, well, you've all been waiting for the news.
Scott: That's not what they're waiting for.
Scott: They're waiting for the mystery main bit.
Rym: No Because according to that thing we did trying to figure out what people like about the show.
Rym: the primary thing they like is the news And the things of the day.
Rym: Oh, okay.
Scott: Well here comes the news and the things today.
Rym: All right.
Rym: You want to go first?
Rym: What do you got?
Rym: my news that you wouldn't tell me what your goddamn news was?
Scott: It's the main Mutant.
Scott: Apparently, I'm gonna paraphrase this entire story because it would go over.
Scott: all the details take too long.
Scott: in parts of Maine There is a legend of some sort of monster that way.
Rym: Wait, wait a minute.
Rym: Is this that mutt dog with the deformed skull that someone ran over?
Rym: Yep That was on Fark a while ago.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Okay now I know exactly what you're talking about But go on anyway, because it's actually kind of interesting And of course everyone who is in the same camp as us was like crypto zoology, that's all bullshit.
Scott: There's no Bigfoot.
Scott: There's no main monster.
Scott: There's no Loch Ness monster.
Scott: It's just a bunch of crap.
Scott: and You know this thing had like been attributed to like chasing down a few dogs and like it killed a Doberman or something That's Doberman will fight.
Rym: That's quite a achievement.
Scott: Yeah, and whatever.
Rym: I mean, I couldn't kill a Doberman with my bare hands.
Scott: No, so there was this legend of like this main monster that was like this horrible mutant deformed dog that did all sorts of bad things and you know, it was just a legend.
Scott: and Recently like I don't know in the past few weeks Someone was driving their car and his cat ran across the road and this mutant dog was chasing it and they hit it with their car and A bunch of people want to look at it and there's a couple of pictures I think on Fox News There was some pictures.
Rym: Yeah, the pictures are a little misleading.
Rym: It probably doesn't look quite that freaky because those pictures were post being run over by a car and rotting for a little while.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty much a slightly strange looking dog.
Scott: That's rotting and I think there were some pictures on another site that showed that it had weird claws that went up.
Scott: It was it was kind of strange.
Rym: Yeah, well that a lot of people have said that that part of the picture might just be an illusion.
Scott: No, no, no, I'll show it to you.
Rym: I only saw one picture on Fark.
Rym: I saw it for about 30 seconds.
Scott: the claws going up the extra claws that aren't natural for Dogs to have is definitely not an illusion.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Scott: So it's probably just some sort of strange dog.
Scott: Whatever, you know some cryptozoologist went to look at it and he said that it was probably a chow We that it turned feral Whatever.
Rym: Yeah, there was actually a long discussion on Fark as to what breeds of dog were probably mixed in there.
Scott: Yeah, it was just.
Scott: it was had a slight genetic Whatnot and it was a crazy feral wild animal.
Rym: Well, I do remember when I was in Michigan in high school in sterling heights There was a bit of a brouhaha when a liger Got loose and was roaming around.
Rym: Yes a real liger.
Rym: Okay Like it was Bradford skills and magic.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: There we go.
Rym: Okay, and I Remember when I heard that on the news and the first thing I thought was there's no such thing as a liger What I thought?
Rym: and then I looked online and I found all this information on ligers and their magical powers.
Scott: Here's the thing about ligers.
Scott: I understand don't forget tigons.
Rym: They also exist.
Scott: Yeah, but if you're a lion, right?
Scott: Wouldn't you want to do the hot lion tempestresses and not the tiger tempestresses, I don't know.
Rym: I always thought tigers were generally better-looking than lions.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: I think there's only one way to find this out.
Scott: actually is we had to find some lion Furries and ask them if they're into the tiger furries and vice versa.
Rym: I think that's a good way to approach this.
Scott: Yep, so get right on that.
Rym: It's no smoldering cheetah temptress.
Scott: But yeah, that's what I was going for.
Scott: Yeah yeah, of course, how can.
Rym: there's no cheetah's or Titus because the cheetah gets away.
Rym: Oh I Guess tigers went out because they have the nice stripes.
Rym: Some of them lions are generally kind of bland looking at least the females.
Rym: They don't know those big man.
Scott: We see like a Google video of a tiger clawing some guy.
Rym: Yes, we did.
Rym: So there was some idiot hunters on an elephant and they're throwing sticks at this tiger and this tiger is not happy.
Rym: So it jumps up and kills them all.
Rym: awesome Okay All right, yeah, so my thing of the day is somewhat.
Rym: very you mean your news yeah.
Rym: Oh, yeah news is right my news.
Scott: I know my news seems somewhat thing of the day.
Rym: is it is thing of the day ish.
Rym: Okay I got off track a little here.
Rym: Mm-hmm Yeah, my news is actually somewhat depressing and sad though It's really par for the course for this company.
Rym: now for those of you who aren't familiar with Macro vision it is one of the earliest forms of well, I'd say DRM, but it's really ARM because it's analog.
Rym: I'm not going to explain how DRM or how DRM works.
Rym: I'm not doing to explain how macro vision works, but suffice to say macro vision is a method of Protecting things like VHS tapes where if you try to copy them Devices like VCRs all have a thing that will react to the macro vision that is in the signal and totally ruin the copy you're trying to make.
Scott: if you plug two VCRs into each other and try to copy a tape from one to The other macro vision will stop you.
Rym: Yes You also run into this problem as a side effect if you try to plug a DVD player Into a VCR.
Rym: because most people when DVD players came out didn't have RCA or component inputs into their TVs But they had VCRs which did so.
Rym: what they did is most people tried to use their VCR as a RF modulator Which would have worked perfectly?
Rym: Except for the fact that macro vision for a completely arbitrary reason blocks that and makes your DVD fade in and out and in and out because they don't want you to take your DVD and Record it onto a VHS tape.
Rym: so because there was such a trade in VHS rips of DVDs I know that there was gonna be.
Rym: I mean VHS is so high quality.
Scott: so the news about macro vision the evil fuckers is well the to put it very briefly a Company.
Rym: well there have been a lot of companies But there's one company in particular have made machines and methods of taking old VHS tapes and digitizing them in order to Archive the footage and record whatever video was in this old failing analog format.
Scott: There are many people who are in that business and all you really need is a computer with an in you know a card like an Aver or an ATI whatever Macro vision like the planet of the moles in Futurama was firing lawsuits everywhere about this.
Rym: They do not want anyone to be able to crack macro vision or in any way Circumvent it in order to get data off of old analog tapes.
Scott: But what if I have my home movies on old analog tapes, and I want to put them on my computer?
Rym: Well the thing is your home movies probably don't have macro vision in them.
Scott: That is true.
Rym: However, however in general the best part about this is that they were trying to sue everyone under the DMCA the D MCA D D digital.
Rym: it is not a digital rights management is an analog rights management.
Rym: The law does not apply in any way because there is no digital mechanism whatsoever protecting the data.
Rym: good God, I almost ran out of breath there.
Scott: Wow that is true.
Rym: the thing is it's not just the issue that macro vision is being kind of evil and trying to Manhandle the laws into protecting their crappy DRM.
Rym: Well ARM that doesn't even really work so well.
Rym: I mean, it's trivially circum circumvented, but more so than that Macro vision has in general for as long as it has existed been one of the most evil entities out there in the world.
Scott: This is basically a company that has made a product and then they make a law that says Anyone who is in this business must purchase our product and become our customer.
Scott: I mean and they make another law that says we can never go out of business.
Scott: We must always get money.
Scott: Well, I mean what the hell?
Scott: I mean if what a McDonald's said everyone must eat at McDonald's it when they want a hamburger and if McDonald's doesn't make enough money then you know people have to pay McDonald's to keep it in business.
Scott: You don't make laws like that.
Scott: That's so far from what capitalism is.
Scott: It's insane.
Scott: I mean that's that's even worse than communism.
Rym: now luckily some good news here is that while they originally won their case pretty much the Injunction that was put in place is now being reviewed and on the whole number of organizations Including among other people the wonderful EFF
Scott: Of course
Rym: are right there and I have a feeling that the judges aren't going to be stupid and macro vision is going to die In a fire,
Scott: you know if I was like the FCC or whoever can do whatever about this I would just make say macro vision.
Scott: everyone in charge of macro vision goes to jail and the company's gone.
Scott: Goodbye.
Rym: No, I wouldn't put him in jail, yeah, I would.
Rym: now I just make their company go away.
Scott: No, I put him in jail.
Rym: Why would you?
Rym: but we have enough for we rail against the prison industrial complex constantly.
Rym: We hate jails.
Scott: That's the point is like, you know, cuz that most of the people put in jail Don't need to go to jail.
Scott: But the thing is if you take the heads of macro vision or probably these rich assholes You know who are just evil and you put him in jail You don't need to put them in there for like a month and it had to be a real jail.
Scott: None of this like, you know jail with no fences Country Club crap, you know, you know that there aren't so many of those.
Rym: It's not really that way.
Scott: the media really governor of Connecticut went to one.
Rym: I saw it yeah, but the media always makes it out like those minimum security.
Rym: prisons aren't so bad and There really are kind of bad because you're still trapped in there with a lot of really terrible people.
Scott: You're not being raped in the ass.
Scott: You have to send into a prison where you get raped in the ass.
Rym: I'm generally against this whole people being raped in the ass in prison business.
Scott: I'm for it as long as I'm not in prison.
Rym: Well, here's the thing the prison industry proves a whole bunch of stuff.
Scott: I mean look we can't keep God's not do an episode about prison.
Scott: All right, the point is is the macro vision.
Scott: people are bad and I want them to be harmed.
Rym: Well, how about they just die in a fire?
Scott: that works, but can they be raped in the ass before they die in a fire?
Rym: I mean, I've run afoul of macro vision so many times and the thing is the vast majority of those times I was not even trying to break the law.
Scott: most of the time We were just trying to watch a DVD on an old television Through a VCR and they would fade dark and light and dark and light and it was just annoying things of the day of Today.
Rym: Oh, wow.
Rym: You didn't say thingy.
Scott: I know I tried to change it up.
Rym: Wow good for you.
Rym: Yep, all right my thing of the day.
Rym: I had something else and it was some old thing that was actually kind of cool But I had to change it up because Scott showed me something and then I remembered that today is Pretty much the beginning of all the premieres for probably our favorite movie of the year snakes on a motherfucking plane
Scott: motherfucker.
Scott: Now, oh my god.
Rym: This is actually quite hilarious.
Rym: It is Samuel L. Jackson Appearing on The Daily Show talking about soap.
Scott: Yeah, that's actually worth, you know, it's like.
Scott: I'm not gonna pay to see this movie You know just because of what they've done.
Scott: I'm not gonna support it with money.
Rym: See, here's the thing.
Scott: However, I enjoy the craziness that's going around.
Rym: I support it for one reason and one reason alone Because originally I mean one.
Rym: I've told the story of snakes on a plane before because for anyone who isn't hit to the internet This snakes on a plane thing may seem like it's new like it's been exploding for the past few months.
Rym: I don't think you all realize just how long this is.
Rym: movie has been known about and made fun of on Fark Years, I mean to the point that the the line snakes on a motherfucking plane and got them.
Rym: The origin of that was not in the movie originally.
Rym: it can very likely be traced to some of the early photoshops when people heard about the title of this movie and Then they heard that Samuel L. Jackson was gonna be in it and they started making fun of it.
Rym: But the fact that Samuel L. Jackson and the people who were doing this movie Recognized that the internet had found their movie and liked it and took it was hard not to recognize.
Scott: Yes, it was literally be not on the internet to know about snakes on a.
Rym: well No, I mean when because the thing is a lot of this came after the fact They had to have been reading Fark or new people who read Fark or possibly like 4chan.
Scott: I imagine they were doing it just going on casually and then Someone noticed and one guy came along and he's like, hey guys check this shit out.
Scott: Yeah, probably some intern was like, alright guys I was on Fark and they probably went oh shit Wait a minute and then dollar sign showed up in the eyeballs.
Rym: But the fact that they took all the advice of the internet and they basically made the movie the internet wanted.
Rym: We're going to find out if the movies that the internet wants are movies that the internet actually wants, you know, what's coming soon?
Scott: Go see.
Rym: the movie Go see is not a movie.
Rym: go see is if anything the flag of the Internet.
Rym: I agree Well that we have much to say about goat.
Rym: see me do indeed.
Rym: But first anyway, if you have any chance at all, I highly recommend you watch this video of Samuel L. Jackson.
Scott: It's probably just as good as watching snakes on a plane the movie.
Rym: Well, the thing is Sam is really a funny guy and I always enjoy watching interviews with him.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: He's cool All right, my thing of the day now.
Rym: you didn't you refuse to tell me what your thing of the day was.
Scott: Oh, it's awesome.
Scott: It's called Just one Club card.
Scott: What this is is you have Club cards, right?
Scott: I got the shop right one.
Rym: Wait a minute.
Rym: Is this the guy who copied his barcode put it on the internet and told everyone to use it?
Rym: No, okay.
Scott: And you got the stop and shop one, right?
Scott: Yeah, and I think you know a bunch of places have.
Rym: I have the discount liquor one.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well that I have a.
Scott: There's a Dominic's is a possibility.
Rym: No, you know why I have a Dominic's?
Rym: because when I went to anime central the first time which was God that was like 2002 We threw that party and we drove around Chicago looking for a grocery store to buy mixers for the non-alcoholic bar.
Rym: we were gonna run in the room because the room had a full bar in it and We found a Dominic's and Scott Johnson got a Dominic's card and then he gave it to me So he wouldn't lose it.
Rym: and then the next year when we went back to Chicago We went to the same Dominic's and used it again.
Scott: Yeah well if you're like me and You have a Jimmy wallet or you have some wallet that can't hold a lot of cards or you hate having all that shit hanging On your keychain, you know one for every possible place.
Scott: There's a website where you can choose up to eight different cards from eight different places Or eight of the same place if you like that and you type in the number under your barcode For each of those places and it will allow you to print out one card with eight barcodes on it.
Scott: And it supports a lot of places.
Scott: I mean A&P Albertsons.
Rym: by low At least one-dimensional barcodes are not terribly difficult to reverse engineer.
Scott: Yeah, stop and shop staples PetSmart Petco.
Rym: The next step of this is to make a small website where people can publish much like bug me not numbers from their cards Mm-hmm.
Rym: That way we can totally randomize everything and completely ruin this entire tiny industry.
Rym: I agree.
Scott: But yeah, this is just awesome because now if you have if your wallet is full of these club cards You know one for every store and you just have them to like get know what you know what forget the website.
Rym: We're gonna do that in the forums.
Rym: I'm going to post all my discount card numbers and Scott will do the same and we urge all of you to do this as Well,
Scott: yeah, and that way if anyone needs a discount card instead of signing up for it you just go to this just one Club card website type in someone else's Club card number and Print out a working barcode card.
Rym: Yeah, and it's not like.
Scott: and you have one card, you know You can decrease the number of cards you have in your wallet by a factor of eight and it's not like.
Rym: this can be used To hurt anyone because there's no way you can you.
Rym: I mean, it's just information about what you buy.
Rym: Yeah, like these aren't.
Scott: these aren't credit cards.
Scott: These are discount cards.
Scott: I mean, we're not even talking about reward cards here, you know, I mean, well, I think some of them might be reward cards Whatever.
Scott: Yeah, these are mostly discount cards like if you have the card you get a discount.
Scott: if you don't you don't and It's you know, generally sort of a not.
Scott: I mean you can sign up for one of these things with fake information and they'll give it to you.
Rym: Yeah, in fact the Wegmans car or no the stop-and-shop car that I used for a number of years and I still have is One that I found on the ground outside of a stop-and-shop.
Rym: once yep The shop right one Scott got semi legitimately the Wegmans one.
Rym: I used a fake ID.
Scott: Yeah, the other the other advantage of this is you know Like I have a shop right card Rym has a stop-and-shop one.
Scott: now We both have both because we're both gonna print it out Great and if someone looks at you funny for taking a little piece of paper and waving it over the barcode thing You just give them the finger.
Scott: if it beeps it beeps fuck.
Scott: Yep So this is way cool way.
Rym: So, you know what.
Rym: all of you go to the forums and post your information and we're going to make something awesome.
Rym: Yep, cool.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I don't think we can contain it anymore.
Rym: It is time.
Scott: Let's get on with it.
Rym: I think before we describe exactly what we did in the events that went down in Wildwood, New Jersey Talk about our new motto.
Rym: All right I will tell the story of the motto and then Scott can describe what kind of place Wildwood New Jersey is because that is critical for the story that is about to be told extremely critical.
Rym: now.
Rym: We are good friend Yuko who she does a webcomic.
Rym: She's a wonderful artist and she hung out with us along with all of our other friends during what we call the week of awesome.
Rym: Every year the front row crew gets together and for an entire one the hobo one.
Rym: Yes For an entire week after Otakon we all congregate somewhere often Wildwood and Generally do things together and make an awesome week of it.
Rym: It's like our annual homecoming.
Rym: Now Yuko stayed at RIT along with our good friend Conrad and a bunch of other people at home bad home bad and we'd all graduated and they were all.
Rym: they were on the eboard of the RIT anime club and One day they were in one of the meetings and Yuko apparently drew on a little piece of paper a little note with a doodle on it and the words on this note were Hey Conrad, let's do dumb shit after this.
Rym: Now this was hilarious.
Rym: The note was hilarious and the the words let's do dumb shit after this which has been shortened somewhat to Let's do dumb shit has recently caught on as the new logo and catchphrase of the front row crew.
Scott: It's a motto not a logo motto, yeah, let's do dumb shit.
Scott: everybody You know, it's like we used to freak some squares.
Scott: That was the thing we used to do before is freak the squares now.
Scott: Let's just do dumb shit.
Rym: Yeah, basically we use this term to refer to the things we do that typically become funny stories later.
Scott: Yeah things that would have been previously referred to as freaking squares or possibly having a vision.
Scott: Oh my vision.
Scott: I have this vision.
Rym: I have a vision of us doing dumb shit.
Scott: Who might freak squares and we'll do dumb shit.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Yeah, we should.
Rym: we'll tell the.
Rym: I have a vision story someday.
Scott: That's an okay story.
Rym: Did we ever tell the bamboo story that goes along with it?
Rym: No, good God That's a different episode.
Rym: someone remind us to talk about the bamboo.
Scott: the bamboo and The vision will be an episode together.
Scott: put that in the forum thingy.
Rym: I have a vision of bamboo Bamboo visions.
Rym: Oh god.
Rym: That was one of the worst days of my life.
Scott: So Wildwood, New Jersey Wildwood, New Jersey is basically a beach a public beach.
Scott: that means anyone who wants to for no money can go and sit on the sand in the sun and go in the Atlantic Ocean and get wet and play with crabs and get crabbed.
Scott: and Yeah, jellyfish jellyfished and dig in the sand and all that good stuff by a fudgy wudgy.
Scott: Yep, there's a guy walking with ice cream, but you need to pay him.
Scott: That's not free.
Scott: it's also incredibly touristy as Public beaches are want to be now attached to.
Rym: the beach is one of the biggest old-school boardwalks around.
Scott: Yes, it is a long boardwalk with many piers that aren't don't really jut out into the water.
Scott: They jut out into the sand.
Scott: now The boardwalk is sort of far back from the actual water for anyone.
Rym: I mean boardwalks are really a thing that only exists on ocean coasts in New Jersey.
Scott: Yeah No, there's there's.
Rym: there are a bunch of boardwalks out west.
Scott: there are but they're big in New Jersey.
Rym: Yeah There is.
Rym: he is like the boardwalk state and they're really not that common in the world as a whole.
Rym: No, and they're kind of going out of style.
Rym: But basically you have a beach and then someone builds piers, you know for ships and they go out.
Rym: But instead of having ships go on those piers They put buildings on those piers and then the boardwalk which is literally a boardwalk it's a whole bunch of boards held up like a deck and Then they put shops and arcades and things all along it or casinos or whatever.
Scott: Yep So the boardwalk in Wildly, New Jersey is the schlockiest place on earth.
Scott: if you're looking for touristy dreck carny games arcades Any of that sort of shit, you know greasy food and funnel cake one dollar pizza one dollar pizza slices.
Scott: This is the place to go.
Scott: I mean if you want a cheap t-shirt if you want like a one dollar bathing suit
Rym: If I want a snow globe with a picture of a duck in it
Scott: Yeah, if you want like a bootleg, you know dollar store f1 car that where all the names on it are changed.
Scott: This is the place.
Rym: Yeah, I mean it's.
Rym: I don't want to say it's low-class, but it's pretty low-class in general.
Scott: I'm quite low brow.
Rym: Granted we love Wildwood.
Rym: Oh, it's so great in addition to having all this stuff Which is just a hilarious to see.
Rym: it has probably one of the last bastions of true arcade culture in this entire country.
Rym: Indeed Wildwood has some of the best arcades I've been to in a decade.
Scott: three DDR supernovas right next to DDR.
Scott: seventh makes a in the groove two and two air hockey machine to regulation air hockey machine.
Rym: Yeah photons bitches Yeah, so Wildwood is our arcade capital where we go every year to play arcade games.
Scott: now You might imagine that much of the boardwalk is not arcades and therefore what do we care?
Scott: You know, in fact to most geeks, it would be painful.
Scott: You see carny games.
Scott: You see food that while tasty and most geeks will eat it.
Scott: You can't eat too much of it or you'll die.
Scott: Yeah, and you see like schlocky t-shirt places selling t-shirts.
Scott: that's a really really dumb shit on them.
Rym: Yeah, like God, what was that one?
Rym: There was this one shirt.
Rym: It was big and black and it said like Master of the game in like four different fonts and it had this big bulldog and the bulldog was biting through a football.
Scott: Yeah, I mean that kind of crap like really cheap crap t-shirts and stuff.
Scott: So, you know that stuff is generally not interesting and even off-putting to most geeks Except the first time you go to a place like that.
Rym: Oh, yeah the first time you're just overwhelmed.
Rym: It's like this crazy carnival of color and lights and you can barely keep your senses.
Scott: But if you go there You know for many many years year after year for and you stay there for many many days like an entire week.
Scott: I mean people barely spend a day there usually a weekend if they're lucky we spend a week there.
Rym: I once lived there for about a month.
Scott: Yeah, so Eventually you see through that and it just becomes like, you know, it's it's a boardwalk whatever.
Rym: Yeah, so we other than playing DDR we had grown somewhat tired with the boardwalk.
Scott: There are go-karts there, which are also cool.
Rym: I mean every year we'd walk the length of it to show the new people we brought.
Rym: but other than that.
Scott: Yeah, so This year we finally figured out how to breathe new life into this carny sort of drech schlock.
Scott: You know crappy boardwalk.
Rym: The answer is hacking.
Scott: Yes now not computer hacking But hacking the boardwalk, I mean hacking is a really generic term.
Rym: I mean social engineering is really just people hacking.
Rym: Yep At RIT.
Rym: We always tried to do elevator hacking And we always failed.
Rym: Yeah Now and Wildwood there are a number of ways that we've learned and we had so many ideas We only had the chance to undertake two of them.
Scott: Yep well now the idea of hacking in general is to take something and to sort of repurpose or enhance it.
Scott: like if you Find a way to use your cell phone to also open the door to your house and remote control your television That's hacking, you know.
Scott: so we're take we're going to or we did attempt and succeed to take the schlocky drek shit on the boardwalk and Repurpose it into awesome.
Rym: So the question now is which of the two stories do we tell first the best t-shirt in the world or the best food?
Scott: In the world, I think the best t-shirt in the world has to come first because it came first chronologically All right.
Rym: So at one point we were walking past as a whole.
Rym: the whole front row crew for the most part was walking past this one Shop and we see a sign wait, but there are many many stores on the boardwalk.
Scott: They sell cheap t-shirts and this was one of them.
Rym: now.
Rym: This one stood out to us in a way that none had ever had before and it was definitely a recent development.
Scott: Yes There was an eight and a half by eleven piece of paper poorly clipped on to one of their t-shirt displays and on it in plain black text was printed the words any band you want and Next to it was another one that said any wrestler you want and I said, all right.
Scott: All right They probably have every wrestler But there has to be some obscure ass band that they don't have a t-shirt for.
Rym: and the t-shirts were fairly high quality.
Rym: They were definitely a couple steps up from just an iron-on.
Scott: Yep, and I said Alright either you know immediately after about a minute of thinking about it.
Scott: I'm like, okay either they're false advertising and we're gonna pun them or They have some sort of.
Scott: they can print t-shirts from computer images device.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So we basically realized that they were either going to be completely stupid and false advertising or they were doing something illegal and we decided That either way this was going to be hilarious.
Scott: So we go into the store and I asked my friend Pete.
Scott: I said hey Think of the most obscure band you can think of and he calls his brother who knows even more obscure bands.
Scott: and they come up with the band nihilist spasm band.
Scott: and I'm like, okay, let's go in.
Scott: and Pete asked them.
Scott: Can we have a t-shirt for nihilist spasm band?
Scott: and They get to work on their computer and I'm like, okay, are they using Google Images?
Scott: What are they doing?
Scott: And Eventually this girl turns around with a pretty poor image of the nihilist spasm band logo and we go Oh, it's Google Images.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So we told the people, you know, what are you doing is illegal?
Rym: Not that we care, but you're totally breaking the law.
Rym: and we walked out laughing.
Scott: Yeah, we're just like, yeah We just wanted to see how you did it, you know, etc, etc.
Scott: And we walked out laughing and they were kind of whatever.
Scott: and that was that.
Rym: now later on that evening We were playing DDR and playing games in the house and an idea started to foment.
Rym: And I fermentation produces poison.
Rym: because we started thinking wait a minute so they can make a t-shirt of anything Huh?
Rym: by the same token We can tell them a word and they will look up a picture of that word and there is no way they will avoid seeing that picture.
Rym: Go see go see go see go to go to go to go to go to go to go to you We're just.
Scott: we figured we would walk into the store say can we have a goat's t-shirt?
Scott: Yeah, and they would see goatse and go.
Scott: Oh, oh god.
Scott: Oh god, and we'd laugh and walk out.
Rym: And then our friend Pete goes one step further and says why don't we actually get a goatse t-shirt?
Scott: Oh my god brilliant genius.
Rym: now we're sitting there and we're just awed by this idea because nothing would please me more in the world than to wear on my Chest proudly a picture of a man stretching his own anus apart.
Scott: I mean we've taken what was five minutes ago a Drexlock store that in no geek would care about and only stupid, you know American consumer tourists on vacation would even consider spending money at and turned it into an Amazing like pool of potential.
Scott: awesome.
Scott: now go see awesome.
Rym: The final step came when and I'm not going to be modest about this I had a stroke of genius and I said the words We should put the First Amendment in text on this shirt.
Scott: And we said, holy shit, that is absolutely right.
Rym: so the t-shirt we envision now is goatse and then the First Amendment in text around it in Big black letters and we're like, ah, that would be the best t-shirt ever.
Scott: Like oh my god amazing.
Rym: and Pete says I'll do it.
Scott: We'll do it we.
Scott: so we went to the t-shirt place that night and we said, all right.
Scott: and As soon as he walked in the girl recognized us and she's like, oh no, no, no You guys are here before you're not gonna do the same trick again, and we're like, no, no, we're serious You want a shirt really and she's like really really.
Scott: so we go in and we're like Okay, guys goatse and I had to.
Scott: at first we had to instruct them how to turn off their filter on On Google Images.
Rym: now The other thing is the fact that they didn't immediately recognize the word goatse means that they are not Technology savvy people.
Scott: No, they were not.
Scott: we had To find the image.
Scott: I had to guide them to Wikipedia and then from there guide them to the Mirror of goatse.
Rym: I mean regardless of your feelings for the actual image, which is pretty horrific I'm not going to say it isn't.
Rym: that is an iconic thing at this point.
Rym: goatse is like this legendary piece of the internet and whether you like it or not.
Rym: That is a part of our human history.
Scott: Yes, it is.
Scott: I mean if you've never seen it before it's quite horrific But once you've seen it a thousand times, it's just nothing.
Scott: It's just up.
Scott: It look it's goats.
Rym: I mean in the mid 90s, there was nothing more fun than tricking people into seeing that image.
Scott: But nowadays it's like oh you haven't seen goatse if you've been living under a rock.
Scott: That's like saying you've never seen the American flag.
Scott: What's wrong with you?
Rym: Remember that thing of the day we did where that one guy showed people who had never seen it and then took pictures of their faces.
Scott: the moment there is a Group or something of pictures of people seeing goatse for the first time the best was Ron Jeremy because his face is like What the fuck is that?
Scott: And he's Ron Jeremy.
Rym: and then his second face.
Rym: He's looking at it more closely and has this look of just utter disgust.
Scott: Yeah all right, so We go in and we try to wheel and deal this guy to make the goatse shirt.
Scott: And he seemed you know after all the employees in the store or you know having a fun time and we're having a fun time You know, they didn't really seem apprehensive about making it like that.
Scott: You're like, yeah, we'll make it for you.
Scott: And then we're like, alright, we want you to write the First Amendment on it and they're like, yeah, we can do that.
Scott: We're like, oh shit.
Scott: It's this awesome.
Scott: And Eventually, you know, they had a printer there which printed out some sort of t-shirt Screening stuff and they had some sort of machine and they got a t-shirt and plain white shirt and they went.
Scott: And there you know it there's the shirt Really?
Scott: Well done very well done.
Scott: I mean it was a picture of goatse with the words the First Amendment on it.
Scott: Perfect It looked like a t-shirt you bought in the store.
Scott: It was so great.
Scott: And then our friend had to deal with them on the price of the shirt.
Rym: now Pete pointed out later he wished he'd realized this earlier that he was in a very high position in terms of the Debate over the price because quite simply no one else in the world would have bought that shirt and it was already made.
Rym: So basically he could have said five bucks or I'm not taking it and then walked away and they would have been stuck with This shirt, they probably just throwing it out.
Scott: that shirt probably cost them less than five bucks.
Scott: Maybe they don't care, you know, but anyway now, but I think he eventually paid like 30 for it.
Rym: Yeah, I think it was worth it.
Scott: Yeah, it was definitely worth it.
Scott: And you know, it's sort of like, you know, we put the guy through a bunch of trouble.
Scott: We made him look at goat.
Scott: see what about.
Scott: it's okay if we get ripped off on it.
Rym: I think my favorite part is when you said something to him like Yeah, it's not as bad as like lemon party or all that other stuff.
Scott: and then he wanted to look it up.
Scott: He wanted to look up lemon party and tub girl because I mentioned I Think we tainted them.
Scott: We did indeed taint them.
Rym: You know what have been the best if after this was all done we'd call the police because they were breaking the law.
Scott: Otherwise, that would have been hilarious should have been like give us this t-shirt for free.
Scott: We're calling the cops on your bootlegging operation.
Rym: You know what.
Rym: if they're next there next year I think we'll have some words with them.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So anyway, the moral of the story here is that if you go to the link to the discussion from this post About this show right now in the forum are all the pictures of this shirt.
Scott: It's two pictures of the shirt.
Rym: Yeah, all of them.
Scott: Yeah Well, actually no, I think we can only do one link from the post to the forum and There's gonna be two forum things one for this story and one for the other story, huh?
Rym: Yeah, are we gonna do that?
Rym: I'll link to him.
Scott: some just link to him in the post instead of with the forum.
Rym: There will be an obvious link.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Anyway now this emboldened us.
Scott: Yes, we realized wow, there is potential here and these things on the boardwalk to create amusement for us, you know Cuz these things are designed to amuse idiots who just like to buy crap.
Scott: So we need a lot more.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: We need different things to bring us amusement and Places and things that previously brought us no joy and in fact often pain Where now could be repurposed to bring us hours upon hours of entertainment and joy.
Scott: So we just had to find more ways to utilize Things on this boardwalk to make them entertaining to create good to make lemonade from lemons.
Rym: If life gives you shit, what do you make?
Scott: Shit pie.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway now I noticed just now as I'm thinking about it that we use Pete more than anything to accomplish all of This.
Rym: yes, because Pete is pivotal in the second thing we did.
Rym: Mmm now last year Pete had ordered a caramel Funnel cake which defeated him.
Scott: Yeah, I mean you used to be you just got a funnel cake.
Scott: nowadays You can get deep-fried Oreos, which is Oreo in funnel cake.
Scott: It's really good You can get.
Scott: you know.
Scott: funnel cakes with powdered sugar on them funnel cakes with Caramel.
Rym: now, there's one cinnamon apple funnel cakes that has pretty much anything in the world.
Rym: deep-fried I mean they have every candy bar Apples, they'll just deep-fry anything they've got.
Rym: Yeah, they'll do anything you want.
Scott: They'll put it in funnel cake batter deep-fry it and serve it up to you.
Rym: So Pete has always been thinking because he'd always order like the craziest thing like the cheese fry pizza or the caramel.
Scott: He has a history of eating weird things.
Scott: I remember there was a place called pita pit where you could get in our God we get any pita you wanted and You know I. he said that there was impossible to make a bad pita from the pita pit menu and I challenged him to this and I Concocted from the pita pit menu perhaps the worst combination of pita you could get.
Scott: I mean It's pretty much like every kind of nasty sauce and all the seafood combination and it was crazy and he ate it.
Scott: so Of course, this is his department to do the crazy things with deep-frying.
Rym: So he walks over to this place where they deep-fry a whole bunch of stuff and he asks if I bring something to you Will you deep-fry it?
Scott: and they said yes, they.
Rym: and he said are you serious?
Rym: He said if you pay we will deep-fry it Mm-hmm.
Scott: He then was sure there are many health code violations with you bringing food to a restaurant for them to cook.
Rym: Well considering that I don't think anyone in Wildwood wears gloves.
Scott: most of them are Europeans making barely minimum wage and Of course, I'm not too worried because it is deep-frying.
Scott: anything that goes in there is dead.
Rym: So then he goes immediately Immediately to the next-door pizzeria Buys a slice of cheese pizza and says to the man pepperoni pizza was it.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Oh god.
Rym: I wasn't paying attention.
Rym: No, you weren't.
Rym: and then he says to the guy I am going to go have this deep-fried And we took pictures of like him shaking hands with the pizza guy.
Rym: Yes, you definitely want to look at the forum post about this because we have an entire photo archive courtesy of James Yep, and you just look at all the pictures in sequence and it kind of tells the story for you, you know.
Rym: So then he takes it back over to the deep-fried place and there's a little bit of debate and the people are like Are you sure?
Rym: and he's like yes bring it on.
Scott: and he was like, you know We had to confirm that yes, they would do this and how much would it cost?
Scott: You know.
Scott: and they I think they said four dollars.
Scott: in the end was yeah, that was worth it.
Scott: Yeah four dollars That's like free.
Rym: So then they cut it up and they deep-fry it in powdered sugar and Funnel cake batter.
Scott: they had to cut the pizza up because it wouldn't all they couldn't get batter on the whole thing at once Because it's a pretty big slice, you know, that's what you get on the shore.
Scott: But yeah, they cut up and we had like three or four pieces of deep-fried Pizza slice of pizza covered in what is essentially funnel cake and Powder sugar.
Rym: now they are laughing hysterically the entire time.
Scott: Everyone is laughing hysterically.
Scott: The employees are laughing hysterically.
Scott: It's a good time was had by all.
Rym: so Pete takes it back over to the guy who sold him the pizza to show that He wasn't bullshitting.
Rym: He was not a shit talker.
Rym: Here.
Rym: It was the deep-fried pizza.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: He shook the guy's hand.
Rym: The guy was like you're gonna die.
Scott: Yeah And then we went back to the deep-fried place to sit down and eat it.
Rym: now what follows can be described But is best seen in the pictures.
Rym: Yes, because each one of us starting with Pete would take a piece Eat it.
Rym: and then there is the reaction shot to the flavor of this item that we have made.
Scott: The only thing I can tell you is something that everyone else seemed to agree on.
Scott: it tastes like a sugary hot pocket.
Rym: Surprisingly, yes, it tasted exactly like one of those hot pockets that you could buy for like middle school lunch and only sugary.
Rym: Well because we put powdered sugar on it.
Scott: Well, also the funnel cake is the sugary batter.
Scott: if it was a non it was a different batter.
Scott: It would have been a hot pocket now in retrospect.
Rym: It was not the best piece of pizza to begin with.
Rym: no, it really wasn't and we probably could have done better, but The pictures of Pete eating it are some of the funniest things I've seen in a long time.
Scott: Pictures of everyone eating it are hilarious.
Rym: I mean for Pete there's a picture of him holding the slice up.
Rym: I like about to take a bite out of it.
Rym: Then there's a picture of him looking down like laughing but not able to quite deal with what is in his mouth.
Rym: Then there's a picture of him looking far more defeated as he tastes the full flavor of this item.
Rym: I Look like I'm about to vomit.
Scott: I have this look of like what if you Ever go somewhere that has a deep fryer and funnel cake batter and they're looking like this cool employees there Try to get them to deep-fry weird shit.
Scott: Yeah, it's worth it.
Rym: They probably will do it.
Scott: It's a lot of fun and you know, their jobs are boring and kind of unexciting and if you you know It'll be exciting for you and exciting for them and it just makes the world a better place.
Rym: now the funniest and scariest Part of this whole thing is that we as a group ate the entire goddamn thing.
Scott: There were a lot of us.
Scott: I think that we had a small bit left over that we gave to the employees while we as a group ate most of it.
Rym: Pete ate More than he should have.
Scott: he did.
Rym: indeed He ate an entire piece all the way through and he had parts of all the other pieces.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, I had like two bites now for the rest of the night.
Rym: about an hour later Pete turns to me says something like My stomach has decided that what we just did was not the best idea and like know what you did was not the best idea.
Scott: I didn't eat enough of it to make it bad.
Rym: I ate two bites of it and my stomach was a little grumbly.
Rym: My stomach said what the fuck did you just put in me?
Rym: Good God god damn got damn motherfucking damn Fried funnel cake on a pizza.
Rym: It's not a goddamn thing.
Rym: You can do about it.
Scott: Okay kind of pizza.
Rym: Hope I Can't describe this any better.
Rym: You really need to go see these pictures.
Rym: They're Hilarious absolutely fantastic.
Rym: Now the moral of the story.
Rym: because we're drawing this Thursday episode to a close the last episode of room will not have a pop Filter.
Rym: you won't have to put up with my popping peas all over the podcast anymore.
Rym: penis You know, I really honestly did not expect you Scott Rubin to say the word penis.
Rym: really I mean of all the times you've said that word This was not the moment, you know the moment when we're saying words that begin with the letter P That you would in fact say the word penis.
Rym: really nah, nah, really?
Rym: Yeah, really?
Rym: But the moral of this story is that any time you were bored Anytime.
Rym: you're in a place either with people you find uninteresting or a place that you don't think can entertain you.
Rym: I Know there is no place on this earth where you cannot entertain yourself in some way by either hacking or pleasuring yourself.
Scott: Yeah, seriously if I was in solitary in a prison I could just I'll just whack it For days.
Scott: who's gonna stop me?
Rym: Yeah, you know, there's a story about that.
Rym: We're not gonna tell because it could get both of us in trouble.
Rym: Oh, right, right Suffice to say.
Rym: Hacking does not apply to computers and computers alone.
Rym: hacking applies to the world.
Rym: You can be a hacker if you do anything.
Rym: Awesome.
Scott: Well anything awesome that is hacking.
Rym: Well, yes.
Scott: Yeah, I mean you can do awesome things that are not hacking such as heroic deeds.
Scott: and Now if you hack in order to do heroic deed plus plus oh man Heroic hacking is the best is the most awesome thing you can possibly do.
Scott: I don't think you can possibly be more awesome than hacking heroically.
Scott: All right, that's about it.
Rym: Yeah, I don't think we have anything else.
Rym: once again to all of our new listeners out there I will have a pop filter next week.
Rym: Welcome to GeekNights.
Rym: Join the forums.
Rym: join the frapper.
Rym: Go to the website.
Rym: You'll find links to everything we talk about.
Scott: and god damn do not eat fucking deep-fried pizza Oh my god, and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.