Scott: It's Wednesday June 21st, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We talk about the recent anime convention Anime next and I gotta say we were gonna have a much more exciting episode tonight.
Scott: Oh were we ever?
Rym: now?
Rym: Jim Vowles is the con chair of Otakon Arguably the biggest anime convention in the world outside of Japan If not, if not the biggest in terms of area definitely in my opinion the best.
Scott: and from talking to him He's definitely an awesome awesome, dude.
Rym: Yeah, he even I mean he took his time to come and talk to us about Otakon and himself And we were gonna have this great interview for you tonight.
Rym: now for those of you who listen to our Monday episode I Complained quite a bit about garage band and my new Mac and how it doesn't quite work at all for podcasting Yep, even though we're still using it right now.
Rym: Yeah, mostly because I decommissioned my old Linux box, but that's beside the point Now decommission too soon.
Rym: So we're all set.
Rym: he's online.
Rym: we're talking to him.
Rym: You know idle chat getting ready to the interview and I had tested because the way we were going to do this interview was over.
Rym: I chat because as far as Apple says it just works.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Wait, I think this is the time for me to read Apple's website.
Rym: All right.
Rym: This is what Apple says as to how to make this happen.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So even if today's guests are in Paris while you're in Peoria, you can still put on a podcast together.
Scott: Just start an audio chat using I chat and hit record.
Scott: Garage band simultaneously records the audio from your chat and assigns different tracks to each participant identified by buddy name and icon so you can edit everything seamlessly.
Scott: and if using eyesight cameras to conduct a video chat Garage band even captures the real-time still image every time each guest speaks.
Scott: see Instant podcast talk show and you didn't even have to dodge a flying chair.
Scott: That is the text from Apple's website on how to do an eye chat plus garage band Podcast internet audio interview.
Rym: now, there's no more details.
Rym: or here's exactly how to do it.
Rym: Or here is here's what to do.
Scott: or click this then click that.
Scott: then click this.
Scott: then click that that.
Scott: Instructions do not exist now.
Rym: All right, it says run.
Rym: I chat Run garage band start start an audio.
Scott: I chat.
Scott: we already did that.
Scott: Yep hit record.
Scott: We did that All right.
Rym: Now the thing is it doesn't even say in what program to hit record.
Rym: I assumed correctly that in garage band.
Rym: I had to do this, but it does not actually say.
Scott: it doesn't actually say But it does have a little picture here of the record button from garage.
Rym: Yes I figured it out when I saw that there was in fact, no record button in.
Rym: I chat.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So I hit record in garage band.
Rym: now well first off I did this yesterday evening as I said with James and Lisa to test it to make sure it works because Jim Vowles is a guy we really wanted to talk to for a while and we wanted everything to go smoothly for him because he's Taking time out of his busy schedule to talk to us and being
Scott: smart technology professionals We always test something in a development sandbox before we do the real deal.
Scott: We make sure it works in advance and then when it comes time to go for real We do it the same same exact thing we did before.
Scott: that worked.
Rym: So James and Lisa were gracious enough to start up a little chat and James even turned off much of his firewall to make it Because he is more security conscious than we are.
Rym: Mm-hmm And I start.
Rym: we started a little chat and then I hit record in garage band and garage.
Rym: then Ben said hey We noticed that you're trying to use garage band and I chat something something.
Rym: Would you like to record your I chat conversation?
Rym: I said yes, and then it created a nice little Podcast thing with a track for every person in the conversation recorded all of our voices perfectly and even did a little meta thing in The Podcast track.
Rym: All right, I'm recording with them and then about seven minutes into my recording garage band suddenly says hey I can't record anymore There are too many tracks or events or something and I'm done and it wouldn't let me record more than that.
Scott: seven minutes Wow, seven minutes.
Scott: That's a great podcast.
Scott: seven minute interviews BAM
Rym: I was able to extend that somewhat by deleting the enhanced podcast track the jingles track, you know every track But the one we were talking on but even then I wasn't able to test how long it would actually let me record Nor was I able to determine exactly what factor it was.
Rym: You know what factor was using to decide I couldn't record anymore.
Scott: Did you change the beats per minute like the guy in our forum said to?
Rym: yes I tried that.
Rym: that caused all sorts of trouble, but then I finally got that to work and it didn't help.
Rym: No Okay, but I recorded a conversation and I figured I could deal with those little issues talking to Jim.
Rym: So tonight just now a little while ago.
Rym: This is why this episode is late because normally we'd be done by now and we just be talking about the cool interview we had.
Rym: We start our little I chat.
Rym: we're having some trouble because as we learn later, there are a whole bunch of terrible bugs in the newer versions of I chat and Apple won't say anything.
Rym: but it seems like the internet is a buzz with people complaining and Saying that oh you have to use this back level of QuickTime and this different back level of I chat and this version of OS X Tiger.
Scott: the actual problem seems to be from from doing a bit of five minutes of research.
Scott: So I'm not a hundred percent sure this is right, but after five minutes of research apparently in some version of I chat they added some quality of service packets and that means that a packet will go to the router and say I need to be sent faster and it'll get sent faster and If the router doesn't support that it she just sends it normally.
Scott: Apparently it was screwing up some routers making the packets get sent slower So that when the packets didn't go through fast enough.
Scott: Apple gets a message.
Scott: the I check gets a message saying your packet didn't go fast enough and then it gives up saying oh, it's not fast enough screw that.
Scott: I Wonder what are these programmers at Apple writing this offer?
Scott: What the hell are they thinking?
Rym: Well one why were they trying to you?
Rym: I mean, it's fairly common knowledge among internet professionals that the vast majority of any QoS metadata is Ignored at best by the majority of the world.
Rym: Mm-hmm QoS is Effectively impossible on the internet because the Internet's the Wild Wild West.
Rym: Why should I who has a router in some company somewhere let someone else tell me?
Rym: Hey my packets important.
Rym: Please let me through fast because if that worked Everyone in the world would tell their packets to say that and then you've defeated the purpose.
Rym: No one plays nice on the internet So QoS doesn't work, but I'm not gonna.
Rym: that's not the topic for today And I'm sure none of the anime fans care about the inner workings of the Internet's.
Scott: But
Rym: anyway, despite that we had some glitches with you know, actually connecting in I chat due to this weird Bandwidth QoS problem, but we eventually got it to work and we're talking with Jim and it's going really well And he's a really cool guy and
Scott: he was really nice.
Rym: Yeah, like we asked him all the questions we had that we weren't gonna bother with on the interview But we just wanted to know and Walt Walt Scott's talking to him I'm setting up everything and then alright, we've got the audio chat going.
Rym: I've got garage band open.
Rym: I got a podcast ready I hit record and The little nice dialogue doesn't pop up.
Rym: It just starts recording as though there's.
Rym: no I chat going on.
Scott: It seems to be the case that if you have to start the audio chat with someone else You have to be the inviter in order to get the recording to start now.
Scott: No one else invites you.
Rym: It doesn't seem to record though I think I got it to work that way with James and Lisa But I'm not a hundred percent sure.
Rym: I'll have to do some testing with whoever is willing to run I chat and play with me later.
Scott: Yeah, this cannot be confirmed or denied by the internet.
Scott: It's just a good guess because we were never able to get around that bandwidth issue when we started the chat.
Scott: So we could never test both circumstances.
Rym: Yes, but bandwidth aside garage band just ignored the thing and it didn't give me an error or anything.
Rym: and the Apple documentation said Oh, it'll just work and there's absolutely no indication of what order you'd have to do anything or any possible problems you might run into.
Scott: and Like they don't give you any more controls or options.
Scott: all you can do is push the one button they give to you.
Scott: It's like if there was a giant factory and the giant factory had one control big red button.
Scott: And you hit the big red button and a car comes out.
Scott: It's a car factory.
Scott: I just decided that you hit the button again.
Scott: a car comes out.
Scott: you hit the button again a car comes out you hit the Button a car doesn't come out.
Scott: What can you do besides jam that big red button a million times and then kill yourself?
Scott: You don't have any other controls.
Scott: That's all they give you.
Scott: they made it easy and as a result They made it impossible to do anything different.
Scott: if something goes wrong figure out what goes wrong or anything.
Rym: Now to extend that a little bit further I want to because Scott's analogy here is really good and I want to extend it because People have really seemed to express some confusion as to what I mean by Context when I'm talking about max and why the fact that max now especially not so much OS X But the applications like garage band and I chat are so contextual.
Rym: But they're contextual in such a bad way that it just frustrates me to no end and causes trouble.
Rym: the red button has one context the context.
Rym: the default context meaning a context is like a Scenario or a point of view in this context.
Rym: I hit the button a car comes out.
Rym: now Let's say next to the button There is a big lever and the levers.
Rym: to the left it says car and if it's to the right it says SUV.
Scott: So this yes, so the same control.
Scott: the button does multiple things depending on different Contexts.
Rym: now context is fine.
Rym: I mean almost every computer program in the modern world uses context and that's very important.
Rym: That's how you eyes work on.
Rym: contextual interfaces are the cornerstone of modern gooeys and modern computing.
Rym: now Say we've got the red button and the lever.
Rym: this is car and SUV.
Rym: great I can look at the lever and see what state I'm in.
Rym: I can see what context I'm in and from that I can know What the red button is going to do.
Rym: if I hit the red button and an SUV comes out.
Rym: But I wanted a car I can look and say oh the thing has to point to car not to SUV.
Rym: Let's say that lever is hidden.
Rym: Let's say instead of a lever there's a dude sitting in a glass room above the factory and he's watching me.
Rym: and If my hats on forward, it's an SUV button, but if my hats on backwards, it's a car button.
Scott: There's no way for you to know.
Rym: that's what Apple seems to be.
Rym: Well, not.
Rym: that's what GarageBand and I chat and all these I life applications seem to be doing.
Rym: they're super contextual But they never directly tell you what context you're in.
Rym: Thus behavior is often unexpected or seemingly random and because there's no feedback There's no way to know what's going on or how to fix it.
Scott: It's like if you have this side panel open and you click this button then the button does this.
Scott: But if you have this track selected and drag something into the side panel Then it does something different than if you had this track selected and you drag something into the same side panel.
Scott: If I drag something into a panel, it should do the same thing no matter what else is going on every time.
Rym: but anyway We as a result did not get to interview at least on the air.
Rym: Jim Vowles sorrow Though we're going to try to schedule something again in the future Once we figure out a way to make this work probably involving Skype, which is a non Apple software Which works very nicely even though it was developed by the Kazaa guys.
Scott: While they were evil in back in the day They were very good at programming evil and they programmed a very good Skype and eBay.
Scott: some other good Programmers bought it and made it non evil and Skype is awesome for now.
Rym: Yep So we're probably going to try to use that now, of course Jim This was like his last free night before he goes off on a flurry of conventions and leave and fun So we might not actually catch him until after Otakon at this point.
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: We'll get a whole bunch of.
Scott: we can just not go to the con feedback panel.
Rym: Yeah, and it'll be pretty cool Yeah, but definitely look forward to it.
Rym: We'll keep you appraised because from what little we got to talk to him He's a great guy.
Rym: I think he'll really be able to tell you a lot of interesting things about Otakon and anime conventions in general.
Scott: Yeah, especially the difference between Otakon and every other anime convention Which is something a lot of people don't understand and I'd rather have him explain it than me Even though I understand it perfectly now as a as a nice Bonus or a consolation prize.
Rym: because we don't have the audio interview what I'm going to do?
Rym: I'm not gonna talk about it on this episode, but we'll probably talk about it on the next episode.
Rym: We got before we did this.
Rym: he gave us and I we did a text interview over email.
Rym: We told him what questions we wanted to ask him and he responded an email in case we didn't hook up audio wise.
Rym: So I'm gonna put that in the forums with a link for anyone who wants to get Just basically the text of a short interview we had with Jim
Scott: Yep, so if you're interested in seeing what Jim Vowles had to say We have some of what he had to say in our forums and you should join them if you're awesome.
Rym: Yes So yes, it's definitely a trick to get you to join the forums.
Rym: But also he really had some interesting answers about such topics as why the cosplay this year is going to be in the arena Which I think is awesome Mm-hmm.
Rym: All right.
Rym: But anyway, it's we're gonna hit some news.
Rym: I don't have a news because I'm just kind of angry at my back even though I love my Mac.
Rym: I just it's.
Rym: it's like a puppy that's really cute and then it pees all over my floor.
Rym: That is so exactly what it is.
Rym: I still love the puppy, but why won't it stop peeing?
Scott: And everyone else has puppies and they say they're so great, but they don't.
Scott: my puppy doesn't pee on the floor.
Rym: Yeah, you know what either.
Rym: you're not trying to use your puppy to make podcasts.
Scott: They're not trying to train their dog to sit up they're just letting it roam free, you know what.
Rym: maybe they just can't smell puppy pee.
Scott: Maybe they can't smell puppy pee.
Scott: Maybe they don't give their puppy any water.
Scott: So it doesn't pee.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I'm not gonna pour water in my Mac and I never thought in all my life that I would say the words puppy pee.
Scott: on a radio show I Just pictured a bumper sticker with a puppy peeing on an apple.
Rym: I Just picture a puppy peeing.
Rym: Hey, I've dealt with puppies.
Scott: lift up one leg next to the tree.
Scott: It's all good.
Rym: a a herd of Irish setter puppies like little tiny puppies took me out once.
Rym: Okay, I'll tell that story some other day if we do a show on dogs But these puppies just took me down.
Rym: Anyway, I don't have a news which is fine because rims news Rym is angry at Apple.
Scott: Yes flash news flash Rym is still angry at Apple news at 11 And in fact, it is 11 because son of a bit running late My news Bill Gates is now slightly cooler because he is a pirate are.
Rym: Now I want to note right now that the argument all the arguments about piracy and a little actual property.
Rym: I've just been turned a little bit on their head because Bill Gates the man who has the most money of anyone.
Rym: He could buy a record company by musicians and he could buy to Hollywood period.
Rym: He could buy Everyone.
Rym: he could buy everyone who's ever made music and hire them to make him music and play it.
Rym: live for him every day.
Scott: You think like, you know rock stars are rich.
Scott: Bill Gates could own every rock star.
Scott: Bill Gates could buy and sell Michael Jackson Madonna the Rolling Stones the Beatles and everyone twice.
Rym: So, uh, what did Bill Gates just do?
Scott: Well, let me there was an interview between the Wall Street Journal and Bill Gates.
Scott: Well, and yesterday.
Rym: This is the kind of thing I expect from like a blogger who happened to allow me to read four lines So classic from this interview.
Scott: ready.
Scott: Wall Street Journal says You watch physics lectures and Harlem Globetrotters on YouTube.
Scott: question mark.
Scott: Bill Gates says this social network thing this social networking thing takes you to crazy places.
Scott: Wall Street Journal says but those were stolen, correct?
Scott: Gates says Stolen is a strong word.
Scott: It's copyrighted content that the owner wasn't paid for.
Scott: so yeah Yeah, yeah, mr.
Rym: Bill Gates who has all the money in the world has no reason to pirate pirates.
Scott: I guess Bill Gates is saying it's okay to do those Windows XP and Vista torrents on YouTube on Pirate Bay.
Scott: So let's have that now.
Rym: I guess that the the actual serious point I would make is that look at the industry and look at this commodity of intellectual property particularly audio and Not so much full movies but snippets of movies or short films or excerpts from things digital video TV episodes.
Rym: now Bill Gates who has infinite money found it convenient trivial And in fact, he didn't even rethink that he was doing anything wrong to just watch this stuff.
Rym: It's so easy to do it.
Rym: It's so easy to get it.
Rym: The most convenient way to get this media is to just download it.
Scott: I think I would just release now one of my many many arguments against Copyright or at least modern copyright.
Rym: Yeah, we're not against people getting credit for their work or even from having a small monopoly.
Rym: We're against modern copyright law.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: Let me just release one of my arguments.
Scott: There is supply and there is demand.
Scott: What are the rules of supply and demand Rym?
Scott: when supply goes down when supply goes down?
Rym: Price goes up.
Rym: Uh-huh when price goes up.
Rym: Well price really is the floating factor here.
Rym: When demand goes up price goes up.
Rym: if demand goes up and supply goes down price skyrockets.
Rym: Now if supply is infinite Meaning supply keeps going up then prices keep going down and as the supply approaches infinity the price approaches zero.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Now, let's say the world had infinity apples.
Scott: There was an apple tree.
Scott: They just spewed out so many apples that if at any moment at any time during your life you wanted an apple There that rare was Apple immediately.
Scott: and they're just there's more of them.
Scott: There's no running out of them now in this world.
Rym: Could you ever sell just an apple to someone?
Scott: No Because if they wanted an apple they could just snap their fingers and one falls off the infinite apple tree.
Scott: and there it is.
Scott: So apples cause nothing when they are an infinite supply and they don't cost anything to transport and it doesn't cost anything to get Them now.
Rym: despite this the Apple economy does not collapse because while apples are infinite and free There are still businesses now for turning those apples into pies or baking those apples making those apples into caramel apples Stacking the apples up nicely in your pantry instead of having them fall randomly.
Rym: There are still opportunities for economic advancement despite the fact that a commodity that was once limited is now unlimited.
Scott: now Look at the world.
Scott: We live in today.
Scott: Recorded digital audio and video is infinite in supply.
Scott: Therefore it is worth Jack and shit.
Rym: It's free.
Scott: it's free to distribute.
Scott: it's relatively free to distribute.
Scott: you pay the cost of internet connection Which is already paid for and once you've paid the entry fee you live in a separate world where digital audio and video cost Absolutely nothing.
Scott: someone going around trying to sell digital and audio and video in a world in which they are free would be like someone Going around and setting up an Apple stand where apples are a dollar in a world of infinite apples.
Rym: I like how you've slipped into this kind of like Sunday morning TV preacher.
Rym: boys It's good.
Scott: Is it good?
Rym: It's good.
Scott: I like it sound like a Sunday morning preacher.
Rym: I wasn't trying to keep doing this kind of whoa.
Scott: I wasn't trying to.
Rym: it was good.
Rym: I liked it.
Rym: Okay, but anyway despite this there's still an economy around Audio, you can't sell the audio digital file because those are infinite but you can sell things like a live performance swag about the audio an interview a Compilation that's easy to get as opposed to the free ones.
Rym: You can get you can sell your audio manipulating skills.
Scott: Let's say I'm an apple pie master, you know, the people want to hire me to make apple pies.
Scott: Let's say I'm a remixing master.
Scott: Someone doesn't have a remix as you know, and they want it, but it doesn't yet exist.
Scott: They pay me to take these free digital audios on the internet remix them into something new and great Which is then free, but I've been paid to make it not paid You know to give it out or for the work itself.
Scott: I'm paid for the creation my labor.
Rym: now Let's just talk about audio right now because video is Still a whole.
Rym: not so much video but movies and feature films are a whole nother beast for all.
Scott: the real problem with them Is that they had they cost a lot more to make?
Scott: Modern high special effects full-length feature films where audio really doesn't cost anything to make.
Rym: yeah And we've got a lot of ideas on that that we really shouldn't get into on anime day.
Scott: yes, all I can say about that is that right now to make less than full-length feature film quality video is Cheap enough where anyone can do it and it's basically free.
Scott: However, but to make full if you want full-length feature movies You're gonna have to wait for the cost of producing them to go down or for now pay which luckily People are still paying enough to where movies keep getting made.
Scott: Yeah, cuz DVDs just seem to be worth it for some reason.
Rym: Yeah, I mean look people will pay the money for a DVD even though it would be almost trivial to pirate that movie.
Rym: That says a lot.
Scott: Yeah, there is also, you know, even today with the current downloading technologies Even the best pirated copy you can get from the internet is just not as good as a DVD.
Scott: I mean, nah, the DVD rip is many many gigs Which no one gets and you don't get the extras and you don't get the surround sound and it just it's not.
Scott: you know You're getting something for your DVD.
Rym: now.
Rym: the argument people make that I want to address right now and it's so easy to squash at least for audio because The argument I always hear is but if there's no direct compensation like that that no one will make anything anymore.
Rym: And I point out to you that Scott and I do a podcast four nights a week.
Rym: We're pumping out hours and hours and hours of at least I think is pretty good audio content with Absolutely, not only no compensation, but no expectation of compensation.
Scott: In fact, we discourage compensation and we have a Creative Commons license, which means you can remix this shit all you want.
Scott: I'm surprised no one's made a Rym and Scott Funky remix track.
Rym: I'm sure we've said enough words to where you could put the words together and make us say hilarious things Yes, or make a techno song and you know make the vocal tracks.
Scott: Rym saying Rym doesn't give a shit Rym doesn't give or something like that.
Rym: as long as I'm wearing these I can cast two spells Simultaneously, there you go All right.
Rym: That was the most inside joke we've ever said on the air.
Scott: Well, is it really?
Rym: Yeah No one knows about that, but the two of us and possibly can on the forums, okay well, we're gonna Tailor two things of the day.
Rym: All right now for all of our new listeners out there.
Rym: We were kind of angry at the beginning so we didn't do it.
Rym: But this is new listener week because we've noticed all of you downloading the episodes.
Scott: Yes, so we're gonna do a little new listener spiel before we do the things of the day And then we'll do the new listeners the thing of the day spiel.
Rym: But to all you new listeners that music means it's time for things of the day.
Scott: Yes It does.
Scott: the thing of the day is on this podcast every episode.
Scott: We each talk about something cool Usually on the internet.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Now you should go visit it.
Rym: Yeah, my thing of the day is actually kind of old-school but I've realized that a lot of people haven't got it when I've made jokes or references to it.
Rym: and While it's a staple on Fark calm.
Scott: Oh, we didn't do the explaining.
Scott: That's fun.
Rym: All right.
Rym: All right, that's explaining.
Rym: I forgot.
Scott: Yeah, just get right to that thing of the day.
Scott: So anxious.
Rym: Yeah, partly cuz I'm staring at GarageBand and seething at it.
Scott: yeah, so GeekNights is a podcast four nights a week.
Scott: It's a late-night show for geeks.
Scott: Yeah, I'm Scott.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: There you go in case you're confused.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, what else do we say about?
Scott: all right.
Scott: Monday is science technology.
Scott: Tuesdays video games board games and role-playing games.
Rym: Wednesdays anime Comics.
Rym: Thursdays pretty much anything.
Rym: We've got a couple of very popular series such as how to not suck and our geek fables.
Scott: Yep, so and soon to be something else also.
Rym: Yeah, we got some fun things in the works.
Scott: Yeah, so it's a Wednesday.
Scott: It's anime manga and comics.
Scott: We're gonna talk about anime next which is a convention.
Scott: We went to recently.
Scott: Yeah, we were going to give you an interview with the head of Otakon But we're not going to because you already explained that we got a website Www.frontrowcrew.com.
Rym: We've got forums there with a rockin community.
Rym: We've got a frapper map.
Rym: You can put a little pin in a map and see where all our listeners are.
Rym: Many of them are in Australia in the United Kingdom.
Scott: Yes, go to the frapper map and put your little dot on the map so we can see where you are.
Rym: We've got listeners on almost every continent.
Scott: Well, there's no Antarctica listeners.
Scott: No, I think this is Asian listeners.
Scott: I want to see some listeners in the Middle East.
Scott: Yeah, that would be cool.
Rym: Well, I Africa - I know someone who knows someone who's living in Egypt.
Rym: now I should ping him and tell him to listen to our show.
Scott: Oh, that'd be great.
Rym: Anyway, yeah, so you're obviously listening.
Rym: I'm sure many of you especially since it's anime day might have heard about us at anime next which is what we're going to talk About and if you did welcome, we're glad you saw our flyer or met us.
Scott: Yes And right now we're gonna do the things of the day, which is every episode.
Scott: I already said we talked about something cool.
Scott: We saw on the internet one each one for him and one for Scott.
Rym: So like I was saying my thing of the day is something that is really well known and to FARC and to a lot of Geeks, but it might have you might have missed over this one because it was kind of a flash in the pan I refer to lightning bolt lightning bolt lightning bolt lightning bolt lightning bolt sleep sleep death death death.
Scott: That's a good one.
Rym: Yeah, it's alright LARPing live-action role-playing which I want to say right now.
Rym: I have nothing against.
Rym: I think it can be really cool.
Scott: I think it's scary.
Rym: Well, it can be really cool and I have nothing against it as an idea as a game.
Rym: I have issue with many of the people I have met in my life who happen to do it.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: I think I think it's not even many.
Scott: I think it's pretty much all.
Rym: it's not all.
Scott: it's like if you had A movie and the movie could be cool.
Scott: But the problem is is the only people who ever go to see this movie are scary perverts and They jerk off to the movie all the time and no one else ever goes to see it.
Rym: However, I would be cool.
Rym: I went to a gaming convention a long long time ago and they had a LARP D&D which was actually really really awesome Mm-hmm.
Rym: But anyway now there are some classes of LARPers just role-play.
Rym: some of them think they're actually vampires or witches or whatever they happen to believe and some of them go out into the woods and hit each other with bafa weapons or Foam-covered weapon and some of them do all three of those things and more.
Rym: now This is just a short video Someone took of a group of nerds and I say nerds as opposed to geeks.
Rym: be and you'll see why when you are there nerds.
Scott: Oh, these are nerds now.
Rym: They're they're having some sort of D&D fight there.
Rym: It looks like some climactic battle and there's this one guy who's a wizard and he looks like like, you know Those SCA people the Society for consenting adults.
Scott: I thought it was creative and a heck of a.
Rym: You know what it could go either way it goes both ways like a bisexual yes - that was a joke.
Rym: Now this guy he's For you get the vibe that he's one of them except those people are usually pretty cool.
Rym: This guy is uh, You just have to see it.
Rym: He's casting lightning bolt Which means he's running at this guy throwing tennis balls at him and yelling Lightning bolt lightning bolt lightning bolt lightning bolt lightning bolt and it's just a wizard can't even this is this is nerdy You ready for this already?
Scott: You can't even cast lightning ball more than once every six seconds.
Scott: He's obviously cheating or he's so high level.
Scott: He has some sort of metamagic feat.
Rym: He could have a quick casting feats or something.
Scott: That's what I said.
Rym: metamagic feats Yeah, or it could be second edition where you can just make stuff up.
Scott: It could be second edition.
Scott: Then he could have haste.
Rym: Oh real haste haste That's that's.
Scott: I miss haste and then like boots of something else to get double haste.
Scott: And then a vorpal sword and oh, yeah, I think that other guy had a verbal sword The other guy had freaking power word kill.
Scott: Yeah, I guess no one made their saves.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So if you've ever heard me yell lightning bolt lightning bolt lightning bolt and you thought I was just being weird Kind of like when no one knew what that ha ha thing was We're making fun of nerds not geeks nerd.
Rym: Yes There's a big difference between nerds geeks dorks dweebs assholes doofuses doofuses.
Rym: So everyone's a doofus sometimes Yeah, but some people are doofs.
Scott: Yeah doofus not a doofus Don't this.
Rym: yo don't do what Donnie don't does don't doofus what Donnie do don't do dang dilly dang dong dang Dang it.
Scott: So my thing of the day is awesome is really awesome.
Scott: I went through a whole bunch of things today before I settled on one.
Rym: Yeah, he had something else.
Rym: and then he found this while I was typing up the show notes for this episode.
Scott: Yeah, it was like at the last minute the best one came up now.
Scott: Who knows the karate kid raise your hand.
Scott: Really don't raise your hand.
Rym: I'm not.
Rym: I'm doing that a crane kick thing.
Rym: Okay, I actually am.
Scott: so I guess you're raising both hands.
Scott: There he goes.
Scott: So there was a karate kid game for the NES and a whole bunch of kids who like the karate kid.
Scott: I actually didn't see the karate killed too much later in life.
Scott: So I didn't like the karate kid.
Scott: But people who like the karate kid were kids obviously and they bought the NES game of the same name.
Rym: I want to say right now that I played that game many times.
Rym: I owned it and then I sold it back to Funko Land and Watching this video was one of the most cathartic experiences I've ever had now.
Scott: I'd never played this game.
Scott: I might have played this game once in an emulator, but that doesn't really count.
Scott: I didn't even know I knew this game existed kind of like.
Scott: I didn't specifically remember it But if you would have set asked me was there a karate kid NES game.
Scott: I would have said yes, I Couldn't tell you anything about this game until watching this video.
Scott: the kid basically And he seems like a cool kid, too Plays the karate kid NES game.
Scott: He gets pissed off at it with good reason and Then he explains why he is so pissed off in Hilarious fashion.
Rym: with video like this the best part is where he's talking about how easy it is to die.
Rym: now you keep falling into pits and enemies keep knocking into pits and you can't jump because when you jump enemies knock you into pits and Meanwhile, it just shows the guy falling into pits constantly despite playing as well as a human code.
Scott: The last time he falls into a pit is just hilarious because he avoids it so many times before falling in.
Scott: And if you're a hard score old-school NES gamer and you see this you will go.
Rym: yes, yes Yes, that's exactly what it was.
Scott: Yes And if you're not an old-school NES gamer if you're one of those kids where the first Final Fantasy you played had a number higher than five You know in the US Or you know a PlayStation to you is old.
Scott: PlayStation 1 is old school as far as you're concerned.
Rym: Yeah, I mean to us the PlayStation 1. is this upstart.
Rym: Yeah this punk kid that appeared.
Scott: Yeah, or if you think Goldeneye is an FPS classic as opposed to Wolfenstein 3d or doom We lived in a world where the number one and number two gaming platforms were Nintendo and Sega Where when it was a rumor, there were only 16 bits in those days.
Scott: back in my day We had 16 bits to run our video game systems.
Rym: Yeah back in my he thought that was too many.
Rym: We didn't have video games.
Rym: every morning our old man would take us out to the granny of mines and beat us with belts all Day, you know what and we liked it.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: But if you're a new school gamer at least newer school at least if we would consider you new school.
Scott: If you're a punk kid as far as we're concerned Yeah Cuz we're.
Rym: you need
Scott: to watch this because then you will understand what NES gaming was like for the vast majority of NES games And you will see why you suck at video games because we beat these things
Rym: Daily, I mean today like look at the new Mario game for the DS.
Rym: you can save Your game.
Scott: I beat that thing in like a day or two.
Rym: You don't in Mario 3 the best Mario ever as far as I'm concerned with.
Scott: Sometimes if I tried to beat Mario 3 first of all, it takes forever.
Scott: Second of all, sometimes I can't beat it.
Scott: Sometimes I die near the end Or I mess up my p-wing and then I don't have enough.
Scott: yep, I mean he wings.
Rym: it used to be that Beating a game.
Rym: it's not like now where you're pretty much guaranteed to beat the game if you play it for the records amount of time.
Rym: Back then beating a game was an event whereupon you called your friend down the street.
Rym: You don't care if it was 2 in the morning and you said oh my god, Joe you gotta go over here.
Rym: I'm just about to be Final Fantasy 1. you got to see the end.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: Yeah, because the odds of all of your friends beating the same game we're next to nil.
Scott: It's like everyone had Megaman 2, but I beat Megaman 2.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: No one else even came close.
Scott: They're busy playing other games.
Rym: everyone specialized like Scott's the Mac master of Megaman 2.
Rym: But I am the only one in this household who can beat bionic commando.
Scott: I could be bionic commando if I tried now that because when I played bionic commando, first of all I never had it on the NES.
Scott: second of all I didn't know you could level up until much until you showed me that.
Scott: now knowing that I can level up I could probably get significantly far by command.
Rym: You can get to the end But I'll note that the levels with the flame at the end are not.
Scott: maybe I'd have trouble with the flame But I think I could beat the Hitler.
Scott: You ever give it about Hitler?
Rym: No, no, I haven't.
Scott: Okay, so Everyone needs to watch this thing of the day.
Scott: It's very very important and very very amusing.
Rym: Alright now nominally we're gonna talk about anime next today, which it's gonna be a little short on the main bit.
Rym: We're gonna go a little short here for one because we weren't planning on talking about anime mag.
Rym: next We're planning on interviewing Jim Bowles.
Scott: But since we have to talk about anime next and we spent a bunch of time dealing with technology that sucks Apple Apple we now have to Cut this short because we're tired and I have to go to the city tomorrow for a concert.
Rym: Well, as do I but it's fine.
Scott: How are we gonna do an episode tomorrow at some concert?
Rym: shit?
Rym: We might not.
Rym: oh shit You know I don't think there's gonna be an episode tomorrow cuz we're not gonna get back home from New York City until like Late.
Scott: Wow, there goes new listener week.
Rym: Yeah, we're not gonna record an extra episode tonight, oh, yeah, I guess not we're not.
Scott: I wish you would have thought about that before.
Rym: Yeah, you know what?
Rym: Well, maybe we'll do an episode Friday to make up for it With people here.
Rym: Yeah Stay tuned for a possible first use of our on the scheduled episode category.
Scott: yeah, there might be a special GeekNights on Friday and if you only subscribe to one day of the week you won't see It.
Scott: you'll only see it if you subscribe to the total GeekNights or just go to the website and download that.
Rym: Yeah, that works, too Yeah, but it works out because honestly anime next is a great con, but we don't have a lot to say about it.
Rym: That's particularly insightful or different from what we'd say about any other good anime con we go to.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think there's a lot to say about anime next itself But there is stuff to say about our experience at anime next.
Scott: true because anime next for us Was different than other cons because we didn't know anyone there We didn't have plans and we only went for one day.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Also, this is the first con I've gone to in a long time at least anime cons because gaming cons are different but normal anime con Where I wasn't staff, I wasn't a panelist.
Rym: I wasn't there with the press I was just me some schmuck who paid to get in and I was also some schmuck and so was our friend katsu Yep, and I got him a bit.
Rym: It was a little weird.
Rym: Like I'd see punk kids about to cause trouble This was the biggest thing is I'd see a group of kids running through the hall with the sword or something Something bad was about to happen and I was about to get up and run over and go All right, you guys gotta settle down blah blah blah.
Rym: then I realized I don't have any right to do that.
Rym: I'm just some guy.
Scott: you are just some dumb guy.
Rym: I don't have some badge that gives me power.
Scott: Yep So anime next.
Scott: we were only there on Saturday.
Scott: We stayed pretty much most of Saturday.
Rym: Yeah from when the con started pretty much like a half-hour into it I was kind of up for saying later and going to the rave and everything But katsu and Scott weren't so much.
Scott: Yeah, it wasn't too into the rave and Scott had to drive home.
Rym: so I don't really feel bad for Avoiding the rave even though I kind of like this is.
Scott: the drive there was less than perfect.
Rym: Yeah driving to this convention, which is hate driving in Jersey.
Rym: It's in the metal.
Rym: I hate driving in Pennsylvania a lot more than I hate driving in Jersey Because at least in Jersey if you can get to the Garden State, you're okay.
Scott: at least art for ours.
Scott: We're concerned.
Rym: Yeah, who goes anywhere else in Jersey?
Rym: people do yeah, we don't do actually probably will soon but anyway Yep, now getting to the Meadowlands.
Rym: We've gone there for well.
Rym: I've been there for three conventions and Scott's been there for two.
Rym: We never fail to have trouble getting there Mm-hmm.
Rym: It's just it's a somewhat obtuse place to get to.
Scott: I think what happened is he wanted to get off exit 17 But there was traffic and I didn't see the exit sign and there was a road that was closed.
Scott: But it wasn't really closed and it totally threw us off.
Scott: So we had to go across a bridge turn around come back.
Scott: There wasn't an exit 17 on the way back had to get off the road drive around on random roads Turn around in a commuter lot until eventually I was like, hey, there it is.
Rym: Yeah Just by luck the first uber con I went to.
Rym: I got lost and it was like 2 in the morning and I ended up Just driving back.
Rym: I like the Takani.
Scott: at least now we know our way around the Meadowlands Mall Plaza Hotel convention area.
Scott: Yeah, so if we're ever there again We know how to get in and out.
Rym: Now the main guests of honor at anime next which actually was cool because we actually listen to them talk And usually I don't go to panels.
Scott: I mean I went to panels my first Otakon at least, you know famous guest panels and now I tend to not go to them because I don't find them so interesting.
Scott: but Well, we went to one.
Scott: Yeah the first time in a long time that this was our Rintaro and Masao Mariyama Mariyama.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Mariyama is gonna be at Otakon - he's he's making the rounds him now If you don't know cuz this is the kind of thing the anime world order guys They'll probably yell at us if we get it wrong, but don't yell at us, please.
Scott: just we're gonna Notables.
Rym: the things that Rintaro worked on include a Galaxy Express 999 bunch of Captain Harlock stuff Metropolis X I'm not gonna mention it Final Fantasy Legend of the Crystals, which is Not his fault Phoenix Dagger of Kamui one of the Phoenix anime.
Rym: Yeah all sorts of stuff like that.
Rym: He worked alongside Osamu Tezuka back in the day.
Rym: who is the god of?
Rym: in fact It says here in the con book god of manga.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Osamu Tezuka is the god of manga.
Rym: I mean I am in the process of getting all his manga except astro boy and I want to say that in our case That is not an opinion.
Rym: That is the accepted Nomenclature of everyone in the world who knows about manga.
Rym: Yes No one is.
Rym: I mean no one disagrees on that point.
Rym: I defy any of you to disagree on that point because we'll seek the anime world order guys on you and they'll find the truth Of kicking your ass
Scott: and I will throw my volumes of Tezuka manga at you and you will feel the lump on your head And you will die in a fire.
Rym: now the other guy Murayama parakeets Monster the TV show which I didn't like the new vampire hunter D X metropolis.
Rym: Oh, I didn't realize he was gunslinger girls.
Scott: Yeah, madman studios.
Scott: He's the.
Scott: he's basically a producer.
Scott: Rintaro is a director.
Scott: So Rintaro makes specific shows and he directs them and Murayama is the producer of madman studios which made shows like try gun and and Yep, jubei-chan, perfect blue, card cap or Sakura Sakura Some stuff for the anime tricks he had to hand in.
Scott: yeah, I think they produced the new Nana show.
Rym: Yeah, Nana which I love.
Scott: yeah madman is is a very big anime studio.
Scott: they're up there with.
Scott: Who's else is big anime studios gonzo?
Scott: Gainax All those big anime studios madman's one of the biggest.
Rym: now two things about their panel is that one.
Rym: they showed us a Video clip of a whole bunch of openers to shows shows that weren't out yet in America shows Americans shouldn't know about.
Rym: they presented as a. here's what we're working on right now.
Rym: Here's the cool stuff from Japan.
Scott: Here's the cool stuff that's on TV right now in Japan that we made.
Scott: We've seen all of their shows that every show that they showed we knew about and had seen.
Rym: in fact We're watching regularly multiple numbers of them.
Rym: That is correct except Black Lagoon, which I have almost no interest in.
Scott: Yeah, Black Lagoon and we watched one episode and that was that we didn't even watch the whole episode.
Scott: We did.
Scott: we'll review that in some show coming up.
Rym: Yeah ice once con season winds down.
Rym: So after Otakon, we're gonna start reviewing anime again.
Scott: We'll probably crunch like a whole bunch of anime per show because we'll do all the crappy ones.
Scott: It don't require a lot of talking.
Rym: Yeah, cuz I think Nana is gonna get its own episode.
Scott: at this point I think it definitely is right when it's done.
Rym: In fact a quick aside because people have actually been asking me and we kept saying we do it But we're not.
Rym: well we haven't.
Rym: but right now what we're watching because people have wondered what what's going on?
Rym: Do we still watch anime?
Rym: We're watching Nana, which is a very good show.
Rym: I highly recommend it regardless of what kind of anime you like.
Scott: You probably will like Nana, especially if you have a vagina.
Scott: You will like Nana a lot.
Rym: now I point you have a penis.
Scott: you will only like Nana if you can forget that you have a penis for like five minutes.
Rym: Okay, I just I find that funny coming from Scott because this normally a show.
Rym: I mean, this is a show about two girls living together in Tokyo.
Rym: That's the kind of show Scott would say whatever.
Rym: that's stupid.
Rym: He's watching it along with me and loving every second of it Not every second.
Scott: Yeah some parts of it are a yeah, whatever you love it.
Scott: It's really similar.
Scott: It's a I always seem to watch like.
Scott: I'm big on the intellectual Animes like the stuff that Satoshi khan makes and a big on the literary manga like the stuff Tezuka makes.
Scott: But all the time I always have one show that's like a crap.
Scott: Not intellectual show.
Scott: that's just stuff that I watch like.
Scott: I watch initial D And then I watch Goku Sen which is about a teacher who's in the mat Yakuza and then I watch back and this is really similar to back.
Scott: So this is my non intellectual show of the moment.
Rym: Yeah, I love Nana and I at least watch a couple episodes.
Rym: I almost promise you'll like it.
Rym: if you don't like it call in give us some feedback and tell us why not.
Scott: Yeah, and some of the I think I was that's four and five maybe six are part recap But watch them anyway, because they're recap plus plus.
Rym: Yes, like they're they're really worth watching.
Rym: I can't stress that enough.
Rym: just bear with it because it's worth it.
Scott: There's payout and there's also the Nana manga, which I haven't read.
Scott: I probably not going to.
Scott: maybe I'll look at it in the store.
Scott: Maybe I'll buy the first one.
Scott: Maybe I'll get rimmed to buy it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Now other things we're watching.
Rym: We've been watching ergo proxy, but we've kind of tape.
Scott: We have a shit ton of episodes.
Scott: We got to watch him.
Scott: Yeah, of course, I think it's licensed.
Scott: So maybe the DVDs will come out before we ever watch it and we'll buy him instead.
Rym: That's why we kind of tapered off on that.
Rym: I am watching a host club or on high school host club, which And Scott's watching it off and on with me.
Scott: Yeah, it's basically I don't really care where the show goes Because I pretty much got everything in it.
Scott: you get out of it in the first episode, but it's funny.
Scott: So, you know, I could watch any random episode to get the comedy and I don't really need to watch the whole show.
Rym: Yeah, it was kind of like you were with a honey or a dango.
Scott: Yeah, exactly of course honey or a dango after the.
Scott: you really want to watch that show the first bunch of episodes and then stop.
Scott: because Yeah, pretty much watching watch up until shows that one with like the H or something.
Rym: Yeah, the four F for the 4h whether it's not for age the 4f.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Yeah know the f4.
Scott: Yes, Emily and I were talking about this last night because she watched the honey or a dango has a manga and a TV drama Which she just watched and an anime and doesn't have a movie.
Scott: maybe I don't know if honey or dong is one of those things that exist in every medium in Japan and it's It's hard to say which one's the best.
Rym: Yeah, we'll write you a whole show on it cuz there's a lot we could say about.
Scott: we'd need to go get some manga and Something I don't know.
Scott: Yeah, it's also called boys over flowers.
Rym: Yes Now also that what was that show?
Rym: Utaware or something Utaware Rumono.
Rym: We only watched one episode.
Rym: I want to watch more.
Rym: I just haven't gotten around to it, but it's on the list of things that I'm going to be watching.
Scott: Yeah, I don't really have an interest in watching that show more than the first episode But I do want to know what to do with the mask is.
Scott: so if anyone knows the deal with that guy's mask Like is it a demon?
Scott: Is it a?
Scott: just just tell me cuz.
Scott: that's all I want to know.
Rym: Don't tell me it.
Scott: don't tell rims out when he watches the show.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I haven't had a chance to watch it.
Rym: He's having busy.
Scott: Yeah, also I bought according anime world order again.
Scott: Listen, the anime world order podcast.
Scott: Come on.
Rym: We don't even need to play a promo.
Rym: Just listen to them.
Rym: They're awesome.
Scott: Yep I Bought all of master Keaton, which is eight DVDs for in 35 episodes I think for five bucks each at anime.
Scott: next here we go back to anime.
Scott: next If it's not good anime world order, I'm gonna kick your asses at Otakon.
Scott: You made me spend 40 bucks.
Rym: now speaking of that This is a nice tangent to get us back onto our main topic anime next.
Scott: That's why I did it.
Rym: now.
Rym: Scott said he bought all of master Keaton.
Rym: in addition I've we bought between all three of us myself Scott and Katsu what like 40 DVDs?
Scott: It was a lot of DVDs compared to.
Scott: I really don't buy anime DVDs so often anymore since initial D and Gundam seed finished.
Scott: So the fact that I bought so many DVDs is crazy.
Rym: now we're walking around in there.
Rym: we see a guy was a huge sign.
Scott: It's no wait.
Scott: Let's start a little before that.
Scott: We don't really go to cons to the dealers rooms anymore.
Scott: The dealers rooms are kind of and we've seen everything they got.
Rym: we're jaded old men.
Rym: We go to a dealers room.
Rym: We're like man.
Rym: seen it seen it crap crap seen it crap Exactly.
Rym: We walked into this dealers room expecting like we're gonna walk in walk out and then we'll go on with our con business.
Rym: We ended up buying a pile of stuff man.
Scott: They had the best deals on you know, PVC figurines And and they had really good deals on little keychains.
Rym: Yeah, I have such an awesome set of Lupin PVCs that I can't get over it.
Scott: Yep I bought a nice link thing for my cell phone.
Scott: I have a Zelda one link stabbing the sword on my cell phone.
Rym: not the wooden sword Not the red sword the sword the sword.
Scott: That's a geek fable It sure is.
Rym: All right, and I got a little lockers club.
Rym: It's not really lockers Klein, but Screw you all it's lockers Klein.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Let him see destiny does not exist.
Rym: Yeah, as far as I'm concerned cuz I bought a little cell phone dog.
Rym: Lena's cute lockers Klein.
Rym: I go to the people selling like.
Scott: well, there were two lockers Klein's.
Scott: It was a cute one and a not-so-cute one.
Rym: I was like, give me that cute lockers Klein and they're like, oh that one That's not lockers Klein.
Rym: That's uh, what's her name?
Rym: What's her name from destiny?
Rym: blah blah blah blah.
Rym: and they talked and talked and talked and talked and talked and you wish they wouldn't Have said that.
Rym: and then they were like.
Rym: and then they reached to give me the real lockers Klein.
Rym: I was like now just give me that other girl and I'll pretend it's lockers and they're like.
Rym: You should watch destiny.
Rym: It's really good.
Rym: And then they gave me their list of reasons why it's good Which was identical to my list of reasons of why I don't want to watch it.
Scott: What was their list of reasons?
Rym: They were like.
Rym: it's it all the cool characters from before come back and you get to see them all doing stuff again and There's all sorts of lockers and Osterota and just fan service a crap.
Rym: Not fan service like TNA but fan service like.
Rym: I don't want to ruin Gundam seed But Gundam seed does a thing where a character appears near the end for no purpose other than the audience to go.
Scott: Yep, it would be like in you know If you have a show and as a favorite character and you make a character that people like and then that character, you know for some reason in the plot dies or goes away or you know does it becomes a traitor or something like that and Then in Later in the show you just make hints to that character because it you know people like the character so much they get all excited.
Scott: So it was like if you made a show Just doing things in the plot where the plot is there only to make fans happy and not to have a decent plot.
Scott: That's what the kind of fan service are talking about now.
Scott: It's like if someone just wrote a fanfic of Gundam seed and call the Gundam Z destiny.
Rym: Yeah, I mean apparently Gundam seed destiny had these other characters But no one cared about them and eventually they just brought all the original characters back in Great, that means they didn't plan it from the beginning.
Rym: and yeah Yeah, but anyway, we bought a pot while we're buying all this crap in the dealers room.
Rym: Just bye.
Rym: Bye.
Rym: and then We see a big sign five dollar DVDs.
Rym: and I think all right, that's got to be a pile of crap.
Rym: But let's go check it out.
Rym: There might be a gem a lot of gems.
Rym: They were all gems.
Rym: It was good anime.
Rym: that just happens to be five dollars because it's old.
Scott: got all of master Keaton.
Rym: I got a someday dreamers.
Scott: I would have gotten three DVDs of crying Freeman, but they didn't have DVD number two.
Scott: So I only got DVD number one and I let DVD number three just sit there.
Rym: I got a bunch of random Lupin.
Rym: I almost bought all of MIDI got it many goddess But I wasn't sure if it was five dollars per DVD in the set or five dollars for the set And I think anything that was packaged on its own was five bucks.
Rym: The reason I was Larry's that I also saw many goddess DVDs separately.
Rym: Oh and like it was too crowded to ask the guy and I was gonna go back and ask later when there was no one Around but I never had time for that.
Rym: So I didn't get it yet.
Scott: Nay under seven five bucks a DVD.
Scott: Yep Hi, Bonnie Renmei five bucks a DVD.
Rym: Yep So I bought basically the first episode of everything I could grab because I love owning the first episodes of things.
Rym: Yep, well the first DVD.
Scott: what else do they have there?
Scott: Lots of old robot shows.
Scott: I bought kitchen core if you don't know about kitchen core Aka geo armor in the United States, but it's kitchen core.
Scott: Fuck you That is a fucking awesome show and you should get it.
Scott: It comes in just one little box.
Scott: I think there's two or three DVDs in it with the whole show maybe six episodes.
Scott: I think it is freaking awesome steam powered Nazi fighting robot action.
Scott: it is worth every penny five bucks.
Scott: It's like I was robbing the guy.
Rym: Yeah, every DVD I picked up.
Rym: I thought I don't really want this but it's only five bucks.
Scott: But yeah, so dealers room.
Scott: Surprisingly jaded old men who don't care about dealers rooms found that to be one of the highlights of the con.
Rym: Also, I'll note that there was a lot of Death Note merchandise in the dealers room.
Scott: Oh, was there ever I expect by Otakon?
Rym: It's just gonna be a sea of Death Notes and people dressed up as Misa.
Rym: Misa.
Scott: now Gotta watch out for those.
Scott: are you cosplays?
Rym: That's the action is the first one I see.
Rym: I'm gonna interview him.
Scott: Yeah, how long did it take you to make this?
Scott: You're awesome.
Scott: Wow, that's awesome.
Rym: In fact, I should carry.
Scott: how awesome are you?
Scott: All right.
Scott: Let's see.
Scott: I'll give you $1 if this costume also does the upside down e inside out e and the twisty and the twisty Alright.
Rym: now anyway aside from that we went to some of the panels now.
Rym: We didn't go to many just because you know, we're only there one day and we didn't have that much time.
Rym: But there was a panel.
Rym: Oh, we want a revolution now.
Scott: the reason I went to this panel is because the guy on the panel was a fellow podcaster named Ian Levenstein and he does a Podcast called geek speak.
Scott: I think his website.
Scott: I'm not a hundred percent sure is geek.
Scott: speak geek Dot-com or speak geek speak.
Rym: Oh great.
Rym: That's helpful.
Scott: No, I think it's speak geek speak dot-com speaking geeky.
Scott: But geeky, let me try it.
Scott: You can just keep talking about the panel while I type in his URL.
Rym: Yeah Well, it was just.
Rym: I don't know why this panel existed.
Rym: I mean no offense to the guy but it was just him talking about the Wii and what bothered me and this.
Rym: Things like this bother me.
Rym: It bothers me when there is someone who isn't an authority and isn't even pretending to be an authority But because they're behind the magic table of being a panelist or a staffer as opposed to a con goer Everyone who isn't on that side of the table Assumes that they're an expert and treats them as though they're like this deferred to authority figure.
Rym: Yes Well, we're asking him questions that there's no way he could have known the answer to and he was just making it all up.
Scott: The other thing is he doesn't know any more than we do.
Scott: In fact, we knew more than he did because we read the internet a lot more than he does.
Rym: We had to call it like we wouldn't talk to him after and he was cool but we had to call him out and point out that he had.
Rym: they had two examples of you know, Sony's missteps with HD and blu-ray and everything and the two examples that they talked about were both Completely debunked and disproven by the internet hours after being reported.
Scott: Yep His website is speak geek speak calm and he does some podcasts.
Rym: Yeah, we're just busting his balls because of the panel he did he seems like a cool guy.
Scott: Yeah, he is.
Scott: He is a pretty cool guy and his podcasts aren't so bad.
Scott: He even had a nice rant on one of his recent podcasts even though I forget the topic of the rant.
Scott: Oh I think it was the.
Scott: it was a rant about how people just dismiss all manga as a genre as opposed to a Medium.
Rym: that's a good rant.
Scott: Yeah, it was a pretty good rant.
Rym: now There was a panel we wanted to go to but didn't just because it was late at night.
Rym: bad anime bad.
Scott: I've seen that panel listed in a lot of Con schedules, but I'd never gone to.
Scott: it is if anyone out there has been to a bad anime bad panel Tell me about it.
Scott: Tell me if it's worth going to because again anime world order has made it Unnecessary to check out.
Rym: bad anime God I still it's like it's gnawing at my brain that I have to see the unedited version of that.
Rym: now.
Scott: No, you don't know I have to bad Rym bad.
Rym: I've gotta know.
Rym: Okay, it's the end.
Rym: I'll see it and then I'll kill myself and that'll be the end of it.
Scott: Yep, the cosplay we didn't go to but it actually looked like there was some good stuff going on.
Rym: We walked in at the back and peeked in it in the middle of one of the most elaborate cosplays I've ever seen.
Rym: Yeah, it was like this choreographed Utena set to music thing and the costumes were really good and I didn't know what was going on because I missed the beginning of It but it was cool looking it.
Scott: usually choreographed fight cosplays are terrible.
Scott: They're the worst cosplays imaginable But this one actually wasn't so bad Like I was like, oh, all right.
Scott: Good job That was that was.
Scott: see that should be the gold standard for the average cosplay.
Scott: if you go to a cosplay at a con Every cosplay should be at least that good and then the winners should be even better.
Scott: if it was like that I would go to every cosplay ever.
Scott: The problem is most cosplays are far far worse than that one.
Rym: Yep, though we have friends who do good cosplays and there are good cosplays out there.
Scott: There are good cosplays do exist, but the most cosplays do not good.
Scott: Yeah English lose Unpossible.
Scott: be.
Rym: do at least with Otakon this year because the cosplay is going to be in the arena.
Rym: I think they're gonna mitigate a lot of the line problems.
Rym: So it might be more worth it for people who we would normally say ask if the cosplay to go check it out.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: It's still.
Scott: it's both appealing to me to go to the cosplay in the arena, which will be insane But it's also appealing to hang out in the convention center while it's empty because everyone else is at the cosplay.
Scott: Now they're actually on Saturday night, which is happening.
Rym: I'll also just note and anime next which seems to be a trend this year and all the cons I've been to so far.
Rym: there has been a significantly increased furry and plushie presence.
Scott: Super doll fee presents a lot of time presence.
Rym: Yeah, but yeah, we hentai has been on the rise for a while.
Rym: I've expected it.
Rym: I haven't expected furries to explode so suddenly into con culture it the whole perverted Aspect of the con.
Rym: right now I'm looking at one page of the panels anime next and half of them are hentai panels or here's one the pervy plushie Workshop.
Rym: that can be nothing but horror.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Now.
Scott: Here's the thing that gets me is back in the early cons I went to like the first couple years of going to cons.
Scott: the cons had a hentai panel.
Scott: They had people who liked hentai.
Scott: They had a hentai showing possibly But everything that was like that was sort of in the back.
Scott: it was toned down.
Scott: it was not the focus.
Scott: It was you know, it was pushed away hidden like yes, we do this But we don't like to talk about it as it should be now nowadays.
Scott: It's the forefront.
Scott: They push it out in the open like come on to the hentai.
Scott: We're having a yuri con a yaoi con a furry con.
Scott: Don't let's all be perverted.
Rym: Oh Scott furry cons are old and Steeped in tradition.
Scott: Yes, but I'm saying now the anime cons are leaning more towards the furry cons the yaoi cons.
Rym: I think what it is and I'd love to do a whole show on this is that of all the geek fandoms It seems that anime is the most universal of the most rod spread or it has the most overlap with all of the other geek.
Rym: So if you go to a gaming con, it's pretty much all gamers go to a comic con.
Rym: It's all comic people go to an anime con con.
Rym: It's gamers and comic people and anime people.
Scott: It's because there's the manga which tracks taps to the comics.
Scott: There's the anime which taps to the video games.
Scott: There's the anime.
Scott: there's the anime that taps to Japan which taps to anything Japanese, which includes video games and live-action cinema.
Rym: There's also the furries who just go because there's a whole bunch of geeks.
Scott: and there's sci-fi anime which taps to real sci-fi.
Scott: It taps into every geekery.
Scott: Other geekeries don't do that as well as anime does, you know I just I can't stop looking at.
Rym: there's two plush workshops and I'm not gonna explain what plushies are But they're a little bit more sinister than just stuffed animals.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Now the thing is is that The anime cons most of the attendees are hormone enraged Attention whoring high school kids.
Rym: Why couldn't these cons have been around when I was a hormone raging kid exactly hot?
Scott: So now old men go to these things and all they see is a bunch of really horny teenagers running around being pervert.
Scott: Now I'm not gonna say they shouldn't do that because that's what I would have done when I was a kid.
Rym: Yeah, plus the thing is when I go to a con and I see that I don't think damn kids I think yeah, those kids look like they're having a lot of fun and they're not in my way.
Scott: Yeah, as long as they stay out of my way, you know The worst that they can do to me is make me cringe if I see them do something terrible.
Scott: But even then I think yeah, that's something I would have done Yeah, but I also cringe to think oh, that's something I would have done.
Rym: You were once a kid running around.
Scott: that is true, but think about this.
Scott: I was once a kid doing all the same stupid things But if I could travel back in time, I would prevent myself from doing every one of those stupid things.
Scott: Teach myself straight.
Rym: I tell myself to do more stupid things.
Rym: the I don't regret anything in my life But there are.
Scott: I don't regret anything at all But there are a lot.
Scott: it would be so much more awesome.
Scott: Imagine if I was as awesome as I am now and I was three.
Scott: Yeah fear that fear that shit.
Rym: See I would go back in time and tell myself to do a lot of the stupid things that I realized were stupid and didn't Do because by doing them I'd have more stories.
Rym: today.
Scott: I guess I would you know be doing a different set of stupid things and perhaps a lot of Awesome things.
Scott: instead of stupid thing.
Rym: I missed out on a lot of things that were probably would have been really stupid to do But at the same time they probably would have ended up being awesome or I would have died.
Rym: It would have died.
Rym: Yeah, I would have been stranded like I don't know in Alabama with no money in my cars missing.
Scott: Let's talk a little bit more about anime next.
Scott: the thing about anime next that I think is its best Feature and its worst problem is that it's too big for its location And I think they know this because it's one of the questions on their survey.
Rym: Yeah I mean It's pretty much as big as it can be where it is and there's nowhere to move to.
Scott: yes the meadowlands area Plaza place which is not you know giant stadium and the continent Airlines arena.
Scott: It's down the road from that It.
Scott: there's a little Expo Center there, which they use the entirety of.
Scott: there is a Embassy Suites Hotel in which they use I think three rooms and There is a Holiday Inn in which they use the whole mess of rooms.
Scott: They had the video games over there and all that.
Scott: The problem with that is that if the weather was bad walking from building to building would have been a nightmare.
Rym: Luckily, the weather was nice and there was a lot of cool hanging out outside.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: There was basically outside.
Scott: This is an outside con which is very interesting and unique in that, you know, people only went inside to do con events.
Scott: You only went in the Holiday Inn to play video games.
Scott: You only went in, you know, the embassy to do a panel.
Scott: You only went in the main con center to go to the dealer's room or a main event.
Scott: other than that you hung out outside where there was lots of cosplaying and Lots of DS playing and art drawing and all sorts of con hanging out.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Once again a quick aside just to continually Rub it in the faces of PSP people because we can and we know you'll yell at us in the forum Someone PSP, I think yeah, one guy was carrying.
Rym: He wasn't playing it.
Rym: We've never seen anyone playing a PSP in public, but he was carrying it around open-lit Like to show people he had it.
Scott: meanwhile up in the video game hallway There were so many DS's that the wireless went down and we had to split up and form separate land parties and we went outside Into the grass and had us a good old time playing Mario Kart and Tetris.
Rym: Yep We played some hellish Mario Kart and some awesome Tetris that we did Proved all these young punk kids that I am the supreme almighty god of Mario Kart and I did pretty good in Tetris.
Scott: But I think this one kid was actually better than me.
Rym: He was really good because I died early in one round and I was watching him.
Scott: I did win a whole bunch of rounds.
Rym: you did you did Okay But he was the only one there who probably Could have at least broken even with you given enough time.
Scott: and as of any group of punk kids most of them are annoying and There's always one smart kid Who is you know reasonable social skills and it seems like a normal person.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I forget all their names, but whatever They're just punk kids.
Rym: They might be listening.
Rym: We gave him GeekNights flyers.
Scott: Oh, did we?
Scott: Yeah Hey punk kids who played DS on the lawn with us.
Scott: One of you doesn't suck?
Rym: Yeah, you should all join to figure out who.
Scott: yes That is that is what you should do.
Scott: You should come to Otakon and meet us and I remember Kind of what the one who doesn't suck looks like.
Rym: so I can point him out, but there were so many DS's.
Rym: I mean we were sitting in that we panel which no offense dude, but it was kind of boring as hell.
Rym: so we were picked out chatting and There are all these people out who were in the panel picked out chatting with us who were like this sucks and they left.
Scott: well one Person was in the panel picked out chatting with us and one person was in the cosplay line picked out chatting with us.
Rym: And then one guy left the panel to go get in the cosplay line Because he didn't like the panel and he kept picked out chatting and he was like, come on You should leave join us join us in line.
Scott: and I said, uh, no, I don't want to see the cosplay.
Rym: Yeah Not a big fan of the cosplay And I mean other than that the con was just a normal good con.
Rym: I definitely recommend anyone who lives within a couple hours at least go for Saturday.
Scott: Yeah, if you live see that's the problem.
Scott: It seems to be with cons if they're far away You can get a hotel and go to the get the full experience.
Scott: But if you live close by But not so close by you can drive back and forth Like if you don't live.
Scott: if you live within a half hour, you can drive back and forth like two or three times a day But if you live more than an hour away, it's not worth it to drive back and forth Friday Saturday Sunday But it's also not worth it to get a hotel because you're so close so you can only really go for one day.
Rym: Well, it's like my good friend Nuri when I went to an amazement and you know staff and all that there Despite the fact that she lives somewhat like really close to the con She had a hotel room that we all stayed in because it wasn't worth it to drive back and forth.
Scott: Yeah, well if your staff and you have to stay all three days, you know.
Scott: Then you got to get the hotel room to make it easy and convenient.
Scott: Yeah, but I imagine if she wasn't staff and you were just attending that con we still would add hotel room Depends how cheap the hotel is.
Scott: if the hotel is really cheap dude.
Rym: It's not New York City or Baltimore.
Rym: hotels are cheap as dirt in most of the world.
Scott: You like that one.
Scott: We stayed in when we went to RIT.
Rym: Oh my god, that was the second cheapest hotel.
Rym: I've ever stayed in.
Rym: and the actually nowhere near the crappiest.
Scott: No, no, it's probably the third or fourth worst hotel.
Scott: I've stayed in.
Rym: I stayed at a family in Somewhere in West Virginia.
Scott: I stayed at the Paramount Hotel.
Scott: I'll take you to the Paramount Hotel sometime when we go down Route 17.
Rym: I just want to note that this family Inn in West Virginia was the scuzziest place I have ever slept in my life and I have slept on the streets of New York City.
Scott: I'll show you the Paramount Hotel next time we go down Route 17.
Scott: The Paramount is something I could do a whole geek fable episode about the Paramount.
Scott: Seriously, I stayed there many times.
Scott: Don't ask why.
Rym: all right, what else did we do at anime?
Rym: next we met the uber con staff Which I think we're gonna try to either do a live show at one or both of the uber cons and more importantly We're definitely gonna be running some games at these cons.
Scott: If you go to uber con we will be running German board games all day and playing burning wheel all night.
Scott: Yes That's what we're gonna be doing.
Rym: that's pretty much it.
Scott: maybe doing a panel yeah, maybe doing a podcast panel.
Scott: We met the game station radio.
Scott: guys were aggressively marketing their podcast.
Scott: I listened to it and It was okay.
Scott: You can go listen to it.
Scott: See if you like it.
Scott: It's a. it's a video game podcast.
Rym: Yeah, no, they were marketing.
Rym: I mean, we don't.
Rym: we really are uncomfortable promoting ourselves.
Scott: It's weird like we made because we hate advertisers so much that becoming a salesman becoming a pusher.
Scott: You know, we were complaining about pushers at Wizard World Philly.
Scott: we can't be a pusher.
Rym: I mean I can sell like I could sell something to one person.
Scott: Yeah, like if I had a job, you know in a Best Buy selling computer parts, I could do that.
Rym: well, even like I you know I do this panelists and staff on all these cons and I've gotten into all these positions everywhere and I every time I interview for Jobs in the IT world.
Rym: I always get him It's I'm really good at selling myself and selling things I do to people as long as it's on a one-on-one basis and I'm talking to someone.
Rym: I don't feel comfortable Advertising to mass audiences.
Scott: You're just walking around saying listen to me.
Scott: Listen to me.
Scott: Listen to me feels like you're a spammer.
Rym: Yeah, I feel like a whore.
Rym: now these guys were just handing out their flyers and we wouldn't do that like we would like hand a flyer to one guy after We talked to him for a while.
Scott: or you leave them on a table and let people take them as they would.
Scott: Yep, and These guys they gave us their flyer like three times because we ran into them.
Rym: the third time I was like, dude, you've already given us - he's like, oh, yep Oh Well, there were some other podcast.
Rym: Yeah otaku generation.
Scott: Yeah, they had a big panel there and they had lots of fancy equipment and I listened to part of one of their episodes.
Scott: You can go listen to that one for yourself, too.
Rym: I like how you're.
Rym: you're not passing your judgment But if this is we're already at war with one podcast.
Scott: those stupid moon masters You know those those sons of bitch moon masters were at war with the you know, those coast retards.
Rym: Well, I heard what they did.
Scott: I don't have any resources to go fight with any other podcast if we can't fight a war on two fronts.
Rym: Yeah, well, you know what?
Rym: I at least otaku generation.
Rym: They uh, they kicked my dog.
Scott: They kicked my dog My dog.
Rym: that's like the oldest thing.
Rym: Well, I'll kick my dog but we went in and talked to him.
Rym: We didn't really get a chance to stay for their panel because we had to go eat steak Steak at the Outback.
Scott: Yep, where do we?
Scott: lunch meat lunch at the cheeseburger something the place with the steel drum cheeseburger paradise.
Rym: We were so excited.
Rym: We're sitting there eating and then this guy comes out and sets up steel drums.
Rym: It looks like he's gonna do some awesome steel drumming.
Scott: I love me some steel drumming.
Scott: I'm gonna go download some on YouTube and and You know Pirate Bay and all that his steel drumming was pretty mad and it ended up just being real annoying.
Rym: Yeah, his steel drumming was mediocre at best But I gotta say the Outback will not cook steaks as rare as I want them.
Rym: Nope I was like give it to me as rare as you can and it was.
Rym: it was cooked at least three times as long as I wanted it to be cooked.
Scott: Yeah, anyway Is an interesting side note while we were sitting in cheeseburger paradise eating our amazing lunches there on the TVs was the World Cup, which is relatively interesting and some boxing which is you know boxing.
Scott: and then we got into a discussion about Mike Tyson and I think we're gonna have to talk about Mike Tyson in the future.
Rym: I think we're gonna do a whole Thursday show at some point on Mike Tyson.
Scott: really a whole Thursday on Mike Tyson.
Rym: You know what I could do a whole Thursday on Mike Tyson.
Scott: All right, maybe we should.
Scott: Especially I bet you there hasn't been a podcast ever about Mike Tyson.
Rym: Yeah, unless maybe for a second I thought I wonder if we could get him on the show and the answer was no You don't want him on the show.
Scott: No, definitely not.
Scott: but he might have been mentioned on a sports podcast at some point You know in passing or he might have been.
Scott: Mike Tyson's punch-out was probably mentioned on a video game podcast But I don't think anyone's ever done like an annotated biography of Mike Tyson in a podcast.
Rym: in the very least We'll make a thing of the day a video of him fighting.
Scott: Yes all I can say now is that after watching Mike Tyson fighting on YouTube and some other YouTube videos of Mike Tyson and reading Mike Tyson's Wikipedia while he is a horrible horrible man, I now view him in a different light and Respect some aspects of his life.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: I mean to his credit.
Rym: I really think that a lot of the problems he had and the things he did were very much a result of the culture and The way he lived.
Rym: I mean he'd lived by beating people up and getting beat up and that didn't affect his brain so well.
Rym: in addition His childhood wasn't so great and a lot of people even when he was a professional took a lot of advantage of him because he Really didn't know.
Rym: Yep, and not to excuse the things he did.
Scott: No, no That's the last thing we're gonna do.
Scott: but you know the thing that I like it's like with Hitler.
Rym: I don't like what Hitler did but I understand why he did it.
Scott: Yep The thing I learned most about Mike Tyson and respect the most is the fact that he knew he was bad and stupid.
Scott: He knew it.
Scott: He you know, he was sitting there saying I'm a convicted rapist.
Scott: I'm a terrible guy, you know I'm not an eloquent man.
Scott: What do you want from me?
Scott: And I was like, huh?
Scott: At least he knows.
Scott: at least he you know He has balls to admit it.
Scott: and I realized if I was ever famous like that I would probably have to deal with some of the things he deals with because I'm too brutally honest and too open and Most famous people put up this fake thing and Mike Tyson doesn't do that and it for that one thing He's I guess better than Complete shit.
Scott: It's better than Hitler at least.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway to get off that tangent Mike Tyson anime anime anime.
Scott: next Mike Tyson.
Rym: I don't know what else we can say about anime next but if any of the staff are listening because We've found that most of the cons we go to all the staff either listen or end up listening Which seemed to start with Katsu Kahn, but you guys put on a really good con And I hope you find a way to deal with your space problem.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: The con was run very well.
Scott: There was no problems with the running of the con.
Scott: registration was smooth.
Scott: staff were courteous.
Rym: There was one problem.
Rym: Actually, I want to talk about this.
Rym: Okay, we went upstairs to the gaming room because we wanted to play some games.
Scott: You are correct.
Scott: There was one problem.
Rym: The room smelled like horrible fanboy like I gagged.
Scott: This is the board gaming room not the video gaming room.
Rym: now also in the video gaming room They had two video game rooms.
Rym: One of them was a normal video game room.
Rym: the other room which was almost as big as the first room Was just a DDR machine and the air conditioning was turned on max.
Rym: They are geniuses.
Rym: There was no smell.
Scott: There was no smell that the room was filled with people.
Scott: There was one DER machine.
Scott: There was a crazy air conditioner.
Scott: There's nothing else in the room, but DDR and it was perfect.
Rym: But the board gaming room smelled like a fanboy who had never seen a bar of soap.
Scott: Yet when he returned hours later, the smell was gone.
Scott: There was a warning sign on the door.
Scott: The room was crowded full of people.
Scott: gaming There was and there were.
Scott: there was many Lysol's and for breezes.
Rym: Yep So either that I think they just kicked the dude out who smelled like an open asshole.
Scott: I think they must have.
Scott: there's no other explanation for it.
Rym: Yeah, I really that's the one thing.
Rym: I think all conventions to take a very strong stance on that because people who don't engage in basic human hygiene Really give anime fandom and well more so gaming fandom a bad name.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Now I think you have the freedom to not bathe.
Scott: Do you have the freedom to smell as bad as you want?
Scott: But as soon as you set your stink into my nose you have how they say Had you know, they're right to swing your fist ends in my face if your smell gets in my nose that's in my face.
Rym: No Yeah You can make the argument that what if someone puts on too much cologne?
Rym: or what if you just don't like their cologne or so?
Rym: Really?
Rym: My point is more that a convention is fully within its right to kick you out if you don't wash yourself.
Scott: Oh hells Yes Convention is has the right to kick you out for any reason whatsoever.
Scott: They can kick you out because they don't like that.
Scott: Look at you.
Rym: I like to say right now at any conventions that don't feel like to have the Moxie the Cajones, well, it's not so much conventions.
Scott: any conventions which has them as a whole has the moxie and the hutzpah to kick people out.
Scott: It's the individual staffers of the convention.
Scott: I'll tell you all right I've never seen a con guide that doesn't say we can kick your ass out.
Rym: I've done it.
Rym: and our anime club at RIT.
Rym: We kicked people out who smelled.
Rym: Yeah in no uncertain terms.
Rym: and Anime anime net era.
Rym: god an amazement.
Rym: all these cons start with anime So I keep mixing them up.
Rym: I Mentioned to a few people that perhaps they should go take a shower Mm-hmm where they DDR players or obese people, uh, you know, they weren't obese.
Rym: They were punk kids.
Rym: They had been doing something and I'm not sure what.
Rym: oh Okay, I don't know if they were playing games or running around or what but they smell bad bad bad smell bad very bad.
Scott: Okay Can we go to bed now?
Rym: I had to go to the city tomorrow, yeah, I got to do post-production on this bastard.
Rym: now Once again, we would have had Jim Vowles.
Rym: We're sorry.
Scott: We didn't sorry to Jim Vowles.
Scott: He wasted his time.
Rym: He's an awesome guy.
Rym: we're giving the middle finger to Apple for wasting our time and Jim Vowles time and We'll do everything we can to have an interview with him either in the very near future or after Otakon.
Rym: Suffice yourself by going to our forums and reading the interview.
Rym: We already did with him which will comment on next Wednesday if we don't have the actual live interview with him because I like to comment on that interview, but not right now.
Scott: Yep, I'm gonna.
Scott: we should make a post that says there won't be an episode Thursday or something.
Scott: Or maybe we should make a little tiny mp3 saying sorry no episode Thursday and put it in the Thursday feed tomorrow.
Rym: Yeah, we can just do it Thursday when we get home.
Scott: That's too late around midnight.
Rym: I put up the episode later than midnight before.
Rym: in fact, I'm gonna put it up it's midnight now.
Scott: All right.
Scott: I'm going to bed.
Scott: I had to wake up real early.
Rym: Yeah, great.
Rym: So do I awesome.
Rym: I got a meeting with the CEO of my company tomorrow Awesome, and then we're going to that concert.
Scott: awesome.
Rym: All right, we're out.
Rym: We're glad we have all your new listeners.
Rym: We're sorry didn't have Jim Vowles and Anime next was awesome.
Rym: And that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 15 37.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is accorded with absolutely no studio and no audience But unlike those other talk shows it's actually recorded at night.