Scott: It's Monday February 20th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Scott: We do a roundup of tech news.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: so I just got back from Katsucon and I'm not gonna talk a bunch about it today because it doesn't really fit into side tech and we're really trying to keep on topic for each of the different days a little bit
Scott: especially when we Start doing the separate feeds and people's might start heavily subscribing to them.
Scott: We don't want to like have people subscribing to this expecting video games all the time.
Scott: And then oh we talked about anime that day because we were whatever on a whim and then they'll be kind of disappointed.
Rym: Well that and Katsucon was freaking fantastic.
Rym: I mean it was an amazing con at a wonderful awesome crazy time.
Rym: I have at least three or four full podcasts to talk about worth of content from this con.
Scott: if I really wanted to I don't Think we're gonna give you three or four podcasts to talk about.
Scott: well
Rym: But I'm doing a full con report on Wednesday anime day And I'm going to talk a lot about the video gaming that happened at Katsucon tomorrow
Scott: Mm-hmm
Rym: and Various other things and I would have kind of wanted to talk about more right now But I'm gonna be strangely silent through most of this podcast at least as silent as I can make myself be Mostly due to the fact that I caught some sort of throat infection at Katsucon,
Scott: so it wasn't Perfect
Rym: and it well it was perfect because this didn't affect me until after the con But it's actually painful for me to talk right now.
Rym: I didn't even go to work today.
Scott: well, we'll see what happens because Next week is the New York Comic Con.
Rym: Yeah, so All right, so you had something today.
Rym: well for the weekend while I was out of town.
Scott: Oh a lot of shit happened over the weekend.
Scott: We were out of town But most of it was just me getting my personal affairs in order or more in order than I had them before And I finished that today by getting my car inspected which past inspection being a brand new car.
Rym: No yeah, I'm not surprised.
Scott: Yeah, so um another thing happened is this podcast I listened to which It's.
Scott: it's actually scarily popular.
Scott: It's comic geek speak, and it's all about comic books and whatever and You know actually their forums are really awesome a lot more awesome than ours, so That's mainly because they have a bunch of people there.
Scott: I wish we had that many people.
Rym: Yeah, though don't don't take that the wrong way.
Rym: the people who are on our forums now are awesome.
Scott: Oh, yeah, the thing is it's like What their forums are is like our forums if they were big?
Scott: That's why I want more people in our forum because we know you're all listening.
Rym: I can see you in feed burner, but you're not in the forums.
Scott: Yeah, they're awesome.
Scott: So whatever Yeah, but you get to the forums.
Scott: is front row crew comm slash forum?
Rym: Yeah, or click on the forum link at front row crew calm which will be bigger once I change the theme to the new theme.
Scott: I'm working on that.
Scott: I'm almost done with yep.
Rym: He showed me a lot of that.
Rym: he'd gotten done over the weekend when I got back from the con And I think you're really gonna like it.
Scott: Yeah, it looks like the forum.
Scott: You want to know what it's gonna look like.
Scott: look at the farm.
Scott: All right, it's enough of that.
Scott: So what happened was is my signature in their forum says, you know, listen to GeekNights.
Scott: We have over 50 episodes.
Scott: We're awesome Whatever.
Rym: Yeah, this is episode 61.
Scott: Yeah And my screen name there as Everywhere else is a PR ECHE.
Rym: Yeah, it's weird Like my screen name is basically Rym But it's also the name I use in the real world like everyone in the world calls me Rym Except for old relatives who don't really know better and a couple people at work.
Rym: Yeah, don't that's a long story.
Scott: Don't anyway, that's been my screen name online for Almost ten years at least nine years probably ten I don't even know and it's I'm the only one who uses it as far as I know and It's me if you see that name somewhere.
Scott: It's me.
Scott: The thing is is until podcasting It's never been pronounced and I'm gonna spare you the story of where it came from.
Scott: You can read all about that like in my about page on my blog or something I don't know what somewhere or if we ever do our origin story podcast.
Scott: Yeah, it's somewhere on my blog somewhere.
Rym: He was bit by a radioactive spider.
Scott: Yep, and then all of a sudden my screen name appeared before my eyes in my you know radioactive Hallucination haze.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway anyway, so they The cool guys in the comic podcast we're doing some casual shoutouts to other podcasts and they shout it out to us Which was nice because they didn't have to do that.
Scott: I didn't ask them to you know They're cool, and I figured I was you know, kind of an asshole in their forms, but I'm kind of an asshole kind of an asshole everywhere.
Scott: Yeah, I Really wasn't that big an asshole.
Scott: most of my ass oneness was when they were talking about like the big comic Crossovers and all the things they like so much.
Rym: I'm like those things all suck because they do But it's got real good at that sort of thing.
Rym: Yeah, if you guys ever meet him in person I mean, we're all good friends, but Scott's an asshole.
Scott: Yeah, you're an asshole, too.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I'm just different kind of asshole.
Rym: Yeah, the goatee can okay Yeah, yeah, so Why are we so silly today?
Scott: I don't know but I'm gonna finish this story real quick.
Rym: Don't worry I swear to all you guys.
Rym: once the thing of the day music comes in we're gonna straighten ourselves up That's for sure and just do the show, okay Really?
Scott: Yeah, really, but six so Because it's a podcast and I'm no longer You know just typing things they had to.
Scott: this is like the third time they've had to do this because I've sent them email before And stuff.
Scott: they've tried to pronounce my screen name.
Scott: They had to say it and it's never really been said.
Scott: and I really never said it because it's an online Text name.
Rym: now the first time I saw it which was when we were freshmen at RIT.
Rym: God what four five six seven years ago six years ago six years ago seven who knows a long time going on.
Scott: seven.
Scott: See when it comes to uh, it'll be seven in like September.
Rym: I think God I feel old.
Rym: Anyway, when it comes to any sort of like online communication I am basically J Edgar Hoover and I have logs and transcripts of every I am Conversation I've had going all the way back to when I got ICQ in 1996 and I'm Richard Nixon.
Scott: I go looking in his logs to find scary things.
Rym: So I remember way back anyway when he messaged me and he asked me like.
Rym: he said like he was the guy from this gaming Club we've gotten together with and then I saw his screen name was a presh and I just assumed it was pronounced a presh The first time I saw it.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Well, it seems that I never really decided how it should be pronounced and They couldn't seem to figure it out either.
Scott: Like I was hoping really hoping that they would come up with some pronunciation and just be like, yep That's it.
Scott: So then I would say, okay, whatever they said is it?
Scott: but they seem to have some trouble just as I do.
Rym: I don't see the trouble.
Rym: It's a presh.
Scott: Oh, okay, whatever.
Rym: I mean what a preshy.
Scott: Who knows it's.
Scott: it's up to a preach.
Scott: a I don't know.
Scott: fate fate I Is good.
Scott: What would they?
Scott: let's see phonic phonetically it would be Prey.
Rym: It'd be a presh probably because that you would most.
Rym: it'd be a preach.
Rym: actually maybe maybe I don't know.
Scott: So I started a thread on their forum entitled pronounce my name.
Scott: Let's see, this guy says it should be appreciate without the eight.
Scott: so that would be appreciate.
Rym: this person says Appreciate I'll preach it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Um, this guy says sounds like aftershave.
Scott: What I don't know.
Scott: I appreciate I appreciate a preachy.
Scott: Let's see this guy just posted a picture of the prince thing.
Scott: The next guy says I didn't know.
Scott: Appreciate whatever was pronounced as.
Scott: hey What wacky stuff can I do to get out of my incredibly shitty record contract and get lots of PR in the process?
Scott: That was in response to the prince logo.
Scott: Yeah, I figured this guy says I always thought it was a presh.
Rym: See, that's not me though.
Scott: It's pronounced a fur.
Rym: You know what I think what we're gonna have to do is have some sort of pole on the site of how to pronounce it and bind Ourselves to whatever the result.
Scott: no our forum doesn't really have poles.
Scott: I should implement that or get a plug-in.
Scott: this guy It's a the person who said opera che.
Scott: he posted a thumbs up under that and this one says a prey Shay.
Scott: Hmm, I don't know.
Scott: We need to come to some sort of consensus.
Rym: Yeah, now that it really matters.
Rym: I mean on the show your notice Scott.
Scott: Yeah, that there's a reason for that and this is part of that.
Scott: Plus there was a Forget it.
Scott: What were you gonna say?
Scott: I was talking about another podcast where they started out using their online names and they gave up and use their real names.
Rym: See, we're kind of.
Rym: it's weird because you tell a lot of people think that Rym is an online name But it's not.
Rym: I go by that in the real world.
Scott: - yeah, Brandon.
Scott: Yeah named Brandon.
Scott: Yeah, his real name is Brandon.
Scott: Oh my god, call him Brandon.
Scott: Really care the money.
Rym: I mean the only weird thing is there was one guy at RIT who found out my name was Brandon And started calling me that and I didn't notice like.
Rym: I didn't notice but I don't like.
Rym: if someone says Brandon I'm not paying attention.
Rym: I won't look up.
Rym: I don't even really respond to it anymore.
Scott: Yeah, but yeah, it's like sometimes people like hey Scott, what's your middle name?
Scott: And I'm like Lloyd because my mom had this thing with Frank Lloyd Wright.
Scott: So she was like Scott Lloyd Rubin.
Scott: Frank Lloyd, right?
Scott: You know, uh-huh.
Scott: So when I tell that to people they're like, okay Lloyd Lloyd Lloyd Lloyd, and then I'm like, I don't care And then they give up.
Scott: yeah, I mean those people call me Ruben but whatever I don't care about that either.
Rym: Yeah, well in high school, I mean some people called me room.
Rym: Some people called me to cost her.
Rym: Yeah, the thing is I thought it was weird cuz one time I call you Thomas.
Scott: Yeah Hey Tom, what's up?
Rym: See actually was weird.
Rym: but one time in high school senior year after we'd all graduated me and a bunch of friends are sitting around and We've got a bonfire out in the woods and we're just kind of sitting around, you know reminiscing learn a nation.
Rym: This is the end of high school.
Rym: We're all gonna go on with our lives and whatever You know the thing that high school kids do before they actually leave their hometown and go to college.
Rym: None of them I'll note none of the people I've been talking about now actually graduated college.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: I think you know what I did after high school before I went to college what I went to Israel Mm-hmm.
Scott: I didn't sit around no bonfire in the woods.
Scott: Well, I guess I think we might have done that at one point, but it was a desert not a woods.
Rym: But we were talking about names and it and it came up that half the people I knew called me decoster and the other I've called me Rym and Basically, we came to the conclusion that decoster was just a real good call a guy by that name name Like it.
Rym: just it felt right.
Rym: So people just called me that a lot.
Rym: Mm-hmm Alright, yeah, I wasn't really going anywhere with that.
Scott: Yeah, all my names work.
Scott: I don't think people like saying Lloyd and I don't think people like saying my screen name either.
Scott: Yeah, I don't even like saying it's not pleasant it doesn't roll off the tongue, yeah, so yeah I think we'll stick with.
Scott: it's a real toothy word.
Rym: Yeah, it's not gonna be GeekNights with Rym and opera che that's for sure.
Rym: Alright that music means that it's both things of the day and that we're not gonna be silly anymore for the rest of the show Tonight, of course, that doesn't mean our things of the day aren't silly.
Rym: Yeah, so remember way back I think it was Scott's thing of the day.
Rym: It was a trailer video with voices to Phoenix, right?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Did we do that?
Scott: I remember we did the one where you type in words and then Phoenix Wright says them.
Scott: I don't know if we actually did the one.
Rym: this wasn't a thing of the day then.
Rym: it was definitely something we talked about in The pre broadcast episodes.
Rym: Yeah, because we did talk about it on the show.
Scott: basically, there was a flash video that was supposed to be a Preview of what Phoenix Wright gameplay was gonna look like it was from the Tokyo game show.
Scott: So if you went to the Tokyo game show to the Capcom booth and looked at the Phoenix Wright display This is the video you saw telling you all about how awesome Phoenix Wright DS was going to be.
Rym: well, someone has translated it and here it is fully translated.
Rym: and My favorite part is when it turns out like they're arguing about the DS and the PS or not the PSP the Game Boy Advance and the Game Boy SP and the Edgeworth.
Rym: the prosecuting Attorney doesn't have a DS and everyone else does and then like he's yell something to the judge and the judge looks up and he's like I've got one.
Rym: In fact, I'm playing it right now.
Rym: Yeah, like during the trial.
Scott: and then they're like Edgeworth.
Scott: You have to go and get one right after this trial is over and it's like like I have any choice.
Rym: It's hilarious.
Rym: Watch it.
Rym: Yeah, and buy the game if you can find it.
Scott: if you can find Phoenix Wright Freaking get it.
Rym: It's going for 50 60 bucks on eBay.
Rym: Yeah, it's hard to find.
Scott: I got some more news on Phoenix Wright tomorrow.
Scott: So we'll hold off.
Scott: All right, my thing of the day.
Scott: You might have seen in the past the old cliched, you know, what was it?
Scott: I attacked the darkness.
Scott: I cast magic missile, you know, if you don't know what that is You're lost at the internet.
Scott: go away.
Scott: Yeah, just forget it.
Rym: go home fast forward Whatever if there are any girls there.
Rym: I want to do them.
Scott: Yeah so Instead of dragging that back up Someone's made something newer and even worse yet.
Scott: It contains far fewer cliched able repeatable Lines, which I guess is okay, but it's called fear of girls and it's live-action short movie I guess short film of Two guys, they're definitely acting pretending to be the scariest D&D players ever in this.
Rym: The Scariest part is that I've met people just like this at gaming conventions before.
Scott: Yeah, that's true.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: I think the funniest bits are the larp bit the Christian Relatives bit compared to the druids.
Scott: He's going to hell He's going to burn Whatever.
Scott: and then the Was the homo Suggestions that they made.
Rym: Oh, yeah the homoerotic nature of their relationship.
Scott: Yeah, but the mast concealed homoerotic nature of their relationship.
Rym: You've got to see it.
Rym: Just watch it.
Scott: Oh my god, if you know anything about scary gamer RPG gamers then this will Disturb and amuse.
Rym: So anyway in the news, like we said, we don't have a particular topic today.
Rym: So instead we're gonna round up all the recent sci-tech kind of news that we have anything to say about.
Rym: Expect a lot of opinions.
Scott: Yeah, so Something that's been a trend lately or at least a buzzword lately is pod-fading.
Scott: now Pod-fading it.
Scott: I think they've decided that it.
Scott: I don't know who decided but the the colloquial.
Scott: they I don't know even if they can be colloquial, but they have decided that pod-fading means That Someone has started a podcast because they want to try it out and then within ten episodes.
Scott: They just stopped doing it.
Scott: It's like someone dips their toe into the pool of podcasting and then pulls it out.
Rym: And that's like all those people who make a geocities website and then never update it again.
Scott: It's like all the thousands of people who are like, oh, I'll get a live journal.
Scott: I'll get a blog I'll get it and they just don't continue, you know, it's like a thing They try and then it gets boring and they stop.
Rym: so ten episodes a yep We kick that's ass.
Scott: That's for sure 61 already.
Rym: I'm not even counting the like ten or so pre episodes.
Rym: We did mm-hmm.
Rym: that while I keep mentioning.
Rym: No, you're never gonna hear them.
Scott: We got some of them, right?
Rym: I've got them all.
Rym: Yeah, in fact, they're on the internet if you search hard enough.
Scott: Are they really?
Rym: Yeah, they are.
Scott: We should sell the access to them or something.
Scott: Yeah someday.
Rym: Maybe we'll give away a CD with all because they're terrible.
Scott: Yeah anyway.
Scott: So, I don't know People are like making a special name pod fading for something.
Scott: That is just happens to anything of this nature.
Scott: You know, I don't know what the what the deal is, but people are acting like it's a big problem.
Rym: Yeah, I mean when geocities first offered, you know real space everyone and their mother made like a website for their family Mm-hmm, and then none of those got updated.
Rym: most of them disappeared.
Scott: Yep I think they're pretty much all gone.
Scott: now Even mild geocities site is destroyed.
Rym: mine actually was up until at RIT.
Rym: I needed a place to host something real quick and I remembered I had this account and I found my ass old God-awful website and I promptly deleted it and put a big file there instead.
Scott: Mm-hmm Yeah, I just stopped taking care of it.
Scott: And then eventually it was gone.
Scott: I think I had a geocities site and then I moved to crosswinds, which is slower but had more space and then I Eventually put it on like the RIT hosting.
Scott: Then we had the web server in the bedroom and whatever.
Scott: Oh, yeah Yeah but Yeah, I just like to say all you pod faders out there.
Rym: Nice try Happens to everyone except us.
Scott: I think it's just more evidence that as I previously claimed.
Scott: I don't know if I claimed it on the podcast, but my shit talking days are over.
Scott: Well, there you go Yep, don't?
Rym: we've said the word shit talking a lot and I guess well I'll just warn you that that I forget where it came from, but some punker was talking about punk rock one day And I happened to catch it.
Rym: they were yelling at each other and one guy basically accused the other guy of being a shit talker Which isn't really the kind of terminology we tend to use for things.
Scott: I imagine it's someone who talks shit exactly.
Rym: We tend to be very either verbose in our swearing or very to the point about it But never like.
Rym: shit talker is really kind of a. it's more crude than we tend to be unless we're trying to be crude on Purpose.
Scott: but shit talker very much means something specific.
Rym: Yep, because basically the other guy's like what the hell's a shit talker and this other punk in very great detail explains The shit talker is someone who talks shit up But that never does anything.
Scott: as in you talk the talk without walking any walks.
Rym: Yep of walking and we realized that we have.
Rym: we have missed the boat many times where we had an idea and we planned It all out and we just didn't execute it for various stupid reasons.
Scott: Well, we are not shit talkers by definition.
Scott: very often we have talked shit.
Scott: we're be like, oh we're gonna do this Awesome thing.
Scott: I got this really awesome idea.
Scott: I'm gonna do it.
Scott: Yeah, I'm gonna do this and then we don't do anything.
Scott: We just do shit and we just talk and then we talk about it.
Scott: Yeah, so I you know what?
Rym: That's why this podcast is great.
Rym: All we have to do is talk.
Rym: So there's no more shit.
Scott: Yeah, exactly by talking we have avoided our shit talking this And if this weekend of productivity by me is any evidence I have also avoided shit talking in other areas.
Rym: so Fair that themes actually coming along.
Scott: Yep, so We are shit talkers.
Scott: We are not and shit talkers.
Scott: The pod faders are.
Rym: well You realize that we have to actually make that MMO.
Rym: We've been talking about before we can say anything one day.
Scott: Yeah We're not hundred percent clear yet.
Rym: All right, so what's that next news bit you had about?
Rym: someone stole someone's camera.
Scott: So this lady lost a camera.
Scott: I don't know the details of how it was lost and people found it.
Scott: it's apparently these these parents and a kid and it was like this crazy huge news on the internet that someone lost a $500 digital camera and Stay.
Scott: she found the people who found it and they wouldn't give it back.
Scott: they were like we already bought batteries and a memory cards for it and our kid really likes it and we don't want to take it away from him and he has diabetes and Yeah, and she's like well fuck you you suck.
Scott: And yeah, they do suck.
Scott: She's like I want my photos back.
Scott: Give me a memory cards back.
Scott: They didn't send her to the memory cards.
Scott: They said they needed them to operate the camera.
Scott: They say copied her pictures to CDs and sent those to her.
Scott: So she's kind of pissed and people on the internet were pissed.
Scott: now I was like, yeah, that sucks those people suck.
Scott: But I posted a comment in one or two places saying You know while those people suck in their assholes and I don't even know even the worst person I know would give the camera back.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know a person that bad but you know Finders keepers losers beepers.
Scott: You should be more careful with your stuff if it's that important to you.
Scott: I mean I lose shit all the time and break my own shit all the time.
Scott: I mean when I do I just go up.
Scott: shit happens.
Scott: What are you gonna do?
Scott: I don't get all upset over it It's just not worth it.
Rym: I like how I just finished talking about how we're not that crude and you're immediately like yeah shit shit shit shit shit shit.
Scott: Well, that was the point.
Scott: It was on purpose.
Scott: Yeah, I'm sure okay Anyway, you know, but Rym here seems to say that no they have to give it back.
Rym: well, keep in mind that this is.
Rym: I agree with Scott in that You should do your own due diligence.
Rym: And if you lose something don't expect to get it back, however legally just purely from a legal standpoint.
Rym: if you find property anywhere money, whatever and You can reasonably know or assume that whoever lost it did not intend to lose it You're obligated to turn it into the police or a lost and found or something.
Scott: see The way I was.
Rym: the laws vary a bit from state to state, but that's basically what you have to do.
Scott: Yeah, see if that's true then part of what I said.
Scott: I feel dumb now because I was acting like, you know homeless people pick shit up off the street all the time.
Scott: Are you saying all of them are thieves and I'm kind of like?
Scott: that doesn't make any sense.
Scott: If someone leaves something lying around on purpose or by accident, you know, it's just the tough shit rule.
Scott: It sucks, but you should have been yeah, but like what's the line?
Scott: you cared about it?
Scott: You should watch the line.
Rym: What if you're in the library and you leave your laptop sitting somewhere while you go to pee you come back and it's gone the Art.
Rym: if you walk up to a laptop and you find it there and it's on and word is open and you take it I mean, yeah, the person should have done their due diligence, but you're still a thief.
Scott: Oh, yeah Let's see It's kind of like I kept thinking about the beach because the beach is a place a lot of people lose things, right?
Scott: If I'm walking down the beach and there's an umbrella and a bunch of towels and chairs and books, right?
Scott: Which is what you usually see if we're at the beach, right?
Scott: Obviously those people are in the water.
Scott: Come on, you know and you see people in the water You don't take it because obviously there's someone there It's it's attended.
Scott: if you're walking on the beach and there's I don't know a gold fork just in the sand alone It's yours go for it.
Rym: Yeah, the law is fairly vague on purpose because that way judges get to decide.
Scott: but basically that's good That's good something a judge should decide now.
Rym: I have two anecdotes.
Rym: Well, actually three regarding this and that's Well one.
Rym: one's real short.
Rym: when I was a little kid We're in Meyers super stores in Michigan buying groceries and I saw a $20 bill on the ground All right, and I picked it up and I didn't say anything about it.
Rym: And then we were in the car.
Rym: I said mom I found a $20 bill and she said awesome share it with your brother.
Rym: We'll go to the Toys R Us tomorrow Awesome.
Rym: Yeah So, alright, whatever.
Rym: I technically broke the law, but I was a little kid and whatever.
Rym: it's 20 bucks.
Rym: See, I think money is something different because no money follows under the same rules and you have to turn it into the police.
Rym: That's my second anecdote.
Scott: It's true.
Scott: It's true But all money.
Scott: unless someone like I has an identifying mark on the money or remembers the serial numbers of their money They can't or remembers the amount because we were at Cedar Point like many years later.
Rym: I was still kind of young but we found we were get taking our picture in these like old-time Constantly things.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, whatever.
Rym: and We found a plastic baggie with like $300 in it.
Rym: Oh, wow, and I was like, dude We're buying video game in the world.
Scott: Here's the thing is the plastic baggie is like, you know, so guy will plastic baggie had nothing to do with it.
Rym: Basically what happens is you have to give it to the police and Then say, you know, I found this here Whatever whoever lost it has an X number of days depends on the state and the town or whatever to try to claim it.
Rym: Now basically you have to identify it in some way.
Rym: So say you lost money.
Rym: you have to say within a reasonable degree of how much money you lost, you know I lost about $300.
Rym: So if you claim that you lost about $300 and the police find about $300 they give it to you Mm-hmm.
Rym: Now if no one claims it in X days, they give it back to whoever found it.
Rym: Some states take like a 10% finders fee or whatever, but usually they just give you all the money.
Rym: They don't care.
Scott: Yeah, what do they you know?
Scott: We should start calling police station saying we lost a hundred bucks.
Rym: You could do that.
Rym: The problem is odds are no one lost the amount of money.
Scott: You're saying 20 bucks 20 dollar bills falling all over the place.
Rym: Yeah, you know what.
Rym: people generally don't turn that into the police.
Scott: Anyway, I know that's the problem I do.
Rym: Well, it depends a lot on the situation.
Scott: It does depend a lot because the third anecdote is at Katsucon.
Rym: I was walking around the dealers room and I found a wad a small amount of money in a wad on the ground.
Rym: I saw it there and I get bent over and I picked it up and I'm looking at it and I'm thinking to myself Wow, if this were three years ago, and I was at a con this would mean I can eat tonight And I wouldn't have given it back to anyone.
Rym: But now that I'm fairly wealthy and you know, I mean we consider ourselves wealthy we can do everything we want to do.
Rym: yep, like we go to cons and we buy food for all the poor fanboys and Well, not look at boys, but the the fangirls.
Rym: Yeah and I see this girl standing there and She's kind of looking at me kind of not and I just I hold it up and I ask her Did you drop this?
Rym: and she hesitated for a second?
Rym: And at this point, I'm a hundred percent certain that it is not In fact her money.
Scott: Yeah, I am also 100% certain and I wasn't even there.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, but the thing is she hesitated and that's the reason I decided.
Rym: all right bullshit, but then she said yeah And because I had no other way to know who's it was and I knew it wasn't mine.
Rym: I just gave it to her.
Rym: whatever whatever.
Scott: See, it's like if I found the plastic bag with $300 in it.
Scott: It's like, okay Someone was that like a water park carrying their money in a plastic bag to keep from getting wet And this is all their money for the day.
Scott: I'm gonna turn this in but if I'm walking down the street, there's a $20 bill on the ground.
Scott: Whatever it's mine.
Rym: Well, it's like if a cashier gives me too much change back.
Rym: I'll probably just keep it.
Rym: I probably won't even notice.
Scott: Oh my god That's.
Scott: that's another great story.
Scott: when I was in Boston and I was a middle school my eighth grade we're in Boston and this is the magic card days, right and Basically all we.
Scott: there was a game store in this place in Boston.
Scott: We went to right so we were all about that.
Scott: You pretty much went to go to the game store But we went to get lunch at a pizza place and I gave him a five and they gave me change for a 20.
Scott: That was a whole bunch of packs of magic cards.
Rym: They gave me Yeah, all right, all right that was barely tech news.
Scott: so we'll move on okay, so I don't know how tech savvy everyone is but If you are an administrator at a company you want to make it so that no one can use little USB drives and stuff on The company computers.
Scott: the reason for this is because people will put important company documents on them and leave with them.
Rym: See now I disagree in that if people want to steal your company's secrets like that and they're easily accessible like that Anyway, I can just get them to
Scott: Begin with
Rym: no not just your security But if your employees would want to do that something's wrong with your company in the first place.
Scott: That's also true but the the the situate.
Scott: the specific situation is is that You have someone who is part of their job accesses, you know secure important documents But you don't want them leaving that compute computer that they're using.
Scott: so as an administrator you're responsible to Technologically prevent the documents from leaving that computer, you know, they have to do all the work on the company's machine.
Scott: It's all you know.
Rym: Yeah, though I will say that at like as an IT guy and I do do a lot of security work in IT Basically if someone wants to steal something from your company and they work there There's nothing you can do to stop them.
Rym: The only real security when it comes to them.
Rym: The only real security when it comes to documents is making sure your employees don't want to or can't benefit from it.
Scott: Yep, that's true But anyway, it's something that you do want to at least do something to prevent.
Scott: Usually people disable USB in the BIOS because no one's smart enough to turn that back on or something.
Scott: but the latest problem people are talking about is pod slurping where People will come in to your company Plug their iPods in to the company computers run a program that will search for sensitive documents Put them on the iPod and then leave with the iPods to take your sensitive documents away.
Rym: Now.
Rym: This is nothing new.
Rym: No, people are making out like iPods of this new threat.
Rym: I will note that in the in the early early 90s.
Rym: I had a game that came on two discs and I basically noticed that there was a lot of free space on the discs.
Rym: So I deleted a bunch of game files, whatever.
Rym: I basically Resurrand wrap the executable into a Trojan and I made discs that you put them in to install this game and it installs the game And while it's installing it searches your computer for a doc and text files and copies them to the disc.
Rym: Awesome, then they give me the disc back and I have whatever documents they had.
Rym: I made a slurping Trojan in the early 90s.
Rym: This is nothing new.
Scott: Yeah, this is a bit of problems ever since floppy disk existed where you could take data away from a computer and carry it with You.
Scott: the thing is is people are talking about it now because you use an iPod to do it and iPods don't look Conspicuous and you don't consider them a security threat when you see them around your company.
Scott: It's like, you know at my company everyone has a freaking iPods.
Scott: I mean, I have one co-worker has on the other co-worker has one.
Scott: someone upstairs is always sharing iTunes with me, you know but now Administrators have to look at them in a different way.
Scott: I Guess yeah, though.
Rym: The thing is this has always been a problem with the iPod.
Rym: It's basically just a USB hard drive.
Scott: Yeah, that's exactly what it is.
Scott: Only the hard drive happens to come with a little decoder chip to play music.
Rym: I mean, I remember a long time ago with the older the PlayStation, you know, it had a Broadband adapter that no one use.
Scott: the PlayStation 2 I think did.
Rym: now there was a thing for the PlayStation 1 was there.
Rym: I don't buy them in the Dreamcast.
Rym: I think was the Dreamcast?
Scott: the Dreamcast definitely had it.
Rym: Yes I'm pretty sure.
Rym: anyway Someone made a disk that would basically turn your Dreamcast into a network sniffer and it would store data to cards in it.
Scott: Yep, that sounds good.
Rym: So you could just take a Dreamcast somewhere in a company plug it into a network jack and go nuts.
Scott: Dreamcast is really Windows CE computer.
Scott: They hacked the hell out of that thing.
Scott: Mm-hmm There were just so many hacks for the Dreamcast.
Scott: It was a PlayStation emulator.
Scott: at one point even.
Rym: yeah, I mean my whole if I had finished the song yet I play the Rym doesn't care song.
Rym: but Security really begins and ends with people and very few technological measures will actually increase your security any substantial way Beyond basic due diligence.
Scott: Yeah, once you pretty much covered all the bases like, huh?
Scott: We don't let people just you know send packets into our network randomly and you know, we don't let people run programs They shouldn't be running and all that not.
Scott: everything else is only like slight helps.
Scott: You know, you know blocking iPods only helps you a tiny bit.
Rym: see the thing is people really have a weird.
Rym: I should do a whole show on this.
Rym: Yeah, we should do a show about securities next Especially since I've been doing a lot of security type work lately.
Scott: I took a lot of security classes and I know a lot about writing secure software.
Rym: Yeah I'm talking.
Rym: I know a lot about like institutional security and Audit security and Sarbanes Oxley security and all that horseshit.
Scott: All right, let's do it then.
Rym: All right, because it's too complicated to talk about now That's for sure.
Scott: but
Rym: the best I can say kind of a teaser for our show is that Security is not what you think it is when it comes to IT and people really especially people who are in power in companies really don't understand it and They'll crack down on things that look like security holes that aren't
Scott: because magazines tell them to
Rym: and they'll ignore things that are security holes But don't look like it
Scott: because basically no one in a company wants to spend money on security because they don't get anything.
Scott: They don't get money out of it or a company decides risk aversion.
Rym: Actually a company a lot of times will decide that security is an important thing and they'll pump tons of money into it Basically ineffectively.
Rym: Yeah, or they'll become too secure technologically and then they make their business less efficient.
Rym: either that or worse They'll make their employees less reliable because the employees resent being treated like criminals.
Rym: and then employees will think oh They think they can keep me from getting this data.
Rym: I can get this data Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, so we'll do a whole show on that cool someday.
Scott: They might do more than one show on that.
Rym: Yeah, maybe we'll do a series.
Scott: Anyway, next news There's this guy and I don't know a lot about him But apparently he's a funny famous British guy called Ricky Gervais, I think is the correct pronunciation.
Rym: Wow, that was that would have been funny if you'd done it on purpose.
Scott: I mispronounced correct pronunciation.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: All right, Ricky Gervais.
Scott: Anyway, he has a podcast that was number one in iTunes.
Scott: it for a while.
Scott: It's still pretty high up there and I haven't listened to it, but it's supposedly funny.
Scott: I'll take people's word for it because people of all shapes and sizes have been praising it.
Scott: anyway It's been decided that starting next month.
Scott: His podcast is no longer gonna be free.
Scott: He's gonna charge seven dollars a month to listen to his podcast.
Rym: That's the end of that.
Scott: Yeah, there he goes down Shitter.
Scott: I don't know anyone who's gonna pay seven dollars a month unless He makes like a one-hour episode seven days a week.
Scott: that's like Ridiculously pee in your pants.
Scott: hilarious.
Rym: Now.
Scott: I was not gonna get many buyers.
Rym: I wonder how exactly he would do that.
Rym: You have to buy it through iTunes.
Scott: Yeah in iTunes, you know when you go to get a podcast it just says Subscribe.
Scott: we're in the spot where it normally says.
Rym: All right, so it does all this through iTunes.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah See, I don't really use iTunes.
Rym: So so the way I think of a podcast I think of just an RSS feed.
Scott: Yeah, well in iTunes Subscribing to an RSS feed for a podcast that's in the iTunes directory because you can't just cut and paste URL of a feed into iTunes.
Scott: This is subscribe button Which is the same button that you would normally push to buy a song.
Scott: that's that would say buy on it.
Scott: It just in in the price where the place of the money the dollar amount usually says 99 cents.
Scott: It's it's free.
Scott: So you see a podcast.
Scott: you just click subscribe and you're subscribed For his.
Scott: apparently what it's gonna say subscribe.
Scott: So you clip subscribe you pay seven dollars through iTunes and then it gets subscribed.
Rym: great Honestly, I'm gonna keep an eye on this but I really think that his podcast is going to completely disappear in short order.
Scott: I think this is gonna be because it is really popular and supposedly really funny.
Scott: I think this is gonna be the first real test of whether people are willing to pay money For audio content.
Rym: if it's good enough, I can tell all of you out there now that GeekNights will always forevermore be free.
Rym: Yep, we might do things to make money someday if we get crazy popular But those things would be like tell it selling t-shirts or whatever.
Rym: We would never selling public appearances.
Rym: Yeah, we would never ever ever make you pay for GeekNights selling our bodies.
Rym: Yeah, at least my body.
Scott: Yeah, whatever We might you know, even if crazy stuff happens and we still want to do this for some reason we'll do whatever.
Scott: We'll post it in foreign lands and go to Antarctica.
Scott: Who knows?
Rym: Yeah, but GeekNights will always be free.
Rym: You can quote us on that forever because we're basically doing this for fun.
Rym: any money or fame We get as a result of it is purely just awesome.
Scott: You don't really nights is ever not free.
Scott: Come kick me in the nuts and bring this episode of the podcast with you.
Scott: Play me saying it and then kick me in the nuts and then do it again because there's nothing we could say to that?
Scott: No, not really that we would be pooned totally pooned.
Rym: Yeah, I like to think that we're fairly incorruptible But I wonder what would happen if an evil man came and said here's five million dollars charge a dollar for your podcast.
Scott: I would use the five million dollars to purchase a cup.
Scott: All right.
Rym: All right, so You know for someone who has a throat infection and it's incredibly painful to talk after been talking a lot Yeah, you're you know, that's why we pushed all my news is to the front.
Rym: and now yeah, so Propaganda has always been around and The United States military makes great use of.
Scott: I don't think Hammurabi had propaganda did he?
Rym: There was propaganda in the ancient Greeks.
Scott: Alright, that's that's early enough.
Rym: There were a lot of things written about various cities in Greece that are very disparaging and they were mostly written by people in other Greek states, I wonder if some of the hieroglyphs in Egypt are propaganda.
Rym: Well, you realize that there's evidence that the Egyptians had another language that they use for day to day.
Rym: Oh, yeah, hieroglyphs were like an archival language.
Scott: Yeah, but I'm just.
Scott: I'm just wondering if I assume they did.
Rym: I assume there are things like Cleopatra.
Rym: does the nasty?
Rym: You've never seen Bubba hotep go see it right now.
Rym: Yeah, pause the podcast go to a blockbuster rent Bubba hotep and watch it or else you won't get the following joke about Suck the dog dick of Anubis asswipe.
Rym: So anyway propaganda, I'm not gonna talk about the history of propaganda, even though I'd like to.
Scott: yeah, that'd be fun.
Rym: Yeah, that'll be a show someday.
Scott: All right, we're really good at you.
Scott: Don't forget them.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, let's see propaganda show because people have complained about how we talk about a show that we'll do and they say oh, that's awesome I can't wait for you to do it and then we never do it.
Scott: yeah, go to the forums and make a list of all the shows you want us to do because We have a lot of hard times usually Monday and Thursday going.
Scott: what are we gonna talk about?
Rym: I don't know All right, but basically Donald Rumsfeld to sum this up really quickly Donald asshole.
Rym: He wants The u.s.
Rym: To make its propaganda machine more efficient and quicker.
Scott: Wait, so he's just like we're making propaganda.
Rym: We need to have it quicker.
Scott: Let's do it better.
Rym: quote the u.s Must fight back by operating a more effective 24-hour propaganda machine or risk a dangerous deficiency Uh-huh.
Scott: How about um, just not making any propaganda and letting honesty and truth come out of Media machine.
Rym: this really perplexes me.
Rym: So we now have a news item.
Rym: This is in the international news.
Rym: Well, the US government admits to propagandizing the Iraqi people and talks about how they need to do it better.
Scott: Now, uh, we're not lying to these people and convincing them and implanting our ideals in them enough.
Rym: well, no, I don't know about you, but I can read the newspaper and some dude in Iraq can also read the newspaper.
Rym: and if he reads in the newspaper that the u.s.
Rym: Is trying to propagandize him and Openly admits to doing so and then he turns and he sees u.s.
Rym: Propaganda.
Rym: I don't see it being so effective anymore.
Scott: You know you think that but the nature of propaganda these days is very different.
Scott: It's like back in the day.
Scott: propaganda would be like a poster saying, you know Russia bad Well now yeah now they're called like information ops.
Scott: yet now It's like what they'll do is hire a PR guy who goes to a newspaper and talks to a journalist and that journalist writes a story for the newspaper about how you know something.
Scott: something is so great or something something is you know, The new popular trend or a new fad and it to you.
Scott: It looks like a normal news story and it is a normal news story.
Scott: It's not an advertisement and it wasn't paid for by anyone but some PR guy Got the journalist to write it and got to write it the way they wanted to.
Scott: and that's how propaganda works these days.
Scott: You can't tell.
Scott: it's not obvious like the stuff in your social studies book.
Rym: I mean I'm not talking about this issue because of.
Rym: I want to talk about what's going on in Iraq Because we talked enough about our political views randomly anyway.
Scott: Nobody in the world agrees.
Scott: Yeah Because we just piss everyone off.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, but not to talk about Iraq but just talk about propaganda.
Rym: and technology has really changed the way propaganda works.
Rym: and Scott just mentioned the Media campaigns that people will do for various reasons and I will note that there is probably one going on right now That I have just picked up on.
Rym: so see if you can see this in the media.
Rym: curling Not curling your hair Curling the Canadian sport.
Scott: It's Canadian.
Scott: It's not Canadian, but where I grew up I've always known it is like a thing people only care about when it's in the Olympics.
Rym: Oh, no where I grew up curling was fairly well known really and in Canada curling is very popular.
Rym: Okay?
Scott: I had one friend's dad in high school and his dad curled and he has curling stone in the basement.
Rym: I've tried it a couple times.
Scott: I never actually tried it.
Scott: It's kind of fun.
Scott: Yeah Well, I figure it's a lot like bowling.
Scott: you just throw this rock down the ice and a bunch of guys do the broom You bit and you know, that's it.
Rym: It's kind of like high-stakes.
Rym: Awesome bocce.
Scott: Oh bocce is cool.
Rym: I love bocce.
Rym: Yeah Alright, I've just noticed cuz we don't watch TV at all.
Rym: But I was in the laundromat today and I caught on the news.
Rym: they were showing like the results of curling and then they talked about how Bush went to watch curling.
Rym: and Then Later, I caught a commercial for another news bit where they were gonna talk about the rise of popularity and curling in the u.s.
Rym: And like why it's becoming more popular and now they think it's gonna be popular in the south Like it's gonna move down.
Scott: You know what that is.
Scott: See curling isn't actually popular.
Scott: No one gave a shit about curling.
Scott: They're making these news stories Saying people give a shit about curling and as a result of these stories people will begin to give a shit about curling.
Scott: It's a self-fulfilling Prophecy a self-fulfilling not to disparage curling.
Rym: I think it's a cool sport.
Scott: Yeah, curling is not so bad It's a lot worse things.
Rym: They're trying to make it popular for some reason and I'll bet that reason involves money.
Scott: I bet that in reason involves the curling Association of whatever who knows paying PR guys to make this happen.
Rym: Because you could see I mean just kind of keep an eye out in the news and see if I'm right about this.
Rym: just pay Attention watch for people talking about how popular curling is nowadays.
Rym: Mm-hmm The same thing happened with Sudoku a while ago.
Scott: Yeah, did you Sudoku?
Scott: Did you see a bunch of people playing Sudoku before you saw it on the news or after?
Rym: Yeah, there were news articles all over the place.
Rym: suddenly like a blitz Sudoku is becoming crazy popular in the u.s.
Rym: All the smart people have been playing Sudoku in the u.s And then people started playing Sudoku and you started seeing it in supermarket.
Scott: news started seeing it all over the place.
Scott: It comes, you know, this isn't a chicken egg mystery.
Scott: We know which one comes first.
Scott: It's obvious to anyone with eyeballs.
Scott: People were not playing Sudoku like crazy nuts.
Scott: It's a very old silly puzzle that a computer can figure it out in two seconds.
Scott: You know, it's a simple brain task.
Scott: Just anyone can do it.
Scott: It doesn't take a genius, you know.
Scott: It just makes dumb people feel smart when they fill it.
Scott: figure it out because it.
Scott: you know It's just a matter of time not a matter.
Scott: But anyway, the point is that they said it was popular and therefore it became popular.
Scott: The same thing with the Tickle Me Elmo things and the Furbies and the Tamagotchis.
Rym: They hype them up like they're gonna sell out of the note.
Rym: They sell out.
Scott: Yeah, if they didn't say anything about the Tickle Me Elmo's on the news.
Scott: No one would freaking want one.
Scott: It's a stupid toy.
Scott: Same with the Tamagotchis.
Scott: Those things are like a waste of time.
Scott: They're boring.
Scott: Yeah, not like the Pokemon.
Scott: Those are Ten dogs you get the drift.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway, we'll do a whole show on this and I actually wrote it down So I won't forget because I took a lot of classes on this.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I went to school for IT, but I kind of scanned my way around getting into classes I really shouldn't have been able to take and I ended up taking the entire professional technical communications major Which includes a lot of like persuasion propaganda type stuff.
Rym: I could talk about this for hours, especially if my throat didn't hurt.
Scott: Yeah alright.
Rym: so Windows Vista Great again.
Rym: Yeah, it's just the worst thing in the world.
Rym: So Yahoo News has what looks like an op-ed about Ten reasons why you should buy Windows Vista.
Scott: Wait, wait, there's one reason we should buy Windows Vista.
Rym: Well, alright, so this guy claims to have ten reasons why we're buying Windows Vista is going to be alright.
Scott: Let's play a game ready.
Scott: You say the reason and then I'll shoot it down.
Scott: and if I fail every time I fail to shoot down a reason I'll give you a dollar.
Rym: or how about this?
Rym: for every reason you fail to shoot it down We'll each buy one copy of Windows Vista.
Rym: Alright, cuz I've already read through these.
Scott: Alright, let's go for it.
Rym: Alright, so one Security Windows Vista is gonna be really secure.
Rym: It's gonna come with a firewall and such.
Scott: So wait, so it's already so insecure.
Scott: It's running all these services.
Scott: It needs a firewall and to.
Scott: Let's see how long it takes to hack it.
Scott: Let's see one day.
Rym: Well, the same claim was made about Windows XP.
Scott: Yeah, Oh Windows 2000.
Scott: I was like security problems.
Scott: here comes It was really well.
Rym: while your problem they released like eight patches recently like in the last couple of weeks.
Rym: They talk about how there's the Windows services hardening which is this buzzword thing where it prevents quote obscure background processes from being hijacked and changing your system.
Scott: All right, we're gonna start a betting pool to see how long it takes those spyware guys.
Rym: They've also got full disk encryption, which you might think is cool But I see it as one performance hit and two.
Rym: if your Windows installation breaks your data is gone forever.
Scott: Yeah, great.
Scott: there's also another problem of full disk encryption is that you're not gonna be.
Scott: you know your Linux.
Scott: you're not gonna be able to mount your Vista file systems or anything.
Scott: How are you gonna recover them?
Scott: There's just no recovery whatsoever.
Scott: You're screwed All right.
Rym: Now this one shoots itself down to Internet Explorer 7 now.
Rym: Here's the quote ie Gets a much-needed Firefox inspired makeover,
Scott: okay while this could have something to it because ie is a little more Optimized performance wise and memory usage wise than Firefox is on the Windows platform
Rym: That's mostly because ie is also the Explorer in Windows and it's running all the time.
Scott: Anyway, yeah And it all that causes actually a problem and that it's most of the security holes in Windows are because ie is so tied Into the OS that through the web browser.
Scott: You can attack the operating system itself.
Rym: Anyway, so that's what they claim to a fix with ie7.
Rym: They well that it runs in a reduced privilege mode So that it can't access other code and it's basically in a sandbox.
Scott: well, that's good, but on the other hand a lot of people have been using the ie7 beta and From all every single review I've read has said it's much better than ie6, but it's still no Firefox.
Scott: They know how to copy Firefox and they didn't quite do it all the way.
Rym: No, here's the thing.
Rym: There are two versions of ie7.
Rym: You only get the real version if you're running Vista.
Rym: No one has used the real version yet requires Vista.
Scott: Well, if the non-real version of ie7 is not quite Firefox I can't Down the point here not the fact that it sucks in general.
Rym: Yeah, their point is that ie7 is better because now it runs into the secure protected mode.
Rym: In Linux and I mean Windows you're fucked anyway, but at least in Linux Firefox Already runs in a limited mode because you're not root so it can't do crap.
Scott: You could run Firefox as a root.
Scott: You can't.
Scott: even then You know, it can't really.
Scott: it's still not very limited.
Rym: Well for anyone who hasn't used Linux in Windows you pretty much have to be administrator or you can't do anything.
Rym: Hmm in Linux, you never need to be your root almost ever.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much only if you're configuring the computer installing software or something All right.
Rym: number three because I want to get through these.
Rym: there's a lot of them.
Rym: All right righteous eye candy.
Scott: Um Actually all the XGL type stuff is coming out for links actually starting to work out all the fancy 3d stuff or you know It was like all weekend.
Scott: and yeah OS X is look good for years.
Rym: Yeah OS X is fantastic and beautiful.
Scott: So basically they're openly admitting that Windows is ugly and that finally it's gonna look better plus they're not doing it very elegantly.
Rym: Final quote here.
Rym: You need powerful graphics hardware and a robust system to manage all of these effects.
Scott: Wait, so it's actually a reason not to buy Vista because it doesn't work on shitty computers.
Scott: It only works on amazing computers that don't exist yet.
Rym: All right, I'm gonna do the rest of these.
Rym: real quick desktop search.
Rym: Already have that?
Rym: even though I don't use Google I can already do ctrl F and search for anything.
Rym: Yep, all they're doing is making it faster.
Scott: They're making it Google desktop styling.
Scott: I think better updates.
Scott: Yeah, I heard that instead of using a web page in IE to update the OS there's gonna be a separate updating program.
Rym: Yeah, a separate updating program that won't let you update a pirated copy of Windows, which I know most people I know have sucks more media.
Scott: But the windows media programs suck.
Scott: you always use some.
Scott: you replace every single one of those.
Scott: that's the first thing you do.
Rym: Any media you want online is gonna be free.
Scott: Anyway, actually, I heard that when amps dead people are all using something else.
Rym: WinAmp is dead Yeah, I've had a security hole in it recently too sucks.
Scott: But yeah, everyone's using VLC and whatnot.
Scott: No one uses freaking the windows media player crap.
Rym: I think they're talking mostly about the Proprietary protected content.
Rym: that'll only be able to be watched on this.
Scott: That's the stuff that you don't want.
Scott: is the DRM plus.
Rym: someone will crack it and you'll be out there for free.
Rym: Yep Alright, um parental controls.
Scott: That's a good thing.
Scott: Not that I know of.
Rym: Yeah, what do they mean by parental controls?
Rym: I mean If you want to control your kids access you give them their own account and you just restrict it.
Rym: If you really don't want to get access you set up some sort of net filter like net nanny or whatever if you're that much Of a horrible parent.
Scott: Yeah, you can't freaking pay attention to what your kids are doing and make sure you know They know what they're looking at.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, I'm not gonna get off on a rant here to you know to quote comedian but anyway My parents Dimly understood what was going on in the internet and they just gave me free rein.
Rym: I had a full-on completely unlimited internet connection for much of my life and I turned out.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: Yeah I played whatever video game I want and internet did pretty much whatever I wanted and my parents would sometimes be like, alright Yeah, you probably shouldn't watch that.
Scott: or yeah, don't go looking at porn or whatever.
Rym: But basically they're all these features that like here you can even block access to games based on the ESRB ratings.
Scott: It's not really useful Alright, most PC games worth playing nowadays are highly rated.
Rym: better backups.
Rym: They claim they made that system restore better not suck.
Scott: All right, that's good.
Scott: However, are they gonna be encrypted?
Scott: because if they aren't then that kind of do.
Rym: more importantly that never really works.
Scott: I Think what that's what they're saying is that the new one is gonna work.
Scott: Yeah We'll see if it actually does because backups really don't make sense anymore now that we have these gigantic Hard drives.
Scott: you really need a hard drive to back it up.
Scott: So there really needs to new be a new backup paradigm to.
Rym: well, you know what my backup paradigm is raid.
Scott: Yeah, you don't.
Scott: mine is my important files go on a DVD and there aren't many of them.
Rym: Well, I guess we could do a whole show on backing up if we wanted to.
Scott: Oh God Today's thing.
Scott: I could do a whole show on Asterisk.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well backing up includes two different things.
Rym: one is Backing up data so that if there's a hardware or major software failure, the data is still intact.
Rym: the other important part is taking snapshots of a system so that if a change is made and you have to undo that change you'll Be able to undo it by reverting Mm-hmm.
Rym: Those are two separate issues that are backed up in separate ways.
Rym: raid covers The first one only tapes cover.
Rym: the second one.
Rym: only having both is expensive.
Rym: You have to make a choice Mm-hmm.
Rym: Yeah, we'll do a whole show on that too.
Rym: Let me note that here.
Scott: Well, you can use tapes for the first one, but it sucks.
Rym: Yeah, it's not very efficient and tapes are actually very expensive.
Scott: now They are especially those machines that move the tapes around but those are fun to watch where they go.
Scott: Okay All right, is that all his reasons?
Rym: peer-to-peer collaboration?
Rym: It claims that the windows collaboration module uses peer-to-peer technology to let Vista users work together in a shared workspace.
Rym: now basically, this is probably the only one that has any sort of Usefulness to it at all.
Rym: Basically, they're saying that it looks like Windows Vista is going to come with VPN ad hoc workgroup networking.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: There are a million third-party things that have been doing this for years Hamachi.
Scott: Yeah, there are also websites that do this sort of thing.
Scott: You can just all visit the website and then you'll be collaborating.
Rym: Yep, I mean, I'm not saying that It's a bad thing.
Rym: things like this are cool.
Rym: But why does the operating system need to do that?
Scott: Yeah, that should be like some piece of software that does that?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Alright, the last one is quick setup.
Rym: They say that it takes about 15 minutes to install Vista.
Scott: It takes five minutes to install Ubuntu shut up.
Rym: Yeah, not picks it take you hit enter or no.
Rym: You type install and hit enter.
Scott: you don't even have to type in.
Scott: Oh if you want to install it?
Rym: Yeah, if you want to install it true Okay.
Rym: Yeah, I'm done with that.
Rym: Windows Vista is a terrible thing.
Scott: OS X it comes installed.
Scott: Yeah All right.
Scott: The last thing I've got here is this thing called feed tree Which I haven't actually used so I can't give a full review of it.
Scott: but supposedly what feed tree is is Bit torrent for feeds.
Scott: right now the way it works is a lot of people who are web.
Scott: You know server guys like me know this problem.
Scott: You have an art RSS feed.
Scott: people subscribe to the RSS feed.
Scott: The RSS readers check these feeds like Every five minutes to see if you posted something new.
Scott: if you have a blog where you update once a week This can eat up a whole lot of bandwidth and you serving a whole bunch of requests that are basically useless.
Rym: Well, I mean for our look at our site feed burner gets hundreds and hundreds and hundreds and hundreds of hits Just constantly, but they know that we're only updating once a day around midnight.
Scott: So, you know, why do we have all these extra things?
Scott: is the only way we can make it work Right now is a polling system as opposed to an interrupt system.
Scott: computer science bla bla bla bla bla bla.
Rym: Yeah I mean luckily all the good like feed aggregators or podcast directories.
Rym: The directory will only ping us once a day or will ping it and then it'll update.
Scott: Yeah, the pinging us pinging the directories is a very good system.
Scott: Yeah, the problem there are people still subscribing to the feeds in those directories, you know asking them.
Scott: Is there a new episode?
Scott: is there?
Scott: So feed tree attempts to solve this problem by using the bit torrent solution Which is where the people themselves ask each other if the feed has been updated.
Scott: and they don't really ask each other They also kind of tell each other.
Scott: so if a bunch of people use feed tree to subscribe to say the GeekNights feed and There's an update to the GeekNights feed then somehow behind the scenes instead of everyone constantly asking GeekNights Is there a new episode or is there an episode?
Scott: One guy finds out about a new episode and then he just tells all his friends who tell all their friends tell their friends And anyone else who is using feed tree and is also Subscribed to GeekNights.
Scott: We'll find out from other people using feed tree subscribe to GeekNights.
Rym: I think it's a neat idea one.
Rym: It has.
Rym: they have to make sure it's secure.
Rym: I mean I can think of a million ways to all use that for evil.
Scott: Yeah Oh, look, I see who's subscribing to these feeds.
Scott: Oh, look, I tell someone that there's a new item in that feed, but then I point them to my malicious site.
Scott: I point them to my site where there's something that looks like an mp3, but it's actually a Trojan, you know All kinds of horrible things.
Rym: Yeah, the other thing is it's encryption solves that but it solves a problem that doesn't exist yet.
Rym: The bad RSS is used by a tiny fraction of the number of people out there.
Scott: It is but it's also a very high percentage of bandwidth on sites that do have it.
Scott: It is.
Rym: if you look at a site like yes, I'm saying that I'm glad I'm not saying this is a bad thing.
Rym: I'm saying I'm glad this appeared now before the bandwidth became a real problem like a pressing issue Because now by the time people really have problems with RSS bandwidth usage This thing will already if it's as good as it claims to be be in place or be ready to be accepted.
Scott: These people do really have problems with our this bandwidth usage.
Scott: It's not that the bandwidth usage of RSS is so much.
Scott: They can't handle it.
Scott: No, that's the mp3 downloading.
Rym: Yeah
Scott: the problem with the RSS is that the percentage of bandwidth the RSS requests are taking up are is Disproportionate to the file size and how often it actually should be requested as opposed to other things Like if you look at like just look at my blog, it's a crummy little blog.
Scott: Maybe a hundred people subscribe to it.
Scott: I don't even know.
Scott: I don't care.
Scott: I don't pay attention to that so much and The RSS feed is by by far the most bandwidth and most requested thing.
Scott: There is because if one guy subscribes to it, that means he's gonna check it a hundred times a day.
Scott: You know lately I've actually been posting something to it once a day because Rym wasn't here and I had son nothing better to do.
Scott: but Usually I post once every few weeks.
Scott: these are people constantly downloading this one file from my website for and get nothing out of it and As opposed to like actual blog entries even ones they get crazy popular, which I've had a couple of those in my time It's nothing compared to what the feed gets, you know, it's just out of control.
Rym: Yeah, so hopefully this will pan out.
Rym: we'll probably report on it again once we know more about it.
Scott: I think I'm gonna try it out tomorrow.
Scott: Yeah I'll tell you what it what it's like if it's any if it's worth it.
Rym: So that's all we've got for today.
Rym: At least we've come up with a bunch of ideas for shows to do on Mondays since Mondays are always the days where?
Rym: It's easy to find news.
Rym: It's hard to find good sci-tech stories to talk about where we could actually provide insightful commentary.
Scott: Yeah, Oh another thing is.
Scott: I'm thinking about having themed weeks Like.
Scott: the one idea I came up with is a robot week.
Scott: we're on Monday We can talk about robots and then on Tuesday, we could talk about robot games and on Wednesday We could talk about robot anime and Thursday.
Scott: We can talk about robot something else.
Rym: So you guys think this is a good idea.
Rym: We'll go with it.
Scott: Yeah, if you can think of anything else, that would be a good Themed week, you know something where we can talk about it and a science tech perspective and then it.
Scott: you know video games containing it and then Anime and manga and comics containing it and then something else.
Scott: Then you know, I need more ideas like that.
Scott: That way we can you know, have a bunch of themed weeks and it'll be all really cool.
Rym: Yep, so email us or hit us up in the forum.
Rym: Yeah, and stay tuned.
Rym: tomorrow when among other things I'll be doing the first half of my Katsucon coverage.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: and Wednesday when I'll be doing a full podcast length Katsucon khan report.
Scott: and Thursday, what are we doing Thursday?
Rym: We haven't decided yet.
Scott: I thought we came up with something.
Rym: Yeah, we did.
Rym: I already forgot.
Scott: and next week New York comic-con.
Rym: Yes, New York comic-con week after that spring break.
Rym: We might have some people coming over.
Scott: Yeah, there's also non khan the following week where I might get to play that new German board game.
Scott: Kalis Kalis.
Scott: Yeah, so well, we got Well beyond ten episodes.
Rym: Stay tuned.
Rym: Yeah, and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.