Rym: It's Tuesday October 17th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We come out of our funk to bring you Japanese style versus puzzle games.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: The sad fact about yesterday's show is that we did a much better show after the show while we were laying around talking.
Scott: Well, I guess it's cuz we weren't being informative.
Scott: We were just laying around talking which is I think Getting the idea from listening to a lot of podcasts and from listening to our podcast that the entertaining bit is when People are just laying around talking and not trying too hard.
Rym: Well, it depends.
Rym: I mean sometimes we've been informative and it's awesome.
Rym: I Think it was a combination of the topic and whatever.
Rym: But anyway, today is a much better day for today.
Scott: If you if you show me a show that has never had a bad episode I mean, come on, seriously, even the greatest shows.
Scott: there's a bad episode of cowboy bebop that one with the aliens.
Scott: It wasn't so hot.
Rym: It was fine.
Rym: What are you talking about?
Scott: So you get the point is that we don't have to make every episode amazing.
Rym: Yeah, we do.
Scott: All right, whatever.
Rym: more importantly I would like to point out because a lot of people seem to have noticed that the episode didn't appear properly in the feed last night.
Rym: Yeah, all Scott.
Rym: Yeah, I forgot to attach the category I just want to note because the one time a while ago when I went to sleep without dealing with the show properly Scott raised holy hellfire about it.
Rym: Yeah, so, uh, I just had to bring that up.
Rym: Okay, that's all I'm not gonna rag on him because I've done it before now.
Rym: We're in a level playing field again.
Scott: I know you screw up.
Scott: I can rag on you again.
Rym: Yeah until you screw up and then we're even again.
Rym: exactly.
Scott: So you're the only gets rag done.
Scott: Cuz all your fault.
Rym: Anyway more importantly we mentioned yesterday Probably my favorite thing ever now.
Rym: I know I say that a lot.
Rym: But this is this is particularly special.
Rym: my man scrote's.
Scott: Okay, so you're hanging out over the weekend and our friend was showing us this game magic pencil magic Pendul a game that now like a year to have.
Rym: two years ago He says I got this awesome game that you need to see for the ps2.
Rym: I'll bring it when I visit.
Rym: he visited.
Rym: He brought the game.
Rym: He did not bring a PlayStation 2 and none of us owned one.
Rym: Oh, well, he says he'll bring it to Otakon.
Rym: With the ps2 forgets the ps2.
Rym: we go somewhere where we have a ps2 forgets the game.
Scott: He basically failed to show us this game forever.
Scott: So finally we go to his house.
Scott: So he shows us the game now.
Scott: The way the game was described to me is that I thought you drew some sort of two-dimensional Monster and then it came to life and fought other monsters.
Rym: Apparently you draw a three-dimensional monster.
Scott: three-dimensional monster But it's not quite as freeform as I had imagined.
Scott: but you can do a lot.
Rym: It's very freeform.
Rym: You can do a lot of things.
Scott: It's not as free as I hoped but it was still very free because what you hoped for was impossible.
Rym: with that level of Technology, I guess.
Scott: but where's the ps2 supposed to be able to control icvms with nukes on them?
Rym: Um Scott we got to the moon as the United States with something less powerful than my TI 85 Calculator before I overclocked it.
Scott: I know but remember when they could.
Scott: they didn't want Saddam to get ps2s.
Rym: Yeah You know what that brought back a whole bunch of sad memories.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway, yeah for all of our political leanings Clinton was awesome, but those weren't the best president's years.
Scott: I'll say that anyway, so He finally shows us this game and he shows us all the cool monsters.
Scott: He's made.
Scott: He's got like Godzilla looking thing and uh, no, there's a thing that looks like the big monsters from Nausicaa.
Rym: Yeah, he made some.
Rym: really he made a monster.
Rym: That was himself.
Rym: Yeah, now the thing is the monsters look pretty cool but they were alright.
Rym: and then he showed us how you draw a monster and the monsters he drawn became a Billion times more impressive.
Rym: because I can't imagine doing something like that in 3d with an analog thumb nub.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if there was a study this game needs a DS for real.
Scott: cuz on the ps2 you're really limited by the interface.
Rym: Yeah, this game on the DS would make gangbusters.
Scott: Anyway, it would go gangbusters.
Scott: He starts to draw a new monster to show us what a drawing a new monster is like.
Scott: he draws a blob with blob feet And blob arms and a blob head and we're like what the hell aren't you gonna draw like a penis?
Scott: and he?
Scott: In all the time of owning this game for years never drew a penis, can you believe that?
Scott: That would be the first thing that any reasonable person would draw.
Rym: Yeah I mean the DS proved to the world and I started a new thing.
Rym: where if you are given an Electronic media where in you can draw something.
Rym: the first thing any human being will draw is a penis.
Rym: If you do not draw a penis you were not a human being.
Scott: even Gabe who draws day in and day out You know goes up in front of a class of little kids teaches them how to draw a funny cartoon.
Scott: And what is the first urge?
Scott: don't drop penis don't drop penis don't drop penis.
Rym: So now I will note though that he didn't really play the game a lot since the DS came out and the DS was really the beginning of that trend.
Rym: Yeah, I guess it was because I mean before then there was the cock boat.
Rym: But other than that, I didn't really draw penises on a regular basis.
Rym: I've drawn more penises since the DS came out and then the rest of my life combined That is true.
Rym: Yeah, including the 11 to 14 year old years, which are key for penis drawing.
Scott: They are indeed the era.
Scott: in fact most penises is drawn but in our times there wasn't so much penis drawing.
Scott: There was a lot more stick figure with boobs drawing going on.
Rym: Really?
Scott: Yeah, at least in my town No one could really draw.
Rym: there wasn't much drawing.
Rym: The thing we would always do is we draw stick figure wars.
Rym: you draw like a thousand stick men with white heads Fighting a thousand stick men with blackheads and they all had guns.
Scott: Well, that was racist.
Rym: See it wasn't.
Rym: so much racism is that we couldn't draw and the only way we could differentiate Stickman was to color in the head or not color in the head anyway.
Scott: So he finally drew a penis in this game made a penis monster.
Rym: now Not only did he draw a penis but the whole room the whole front row crew who was there is sitting around Directing him like make the shaft longer make the head a different color make the balls brown and gnarly put some wrinkles on him Get some veins in there.
Scott: in the end I thought it was done, but they continued to add a bunch of scraggly nasty hair And some varicose veins of varying color.
Rym: now I'll note that every now and then he could go into this thing.
Rym: that would show you a rough idea of how it would look when it was walking when it was dancing when it was attacking when it was sad and When once it was mostly complete and he sets it to the dancing thing Scott who was staring at the screen?
Rym: Rapturously the entire time with rapt attention says oh Yeah, oh, yeah.
Scott: It wasn't oh, yeah like that.
Scott: It was oh, yeah, like oh, yeah, it's awesome.
Scott: It was freaking awesome.
Rym: It was more of a oh, yeah.
Scott: No, yeah was no.
Scott: Considering it was it was like Kool-Aid.
Rym: Oh, yeah No Because after you said that the entire room turns and looks at you there is exactly eight seconds of silence And then we all died roughly.
Scott: What does that say about you guys?
Rym: That we figured something out about your personal life, and it was hilarious.
Scott: But I think it's awesome when there's a hilarious dancing penis.
Rym: So we finally start playing the game and it just gets worse because first of all he names it scrotch in the game.
Scott: It was a perfect name.
Rym: I suggested testicles, you know a nice regal Roman sounding name king testicles.
Rym: But testicles croats was good.
Rym: and scrotch comes out and then this little girl comes out with her monster to fight our Monster and this little girl's monsters this little stuffed animal and the stuffed animal like runs over and bats at the penis and does a little bit of damage and then scrotch rears up and Does a horrible motion.
Scott: it's think of M bison psycho crusher You know turns horizontal flies through the air and bangs into the enemy only it's a headbutt in a in a in a penis Sort of way.
Rym: it just leans down and BAM or it'll do a nice spin where it kind of whips the testicles around and hits It.
Scott: yeah, it'll.
Scott: it'll spin around really rapidly You know just with the testicles Sort of like a helicopter blade only on the bottom and then whack the bad guy a few times with the nuts.
Rym: Because the worst thing was that as the final touch at Kate's request They added a little bit of stretchy spooge kind of hanging down from the tip.
Scott: That was kind of nasty Unnecessary if you ask me gratuitous.
Scott: one might say yeah, it definitely made it look uglier.
Scott: I mean it looks so nice and pristine.
Scott: before they added some of that shit.
Rym: I gotta say it was a little disturbing.
Rym: when he goes into the pasture You know where he keeps all his monsters.
Rym: you see it.
Rym: Just kind of frolicking in the grass and bounding around.
Scott: Yeah, it was rather unpleasant.
Rym: That is the story of scrotch.
Rym: I I implore Nintendo or anyone to make a game like that for the DS.
Scott: I Think the lesson learned is if you have a game that lets you draw a penis There's really no two ways around that now, it's really hard to avoid Alright news time.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Rym: We got some news.
Scott: so my news there.
Scott: You may not know this, but there's something called DS homebrew, and it's this whole Sorta.
Scott: Yeah, it's this group of people and this technology that allows you to do things with your Nintendo DS.
Scott: besides What Nintendo expects you to do with it?
Rym: Hey Scott?
Rym: Is it a witch's home?
Scott: No, it is not a witch's homebrew.
Scott: I got another question is it about which is homebrew?
Rym: no maybe anyway style.
Scott: So Basically what people would do is they would use the original was the pass me device You know which would allow you to take code from your computer and play it on your DS.
Scott: But then they went on and they got better things like the m3 And you know they got different kinds that they put like flash cartridges in the GBA slot And they'd put like boot cartridges in the DS slot that would stick out of your DS.
Scott: None of these things were very elegant and none of them were elegant solutions.
Scott: You know they would work, and you could play NES roms SNES roms GBA roms DS roms.
Scott: You could also do a lot of software written for the DS by just people.
Scott: you know I mean There's a. there's a comic reading software for the DS.
Scott: You could read comics on that thing.
Scott: They're mp3 players all sorts of stuff.
Rym: I gotta say the only reason I didn't get into it was that I never heard someone who had one have anything Particularly glowing to say about the one they had.
Scott: I mean there were some people who would flash the DS itself to replace the firm.
Rym: I'm gonna happen.
Scott: if there was a guy I saw a video of him doing it and if I had that guy do it for me I would have said okay, but I'm not gonna try that myself see.
Rym: the last time I did anything like that was when I modded my ps1 with a six-pin mod chip Mmm, and I I can't solder anymore.
Rym: I used to solder stuff all the time as a kid.
Rym: I you know circuits and stuff and I was playing around with electronics.
Rym: I was in science Olympiad.
Rym: I can't solder anymore soldering that mod chip.
Rym: I burned myself like nine times.
Scott: Yeah, I've also lost that skill mostly.
Scott: I gotta get it back.
Rym: It's not that useful anymore.
Rym: It's easier just to buy a new.
Rym: whatever thing broke that you're trying to fix.
Scott: Yeah, but what if you're trying to make something new?
Rym: I buy an IC or mod something anyway You get a mod chip the sticks on the outside.
Scott: Yeah There are flash me's and past me's and all this dreck that you had to deal with and it was all Expensive and confusing and nothing was perfect.
Scott: now.
Scott: There is a new thing called the DS - X dream and This is as pretty much as close as we're gonna get to perfection now.
Scott: It's a bit expensive.
Scott: It's like over a hundred bucks for this thing.
Scott: But what it is?
Scott: it's a DS cartridge that has a little tiny USB connector at the top so you can plug it into your computer and inside of this flash cartridge DS cartridge is 512 megabytes or 4 gigabits of flash memory and In that flash memory you can put DS roms mp3s And it's got a cool little you know menu system.
Scott: so you could.
Scott: you know a big DS ROM usually is only about 30 megabytes.
Scott: so you can put a whole lot of DS roms inside this one DS cartridge and Put it in your DS and then choose in the menu which DS game you want to play.
Scott: The best thing is that this fully supports, you know one cartridge play.
Scott: So if you have a ROM of say Mario Kart you can play it with.
Scott: you know All your friends even if they don't have Mario Kart.
Scott: and pretty much these guys Tested a whole bunch of different games and the only game that didn't work right was Pokemon diamond from Japan.
Rym: Oh well Yeah, I got to say if I actually jump on this boat and get some sort of play roms on my DS Nintendo and a lot of other companies are going to lose a lot of money because I bought bionic commando for $20.
Rym: If I could just play my ROM collection on my DS that is my roms Minus the roms that suck times $20 that they're losing and I'll say right now that I'll pirate them and I'll do that.
Rym: And that's the end of that question.
Scott: Yeah, the way I figured out if you want to play NES SNES.
Scott: Well, not SNES doesn't work so well but NES, you know GBA type roms you have to do is get one of these programs for your computer and You take that program and you take say an NES ROM and you feed it into the program and the program will spit out a Nintendo DS ROM of the NES game and you load that onto the cartridge to get it to play.
Scott: and That's how these things kind of work.
Scott: but DS doom Supposedly works even though one guy couldn't get it to work.
Scott: Everyone else could scum.
Scott: VM DS works So you can play monkey island on your DS of this thing.
Scott: Oh Yeah, this is this is a hot thing.
Rym: you see This wouldn't be an issue if these companies would all have to embrace the DS and brought out all these games that now we're pirating.
Scott: I know why the problem is is that you know, the DS can play GBA and DS games.
Scott: So I'm if I get one of these I'm not gonna be using it to play GBA and DS games.
Scott: Oh my DS.
Scott: if I want to do that, I'll just buy the game.
Scott: It's.
Scott: you know, I don't need to pirate that even though some you know I could understand 13 year old kids with no money doing that.
Scott: I'll excuse them me.
Scott: What do I care?
Scott: $30 DS game?
Scott: It's not like there's so many DS games.
Scott: I already have every DS game I want.
Rym: wouldn't need to pirate one for but like imagine if Sierra had just taken all the police quest space quest quest for glory games And put him out on the DS.
Scott: I would have bought them all.
Scott: but no they're not doing that.
Scott: And you know while I can get a lot of these games on my computer, you know I'm using Linux and we got a Mac downstairs and you know While I can emulate the games there or perhaps get the original versions there or get an actual like old NES out and play the old games.
Scott: It's so much effort and it's not portable.
Scott: If I got an NES game, I want to play it portably, you know.
Scott: and Rym look he's willing to pay for it.
Scott: He just bought bionic commando for the GBA.
Rym: Yeah but Strider counts as negative money as far as I'm concerned and mighty final fight is a pretty much useless game.
Scott: It's worth it to play one time.
Rym: Oh, yeah one time I've ever I already played it.
Rym: Yep before I bought this game I played it again to remind myself that the game involves drop kick drop kick drop kick drop kick drop kick drop kick.
Rym: That's how you win.
Rym: Yep right now.
Rym: I just spoiled the game.
Rym: if you drop kick everyone you can't lose.
Scott: but anyway, the point is is that this is awesome new cart that you can buy and You put it in your DS and you can.
Scott: your DS basically becomes this Programmable portable computer that can do all sorts of awesome things that it's not meant to do.
Rym: isn't James or someone gonna get this?
Scott: Yeah, I'm gonna convince someone to get it.
Scott: now that I figured out You know how it works.
Rym: We've often used James as our testbed for things.
Scott: Yeah I'm using him as the testbed for this department because he's a lot more interested in it than I am because he wants to program Some DS software.
Rym: we do too.
Rym: We just don't have time I know.
Scott: I know.
Rym: remember when we tried to get a DS dev kit Nintendo laughed at us.
Scott: Yeah Well now who's laughing?
Scott: now, I'm gonna get one for a hundred bucks and change You know Def Con.
Rym: Yeah Def Con on the DS.
Scott: Oh shit.
Rym: That would be Wow, I wonder if he thought of that.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I'm gonna email him and just say hey Did you consider putting Def Con on the DS?
Rym: Yeah, and I'll just fill the rest of the email with dollar signs.
Rym: All right speaking of dollar signs brand theft auto for You know, there's it's gonna have all these high-res polygons You know, I just got to say something real quick about Grand Theft Auto.
Scott: a great I played Grand Theft Auto 1 and in its day on the PC on DOS.
Scott: That was a fun game and then I played the expansions for Grand Theft Auto London Which is the same game only it was a little bit more fun because they said funny British things and the cars are cool And London was a lot more fun to drive around.
Rym: Why is that?
Rym: Why is it that British accents make things cooler at us in the
Rym: u.s.?
Scott: I don't know but the Austin Powers car was wicked cool.
Scott: anyway.
Scott: GTA 2 came out and it was basically the same game only they changed it.
Scott: It was darker and it was like it was just it wasn't good.
Scott: They had like these gang wars and crap and they added all this extra crap to the game.
Scott: It was no longer simply run around, you know for fun driving and running over people, you know, it got kind of bleh.
Scott: GTA 3 I played it once and I was like, oh well, this isn't the game It used to be.
Scott: screw this shit, but yet somehow it's the most popular game.
Rym: See, I enjoyed it because it was.
Rym: it was the first widely known sandbox kind of.
Rym: here's the world interact with it game.
Scott: But GTA 1 was like that.
Scott: GTA 3 was like a worse game, but they made it 3d without, you know It's like the game itself was 3d But it was the same as the 2d game only not
Rym: really Because the world was a lot more immersive being 3d and having better graphics and the way the game was.
Rym: it was more immersive and you Could do more.
Scott: Hey, not much more.
Rym: Yeah quite a bit more.
Scott: you shot people.
Scott: you beat people up your random over with cars.
Rym: Yeah, it was a lot more fun to me in the 3d.
Rym: But then again, I played the 3d.
Rym: exactly how long I could have enjoyed that about two hours.
Scott: Yeah I actually beat.
Scott: you know GTA 1.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But anyway, that's not my point.
Rym: Yeah I don't care at all.
Rym: People are allowed to enjoy grind theft auto Mm-hmm captain.
Rym: any game that I don't like sucks ass and people who play it are stupid.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: If I don't like it, I'm gonna say it sucks.
Scott: That's how.
Scott: that's what people say things suck when they don't like them.
Rym: No, no Cuz you always go the step further and say and you're wasting your time and you're stupid and you are Except you I recall last week would come home from work and play Sonic the fucking Hedgehog like - Sonic the Hedgehog 2 was awesome.
Scott: Okay, yeah.
Rym: anyway.
Rym: now Grand Theft Auto 4 is gonna be coming out for the PlayStation 3 and the Xbox 360.
Rym: No kidding, but they had announced a while ago There's going to be exclusive content on the Xbox 360. if you get that version of the game you get extra.
Rym: Now the news here is not a hundred percent verified yet, but they've got a source who they call source And I don't if whether it's true or not is not the issue.
Rym: But this sort of thing has been happening a lot lately.
Rym: The rumor is and I'll give it about a 75% chance being true Grand Theft Auto 4 is going to have alternate exclusive content for the PlayStation 3 release Uh-huh.
Rym: So it's kind of like when Soul Calibur 3 or 2 2 was released on three system I'm just gonna say that and each one, you know one had link had someone else one had someone else.
Rym: You can tell which one I cared about.
Scott: Yeah, and much most people cared about because apparently the GameCube was the most popular Soul Calibur 2 platform.
Rym: Yeah to anyone who thought the GameCube didn't do well.
Rym: I mean it outsold the Xbox worldwide and Soul Calibur 2 for the GameCube sold more than either for the other ones.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I think the ps2 sold more possibly but I think that like at tournaments and stuff people always played the GameCube one.
Rym: Well part of the thing remember it's kind of founding issues there I mean the GameCube one looked better because the PlayStation 2 was really kind of at the end of its life.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, it's still at the end of its life, but games are still coming out for it.
Rym: Yeah, and I'll bet games will keep coming out for it.
Scott: Yep for a while now.
Rym: What's bothered me now is that a lot lately people are saying?
Rym: Oh, this game is exclusive for three months and three months later.
Rym: It comes out on another platform Yep, and I guess it seems like such a dishonest and crappy business practice.
Rym: But yet people fall for it.
Rym: There are people who buy a console because of an exclusive game even though the game will come out for another console later.
Scott: Yeah, I mean that's the number one thing I use if I'm deciding on what console to buy.
Scott: my number one decision factor is the exclusive games.
Scott: because you know If there's a game that's gonna come out for the ps3 the Xbox 360 and the computer Well, and I really want the game then I'm gonna get the computer.
Scott: Why should I buy a console?
Scott: I have a computer, you know.
Scott: So it all comes down to okay.
Scott: If I'm gonna buy a console it has to have a lot of games that I need that console in order to play.
Scott: you know that are games that I must play that I can't live without playing somehow and You know Nintendo always seems to have the exclusives.
Scott: You're not gonna see Zelda hunt anywhere else and you know, you're not gonna see it anywhere else.
Rym: things of the day.
Scott: I Had another thing of the day planned, but it got.
Scott: I'm gonna push it back to tomorrow because My brother informed me I had a more important thing of the day to use.
Rym: See the thing is I could totally preempt your thing of the day now because I'm the one who found it and showed it to You.
Rym: I build it up for a whole day.
Rym: I was like I got this awesome thing and when you see it, you're gonna go.
Scott: it's my thing of the day.
Scott: I got dibs.
Scott: I called dibs and I'm gonna do it tomorrow.
Rym: But if what?
Rym: if I do it today, you could still do it tomorrow.
Rym: No Why not?
Scott: because it's already been done.
Scott: We never duplicate things of the day unless we forget.
Rym: Well, if I do it today, then it would be your choice to duplicate it tomorrow.
Scott: I already got dibs.
Scott: if you violate dibs, there will be consequences.
Rym: All right, fine I'll just say that Scott's thing of the day involves Batman Hey and Super Mario Brothers - stop giving away my things of the day.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah All right, you can give my things of the day away.
Scott: I forget everything that it is.
Scott: Really?
Scott: Yeah, what is it?
Rym: All right, so there's this game a little flash game that came.
Rym: Oh, yeah I can't remember now and Scott pointed me to it after.
Rym: well first he starts playing in his room and I hear him because whatever He wants attention.
Rym: He'll talk really loudly in his room hoping I'll walk in.
Rym: So I hear oh a game huh, oh Fuck fuck Fuck this game.
Rym: and he runs into my room and says you got to try this game and and you tried that game this game It's just.
Rym: you know those games where you got a little cursor and you get contribute.
Rym: Basically, you have a block that follows your mouse cursor.
Rym: You have to move it around an obstacle course without touching anything and get it to a goal.
Rym: No big deal.
Rym: This one reverses your mouse.
Rym: up is down left is right.
Scott: It really sucks in.
Scott: it really sucks.
Rym: Now I got to level 19 and I stopped only because it was late and we had to do the show.
Scott: It was indeed level 19.
Scott: I saw it.
Rym: we're not lying now this game Will.
Rym: it's painful to watch someone else play it.
Rym: It's painful to be more painful to play it because when you lose it makes this noise And you just and it's like shock therapy.
Scott: It really is just so irritating to even be near this game.
Rym: now something interesting Is that after I played the first two levels?
Rym: I got really really really good at it And now I can just sit down and get back to level 19 in about five minutes.
Scott: Oh, yeah, it's really a matter of patience it beating the game.
Rym: No, it's a matter of muscle memory.
Rym: If you play it for like an a half hour or so You can just use a backwards mouse.
Rym: fine.
Rym: Now.
Rym: I can just use a backwards mouse without even thinking about it.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, but I mean anyone can do that.
Scott: So it's just patience.
Scott: and are you gonna sit there and build that skill?
Scott: and once you do It's just how long are you gonna spend playing before you win?
Rym: I think the skill is permanent.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I'm gonna a week from now.
Rym: I'm gonna try to play the game cuz just now I played the game and I literally went level one two three four five six Seven eight.
Rym: without even trying I could just move the mouse around backwards.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: However, I'm not to get to that point I had to play the game for over a half hour yesterday and got fucking damn.
Scott: Was that worth it?
Rym: Yeah, I think it was.
Rym: All right, and you know what?
Rym: It's more worth it than learning to type into for ack Haha.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So what was your thing of the day?
Scott: All right, so today Is a special day.
Scott: It is Tuesday the 17th.
Scott: Oh shit You may not realize this but Tuesday the 17th only occurs alongside a Friday the 13th.
Rym: It is in fact the unluckiest day of the year.
Scott: It is indeed the unluckiest day of the year now.
Rym: Luckily.
Rym: We had some beef carcasses today.
Rym: So we're okay.
Scott: We're okay with our beef carcasses.
Scott: now my brother.
Scott: I am me and he was like bad juju.
Scott: That's all he said and I immediately knew what he was talking about and sent him a YouTube link To my thing of the day, which is an episode of Ren and Stimpy.
Scott: That is very old that we both remember called.
Scott: What's it called?
Scott: like Stimpy or superstitious Stimpy is the name of the episode?
Rym: I had totally forgotten about this holiday.
Rym: Yeah, I mean this is right up there with shouted the sky day and International talk like a pirate day International Day of Slayer.
Scott: Yep superstitious Stimpy is an episode of Ren and Stimpy where it's Tuesday the 17th and Rym is Rym Rym.
Rym: Haha, I guess that makes you Stimpy.
Rym: no anyway picture catch you catch you pitch you pitch you get you get you get snow.
Scott: Good red red is really unlucky.
Scott: in fact he's the unlucky beast like.
Scott: he was born on Tuesday the 17th and he has webbed toes and They basically really make fun of superstitions.
Scott: but they they're also true in the episode where people get hit with lightning because they do something unlucky and It's pretty hilarious.
Scott: and today's Tuesday the 17th.
Scott: My brother used to think he was born on Tuesday the 17th because he was born on a 17th.
Scott: But I just checked and he was born on Monday the 17th.
Rym: Whoa lucky.
Rym: Yeah Well, if he hadn't been lucky he would have been born on this Tuesday the 17th exactly.
Scott: just to clarify Superstitions are all bullshit.
Rym: Yeah, except apparently throwing salt over your shoulders.
Scott: It's not a superstition It's a. it's a ritual just like pen says.
Rym: I won't bring it up in too detail now because I don't want to go long in the episode But I recall you getting quite perturbed at one point when we prevented you from throwing the salt over your shoulder.
Scott: You got rituals you do like what?
Rym: Stuff like what?
Rym: I'm curious.
Rym: I'm not denying it, but I'd like to hear some evidence.
Scott: What are some of rims ritual?
Rym: Ha Scott can't come up with anything Besides.
Rym: Scott is the one who was so anti Religion spirituality philosophy anything and getting through salt over his shoulder to keep the demons away It's not to keep the demons away.
Scott: There's nothing wrong with doing things as long as you don't, you know.
Rym: Well, I'll note that the reason you gave us for many years that you did it was quote because otherwise something bad will happen.
Scott: No, I didn't say that.
Scott: Yes, you did said something will happen.
Scott: Okay Something will happen.
Scott: something always happens.
Scott: something's happening right now Who knows.
Rym: so it's okay to make a pedantic kind of BS argument like that.
Scott: It's okay to have a meaningless ritual if it's not harmful.
Rym: World of Warcraft is a meaningless ritual.
Scott: Oh, it's not.
Scott: that takes way too much time.
Scott: Why if all right, if you're ritual because you're wasting salts?
Scott: salt is wasting salt.
Rym: You're also making a mess.
Scott: that's not harmful either.
Scott: the salt you make things clean right whatever?
Rym: today We're going to talk about Japanese versus puzzle games because over the weekend We didn't bring any board games to the northern geek house.
Rym: We pretty much just played video games hung out and drank a little Yep, and we watched one movie, but I slept.
Rym: Yeah, it wasn't that good a movie.
Rym: I was really disappointed.
Scott: Oh good I'm glad I slept.
Rym: Yeah For reference the movie was all the Queen's Men, which would have been a useless movie But it had Eddie Izzard in it and it had some really good lines, but the movie was overall kind of met all right.
Scott: Anyway for those of you don't realize you know we play Tetris in this country And I think we play.
Scott: what are the games?
Scott: they play?
Scott: bejeweled and you know all those puzzle games were stuff falls from the top And you guide it to the bottom or stuff falls from the top and you kind of move stuff around to arrange it in a better fashion.
Scott: and And Well in Japan there's a lot more of those that we never get to see or They get turned into something else before they come over to this country.
Rym: Not only that just the whole genre of that a versus style puzzle game for things fall from the sky and time as a factor Is really more advanced over there?
Scott: Yeah, if you try to play like for example Cardcaptor Sakura Tetris.
Scott: right you play this thing on the PlayStation in Japan.
Scott: now It's Tetris only it has Cardcaptor Sakura on it.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: It has a nice theme very nice.
Scott: however, if you play versus mode you actually choose a character and Depending on which character you choose when you do damage to the opponent your character will do damage in a different pattern Based on the character you choose and some characters are actually better than others and drop more dangerous patterns on the enemy.
Scott: You know you ever play some good examples or in the u.s.
Scott: Would be super puzzle fighter where your street fighter guy does attacks to the other side.
Scott: Only imagine the character mattering a lot more.
Scott: Japan has a lot of games like this.
Rym: yeah, basically I would say that these games aren't so much puzzle games as they are fighting games.
Rym: They're just abstract fighting games.
Scott: Yeah, I guess you could look at it that way.
Scott: You know it's a fighting game.
Scott: We know cuz reflexes and control of the gamepad matter just as much.
Scott: Only it's more about quick thinking and it's sort of like you know.
Scott: you solve your puzzle in a way That you know causes an attack.
Scott: so instead of just pushing a button to make an attack happen You sort of build an attack on in your board and then unleash it at the critical moment while your opponent might unleash attacks on you which you know mess up your board and Defeat your ability to release attacks.
Rym: now normally we talk about how awesome We are at things, but we're not the old-school masters of these games.
Rym: in fact I had never seen these games until I got to RIT and at the RIT Anime Club social nights I saw a lot of people older than me playing these games Very quickly and very well.
Scott: Yeah, we suck relatively speaking.
Scott: I mean I could probably beat most of the listeners until oh wait a way to throw down my.
Scott: Okay, I mean the listeners who?
Scott: because who else is there this?
Scott: meet you me and the listeners, right?
Scott: So I could buy beat most listeners who never played the game before But I imagine a lot of them would advance their skill rapidly and thwart us.
Rym: see like we'll be.
Rym: watch our friend Adam And our friends go Joe play the game right.
Scott: they would kick our ass every time watching them play each other.
Rym: the game looks really Easy, and they're just throwing stuff around.
Rym: throwing stuff around throwing stuff around.
Rym: then five minutes later someone dies.
Rym: So then I sit down next to him like Adam, and I play.
Rym: I Died within 11 seconds, yeah I'm like.
Scott: I'm thinking this game is completely unfair because I have no chance to do anything at all.
Scott: I'm like.
Scott: this is just bullshit.
Scott: screw this game.
Scott: It's not worth it.
Rym: so one of the games We play this weekend was magical drop.
Scott: magical drop is a classic.
Scott: I think they're actually newer ones like magical drop F or magical drop J Or s. I don't know the letters.
Rym: the games are that.
Rym: the gameplay is very simple.
Rym: you can.
Rym: Gems of different color are coming down in pad in square patterns from the sky, and they're basically it's like Tetris upside down.
Scott: Yep, like this is bored growing on top of you, and you can think of it like Stalag tights coming down from the ceiling.
Rym: yeah because remember Stalagmites might hang from the ceiling But they don't right.
Scott: and you're this little jester and the jester is at the bottom of the screen.
Rym: see I don't think you're the jester.
Rym: I think you are the Ranging between cute and slightly edgy girl standing in the background of the jester is your minion?
Scott: Okay, you could put it that way, but anyway you control the jester and the jester can do two things.
Scott: He can pull balls from the top of the screen into notes Yeah into his hands skirt And he can take all the balls in his hands skirts and toss them up to the top of the screen.
Scott: Those are the two things he can do.
Rym: now There's different colors, and the goal is to get what three four four in a row I think for a number in a row vertically of one color.
Rym: if you cause that to happen then Every gemmy of that color touching those will disappear in addition to those mm-hmm.
Scott: So let's say there's a horizontal row of blue balls.
Scott: you you go to the far left You pick up you pull the blue ball down into your hand.
Scott: you go right you pull down another blue ball.
Scott: You go to the right you take the two blue balls You're holding and throw them to the top of the screen.
Scott: now You've got three blue balls in one vertical column.
Scott: they disappear But they're touching this horizontal row of blue balls that are still remaining.
Scott: all those disappear as well.
Rym: Yeah, because if blue balls are touching a horizontal row of blue balls That's the best way to get rid of blue balls of course.
Scott: now the problem is you can only hold one color ball at the same time.
Scott: So if you're holding a blue ball you can't pull down a yellow ball or a green ball.
Rym: So if you see you know you can say there's five blue balls You can grab.
Rym: you go grab grab grab grab.
Rym: then you throw them all in one spot and make them all go away.
Scott: You got to toss up the blue balls before you can grab the green balls, and there's other things.
Rym: I mean depending on what character you are.
Rym: because every time you make things go away or get combos it drops Bad things on the other person's screen the little slimes with eyeballs, and they will know that's battle That's a different game.
Scott: All right.
Rym: That's battle balls.
Scott: I'm thinking wrong game Yeah, drops ice cubes and all sorts of other nasty.
Rym: It just drops other stuff on the other guy's screen does damage them.
Rym: the pattern of the damage depends on what character you play.
Scott: for Example one character does a lot of damage in the middle.
Scott: so if you want to defeat this character You're gonna have to have a strategy where you take balls from the middle and put them on the sides Or else the middle row is gonna get really long and come down and stab you right away When the sides are gonna be really shallow and not near killing you.
Rym: I'll note that if you've never played these games before it doesn't matter.
Rym: You'll just lose.
Rym: Basically yeah unless I mean when Scott and I played against each other was fine because we both really sucked and the game actually Was playable hmm?
Scott: Well, I think what makes the games interesting in general is that if you play something like Tetris It's the same every time.
Scott: it's who's gonna play Tetris better.
Scott: but these characters while they might unbalance the game at points and What they do is they force the the other the opponent to change up how they play the game in order to win.
Scott: You know if I play the game in a certain way all the time and you use a different character it drastically changes the pattern of the pieces I have to play with and I'm forced to completely change my Strategy or lose unless you don't know what you're doing in which case it doesn't matter okay.
Scott: the other game We played was battle balls.
Rym: Right after we Generated and played with throats for about an hour.
Scott: right now my first playing a battle balls I was playing against someone is really good, and I couldn't do anything.
Scott: So I thought the game was complete crap and useless And I was right about some of that and not so right about some of that You know, but it wasn't as impossible as I thought it was.
Scott: But it's still a little bit annoying and a little bit luck-based at points.
Rym: my experience with the game was thus I have a little triangle of balls falling all right.
Rym: I'll let him fall somewhere.
Rym: Oh look they rolled out They spread out.
Rym: Oh another set.
Rym: who?
Rym: I can get those colors to line up.
Rym: Hey, it didn't fall where I wanted it to do.
Rym: what the fuck.
Rym: I'm dead.
Scott: Yeah, see the problem with this game Is that you have these balls.
Scott: then they come down in sets of three and they're different colors.
Scott: And if you can you know you put them down and if any of them are kind of not balanced properly They'll fall down.
Scott: and you know roll around until they land somewhere.
Scott: yep Yep, so think of it.
Scott: like you know you're taking a bunch of pebbles in your hand And you just let go of them.
Scott: you know some of them land on top of the pile and stay there.
Scott: some of them roll down the sides.
Scott: Now if you match up enough balls of the right color touching each other they disappear And that causes the balls on top of them to fall down which in turn Hopefully will make another set of colored balls that will disappear and cause a chain reaction Eventually doing extreme damage to the opponent.
Rym: the goal of experienced players seems to be to Set up a giant combo build and build and build and build and build and build and build.
Rym: and then it's kind of a Bringsmanship thing where both people are building.
Rym: if you set off a combo and the other person sets off a combo while you're doing it To counter your combo They basically end up doing more damage to you than you do to them because they counter it and then they counter attack.
Scott: Yeah, the timing has a lot to do with it Which is why you know we did say it's more.
Scott: It's a lot like a fighting game And you know I mean normally the combo the other guy did would have just done a whole bunch of damage.
Scott: You know if you play Tetris if I get a Tetris and Rym gets a Tetris it evens out.
Scott: Imagine if the timing of when you set off the Tetris caused.
Scott: you know the guy who does it at the right moment actually does More damage to the opponent.
Scott: it adds this whole other level to the game instead of just putting the things in the right places But putting them in the right places at the right time.
Scott: sometimes you want to go slow sometimes you want to go fast.
Rym: now This is the game that has that horrible damage thing.
Rym: Damage seems to come in the in the form of little slimies that fall into your board and any time They come across one of your balls They grab it and turn that color.
Rym: now they count as walk that color and you can destroy them by destroying normal balls next to.
Rym: But you can't destroy them on their own.
Rym: and furthermore when you destroy them the slime goes away and the ball They originally were remains.
Scott: Yeah, so you basically have two kinds of balls this the colored balls and there's colored balls with eyeballs.
Scott: And if it has eyeballs that's not good.
Scott: and when you get damaged you bet your screen basically fills up with eyeballs.
Scott: normally There's only a few eyeballs on your screen But when you get damaged there's a lot of eyeballs on your screen a whole lot of eyeballs And you can't get rid of an eyeball unless you match up some non eyeballs on top of them and Often playing against a good opponent They'll fill your screen with eyeballs to the point where you have no room on top of the eyeballs to make any matches whatsoever Unless you're really really lucky and the pieces that you get you know don't have any eyeballs in them.
Scott: And then all the other opponent has to do is you know let's say I'm near the top of the screen but I can still make a match and clear the whole screen away.
Scott: I Put down a piece then he drops a few more eyeballs on me.
Scott: I'm done.
Scott: There's no way I can win That's it.
Scott: There's eyeballs there.
Scott: There's no way to get rid of them.
Scott: There's no room game over.
Scott: and That's.
Scott: what kind of bothered me is that it felt like you know when you weren't dead you were dead anyway.
Scott: And I really don't think a game should have that situation where you know if I have lost it should be game over.
Scott: You know it's kind of annoying when it's game over, but it's not game over yet.
Scott: I disagree in this game because one that situation lasts about five seconds It does But it's still annoying and I go through this five seconds of time where I'm trying to save myself.
Rym: That's theirs.
Rym: because if you were actually good that Usually you're not as hurt and that gives you the chance to if you had a combo set up to get to it.
Scott: Sometimes there is a small there was a small chance.
Scott: You know and people did escape from that horrible situation.
Scott: However it mostly depended on what balls they were given which is random and not a matter of skill.
Rym: The situation that most lasts a few seconds is not a big deal in this game.
Rym: Yeah
Scott: the other thing that bothered me is like you know I would set up a big combo and I would just need one particular colored Ball to set it off, and I wouldn't get that colored ball for like you know too many pieces in which case It didn't matter anymore need a completely different color And I never get exactly what I need.
Scott: and It's just kind of annoying because you know all the timing in the world and all the nice setup in the world won't help You if the game doesn't give you the color that you want.
Rym: it also has the interesting mechanic that the game is pretty much Symmetrical both people get the same pieces.
Rym: imagine playing Tetris where everyone gets a square Then everyone gets a line then everyone gets another square.
Scott: Yeah, it's kind of tricky though I mean it doesn't.
Scott: you know as people really start playing you know one guy either drops away more pieces than the other guy and Then one guy gets attacked And it doesn't really you know matter so much anymore.
Scott: And you know who knows where in the sequence of balls each guy is.
Rym: well Yeah, but you get the same starting sequence, so you start on a perfectly level playing field.
Scott: Well, you know it's it seems perfectly level.
Scott: But then you know a couple eyeballs will fall down and that mixes up the whole thing.
Rym: But that's after the start.
Rym: I said you start with a perfectly even playing field.
Scott: yeah, I guess.
Scott: so It just doesn't really.
Scott: it's not really equal.
Rym: It is kind You're just gonna blame because you suck at the game, and I also suck at the game.
Rym: But I accept that fact and move on.
Scott: yeah, well I accept the fact that I suck at the game.
Scott: I'm just pointing out.
Scott: You know these slight imperfections in its puzzling.
Rym: Yeah, I mean there are a lot more games like this like put your pop and whatever.
Scott: Yeah, put your pop.
Scott: That's the one where you just drop the little eyeball guys and match the colors.
Rym: now You shoot them up.
Scott: I think I don't remember.
Rym: There's a million of these games.
Scott: Yeah one other one I just want to talk about real quick is panel day pawn Which you might not know as Pokemon Puzzle League for the n64.
Scott: They changed it to Pokemon when they brought it over here because they figured otherwise no one would want it.
Scott: But it's actually this really kind of good puzzle game.
Scott: where?
Scott: You you know there's a bunch of squares of different colors And you kind of flip them and you try to match them up.
Scott: You know to be the same color like you know.
Scott: oh, there's a red and a blue next to each other.
Scott: Let me you know make them switch places now.
Scott: There's three Reds in a row, and they disappear and it came out.
Scott: Oh, no, or did it not come out.
Scott: I can't remember they.
Rym: oh if I had a thought bird It would play right now.
Scott: They made a GBA compilation of puzzle games, and they put dr.
Scott: Mario, and it was either panel day pawn or something else on there.
Scott: It was original Yoshi's cookie And I know she's cookie is a bad game.
Scott: I like Yoshi's cookie.
Scott: I think they took out panel day pawn which they were gonna put on there originally which kind of sucks because I like it.
Scott: But yeah, that's it's another similar game.
Scott: You know you choose a character and that changes the kind of stuff that happens to the other guy.
Rym: Yeah, if you see these games around they're the best places to find them are usually at anime conventions.
Scott: Another good place is just anywhere you can get PlayStation roms.
Scott: I mean we're talking about PlayStation roms anyway.
Scott: They're all Japanese games, but the menus are pretty simple.
Scott: I mean you go to one player.
Rym: not only do you not need to know Japanese to play the game?
Rym: But even if you have trouble there are a million facts and walkthroughs and translations because these games are very popular in the u.s.
Rym: Among anime fans and hardcore gamers.
Scott: I think most of it has to do with the fact that a lot of them like I said card captor Sakura Tetris and Game like magical drop has an anime intro to it.
Scott: You know they're all anime characters or anime style characters that you're choosing from and that really appeals to anime fans.
Scott: Something else you just want to warn anyone about who tries to play a Japanese PlayStation game because most of these are PlayStation games.
Scott: is That in America?
Rym: X is yes, and you know square or triangle is which I never got because I played Japanese games from PlayStation Long before I ever played an actual English game.
Rym: It makes sense.
Rym: circle yes X no.
Rym: why did they change it?
Scott: in America, I don't know.
Scott: but In Japan and all these Japanese games circle is yes And X is no.
Scott: so when you want to go through the menu to the game you have to push circle.
Scott: if you push X You're gonna go back out into the menu again.
Scott: You don't want to do that.
Scott: I Just you know it gets a lot of people the first time they sit down to play one of these things And you're trying to progress through the menu and you get to the character select screen And they push X and you're like what did you do now?
Scott: We're gonna go back push circle, and then they push X again.
Scott: It's like goddamn.
Scott: it don't push X.
Rym: Yeah, so you just gotta have scrotch there to tell you what to do.
Rym: I guess I guess we're thinking scrotch should become the mascot.
Rym: We're gonna try to get a picture of him off of the PlayStation game to put up for everyone to see.
Scott: That's a good idea.
Scott: I think it's absolutely necessary.
Rym: Yeah, I haven't searched to see if anyone else has done it And I'm sure Adam is working on a better version of scrotch,
Scott: and you know if You want to make scrotch do his thing make sure you push circle,
Rym: and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Scott: make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.