Rym: It's Thursday November 30th.
Rym: I'm Rym and I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight.
Rym: we take a look back at the previous 221 episodes we've done for a little bit of meta discussion.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: You know, it was kind of weird today riding my bike at night Being the fact that it's the end of November December starts.
Rym: what tomorrow?
Scott: Yeah, tomorrow's December 1.
Rym: Yeah, so I'm riding my bike at night In shorts and a tank top.
Rym: I ride past a house that not only has Christmas lights up But the Christmas lights are illuminating the bright green lawn.
Rym: Yeah, and we live in New York.
Scott: I think the weirdest part about it is the night part because you know, it's.
Scott: it's so weird now on the way home I got to use the headlights and it's like dark but you realize that happens every year.
Scott: That's not weird at all I know but that's my I feel every year.
Scott: It's like whoa drastic change.
Rym: Okay, so you're saying it's weird that something that's happened every year since the dawn of earth Happened again this year.
Rym: and yet I'm saying it's weird that it's basically December and I'm riding my bike at night in shorts and a t-shirt.
Scott: Yeah, you know what?
Scott: It means though.
Scott: It means that we're gonna have snow and March and possibly April doesn't mean that at all.
Rym: We don't know what it means.
Scott: No, but that's probably what it means.
Rym: I'll bet it means the opposite.
Rym: I'll bet not only did when the fall basically not happen and it just stayed summer until now.
Rym: But it's probably going to be a short winter and it's gonna be.
Scott: Until now there were a couple weeks of coldness coldness.
Scott: It never dropped below like 50 during the day at all Even once there was a week or two where I had to wear a coat.
Rym: what when I didn't wear a coat?
Scott: Well, this is you didn't doesn't mean everyone else wasn't.
Rym: Yeah, I mean Pete don't need to wear coats.
Scott: Yeah Pete's been complaining about the cold lately because he lost weight.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So so yeah, apparently it frightens you that it gets dark out in the winter.
Scott: Yeah dark is scary.
Scott: Warm is not scary.
Scott: dark is even though I like dark better.
Rym: But I can think of warm things that are scary and dark things that aren't scary.
Scott: I can think of the opposite so that doesn't mean shit.
Rym: Anyway, it means your correlation is false.
Scott: You know, it's scary the we froze today.
Rym: Yeah, actually that happened a little while ago.
Rym: Scott was playing bowling or something.
Rym: I was making a D&D character and suddenly it freezes the we just freezes and starts making this noise.
Scott: No, it wasn't actually making a noise.
Scott: What had happened was it was in the process of making a noise like out of the speakers of the TV and it froze And just held the tone.
Rym: Uh, it sounded like that noise was coming from the unit.
Scott: It wasn't when I went up to the unit I listened in.
Scott: it was coming out of the speakers of the TV.
Scott: You're sure I'm a hundred percent sure.
Rym: Okay still the point is your.
Scott: we froze It froze up and I had to turn unplug it plug it back in and then it was all good.
Rym: What are you gonna do about that?
Rym: What if it freezes again?
Scott: if it keeps freezing too many times?
Scott: so far It's frozen once and I don't remember but I might have like banged my foot on the floor.
Scott: That could have been the cause, you know.
Scott: Considering the nature of a lot of the games that are played on the Wii I know but if it continues to freeze more times, I'll just get a new one for Nintendo Alright, so what's the over-under here?
Scott: if we were to make a wager under as to whether or not it'll freeze again If it freezes when I'm fighting a boss in Zelda and I have to redo a lot of stuff and I get pissed off Then I'll get a new.
Rym: I'll bet that within 14 days.
Rym: It freezes again.
Rym: I just that's my hunch.
Rym: I will go up to 14 days at a considerable sum.
Scott: No, we'll find out.
Rym: Well, you don't want to take the wager.
Scott: No, not really not.
Rym: Because don't you trust Nintendo?
Rym: Yeah, so you don't trust Nintendo.
Scott: I don't bet if it's not a sure thing But that's stupid.
Scott: It's smart.
Scott: I always win.
Rym: No, cuz you're always betting on things.
Rym: You're betting that you won't crash when you drive to work.
Scott: You're bad.
Scott: I don't.
Rym: but you're betting it's not a sure thing.
Scott: It's a sure thing.
Scott: I won't crash.
Rym: No steamroller could just pop out or a car could steamroller just pop out.
Scott: They're so slow.
Rym: a car could just ram you And we could be stopped at a traffic light.
Scott: if a guy rams me he wins.
Rym: oh, yeah I'm not saying he doesn't win.
Rym: I'm saying you're betting that that won't happen cuz you could.
Rym: the only sure bet is to not go out the door.
Scott: a sure enough Bet.
Rym: well, so what's the threshold of so sure enough?
Rym: What's the line?
Rym: What makes something a sure bet?
Rym: Cuz nothing sure where I'm sure you're sure.
Rym: So your threshold of sureness is not a hundred percent proof sureness.
Scott: No, okay.
Rym: That's all I wanted you to say.
Rym: Anyway, I'm actually on my way to work.
Rym: I passed a fatal accident again Two days in a row.
Rym: I have passed a fatal a fatal accident today, and I'm not sure if it was a fatal accident Yesterday and they were both at approximately the same spot on my way to the commute.
Scott: watch out for that spot.
Rym: It's a straight road And both of them were single car accidents.
Rym: The thing is what was sad is I was.
Rym: you know the driver appeared to be fine And I'm pretty sure was the passenger who got killed And it looked like they died.
Rym: they weren't wearing their seatbelt because the oh well the windshield where the passenger was was shattered with a more shattered a head-shaped spot and A red spot in the middle of that where you got damn seatbelt.
Rym: if you don't and you deserve what you get yeah It's just the fact that there were two acts.
Rym: not only that there were two.
Rym: You know these two accidents at the same spot on my way to work on my way home today There was an accident at the same spot on the northbound side And again, it was a single car accident.
Scott: I didn't see any accidents today But I saw a lot of activity of ambulances and police cars driving really fast and going somewhere.
Scott: So that's usually either an accident or a fire or something like that.
Rym: see I knew it was a bad sign.
Rym: I was driving to work and a police car came up behind me, and I was going like 80 85 But I wasn't like I was feeding it relative to the rest of the traffic.
Rym: Everyone was going that fast and the cop didn't pull anyway.
Rym: He just kind of pulls up behind us we all get out of his way, and he speeds off at like a hundred and Then you know I keep driving.
Scott: then another cop car passes me And I started easy - that means there's an accident pretty much all the time.
Rym: And sure enough five minutes later I get to this accident and the road was totally blocked a couple days ago.
Scott: There was an accident in Connecticut on Exit 23.
Rym: I get all I saw signs warning me about that on the way to the taconic.
Scott: Yeah, what I was?
Scott: I get off exit 20 end.
Scott: ah which is three exits before.
Rym: that was it blocked past your exit?
Scott: No But when I was at exit 18 There was like this huge slow down for like half a mile that I pretty sure was a wave of Slowness caused by the accident.
Rym: we should talk about traffic waves sometime.
Scott: sometime We should because actually it's funny.
Rym: every I've I've witnessed five or six accidents during my commute and almost all of them Were caused during a traffic wave and in more than half of them the person who caused the accident had out-of-state plates.
Rym: I think that people who aren't used to traffic waves don't expect them Because I don't think they happen in a lot of places in this country to the degree that they happen in downstate, New York.
Rym: I mean literally you'll be driving Around here and traffic will be going 75 85 and then suddenly this wave will pass through and all the cars will be going 10 And then 30 seconds later traffic suddenly go in 75 again.
Rym: Yeah, no reason no accident nothing There's no warning it just comes out of nowhere.
Scott: I mean there are ways to bust up a traffic wave, but you have to know it's coming and prepare for it.
Rym: Yeah, actually the best way to prevent traffic.
Rym: Well, no, we'll do a show on it instead.
Scott: lots of do lots of Don't leave lots of space between you and the car in front of you.
Scott: Well, they're gonna eat it up at the right, right?
Rym: Yep, yep And yeah, of course the thing is you can't.
Rym: you do much to traffic waves in front of you But you can prevent them for people behind you by gunning it.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, yeah, it's just scary how many accidents I see on the way to work.
Scott: All right, you got a news.
Rym: I do have a news and I talked more about it, but I want to turn it into a regular show.
Rym: But I don't want to do it as the show tonight because it's something that I think.
Scott: so We'll try to limit our talk about this news.
Rym: I'm just gonna bring up the issue and I don't think I need to say What my feelings might be or what the problem here is, you know, let's try it.
Rym: an exercise.
Rym: I'm going to say certain facts and you can infer whatever opinions you want about these.
Rym: one according to recent data Seven million people as in one in every 32 American adults is behind bars on probation or on parole.
Rym: alrighty one in 32 if you count our extended friend group then Statistically several of our friends should be in jail or at least on parole or probation.
Rym: Yeah probation Yeah, not that much difference As far as I'm concerned to me because it doesn't affect me because I'll never be on any of those things.
Scott: No, probably not.
Rym: if either of us gets arrested It'll probably be by some secret police and we'll be shot in a back alley against the wall.
Scott: Probations really not so bad.
Rym: What do you know?
Rym: Well, how does probation work Scott?
Rym: What exactly does it entail?
Rym: How specifically is it different from parole?
Rym: what bodies adjudicated and administer it?
Scott: It's sort of like academic probation.
Scott: It's like you're doing bad, but not bad enough to go to jail yet.
Scott: So we're gonna keep an eye on you to make sure you don't do anything bad.
Rym: Yeah Well probation is like yeah, you fucked up.
Rym: You're guilty.
Rym: We're gonna put you on probation if you do anything wrong.
Rym: We're throwing books at you.
Rym: Yeah, I'm sure someone will yell at us and say that technically whatever.
Scott: It's a good general Saying specifically what it is.
Rym: now, I don't know specifically what it is and Generally what it rolls when you were in jail and they let you out But if you screw up you're coming right back in or something to that effect.
Scott: Yep, but one in 32 Americans Think about American adults kid, you know, that doesn't count the yeah.
Rym: Well, the thing is it's almost all males.
Rym: So it counts the whole population, but most people in prison are males.
Rym: So if you just look at males, then the number is significantly scarier than one in 32.
Rym: Well, in fact and there are some areas in America not a lot But there are areas where if you're African American and you're a man It is more likely that you have been in jail or on parole than that.
Rym: You have not Yikes.
Rym: Yeah, not.
Rym: that doesn't imply any racism.
Rym: that implies just data a lot of bad things.
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: But another scary statistic is that prison populations are increasing despite the fact that prison releases are also Increasing.
Scott: that means prison entries are increasing faster than prison releases are increasing.
Rym: Yes, I don't think you needed to say the other increasing on the end.
Rym: I think it was implied.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah a little tired.
Rym: Yeah, both of us because it's Thursday We've had a we and I didn't play Zelda today.
Scott: I played boxing a hundred times to get pro level tomorrow playing Zelda See.
Rym: instead of doing the show like I should have been doing I was making a D&D character I was riding my bike and I was writing or playing Really cheesy rock music on this keyboard.
Scott: Okay, so what else is in your news there?
Rym: Well according to this also of the increase in prisoners a full half are Nonviolent drug of their drug related offenses.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Scott: All righty.
Rym: Yeah This isn't in the article, but it's related information.
Rym: America has the highest prison population of any country in the world.
Rym: not per capita But raw.
Rym: we have more prisoners than China or Russia.
Scott: Wow It's scary.
Rym: not people on parole actual prisoners people in jail currently behind bars.
Rym: Can't get out.
Rym: Now if you look at per capita, it's a little bit better.
Rym: percentage wise we're number two.
Rym: Oh Number one is Rwanda.
Scott: Oh Rwanda Yeah, where they put like half the people in jail?
Rym: As far as I Rwanda could just be a giant wall around the country.
Scott: yeah, so Rwanda is the only place worse than the US in terms of locking people up.
Rym: now I could go on and on about these statistics.
Rym: just read this article and I suggest you read the Wikipedia's and various statistics about prison populations and what Offenses people who are in prison Have been convicted of and the rate.
Rym: it's kind of scary and it's amazing that despite the fact that America is viewed by many As a free country we incarcerate more people than any other country in the world and most of them are incarcerated because They hurt themselves and didn't hurt anyone else.
Rym: Yeah, well, I think it was Jimmy Carter Before Congress, he was talking about the drug war and he effectively said that the punishment for doing drugs should not cause more harm Than the drugs themselves cause.
Rym: Oh burn wiser words have not been spoken about that.
Rym: I'm not gonna say that it's cool to take crystal meth and freak out all the time.
Scott: No, that's so.
Rym: or or take heroin until you die in an alley.
Rym: But if you punish someone for doing that worse than the drugs were gonna hurt him in the first place.
Scott: Man, yeah, the thing is is like it's someone doing meth right out in the middle of nowhere.
Scott: That kind of sucks, I don't really want them doing that but they can do whatever they want.
Scott: They're hurting themselves pretty bad.
Rym: Yeah, well meth heads tend to hurt other people too.
Rym: There's a problem there and making meth is a really dangerous bad thing.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: But you know for the most part they're hurting themselves.
Scott: most damages on them And if we you know Put them in jail, that's even more harm on to them.
Rym: But now you think these people get help when they're in jail.
Scott: But the thing is what you're really doing when you put him in jail is doing more harm to me.
Scott: I got to pay for that jail.
Rym: The thing is I would rather pay for free drug support programs for people.
Rym: I say there should anyone who wants to get off drugs go to the government and get help.
Rym: the thing is it has to be Science help though not narking on bullshit brandy help.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is most people in prison are either drug offenders violent crazy criminals insane people and drunk people Except in many cases.
Rym: They rarely send drunk drivers to jail.
Rym: They just find them a bunch of money and then they end up on the road again.
Scott: Anyway, I mean like not prison but jail like overnight jail is most of what police do.
Scott: Drunk people, you know, you're drunk.
Scott: You're going to jail.
Rym: Well, I think it depends a lot on the area.
Scott: It does it does but it's like we could fix some of those problems.
Scott: The only people who really need to be in a jail or jail equivalent are the crazy violent people.
Scott: We could take all the nuts and we can you have nut houses again instead of jail?
Rym: Yep, we need nut houses drug houses and I say for nonviolent crimes.
Rym: I mean, I'm not you know, there are some libertarians out there say things like yeah We shouldn't put people in jail and we don't need police.
Rym: Yeah But I am perfectly okay with police.
Scott: people who need to be in a prison are people who would be dangerous If they were walking on the street or I would argue repeat offenders.
Rym: Hmm I mean even if you commit nonviolent crime, yeah, if you shoplift 40 times in a row, yeah Well, I mean, it's not necessarily a violent crime that hurts people, but it is a harmful crime.
Scott: They're hurting other true true and they are causing damage repeatedly.
Scott: I mean if someone doesn't kill people but he goes around Smashing statues or something and he keeps doing it a lot He needs to go to jail so he can see he doesn't do it anymore.
Rym: Yeah, or the nut house depending cuz it could be a crazy statue smash course.
Rym: We follow that other recent scientific article to come out.
Rym: All we need to do is make it meet a bunch of fish and I'll calm down.
Rym: Oh god I don't know if we actually talked about that.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: I'll save that for the prison episode.
Rym: So Yeah, but there's violent criminals from what I've read and all these statistics seem to make up the minority of people who are convicted Of crimes.
Rym: I don't know if that has to do with plea bargains or any other shenanigans.
Rym: I didn't look at the raw data and I really don't have access to it.
Rym: Yeah, but I Imagine if we only locked up.
Rym: I mean, this isn't obviously a feasible solution.
Rym: But what if we only locked up violent criminals and we had other solutions for everything else?
Scott: I wonder what if we had another solution for anything besides just prison.
Rym: Yeah, except I don't know what with a violent criminal?
Rym: There's really nothing you can do other than put him in a nut house.
Rym: if they're actually nuts put him Exile.
Rym: Where are we gonna exile him?
Rym: - no, I mean what.
Rym: we're gonna leave him in Rwanda drop him in the ocean.
Rym: That's basically Execution.
Rym: why bother with the exiling?
Scott: just kill him at that point because technically it's not an execution.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, you know that's what Oedipus his parents thought they're like, you know what?
Rym: We're gonna kill this kid, but we don't want to actually kill him in case the gods get pissy about it.
Rym: So we'll just leave him out in the desert.
Rym: and if he dies Well, that's great.
Rym: And if he doesn't die if the gods want him to live then nothing will happen to him And then we won't get in trouble.
Rym: That's the argument you just made and you know, what happened to Oedipus?
Scott: No, no, but that's fine.
Rym: You want to know what happened to Oedipus?
Scott: He made it.
Rym: He made it in a sense.
Rym: If I made it you mean he grew up with a gimp foot had sex with his mom Killed his dad and ended up stabbing his eyes out.
Scott: Yeah, it's good enough.
Scott: All right, so Here's my news.
Rym: Oh, yeah, you got some news.
Scott: I do.
Scott: I do actually have news.
Rym: All right lay it on me.
Scott: There's this thing called if you don't know about it the Antikythera mechanism.
Rym: I can't pronounce Greek for shite.
Rym: So I hope you pronounced it right cuz I don't know a n t i k y t h e r a. and to get there I get my Greek pronunciation from the Byzantine Empire's guy who said straight up.
Rym: You can't pronounce words in Greek.
Scott: Yes I think Greek might be one of the only things I can't pronounce.
Scott: Well anyway This is a very very old Mechanism.
Scott: it's like from a hundred or a hundred and fifty BC.
Scott: This is ancient shit, man.
Rym: Yeah, it's basically depending on how you look at it.
Rym: One of the earliest computers, right?
Scott: So we had this thing.
Scott: we found it and we knew it was some sort of ancient computer Instrument.
Scott: well mechanical computer instrument, you know, and yes, but we just couldn't figure it out.
Scott: Like what exactly does it do?
Scott: How does it exactly work?
Scott: I mean we took how old was it really?
Rym: we took x-rays of it and we saw these gears and things in there and a lot of Randy nut jobs have pointed at it as evidence of all sorts of crazy shit.
Rym: and I hate that because They have kind of overblown this thing and made it this mystical thing and use it as the basis for a lot of their bullshit Arguments, but all that aside.
Rym: It's still a really amazing discovery and I think them Aggrandizing it that way kind of cheapens it.
Scott: Well, anyway some guys who are researching it Think if they they're pretty sure they figured it out.
Scott: their findings showed that the inscriptions it has inscriptions on it.
Scott: They related to lunar solar motions and the gears.
Scott: it's full.
Scott: It's basically a box full of gears.
Scott: We're a mechanical representation of the irregularities of the moon's orbital course across the sky as theorized by the astronomer Hipparcos.
Scott: So basically this Hipparcos astronomer said, oh this is how the moon goes across the sky.
Scott: This is how the Sun goes across the.
Scott: you know sky and etc, etc, etc.
Scott: And they made this device where they would turn knobs on it and it could track those motions So it would remember, you know where the Sun is where the moon is where it's gonna be.
Rym: So think of this.
Rym: the allerian Romans, you know the Greeks back in early Roman times basically made mechanical computers and then a thousand years later Europe was a stinking cesspool of medieval bullshit.
Rym: Yeah, good game Barbarians.
Scott: and this thing had 30 possibly 37 Hand-cut bronze gear wheels and they were.
Scott: they had an in gene.
Scott: It's a in G. I'm reading from the article an ingenious pin and slot device connecting two gear wheels.
Scott: Something something.
Rym: see that's big stuff.
Scott: cuz I made cuz I think about this.
Scott: This is this machine that existed in a hundred and fifty BC.
Scott: It was this technology was lost and they had to reinvent the gear hundreds and hundreds of years later Here let alone all the mathematics that went into this.
Scott: Yeah Well Hipparcos wasn't the most exact astronomer, but it was pretty good for the time.
Scott: You know, it's like ah I got this wicked cool mechanical computer that follows the.
Scott: who is the guy who thought the Sun was at the middle the?
Rym: a lot Of people thought that I know the guy who Copernicus.
Scott: Yeah The Copernicus model and it's like oh no Well, you got a computer.
Scott: that does it right for that wrong model.
Rym: Oh well The wrong model of the Sun is in the center of the.
Scott: I meant the earth isn't okay.
Scott: Center who is okay?
Scott: Everyone before that right, but the guy what's the guy with the us at the end of the day?
Rym: Copernicus?
Rym: no, what other guy?
Scott: Damn, what's the name of it?
Rym: What guy are you talking about?
Rym: I mean, obviously you're talking about an earth centric universe view, but Whatever.
Scott: I don't remember the name.
Scott: I don't know not everyone's seen that movie.
Rym: Everyone should have it's it should have.
Rym: yes I mean, it's in that genre of movie that we like so wonderfully amazingly much, you know all those movies like Reservoir Dogs and Snatch Lockstock.
Scott: Oh Pretty much all made by dog Saints.
Scott: all those movies are made by maybe yeah guys.
Scott: Well boondock Saints is made by one other guy.
Scott: But yeah suicide Kings.
Scott: All right, that was made by a fourth guy.
Rym: Oh way to shoot the theory down.
Scott: Yeah, but the king is the only one.
Rym: Yeah, but we really like movies that are dark humor about guys with guns.
Scott: I mean the guy who made Snatch and Lockstock was Guy Ritchie.
Rym: He's pretty much a one-trick pony.
Rym: He makes that kind of movie.
Scott: He makes it real.
Scott: Well, but he is Madonna's husband.
Scott: I think now what?
Scott: yeah I think he's been Madonna's husband for a long time.
Rym: I read FARC, but I pretty much skip over anything that has to do with celebrities.
Scott: Yeah, unless it's Jack Thompson Jack times is not celebrity.
Rym: Yeah, but I can't talk about him.
Rym: He didn't do anything particularly good.
Scott: I made Pulp Fiction again.
Rym: I don't remember Quentin Tarantino that guy.
Scott: I knew the name.
Scott: I just I couldn't get it to come to me.
Rym: Anyway, Pulp Fiction is You know a long movie and it's a good movie, but you know how there's been this trend of people Remixing a movie or remixing a movie trailer or phantom edits and all these things.
Rym: So this guy took Pulp Fiction and he cut it down to a kind of abridged version.
Rym: It has everything important in Pulp Fiction.
Rym: If you watch this you will get everything you would you would normally get out of Pulp Fiction.
Rym: For you see this is a cut of Pulp Fiction.
Rym: It's a video where they've cut out any time That a character is not saying the word fuck or a short phrase involving the word fuck like motherfucker.
Rym: Yeah, you it includes probably my favorite line in the entire movie you motherfucker when the In case you haven't seen the movie.
Rym: I can't ruin it, but Yeah, it's good stuff.
Rym: I mean the movie is really good But watching this you get one a sense of just how many times they say the word fuck in this movie to the point that The movie makes perfect sense if you cut out every word, but fuck Yeah, if you watch this
Scott: you'll get it you'll.
Scott: it's everything it's everything.
Scott: This reminds me that I found a long time ago like some cuts of rap songs where they only left in the word fuck.
Scott: I remember it was like fuck the police, but it was just like but but but but but but it was good stuff.
Rym: Yeah, actually it was Yuko who told me about this.
Rym: It's old and I believe I might have seen it or heard of it at least a long time ago And I totally forgotten about it.
Scott: I was reminded of it again and Well, it's definitely never been used as a thing of the day.
Rym: Yeah, that's my test.
Rym: Well a couple of our listeners complained once that a thing of the day we used was old hat.
Rym: They'd seen it before and that's not really the point of GeekNights.
Rym: We're not the bleeding edge news because you can just read Fark if you want the bleeding edge news.
Rym: We just pick things we want to talk about.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So check this out.
Rym: I'm checking.
Scott: one of my favorite Classical music.
Scott: well guys is the Tchaikovsky dude, right and he did the Nutcracker and he did the Swan Lake which both rocked the house and Some other guy apparently likes Tchaikovsky.
Scott: Also, he decided he was gonna make play the Nutcracker suite and record it and Put it on the internet, but he didn't have any instruments didn't have an orchestra.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: He must have had a computer, but I guess he didn't want to use that.
Scott: So he decided to use a bicycle.
Rym: Now you might think okay How the hell can you play that on a bicycle?
Rym: now my way the way I would do it is I would take a bicycle Right and I'd mount an iPod mount to it.
Scott: Now this guy used the spokes of the bicycle as the glockenspiel and clarinet melody.
Scott: he Had derailleur cables like, you know pole to different lengths and he plucked them.
Scott: You know cellos and the violins.
Rym: You could just say derailleur because the word derailleur in English means that in French.
Rym: It doesn't matter.
Scott: Well, the derailleur is is like the device.
Scott: It's the actual cables that he's plucking.
Scott: Yeah, the derailleur is like is the?
Rym: yeah, but the derailleur cables can be called derailleur cables Don't need to say in French.
Scott: Anyway for the triangle.
Scott: He hit the disc brake with something and Everything else the percussion.
Scott: he would shift the gears.
Scott: he would you know pull the brake he would pull on the chain He would spin the wheels around all kinds of stuff.
Rym: Scott played this for me and it's pretty badass.
Scott: Yeah, if no one told you that it was being played on a bicycle you you would might not know.
Scott: cuz it's so Exact it sounds great.
Scott: Yeah, it's short though, but whatever.
Rym: So today as usual for the course of Thursday, we weren't really sure what to do.
Rym: We debated for a while kind of lazily Where we had some really gems of ideas as to what to do the show on.
Scott: I Came up with an idea that we already did.
Rym: Yeah Which I'd make fun of him except I've done that before too.
Rym: Yeah, I'll sit there be like, let's do a show on Big O Let's do a show about waiting in line.
Scott: And the other thing is like he coming up with the Monday Tuesday Wednesday ideas and not so much Thursday Yeah, and I come up with Thursdays but we always.
Rym: they're always something where we want to do research and put forth a case instead of just bullshitting about it and We just don't do the research.
Scott: Yeah, like we could have just bullshitted about that whole prison thing for the whole episode But we would have got pwned because we didn't do research.
Rym: besides that one article Yeah Cuz I'm still compiling all my evidence for when I finally do our thing on Why we hate the way the prison system works in the United States.
Scott: fuck the police All right, so so so What are we gonna do this?
Scott: What did we decide?
Rym: Well, we decided cuz it you know, we've done a lot of episodes of GeekNights.
Rym: In fact, in fact, we've done 221 episodes of GeekNights not including number two to two.
Rym: Yes, two to two.
Rym: Ooh, very nice number.
Scott: Yeah, very nice divisible by three.
Scott: Yeah, cool.
Rym: Actually, I Impress someone.
Rym: Well, I have a couple people in independent conversations recently.
Rym: with that I'm gonna let you all in a little mathematical bit of magic.
Rym: in case he didn't realize it.
Rym: any number is Divisible by three if you can add up the digits of the number and that number is divisible by three.
Scott: It's true.
Rym: So Yeah, that's all I got to say about that.
Rym: But yeah, we've done two hundred and twenty one Point-five episodes of GeekNights plus the six or seven beta episodes and all the stuff we did before.
Rym: we even had a microphone And it's been a while.
Rym: It's taken a lot out of us and I don't know we could talk about that in some kind of meta self introspective looking inward focused Meta blah, I said meta twice.
Scott: Well, we've done 28 meta shows before.
Scott: have we?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: It says meta discussion.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: I gotta go through and clean that up because honestly I Start originally I use tags in certain ways and I kind of use tags in different ways as the show went on.
Rym: So sometimes I would put a tag on an episode if we did a news about that topic.
Rym: Sometimes I wouldn't.
Rym: Lately, I've only been doing it if we did a long or an important news on that topic.
Rym: Meta and site news.
Rym: There's some overlap.
Rym: Yeah, I can fix that though.
Rym: That was just me being lazy And I don't think one of those tags didn't exist right away and then I added it.
Scott: Alright, so what do we got to say about us making?
Scott: 222 episodes of GeekNights.
Rym: Yeah 222.
Rym: I know a couple recent podcasts were happy about how they had almost broken a hundred and Not gonna gloat, but we're so awesome.
Rym: Yeah, we're so totally awesome.
Rym: Either that or we just really have no lives.
Rym: We have lives, you know, we don't have shit to talk about, you know, we don't have fucking sleep.
Scott: God, yeah, you know what?
Scott: I wake up every morning lately Like when my alarm goes off.
Scott: I get up out of bed because my alarm is across the room.
Scott: I turn the alarm off I get back in bed and I wake up like 10 minutes before I have to leave the house.
Rym: I used to wake up at 6 o'clock.
Rym: Yeah, well except when I worked at IBM when I'd wake up at like 8 45 and roll into work around 9.
Rym: Those were the days.
Rym: but no now I get up at like 6 30 6 45 So I don't have time to shave or shower Properly and I run to the car because if I don't leave the house by 730 I'm totally fuck.
Rym: trying to drive in because everyone else who's running late is on the road and the people running late.
Rym: I'll drive like complete and total asshats.
Scott: Yeah, I get up.
Scott: I set my alarm for 630.
Scott: I don't get up until 745.
Scott: I gotta leave.
Scott: I'd like to leave at 8, but I've been leaving after late 8 a lot lately.
Rym: So I guess here's something we can do.
Rym: Let's kind of diagram a day in our lives from back before we did the podcast and a day in our lives now and then a Weekend from before and a weekend now just to illustrate to all of you out there who now we're not complaining Don't get us wrong.
Rym: We love doing this but Doing a show like this has taken a lot out of us.
Rym: And if you think that you could do if you want to do a podcast Just be advised that your life will be a little bit different if you're serious about it unless you do a weekly show.
Rym: If we did a show we show.
Rym: if we imagine if we did a weekly show, it'd be like two hours long and perfect.
Scott: It's something like that.
Rym: Yeah, maybe some month We'll take a month hiatus and just do a once a week like special episodes all month.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: like in con season Maybe I don't know.
Rym: I just got crazy ideas.
Rym: I mean if we ever go out of town, you know, those aren't crazy ideas Those are lazy ideas.
Rym: You know what crazy lazy.
Rym: There's no difference.
Rym: They're right there.
Rym: They're almost the same.
Scott: Practically the same letter makes a big difference.
Rym: They're practically the same word Just like dick and mick.
Rym: What the fuck?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Yeah, so before we did the show I would you know, we go to work and we'd both be home by like four maybe five.
Rym: We would cook dinner that took until about five forty five including eating and then we'd play video games for like two hours.
Rym: We'd watch anime for like two hours.
Rym: We'd if anyone was around we'd play games with them and board games.
Rym: I'd go out running.
Rym: we'd ride bikes together.
Rym: I know so cute.
Rym: We ride bikes together and every day was just.
Rym: it got to the point where we didn't have enough to entertain Us in a given day.
Rym: Yeah We would sit there like nine o'clock at night bored because we'd already watched like four episodes of anime and we played every video game We wanted to play that day.
Scott: Well, sometimes you would sit around for an hour or two just talking about bullshit.
Rym: Wow Wow, I I can't.
Rym: it's so weird that we never just sit around anymore.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, that's what I miss the most.
Scott: I think another thing is back in those days I was working in the city.
Scott: So I'd get home later more like six something.
Rym: Yeah, like when I usually sometimes even seven something.
Scott: now I get home at five something.
Rym: That's just cuz you show up at work late and you leave early.
Scott: No one else is there.
Scott: What are they gonna do about it?
Rym: I'd do the same thing.
Rym: Yeah, but now well aside from the work issue because work changes just because we're Technologists and technology jobs tend to change a lot we get home we get in our hour Maybe an hour and a half of video gaming and internet doing.
Rym: we cook dinner We do the pre-production for the show.
Rym: We do the show.
Rym: We read some manga and we go to sleep.
Scott: That's pretty much what it is.
Scott: The problem is we do a lot more cooking now than we used to actually and it takes time to cook and Usually there's something to do like dishes or some shit or some errand.
Scott: we go Or maybe it's a run to the grocery store Used to be.
Scott: you could run to the grocery store cook dinner and have time to spare now if we do that.
Scott: Well, no playing video games tonight.
Scott: Yep So it's like I get home and I pretty much have until dinner to do anything fun.
Scott: I can't sit on my computer at all or anything and we eat dinner We do the show and then maybe we have time to watch something while we eat.
Scott: That's about it.
Scott: After the show all I could do is lay in bed reading comics and then sleep.
Rym: now the actual reality is that really?
Rym: We don't do much less when we're doing the show than we're not doing the show.
Rym: It's more that we seem.
Rym: we lose a lot of the time between doing things where you Unravel a little bit and maybe relax.
Rym: Yeah, I mean we're.
Rym: we get home and we immediately it's like alright, we got to start watching anime right now.
Rym: Alright now I got to go run for 10 minutes while you do that thing And then we got to play excite truck before the show and oh we got to cook dinner.
Scott: Yeah, we you know, usually you spend a few minutes between things just sitting there thinking looking around.
Scott: that doesn't exist anymore.
Scott: It's got a doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo.
Rym: Of course part of that is that in the last couple weeks?
Rym: We've been lazy and when we're doing pre-production for the show we end up putting all that time.
Rym: We would have spent doing nothing before we did the podcast Wedged into the time.
Rym: we're trying to get the show ready.
Rym: So we already know what we're gonna do.
Rym: We got the news.
Rym: We got the things of the day.
Rym: We got the topic.
Rym: We're ready to go and we sit there for 45 minutes watching Family Guy and Simpsons clips on YouTube.
Scott: That is true.
Scott: We just did that.
Rym: We do seem to waste a lot more time looking at internet shit under the guise of working on the podcast Even though we don't use any of that stuff in the show.
Scott: Well, usually it's like as soon as we know everything we're gonna do on the show, you know, and we found news.
Scott: We found things of the day and we found the topic.
Scott: we do the show immediately as soon as that's all set.
Scott: Yeah, what we'll do is we'll be looking for things of the day and that's when we'll start watching videos on YouTube and wasting time.
Scott: We won't know a main topic.
Scott: So we'll look to our computers for inspiration and start watching videos on YouTube or playing flash.
Rym: But it's definitely subtle Subconscious procrastination because oftentimes we need a topic and we just watch Family Guy crap.
Rym: That's not going to inspire us or Will it?
Rym: No, it never has.
Rym: play Jerusalem You can't plagiarize ten plagiarism owes anyway, I Just realized I hadn't make that you can't blank ten blank joke recently and I had to bring it back.
Rym: All right, because I think that's gonna be our first t-shirt.
Scott: You can't hold ten Pokemon You can't make ten.
Rym: you can't make ten jokes.
Rym: ten jokes make what the fuck.
Rym: I realized that if you try to recurse that joke, it becomes infinitely recursive.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Oh, no.
Rym: No, wait, I can break it.
Scott: I got it.
Scott: You can't make ten.
Rym: make ten jokes.
Rym: Yeah, you can't make ten.
Rym: You can't make ten jokes ten joke Damn it.
Rym: Let's hear your option your way.
Scott: Well, it's you can't blank, right?
Scott: So it's you can't you can't you can't you can't you can't you can't you can't you can't you can't you can't you can't etc.
Rym: Well, yeah, if you do a pure recursion, yes.
Scott: and then if the recursion is, you know doesn't have a stopper.
Scott: and then if there's a as soon as it's Finishes out right?
Scott: It's if one you can't As soon as it breaks out of that, you know downward spiral, it's you can't.
Scott: Eventually, you can't make ten except break can't you can't you can't.
Rym: Breaking out of that downward spiral is like breaking out of a point zero repeating with a one at the end of it You're never gonna get to that one.
Rym: That one's not there.
Scott: I know That's kind of the point.
Rym: Wow.
Rym: Yeah that that wasted some time.
Rym: See that's the problem.
Rym: when we try to be unstructured we just kind of talk about the stuff We would have talked about if there were no microphones around Which you guys seem to find entertaining.
Rym: So now I'll get back on topic.
Rym: that in itself that Busyness from the fact that we do the show wouldn't really affect our lives that much because one Friday through Sunday We have infinite free time.
Rym: or we did.
Rym: you see when he first started doing the show It didn't matter that we did the show all week because we lived out here pretty much alone.
Rym: None of our friends lived really anywhere near us.
Scott: So we it's like every weekend We would drive down to the mall play a bunch of DDR.
Rym: Yeah, we used to drive to the mall and play initial D for like an hour.
Scott: Yeah, we used to do all kinds of weird stuff around here.
Scott: We go to the anime store all the time.
Scott: Media play.
Scott: remember that media play was still in business.
Rym: Yeah, then it was going out of business.
Rym: We kept going up there to buy the ever-increasingly discounted crack.
Scott: Yeah, we did all kinds of stuff.
Scott: We went, you know now it's like Down the road one day.
Rym: I even took Scott mountain biking.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, we did all kinds of crazy shit.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but weekends were totally relaxing and totally free.
Rym: I mean other than con season which Didn't hit us so bad back then because we didn't go to that many.
Rym: we went to like maybe five or six cons back then.
Rym: Yeah, which I mean we had every weekend was free.
Rym: I'd wake up at like 11. we do whatever we wanted.
Rym: We stay up until like for playing video games.
Rym: We sleep till noon the next day.
Rym: Now all our friends live out near us.
Rym: not that we're really complaining because it's kind of awesome No, but now we're just constantly doing shit on the weekend.
Scott: It's like before.
Scott: you know, it's like I need to go to Home Depot to buy something.
Scott: Well on the weekend I could just go.
Scott: it'd be all easy.
Scott: now It's like I gotta run around and get.
Scott: there's no time to get the shit done even on the weekend.
Scott: I mean, let's say I need to take days off work if I need to go down the road to get like household goods.
Rym: I mean we have people come over to our house or we go over to someone else's house or we go to a con Every weekend like if I need to do laundry, oh shit.
Rym: Oh laundry.
Rym: There was a time when the thing is and this is the one thing that really scares me and reminds me of how awesome college Was.
Rym: we had even less time in college free really than we do now.
Rym: Mmm, the only difference was in college.
Rym: We could skip our responsibilities in order to have fun.
Rym: I can't skip work in order to have fun on a regular basis.
Rym: I could skip class whenever I wanted.
Scott: Yeah, the other thing is in college There was a lot of time between classes like I remember when I watched all of Matt cross one episode a day.
Scott: I would watch that episode around lunchtime You know, I had my class schedule set up where it's like every day.
Scott: I would be home at lunch I would get I'd like make a sandwich watch one episode and then go back to classes.
Scott: Yeah, I don't have that like our breaks in the middle of the day to do stuff at home.
Scott: I mean, I'm at work I can do whatever I want there pretty much because no one else is there But I'm not at home and I can't like go out to the store or because there really aren't any stores over there.
Scott: So it's really limiting.
Scott: All I can do at work is do something on the internet or read something or play a DS game.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: It really limiting the options.
Rym: Yeah I mean we really feel it.
Rym: on Friday when we don't have to do a show we come home from work and we're sitting there We're watching anime and we realize that we're free Free.
Rym: we can do whatever we want until everyone comes over to hang out like an hour later.
Scott: Yeah, well the show's affected us in other ways besides yeah taking up time.
Rym: Well, the way I've looked at it is that when we were in college, I mean not to self-aggrandize Really not at all, but we had a wide circle of friends, you know The front row crew was very tight and we did stuff together all the time.
Rym: but we also ran that anime club with its hundreds of members and Not that we had fans or anything like that.
Rym: But there was a large large body of people who knew us among a tiny Tiny group of very specific fan oriented people.
Rym: we were tiny minor celebrities.
Scott: We had a large network of acquaintances.
Scott: Like there were a lot of people who fell into that category of like.
Scott: hey, I know that guy that guy knows me What's up, but we're not really friends.
Scott: They don't call each other.
Scott: I am each other or anything.
Rym: Yeah, like I never called Mitch or hung out with Mitch But I was there cheering when Mitch took on the one gallon challenge.
Scott: I knew Mitch freshman year.
Rym: Everyone knew Mitch.
Scott: Yeah You know, they're a bunch of.
Scott: we knew a lot of people.
Scott: but now, you know when you move to a new place You know your people who are your close friends will stay in contact But those that acquaintance network is pretty much disintegrated as soon as you move away.
Rym: Yeah and I'll admit that it was kind of a blow that I went from having this club with hundreds of people in it.
Rym: who would you know, they They would come to this thing and I would be at the front of the room and they would listen to everything I said.
Rym: if they saw me when I was walking down the street They'd be like hey Rym blah blah blah.
Rym: and I always thought god damn it you fanboys.
Rym: Just leave me alone.
Rym: I'm trying to go to class.
Rym: But then when I didn't have that anymore after about a week, I started missing it.
Rym: I miss those fanboys and I wanted.
Rym: I wanted that.
Scott: I don't miss the fanboys.
Scott: I miss the non fanboys.
Scott: Yeah, this just you know.
Scott: seeing.
Scott: you know, it was good to walk around a place where there's lots of people, you know.
Scott: Instead of nowadays, I don't see people during the day.
Scott: I don't see anyone.
Scott: so it was good to just see people.
Scott: and You know if I needed if I wanted to talk to someone, you know Usually if I walk around for ten minutes, I'm gonna find someone and be like, hey, what's up?
Rym: Yeah, I mean on any given moment we like if one of us didn't have class we'd wander into one of the eateries on campus.
Rym: We're almost guaranteed to run into someone to hang out with.
Scott: Yeah, and then nowadays if we go to a restaurant, you know, we're gonna be the only people there We know is us unless it's a restaurant We frequent often in which the waiters will know who we are or one of them are a few places like that.
Scott: But you know, there's not.
Scott: it's not like.
Scott: hey, man, what's up?
Scott: We know you but in college, you could walk in anywhere and be like, hey, I know you let's sit together and talk about something.
Rym: Yep, plus being at college and being in these clubs and having this social network gave us an in into a lot of things.
Rym: I mean we started getting into conventions free and We started like I started giving speeches and doing panels to anime cons years and years and years ago just because I had this in from you know, the college and the people I knew and the campus and the club.
Rym: and Once you graduate you realize that you don't have access to that anymore.
Rym: I mean, what was I gonna say?
Rym: You know now if I didn't have GeekNights and I tried to go back to cons and be like, hey Let me run a panel at your con or let me be staff at your con.
Rym: What's your experience?
Rym: Three to five years ago.
Rym: I was the president of an anime club.
Rym: What have you done since then?
Rym: work nine-to-five?
Rym: going nowhere.
Scott: Yeah, GeekNights has sort of been the replacement for that.
Scott: Yeah, how we do something?
Scott: therefore we're worth something and we have an acquaintance network And we have a forum where people talk to us.
Rym: Yeah And I got to say we've met a lot of cool people doing GeekNights.
Rym: Most of you people in the forums are super awesome.
Rym: most You know who you are.
Scott: But seriously, I mean we can't be ten cool people.
Rym: We've met a bunch of you at various conventions and you guys are all.
Rym: we've never met one of you.
Rym: That was not at least above the level of being cool.
Scott: Another thing is that we've entered sort of like the podcast community or like not the big podcast community.
Scott: most podcasters.
Scott: There's no clue about GeekNights.
Scott: We're not big time.
Rym: I believe you mean the anime world order Ninja Consultants fast karate for the gentleman night shift half I happy house a hentai podcast community.
Scott: Also, there are a few others that were loosely tied to like board games to go actually movies.
Rym: Actually, no, it's the exact opposite of a bit shit.
Rym: I love that podcast.
Scott: Comic geek.
Scott: guys know who we are.
Scott: Yeah, you know, there's a few podcasts.
Scott: There's a lot of people, you know If we didn't make a podcast like I would be a listener of their shows Maybe because I wouldn't have known about anime world order anything.
Scott: if I you know, they hadn't.
Rym: yeah The only reason we even knew anything about anime world order is because Daryl Surratt Randomly interviewed me at Katsucon while I was a little bit drunk.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, and I first I was like What's this guy trying to do a podcast or something?
Rym: What's this?
Scott: No Hey, you're a podcaster at the time.
Rym: Yeah, but I didn't have a recording bit or anything.
Rym: I wasn't GeekNights was hardly professional back then.
Scott: No, it wasn't.
Scott: Well, it's hardly professional now.
Rym: Yeah, it's more professional than say other podcasts.
Rym: See, I'd say here's the thing We're more professional than fast karate.
Rym: But that is not in any way disparaging to fast karate because they're.
Rym: unprofessionalism is what makes their podcast.
Scott: Awesome It really depends on the podcast.
Scott: how much professionalism you need or you should.
Scott: you know A lot.
Scott: the best kind of podcast really in the world would be where everything is ultra professional But no one can tell because you're unprofessional on purpose.
Rym: Well, like the audio quality is good and perfect, but the people are just schmucks like us.
Scott: Yeah Yeah Well, you don't even need the perfect audio quality.
Scott: like you can have perfect audio equipment and then intentionally like get the unprofessional sound Professionally, yeah, you know see I don't.
Rym: I don't like things like that.
Rym: I'd rather just every podcast be perfect perfect audio.
Rym: That'd be good too because hearing something sound professional doesn't rub me the wrong way like it does some people.
Scott: Yeah, whatever It depends really, you know some things, you know need to sound a certain way.
Scott: You know, it's like.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: I think of it like making 8-bit music, you know as opposed to making 16-bit music.
Rym: Yeah, I'll follow that but just don't tread into the realm of.
Rym: I put film grain into my digital film For artistic reasons.
Scott: No, that's a bad move.
Scott: That's a bad.
Scott: That's kind of the same thing is I'm thinking more like make a black-and-white movie with the highest end video equipment.
Scott: You know something like that.
Rym: That's what I'm talking about Yeah, but just I mean all these cool people we've met as a result of podcasting like HD black-and-white movie.
Rym: But like remember we had those the two wonderful movies.
Rym: You see people were guests on our show and they did a guest episode of GeekNights.
Scott: Yeah No one else wanted to the bums.
Rym: No, we had a few people who wanted to but they were probably the best people to do it at the time and the most Professional.
Scott: and yeah, they did a good job.
Scott: Like I was it was cool cuz you know Yeah, I was all excited to hear whatever they had to say what they were gonna do, you know It's cooler than listening to your own show being done by someone else.
Scott: Yeah, it's kind of weird though It's like it's a pretty good podcast.
Rym: Like I'll listen to it if I don't have anything else to listen to I've done that Cuz I forget what I say on the show and I go back and listen to.
Rym: it's like wow That was kind of funny or what?
Rym: What the fuck was I talking about?
Scott: Usually are we talking about?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: It's Thursday.
Rym: We can do whatever we want.
Rym: Thursday is the least subscribed to night of GeekNights.
Scott: So sad Thursday.
Rym: Well by least subscribed I mean it has 20 less listeners than the rest of GeekNights.
Scott: Where are those 20 people?
Scott: They think I listen I.
Rym: There are 33 people who are regularly subscribed to Thursday, but that doesn't count, you know the hundred.
Scott: It's 30 people who listen to Thursday only.
Rym: Well, they might be subscribed to like Monday Thursday.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: Hey if anyone listens to Thursday only Say something.
Rym: Yeah, leave us an audio.
Rym: I'm curious about that.
Scott: Yeah, I think that's another thing with the podcasting is
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: yeah,
Rym: yeah used
Scott: to forget before
Rym: but like we have these hundreds and hundreds of people who listen to the whole week At least they subscribe to the whole feed and then we have all the feeds for the different days and the hits to those feeds very wildly and You know what if you use those specialized feeds, let us know.
Rym: We're just curious.
Scott: I know a few people use and there's a lot of people going for that Tuesday only feed a lot of them.
Rym: Yeah, that's our most popular feed.
Scott: Well, no the the everything feed is the most.
Rym: well, it's our most popular individual day feed.
Rym: Yeah, even though the feed it's amazing that half of you In fact, sometimes more than half of you download the show manually from the website or from a podcast Site instead of using a pod catcher.
Scott: You should use a pod catcher.
Rym: Yeah, if you're downloading the site or the GeekNights from the website every day, that's awesome.
Rym: But you might be better off using a pod catcher.
Rym: It'll make your life a lot easier.
Scott: Yeah, I don't really care how you get the show.
Scott: I mean, that's why we make it available in so many different ways, but it's probably better for you.
Scott: I'm trying to help you out here.
Scott: Your pod catchers make things easy.
Scott: There's a reason.
Rym: they exist of course, we only have the most recent 100 episodes in the feed and Episodes before that are getting a lot of downloads.
Rym: So you guys are going through the archives.
Scott: Yeah, I don't understand if you will go through the archives.
Rym: I go through the archives of every podcast I listen to.
Scott: I've listened.
Scott: There's some podcast where you can go through the archives and some that you just shouldn't.
Rym: well apparently ours you can because everyone does it I know.
Scott: but if I was a GeekNights listener, I would not go through the archive.
Rym: I would you know what I do.
Rym: I'd go through the website.
Rym: Maybe this is why we get so many web downloads.
Rym: I would go to the website and search for things I want to hear about because odds are it's in there.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I mean I would go and get.
Scott: I wouldn't listen to the whole archive straight through.
Scott: is what I'm saying?
Rym: Well, you know what?
Scott: I would get some choice episodes out of there, but I definitely would not listen to everything.
Rym: I've listened to almost the whole archive of movies.
Scott: You should see that's not the biggest archive.
Rym: fast karate for the gentleman.
Rym: Anime world order.
Scott: I never will order.
Scott: you can listen to all of pretty easily.
Rym: Yeah, and NPR a lot of that stuff I've got.
Scott: NPR wouldn't.
Scott: well, it depends on the show on NPR.
Rym: NPR politics.
Rym: I went back through as much of as I could get.
Scott: Wow, that's scary.
Rym: I like NVR politics.
Scott: It's only 10 minutes long I'm just saying like onion radio news.
Scott: I've gone through Too many of them.
Rym: I've gone through much of the pendulette podcast archives.
Scott: Yeah, it's another one where I would just go through and get some choice episodes and not listen to all of them.
Rym: But yeah, anyway, I don't know.
Rym: We weren't really trying to say anything.
Rym: We were just kind of rambling.
Scott: I guess you had nothing better to do today.
Scott: What do you want from us?
Rym: Yeah, it's been Two hundred and twenty one point nine episodes of GeekNights.
Rym: I mean that's kind of crazy.
Rym: even every whenever I think about it.
Rym: I mean I look at the gigabytes and gigabytes of GeekNights archives I have on this computer and it's kind of staggering that I that we did that.
Scott: All right, so Ignites, it's the second season.
Scott: It's a second season is about a month old now, right?
Rym: Yep, as the new year comes a lot of stuff is going to happen.
Rym: We're gonna update the website.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it's gonna be the holidays in a couple weeks You know, this is gonna be like the GeekNights mellow month of December, right?
Scott: And then we're gonna have you know, a big New Year's party that we always have and everything, you know in January Expect like GeekNights double renewal.
Scott: We're gonna start, you know doing a push for more listeners.
Scott: We're gonna hopefully, you know get the website nicer.
Rym: Yeah, we're gonna get our artists to finish the site design and we're gonna run an exchange.
Scott: We're gonna start selling swag.
Scott: We're gonna come out with the DVDs.
Scott: We're gonna do all.
Rym: that awesome shit is coming up early next year and it better come early next year because also early next year Is con season dumb dumb dumb.
Rym: see it used to be that con season for us was the summer And that was pretty much it.
Rym: like we go to Katsu.
Rym: I'd go to Katsu con and then we'd have con season which was like March through August and even then it was on.
Scott: season was really February through November.
Rym: Well, no September September it's February through September.
Rym: so we get October November December and we January.
Rym: we might lose January.
Scott: How are you gonna lose January?
Scott: Cuz well, you know what the New York Comic Con is in January and generic on.
Scott: Yeah, it begins con season most of the year always.
Rym: Yep Also expect us to be doing a lot more at cons.
Rym: I mean this last year we had most cons where we did stuff we tended to do Podcasting stuff.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: We're gonna do a lot more Non-podcasting stuff because no one wants to hear another panel on what a podcast is.
Scott: Yeah All right, so all you GeekNights listeners out there like, you know, get ready Yeah, and you know what?
Rym: Thanks for listening cuz it's just awesome that you guys all listen to us Rant late into the night about often useless bullshit.
Scott: I think you're just fucking crazy.
Scott: I know it's wrong.
Rym: I Guess I'll end this with probably the most fitting anecdote that one of the reasons we decided to do a Podcast we've talked about this before was that when we made a bunch of new friends when they were freshmen at RIT but we were like juniors and seniors and they'd come over to our house or sleep in our apartment and They'd see us talking to each other in the bedroom and our separate beds while they were trying to go to sleep.
Scott: And well, they see us talking at all.
Scott: We just had normal conversations in the living room and they were perfectly normal conversations to us But everyone else is laughing hysterically.
Rym: So we realized that maybe we're funny.
Scott: Hey If we just talk the way we normally talk other people seem to really be Entertained so much so that they have nothing to say except they sit there and laugh and are happy.
Rym: So yeah Yeah, maybe we'll turn this into an annual GeekNights retrospective.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: May.
Rym: maybe we'll turn it into a semi monthly one depending on how lazy we are with Thursday shows.
Scott: Yeah I got a few ideas of things that we should do in the near future.
Scott: like every other podcast seems to do contest I think we can come up with a better contest system.
Scott: another podcast do.
Scott: I'm working on that.
Rym: Oh, you mean like anime world orders contest where they just randomly pick names.
Scott: I'm thinking there people do better contest than that.
Scott: But I think GeekNights can have the best contest of any podcast out there.
Rym: We'd have a contest like we'll get our friend Conrad love a contest contest.
Scott: you can come up with the best contest you win.
Rym: No, no, what do you win?
Rym: the contest?
Rym: you get to run it?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: No No, and we're gonna come up with some good stuff there.
Rym: And yeah, plus one thing we're gonna be doing that a lot of people have asked us about is we're lining up.
Rym: I know we said this before and we did have all the these interviews lined up, but we just didn't do them.
Rym: We're gonna actually follow through and interview all these people.
Rym: we keep saying we will Because I mean it's fun to have us on the show all the time But it's nice to break it up And I think we've got some really cool people that we may or may not have on the show in the coming months.
Scott: Yeah, and if you have if there's anything you want I mean One thing that a lot of other podcasts seem to be more successful at getting than we do even podcasts with lower Listenerships than we have is lots of feedback.
Scott: I think that's because we don't read feedback on the show often enough.
Scott: like when we were doing the geek backs We started getting lots of mail and since we stopped doing the eek backs as often we get less mail.
Rym: Well, the thing is no one really comments on the show itself.
Rym: they comment on things we've said on the show.
Rym: We never get meta feedback anymore.
Rym: Yeah, like in the first month we'd get complaints like oh the audio sounded bad that day.
Rym: or You guys should stop doing this segment because it's boring.
Rym: No one says anything anymore.
Rym: so if you have a complaint about GeekNights lay it on.
Scott: or if you have Suggestions and ideas and all that jazz, you know Show is not like some set-in-stone Show whatever even though it might feel like it because there's not a lot of user listener participation.
Rym: Well, actually there is and it's all in the forums.
Rym: It is doesn't like.
Rym: the thing is someone will say something in the forums and then our listeners will respond in the forums.
Rym: Then we'll respond in the forums.
Rym: So none of that ever even hits the show.
Scott: Well, sometimes it might hit the show but we won't let you know in the show that it came from the forum.
Scott: like someone will say something in the forum or Send us an email and then we'll talk about something related to that in the show.
Scott: and unless you're a forum visitor You won't know.
Rym: though The forums honestly are make me happier than anything because I wager if the show went away The community in the forums would far outlive it.
Scott: Yeah, probably.
Rym: and he's gotten to the point where the people in the forums are all really cool.
Rym: They all know each other.
Rym: the forums have their own in jokes separate from the show.
Rym: Yeah, all right, I think we're done.
Rym: we actually went long for this bullshit episode.
Scott: Yeah, I know it's kind of hard not to but so GeekNights 222 episodes behind us not yet.
Scott: It's okay, and in the future More action, but in the near future the same action.
Rym: You can't listen to ten GeekNights.
Scott: You can Did.
Rym: this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at frontrowcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.