Rym: It's Monday May 1st, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We're going to talk about internet hosting solutions.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: We had a wonderful weekend after our we show Though I will note that as it's now allergy season I have a screaming headache and my nose is full of various unmentionables, so I might sound a little off today.
Scott: I'm just awesome because I don't have allergies.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, I'm pretty much immune to Everything except maybe girlfriends.
Scott: no.
Scott: So yesterday I upgraded the hosting that we have not for the mp3 files of eat nights But for everything else the forum and the website and the feeds.
Scott: well I guess the feeds are on feed burner But the WordPress where the feed burner feeds come from and all that.
Scott: you might have noticed a slight short interruption to service yeah, last night when no one was using it anyway, but basically the Everything is doubled.
Scott: We have twice as much CPU twice as much RAM twice as much hard drive space Twice as much bandwidth.
Rym: So we're doing our best to fill that up right quick.
Scott: Yep However, we also doubled the money we pay for it.
Scott: So what was once 40 bucks a month is now 80 a month.
Rym: So for anyone who's curious because it was asked of us before and we didn't really give a solid number.
Rym: It cost us a grand total of twelve hundred dollars a year to host GeekNights.
Scott: Yep, which is Considering is two of us a pittance.
Scott: It's pretty much a pittance.
Scott: However, when I thought about it, I was like ugh 80 times 12 is 960. it kind of made me go but I'm paying it anyway, cuz I don't care.
Scott: However in the past someone came up to us and was like, hey, I wanted to PayPal you money But there was no PayPal button and I was like, yeah, we don't really need money because we have money from our jobs.
Scott: But now because I'm paying twice as much a month I'm not asking anyone to PayPal us money.
Rym: Yeah, don't send us money.
Scott: In fact, I'm telling you don't send us money because we probably have more money than you.
Scott: but I have put a PayPal donate thing like in the Darkest corner of the front row crew comm page in the bottom right somewhere.
Rym: Yeah, we basically just wanted to mention it on the show.
Rym: So people don't see it and think oh, they're hurting for money.
Scott: No, we're not hurting for money.
Rym: We're not gonna pull a Nick you here.
Scott: No, we're not gonna pull it Which we'll talk about some other time.
Rym: We talked about it.
Scott: I think did we?
Rym: Actually, that was like long story short.
Scott: some guy made a webcomic.
Scott: That was awesome.
Scott: He said help.
Scott: I need money.
Scott: We all gave him like a dollar.
Scott: He made two more comics and then he ran away.
Rym: Asshole.
Rym: we talked about that.
Rym: I'm like the fifth or sixth episode of GeekNights.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Anyway, so there's a PayPal donate there.
Scott: It's not there because we need money.
Scott: It's there because if you are so crazy that you just want to give us money I'm not gonna deny you.
Scott: previously we were denying you.
Scott: now.
Scott: We are no longer denying you the ability to give us money.
Scott: We're just trying to tell you not to.
Rym: it's like the custom in some places where you have to refuse a gift three times And then you take it grudgingly.
Scott: Well that it's not a show though.
Scott: We really don't want to take.
Scott: yeah But if you are so crazy that you want to give it to us, we won't deny you the ability to do so.
Rym: freedom Yeah, but we're really not hurting for money.
Rym: I mean, actually I'm going to be making quite a bit more money because I was just offered a job that I think I'm going To take.
Scott: yeah, and if my job doesn't give me some work to do.
Scott: in the next two weeks I'm gonna be looking for a new job.
Scott: So yeah.
Rym: Yeah, actually once Scott gets a new job I think our household income will be six figures.
Scott: seriously Six figures.
Scott: two people no kids, obviously Obviously And considering we've already bought just about every gadget we need we can start going for the useless shit.
Scott: Yeah like Ferraris and double Hawks double Hawks Projectors oh, I know Mackintosh's.
Rym: yeah Yeah, but then we'll have one less excuse why we don't do AAC with enhanced whatnot which we're not gonna Do cuz I already gave ten reasons which is plenty.
Rym: Yeah, I'm glad no one brought it up again.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Rym: So the show tonight is going to be about hosting because we changed the hosting and it's a pretty good idea Yep, especially since a tiny bit of research opened up a whole new topic We're going to talk about when we're in the garage in regards to hosting.
Scott: Okay, so let's do some.
Scott: news is first All right, so there was some news today about Linux getting an enhanced Wi-Fi stack.
Scott: if you don't know Support for wireless in Linux isn't terrific.
Scott: I mean you can get just about any wireless card to kind of somewhat work.
Scott: there are a few cards that work really really well and Most cards don't work at all or work poorly or hard.
Scott: to get them to work You have to use a thing called the NDIS wrapper Which basically means you take the Windows driver and you cram it in sideways into Linux like a square peg in a triangle hole.
Rym: It should be obvious why that's a bad idea.
Scott: Yeah, so this company be called device scape.
Scott: what they make is a stack and An advanced data path 802 11 driver stack.
Scott: if you don't know what this means It means this let's say Rym owns a company and Rym makes wireless cards for laptops and things.
Rym: We I only know to hire people to make Windows drivers.
Scott: No, no, you only know how to.
Scott: you don't even know how to make drivers.
Scott: you want to do as little driver making as possible Because you're mostly in the business of making and selling cards.
Rym: some other company has Windows.
Rym: they make drivers for me for Windows, right?
Scott: So device scape will sell you this 802 11 stack.
Scott: That means that if you want to make a driver to distribute with your wireless card that you want to sell You need to do very very little work because most of the work is done for you.
Scott: Give you all the meat and you just have to put some clothes on it.
Rym: I thought you were gonna say potatoes.
Rym: Okay, I don't know why you use the word meat.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: So why all the meat and you just add the potatoes?
Rym: Yeah, okay.
Rym: What's what are?
Rym: you grill it up meat clothes?
Rym: I mean, I have a meat helmet, but it's a Bobby.
Rym: Yeah, we're gonna do a show on inside joke soon.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Okay, so Yeah Yeah, this is good news though I mean we had a friend Alex who had a laptop that for the longest time the wireless just couldn't make it work and it Was painful, right?
Scott: So this device scape company in the interests of themselves being more awesome has taken the code for their meat And they may gave it under the GPL to the Linux guys.
Scott: It'll probably take them a while to shove it in the kernel because I mean there's some stuff in the kernel that does the same Stuff that this does and there's some stuff in the kernel that does better than what this does and this does things better than What the kernel does in someplace?
Rym: Yeah, they're gonna have to look it over and mesh things together.
Scott: Yeah, so it's gonna take a while But the odds are pretty good that this code will make it into the Linux kernel Which will mean that it will be very very easy to get for people to write just about.
Scott: It'll be very very easy for Linux device driver writers to write a driver for just about any wireless computer using this stuff
Rym: Which is a good thing because a lot of the reason that hardware isn't supported in Linux is simply that the people who make the Hardware don't know or care or they don't want to put extra effort into something that not that many people use.
Scott: Yeah The guys who write to make the hardware don't want to put any effort at all.
Scott: That's why device scape exists.
Scott: They did all the effort once so all the different hardware companies do the tiniest bit of effort.
Scott: So now if that company gives their stuff to Linux well Hey now only Linux has to do the tiniest bit of effort for each card, which they're just fine with.
Scott: it's piece of cake.
Scott: So wireless cards and the other thing is all of the crazy features of wireless cards that haven't worked quite So right in the past.
Scott: now they're gonna all work just great and wireless is gonna work faster and better and more reliably.
Rym: and Now if only we could get ATI to have something like that stupid ATI.
Scott: I mean they gave a driver ATI, but it's terrible.
Scott: It's terrible.
Scott: It's not nearly as good or reliable as the Nvidia driver.
Rym: Well, even in Windows the ATI drivers are pretty piss-poor.
Scott: Yep Yep.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So today I was poking around the internet and I noticed that CNN is running a story and msnbc picked it up That there was a virus for the Macintosh the OS X And I thought oh it finally happened.
Rym: then I read the story.
Rym: They were basically reporting on I'm pretty sure the Oompa Loompa Trojan that appeared back in like February or March.
Rym: Not only is it not a virus and is it nothing new, but it's really not a danger to anyone except an idiot.
Scott: How many times are we gonna hear some non technical news group?
Scott: Reporting on technical news because they're dumb.
Rym: now a lot of people have put forth that.
Rym: hmm msnbc was breaking this.
Rym: Hey, maybe a run-up to Vista.
Scott: I Don't think so, I don't know.
Scott: I think it's just another stupid tech journalist at the Associated Press.
Rym: The funny thing is that they was on FARC and mostly the comments for people with windows saying yeah You Linux you're uh, you uh, Macintosh people suck.
Rym: You're just as bad as us.
Rym: There's people.
Rym: don't target you yet because you're not popular Still think that oh my god.
Scott: Yeah, how many times do we need to debunk that stupid myth?
Rym: Yep to real briefly because I feel like debunking it again.
Rym: Macintoshes and Linux's are more secure by design.
Rym: There's no way around that.
Rym: They're not a hundred percent secure, but nothing in the world is a hundred percent secure.
Scott: Yeah, well there is there's.
Scott: there's a hundred something per hundred percent of cure a safe made of indestructible steel With the keys inside of it and it's locked.
Rym: There's no such thing as indestructible steel.
Scott: shut up.
Rym: black hole could get that open shut up.
Scott: but yeah, that's you know, I Mean there's the architect.
Rym: It's secure and the code is at least for Linux open.
Rym: So a lot of smart people look at it all the time.
Rym: and if some smart hacker thinks hey I can break in Some smart less evil hacker thinks hey, I can keep people from getting in and fix it.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: and as for Macintoshes, they put a lot of money into their software because their software is it that is their company now.
Scott: Well that and iPods It's really just the way.
Scott: I mean.
Scott: plan 9 is an operating system.
Scott: It's also a movie but that's that's where I got its name from and that's If you go to read about plan 9 just search on Google for plan 9 and it you'll read about this operating system.
Scott: By design, it's as secure and as awesome as an operating system can be but at the same time by design It's not really useful or practical.
Scott: Yeah, but you'll see how.
Scott: oh look the way this is designed.
Scott: security is like super perfect and Linux is designed a lot closer to the way plan 9 is designed than the way windows is designed.
Scott: You know, even if Linux is the number one operating system in the universe Sure, a lot more people would be trying to break it But at the same time all the breakages would be fixed really quickly a lot slower a lot faster than the second Tuesday of the month.
Rym: Well, I saw someone slashdot made a nice analogy to robbers breaking into houses with security systems.
Rym: They don't break into the houses that have the popular security system they break into the houses that have the weak security system.
Rym: Now before I say my thing of the day I'd like to say right now that I don't want to get any guff about this being old
Scott: Because guff guff McGuffin
Rym: McGruff take a bite out of crime
Scott: rough
Rym: Alright, so I saw an animated gif from my thing of the day the previous I think Monday or Tuesday on Fark And I wondered I wonder what that is.
Rym: Then Thursday, I saw it and I thought oh if it weren't for the fact that I already just recorded the show This would have been my thing of the day.
Rym: I'll make it my thing of the day Monday.
Rym: Then it exploded over the internet to the point that someone even posted it in our forums.
Scott: I think two or three people posted in our forums.
Rym: So thus my thing of the day for anyone who hasn't already seen it because goddamn it It was an awesome thing that no one had seen when I saw it.
Rym: Okay Okay, so I'm sure you've all heard of Firefox flicks, it's basically that a contest to make ads for Firefox and This was the second place winner of the contest even though it technically broke all the rules of the contest.
Rym: Yeah, it probably would have been in first place if it weren't for the fact that it broke almost every rule because it's hilarious.
Rym: I can't say any more other than that.
Rym: It is an accurate representation of the web browsers out there.
Scott: I like how opera wasn't represented at all.
Scott: No one cares about opera, that's why it wasn't there.
Rym: I'll care a lot more when I get it on my DS.
Scott: Yeah, probably Anyway, my thing of the day.
Scott: Well This isn't funny or anything like that as usual.
Scott: There's this guy Douglas Rushkoff.
Scott: I've known about him for like six years.
Rym: Yeah, in fact you won his contest.
Scott: I did win a contest and he sent me like a signed copy of his latest book, which is about Innovation from the inside out.
Scott: But anyway, he's an author.
Scott: He's an adjunct professor of media something at NYU.
Scott: He's on all kinds of documentaries.
Scott: I think he did two different frontline documentaries.
Scott: One of them was the very popular merchants of cool.
Scott: He basically knows all about marketing and Trends and media and all that sort of stuff and he's really really smart like he's an intellectual for a living like goddamn.
Scott: and Currently he's writing this cool comic book called Testament, which is Biblical but also not biblical.
Scott: at the same time You should actually if you haven't read it go to the comic store and find issue one I think.
Scott: actually I think the trade paperback should be out or the either this month or next month.
Rym: Well speaking as the one who doesn't like comics so much.
Rym: I'm probably going to read it because it does look good.
Scott: It's not a superhero comic.
Scott: It's like what they do is they'll have like a story in like a somewhat near future.
Scott: it's two stories at once.
Scott: it's Bible stories and somewhat near future sci-fi stories and He'll show you some kids like rebelling against the evil big brother government and they all have RFID tags in their hands.
Scott: and Then he'll show you a story from the Bible like every other page and they match up like the characters match up and what they're doing matches up and it's like.
Scott: That's what I have to learn from that story in the Bible.
Scott: But this isn't like your bullshit grandma Christian Bible.
Scott: This is like the real deal, too.
Scott: If you haven't read some What's the word for them?
Scott: the books that didn't make it the apocryphal texts?
Rym: Yeah apocryphal texts Yeah, like the Gospel of Judah.
Scott: and if you don't know Judas Judas.
Scott: Yeah, and if you don't know actual history as opposed to just Biblical history then a lot of this won't make sense.
Scott: however He also wrote this book.
Scott: while he's big you let me just say he's a big Jew like losing Brooklyn.
Scott: He's a big Jew And I wasn't really sure how much of a Jew he was.
Scott: I read his book called like nothing sacred.
Scott: It was all about Like what being a Jew is really all about and this stuff and it's actually pretty cool.
Scott: Like it's not religious It's about Judaism from some other kind of standpoint.
Scott: I don't think there's really too many books about religion like that one.
Rym: Yeah, well, this is you coming from mr.
Rym: Open source Jugel.
Scott: Yeah, that's what this guy came up with open source Judaism this.
Scott: Anyway today on his blog he came out with this article that was like holy crap And that's my thing of the day.
Scott: There's this article on his blog.
Rym: It was a good article.
Rym: I gotta say god damn.
Scott: So this is a guy remember this guy's wife wrote a book about fun things to do on Hanukkah.
Scott: He's a Jew and the name of this article is faith equals illness.
Scott: why I've had it with religious tolerance?
Scott: Okay, so let's get into this God game.
Scott: There's no goddamn guy You got damn cut the ham.
Scott: This is a big juice hang.
Scott: There's no God.
Scott: Usually if you talk to like Hasid's and like super Jews like really really religious Orthodox Jews They'll like kind of dodge the question.
Scott: You'd like there's no God.
Scott: He hasn't done any miracles and they'd be like a Mumble mumble tradition mumble mumble.
Scott: My father did it mumble mumble Always with the mumbling.
Scott: Yeah, they don't.
Scott: I don't think they a lot of them actually believe in like magical craziness.
Scott: They just believe in like, you know, their juice stuff.
Scott: I'm sure there are some who believe in magical craziness, but kavala.
Scott: I haven't really met so many of them.
Scott: so In this article what he writes about is basically there's no God and we need to use the body.
Scott: The Bible should be the weapon of atheists And it's really cool because he talks about it all from his media genius standpoint.
Rym: yeah, like co-opting stories from the Bible and making them relevant so that they can't be seen literally.
Rym: but there you have to accept them as the Aphorisms that they are or the metaphors that they are.
Scott: Yep, which is really what it's about I mean, I think that's how of a Jew he is is like he won't eat it.
Scott: he looks at the passage in the You know in the in the Torah and it says don't cook a calf and its mother's milk.
Scott: Well the crazy Jews they stay kosher You know.
Scott: and he says, you know, well that obviously just means that you shouldn't add insult to injury.
Scott: It's not only does he not add insult to injury But you know, he won't eat like chicken and eggs.
Scott: Yeah, just for like symbolism sake, you know to remind him, huh, you know You know not for any.
Scott: I'm going to be smitten reason.
Scott: You know, at least I remember him saying that once you've said, you know about a thousand times What I say, I know you just said, you know God damn it.
Rym: Yeah We were just talking about.
Rym: you say like I'm too much.
Scott: Well, I'm done with this thing of the day.
Scott: Everyone should read it.
Rym: Yeah, I mean it's interesting.
Rym: his main point seems to be that the best way to and he really seems to be kind of bent on getting rid of Christianity and religion in general, but Christianity is To make the Bible relevant to modern life in a very direct way.
Scott: Well, his comic book does a real good job of that and so it is his Jew book.
Scott: so if you're interested in that stuff, I recommend you read.
Scott: so like other stuff is about business and Selling people stuff and or avoiding being sold stuff to coercion.
Rym: Yeah, so I'm like so God damn it All right I'm gonna try to stop saying so um and like do I have to play a buzzer every time you say one of those words?
Scott: I don't know if it'll help.
Rym: Well, I'll try it for the next few minutes until I either get sick of it or stop noticing Okay, or my headache destroys me and I just stop talking.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, we're talking about hosting today.
Rym: Since one people have asked us about it and two we didn't really talk about it in depth at our podcasting panel because it is kind of a technical subject.
Scott: Well, the first thing you need to know about hosting is what the hell do you want to do?
Rym: Yeah, I mean a lot of people say like oh I have internet hosting but unless you're gonna do something with it You're just pissing money down a well Well, do you want to have a web page?
Scott: Do you want to have a blog?
Scott: What kind of blog do you want to have?
Scott: Do you want to do a podcast?
Scott: Do you want to have a game server?
Scott: Do you want to have a TeamSpeak server?
Scott: maybe some other sort of Server of some kind?
Scott: do you want to use hamachi?
Scott: Do you want?
Scott: you know it?
Scott: you want to have a jabber server?
Scott: We got to figure out what you're gonna serve before you pick your hosting.
Rym: Yeah, because there are a lot of options.
Rym: I mean to contrast it this way the two ends of the spectrum on one end.
Rym: You've got like Akamai static content with like Clusters of j-boss web sphere awesome application servers running crazy enterprise stuff.
Scott: That's Google.
Rym: thousands and thousands and thousands and thousands of dollars a second.
Rym: or what have you enterprise nuttiness on the other end?
Rym: You've got geocities with two megabytes of web space for free or a blog spot where they or live journal.
Scott: You get a free blog.
Scott: you get a free live.
Scott: You're my space.
Scott: Yeah my space.
Scott: There you go.
Rym: I Mean basically there is an option for everyone in every situation And you really have to figure out what you're gonna do and then narrow your choices down.
Rym: I mean do you want a web hosting or full-on hosting?
Rym: when most people say they have hosting they mean they have web hosting.
Rym: mm-hmm.
Scott: most web hosts aren't Really web hosts.
Scott: well they are but they're not really giving you a computer or even a fake computer.
Scott: They're giving you some space on an existing web server And they're giving you a web site with which you can manage your space on that web server And you can only put certain things in that space.
Scott: It's like if I had set up a whole Linux machine and on that Linux machine I create an HT Docs directory, and I say you can do whatever you want in that directory But you can't go anywhere else in this computer or do anything else.
Rym: Yep, so nothing dynamic.
Rym: No scripts nothing.
Scott: Well, they might enable like PHP and MySQL in there and give you a certain Basis.
Rym: Next step up yeah from just web hosting straight-up crap web hosting.
Scott: oh Yes, static web hosting is kind of black.
Rym: Yeah, that's what geo cities, and what was that other place back in the day?
Scott: That's it.
Scott: That's what it used to be.
Scott: yeah, yeah.
Scott: But then they added you know okay now you can have PHP Which is the same damn thing.
Scott: only now you can put a wordpress in there if you want to Which seems to be the wave of the future.
Rym: I mean not many people make static web pages anymore except You know small businesses and restaurants.
Rym: You don't know better.
Scott: Yeah, I don't remember the last time I made a static web page.
Rym: I made one for a class.
Rym: I took my freshman year at RIT.
Scott: Oh, yeah I guess I made some in school when I had to you know.
Rym: the worst thing is about that page I made.
Rym: I put it up on my geo cities account because I happen to still have the hosting there And it's still there and now I don't know the password or anything so I can't go get rid of it.
Scott: You know what the thing thing is now even if I wanted to do something I've done before we're like a static web page.
Scott: like I remember I made a static web page for a project I did in computer graphics - if I was doing that today I wouldn't make a static web page by writing HTML.
Scott: I would install a wiki and then do it.
Scott: yep It's just no reason to make a static web page anymore.
Scott: But that's a web hosting.
Scott: if all you want is a web page or a blog.
Scott: If you're just doing a blog and nothing else you should probably do a blog spot or wordpress.com or one of those things.
Scott: Wordpress.com is free is it really?
Rym: I believe it is.
Scott: I never checked it out.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: it's supposed to be pretty cool.
Rym: I haven't actually needed to use it since we have hosting Mm-hmm or live journal like you know.
Scott: any of those things would be just fine for you.
Scott: Don't bother spending money on it.
Rym: Yes, there's.
Rym: basically there's a big line between not spending money and spending money.
Rym: There's also a big line between spending a pittance and actually spending money.
Scott: Yeah if you really want to have a blog where you can do all kinds of things and maybe use a Wordpress or moveable type or something like that and you don't want to do a free thing then You're gonna want to pay like five ten bucks a month.
Rym: Yeah, I mean literally for five or ten bucks a month.
Rym: you can get Enough bandwidth to cover any amount of slash dotting and a nice host as long as you don't try to post Photoshops to Fark on a regular basis.
Scott: Yeah, don't post photoshop stuff are.
Rym: those places will probably also do your email for you.
Scott: Now if you want to do something like photo heavy you can use flickr or some such.
Scott: I think there's a flickr competitor now actually and You'll have plenty of image hosting and all that stuff and you won't have to pay for a giant Host full of storage space and all that crap.
Rym: Yeah, basically you're still just basically in web.
Rym: I said basically twice three times Anyway flickr is really cheap.
Scott: flickr is like 25 bucks a year.
Rym: But at this point, I mean you're making web pages.
Rym: you're making.
Rym: it may be dynamic, but it's not heavy content and The price is scaled very very easily toward more and more bandwidth because you're not doing anything fancy.
Scott: More and more storage space more and more bandwidth more email addresses more MySQL databases because you're gonna need one per blog.
Rym: Yeah, but if you're going this route I mean you'll get up to.
Rym: if you get for the forty forty five dollar a month range You've got a crazy amount of bandwidth for most normal activities.
Scott: for forty forty five dollars a month You should probably shouldn't be using something.
Scott: That's just a web interface to a web page.
Scott: You probably should be getting something more for your money.
Rym: Well, it depends on what kind of person you are.
Rym: I mean more for your money also means you have to do more.
Rym: That's true Unless you go to the far end of the spectrum.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So the next level of hosting is actually it starts to break apart.
Scott: There are three different type.
Scott: well, okay, there's managed and Unmanaged hosting.
Rym: that's a good dichotomy.
Scott: Managed is when someone else takes care of the shit for you.
Scott: now I know we were talking about before where you just have a way to better.
Scott: a web interface is Technically managed because they take care of all the software on the computer.
Scott: All you have to worry about is the your web content.
Scott: Everything else is taken care of for you.
Scott: But you can also get Managed hosting where someone takes care of that stuff for you, but you're not confined to a web interface.
Scott: You're actually getting a computer or a fake computer
Rym: Yep, or even to the point where someone takes care of the physical computer But you take care of everything else
Scott: or you just tell someone what to do and they do it for you Like, okay I need you to do this and this and this and this and this and then they do it for you.
Rym: and basically at This point the only difference between the two routes is that the more managed you want it to be the more you want other People to take care of for you and the more the more you're gonna have to pay for each increment of betterness.
Scott: Yeah, and if you can't find a hosting solution that already matches what you want and you want something special now You're gonna have to pay even more money.
Scott: Unmanaged is where you have a computer and you do it yourself.
Rym: I mean that could be either you have a cable modem and you've got a web server under your desk Mm-hmm all the way up to you co-locate which is where you build a computer.
Rym: you ship it off to someone and they maintain the Computer for you, but you do everything else yourself.
Rym: It's your computer completely.
Rym: All they do is plug it in to the wall and plug it into the Ethernet and then they don't touch it.
Rym: You call them if you want it rebooted.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Now if you want a hard rebooted, you can she be able to softly boot it From far away.
Rym: Yeah, well hard reboot.
Rym: I mean if you want to reboot it you screwed something up That's for sure.
Rym: cuz you're not hosting this on Windows.
Scott: No, you're not.
Scott: if you're hosting with Windows You got a problem even though a lot of people do.
Scott: it's scary.
Scott: Yeah, it is scary and they remote desktop in and do stuff.
Rym: and uh, though at least worldwide most people use Apache.
Scott: Yeah, even they might be running it on Windows.
Scott: Yeah But most people run Apache on Linux or BSD and lamp is number one pretty much Linux Apache MySQL PHP Perl Ruby Python, whatever.
Rym: I'm per lamp room a bigger.
Scott: Yeah Well, the P technically stands for Python Perl or PHP Usually PHP, but they threw Ruby in there because now a lot of people ride the rails.
Rym: Well, we're going off in a lot of direction.
Rym: So I guess let's describe exactly what we have for hosting.
Rym: All right, you know kind of a nice scenario of what our needs were what we got and then why we upgraded.
Scott: All right We have a line ode.
Scott: line ode is sort of a special host that fits our needs exactly which is why we have them And they're unlike almost every other host there is.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: It's an it's a mildly managed solution, which means They don't do anything for me, but they have really good tech support.
Scott: So if I have a problem I just say hey and then BAM someone does stuff for me.
Rym: Yep to put it in fairly non technical terms.
Rym: They have a big Linux computer.
Rym: They have a whole bunch of.
Scott: they have a whole bunch of them But there's just one that we care about.
Rym: that's really big and they chop it up into a whole bunch of virtual little Linux computers.
Scott: You can actually do this at home.
Scott: if you have any computer you can install user mode Linux on it and what this allows you to do is Turn any Linux computer into any number of Linux computers.
Scott: So even though you have one CPU physically you can actually your network and you know for all intents and purposes You could have a hundred Linux computers if you have enough RAM now.
Rym: This is really great for well hosting like we're talking about or for anyone who ever works in the school or teaches.
Rym: It's a great way to set up a classroom.
Scott: Or for developers.
Scott: Yes, if you want to try you want to test something out on a bunch of different Linux's But you only have one computer sitting there.
Scott: Perfect.
Rym: Or if you're just a hobbyist and you want to play around with something cool Yeah, so they have a giant computer and it's split up into smaller computers.
Scott: We get one of the smaller computers.
Scott: So from our perspective, I have a perfectly normal Linux computer where I'm the root and I'm the master and I can do whatever I want.
Scott: it has a lot of bandwidth and It doesn't crash and everything's cool.
Rym: Yep, and basically what they do is they they guarantee us we'll get at least this much CPU at any given time.
Rym: We could get more depending on what the box is doing, but we have a guaranteed minimum.
Rym: That's how most hostings work.
Rym: They'll guarantee you a minimum amount of X. They'll guarantee you at least X bandwidth.
Rym: Mm-hmm that sort of thing.
Scott: Yeah, we have a limit of now.
Scott: We have a limit of 200 gigabytes per month of transfer.
Rym: Yeah, now it used to have to be bytes.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It used to be half that though We started with.
Rym: it was a $40 a month line owed.
Scott: Mm-hmm and it meant a hundred and sixty megabytes of RAM And are like six gigs of hard drive space.
Scott: I think I'm not too much.
Scott: Yeah, if you go to line oh calm we should probably link to it.
Scott: Yeah, and you click on Line ODEs, you'll see all the different line ODEs.
Scott: We had the line owed 160. now We have the line owed 320 which is 80 bucks a month and everything's doubled Yep.
Rym: Now we went with the $40 a month one because early on Scott basically just got it for his blog Yep, and that one was just fine and it was perfect.
Rym: I mean he used it a lot.
Rym: I saw and I thought it was really cool and I was actually thinking about getting one for me back then.
Rym: I never did because well we started GeekNights Yep.
Rym: So we use his and then Emily knew wanted a website and we had plenty of space.
Rym: so we hosted it and then we took over.
Rym: Well, we were helping work with this gaming group near as we've talked about them before.
Rym: so we started hosting their website And then we ran into a problem.
Rym: We didn't run that a hard drive space even levels GeekNights episodes on there Yep, and the CPU was getting pegged, but it wasn't anywhere near the breaking point.
Scott: We were starting to run out of bandwidth, but as soon as you got lips and that was no longer a problem.
Rym: Yeah, we'll talk about them later.
Scott: But we started to run out of RAM because when you run v hosts with Apache Apache spawns a whole nother set of processes and eats up memory.
Rym: Yep, because we only had well it then we only had one but now we had more 60 megabytes.
Rym: But we have X IP addresses and we have X plus Y domains pointing at our place.
Rym: So we have virtual hosting where a one web server is hosting a bunch of different domains and it takes RAM to figure all that Crap out.
Scott: Well, kinda.
Rym: Yeah, we don't want to go into detail of virtual hosting.
Rym: That's another show.
Rym: We'll do the Apache show someday.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So we ran out of RAM.
Scott: I fixed that by making some swap space, but that makes everything go slow and shitty.
Rym: Yeah, you might have noticed that GeekNights site was slowly getting slower over the past several weeks.
Scott: Now I have more random.
Scott: You know what to do with.
Rym: Yep, because it got to the point where we realized alright We've already outgrown our hosting.
Rym: Let's pay more for more and the thing is if you have any amount of money when you're want to host something You can you'll never run into a problem because you can always just throw more money at it and it'll get better.
Scott: Mm-hmm Now I could have solved the problem by switching from Apache to light HdTPD or whatever you want to call it.
Scott: The problem with that is it would have been significantly more downtime to switch to that than to switch to the better line.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and there was more that could have gone wrong that we would have had to then stare at and yell about.
Scott: Yeah, I'm currently looking for a way to possibly when the new version of Ubuntu Ubuntu 6 damper Drake when dapper Drake comes out.
Scott: I'm gonna look into a way to switch to dapper Drake with light TTP D Without go getting a lot of down.
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: because see the way the line ode works now is that basically they have a list of operating system images and Instead of having to do it all manually install We just picked what operating system we want and we say put an image of that on our line ode and it goes
Scott: Yep, when you get a line ode at first, it's completely blank.
Scott: Then you choose a distribution how much space you want it to take up among other options and it just does it for you.
Scott: And they have a bunch of distributions you can choose from.
Rym: Scott pick Gentoo.
Rym: for a number of reasons though We're slowly leaning more toward Ubuntu in general as time goes on because I love Gentoo, but it's a pain in the ass Sometimes.
Scott: yeah now it's less of a pain in the ass.
Scott: I tried out the GUI installer today, but we'll hold off on that.
Scott: Yeah anyway Wait, you can also do is you can split up your hard drive space and install a whole bunch of distributions.
Scott: However, you can only use one at a time on line ode.
Scott: so you got to pick one.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway, you see we don't pay that much.
Rym: I mean $80 a month for a lot of power and a lot of space and a lot of bandwidth But we have to do all the work.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: If you want the sim similar level of hosting, but you don't want to do all that work It'll probably cost you more like a hundred and twenty dollars a month.
Rym: Mm-hmm But it's how much is your time worth to you if you don't know anything about Linux?
Rym: You're gonna spend a lot of time learning it in short order if you try to do what we just did.
Scott: a lot of people In the line ode forums are like well someone take care of my line ode for me and everyone's like why did you get a line?
Scott: Ode this isn't for you.
Scott: This is for people who want to be able to do anything.
Scott: I mean how many hosts out there?
Scott: Can you go and say hey, I need a jabber server and a teamspeak server and I want to use this weird web server That's not Apache and I want to use this weird email thing and you can't get anyone to do that for you have to get a line ode and set it up yourself because the only way to get those sorts of Services to have your own Linux computer out in the real world with those things on it.
Rym: See because there's the big difference to most people only want web hosting.
Rym: we host our own jabber server front row crew.
Rym: That's why if you ever talk to us on jabber, it's Rym or Scott at front row crew calm.
Rym: Mm-hmm We don't host our own email because email.
Scott: we did host our own email, but then it sucked.
Scott: So I switched it to using Gmail for hosted.
Rym: Yeah, the reasons that we'll talk about in yet another show Wow We're just spawning off Monday shows tonight.
Rym: We sure are hosting your own email can be done and we've done it.
Rym: It sucks.
Rym: It really really is not trivial to run an email server in this day and age.
Scott: No it is not.
Rym: mostly because of all the stuff you have to do to protect yourself from spam and Make sure other people can actually get your messages because they're trying to predict themselves from spam.
Scott: and Remember when I talked about virtual hosting.
Scott: having more than one domain More than one domain on the same computer in the same IP address for a web server is relatively easy.
Scott: More than one domain for the same email server is hell.
Rym: Partly email email as you all may know is very old.
Scott: It hasn't changed much in a long long time and there are some email servers You can use these days like qmail that are better alternatives to the old send mail and postfix and I think this XM Also, and they're a little easier.
Scott: But there's still a huge pain in the ass to make them do what you want them to do.
Rym: Plus your IP address might just be in a range that someone doesn't like and then your email won't work.
Scott: Anyway, yeah, if you use you know, I might send someone an email they won't get it because spam filters.
Scott: Yeah, even though I'm not a spammer, you know, they don't know I'm not.
Scott: they might whitelist.
Rym: so I'll say right now.
Rym: I Would highly recommend not as a plug or anything but gmail for domains if you can get a hold of that.
Rym: That is awesome Right.
Scott: So there's also Co-location which you talked about a little bit.
Scott: It's where you send a computer off to the middle of nowhere in terms of the work.
Rym: You'll have to do.
Rym: It's mostly the same as what we have to do now with our line out.
Rym: It's your computer.
Scott: Yeah, the difference is is that you make a computer.
Scott: you can send any computer you want.
Scott: You could go to the new egg and buy a computer that has any amount of CPU hard drive or whatever that you need And then you send it somewhere and what you do is you pay them a monthly fee to keep your computer.
Scott: what they give you for that money is Number one a guarantee usually that no one's gonna mess with your computer like physical security.
Scott: No one can get in the building unless they're an employee, etc, etc.
Scott: To they make sure your computer doesn't fill up with dust.
Scott: They make sure the power doesn't go out because they have generators.
Rym: Yeah, they got air conditioning.
Rym: They'll watch it if it overheats or beeps at them.
Scott: Yep, if your hard drive crashes They'll probably take care of you as long as you pay for a new hard drive all that sort of good stuff.
Scott: They give you a network connection.
Scott: That's really fast a lot faster than what you have at home.
Scott: They'll give you a certain amount of bandwidth.
Scott: They will make guarantee that it'll be up for a certain percentage of time usually 99 or 100 percent of the time.
Scott: Now you and I real IP address.
Rym: now co-location itself.
Rym: Wanting to do it or not It's if you.
Rym: you basically only co-locate if you need a lot of power or you have a specialized thing You need to do because it tends to be more expensive.
Scott: Yep It's you I think.
Scott: last time it looks like a hundred bucks a month for like some kind of normal co-location But it's usually.
Scott: it's usually more plus.
Rym: you have to buy the hardware.
Rym: Yeah, which can scale?
Rym: I mean a server can cost between four hundred and forty thousand dollars.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: That was a 40.
Rym: Yeah Though the biggest server I've ever actually played with was a six thousand dollar one.
Rym: you little one.
Rym: you means It's really thin it and it goes in a rack little x-series cool thing from IBM.
Scott: Yeah, the real reason that co-location is popular is for game servers.
Scott: That's like the number one use of co-location.
Scott: if you want to run a counter-strike server If you want to run it behind a cable modem in your house It's not so easy because you either had to expose it to the internet or you to fiddle with routers and your cable modem.
Scott: The IP address might change sometimes.
Scott: You know, it's not so easy.
Rym: You probably got really really little upstream bandwidth.
Scott: Yeah, that's the other thing.
Scott: is it sure?
Scott: You can always just host something in your house to their cable modem or your DSL except email almost any isp.
Rym: Oh block email.
Scott: Yes, that's true.
Scott: The problem with hosting something behind a cable modem in your house?
Scott: There's a few problems.
Scott: number one, you don't have a guaranteed static IP address.
Scott: It might change.
Scott: it usually won't but it might.
Rym: number two.
Rym: You don't have a guaranteed internet connection.
Scott: Yeah, it might go down your power might go out.
Rym: our cable modem has gone down before we're sitting here and I've got the finished Episode and I can't upload it because I have no internet.
Scott: Yeah, we can't upload it.
Scott: But at least other people can still weed through our archives.
Scott: Hello.
Rym: Yay We we.
Scott: yeah.
Scott: three if you have some sort of router, you know You're it's becomes a huge pain in the ass to have servers in your house behind your router.
Rym: Yes because if you have base you only have one IP address.
Rym: if you have an ISP and you're getting cable modem or whatever very few People pay for multiple IP addresses because net network address translation has pretty much obviated that need.
Rym: However net often breaks things in ways that you might not realize unless you know how net works.
Scott: So if you want to host anything in the real world You need a real IP address like with no net in the way at all.
Rym: I still mostly recommend something like a line ode or a managed host as opposed to co-locating Because co-locating involves a lot more work Like we've said many times and really unless you have a specialized need you don't really need that.
Rym: Yep, because if you're just running a web server, it doesn't matter what hardware it's on doesn't matter anything.
Rym: You just need to know how fast is how much bandwidth you have.
Scott: Mm-hmm The other reasons that you don't want to host a server inside your house is because cable networks tend to be full of you know worms floating around and IP addresses at hosted locations tend not to have being attacked by worms constantly.
Scott: So if you're doing a Windows host, you don't want to put it in your cable modem area.
Rym: Also, you start torrenting and suddenly your server disappears.
Scott: Yeah, that's a great one.
Scott: Yeah, so you can put something, you know And there are solutions to solve some of the problems of trying to host something from your house Like dynamic DNS and such.
Scott: but those things don't work.
Scott: that well It's really not worth it and they're a pain in the ass.
Rym: I mean and you'll you'll only need the server.
Rym: basically like sounds if you're running a game server And if you're running anything other than a game server that needs something specialized like that and a lot of horsepower You're probably doing something big.
Rym: that's gonna cost you money.
Scott: Anyway, yeah a lot of people try to do too much with it and They don't want to spend money, but they want to do a lot of stuff.
Scott: Well, you're gonna have to spend money if you want to do it.
Scott: Well, you're just gonna do a shitty job if you try to not pay enough money.
Rym: now in regards to colocation and game server Specifically, I know I can't come up with any offhand because I haven't cared about this in at least three years.
Rym: But there are many services out there that will co-locate or host for you game servers.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: They're actually really cheap.
Scott: yeah, because Hosting a game server, especially for a modern game.
Scott: I don't know if you want to make I guess battlefield Do they have servers?
Rym: Let's just say a half-life to something something All right a counter-strike source server.
Scott: You kind of need a lot of horsepower for a counter-strike source server.
Rym: Yeah, also actually do need more bandwidth than you think.
Scott: yeah Especially if you want to have a lot of players.
Scott: if you want a five player server It doesn't have to be that powerful.
Scott: if you want a twenty thirty player server.
Scott: You need a serious freaking computer.
Rym: Yeah, that's why you can't really host game servers with normal hosts because our line ode we get what like 50 or 100 megahertz guaranteed On the processor.
Rym: It's not much.
Scott: It's not much now.
Scott: We ran the web server doesn't need that much.
Rym: We ran a moderately popular counter-strike server when we were at RIT.
Rym: It was this crap Oh computer that we threw in the corner plugged into the walls a Pentium 3 450 Let me put it this way.
Rym: RIT had two OC threes and a t3.
Rym: We had basically infinite bandwidth and a direct link to internet - If more than six or seven people connected to our server the pings went up to about 700 and then it crashed.
Rym: Yeah, and that was counter-strike one running the tiniest map we could find.
Rym: I see world.
Scott: I see world was the only map it could handle.
Scott: if we tried to use a bigger map it would crash.
Rym: Now I'm gonna give you all out there who may want to host a game server.
Rym: the ultimate secret.
Rym: the best way to host game Servers in the world is to either be in college or know someone in college.
Rym: Every good game server you've ever played on is either subsidized by a company or subsidized by a big webcomic or something or It's some guy running it under his desk in college.
Scott: an extra computer sitting around in a college is awesome because colleges have crazy bandwidth crazy numbers of players and All you really need to do is get an awesome computer and stick it in the college somewhere and your gold.
Scott: you don't need to buy a co-location You don't need to pay for anything.
Scott: You're all set.
Rym: and the best thing is if you're a geek and you're in college now You'll probably for the rest of your life still know someone who knows someone who's at that college.
Rym: You can pass servers down through the generations as long as no one's a fucker.
Rym: Yeah, but if we make that tribe server, I imagine we're gonna have it hosted somewhere on RIT's network.
Scott: No, I think we might do it under my desk.
Scott: We'll see.
Rym: We'll see with the hamachi because hamachi is awesome now Yeah, but I'll bet we could get it at RIT.
Scott: Maybe we could.
Scott: that'd be cool All right.
Scott: Another thing is dedicated hosting.
Scott: dedicated hosting just means that they give you a computer that's dedicated to you.
Scott: Normally when you get hosting they split up a computer into a bunch of pieces and you get a piece of it Dedicated.
Scott: just means we have a server here.
Scott: If you get dedicated hosting we give you the whole server.
Scott: It's all yours.
Scott: you don't have to share it with anyone and It's kind of expensive depending on what cert they usually charge you based on what kind of server.
Scott: they give you like.
Scott: if you want They'll say like for this wussy server.
Scott: you pay this much for this awesome crazy server.
Scott: You pay this much for this insane server.
Scott: You pay a fortune for this biggest server.
Scott: We've got.
Scott: we take your firstborn.
Scott: That's how it works now.
Rym: We said we'd talk about specifically what we have and we talked about lino then went off on a tangent.
Rym: But we do have two other hostings.
Rym: We actually use three separate hostings for GeekNights.
Rym: We have the line ode which is basically everything.
Rym: It's the websites the databases the jabbers the forums.
Rym: everything that is dynamic is on our web server the line ode and this is kind of the same way that most companies do it because you have the dynamic content on your local server and then the Static content is cached or hosted somewhere else.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: We host all of our static content.
Rym: I eat the podcast of eg the podcast on Libsyn which we don't like but I hate to say this.
Rym: there are really no competitors in the market right now.
Scott: There are some but they're not just as bad.
Scott: They're worse.
Rym: worse.
Rym: I mean, yeah, basically podcasts are gonna present a unique problem to people who want to host.
Scott: Well, it's it's as people want to host different sorts of services out on the internet They need.
Scott: they have different needs.
Scott: Gaming people need a lot of CPU and a lot of RAM But they don't really need hard drive space and they don't need so much bandwidth.
Rym: They just need high speed pings and such podcasters need something that until recently was only the realm of people with deep pockets.
Rym: Yeah, you know lots of bandwidth and you need lots of storage space that will continue to grow at a steady rate forever.
Scott: But you don't really need CPU and you don't really need so much RAM.
Scott: You just need storage and bandwidth.
Rym: Yep You don't even need.
Scott: you don't even leave fast You just need it to be bandwidth a lot of data Even if it goes slowly as long as it goes reliably.
Rym: now, the problem is podcasting wallets cool and popular.
Rym: It hasn't really taken off yet So there's not a huge market for people that cater to podcasters.
Rym: Podcasters have very unique specific needs that are not easily met by the market.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: So recently people like Libsyn have sprung up to you know, fill this void in the market, but they're not too good at it.
Rym: They're definitely wave one Companies.
Rym: whenever there's a new trend on the internet or actually in the world in general like a new thing appears There's always the first wave and the first wave are the people who got into the market quick.
Rym: Then there's the second wave of people who get into the market.
Scott: Well, mmm We're gonna ride both waves and we're not gonna stop riding unless we die.
Rym: I mean honestly the only reason we use Libsyn is because they're the only people out there that offer what we need for any amount of money we Would be willing to pay.
Rym: Mm-hmm We would have to pay hundreds of dollars a month to get that much bandwidth from a dedicated real host.
Scott: Yeah, it's a problem.
Scott: I mean look at the Libsyn for 80 a month.
Scott: We get 200 gig.
Rym: We don't pay 80 a month.
Rym: We pay 20.
Scott: Oh No, I mean for the line ode.
Scott: Yeah, we pay 80 a month for 200 gigabytes of transfer.
Scott: We're doing about a hundred gigabytes of transfer right now.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: So if you how long?
Rym: and remember that's a hundred gigabytes Accounting the fact that most of our mp3s are not there anymore.
Rym: Yeah our Our archives alone generate almost that that in the RSS feed and the forums.
Scott: Yeah, it's not it's not the greatest.
Rym: Now Libsyn we're paying what 20 bucks a month and we get infinity bandwidth and infinity storage space.
Scott: Well, it's not technically infinity because we can only do is a limit and how much podcasting we can do but we don't break the limit.
Rym: Yep We're pretty much on the limit because I didn't want to pay for the next step up because that's way more than we need For now unless I really up the audio quality to something crazy, which isn't gonna happen till we get new microphones.
Scott: So yeah, the last thing you need to know about hosting short of crazy enterprise stuff Which we'll talk about last because you know, no one really cares about that.
Scott: I don't think any company executors listening.
Rym: Yeah if anyone really wants to know about that stuff ask us and we'll do a show on it because I I've worked for IBM and I've done that stuff and I can tell you a lot about it.
Scott: last thing really to talk about is domains.
Scott: a domain is really just.
Scott: We'll explain this at some point in the future when we talk about how computers work.
Rym: Yep It's just a name that turns into an IP address, you know, you type google.com and it goes to 62 dot something something something.
Scott: Yep, all domain names are our words that turn into IP addresses by DNS.
Scott: So a little little trivia for everyone out there.
Rym: domain names are actually backwards.
Scott: Yeah, it's calm.
Scott: Google.
Rym: Well, it's dot dot com dot google dot www.
Scott: Yeah, so you go to calm and then you go down to Google and then under Google you go to ww.
Rym: It's strictly hierarchical.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: so Anyway, so front row crew calm.
Scott: when you go there The DNS says front row crew calm is this IP address?
Scott: and then you talk to that IP address.
Scott: The only reason we have this system is that people don't have to memorize IP addresses, which would be a nightmare Yes, especially if ipv6 ever happens.
Scott: So this is why you need an IP address.
Scott: that doesn't change very often because the if you have a changing IP address Then you need dynamic DNS to make the domain names.
Scott: Keep pointing to the correct address.
Rym: However, if you have a dynamic address Then you're probably somewhere with an ISP who doesn't want you hosting things anyway, and they're gonna try to stop you.
Scott: Yep, and not only that but dynamic DNS is a little slow.
Scott: So there'll be periods of time where your IP address is changed and people are asking Hey, what's the IP address for your domain?
Scott: and it gives them the old IP address and it doesn't work.
Rym: It's also finicky and more importantly most people who offer DNS hosting don't support DDNS for you because it's a pain in the ass for them and it's really not a real solution.
Scott: You should be paying for hosting that's real and we have a real IP address and you're out in the real Internet and not on hidden behind some router.
Rym: now when you when you have a domain you can make infinity things under it.
Rym: Oh, yeah, we I mean one eventually the rest of the front row crew.
Rym: We'd like to give them space on front row crew so we could have you know The whale shark dot.
Rym: front row crew calm a dot.
Scott: front row crew calm beat up front record.
Scott: I can't see up front record.
Rym: And also the way DNS works to go over is really briefly Like we said we have our email hosted with Google even though it's from front row crew.
Rym: The way we do that I think we mentioned this before is the MX record because DNS has different kinds of records.
Rym: There's one kind of record that says alright websites going to front row crew calm go that way.
Rym: Email going to front row crew calm go that way and we pointed that one at Gmail.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: So if anyone tries to send us mail to a certain domain The mail goes to a different IP address than everything else because the MX record is the special mail record.
Rym: now Domains are really cheap.
Rym: And if you want to do anything on the internet get one.
Scott: Yeah, I mean Different places have them for different prices for different lengths of time.
Scott: All you have to do is remember renew it if you're gonna use it.
Scott: if you're not gonna keep using it don't renew it.
Scott: Don't buy too many domains just a waste of money.
Rym: Don't buy a dot biz.
Rym: Yeah That was the biggest failed experiment.
Rym: no one uses dot biz except shady companies.
Scott: There's really no law that says you have to buy a certain Top level domain.
Scott: like you can run an org with a dot-com and you can do a dot-com under an org.
Rym: Yeah, there used to be more strict rules about this, but there's really no way to enforce it.
Scott: Yeah, but just try to do whatever you want.
Scott: I mean and do it sounds right do it?
Rym: Yeah, I mean we've debated for a while between front row crew dot-com and front row crew dot-net because they both kind of fit What we were planning on doing.
Rym: Yeah net pretty net really doesn't mean anything anymore yeah, but generally I use net to mean like a network like a group of people collaborating or a group or a Bunch of services that are all gonna be under one name anything like that.
Scott: Yeah, I have net for my blog just cuz it sounds better.
Rym: Yeah, calm down is the most generic.
Rym: calm is just generic.
Scott: Yeah calm is pretty much anything I mean.
Scott: technically it's commercial things but anything could become.
Scott: it doesn't matter.
Rym: or I really You should really only use org if you're some sort of nonprofit.
Scott: Yeah, I mean slash dot has slash dot org So there's really no law.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but I mean like a lot of open source projects choose org specifically because of that.
Scott: Yeah, that's a really good example there.
Rym: You can't get dot edu.
Scott: Don't try you can't get that edu.
Scott: You can get dot us.
Scott: you can get dot TV.
Scott: You should really only get TV if you're gonna do like a video podcast or something like that.
Rym: Yeah, and you should really only get us if you're trying to do some cool web 2.0 thing.
Scott: Yeah, like delicious.
Rym: Yeah I'm thinking about getting nutritious and making some sort of other thing.
Scott: recipe site with.
Scott: yeah I'm pretty sure there's something for tag recipes already, but if there is why not anyone does it?
Scott: We got it right.
Scott: here is our prior art.
Scott: Yeah, bitches and if they've already done it.
Rym: Well, they put us um Dot-int you can't get.
Scott: no most people don't even know that mil you can't get.
Scott: Yeah, you can get other countries other countries.
Scott: what they do is they have like dot CEO dot the country and Then yeah, that's the standard for the whole internet.
Rym: But basically because the United States kind of invented the internet and built it in the early days We really kind of ran roughshod over the whole thing.
Rym: So we have all the good comms but some UK company ends up with dot co dot UK instead.
Scott: Yeah, but that's cool because then people who live in like Russia know to go to dot.
Scott: are you sites?
Scott: You know and they never go to the stupid US sites.
Scott: Yeah, unless you want to unless you want to but I mean this google.co.
Scott: that are you I'm pretty sure there is.
Rym: Now we have the Libsyn and we have the line ode and we also have the feed burner Which is totally free.
Scott: feed burners not really hosting.
Rym: I mean, well, they host our RSS for us.
Scott: Yeah, kind of they don't really host.
Scott: It's not a hosting company.
Scott: All they do is you send them an RSS feed and they spruce it up and that way you tell people to go read The feed burner RSS feed which is spruced up properly.
Rym: Yeah, meaning we don't have to fiddle with it to make it look right in iTunes.
Scott: Yeah but there are any has to do that.
Rym: I Mention them only because you should remember that if you want a specific thing like a simple specific thing on the internet.
Rym: There's probably a company out there that offers it for free or for very little.
Scott: Yeah, like if all you want is a mailing list You don't need to go get a dedicated server set up a mail server set up Major Domo, whatever the thing is called and then set up a mailing list You can.
Scott: there's someone who will give you just a mailing list probably for free maybe with an ad.
Rym: In fact, we use feed blitz for another site.
Rym: We run.
Scott: Yeah feed blitz I think does it.
Scott: I think Yahoo groups.
Rym: Well, it's actually is kind of cool.
Rym: It's just it'll turn an RSS feed into an email list.
Scott: Yep Yeah, if you don't like RSS readers But you like email and you want to get an email every time some website updates and that website has an RSS feed Feed blitz you can set it there.
Scott: There are other services do the same thing, you know feed blitz might not be the best one.
Rym: Yeah, though feed burner says they're gonna offer that.
Rym: I haven't looked into it yet But we might.
Rym: we might offer that on the side under a link somewhere for anyone who really hates RSS.
Scott: Yeah, you'll get an email every time GeekNights update.
Rym: Yeah four days a week.
Scott: Great Yeah, or every time yelling every Monday reminding you to go read listen to GeekNights, whatever.
Scott: But yeah, you can basically pick any blog or any podcast in the world and say hey, yeah I want to be emailed every time this guy updates.
Scott: It's good for people update infrequently possibly with long posts that are email sized and good for reading an email readers.
Rym: Yeah, maybe you got a blackberry.
Scott: Yeah That'll make it cool.
Rym: God.
Rym: I hope my new job doesn't give me a blackberry.
Rym: Every job I interviewed at they were like, yeah, we'll give you a blackberry and I was like crap We can blackberry each other.
Scott: great Just we want to do So.
Scott: yeah, that's hosting, you know?
Scott: step one figure out why you want hosting.
Scott: do you even need hosting?
Rym: Yep, step two Google and figure out who offers what you want.
Scott: Yeah get the exactly what you want.
Scott: Don't pay for stuff You're not gonna use.
Rym: yeah, because it's usually very easy to upgrade in the future.
Rym: If you need more, you can always just throw money at the problem.
Rym: but don't throw money at it before you need to throw money at it because then you're just wasting money and Go do it.
Scott: There's something out there for you.
Rym: Yeah And don't think that you can.
Rym: if you don't know anything about computers you can still do it.
Rym: there are services out there that'll take Care of you.
Rym: you'll have to pay for it.
Rym: But don't let your lack of computer knowledge prevent you from doing something on the internet that you think is a good thing to do.
Scott: Yep, the one problem you're gonna run into is there just some things you can't do without knowledge?
Scott: There's nothing you can't do without money.
Scott: There's some things you can't do without knowledge.
Scott: Well, no I guess if you had enough money You could always get like a dedicated server and then pay an IT guy with knowledge to do it and then pay someone else to Make the content.
Scott: it becomes prohibitively Expensive to do certain things without money.
Scott: like if you want to develop your own web applications that do something brand new You're gonna need smarts.
Scott: But if you just want to make a blog or a podcast you don't need so many smarts to do that.
Scott: There are plenty of websites that'll help you out.
Scott: lips in effect can do the whole thing for you.
Rym: Yeah, we don't use them for a number of reasons for all that.
Scott: Yeah So that's all there is to it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I'm sorry.
Rym: It might have sounded a little fractured.
Rym: It's Monday.
Rym: What do you expect?
Rym: Yeah We got some good stuff coming up in the next couple weeks.
Scott: Oh, we sure do.
Scott: I think for like the next month we should have good stuff.
Rym: Yeah We've got.
Rym: I mean, we've got some interviews coming up.
Rym: We've got some some interesting tidbits.
Rym: Try not to reveal much.
Scott: got some games.
Scott: We got some funniness.
Scott: It's all good.
Rym: Yeah life's been good lately.
Rym: What can we say?
Scott: So go get more people to listen?
Rym: Yeah, hopefully my headache will be gone tomorrow, which is gaming day where we'll talk about a game.
Scott: What game we gonna talk about?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Maybe you should listen and find out.
Rym: And that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is accorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.