Scott: It's Wednesday September 20th.
Scott: This is GeekNights tonight.
Scott: We discuss the anime kimono zoom a. Let's do this.
Rym: Finally finally we're back to a normal episode where we're not tired We're not trying to do anything stupid, and I don't have to make a stupid voice.
Rym: Yeah, yeah Okay, and that puzzles.
Rym: Rome is still staring me in the face.
Scott: Oh wow you didn't put it away Did you know I didn't?
Scott: I think you're turning into a rummy.
Scott: I mean most of the stuff in that closet is rum.
Rym: Yeah, surprisingly.
Rym: I have a lot of rum.
Rym: however not surprisingly much of it is owned by Scott Johnson.
Scott: Well, you know if I did like alcohol.
Scott: You know I think rum would be the alcohol of choice cuz I mean it's sugar.
Scott: What's better than sugar?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I really like whiskey and Various.
Scott: the queue is that that's corn and stuff.
Scott: I mean if you're gonna make alcohol out of something it better be sugar or at least fruit.
Rym: well You'd probably a wine drinker.
Rym: You know grapes.
Scott: grapes are good.
Scott: That's good as sugar though sugar is like the pure.
Scott: You know you can't.
Scott: it's tough to beat.
Scott: That's all I can say.
Scott: there's a reason they make candy out of sugar.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So what's happening in the news?
Scott: this.
Scott: it was real slow.
Scott: There's no real anime and manga comics news out there.
Rym: Yeah, my news the only reason I even bring it up is because I was reading slash dot and the sheer number of people who?
Rym: Are there misinformed or just stupid about the issue was driving me nuts, but all it's got to his news first all right.
Scott: Well about a year ago There was a study called debunking the game rating myth.
Scott: do game ratings matter?
Scott: and they looked at 260 different video games and they compared how well the games were rated in gaming magazines versus How well the games performed in the marketplace how many copies they sold how much money they made and all that.
Rym: so what was the?
Rym: Correlation they gathered.
Scott: well last year they did the study and it turned out that game ratings don't matter.
Scott: So they did the study again this year and instead of doing it with 260 games they did it with 1200 games and You know what the results were.
Scott: no, I don't game ratings don't matter.
Scott: now I know you and you know me.
Scott: you know that we don't really pay attention or care about game ratings.
Scott: one shit in fact.
Rym: the Last game rating that was that actually mattered was way back in the day when TIE fighter got 97% in PC gamer.
Rym: that was probably the most accurate rating a game has ever been given.
Scott: Yeah, I'm not saying the game ratings are inaccurate or accurate or whatever.
Scott: I'm just saying that you know People like us tend to not give a shit about them.
Scott: We don't use them to make our purchasing decisions.
Rym: honestly the thing is during the early PC gaming era I think a lot of us did look at those ratings because there was no way to try out a lot of PC games before.
Rym: You bought him sort of pirating them, but a lot of your friends didn't have the same games you had.
Rym: So a lot of people would read the reviews of games to figure out what to play and There was really only a few sources of reviews.
Rym: So I think a lot of people were influenced whether they realized it or not But I don't think that that has been the case for at least seven or eight years.
Scott: Yeah, well, I mean there is one situation.
Scott: I can see myself looking at game reviews.
Scott: let's say I was going to buy a game like I don't know a Baseball game a realistic baseball game.
Scott: well There's a whole bunch of those and I don't know anything about those games.
Scott: So I might look at the reviews of every possible new baseball game this year and compare them.
Scott: The thing is I don't really buy those kinds of games, so I don't look at the review.
Rym: more importantly I would never trust a review by any sort of commercial company because oh no absolutely not.
Rym: It seems that there's a lot of evidence that either the companies often send you know Slightly different versions or they'll send the game along with.
Rym: you know some fancy new toys Right now.
Scott: This is the exactly why I wanted to talk about this news.
Scott: Is that game companies think that the ratings are important?
Scott: So they're basically bribing and finagling and public relations in all the gaming media into giving them high review scores When the reviews don't actually matter.
Scott: Why are you wasting your time and effort?
Rym: Probably the same reason.
Rym: a lot of people advertise on sites like slash dot.
Rym: I mean the people who are most likely to run adblock.
Scott: I guess I guess but I guess the the ads on slash.
Scott: that though tend to be Ads that people who run adblock even if they saw the ads wouldn't be interested.
Scott: So those ads are actually going to appeal to the person who visits last night without an ad block.
Rym: well I think another factor and it may sound funny especially people who don't know a lot about.
Rym: you know webcomics or anything.
Rym: But I think penny arcade has single-handedly had a lot to do with this.
Rym: Oh really well for one It's I've found that most serious gamers these days or at least a majority of them seem to get almost all of their gaming Related news or the important stuff from penny arcade.
Rym: at least opinion wise.
Scott: I don't know penny arcade really.
Scott: I think what it is is like.
Scott: I read blogs like joystick Kotaku go Nintendo all that sort of stuff.
Scott: right, but those people they don't give you the information They don't cover every single game, and they don't tell you the release dates of everything and all that stuff.
Scott: They just you know they hit the high points and they put out interesting stuff.
Scott: and penny arcade is sort of the same way.
Scott: When there's something to say you know the top story they cover it.
Scott: But I think that most people not me But most gamers out there seem to always go to IGN or GameSpy or whatever website like that To get you know the complete breadth of information on all the games.
Scott: You know what games are coming out this week.
Rym: Oh, yeah for game information.
Rym: I'm talking about purely trying to find out whether a game.
Rym: You've never played is worth playing.
Scott: Hmm, I think another thing is is that we aren't like super video gamers who buy video games every week and play And trade in games constantly.
Scott: we
Rym: were we were but
Scott: We were never at the point where we were like going to EB twice a week trading in games buying more beating them in a Couple days and rinsing and repeating we were never like that and people like that I think you know tend to do the game reviews and the IGN a lot more than us who just buy all the hits.
Scott: You know I don't care so much about all the other video games because you know time for them.
Scott: The point is just that video game reviews don't matter and stupid people at game companies think they do.
Rym: yeah I was stretching for anything to say because I didn't really care at all about Scott's news Because I haven't looked at a video game review in over a decade.
Rym: I just.
Scott: I only looked at the most recent video game review I looked at was in the EGM which he got for free, and I didn't read it.
Scott: I just kind of went.
Rym: It was a terrible magazine.
Scott: It took me five seconds to read the whole mag.
Rym: Anyone who pays money for that magazine is just an idiot.
Scott: Yeah, I only got it cuz it's free.
Rym: I mean, it's just there's nothing in it at all.
Rym: It was just worthless.
Scott: There was nothing I didn't already know from the Internet's at all.
Scott: there were some pretty pictures and a whole bunch of ads all right.
Rym: So I'll get to my news Which is it actually is something that I was a little bit bothered by.
Rym: now the news and the way it was portrayed was that?
Rym: Vinyl record sales are skyrocketing.
Scott: why no one has a vinyl record player?
Scott: How can that be now?
Rym: the news was that vinyl records are?
Rym: Skyrocketing.
Rym: and then the talk about the news and all the buzz about the news and the articles were implying that this is partly a Revolt against the whole digital music medium where you get a music or a piece of music but you don't own the physical thing to go with it and that the ritual of the Record is the reason that these sales are so high.
Rym: suddenly the kids are rebelling against this new culture.
Scott: Kids are rebelling against the ritual the record.
Scott: we hate the ritual of the record.
Rym: now No, and a lot of the talk went on especially in the slashdot comments about how furthermore records were Superior technology.
Scott: Oh you want to talk about that?
Rym: Well, I want to talk about all aspects of this because one the news was completely misrepresented.
Rym: Yes, record sales were up.
Rym: They were all the way up to 1998 levels this year.
Scott: Yeah, which means almost dick.
Rym: furthermore.
Rym: The only records that are selling at all are singles which Singles aren't really selling.
Rym: It's just that single sells so poorly that if a record sells like 5,000 copies that's a crazy deal because single no one buys singles anymore.
Scott: Wow, that sounds like comic book sales numbers.
Rym: It really.
Rym: We sold 5,000 copies of the white stripe single and that's like such a tiny percentage of record sales and Not many copies of the white stripes album for sold in vinyl at all.
Scott: Yeah, I actually have seen a vinyl white stripes album in a store.
Scott: once it was kind of freaking me out.
Rym: I was like, whoa Well, you know this new stuff this one really reeks of a marketing effort to try to get kids to think add vinyl.
Scott: That's what I was gonna say.
Rym: It's hip and cool so that they'll buy it.
Rym: It's kind of how Sudoku got popular.
Rym: They tell everyone that it's popular assuming that people will then buy it because it's popular.
Scott: Yep I think we've talked about this on the show a lot.
Scott: I like the trend of you know A lot of people don't recognize when a news story is actually trying to change the opinion that it professes already exists.
Scott: And I am making my mission to whenever this comes around make it a news story on GeekNights and point it out to you.
Scott: And this is I'm 75% sure this is a case of them trying to make vinyl big as opposed to vinyl being big and then Them reporting on it.
Rym: Yeah, I mean the news really made it out like vinyl is having its best year.
Rym: It's skyrocketing It's crazy.
Rym: And no it just did slightly less ass than it's done for the past decade.
Scott: Yeah, which means still crap.
Rym: now before I get a little sweeter before I get to the factual You know objective part about the technology about the technology of vinyl I want to give my opinion as to who buys vinyl.
Rym: This is not based on any research.
Rym: This is based on my opinion based on my anecdotal observations and is based on my assumptions and inferences Based on the data I have seen.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: The following types of people are the people who buy vinyl one very old people.
Scott: Well for us that means 50 plus.
Rym: Yes, very very old people.
Scott: There are people like my parents.
Scott: they buy CDs, you know, I tell them not to and they know but they do it anyway.
Scott: But if there was a CD they were going to buy, you know, they still have this nostalgic feel for vinyl.
Scott: They have so many vinyls from their younger days like hundreds and hundreds and hundreds of them.
Scott: And if I was a lot if I was you know alive when they were alive I would also have fun.
Scott: I thought you're gonna say if I was alive today No, if I was alive in their age Then I would also have as many vinyls as they have.
Scott: but if they went to a store today And they had a working turntable Which they probably will soon now that I got my dad a new receiver and they saw a vinyl of the CD They were going to buy for about the same price I imagine they might buy the vinyl and consider buying it just for that Nostalgic feeling it gives them, you know that they've had vinyl most of their lives and that's what they like.
Rym: Yes, now I do also think that that constitutes a somewhat small amount of the vinyl purchases.
Scott: Oh, it does consider very small.
Rym: second type of person are Breakbeat DJ types.
Scott: Mmm.
Scott: I didn't think of them.
Scott: That was smart.
Rym: That is the primary market for vinyl today, and I don't know how often I've talked about that.
Rym: I'm not going to talk about my opinions of that kind of DJing other than the fact that they buy a lot of vinyl and That's probably one of the last legitimate uses of vinyl.
Scott: Yeah, okay I think we'll leave it at that because what's the concept?
Scott: you would not sway too far after it.
Rym: Yes, now the third group of people who are buying vinyl are people who for whatever reason have decided that it is culturally cool to be retro and they think that it's hip to purchase vinyl.
Rym: and I note that most of the vinyl that is not made for DJs is of Underground indie whatever rock emo and nothing else.
Scott: That's fine.
Rym: They can buy they can you know Style it up all they want but it seems that most of the people who buy it They buy what they'll say.
Rym: they have reasons for buying it But it seems obvious that the only reason they buy Vinyls is so that people will see them buying vinyls and they can talk about their vinyl collection.
Scott: Yeah Another thing is vinyls are real big.
Scott: so, you know You know, you can just now leave them in your house and people lose them.
Rym: Most vinyl sales are singles and they're little.
Scott: Anyway And what is the fourth group?
Scott: the fourth group which you're gonna spend most of the time talking about?
Rym: We have a fourth group the audio files, okay, I wasn't gonna see.
Rym: those aren't people.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: All right.
Rym: The fourth group are the audio files who claim that records sound better now.
Rym: They don't just claim that it sounds better in a subjective.
Rym: I like the sound of it way.
Rym: They claim that it is because that that's perfectly okay.
Scott: Some people like the crackling noise, you know, it gives them a thing.
Rym: Oh though to all you audiophile fuckers.
Rym: before I get on to the actual meat of this I want to note that when records started improving in the early days of records audiophiles bitch then saying that those records weren't as good as the earlier records because they had less distortion and it sounded too sterile and cold and mechanical.
Rym: the exact same bullshit arguments You've been making about CDs and debt and everything now.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Don't just don't lie to yourselves.
Rym: You got accustomed to a type of sound.
Rym: you like that type of sound.
Rym: you buy vinyl because the vinyl gives you that type Of sound.
Rym: don't pretend that vinyl has higher fidelity.
Rym: It does not.
Rym: it empirically does nots.
Rym: There are so many things I can describe and explain as to why vinyl has terrible fidelity compared to CDs.
Scott: Yeah, I mean you could theoretically store digital PCM data on a vinyl record and have a needle that physically feels the pits and converts that to zeros and ones and Generates a perfect wave.
Scott: Okay, but that is not how vinyl works.
Scott: So it doesn't matter One.
Rym: they claim that vinyl has a warmer sound that cannot be reproduced any other way.
Rym: My claim account my counter claim is simply that that sound can be very very easily Recreated digitally because all it is is dynamic distortion and a bunch of noise and hisses and pops.
Rym: It's nothing special.
Scott: a very small Algorithm could turn a perfect CD track into a track You could not distinguish from a vinyl track in a double-blind test.
Rym: - they claim that vinyl Because it's an analog medium is not limited in fidelity while CDs and digital media Because of the sampling and the fact that they're digital will sound hard and cold Because they miss out on parts of the audio.
Rym: my counter claim is very simple.
Rym: You can't make a physical medium with a little needle vibrating back and forth that precise.
Rym: you lose most of the high-end to hissing and you can't have sounds below about 30 Hertz because they.
Rym: well that.
Rym: So I'm not gonna get in all the technical details because I was about to talk about like five different frequency ranges.
Scott: Yeah, the reason is that if you have a super audio CD I'll shove it up your ass.
Rym: if you have a whole bunch of bass for example And you try to put that on a record it'll knock the needle out of the track.
Rym: Yeah, and in order to overcome the massive hissing and noise you have to use an equalizer.
Rym: when you're putting the audio on the Vinyl do super duper amplify the high-end, so it'll even sound it all over the noise.
Rym: Now that is the counterclaim to the next argument They make that it's higher fidelity that it actually has better sound quality.
Rym: That is more true to the original sound that you heard in the room.
Rym: That is complete horseshit.
Rym: Vinyl records.
Rym: you might like the way they sound but they do not sound Anymore like what you heard in the room than a good digital recording.
Scott: in fact you know what?
Scott: All my life I would notice this incredibly huge gap between the sound of a live performance and a recorded performance.
Scott: It wasn't until I started getting flack downloads of.
Scott: You know like live recordings and other you know high-quality Superaudio CDs and playing them on my surround sound thing that the drums sound like drums because I have a giant subwoofer but nothing else sounds live.
Scott: and that's with you know a 5.1 surround sound system and a fancy computer and a fancy sound card.
Scott: So there's no way your vinyl which I listen to plenty of vinyl in my life sounds even close To what it sounds like when you're in the recording studio.
Rym: You also in addition to having to you know super equalize the sound by cutting off the bass and pumping up the high-end.
Rym: You have to usually do a whole bunch of tricks to make it sound like anything Rational coming out of that record because the medium is just so horrible.
Rym: Finally last and certainly not least records degrade Rapidly.
Rym: the claim that records last longer on the shelf than CDs is complete.
Rym: BS.
Rym: records are so prone to heat damage Moisture damage dust damage.
Rym: you wouldn't think about that.
Rym: But they collect a lot of static electricity and as a result dust Very small dust will get in the grooves and stick to the record in a way that is almost impossible to remove.
Scott: Yeah, that's another thing and you have something that's an analog storage format.
Scott: It degrades as in it plays, you know Well, then it plays kind of okay that in fact there were standards for how rapidly records would decay.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: There's noticeable decay on the first playing of a record.
Rym: Yep, a noticeable and significant decay.
Scott: However CDs are digital.
Scott: they either work or they don't.
Scott: you either hear the sound that's on the CD perfectly or it Skips and a lot of the sound is missing which means it's broken and scratch.
Scott: Those are the only two possibilities of the CD.
Rym: now There is one other reason that a lot of people like vinyl and are moving toward vinyl and in fact Well, not a lot of people but these people and this is something that a lot of DJs are doing these days Where they'll make a mix track or something and they'll make a Small dub vinyl usually in a custom shop or in their own home equipment to give to other DJs to use in their mixes.
Rym: They do this in order to make it more difficult for people to take their beats and play them too much Because they're afraid that if their beats are played too much They'll become overplayed and therefore unpopular and stupid.
Scott: if you're an awesome DJ.
Scott: You should be making new beats more often.
Scott: That's all.
Rym: no, no, not even that not even that.
Rym: that argument is stupid because they claim.
Rym: Oh, all right So you made this record of your thing and they always say yeah If you try to convert that record to digital you lose something.
Rym: No you don't.
Rym: you can perfectly recreate that first playing if you record it to a good set of digital equipment and then You now have a digital copy that will never degrade again forever.
Rym: It in no way protects your media from anyone copying it.
Rym: Yeah Yeah.
Rym: to move on I just want to say that this whole news about vinyl becoming more popular is pretty much complete Horseshit, it is not becoming more popular.
Rym: It just had a slight upswing in sales.
Rym: that is being used by the PR marketing machine to try to get you the youth of America to purchase more vinyl albums when in fact The only people actually purchasing them in any significant quantity are DJ and those the only people who shit.
Rym: hockey fights of the day.
Scott: Oh, it's still hockey fight week And I think the hockey has begun as of right now.
Scott: all the preseason hockey has begun now.
Rym: We'll go kind of briefly but the two hockey fights I chose now I chose two today for a very important reason illustrate probably all of the important aspects of hockey fighting now.
Rym: the Detroit Red Wings and the Colorado Avalanche had a Bitter bitter rivalry going on between them, you know, that's one of the big things about hockey is the rivalries between all the teams.
Scott: As in any sport rivalries are key.
Rym: Yes, of course in most sports.
Rym: They don't come into straight-up fistfights.
Rym: now.
Rym: the Red Wings and the and the ABS were fighting.
Rym: if they were fighting lose.
Rym: there's a fight going on and For various reasons Mike Vernon the Red Wings goalie and Patrick Waugh the other goalie charged each other and had a knockdown.
Rym: drag him out.
Rym: goalie fight in the middle of this other massive fight where the benches were cleared and The whole time the commentators like what's going on the red the goalies are fighting.
Rym: Yeah, it's crazy.
Rym: Happily Vernon kicks the guy's ass.
Scott: Well, it's super rare for a goalie fight, you know, cuz a goalie is covered in like armor Serious armor, so no one's gonna fight with that guy.
Scott: cuz you're putting even if he's you know Kind of weak relative.
Rym: not only that but think of this.
Rym: the goalie's job is to stand there and get shot by pucks Constantly.
Rym: you think you can punch faster than a puck?
Scott: Yeah, you're not gonna scare him with your fist if you know.
Scott: if he's he's not afraid of pucks.
Rym: so they have this big fight and not one.
Rym: the video really illustrates a big big important part about hockey and hockey fights is that If you keep watching the video after the fight cools down a bit You see two guys who had been beating the hell out of each other.
Rym: They're both bleeding and broken and they're standing there kind of sitting around hold down to each other and they're not fighting anymore They're talking.
Rym: They're just talking like two dudes.
Rym: They're probably saying man, that was a great fight.
Scott: That's that's how hockey works And that's why fighting is okay in hockey and they don't just arrest everyone for assault and throw them in jail.
Scott: Yeah, like they would if say two basketball or two baseball players got into a fight.
Rym: Of course they do.
Rym: I mean there there have been incidents where someone started a hockey fight that was actually completely uncalled for.
Scott: Yeah, but you know when that happens everyone recognizes.
Scott: Oh that guy's really fighting and not hockey fighting.
Scott: We better get something about it.
Rym: Usually what they do is if that guy has ever led to play hockey again He gets attacked and pretty much every game he plays until he quits the sport.
Scott: Yeah, you don't want to have you know, it's a self-regulating industry.
Rym: now I'll skip all that because the father important part of everything in the day is that almost exactly one year later Now Chris Osgood who in the previous year was Mike Vernon's jr Is now the Red Wings goalie and Patrick Waugh is still their goalie.
Rym: and sure enough during this big fight Waugh comes out of the on the ice and this ref is trying to hold him back like no You don't want to do this Go back to your side of the rink and sit there and then he kind of misdirects the ref when he's distracted and he charges Chris Osgood and he skates
Scott: around.
Scott: This guy just like wants to have goalie fights probably because he thinks it's like a novelty.
Scott: So he's like I'm gonna be the goalie who fights.
Rym: Well, he was also pissed at Osgood for a number of reasons I won't get into.
Rym: he was also mad at the Red Wings.
Rym: So he's circling around over there and Osgood is still wearing all of his gear.
Rym: He's standing there like I don't want to fight you what the hell.
Rym: so finally Osgood's like, all right And he rips his mask off takes his gloves off and skates out.
Rym: now Chris Osgood is about two feet shorter than this guy.
Rym: He's a tiny little dude.
Rym: I met him.
Rym: He's shorter than me.
Rym: He's this tiny tiny little dude.
Rym: He's also I'm pretty sure had never been in a fight in hockey at least not in the NHL up until this point.
Scott: Yeah, I mean imagine that not.
Scott: you've been playing hockey for a long time But you were never in a fight.
Scott: and then all of a sudden, you know You've been playing for years then all of a sudden a fight and this really big guy comes over to kick your ass.
Scott: That's a scary thing.
Rym: Let me tell you Osgood does a classic boxer strategy when someone is longer reach than you he moves in and as close as he Can and absorbs a bunch of blows on purpose trying to get close?
Rym: Because the closer you get the less hard the guys hitting you and then he proceeds to thoroughly kick.
Rym: Patrick was ass.
Scott: That's pretty unexpected.
Scott: I mean, you know, you've never been in a fight.
Scott: You don't want to be in a fight.
Scott: some guy comes over and challenges you, you know You reluctantly go into a fight and then you win.
Rym: I was watching that game on TV when it happened as a child and you can even hear in this video the entire arena chanting Ozzy Ozzy Yeah, that people will get up if there's a goalie fight.
Rym: people were freaking get excited like no They didn't call the audience that the crowd down for at least 20 minutes.
Rym: It was just chaos.
Scott: If I was a goalie in hockey I would if anyone like came and messed with me.
Scott: I would start a fight with him because you know if it was if he was worth it.
Scott: You know just because everyone would get all excited that my team would win.
Scott: at least it was at home away.
Scott: I would never do that.
Rym: now before I let Scott go there's one other nice trivia bit about Chris Osgood.
Rym: This is very interesting.
Rym: He was the either second or third goalie ever to be credited with a goal scored in the NHL.
Scott: Yeah, I remember Martin Brodeur was like the champion of scoring goals.
Scott: as a goalie he would like go for it.
Scott: No, you like other goalies would like it might happen by accident.
Scott: Brodeur used to go for it Like if there was an empty net he would try to get the puck and shoot it all the way down the ice.
Scott: Yep, he did it like two or three times - I think he was.
Rym: I think I'm pretty sure Osgood was if he wasn't the Second person to do it.
Rym: He was the second person to do it on purpose and be the single sole person who scored the goal on purpose.
Rym: He saw an opening he shot.
Rym: He got a goal.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Yeah goalies have gotten plenty of assists in the day.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Scott: So this hockey fight which I present to you today is a classic not so much because of the fight itself Even though the hockey fight itself is quite a marvel to behold.
Rym: Yes, if you've ever seen Family Guy Hoedown hootenanny, hoedown hootenanny.
Rym: It is that kind of fight.
Scott: That is exactly what this fight is.
Scott: and What makes it more entertaining is the announcer.
Scott: now the guy isn't that great of an announcer But when this fight starts he goes, you know, the two guys fighting are Tasker and Sen.
Scott: I don't know what teams they're on.
Scott: I don't really care.
Rym: You know I've only seen this fight on the internet a million times because it's widely regarded on the internet is the best hockey fight ever.
Scott: yeah, and Basically the guy starts, you know when he's announcing he's like tasker with a right Sen with a right Tasker with another right a right and a right and a right and right and right and right and it's just hilarious.
Scott: But because they are is they're basically both.
Scott: each guy is holding the other guy's jersey with his left hand and then throwing haymakers Repeatedly and rapidly directly into the face of the other guy.
Rym: They're all connecting.
Rym: It's just BAM BAM BAM BAM BAM And they're both hitting.
Scott: they're swinging it exactly the same speed and power just over and over again.
Scott: Just punch to the face punch to the face punch to the face punch to the edges.
Rym: It's so great and you can see their faces becoming more and more bloodied and purple as this.
Scott: it's like these guys But you know, they kind of size each other up.
Scott: They take the gloves off You know, they're putting up the Dukes and their faces are nice and well as nice as hockey.
Scott: hockey players faces can be fighters.
Scott: Yeah hockey players faces are yeah without teeth or anything.
Scott: and then you know They just go wham wham wham and the faces just turn red and then purple and then god knows I wouldn't know what have been either one of these guys, but I love watching them.
Scott: It's just like the best hockey fight.
Scott: You got to see it All right, anyway on to the main bit.
Rym: today we're going to go back to our traditional actually reviewing anime.
Scott: Oh my god, you're reviewing an anime.
Scott: I wonder who's gonna be happy.
Scott: our listeners.
Scott: Hooray Okay, the anime we chose to review today is called Kemo nozume and I think Rym wants to avoid saying the name out of fear of saying it improperly.
Rym: Actually, just cuz I didn't write it down in front of me and I can't easily use my computer while I do the show.
Scott: Yes, Kemo nozume is a brand new show this season and we watched two episodes.
Scott: This is like a two episode review here.
Rym: Yeah, and there are two episodes out.
Rym: So it's more of a preview than a review, but I have high hopes for the show and I'm going to watch it all.
Scott: Yeah, I'm almost definitely going to keep watching the show.
Scott: There's a 90% chance I'll watch it all but it is possible that somehow the show could take a wrong turn and end up God knows where.
Rym: now It's directed by a Masaki Yuasa who as far as I can tell Hasn't done anything of note other than be a key animator all over the place.
Scott: Yeah I mean, it looks like he's done, you know a few shows and he's been like an episode director or you know a Storyboard guy or a layout guy.
Rym: I think he designed a character here and there but this is the first show where he really it's all.
Rym: This is his show.
Scott: He's directed like two movies, but this is his TV show.
Scott: He's the director.
Scott: He wrote some scripts He directed some episodes.
Scott: He did storyboards.
Scott: He's all over this show.
Scott: This is basically belongs to him.
Scott: and As part of what studio?
Scott: madhouse, I think right?
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It's a it's a madhouse production.
Scott: Those are the same people who brought you all sorts of other awesome shows.
Rym: Now the the main notable things because if the show had been presented any other way it probably wouldn't have been so good.
Rym: but it's a combination really of the style of animation the presentation of the plot and The the elements that are in the show as a result of this plot a monkey.
Rym: Yeah, I was gonna get to the monkey.
Rym: Okay, doo doo doo doo doo.
Rym: And I had a third thing but Scott won't shut up about the monkey.
Scott: we the monkey.
Rym: Let me just say that the show has a monkey in it.
Rym: We'll get to that in a moment.
Scott: Yes, we will.
Rym: now the plot is actually very simple though.
Rym: First of all, the opener is very stylized.
Rym: the moment you start watching this show you realize that this is not like other anime.
Scott: yeah, the opener kind of reminds me of the cowboy bebop opener a little bit in like the way the colors are used and the Way, you know that it like breaks it up into panels and the style of music a little bit.
Rym: I really like the opening song.
Scott: Yeah, it's it's a good song.
Scott: It's all jazzy and hip and cool and everything unlike a lot of other, you know Typical j-rock j-pop, you know idol openers or the.
Scott: you know, boring atmospheric opener.
Scott: This is actually, you know something I'd want to listen to and it's I won't skip over the opener every time I watch the show.
Rym: Yep now it starts up with this pretty boy and this ugly guy sitting in some fancy fancy club and they're sitting there talking and the Pretty boy is talking about his taste in women and he likes the younger girls and he gets them all the time and he keeps talking and the more he talks it starts getting more and more disturbing.
Rym: and Finally in the end you realize that he's not talking about sexual con.
Scott: Oh, yeah, we're gonna spoil like the first episode.
Rym: Yeah, he is talking about killing and eating them because he is in fact a Shoku jinky a monster yep, a flesh eater.
Scott: the story of this world is that there are people and They're also flesh eaters these horrid monsters from ancient times that eat people.
Scott: Yep, and there is a group of swordsmen the key fukan the key fukan.
Scott: They have the key fukan technique or the key.
Scott: I don't know whatever you want to call it style.
Scott: Yeah key fukan style whatever.
Scott: and these are swordsmen martial artists who basically their job is to fight flesh eaters.
Scott: and You know occasionally I like how.
Scott: it's never actually about the fight, you know Like other fighting shows it'd be like oh, here's a fight.
Scott: in this show fights are just kind of like yeah They kill the flesh eater.
Scott: Oh look here.
Scott: They are fighting a flesh eater.
Scott: It doesn't happen too often.
Scott: It's mostly about the lives of people whose job it is to fight flesh eaters because they treat it like a straight-up job.
Rym: I mean, it's literally this nine-to-five thing for these guys.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know, they'll just be out in the field casually.
Scott: You know, there's a monster they chase it down.
Scott: They use their weapons on it.
Scott: They kill it and there you go.
Rym: Now it turns out that the ancient flesh eaters were somewhat different from the ones today.
Rym: And now there's this new kind of flesh eater that's appeared that looks just like a human.
Rym: And in fact when you kill them they turn back into humans and there's no way to know they were once a flesh eater.
Scott: Yeah, and it gets kind of tricky because you know, they'll be walking down the street They'll be a person and they might not know the person's a flesh eater.
Scott: and then oh someone got eaten.
Scott: What are you gonna do?
Rym: Now if that were just it the show would have been okay because it's got this interesting style and this interesting plot.
Rym: But before we talk about the plot further First there is this scene with a monkey.
Scott: Well, it's basically the second half of the first episode.
Scott: the second half of both episodes was the monkey.
Rym: Yeah, so far the monkey is really kind of there in a big way in every episode.
Scott: It's like we're watching the first episode halfway through.
Scott: this monkey shows up and he's there until the end of the episode.
Scott: the second episode The monkey shows up halfway through the episode and he keeps poking his head in until the end of the episode.
Scott: I think the monkey is like he takes over in the second half of every episode.
Rym: I cannot spoil for you what the monkey does.
Rym: watch the first episode of this show And once you see the monkey know that something awesome is about to happen.
Scott: The monkey is high Larry's as any so cute to the way they draw him and if you go to the official Japanese website This is really cute Like 3d animation of the monkey where when like you hover over the menu items the monkey like changes his pose.
Scott: It's so great.
Rym: Now in addition to that the monkey I mean the monkey pushed the show from pretty good - I have to watch all this by itself Mmm, but also so they fight this flesh eater and they kill it the you know, the pretty boy who was killing the girls.
Scott: Oh that reminds me the.
Scott: the name of the show is kenno music a kimonos kimono zoom.
Scott: a good job Yeah, and that apparently means like monster claw or something like that.
Rym: I believe it was Emily who told us that.
Scott: yes, and The way they kill these monsters is by cutting the hands off.
Rym: Yes Their claws are very powerful like.
Rym: that's the source of their power and that plays a lot into how they animate the flesh eaters later - yeah, it's like the claws is like where the mo it's like the weak point.
Scott: if you were fighting them in a video game you would shoot all your bullets at the claws and When people who are actually flesh eaters in disguise Transforming the flesh eaters like the hands are the first part to turn into claws, you know.
Rym: Now if you look at the cover art for the show You can see that drawn out very explicitly when it shows a girl who is beginning the transformation Mm-hmm.
Rym: Now the other point in which the show became awesome is so far.
Rym: It's animated in this really I don't want to say low-budget, but just really interesting style where the characters are all kind of ugly.
Scott: Yeah, well, it kind of reminds me a little of doctor cats and that you have these.
Scott: non They're not like these clear super pristine lines that you get in most other anime these days.
Scott: they're kind of wiggly and moving and no care, you know, every character is identifiable by their hairstyle and their Complexion and the size and shape of their body, but they're not static.
Scott: They're kind of you know moving around and you know They're not always drawn with the exact same lines in the exact same place.
Scott: and it kind of also reminds you that windy tales Anime, yeah, I think that's the only other animation I've ever seen that's like this.
Rym: Now there's so so far the show goes on.
Rym: they they have this fight with the flesh eater.
Rym: Now the main character toshihiko who is the like master of the style other than the father who actually runs the school?
Rym: He has a problem.
Rym: whenever he is about to put the killing blow down on a flesh eater He gets crippling stomach cramps and diarrhea.
Scott: Yeah, the way they animate it is pretty hilarious, but it they never really explained why it happened.
Rym: But the thing is it happens and everyone we've shown the show to goes.
Rym: what?
Rym: Why did they just show what's going on?
Rym: Right away in the next scene the the one of these guys walks over.
Rym: he's like man you always have diarrhea.
Rym: We're just when you can.
Scott: I know it's like he can't control his bowels when he's about to kill a flesh eater.
Scott: I don't know what's wrong.
Scott: I think it's going to be a major plot point later on but in the meantime, it's strange yet hilarious Yep.
Rym: So anyway after the fight now, they beat this flesh eater and they go back to the school and they're talking about yes Flesh eaters are back.
Rym: Now.
Rym: We have a purpose.
Rym: We're going to go do our thing and save people.
Rym: and then the other main male I guess the.
Rym: I forget his name, but the silver haired guy who was kind of a silver haired guy I think is his brother.
Scott: Yes stepbrother.
Scott: Who knows?
Rym: Well, no, he's the.
Rym: I think he's a legitimate brother or the legitimate heir At least and toshihiko seems to be adopted Uh-huh.
Rym: I wouldn't be surprised if toshihiko were a flesh eater and didn't know it or something weird like that.
Scott: I don't know either what's good.
Rym: I got a lot of.
Rym: I got a lot of speculation about it.
Scott: It seems to be though that most of the family is able to like detect a flesh eater even if they're in disguise.
Scott: You know, it's like they just kind of know and they can figure it out real quick because that's what they've been doing for centuries
Rym: Yep, but they're having this talk about you know fighting the flesh eaters and suddenly this guy and like one of his subordinates they start an argument and they stand up and they actually Have ready and waiting a 3d PowerPoint style presentation showing how this giant robot Powered armor that this guy is designed is the way to really fight these things and this pussy sword technique is Useless and they should get rid of it and use this robot.
Scott: Yeah Well see part of that.
Scott: if there's two Sides to that there's actually three sides.
Scott: kind of.
Rym: I really felt like Daryl Surratt when I was saying that part cuz.
Rym: that's the kind Of thing he would say.
Scott: Yeah, is that the toshihiko guy who's gonna like inherit the family?
Scott: Whatever he actually is better at sorting than anyone else.
Rym: despite his diarrhea He's pretty much better at sorting than everyone else in the family combined except for the father.
Scott: So this guy who's second best at sorting is, you know, he wants to get with the roboting.
Scott: instead.
Scott: He's like you're better at sorting.
Scott: That doesn't mean anything.
Scott: I'll do roboting and my roboting will beat your sorting.
Scott: this is what I can do.
Scott: and There's another aspect is he's kind of an ass.
Scott: when he does this the character reminds me very much of sayonji from utana Kinda, yeah a little bit.
Scott: Well the way that guy from gassaraki like that?
Scott: Yeah, like the younger brother who's kind of like girl.
Scott: Why is the older brother so much better?
Rym: just sayonji in terms of the way he talks and the ways inflection and the way he?
Rym: Holds himself.
Scott: Yeah, he's being kind of an ass.
Rym: but on the third He's arrogant because he's actually kind of self-conscious.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But the third point is that he's kind of right.
Scott: the robot does kick ass and it'll probably kill a lot more flesh-eaters than swords.
Scott: Well, you know go with the robot.
Rym: Whoo-hoo Yeah, but then that you know the father.
Rym: they always say things like ah But you don't understand.
Rym: and they actually make a point of talking about how the name of their style Has many meanings and one of the meanings is keeping your inner demons contained.
Scott: Yeah, so perhaps using the robot would be putting the demons in the robot and not containing them.
Rym: or maybe because I always have I'm The one always puts forth the crazy guests at the beginning of like every show before I know anything.
Rym: Maybe everyone has the potential to be a flesh eater and everyone has that darkness in their heart.
Rym: and that's the point of the whole.
Rym: Oh god, that's my that's.
Scott: we would have seen that coming.
Scott: Yeah You know who would have Rym on GeekNights?
Scott: Yeah, that's right.
Rym: I got it right here.
Scott: So anyway, the main plot of the show now, this is a spoiler for the first episode But it is not a spoiler for the show.
Scott: It is basically.
Scott: if this show came out This is what would be on the back of the DVD.
Rym: Yes We're not going to ruin what happens in the second episode when that plot gets resolved in terms of you wonder Which way the show is gonna go once we explain what like
Scott: episode 1 tells you what the show is about and episode 2 shows you how The show is gonna be about that.
Rym: cuz they could have gone in all sorts of directions It could have.
Rym: now toshihiko is really frustrated because of his bowel problems his brother problems and there's a girl a really cool girl Although there's the monkey.
Rym: Yeah, there's the monkey.
Rym: I'm not gonna talk about how we you know, I'm not gonna ruin the monkey plot point.
Rym: All right, I was talking about him and the reason he's kind of distraught.
Rym: There's a girl that he was betrothed to when he was young and it looks like it was an arranged marriage that was canceled and She likes it and he doesn't like it.
Rym: Yeah Well, he is just devoted to the sword and she likes him and she's also devoted to the school and the sword to a degree But not as much.
Scott: she likes him and he doesn't like her and it was an arranged marriage and everyone else seems to want them To get married except for him.
Scott: toshihiko doesn't want to get married.
Scott: So even though his wife is you know supposed supposed to be wife does so.
Rym: one thing leads to another and he is almost landed on By this parachuting woman named Yuka who is in terms of this animation.
Rym: She is obviously in a very beautiful woman.
Scott: He's obviously some hot blonde chick.
Rym: She is she's presented and drawn as incredibly beautiful and he falls in love with her immediately and she obviously At first sight has feelings for him.
Scott: Yep, and then you know things go.
Rym: now at this point The first thing I thought when I saw this woman's face was there is no way on this green earth that she is not a flesh.
Scott: Yeah, well it says that in.
Scott: yeah, that's what the show is about.
Scott: is a guy who fights flesh eaters Randomly by chance falls in love with a flesh eater without knowing it, but then he knows later and you know stuff happens.
Rym: Well, the thing is the.
Rym: the first episode ends on they.
Rym: he's met this woman.
Rym: They end up being together.
Rym: They're in his bedroom They're making love and then there's a flash because there's a storm going outside and as soon as the lightning flashes her mouth She starts to transform a little bit and then she goes back to normal.
Scott: Yeah, she kind of contains it so that he doesn't know he's a little preoccupied.
Rym: Yes, so he doesn't notice He's quite preoccupied, but she is obviously trying to resist the fact that she is about to transform into a partial flesh eater Yep, or a complete flesh eater and then eat him Yeah, and then the episode ends.
Rym: and I don't want to ruin anything about what happens after but I think it's obvious that the show Could have gone in any number of directions from that point.
Scott: Yes The direction that it will go in is determined in the second episode and beyond.
Scott: that we don't know.
Scott: cuz.
Scott: no no episodes are out yet, so what can we tell you?
Rym: I Really like this show.
Rym: I mean pretty much the shows right now that I really like are Nana or on high school host club and Possibly the new mushishi probably the new mushishi and this show right here.
Scott: Yeah this show right here is definitely what I'm looking forward to and the new death note is coming in October 3rd is when episode 1 is To have an opinion on that because I'm worried that it won't be good.
Scott: I am hopeful that it will be good.
Scott: at the very least It'll be some cool animation of Ryuk which will make me happy.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, I guess my problem is the death note is almost entirely people thinking about things a lot.
Scott: Yeah, I'm wondering what they're gonna do.
Scott: I'm thinking of watching it with the manga in front of me to compare.
Scott: You know like I won't do that the first time I watch it But like I'll watch episode 1 again While holding the manga to see if they do things in the same order or if they leave things out and all that sort of stuff, but anyway, yeah Kemo Nozomi very cool show.
Scott: you should definitely watch it.
Scott: It's about a guy who fights flesh eaters who ends up going out with a flesh eater.
Rym: The show is really neat.
Rym: I don't care what kind of anime you like.
Rym: I think there's a chance you'll like this because it doesn't really fit into a lot of the other stereotypes of anime.
Scott: Yeah, this seems to me more like the thing that would have ended up as a very cool Manga that I would buy every volume of sort of like monster a little bit You know, but it ended up as an anime.
Scott: so way to go awesome and there isn't a manga for it.
Rym: Plus there are only two episodes out and it's very easy to get on anime ski.
Scott: Yep, so go get these episodes and watch them for awesome.
Scott: I mean, even if you don't care about fighting monsters or drama of dating a monster.
Scott: There's a cute monkey.
Scott: You gotta watch for the monkey.
Rym: Yes, if nothing else the monkey is.
Rym: the monkey is worth the rest of the show.
Rym: so far Yeah.
Scott: So even if you hate the rest of the show the style makes you nauseous and all that.
Scott: at least watch the first episode For the monkey.
Scott: All right Got anything.
Scott: I think we got some meta bits.
Rym: actually we have meta bits a few like what?
Scott: Well, I upgraded the forum today.
Rym: Yeah, the forum should be a little bit faster.
Scott: to all you people who were complaining to me last night about how slow it was Yeah, well I upgraded the forum and I upgraded all the extensions on the forum that had upgrades available.
Scott: So if there are any problems with the forum, let me know.
Scott: if you're not a member of the forum join it.
Scott: What's wrong with you?
Rym: Yes, there's a lot of stuff in the forums.
Scott: I added a new feature to the forum.
Scott: If you go and edit your profile, you can type in your Xbox Live username to get your gamertag in your profile.
Scott: I can't test this because I don't have a gamer.
Scott: You know Xbox Live account But someone who does can go test it out and tell me if it works.
Scott: I think yeah.
Rym: So the forum should be awesome now, and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott special Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.