Rym: It's Tuesday December 19th.
Rym: I'm Rym and I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We talk a bit about what makes good board games good and fun board games fun.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: So despite the fact that the computer is sitting next to my computer the one I do the podcast on the computer That is you know one gigahertz that is old as hell Barely functions has no case fans.
Rym: In fact, the only fan in the entire case that's spinning is the CPU pan fan, which periodically stops spinning a computer is no good.
Rym: yet that computer is Noticeably and significantly faster and better performing than the fastest computer in our house.
Scott: I think there's just something wrong, you know I mean while the CPU in that computer is the fastest CPU in our house that is currently active Actually, it's the fastest CPU in the house period.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Maybe the Wii is faster.
Rym: No, who is not faster than this?
Scott: Who knows a sempron 2500 plus?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, the sempron 2500 plus is in a $20 motherboard.
Rym: now, I don't see any reasonable situation or circumstance that would cause a CPU that happens to be in a cheap motherboard as opposed to a good motherboard to max out at a hundred percent When I do such complex tasks as clicking on a link in Firefox Moving a mouse in Firefox looking at Firefox or loading a web page in fire.
Scott: It is also a CPU that was damaged by heat at least now again heat damage to CPU.
Rym: We're generally not cause that type of problem.
Scott: I'm just saying is that there are many many hidden factors far beyond our vision that could be causing this problem.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I got a plan.
Rym: if I ever have time I want to build a Gentoo on it and see if there's a software issue or a hardware issue.
Scott: My guess is that is a combination software hardware issue where because it is a $20 motherboard The software does things in such a way and they $20 actually perhaps out of the way.
Rym: what I would blame?
Rym: I hate to say this but I might blame Ubuntu.
Rym: Now here's one dude.
Rym: Remember we tried to install edgy on this computer and it totally bit the bullet and fucked up.
Rym: So we had the motherboards $20, uh, yeah, so we installed the older Ubuntu Dapper Drake.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and then we upgraded to edgy.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I'm Would wager that?
Rym: Upgrading to edgy brought with it a bunch of performance problems the same likes of which we saw when we tried to originally install edgy.
Rym: but if you think those The problems we had when we tried to originally install edgy were that it was slow as hell Installing and then would crap out which is the same thing that this PC is doing now randomly and periodically.
Scott: But that's totally unrelated.
Scott: The pro there's nothing to do with it because the live CD of edgy was not slow.
Rym: Yeah, it was.
Scott: no was.
Rym: yeah I was the edgy live CD barely booted and maxed out the CPU and anyway Any dapper CD is what I used to do anything on the box.
Scott: if that is the case that you know?
Scott: For some reason edgy is slow.
Scott: edgy is not slow on my computer.
Scott: Therefore.
Scott: It's not a problem with edgy.
Scott: It is as I said a combination of edgy and the 20 other board is a problem with edgy not supporting a otherwise generally standard motherboards.
Scott: $20 shitty ass Motherboard.
Rym: $20 motherboard should work.
Scott: what you fucking pay for mean what you paid for.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Good job.
Scott: Hey, we wanted it to be as cheap as possible.
Scott: That's what we got.
Scott: It works.
Scott: You know, it doesn't.
Rym: it's useless.
Scott: It works.
Scott: You should be happy that a $20 motherboard even work.
Rym: Oh, no, the motherboard works, but the PC is useless.
Rym: It.
Scott: it was 20 bucks.
Scott: you can't complain.
Rym: I'd rather have the 20 bucks then the computer sitting here now.
Scott: What the fuck for 20 bucks?
Scott: What other but better a computer you're gonna get.
Scott: that's the best computer You can get in the whole world for $20.
Rym: It wouldn't be worth it.
Rym: It doesn't work.
Scott: It works just fine.
Scott: You're browsing the web.
Rym: Oh, no, I'm not.
Rym: Firefox is crash.
Rym: It's just sitting there because the page that I want to do my news from is still open.
Scott: It's not crash it.
Rym: if I try to move between tabs it'll sit there for like five minutes.
Scott: It won't sit there for five.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, no, it won't anyway, that's so hyperbole.
Rym: now All right, any of our listeners live near us.
Rym: come over and I'll show you this shit piece of a computer.
Scott: It's just the slightest bit of slowness Upset slightest bit of slowness.
Rym: It's less than a quarter as fast at encoding mp3s or Processing wav files as my crap as seven year old barely functioning computer.
Scott: $20 motherboard.
Rym: Yeah Anyway, what you got in the news?
Rym: This isn't tech day.
Scott: I imagine a lot of our listeners have no idea what we're talking about right, so today after a long period of waiting the we weather channel is Available and working for free and you know what?
Scott: It's not so exciting.
Rym: Well, it's exactly what I expected.
Rym: It's not supposed to be exciting.
Scott: No, well, I mean it's like you sit there and you have this we and it says weather channel coming soon and you're like Ooh, I can't wait for the weather channel to be available.
Scott: Finally, here it is the weather channel and you go and you look at it and it's just the fucking weather.
Scott: It takes you about like five minutes and you go.
Scott: Ooh, look I can spin the globe around I can see the weather in Antarctica and that's fun once.
Scott: Now you have the weather.
Rym: the purpose of it is to be able to easily look at the weather on your john your TV and That it does.
Scott: Well, I mean if you want to find out what the current weather is not so useful because like I looked at it Just now at 6 p.m.
Scott: And it gave me the wet the current weather in Poughkeepsie from 6 a.m.
Scott: So that wasn't too helpful, but the five-day forecast was kind of useful.
Scott: I was like, hey, it's gonna it's gonna be rainy and snowy on Saturday.
Rym: Uh, really because the NOAA doesn't say that at all Let me go see because I looked at the NOAA this morning for Yonkers Which is close to here and it said it was gonna be warm all weekend.
Scott: I know the NOAA agrees Saturday 60% rain likely, huh?
Scott: Because this morning I looked at Yonkers said sunny all weekend weather and Yonkers is not the weather in beacon in Poughkeepsie.
Scott: It's a different place except it's real close.
Scott: It's pretty close.
Rym: We'll see if it actually rains though.
Scott: We'll see.
Scott: It's 60% chance.
Scott: So I'll bet you.
Rym: I thought you didn't bet unless it was a sure deal.
Scott: It's a sure deal if I bet on six to four odds.
Rym: No, it's not six to four.
Rym: That means that there's a chance that the four odds will win.
Rym: There's a 40% chance that you'll lose.
Rym: It's not a sure thing.
Rym: I don't know what definition a sure thing you're trying to.
Scott: sure enough because the bed is exactly the same as the odds.
Rym: That logic does not follow the.
Rym: the gains of a bed and the chance of winning the bed are mute are not.
Rym: They're completely separate things whatever.
Rym: By that lock, I'm not gonna get into what that logic entails.
Scott: Yeah, but no the Weather Channel.
Scott: I mean You're gonna look at it right away because it's something new and interesting to do on the Wii.
Scott: on the Wii and the channels Are the most fun part of the Wii but the Weather Channel is not gonna be.
Scott: it's not the entertainment channel It's it's.
Scott: you're gonna go there maybe once in a while to see what the weather is.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know what.
Rym: that's exactly what I expected it to be.
Rym: I figured if we had people over and you know, hey Rym, let's climb the mountain tomorrow.
Rym: What's the weather gonna be like?
Rym: I'd go?
Rym: Hey we what's the weather gonna be?
Rym: and the Wii would turn me and say it's gonna Be sunny Rym.
Rym: We're gonna climb that mountain and I would say see and that is pretty much the maximum enjoyment I expected to get out of that.
Scott: that's about all you're gonna get because the only other thing you can do is As a globe that you can spin around and check the weather in different parts of the world.
Rym: You sound so disappointed like you expected more.
Rym: Yeah, what did you expect?
Rym: What were you?
Rym: What did you think was gonna come?
Rym: I?
Scott: Wanted to have that globe part be a little more interesting.
Rym: How so?
Scott: Have like little pictures of ice climbers in the Himalayas that I could find like a secret.
Rym: How do you know?
Rym: they're not there?
Rym: used didn't look hard enough.
Scott: I did.
Scott: I looked I zoomed in all the way.
Rym: You you're telling me that you actually sat there and looked at all the pixels in the Himalayas.
Scott: You really can't zoom in that far.
Scott: So it didn't take very long.
Rym: Yeah, they might be tiny.
Scott: You want to look.
Rym: you might have to click on something special.
Scott: Why don't you go?
Scott: Look, why don't you zoom in on Canada and see if there's an ice hockey player?
Rym: Do you know where the Himalayas are?
Scott: Yeah, they're in Tibet.
Scott: Okay, okay I know I know where the shit is.
Scott: Oh, you know what?
Scott: I did learn one thing from Google not Google.
Scott: we weather.
Scott: Okay, what I learned that Easter Island is I didn't actually know where it was like.
Scott: I thought I knew but I was wrong.
Scott: Now I know where Easter Island is so we can go there.
Scott: Do you want to go there?
Scott: Not really?
Scott: No, no now that I know where it is.
Scott: I kind of don't want to go Like where I thought before it was closer to Europe, but now that I realize it's to the west of South America So screw that.
Scott: The other news that's more interesting is we finally have Confirmation on the deal with the Opera browser for the Wii.
Rym: it's coming.
Scott: It's coming on Friday.
Scott: Well, first of all opera put out this cute little comic with a little red ninja to tell us all about it and a spider.
Scott: It's pretty cool.
Scott: But on Friday as in this Friday the 22nd There's going to be a free trial version of opera browser for Wii available.
Scott: It's not going to be the full version It's gonna be like the beta version but it's gonna be free to anyone with a Wii.
Rym: So so is that implying that the final version is going to be non free?
Scott: They didn't say like the final version is going to cost money because they didn't say the final version is free.
Scott: They said this version is a free beta available Friday.
Scott: I suppose that it'll be lacking features that you're gonna want probably Yeah, like and I suppose like the ability to follow links or view images.
Scott: I suppose that it will have some bugs if you know that might get updated over time crashes immediately if you click on anything.
Scott: and Yeah, that that's what I'm supposing.
Scott: in the spring They say it in this little comic that it says.
Scott: my ninja sense says spring.
Scott: In the spring the full version is supposedly going to come out and we can only assume logically that it will not be free, but it will probably be free of bugs and It'll have all the features.
Scott: It just will cost monies.
Scott: Yeah Well, I think this is actually kind of good because if they just put out the opera browser and said here pay money for it You know, it's a tough call who would buy it and who wouldn't?
Scott: if they just put it out for free Well, then they're not making any money off of that, you know, so it's not good for them.
Scott: this way people who are early adopters of the Wii can get the browser and Try it out and solve the bugs and all that good stuff.
Scott: And if we decide that we like it a lot if I keep using that browser a lot on the Wii Then I'm probably gonna shell out and pay for the full version when it comes out.
Scott: But if I don't use it so much then I'm not gonna pay for see the way I look at it.
Rym: being geeks we have a Mac Mini already plugged into the TV and We can now pretty much and is getting better by the day use our remotes with that Mac Mini.
Scott: Yeah, that is good.
Scott: However, the opera Wii browser is specially designed to work with the Wii and is much easier to navigate with the wiimote than the Firefox Mac with tiny tiny buttons.
Rym: Yeah, but we'll see If the money versus usefulness ratio is in the proper level, yeah, I mean I'll pay.
Scott: That's the other thing.
Scott: It's great because I'll be able to figure out Through the coming months, you know I got three or four months here to decide how much it's worth to me to pay for that opera browser.
Scott: So when it finally comes out in the spring, I'll say you you're charging too much.
Scott: You're charging not enough.
Rym: I really am much more looking forward to the opera browser for the DS Which I've been waiting for on a daily basis and it's not here yet.
Scott: I don't really need that cuz I'm getting a new phone soon and phone opera for phones is free and awesome.
Scott: I have it on my blackberry.
Rym: I don't see myself getting a good phone anytime in the next three four or five years.
Scott: You know, honestly, I would just get a non, you know PDA phone and non smartphone Except I don't want to carry two things around anymore.
Rym: So I carry my DS anyway.
Scott: Yeah I don't actually carry my DS unless I have my backpack with.
Rym: well I always carry my my phone because I play games a lot.
Rym: So when I'm sitting around I have nothing to do.
Rym: I play video games.
Rym: Yeah, my DS is only in my backpack for less frequent use plus I got a bunch of new DS games to play.
Scott: you did.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Yeah, I still have to go to the store and get the medals.
Scott: Like what the hell?
Rym: Yeah I'll have words about portrait of ruin in the coming weeks after I beat it and then I'll have to play it I guess.
Rym: Yeah, I like it.
Rym: a lot of internet people have expressed somewhat negative opinions like them.
Scott: Castlevania's.
Rym: Yeah, I like a mocha.
Rym: The thing is I like what new Castlevania's are but I don't like them as much as I liked old Castlevania's.
Scott: Castlevania one.
Rym: now Castlevania one was kind of a shit.
Rym: It's anyone.
Scott: my favorite Castlevania ever is still - my second actually, you know I like Castlevania one the most just because the way it is.
Scott: but to be honest I think super Castlevania Castlevania 4 is the best one.
Rym: It was alright.
Rym: I liked it.
Scott: Okay, and of course everyone is going.
Scott: what the fuck's wrong with you Symphony of the night.
Rym: What the fuck you realize when Symphony that came out is when people like us had abandoned console gaming forever as far as we were concerned.
Scott: yeah Symphony night is the first one that is like the ones we're playing now and the GBA and the DS, you know.
Scott: But hey, what you can do?
Rym: Well, I'm gonna keep playing Castlevania until I kill Dracula again.
Scott: Are you sure it's Dracula this time?
Rym: they keep talking about Dracula.
Rym: so far there's these vampire girls and there's death and death comes back and he's like I Served Dracula and the young.
Scott: why would death the grim?
Scott: ripa serve Dracula who seems so much lesser than death.
Scott: It's.
Rym: you realize that Dracula is not just Dracula the vampire in these games.
Rym: Dracula is the embodiment of all that is black and evil.
Rym: He is the Dark Lord.
Rym: The way you can look at it Is that Dracula was the last Dark Lord to be around.
Rym: or the Dark Lord essence took over?
Rym: Dracula or something like that.
Rym: and whenever bad things are about to go down Dracula's castle suddenly reappears and then Some I know Satan there's.
Scott: no there's no one worse than Dracula.
Scott: There's no Cthulhu.
Rym: No, pretty much in you played a dawn of sorrow.
Rym: There's that one guy.
Scott: yeah, whatever.
Rym: no not Aria of Dawn yet DS.
Scott: Yeah DS.
Rym: I don't know where you get a from.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Yeah We're uh that guy that who comes right away One of the sub bosses summons Cthulhu and then kills him pretty much right there.
Rym: then Cthulhu is just this minor monster you run Into all the time.
Rym: Yep, so It's pretty much Dracula's.
Rym: it Makes no sense, but it's funny cuz that you've run into death and the main character guy is like, oh shit, it's death.
Rym: We're gonna have to fight him.
Rym: and deaths like I'll kick your ass Nub and then deaths like blah blah blah Dracula and the kids goes but Dracula's not here.
Rym: This other guys in charge of Dracula's castle and deaths like what I think I've been asleep too long ever go look into this.
Rym: So I'm waiting to see what happens with all that.
Rym: I haven't gotten very far in the game yet.
Scott: You know who's in charge of Dracula's castle?
Scott: Dracul or Drakk or Alucard.
Rym: Alucard is my man.
Scott: All right All right.
Rym: So in the much more stupid news there's been the whole issue with people breaking the straps on their remotes, which I will sum up simply as if you ever Break the strap on your remote.
Rym: You are not using your remote properly.
Scott: There's a video of a guy who adds what.
Scott: he takes a wiimote strap and he puts weights on it until it breaks and he Basically couldn't break it with a lot of weight and baby.
Scott: He tried to swing it and let go of it on purpose until the strap broke He had to swing it so monstrously hard for it to break.
Rym: good god now not one.
Rym: the worst thing is that people seem to be using like letting go of the wiimote on purpose because they seem to think that that's what the wrist strap is for.
Rym: and No, the wrist strap is for.
Rym: if you on occasion like once every five years Happen to drop your wiimote and even then if you drop your remote, you're just as stupid.
Rym: How could you possibly let go of a video game controller while you're using it?
Scott: He just ate some fried chicken, but did you?
Rym: Realize that if one of my friends came over when I was a kid and his hands were greasy and he even looked like he Was gonna get near one of my controllers.
Rym: I would beat him.
Scott: Yep, those people are disgusting those people.
Rym: anyone who came near me with greasy hands if I had something like a video game would Be kicked out of my house.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: In fact, I did kick a kid out of my house once.
Rym: cuz he I caught him playing My Nintendo with greasy fingers.
Rym: Oh, I washed that thing with alcohol And as a result ruined it.
Rym: But no Not Nintendo, you know is doing the right thing and by the right thing meaning the good PR thing and they're allowing anyone Who feels they have a concern to ask for a stronger we strap.
Scott: you can get from one to four?
Scott: Replacement stronger we straps.
Scott: I think I'm gonna ask for him cuz hey free we straps.
Scott: Why not?
Rym: See the thing is one.
Rym: I'm thinking of taking the we strap off of my wiimote and putting it on my DS And then I'm not gonna have a strap on my wiimote.
Rym: cuz I'm I have manual dexterity.
Rym: My Dex is higher than seven.
Rym: I won't drop the wiimote.
Scott: see the only reason I don't do that is because I actually you know Regardless of the protection the we strap provides I kind of like how it feels.
Rym: it only feels good to me Because if I don't put it on I've got this strap hanging or hanging down even it.
Scott: No, even if I took the strap off, I still feel like it's kind of like getting in the car without a seatbelt.
Scott: You know, it doesn't feel right.
Scott: Even if the car didn't beep at you and say hey put your fucking car My car if you don't put the seatbelt on it's like hey put your fucking seatbelt on bitch Like.
Scott: I took it off for a second one.
Scott: So I was driving to you know to do to reach over and grab something and it was like, oh my god Oh my god, beep beep beep beep beep and like shut the fuck up car I'm putting it back on.
Scott: god damn it No, but Even if I take the the we strap off the remote.
Scott: It still feels like I'm not wearing my seatbelt.
Rym: See you could have the same.
Rym: get one of those Lance Armstrong fan things stick it around your wrist and then go.
Scott: That would probably work.
Scott: But why bother?
Scott: it's so much easier.
Scott: Just use the stupid strap, which is already there.
Rym: No, cuz every time you want to pick up the controller, you got to put that strap on.
Scott: that's fine.
Rym: Ah I like to plop down and immediately game and then when I'm done gaming I immediately stand up and hit power.
Scott: It doesn't take me that long to do it.
Rym: Hey, that's eight seconds.
Rym: You're never getting back It's not a.
Scott: it doesn't even take eight seconds.
Rym: You can't take eight seconds things of the day.
Rym: But before the things the day I got a little overzealous there and queued up the things the day before I actually talked about The news.
Scott: good job.
Rym: So the real.
Rym: briefly the news is that green welling LLP has filed a class-action lawsuit against Nintendo over the quote-unquote faulty we straps and the Injuries they have caused and the property damage they have caused and how it's so negligent of Nintendo.
Scott: I think they're gonna lose.
Rym: end of story Maybe one the fact that Nintendo warns every step of the way any time you try to do anything with the weeds It reminds you.
Rym: Hey, don't forget to put the thing on.
Rym: be careful.
Rym: Don't drop it.
Scott: Yeah, they pretty much done everything they possibly can to avoid any sort of lawsuit.
Scott: These guys are just walking into a death trap a Legal death trap if you will.
Rym: Yeah, I mean Nintendo doesn't dick around.
Rym: when people forget that back in the day Nintendo was on the receiving end of a very massive Antitrust they were also first they were on the giving end.
Scott: Nintendo basically got ahead by a lawsuit And then they got on the receiving end of a lawsuit.
Rym: Yeah, people always forget that there was a time when Nintendo was a monopoly.
Rym: They were considered a video game monopoly and the government was trying to break them up.
Rym: Yep But yeah, this company has no chance and the fact that the picture here on Kotaku is a Phoenix Wright says it all.
Rym: Yeah, anyway back to things of the day.
Rym: Once again, I have a very simple one.
Rym: There's not much that can be said about it Other than that.
Rym: the title here is the piddler on the roof.
Rym: now This does not refer to the opening scene of rainy dog Doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo.
Rym: See now if you'd come up with funny lyrics that involved pee then that would have been gold Too late.
Rym: the moment's gone.
Rym: Okay, so the.
Rym: I think I'll have to read the.
Rym: I mean the the fact that these kids put a Penis, they drew a penis on the roof of a school which was then captured from space by satellites and is now on the internet.
Rym: Clearly visible Heroes, they are yes gods among men, but the caption on this picture is balls up Willy-on-roof of posh yarn school as seen from space.
Scott: Did did someone like?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: did the school dress up as a DS for Halloween or something?
Scott: What happened?
Rym: just the fact that?
Rym: Think about the society that we live in.
Rym: you were all listening to a podcast and we're all talking about or you're listening to us talk about the fact that somewhere in the world a bunch of people much like us drew a giant member on top of a School a member that was then seen from space.
Rym: that picture was then beamed back to the earth where people like us can watch it View it a comment on it talk about it and save it forever and laugh at it.
Rym: We are gods compared to the vast majority of human history.
Rym: if this is what we do with our lives Yeah, I mean try explaining what we were doing right now to someone from ancient Greece.
Rym: Yes, you see that you know that penis that those kids drew on top of the Parthenon.
Rym: Here's a picture of it from space.
Rym: So anyway Now the best part of this is that was not the only member that these kids put up during the weekend.
Rym: To quote the article they managed to get on the roof of the friary building and somehow mark on the Willy.
Rym: they also.
Rym: They also burnt a manhood into the grass.
Rym: That is a quote that is verbatim from the article.
Rym: They burnt a manhood onto the grass Right, so Maybe that's how those Greek statues?
Scott: it was just punk kids.
Scott: They attached them on with clay Pictures of them from space And then they snuck him into museums and fooled everyone to think of their works of art.
Rym: See people always thought that Zeus would come down and yell at people or seduce women.
Rym: No, Zeus was coming down to tell the parents of kids that he had to deal with the fact that they're growing penises on every.
Scott: Yeah, cuz we do some fucking Mount Olympus.
Scott: He looks down on the city and he says what the hell is that?
Scott: So what drew a fucking penis on the top roof?
Scott: What the hell?
Scott: They do that.
Scott: It was that you Hermes.
Rym: I think you're forgetting that they also burnt a manhood into the grass.
Rym: now Zeus could take care of that easily with his lightning.
Scott: Now I think you're thinking today's gonna pale in comparison but come on out alright, so my thing today is a short video from a Japanese TV show.
Scott: Oh, we we oh, we we called Sanma palace and I don't know what the hell this shows about and the clip is very short.
Scott: but in the clip they talk to voice actress Ikue Ohtani who is the voice of Pikachu.
Rym: now I Mean.
Rym: we all are aware on an intellectual level that there aren't Pokemon and that when you hear a Pokemon talking It is actually a human being talking into a microphone.
Rym: But seeing is done.
Rym: live by a real human Borders.
Rym: on the frightening.
Scott: I mean, it's one thing to see someone at a convention come up to you and go pick up a guy.
Scott: It's like alright, the person said Pika Pika to hear someone say Pika Pika.
Scott: the way Pikachu says Pika Pika.
Scott: Exactly the way like that's it.
Scott: She she is Pikachu.
Scott: it's like oh, oh god.
Scott: It's it's like lightning in the brain now Burning a member on your front lawn.
Rym: Now I gave Scott a list of the other roles that this woman has had.
Scott: Well, there are really only two of them that are interesting.
Scott: First of all, well Pikachu Pikachu.
Scott: second of all Not only is she Pikachu she's Pikachu and everywhere Pikachu appears including Puzzle League.
Scott: She's Pikachu and Pokemon pinball.
Scott: She's Pikachu and Smash Brothers.
Scott: She's Pikachu.
Scott: Anywhere Pikachu's voice appears.
Scott: this lady did it now.
Scott: you might know the cartoon Animaniacs.
Scott: Well, it aired in Japan and dot Warner was voiced by the same lady who did Pikachu.
Rym: not only that but then the Japanese dub of Full house.
Scott: Yes full house.
Scott: Yes the same that she saw.
Rym: the very same.
Scott: Who was she?
Rym: Some care.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I hated that show.
Rym: I used to watch it.
Rym: I don't know why.
Rym: I really don't know why she was Stephanie Tanner.
Rym: to this day I think back.
Rym: I remember the times when I'd watch full house.
Scott: I never actually watched full house.
Scott: I watched the shows after it.
Rym: now I'll say this that I can't register any emotion from that period in my life.
Scott: I remember the closer full house because I turned on the TV as the closer was going and I would watch the shows that followed.
Rym: I remember watching that other thing where Bob Saget and the other guy that I would say cut it out.
Scott: What was that?
Scott: I have no idea.
Rym: cuz I've done.
Rym: I'm doing it right now cut.
Scott: I know you're always doing.
Rym: I'm doing that all the time cuz I when I was a little kid I practiced hard until I could do it without thinking because it's it's a simple thing to do But it's kind of like a magic spell you got to be able to move your fingers just right or loses the effects.
Rym: Yeah, but of course the effect is getting myself beat up.
Scott: Yeah, so what's the show about today?
Rym: Well after killing all that time talking about penises penis on the parthenon good guy, yeah We decided we talked a little bit about board games.
Scott: It's been a while.
Scott: It has been a while.
Scott: We haven't played too many board games lately.
Scott: At least we haven't played any new ones even though Here's something for everybody.
Scott: I discovered a video podcast called board games with Scott.
Scott: now I had heard of it and it's not me Scott.
Scott: It's some other guy named Scott who's a little bit nerdy, but he's cool And I heard of this thing before but never went to watch it.
Scott: I actually thought it was an audio podcast.
Scott: So I just kind of you know, I didn't have time for it.
Scott: It's actually a video podcast and the guy takes board games out and teaches you the rules and everything and it's pretty cool Like to go there and see some of these games that he demonstrates.
Scott: like if you think die mocker is complicated Go watch this guy named Scott demonstrate and you'll still think it's complicated because that game is Complicated.
Scott: Yeah, but he does a lot of like really new games that you probably can't get yet very easily unless you're all savvy Buying it online or anything like that.
Scott: So it's cool to see how these games work step by step and everything.
Scott: So board games of Scott go check it out.
Rym: Yeah, but see once the Wii came out pretty much we were playing Resident Evil 4.
Scott: I say press a and I beat it the day before the Wii came out.
Scott: I mean if I didn't beat it before the Wii came out.
Rym: I was never gonna beat it Crammed in as much board gaming and video gaming as we could in knowing that a moment that we came out.
Rym: That was the end.
Rym: It was the end and it was the end.
Scott: We don't even really watch Netflix enough.
Rym: We don't do anything now until now that the Wii is awesome still but it's not the ever present driving force in our lives every waking moment.
Rym: We've started doing other things and this weekend when we plan to work on the show We were because we got all that swag and swag coming and we were gonna work on it.
Rym: But then Alex came over and instead of doing that we played Puerto Rico and then we played Calus twice.
Scott: Yeah, and those are all games that we've played and talked about before.
Rym: Yeah, Puerto Rico and Calus are hard board games as in real deal Completely, uh, I don't know.
Scott: Those are man's games.
Scott: It's sort of like if you want to read gecky gum.
Rym: Oh, no, we're not talking man in like the sexist man versus woman We're talking man in the gecky guy ho Joe standing there with a gun.
Scott: exactly I mean a woman can be that manly that got manga gecky guy is to manga as These board games are to other board games.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, I mean it's a woman can be just as manly as a man when it comes to that It has nothing to do with gender.
Rym: It is a special use of the word man.
Rym: Yes Anyway, now I would like to mention the fact just it's masculine.
Scott: How's that?
Scott: But that Specifically Okay, and I'm silly.
Rym: well regardless of all that I'll note that I won every single game we played that weekend.
Scott: Yeah, whatever.
Rym: Yeah, I just had to bring that up because Scott talked to big seat.
Rym: It's no big deal to win a board game because everyone in the crew was really smart and when we play board games It's always a really tough fight.
Rym: But I won the first game of Calus by a bit and Scott was like I'll win next time.
Rym: I was distracted blah blah blah.
Scott: I lost terribly because in the early turns I hadn't played Calus in a while I had forgotten most of the rules and some very important rules and I screwed up now big time Despite
Rym: the fact that Alex who is play until this weekend had played Calus twice in his life Remembered every single rule and did fine if I did better than Scott.
Scott: Well, cuz uh, he remembered all the rules and I didn't.
Rym: well I don't know you I don't know how you didn't.
Rym: wasn't that you were forgotten rules.
Scott: I remember should I did yesterday?
Rym: But That's irrelevant.
Rym: I was just bragging because I won these games and in our crew that that means a lot.
Rym: Yeah next weekend.
Rym: I'll probably lose every game.
Scott: Anyway, today we're gonna talk about what makes a board game Good.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean we own a lot of board games and we have played a Freaking lot of board games, but despite owning all these games all of which we enjoyed when we played them There's only a select handful that have staying power that we continue to play on a regular basis without ever growing tired of them.
Scott: Mm-hmm, and you know, once you play a lot of board games in most people you just play Monopoly Scrabble.
Scott: Sorry Whatever, you know, it's something to do to pass the time with friends.
Scott: It's really just sort of like, you know something to do with your hands while you have conversation and drink or whatever You're doing or hang out with your family.
Scott: When you play board games for the sake of playing them you begin to notice a few things You know like huh?
Scott: That board game won't be fun to ever play again because of X Y & Z or this board game will always be fun Or that one's not fun, but it's a damn good game, etc, etc.
Rym: So I guess.
Rym: hence the best way to categorize this is simply that when we talk about board games being good There are really two completely distinct but non mutually exclusive categories.
Rym: to break things down into very simple terms There are games that are pure and good that are purely good games that they are on some abstract or real level a Very well constructed game that covered all the bases
Scott: Yeah, we're only talking about the rules here not like the pieces and then all that stuff.
Rym: That's none of that matter.
Rym: We're talking about the actual raw game mechanics Yes, and on the opposite end of the spectrum there are games that are fun.
Rym: now I said that these are not mutually exclusive.
Rym: There are games that are not good games that are incredibly fun.
Rym: There are games that are not fun at all that are very good games Yeah, and there are games that are good and fun.
Scott: and there are games that are not good and not fun.
Scott: You can mix it up any way you want because totally different factors influence each thing.
Scott: However, if you are like us and you are the kind of person who enjoys a good game Then good games will be at least a little fun, even though they can also be terrible.
Rym: Yep And the best way to know if a game is good because you can't really know upon first playings or even a bunch of playings Any game how good it truly is in terms of staying power.
Rym: because almost any board game no matter how bad it is is Fun at least once or twice.
Scott: Well, the reason a board game is fun at least once is because I think personally it's fun to read the rules and to Look at all these new pieces and boards and to see how they work.
Scott: Just seeing a new game unfold and learning about it and opening the box and whatever.
Scott: that in itself is fun for me.
Scott: So any board game in the world has that amount of fun in it already?
Rym: I mean that moment Like
Scott: even Hellas
Rym: like any complex game where you're reading through the rules and it's tough and you're not understand and then There's always that moment of revelation in a complex game where it clicks and like you will learn about one more game mechanic and suddenly You understand on a high level how the game works.
Rym: Like oh, it's a bidding game or oh It's a cube manipulation game or like oh, it's that kind of game and that all those moments really They're good experience.
Rym: Yep I think just as important is that the first few times you play a game It's a novel experience.
Rym: Everyone's on equal playing field usually because no one else has played the game before and that's you're having.
Scott: someone who's mad Experience teach you the game.
Rym: Yeah, but then they get the own.
Rym: they get their own unique experience of watching people who have never played the game before play it.
Rym: Yep, but just any game or how bad it is is always novel.
Rym: the first time you played You don't know what strategy is gonna win.
Scott: I mean if you've never played problematic trouble before it's fun to hit that problematic bubble in the middle Especially when you figure out how to make it always give you a six, especially when you're three years old.
Scott: And to be green.
Rym: see when I was a little kid I always thought that headache was a much better game than trouble.
Scott: I know what headache is.
Rym: headache was the one that looked very much like trouble But you had little coney guys instead and you could like capture other people's coney guys by jumping on top of them.
Scott: And okay, we always.
Scott: we usually played sorry more than we played trouble.
Scott: just because our trouble sucked.
Rym: I used to complain.
Rym: my family always wanted to play a sorry But they get mad if I played optimally like I played.
Scott: sorry optimally.
Scott: everyone played.
Scott: sorry optimally No, but I didn't get on those sliders knocking each other off the board.
Scott: It was crazy.
Rym: if I was in second place and I use my sorry troubles to screw over like my dad.
Rym: if he was winning My family would be all like hey, you're just preventing him from winning so you can win.
Rym: and I'm like Yeah, that's what I'm doing.
Scott: That's the point.
Scott: Yeah, I'm just supposed to play randomly.
Scott: then what's the point?
Rym: Okay Luke always made that argument.
Scott: Well, that's just cuz he wanted to win.
Scott: sure that was part of his way of winning.
Scott: Yeah was to act like he wasn't trying to win and convince you not to try to win.
Scott: Therefore he would win cuz he had the only one trying.
Rym: my strategies are much more devious and I tricked other people much more subtle Yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah anyway Forgot where I was going with that train of thought so I'll just continue.
Rym: Yep But once you've played a game a bunch of times and you figured out all the games basic tricks Like you become an intermediate player of the game.
Rym: You're no longer beginner.
Rym: You're no longer learning about the game on any fundamental level.
Rym: That's the point in which you can judge if a game is truly good or not Because that's the point where you realize like you can visualize.
Rym: Would this game still be fun if I figure out the number of bids?
Rym: I should make in the first round because once I figure that out, maybe there's no game anymore.
Scott: Well, there's some good examples for Puerto Rico, which you just talked about right?
Scott: We've played that game a hundred times, right?
Rym: Probably more than that.
Scott: Yeah, and You know every turn you have to make some decisions.
Scott: cuz they're really there's nothing in the game.
Scott: There's no dice or anything.
Scott: It's decisions.
Scott: All you do is make decisions.
Rym: Yeah, I mean literally nothing is random in that game.
Scott: Nope and Every get time you play the game you have to make these same decisions.
Scott: but I've played the game at least 50 to 100 times.
Scott: I don't even freaking know anymore and Making the decisions doesn't get any easier.
Scott: I don't just know the answers.
Scott: You know, I mean if you played what was that game?
Scott: We played Timbuktu.
Scott: Yeah, Timbuktu if you play that game once and you're an intelligent human being if you play it again You know exactly what move to make.
Scott: you don't even have to think about it.
Scott: You just know because it's like solving a crossword puzzle and then doing the same crossword puzzle again.
Scott: You know the answer already.
Scott: It's not fun anymore.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: There are many board games that are solvable Absolutely solvable where if you figure out the game on a fundamental level you have to make zero decisions in the whole game.
Rym: You know exactly what to do to either win or to have the absolute best chance of winning.
Scott: Yeah, and when that happens the games not fun anymore, and it's also not good.
Scott: Yep, the best games are games in which no matter how much you know You still have to do thinking in order to win.
Scott: I mean, you know some got.
Scott: sometimes the games are such that you could possibly reach that level But it's so complex that it's difficult for a human to do Like chess or Tigers and Euphrates.
Scott: Yeah, but sometimes games is just not possible at all.
Rym: to ever solve it Let's break it down into.
Rym: let's give an example of all the different like we got these four corners here a game That is not good and not fun, which would be Hellas.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Hellas is not a good game.
Rym: It is not a fun game.
Rym: The rules are written poorly.
Rym: The game is basically unplayable.
Rym: We have never played the game without running into an unanswerable rules question that prevented.
Scott: Another example would be monopoly.
Scott: Monopoly is not good.
Scott: Whoever wins comes down to dice It.
Scott: why even play?
Scott: and it also not fun because you've got to play forever and it just.
Scott: it doesn't matter anymore.
Rym: See, I will point out monopoly is fun for the first ten minutes.
Rym: Yep, and if you ever play monopoly with your friends ever again I suggest you right now one play by the original rules of the game.
Rym: None of that.
Rym: free parking BS to the Moments.
Rym: the game is not always fun anymore.
Rym: The moment all the property is bought you must immediately knock that board over and run away Possibly screaming while doing so.
Scott: Okay, let's let's have it a game.
Scott: That's fun, but not good.
Rym: I would say Citadel's Citadel's.
Rym: you see Citadel's is an incredibly fun game.
Rym: I absolutely love playing it it but on a fundamental level the Basic tactics of the game break up into two categories.
Rym: The first category is making the Obvious optimal move.
Rym: these you know, but build the right thing do the right thing It's always obvious.
Rym: and the second bit of tactics is very simply the princess bride conundrum Which cup is the poison in?
Rym: and the answer is you can't make a determination so it ends up being totally random.
Scott: Well, I was gonna say apples to apples because apples to apples as a game is just completely subjective.
Scott: There's not even really a game there.
Scott: Yeah, but terms of fun.
Scott: It's like the most fun you're gonna have.
Rym: I agree.
Rym: I think both are good examples of that kind of game a game that is very fun.
Rym: I will play apples to apples anytime.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I will play Citadel's anytime.
Rym: I love both games, but they are not good games.
Rym: They're fun games and I acknowledge this fact.
Scott: All right, what's the game?
Scott: That's good, but not fun.
Rym: Uh, I I would I want to say die marker, but I haven't played it enough.
Scott: Yeah, I played enough to know.
Rym: I played it once and I lost and I wasn't entirely sure what happened.
Rym: Wow Alex won.
Rym: we're sitting around we're counting up the scores right.
Rym: the game had ended and my brain hurt.
Rym: we'd been playing this game for four hours not counting the time.
Rym: it took us to learn how to play and The game ended and then we were reading like we were following the rules and adding up scores and we had no idea Who had won.
Rym: we had no way to know who was even close to winning.
Rym: We just followed this complex Byzantine set of rules at the end of which we determined that Alex was the winner.
Rym: and he said I don't know how I won.
Rym: And I said, I don't know how I lost.
Rym: and we put the game away.
Rym: and that was the end of that.
Rym: Yeah, well, he won by a lot too.
Scott: Yeah, my example is gonna be go.
Scott: Well, some people like go and they think it's fun.
Scott: It might be fun for them It's not fun for me, but I recognize that it is an excellent game.
Scott: Perhaps one of the best games ever.
Scott: I just it's it's not fun.
Rym: make the same kind of point.
Scott: Puerto Rico Puerto Rico.
Rym: To us people like think about.
Rym: there are people who love go and to them go is fun.
Rym: Puerto Rico is very fun to people like us, but to a lot of people Puerto Rico is Objectively an extremely good game.
Rym: It is one of the best games ever made.
Rym: It is an absolutely beautifully constructed game But playing it is to so too many people Somewhat tedious and very difficult.
Scott: it is difficult.
Rym: It is not Intuitively fun.
Scott: You have to be better at it in order for it to be to get the fun out of it or else It just it's.
Scott: well, it's not as bad as age of steam age of steam.
Scott: There's a game that is good But not necessarily fun because you can recognize the age of steam is a great train stock market game.
Scott: However, if you're not good at it The game just beats the freaking shit out of you and it's hard and that can often make it not fun And that when you're not doing well, you actually end up going down the tubes.
Rym: See now this is why I mean it comes down to subjectivity and what we're talking about here Mostly are well, the fun part is more subjective.
Scott: The good part is less subjective.
Rym: Well, yeah But in terms of rating a game overall because no matter how good a game is Very no one almost no one will play a game that is not fun.
Rym: No matter how good it is That's true.
Rym: And the fact that people like us find games fun that other people don't find fun and vice versa is the reason that Puerto Rico Is very popular but monopoly is also popular.
Rym: Yep, even though monopoly isn't good either.
Scott: All right, what's the game?
Scott: That's good and fun.
Rym: tigers and your friends gonna say that you bastard I think Tigers and Euphrates is perhaps the best example of that I've ever encountered.
Scott: It's like Kayla's is good and fun.
Rym: Kayla's is very much good and fun I have.
Scott: I haven't played it yet, but I have a feeling that third in taxes The latest field as you are is good and fun.
Scott: I just got a feeling.
Rym: see I always tell people ask me a lot especially conventions what my favorite board game is.
Rym: And I always say Puerto Rico is the best board game, but Tigers and Euphrates is my favorite.
Rym: Yeah, I think I mean, it's it's hard to quantify why I could do a whole show on why I think that Tigers and Euphrates is the most Fun game.
Scott: Well, we'll do it eventually.
Rym: Well, we've talked about Tigers and Euphrates.
Rym: Yeah, we have and we've talked about Puerto Rico.
Scott: I think all right.
Rym: So have we?
Rym: I'm pretty sure we we've done like 240 episodes.
Rym: We'd better hands.
Scott: I'm gonna go look at it.
Scott: We've only done like 50 something Episodes on games though.
Rym: I think we've done 58.
Scott: Yeah, something like that.
Scott: All right, 59 now.
Scott: So what is it that makes a game good?
Scott: like?
Scott: there are identifiable factors and I thought of a bunch of them.
Rym: Yeah, we can't go into too much detail or we're gonna have a long episode.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Well first is lack of randomness makes a game good.
Scott: if a game is random Like it's just a game a chance roll a die.
Scott: See who wins.
Scott: that makes a game not as good.
Scott: I mean Sometimes you can have randomness and it won't suck and remember it of.
Rym: the biggest thing is How much of a factor is the randomness and at what point is the randomness inserted?
Rym: a lot of good games and great games?
Rym: need randomness or else the game is deterministic where you could figure out.
Rym: if I go first then I Must do this and then I'm most likely going to win.
Scott: For example, Puerto Rico is random in which Plantations will be available.
Rym: That's completely random yep, and you can buy a building.
Rym: in fact that introduces even more randomness into you personally by allowing you to draw a Plantation tile sight unseen.
Rym: Yep, but Calus injects randomness in the very beginning by you draw the six pink tiles and you put them in a random order and that order Really has a huge effect on how the game will turn out.
Scott: it does but all that it doesn't actually have an effect on who's Going to win it just makes this time You're playing Calus different from the last time you played Calus, which is important.
Rym: That's one of the biggest factors in making the game fun.
Scott: Yeah because if it was the same order every time.
Scott: then Calus would be the same game every time but eventually would get stale.
Rym: there is the Bevagung factor or analysis paralysis.
Scott: Yes many games Right.
Scott: Here's example famously acquire God acquire is a game where if you sit on your turn and you just look at the game and do Calculations of every possible move that you can make you will eventually figure out the best possible move Period that you can make.
Scott: it's not hard to figure it out It just takes some time.
Scott: if a game is light is designed in that way where you can sit there think and eventually come up with the best move in your head then it's kind of boring because everyone sits there and does the Best possible move and it takes forever.
Rym: some notable games that suffer from this are obviously acquire Risk to a degree you can calculate statistics forever.
Rym: Yep El Grande is huge for this and we have there's one that was one of the early board games beyond settlers that we really got Into and I kind of want to play it again.
Rym: But that is definitely a game.
Rym: if you can sit there and calculate the exact odds of everything Yeah You
Scott: figure out exactly how many cubes to put where and then you're done
Rym: and I'm worried that Calus to a lesser degree has this problem because the last time we played Calus I spent an extra 30 seconds every turn thinking and that had a profound effect on my strategy.
Rym: surprisingly Yeah, like more surprisingly to me because I didn't expect.
Rym: usually in a game like Tigers of the Euphrates You can think and think and think and there's a point at which you have exhausted All of the thinking you can do and still have an appreciable effect on your strategy.
Rym: But Calus the more I thought the more I could optimize my turn.
Rym: and I wonder if I'll be able to optimize my term Turn completely within a reasonable span of say 30 to 45 seconds because if I can That changes the way I play Calus.
Rym: and if I can't but I could within five minutes that almost breaks Calus.
Scott: Yep All right What's another good factor that makes the game good?
Rym: I thought you had a whole bunch.
Scott: I did.
Scott: We already talked about let's see.
Rym: All right one that we can't explain in detail.
Rym: We'll have to do a whole show on this because we need to talk a lot about game theory first.
Rym: But a game that introduces Tactical decision-making that is not arbitrary Yeah The least.
Rym: the less arbitrariness there is and the more tactical direct decision-making there is and the more weighted Decision-making there is and the more in the more utility decision-making there is.
Rym: I'm throwing out a lot of barely comprehensible terms that mean very specific and alternating things.
Rym: so Yeah game theory if a game is sound as per the tenets of good game theory Helps everybody out there.
Rym: Yeah, you know what.
Rym: I'll read the Wikipedia on game theory.
Scott: I'll just give an example.
Scott: Let's think of one.
Scott: All right, here's one ready.
Scott: You're let's say you're going down a road right and you have a choice left or right and it there's no signs There's no nothing.
Scott: your choice is just left or right and you have no information whatsoever.
Scott: Well, it doesn't matter which one you pick.
Rym: yeah, in fact you might as well remove that decision from the game.
Rym: It's like in the old match game on TV where they'd ask the contestant number one or number two And there's a different question behind each one.
Rym: But because you don't know any information and the decision is therefore completely arbitrary It absolutely does not matter and has no effect on the universe whatsoever.
Rym: What decision you make?
Scott: Yep Like let's say there's a game where there are three different You know hidden cards and you get to pick one of the three.
Scott: Why even bother just have one stack of cards and make them draw the top card?
Rym: Yeah, so good games are games that when at all possible Identify and eliminate decisions like that decisions where there isn't actually a decision.
Scott: Yep And a tactical decision would be alright Are you?
Scott: can either pay one to buy this building or pay three to buy that different better building?
Scott: It's like oh well now you have to think.
Scott: you have to think is that building worth three times as much as that building?
Scott: Etc.
Scott: And yes is what makes a good game?
Rym: or I have five cards in my hand.
Rym: three of them They're blue or one of them is red.
Rym: I can discard any number of cards and draw and I know that there are 45 red cards and 39 blue cards in the deck.
Rym: So I know my odds of getting the blue card.
Rym: I need to complete my set and win the game.
Rym: Is it worth it to take the risk to discard the card?
Rym: Versus playing the card on one of my buildings in order to put a Kerblofel on the board.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I Wanted to use a completely meta nonsensical example.
Rym: there we get my idea.
Rym: a weighted decision is like a decision where you can calculate like I Have a 55% chance of doing good with this decision.
Rym: I have a 30% chance of doing twice as good if I am successful with this decision and then based on that How far ahead you are in the game Where how long game has less to.
Rym: you know stuff like that.
Rym: decisions that aren't completely arbitrary and where there is information.
Rym: The information doesn't have to be totaled but it has to be there in some form.
Scott: Even better is when your decision isn't you know, 30% chance this 60% chance that it's.
Scott: you know the outcome of this decision and you know the outcome of the other decision and you just can't tell which of those two outcomes is Preferable.
Rym: or you know the outcomes of all your possible decisions.
Rym: but across from you is a human being who has an equal but possibly asymmetric list of decisions and You have information based on his stance on the board to make a guess as to what decision he would be likely to make and His decision will have a great effect on your decision, but you end up deciding simultaneously.
Scott: I wonder if this is getting across at all.
Rym: I hope it is.
Scott: I hope so.
Rym: I promise whenever we feel like it.
Rym: We're gonna do a show on game theory.
Rym: And when I say game theory, I mean practical game theory.
Scott: We're not gonna talk about the math We're not gonna talk about economics because I guarantee is actually economics.
Rym: I guarantee that none of you care at all about the math behind game theory.
Rym: Yeah, I Barely care about it and I love game theory, but sometimes reading that theory just uh, no good the numbers just god damn it.
Scott: Alright, so let's just end the show by tell what makes a game fun.
Rym: Novelty is a big thing.
Scott: Novelty is pretty big.
Rym: A game that has novelty Either in individual play sessions or as a game as a whole will always lend itself to being more fun.
Rym: Games that have cool complex pieces that actually have an effect on the game or actually represents something real in the game.
Scott: What was that game where you roll the dice in a big castle?
Rym: Oh, there's a bunch of games like that.
Scott: There's the game Niagara where there's actually little boats that go down the river and fall off the edge The Niagara Falls.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Yeah, that's pretty fun.
Rym: or games like Railroad tycoon which while the game itself is fun It's not the greatest game in the world But it has this massive board and all these pieces and you get so much fun Just building your railroad managing your railroad that a lot of times even if you're losing or the game went to shit You don't even care because you're still having fun managing your railroad.
Scott: yeah, I think one thing that definitely makes a game more fun is when you do things when you have actions and you get something out of It like if you on a turn spend some money and then build some stuff.
Scott: that feels good.
Scott: That's why RTS games are all are kind of fun.
Scott: yeah, because you're building stuff even if you're not winning as long as you're marching forward and You know, you're doing things often and not spending a lot of time sitting around being bored You're actively doing things all the time.
Scott: that that makes a game a lot of fun.
Rym: It's very much railroad tycoon versus age of steam.
Rym: They're effectively the same game except that railroad tycoon You still have the ability to take action even when your loss is a foregone conclusion.
Rym: Yep, so no, man, even though you cannot win it is still and I'm dead serious.
Rym: It is still fun to continue playing the game until it ends.
Rym: age of steam The moment you fall behind by any appreciable amount.
Rym: not only is the game not fun anymore But the one time I played age of steam and I fell behind.
Rym: It was one of the first times in my life Where I decided that it was not worth it to me to spend my time to keep playing the game.
Scott: Yeah, I mean there was no way to win.
Scott: basically There's no way that we could see well that game and there was no way to take any fun Actions and you spent a lot of time doing nothing.
Rym: now I could have avoided that situation by being better at the game.
Rym: But a game that is fun is such that no matter how badly you are doing The game is still on some level entertaining enough to keep you playing and keep you engaged Another.
Scott: I think the last thing that makes the game fun is when there's some sort of element of Like bringing the players into the game if it be it by role-playing or humor for example.
Scott: And you play settlers right a lot of the fun.
Scott: Hey comes are going.
Scott: Hey, man.
Rym: I got a wood you got sheep Ha ha ha ha a joke about bestiality and erection.
Scott: or like apples to apples where you know You act you give someone all these cards and then they go.
Rym: Hitler ha ha ha ha ha ha ha.
Rym: Gandhi Nuclear weapons.
Scott: oh how could you do that?
Scott: That's terrible?
Scott: You know when there is some sort of you know human element brought into the game instead of just cold Calculating pieces moving around the board that makes a game very fun You know.
Scott: that's why D&D is fun even though It's not really a game in.
Rym: the D&D is a classic example of a game that is fun, but not good.
Rym: Yes, I mean it is good at what it is.
Scott: Role-playing games in general are very different really can't be good in the same way that board games can be good.
Rym: That I think it's possible, but games like that tend to be Role-playing games that involve military tactics.
Scott: That is too true.
Scott: Yes Yes But no role-playing games tend to concentrate on the fun and don't really care about me the mechanics aren't meant to be these fair difficult complex thought Experiment you know challenges.
Scott: They're just there to support the fun of role-playing and it's totally different.
Scott: It shouldn't even be entered into this conversation.
Rym: Yeah, and I think we'll stop there just because as always we've gone long.
Rym: I would just like to say once again and this is probably the only time in the history of time that we will ever do this, but dig podcasts is Already the best podcast directory out there other than possibly iTunes, but a lot of you can't use iTunes.
Rym: So if you do not use dig I recommend you use it because Forget podcast alley and podcast pickle.
Rym: Those things are all dead to me.
Scott: Yep, and you know already yesterday We talked about this and I didn't.
Scott: I figured everyone who listen to get GeekNights use dig But apparently that's not true and some people already told us that they started using dig on our recommendation and they can't imagine That they weren't using it before.
Rym: so join the front row crew forums Then look at our usernames and join the front row crew dig clan that is slowly forming.
Rym: Yes, go to dig calm and get an account and and while you're there if you like GeekNights if you dig us It'll make us more popular and the more popular we are the more swag you're gonna get in the near future.
Scott: Yes, but do not feel obligated to dig us.
Scott: We are not, you know begging for digs.
Scott: We don't need them.
Rym: Yeah, in fact, we are already Very highly placed compared to many other podcasts on dig as it is.
Scott: That's just because we're so hip and cool with this internet action that when a new bandwagon comes along We are the first to jump on board.
Rym: Oh, yes.
Rym: In fact, we are on such a bleeding edge that I better go get a band-aid.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com.
Scott: You'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our crapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at frontrowcrew.com Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.