Rym: It's Thursday August 10th, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: It is actually a GeekNights special meaning that me and Scott are not here.
Scott: We fought away Very very far.
Rym: so of course we've said this all week But if this is the first GeekNights you've ever heard by all means listen.
Rym: But this is not what GeekNights is.
Rym: this is a GeekNights special meaning We're not in town, and we've recorded this only to fill in the feed until we get back.
Scott: So enjoy the very few minutes of podcast you're about to listen to now.
Rym: This is a tale of misery and woe but also of triumph and then final utter defeat.
Rym: This is the tale of the 1974 color RCA television that has served us so well and is finally being put out to pasture.
Scott: Well, this is Rym's television in the beginning.
Rym: well Yes to start the tail actually it was my parents color RCA television.
Rym: We had this back when we lived in Detroit.
Rym: It was huge.
Rym: It's not really that big.
Rym: It's like a 20-something inch yeah, but when I was a little kid this thing was huge.
Rym: this thing was a massive massive awesome TV and It probably worked function wonderfully for a number of years, but as time went on it didn't function so well I mean it was perfectly serviceable, and it had a minimal set of inputs in the back of it.
Scott: And it had a remote control, and that's crazy for the time because it's a late 70s model.
Rym: Yeah, and that was really it.
Rym: I mean it was wood paneled it.
Rym: the screen was super super curved.
Rym: It had this ass little speaker in the front of it that barely worked.
Rym: now I needed a TV at RIT.
Rym: When we got an apartment our sophomore year Scott and I and of course we were poor college students I mean we were so poor we didn't have anything.
Rym: We had a bunch of furniture that my dad gave me and my mom gave me this TV.
Scott: Yeah, freshman year all I had was a little tiny TV that belonged to my roommate and had a VCR in it.
Rym: so So we lugged this thing into the apartment And it we plugged it in and we used it for a number of years in fact for all of our time at RIT.
Scott: This was the TV.
Rym: We had now this TV one.
Rym: it made this high-pitched wine.
Scott: always You could hit it and sometimes make the wine go away, but it really wouldn't go away.
Scott: It just become quieter than the volume of the television.
Rym: now We're not talking about that high-pitched wine that all CRT CRT based televisions make.
Scott: we're talking.
Rym: It was loud and annoying and we would walk and we learned the specific place to hit it to make that wine go away.
Rym: Sometimes sometimes we would bang on that thing as hard as we could Not as hard as he could.
Scott: that would have breaking it that possum broken broken it.
Scott: good game good game.
Rym: Also, it had a nice tendency to if it ever lost power if the power ever went out or anything it would make an Unearthly racket like it was exploding for a second.
Rym: It would just go like BAM.
Rym: I've no idea why it did that.
Scott: all I know is I think it was capacitors discharging or something.
Rym: yeah, all I know is many a time it saved me like if the power was out or something even back when I was a kid and The power went out in the middle of the night, right?
Rym: I'd have no way to wake up in the morning, but the TV would make such a loud noise It would wake me up and then I'd know that the power was out.
Scott: Also, supposedly Rym is told tales tall tales.
Scott: Yes of the TV making ball lightning.
Rym: There was one time I was in eighth grade and I was lying in bed and this TV was in my room Scary so I wouldn't sleep with that thing in the room.
Rym: Well, I wasn't afraid of the TV or anything should be because we had a better.
Rym: Actually, maybe was nice.
Rym: I forget exactly when it was but I remember I was laying in bed and The TV was in my room because my parents had gotten a far superior TV.
Rym: Finally We'd gotten it in fact to watch the Stanley Cup playoffs of all things.
Rym: But anyway, we the TV was in my room and I was using it.
Rym: I think earlier in that day I'd watch the lost boys on it unrelated note.
Rym: and I'm sleeping and I'm woken up by this humming noise and I look and there's this glow emanating from the top of the TV.
Rym: and Now if I had been anyone else I probably thought oh my god a ghost.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: Oh my god Aliens, oh my god.
Rym: Yeah instead.
Rym: I thought holy shit What the fuck is that?
Rym: and I get up and I walk over to it.
Rym: I don't I couldn't tell what it was.
Rym: It kind of freaked me out and then I went back into my bed and I laid there staring at it for a while and I figured whatever it was It was either a figment of my imagination or something and I would just go back to sleep and whatever.
Rym: and I went back to Sleep because good idea I mean I was afraid to poke at it because I wasn't sure What it was.
Rym: and if it was some sort of electrical thing I didn't want to hurt myself and it seemed like it.
Rym: I really couldn't tell it was this bluish greenish light.
Rym: So I go back to sleep and in the morning I'm like, hey mom a TV made a light and my mom's like, oh, it's done that before.
Rym: I think it's ball lightning.
Rym: Yeah, and I was like what?
Rym: And then I looked online.
Rym: I read all about ball lightning which may or may not actually exist in the form that is described but Supposedly is very dangerous.
Scott: All lightning is there.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Yes Well in magic the gathering even ball lightning is hella dangerous super but only once only once.
Scott: yes Oh, I guess he only happened once.
Rym: it's okay now the TV also.
Rym: once I had put a glass on top of the TV with water in it while I was drinking and then I walked away for a while and the glass I didn't realize had a crack in the bottom and The water slowly over the course of a day drained out of the glass Down the front of the TV and into the electronics of the TV.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: now when I came back the glass was empty.
Rym: So I didn't even.
Rym: I just left the glass there because I didn't even notice that yeah leaving glasses all around the house.
Scott: What's wrong with you?
Rym: I didn't even imagine that water had leaked out and into the TV, but for another for the next week or so The TV wasn't working so well.
Rym: like the remote control when I change channels it would change randomly and every none than the volume which go up and down kind of randomly and Noises would come out of the speakers, but it still kind of worked yeah, and eventually I Had another.
Rym: I had the same glass and I was drinking and I set it down on the table next to me.
Rym: Then I look and water is slowly leaking out of it.
Rym: And then I look at the TV, and I see the residue of all the water that had leaked in.
Scott: and oh It's all coming together now.
Scott: yes, I see what you did there.
Rym: So of course eventually we moved out of that apartment to where we are now and the TV is also Somewhat heavy and more than heavy.
Rym: It's very bulky and hard to move.
Scott: yeah I mean, it's a TV so the total weight of it probably isn't.
Scott: maybe between 50 and 100 pounds.
Scott: Yeah, I'm like that But all the weight is the big piece of glass in the front of it.
Rym: So it's really hard to carry it when all the heaviness is on one side Especially up and down stairs because we lived in a tri-level apartment style so we had a stairwell to go down to get into our apartment mm-hmm.
Rym: and When we finally moved actually we were debating and how we gonna get this into the house.
Rym: It's such a pain in the ass and our friend Pete who was helping us move Just picked it up by himself carried it and set it down.
Rym: Hooray yes Now we use the TV for a little while.
Rym: then we realized this TV sucks.
Rym: Now.
Rym: one of the reasons it sucked aside from everything we have just mentioned was that the whatever it used to control the stream of electrons.
Scott: Magnets yes, I don't mean the cathode rays.
Rym: yes I don't know what kinds of magnets they were or how they were oriented But they were failing.
Rym: and the TV was this picture would bow in More and more as time went on like it was an hourglass and sometimes it would unbow.
Rym: sometimes It would do it doubly.
Rym: so hitting the TV seemed to affect this but not every time.
Scott: Sometimes you put other magnets near the TV to see if you could fix it.
Rym: Yeah, it was the worst when we were playing games because whenever something fast and bright happened It would just screw itself up and go crazy for a few seconds.
Scott: The TV was no good, but we were poor college students, and we lived with it.
Rym: Yeah We had an RF modulator that was then plugged into like the antenna thing on the back of it.
Rym: And then plugged into that were other things like the VCR and any many RF modulators in a row and RF switches.
Rym: We had so many things plugged into it that they formed an antenna And we could get all the local TV stations without having one.
Scott: yep.
Rym: So we eventually decided to get rid of the TV, so we bought a new TV with Scott's awesome Sony discount.
Scott: Whatever evil Sony we have an evil Sony TV.
Rym: Yeah, Sony makes okay TVs.
Scott: It was cheap.
Scott: It was a hundred bucks for a 27 inch Glass.
Scott: well CRT, but the glass is flat TV.
Rym: real nice TV.
Rym: all things considered it works for us.
Rym: Yep, so we TV.
Rym: so we stuck the old RCA in the closet, and we forgot about it A few days ago.
Rym: Well a week ago.
Rym: We decided all right.
Rym: Let's throw this thing away now.
Rym: where I grew up Garbage collection was municipal and no matter what you put on the curb they would take it away.
Rym: you could put a whole couch and a TV and like a refrigerator out there and Garbage day they just take it all.
Rym: it would all disappear.
Scott: That was not the case where I lived and I knew that you had to call a junk guy to take away the junk or Drive it to the dump yourself or illegally dump it.
Rym: now.
Rym: We weren't exactly sure where we live currently what to do, so I decided all right.
Rym: I knew I'll try something We'll take it out to the curb, and they didn't take it great.
Rym: so then we start trying to call dumps to get rid of this TV or Scrap people or whatever and no one can actually take the TV from us.
Scott: Well, I mean they can but they want to charge a lot of money, or they can't come to our house when we're home.
Rym: Yeah, what's the deal?
Rym: the first guy?
Rym: I called was like he wanted 50 bucks like whatever.
Rym: Can you just come and get rid of this thing and apparently he'll only come Monday through Thursday between noon and 4.
Scott: Nobody's.
Rym: oh, there is not a chance that anyone will ever be in our house on those times ever and wait.
Scott: Don't say that cuz someone might come and rob us.
Scott: not yet on Monday through Thursday between noon and 4.
Rym: Well, we got the security system And we got the old lady in the other house right like you know downstairs.
Scott: that might help.
Rym: But anyway not only that but the guy even suggested well Why don't you just take a day off work, and I said what for that?
Rym: I'm not gonna lose a half a day's pay, which is like 500 bucks and give you 50 bucks I'm just gonna dump it illegally.
Scott: for all that Exactly what's the fine for illegal dumping?
Scott: depending on I guess it depends where you dump it?
Rym: You know what the fine for illegal dumping is probably far less than the amount of money I'd lose by skipping a half a day of work.
Scott: You know what if we just kind of sneakily put it somewhere Like what if we go to a Best Buy and just kind of dump it in their dumpster?
Rym: why don't we just go to Best Buy and act like we want to return it and have some receipt and Make a big fuss like what do you mean?
Rym: We can't return it.
Rym: What do you mean?
Rym: blah fine?
Rym: Screw you guys and just walk out and leave it sitting on their desk.
Scott: or I get a better idea.
Scott: Let's bring it to like a Best Buy.
Scott: right and we'll just go around behind the Best Buy and just put it on the ground.
Rym: That is illegal.
Rym: They could get us.
Rym: a lot of people have TV Cameras watching their dumpsters and such.
Scott: we look around for cameras and we find there's got to be someplace around Or we can just kind of put it like at night and no one will know.
Rym: well we were gonna donate it to goodwill because it still works, but Goodwill is kind of far away and every time we decided to do it.
Rym: We didn't feel like hauling that thing down into Scott's car.
Scott: Yeah, I mean now it's been sitting outside.
Scott: I don't think it works anymore, but it might.
Scott: it's had water in it before I'm cure.
Rym: I'm kind of curious.
Rym: I kind of want to plug it in and see if it still works.
Scott: now It's all you cuz.
Scott: it might explode.
Rym: it might explode.
Rym: It's been.
Rym: it's been in like two rainstorms already.
Rym: Yeah Now currently I think the plan is we're gonna dump it in the dumpster of the plumber who lives next to us who seems Okay with us using his dumpster.
Scott: Yeah We'll see if they actually take the TV.
Rym: the moral is a Township or a town should never make it difficult to throw garbage away Because if it takes more money and effort to properly get rid of garbage then it would take to illegally dump it.
Rym: A lot of people less moral than us would probably just dump it in the woods and that would be the end of it.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I don't see a problem with having private waste disposal But waste disposal has to be cheaper than the fine for illegal dumping.
Scott: Yeah, I mean unless you know You don't care about you might as well not have illegal dumping if you make it hard to dump.
Scott: In fact, you should pay people to dump legally.
Scott: then no one would illegally dump ever.
Rym: Yeah, that's why I guess I really like the system where I grew up where they take everything that way.
Rym: I mean it cost the city more overall But because of economies of scale it costs less than if there are individual people doing it and as a result illegal dumping is not A problem at all except for like, you know toxic waste, but that's an industrial problem.
Scott: I blame NIMBYs for not wanting there to be more dumps.
Scott: You need to have dumps.
Scott: Everyone's got shit.
Scott: It's gotta be dumped somewhere.
Rym: The NIMBYs also fight against recycling plants.
Rym: Yeah, there should be dumps and recycling plants in every town or at least ways that make it easy to properly dispose of Garbage.
Scott: and you need a tire fire also Escalator to nowhere.
Rym: Yes Once again, this is the end of the GeekNights specials.
Rym: coming back next Monday The Monday after you listen to this normal GeekNights again, not only will the normal GeekNights But we will have such a wealth of Otakon content that it will blow your feeble minds.
Scott: They are feeble minds, aren't they?
Scott: I gotta say I mean you have to be listen to the show.
Rym: I wonder what our Monday show is gonna be like, I mean, we're going to be absolutely exhausted.
Rym: In addition, it's a tech day where we won't have really any easy excuse to talk about Otakon.
Rym: Nope, not at all.
Scott: It's gonna be awesome.
Rym: Plus I'm gonna need many hours to go over all of the Countless hours of recording we're going to do at Otakon all the interviews all the panel.
Scott: I thought on that Monday we decided we were just gonna play the recording of our panel.
Rym: true Well, I still have to see if we actually record it and then I have to do all of the post-production stuff to it to Make it listenable.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Yeah, we'll see next week.
Rym: We'll be back to normal.
Rym: Okay, you can don't get your all all your britches and a bunch out there about GeekNights.
Scott: We'll be back I'll be back But Rym he will die at Otakon.
Rym: I might you never know.
Rym: I know Great.
Rym: I know Okay, silly joke and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.