Rym: It's Monday January 2nd, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We talk about food, and we have a special guest.
Guest: Let's do this.
Rym: so happy new year Happy 2006. yep, we're back after our short slight hiatus, and we're tired as hell.
Rym: Yeah, we had a lot of people over for a crazy party all weekend And they're all still here, and we're upstairs locked in a bedroom doing the show.
Scott: well some of them are still here.
Rym: Yeah So we started off the new year with a brand new.
Rym: well You know the exploit that we talked about a couple shows ago the WMF.
Rym: in Windows It's an image file that if you display it or access it at all it can infect your computer with anything like full access.
Scott: no Matter what program you're using if you a picture can be displayed by that program And it displays a picture in this format and that picture has the bad stuff in it Then your computer will be screwed.
Rym: and well somebody made a worm.
Rym: That's exploiting this.
Scott: well there you go.
Scott: I found Windows exploit use.
Rym: it's an I am worm and it spreads through Microsoft Messenger right now, and I don't really need to get all the details.
Rym: But it's not so simple as it shows you the image.
Rym: it shows you a link to a JPEG image.
Rym: But the dot jpg is actually an HTML which links to the WMF which then gives you the virus Which is a collect credit card numbers and send them to someone randomly.
Scott: thing great Yeah, can't they just see where the credit cards are being sent to and catch the guy?
Rym: usually these things are sent to like anonymous Unmoderated IRC channels that then disappear on like shadow IP addresses.
Rym: Oh, that's not very good Yeah, but basically this vulnerability is not patched not easily patchable.
Rym: I mean a lot of people have said that there's a patch for it And that's kind of true.
Rym: some dude and like Gibson that security guy looked at it and said yeah, this is okay This isn't a bad patch.
Rym: they it mitigates the vulnerability it makes it less easy To be exploited, but there's really no way to do it because the vulnerabilities in a certain DLL file that all of Windows uses You under link that DLL which most people don't even know how to do Windows will likely not work.
Scott: Well, you'd have to modify the DLL, but of course it's part of Windows.
Scott: It's closed source.
Scott: No one knows what's in it.
Scott: Modifying it would mean disassembling it and it's pretty tricky.
Rym: Yeah, I mean there are decompilers and they exist.
Rym: But for anyone who doesn't code and doesn't know about this sort of thing Decompilers which take compiled code and like try to recreate the source code for it don't really work.
Scott: They don't work well at all.
Rym: They give you just this mess of useless garbage that if you run a decompiler and then you immediately try to recompile that code It usually just won't even work.
Scott: Hmm most of the time Yeah, I mean a lot of CS students will try to cheat with decompilers.
Scott: They'll be like aha the teacher has given us a working solution to the problem But we don't have any source code and the goal is to write source code.
Scott: that does the same thing.
Scott: The example program does.
Scott: they're like, I'm so smart.
Scott: I will decompile it and just copy the source code.
Scott: Well, there's a reason the teachers don't care about giving you the sample solution and trust me.
Scott: They're CS teachers.
Scott: They know about decompilers.
Scott: Yeah, you they really don't work so well, they won't help you.
Rym: I mean basically if you're a computer science student and you cheat to get a good grade if you cheat well enough to where you Didn't get caught by one of these CS professors you deserve to pass because you're smarter than they are.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if you manage to get a decompiler working even if it to the point where it's the best decompiling job That can possibly be done.
Scott: Let's say you set that up somehow, right?
Scott: And then you're still gonna have to do a lot to that decompiled code to make it something you can submit.
Scott: And if you can do that, then you could probably have done the assignment in the first place.
Rym: Well, you know the situation of a criminal who puts more effort into stealing money than it would take to just get a frickin.
Scott: Yeah Yep exactly that situation.
Rym: but we don't want to scare monger or you know.
Rym: Just really work this up and really not gonna talk about this exploit anymore because it's in the news.
Rym: You can see it.
Rym: We've talked about it twice already.
Rym: But watch out like seriously don't go to websites You don't trust and don't click on links if you don't know where they go or who sent them to you.
Rym: You know, this is a bad vulnerability and it will screw you.
Scott: I just don't get it.
Scott: Like this is the third or fourth time that we've said.
Scott: This is the last straw for Windows.
Scott: Here is a security hole that is easily exploited Difficult to protect from and it pretty much screws you over.
Scott: don't use Windows anymore.
Scott: It's your only hope only hope.
Rym: You'll be one.
Scott: Kenobi You know what?
Scott: People are still using windows and the camel's back has not yet been broken despite being smashed on with many sledgehammers.
Rym: well part of I mean Two factors here.
Rym: one is that people don't seem to realize how much this spyware and adware that they get infected with affects the performance of their computers.
Rym: I mean a clean Windows XP system with all the service packs with old XP without all the crazy patches preventing You know security else but even with all the patches, it's not that bad.
Rym: It's pretty stable and it's generally pretty good.
Rym: But most people have so much spyware on the machines and they don't realize it and that slows the computer down to the point that They think they need to buy a new one.
Rym: Yep, and to a lot of a lot of infection.
Rym: if an infective agents now They're they don't tell you that your computer is infected.
Rym: They don't do anything to you.
Rym: all they do is they spew garbage out of the network port and other people's computers or They hold where's files for other people to get later or they steal your credit card number?
Rym: which you wouldn't realize right away.
Scott: and people complain about a lot of things like ads and You know spam and all that sort of stuff going on.
Scott: But most of that is because your computer isn't secure.
Scott: if your computer is secure and set up properly Ads and spam really don't happen.
Scott: You know, most spam comes from people whose computers who were all infected.
Scott: That's where the spam comes from.
Scott: It's you you're sending the spam, but you don't know it.
Rym: There was a guy at work at my work who doesn't read slashdot and he said he didn't read it because of the ads.
Rym: and I said what those are like the most unobtrusive ads ever and if you really wanted you could block them.
Rym: and and I and he was like unobtrusive their pop-ups and pop-unders and they pop all over the place.
Rym: and At this point I was like what slashdot doesn't have pop-ups.
Scott: It never will and never did.
Rym: it never will.
Rym: even if slashdot turned evil They wouldn't use pop-ups because they're not stupid.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So I look at his computer and he's got just like pop-up spyware and apparently it was just randomly It happened to pop up a lot of the ads when slashdot was open and he assumed that slashdot was the cause.
Rym: Mm-hmm Yeah, I couldn't even fix it because ad aware is not free to corporations and this is work computer and You can use Microsoft anti spyware, but it's none of the spyware.
Scott: things are complete enough.
Scott: There's no way to 100% protect yourself and it's just not worth the effort of protecting.
Rym: So I guess if you need a New Year's resolution and you're a computer guy at all or computer girl If
Scott: you use your computer more than once a day
Rym: Try to learn Linux get an Ubuntu CD or a Linux any sort of Linux live CD and just play with it.
Rym: Because within a few years you might need to move off of Windows if things get bad enough.
Scott: Yeah, you might just.
Scott: you know, if you depend on your computer for your business or especially for your business But for your entertainment or for anything Then you know Windows just might not cut it in a few years.
Scott: if Vista, you know It's all DRM like they say it's gonna be in such now.
Rym: We're not trying to be Linux L. It's like oh use Linux open source.
Scott: We can get an apple if you got mad money.
Rym: Yeah, I get an apple.
Rym: apples are fantastic.
Rym: We're thinking about buying one to do this show.
Rym: Yeah But this is just it's good advice from us to you You really knowing Linux in the over the course of the next couple decades is going to be a very useful skill in the world.
Rym: And even if you don't think it will be you'd be surprised.
Scott: Yeah, even if you're not even a computer guy or anything if you're just you know, some normal person You know, this is a nerdy thing that is gonna come and affect you, you know A lot of people are like, you know They're in some profession and they say oh the things in my profession affect other people and they don't even know it.
Scott: and then You walk around seeing other people getting screwed by that thing.
Scott: You know, like if you're a florist and you see people buying bad flowers, you know, like man, you should really know this You wouldn't buy bad flowers.
Scott: It's affecting you in a bad way.
Scott: You know florist doesn't know about computers but you know if other people bought better flowers that would make the florist happy and it would make the people a lot more happier.
Scott: because You know, they just don't know.
Scott: this is the thing that you should know.
Scott: they can help you out.
Scott: So in Japan they have these hotels I think are really cool.
Scott: They're called the capsule hotels and basically it's like this tube like a tube just big enough for a person to fit in.
Rym: They're actually a little bigger that you can kind of sit off.
Scott: if you're not you can kind of sit up.
Scott: It's not really just that small.
Scott: It's not like a coffin.
Scott: No, it's a little bigger than that, but it's not big at all.
Scott: I mean they stack these things up vertically and horizontally and everything and it's pretty much a cheap hotel.
Scott: So if you're one person on a business trip and you want to save money You know you pay a very small fee and you get a bed and like a little TV next to your head for the night and it's very Practical and efficient.
Rym: Yep, and usually in the building or next door There's a bunch of public showers and things so you can shave and shower and do all that stuff before you go to sleep.
Scott: Yep not like these American hotels where you have like all this space and you have to pay huge amounts of money and go through a Whole ordeal and you get furniture you don't use and all this kind of stuff like, you know The kind of space you would need if you were staying for weeks and weeks and weeks, you know Some people do need but most people will stay in hotels for maybe like a weekend and you don't really need all that stuff you know, there's no point to it, so someone is finally taking this idea out of Japan and into London and They're calling it.
Scott: Well the company I think they're calling it Yotel Y-o-t-e-l.
Rym: Yep, Slashdot called them coffin hotels.
Scott: Yeah, it's not quite coffin sized.
Scott: It's actually bigger than the Japanese hotels.
Scott: They're 10 meters by 10 meters squared in floor space and the ceiling is actually as high as you know.
Scott: A normal ceiling is.
Rym: they're about the size of you ever lived in the on the East Coast on like the Jersey Shore.
Rym: There used to be all these like maybe 10 years ago.
Rym: There used to be all these little like tiny beach houses like on the beach and in Britain London They have these things a lot there not in London But in Britain these tiny little beach houses and they're just big enough for like one person to crash on the floor on a little And change into a swimsuit,
Scott: yep, well these hotels are 10 feet 10 meters squared.
Scott: they come with the sofa that turns into a bed, you know, it's a couch bed couch bed and It doesn't really have a real television, you know, but what it does come with is a sofa.
Scott: I already said that Desk that you pull down.
Scott: So it's like you pull it out of the wall and you can put something on it.
Scott: Closet space very small amount of closet space.
Scott: Some mood lighting which is always cool, you know.
Scott: a shower very useful Wireless internet the most useful an iPod connection so you can plug your iPod into the hotel room and the sound comes out of the Speakers in the hotel room and there's a flat-screen TV, which saves a lot of space.
Scott: And you know these things are gonna put them in airports and all kinds of other places where hotels are used very often.
Rym: But they're also places like that.
Rym: those hotels are used very often, but they're used for like one night usually.
Scott: Yep, if you stay in an airport hotel, that's because your flight got canceled and you're stuck there or it could be because you came on a trip and You know, you have to make a transfer the next day - that's international.
Rym: Yeah So why do you want to pay 300 bucks for a huge hotel room that you're gonna be in for like a few hours while?
Rym: You're asleep.
Scott: You're only gonna use like the bed the shower and maybe the TV.
Scott: You don't it means here.
Scott: has anyone here ever actually used the the the nightstand Anything other than the telephone and the clock and once once I unpacked my clothes into the dresser of a hotel.
Rym: Wow, but I stayed in the same hotel room for a week a week.
Scott: I can understand a week.
Scott: Yeah But anyway, they say it's gonna cost about 70 bucks a night, which is real cheap.
Rym: yeah, I mean we go to Baltimore every year for that Otakon and The cheapest cheapest hotel rooms are over $100 a night and usually we spend about 300 a night.
Scott: and they say you can also Book it for four hour periods Which is real useful if you have like a transfer or you want to just take a little nap before your flight or you got To the airport way early and breeze through security, you know, you can go take a nap there
Rym: Yep, or you're on the road.
Rym: You want to take a shower?
Scott: Yep Now it's not quite, you know The perfect thing that I've been looking for which is even smaller and in New York City Which.
Scott: but this could if it succeeds in Britain come over which would make me very happy.
Scott: Yes I mean, there's nothing I need more in New York City than a place where I can just either crash for the night for like a hundred bucks or Spend 20 bucks take a shower, you know and shave and change my clothes.
Scott: Yeah, that would be so freaking.
Rym: you like say you woke up late for work.
Rym: It'd be so much better to go to go on the same normal train.
Rym: You always go on and then get to the city and then like shave and shower and everything there and then go into the building.
Scott: Yep, I mean and think about this, let's say I go to work for the day, right?
Scott: I'm wearing my work clothes, but after work, I want to go hang out with some people.
Scott: so I spend 20 bucks.
Scott: I could take a shower to get my work off of me.
Scott: You know, I can change into fun clothes and get off the work clothes.
Scott: I can put all my stuff in a locker that I rent out, you know, and I'm good to go.
Scott: Maybe I'll take a little nap if the.
Scott: if I'm going to like a concert that's later at night or maybe a hockey game or Something, you know, who knows?
Rym: Yes, I'd love something like that.
Scott: But as it stands if I wanted to go to a concert or a hockey game after work I have to carry a backpack to said hockey game or concert or event or meeting or whatever You know and I got to change my work clothes in the work bathroom and I'll be all stinky from work You know and it's just a pain in the ass.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So if any venture capitalists are out there listening to the show Either give us some money and we'll do it or give someone who wants to do this money so we can use it.
Scott: Yeah, then, you know, we've got life great and it's glad.
Rym: it's good to see that The idea is finally spreading and actually I'm glad that it's starting somewhere like London because this is kind of a stereotype.
Rym: But I I get this impression that a lot of foreigners as opposed to Americans would be more open to at least trying something like this Mm-hmm.
Rym: So if it succeeds in Britain because people might try and go oh, this is cool.
Rym: And then it comes over here then they can say yeah people in London use this and it's great instead of our at America.
Rym: Here's this weird thing that is kind of weird to you guys.
Rym: What do you think?
Scott: Yep.
Scott: All right, you know 3d realms They were that game developer publisher back in the DOS days that you saw in every freaking game.
Scott: Yep They're still around or no, they're technically still around making that, you know, Duke Nukem forever game.
Scott: Yet so on their website which still exists and I guess is still updated because they did make that max pain game sort of Recently that game was kind of good.
Scott: I never played it but anyway They have a download page.
Scott: and why would just a download page and some game developers website be so exciting?
Scott: Well, this download page has everything.
Rym: what do you mean?
Rym: everything everything this company ever did.
Scott: well Anything even remotely related to this company.
Scott: They've got mp3s from games.
Scott: They've got videos of like game commercials.
Scott: They've got every share where demo and patch for every one of their games hot shit.
Scott: They've got DOS box and assorted DOS tools to make things like networking work.
Scott: They even got a video of an interview with some of their developers.
Scott: Now if you don't think that's so cool, let me remind you of some of the great games made by this company all of the Duke Nukem games ever Raptor call the shadow.
Scott: That was my favorite shmup ever Terminal velocity, which is the 3d shmup.
Scott: That was awesome.
Scott: every commander keen.
Scott: Crystal caves Rise of a crystal caves crystal caves.
Scott: All right.
Rym: What was it?
Scott: I don't really remember.
Scott: I just remember I liked it.
Rym: Then why'd you even bring it up?
Scott: because I remember that those words crystal caves and associated them with good game great Rise of the triad which was like the awesome first person shooter where you had like the hand of God and like a dog's head for a hand and Other weird stuff and you could go up and down.
Scott: That was the big deal on that one Wolfenstein 3d.
Scott: Ah, yes, Wolfenstein All the early ID software ID software was under 3d realms.
Scott: somehow I don't remember the exact legal whatever's huh?
Rym: Cuz I really didn't know that.
Scott: Yeah, but there are also many many many others here and I would say of any download site in any page ever This is the most useful one.
Rym: Luckily.
Rym: We don't have enough listeners yet to wang or slashdot or Farki.
Scott: No No, they've already.
Scott: they were wang recently and they're still good.
Rym: Oh, really?
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Damn.
Scott: They're fine.
Rym: So my thing I really like sushi and that sort of like Japanese food and we're doing our show today about food Just for no reason we couldn't come up with anything better.
Scott: Where's the geniuses?
Rym: Yeah, and Basically, this is an instructional video on Japanese etiquette when it comes to eating sushi.
Rym: Now if you watch it It's gonna look dead serious and it'll act like it's actually telling you how to eat sushi And I will give anyone money if they actually follow these instructions in a sushi.
Rym: Ah There's just watch the video.
Rym: That's all I can really say about this.
Scott: There seem to be a lot of funny things lately where they try to make something serious, but actually it's silly.
Rym: Well like that German forkless video.
Scott: Yeah, it's.
Scott: it's a really good humor thing lately that trend of funniness.
Rym: So anyway things the day aside it is food day and we're going to talk about food and the food we like and We like lots of food.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think there's anyone who doesn't like eating Oh wait anorexic food.
Rym: So we've got a special guest today and he is an expert on food.
Rym: his name is art boy aka Adam.
Guest: Okay, so so my name is art boy, and I'm an expert on food.
Scott: Arting food.
Guest: right you draw balls of fruit troubles of fruit But yeah, um, so we had some good food today though, yeah, we want to.
Rym: We've got that saw up the street and we've mentioned it a couple times.
Scott: we only go there, you know every week.
Rym: Yeah, we eat there so often we walk in and the waitresses are like, oh, it's them.
Rym: You have ouchie, right?
Rym: We're like no sushi today and they're like, oh You bring friends Yep Cuz.
Scott: usually what happens is when we go without friends we sit at the sushi area and we go with a bunch of people.
Scott: It's like hibachi.
Scott: So they kind of figured it out.
Scott: They look at how many people we've got and they're like, uh, and then we're like, no no no For for those uneducated and if you're not educated you should be about this.
Guest: but how?
Guest: bocce is basically like a big table.
Guest: that's also a oven and everybody sits around the table and a Chef is there.
Guest: they do all kinds of cool things with the food like They spin eggs on on their little spatulas and they throw food around and they cook it and they serve it to you right there And it's really hot and good.
Guest: So it's like half show and half restaurant and they make lots of fire.
Scott: Yeah everyone likes fire.
Rym: Only sad thing about is we do it so often that like I'm not impressed by it anymore at all.
Scott: Yeah I have.
Scott: I'd have to go around like Finding different hibachi.
Scott: guys have different things.
Guest: they do like some guy like cuts an egg open like burns it on fire lights his hands On fire does like a thing with it and you're like, yeah, yes Last time I was here impressed me man, like light someone here on fire.
Guest: Let's see you do that smart guy.
Scott: Yeah, they really you know, but it's weird because the guy like knows us.
Scott: It's like we went in with a new person and he's like, oh you're the new person.
Scott: I will do special attention to you.
Guest: Yeah, but the real reason that these two guys brought me in here was partially because I'm their friend and partially Okay, they left the front parts like oh, yeah, we're friends, huh, right?
Guest: No, they wanted me to tell a story about Eating in Japan because I had spent some time in Japan one summer and it was lots of fun.
Guest: And if you're ever a chance to study abroad do it because it's it's pretty fun.
Guest: But there's this place called a yaki Yaki, Niku, which literally means cooked meat and the way it's set up is you pay by the hour.
Guest: So like let's say you're gonna go eat with a bunch of friends for like an hour and a half.
Guest: It's like 15 bucks and you can eat all you want for an hour and a half.
Guest: and there's a little conveyor belt that goes around All the tables and it's like comes out in an island in the middle of the restaurant.
Rym: Well, I didn't think places like that actually existed.
Guest: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, just not here because I mean here, you know You have like filthy children who like The place is like a square or a circle and everyone sits around and all the food is in the middle.
Guest: Yeah it's a think of like a w-shape and the food goes around.
Guest: this w-shape like around the side and then around the middle and then Around the side then goes back into the kitchen where we don't know what happens.
Scott: I got it.
Rym: So if any of you venture capitalists from the previous segment are listening give us money for that too.
Scott: Yes, sir Yeah, we'll make one of those with the hotel attached and have a LAN party inside.
Guest: But so and the food comes out.
Guest: it's usually like frozen like so like when the beat when the meat starts coming around.
Guest: It's like these frozen like slices.
Scott: So you don't want to sit at the beginning.
Guest: What's that?
Scott: You see don't want to sit at the beginning part?
Guest: Well, I mean Even if the food goes around it's it's it's supposed to be frozen.
Guest: So it keeps cold until you cook it.
Guest: Because what you do is you take it off and you put it in this little burner grill that's in the middle And you cook it there like this suction that sucks the smoke off of there.
Guest: So you're not like filling the entire place with smoke.
Guest: now something to understand is that in Japan beef is really expensive Like you don't find $20 steaks you find like a 30 or 40 dollar steak in his like hamburger meat.
Guest: it's like it's ninja food like the ninja food story - if you want.
Guest: but So this foods going around and we're Americans going to the Japanese place and we're like, oh, yeah It's just it's just beef.
Guest: we cook it we eat it.
Guest: So we sit down and we didn't know also at the time that They don't clear your plates as you're eating because all the food comes around these little like the five inch in in radius dishes.
Guest: so they're going around and we're taking food and we're eating and we're taking food and reading and These plates start piling up at the table and they're piling up and they're piling up and the waiters are sort of looking at us.
Guest: funny Because you know, they've never seen like an American person like ever I guess.
Guest: And and you know the plates are piling up and we see them talking to each other and one of one of the guys there spoke a lot of Japanese because he was like advanced and he was like they're asking each Other whether or not they should clear our plates and I was like, oh my gosh, what's why are they doing that?
Guest: We found out later that they don't clear the plates until after you leave.
Guest: like did the help and you don't see them?
Guest: So eventually they like they're like chuckling at us and laughing and they're taking away the plates and we were there for like the full hour and a half.
Guest: But when you put four Americans with small amounts of beef in front of a grill and just have them eat There's never like a filling because you're digesting as you're eating.
Guest: so these.
Guest: we ate something like 132 between four guys.
Guest: Wow 32 plates of food.
Guest: I think you'll imagine this place being like, oh, we just lost so much money.
Guest: Oh, no So, you know and we're eating like desserts everything we walk out of there and as soon as we leave These guys are like laughing their asses off and pointing at us as we leave like we're like, wow, that was cool We gotta go back next time.
Scott: No, you know what?
Scott: They were laughing at.
Scott: was the guys in the back on the other end of the conveyor?
Guest: That's something else we notice is that the meat started out like soft and as we were there the meat started getting like more and more Frozen.
Guest: so we figure the guys in the back are going.
Guest: Oh my god, what's happening to all the meat?
Guest: Shave some more meat off put it on the thing And you know last we went back again like three days later with like eight people.
Guest: the same thing happened Except we like 400 plates of food Like all right, no more guide you.
Guest: yeah, seriously They're like sorry you guys can't say this long anymore because we're losing tons of money on you for eating our really expensive beef.
Scott: I mean, I've heard of business mails file Failing against new technology, but business mails failing against new nationalities.
Guest: They didn't count on the American.
Guest: It was like it was, you know, you think barbecue you eat at a barbecue, you know You keep on grazing you go around.
Guest: So this is like instead of the grazing the food just kept coming to us and we're like hey more beef thrown on the Barbie.
Rym: I can feel like the moment you guys sit down the beef just stops coming back around.
Guest: It's like all vegetables.
Guest: It's like damn Yeah, they found us out.
Guest: The ninja food was kind of was kind of amusing.
Guest: do like if you go to Japan ever or any other country that doesn't have Like native food like a lot of people think like American Italian restaurants are like Italian food.
Scott: Not at all They're wrong.
Guest: You know.
Guest: the same thing happens in Japan.
Guest: if you go to Japan like the only American food you're gonna get Or even anything close is gonna be like McDonald's and that's not really American food.
Guest: That's like just.
Rym: It's not food.
Guest: It's not food.
Scott: It's not food to begin with but it's like pretend American foods.
Guest: it's it's meat flavored food type product.
Guest: and We Went to this Italian restaurant because they were like, oh we want some Italian food.
Guest: So the Japanese were like, okay We'll go to the Italian restaurant.
Guest: What we didn't count on was the ninja food.
Guest: see ninja food is food.
Guest: That is Japanese food trying to be other food.
Guest: So like I ordered I think like spaghetti and something like that spaghetti meatballs.
Guest: And it was like obviously chopped up bits of hamburger with like soba noodles and really really thin like tomato sauce.
Guest: So it was like.
Guest: I was like this isn't?
Guest: this isn't Italian food?
Guest: somebody ordered like lasagna and it was like Like big pieces of like.
Guest: it was like drunken noodles with like tomato sauce and some meat in there and we're like, what is this?
Guest: And they and they of course they jacked up the price too.
Guest: Like, you know like here you can get ramen for like at a nice restaurant.
Guest: It'll cost you like five bucks in Japan will be like a buck fifty Like the equivalent.
Guest: they're like Italian food was like 30 bucks for like a pile of like fake Italian food.
Guest: That was Japanese food.
Scott: Wow, what do people actually eat that and like it though?
Rym: or Food is good food.
Guest: They have the.
Guest: they have like you freaking, you know, seafood like shrimp and seaweed pizza there.
Guest: So I guess it's got to be selling or something.
Guest: I mean it must the horrible things they do to pizza there.
Rym: Good God, no even here I mean our friend Pete is.
Rym: he really knows the Italian food Well, and he's always like at all.
Rym: the Italian food here is crap Mm-hmm.
Guest: Yeah, my sister said she got.
Guest: my sister got back from Italy and she was like, I'm never eating any Italian food ever again.
Guest: No, not gonna happen.
Scott: It's really how it is is like.
Scott: You know.
Scott: all the food you eat in any particular country is you know or 90% of it Anyway is food of that country and if they say it's food of a different country It's just pretending to be that of the country.
Guest: Yeah, that's why I like like the Japanese snacks.
Guest: Japanese snacks are awesome.
Guest: Wherever you go.
Guest: It's always Japanese.
Rym: Yeah, I've got a. I just bought a big thing of those wasabi peas.
Rym: Oh, those are like the best thing in the world.
Rym: Oh, yes Sorry, I mean I assume people who listen to GeekNights know what wasabi is but it's this wonderful green substance.
Rym: It's like a mash and it tastes like mint and I recommend you eat a bowl of it No once.
Guest: yeah, real men can eat a whole bowl without even flinching.
Guest: Yeah, actually it tastes like burning Like, you know those firecrackers those those mentally retarded guys ate.
Rym: Oh god, I saw that on far.
Rym: What really wasn't a joke.
Guest: Yeah There was something like some story on FARC about like in was a Beijing or something like that during the New Year or something.
Guest: It was some Asian country and it was like during the New Year's like two guys died because they ate firecrackers.
Scott: Well, it's what did the firecrackers say on them like food?
Rym: You know what if there's a fuse coming out of your food, don't?
Guest: If there's a fuse coming out there's something else up.
Scott: did they light him first and then eat him.
Guest: I have no idea.
Guest: I didn't read the whole story.
Guest: I was like, I was just.
Guest: you know, you read FARC half the time.
Guest: We don't need to read this exploding.
Scott: Yeah, labor drtf.
Guest: I think it is.
Rym: in fact if you read the story a lot of times it ruins it because the headlines funny and then you read The story is like wow.
Rym: That was a horrible thing that happened to whoever that was Emphasis on was or that was boring.
Guest: That wasn't at all what the the article was.
Scott: Yeah I hate it when headlines are misleading.
Rym: that just pisses me off all the time except the fake headlines on FARC the ones that are there just to trick news anchors and Morning radio news guys who like to just read FARC for the living.
Guest: Those are the disappointing I know.
Guest: just also like on my local wacky radio Wacky DJ radio show like back in Maryland where I used to live You just have Elliot in the morning and they they would always get all these funny news stories.
Guest: I was like, aha funny news stories and then I was like, wait a minute.
Scott: He's reading FARC.
Guest: It's all just awful fun.
Rym: Yeah, every now and then FARC will put like a fake story and then in the comments It'll be like alright the story is fake or This?
Rym: we just made this up or we link to a parody site.
Rym: We know it's fake and then it's just kind of a game to see how many news people reported as truth.
Guest: Mm-hmm.
Scott: It's always good and then they'll be like, you know W whatnot reported.
Scott: This is true.
Scott: Okay, something something something said.
Scott: this is cool.
Scott: This morning radio guy reads FARC, so does this one.
Rym: They all know we read FARC and we're not on the radio, but unless we get some pirate radio going at some point.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think pirate radio is necessary.
Guest: when you have podcast that calls for an mp3 that we need the pirate radio mp3.
Scott: now It's anyway food.
Guest: Yeah, one of the interesting food stories of how we run across recently.
Scott: Well, I don't know.
Scott: We've had a lot of food trouble lately trying to you know, have a party.
Rym: Yeah, we've learned that like we said previously.
Rym: Yes, our friends can eat all the food we have.
Scott: Yeah, I mean we never really we've had parties before but we never really provided food because we were poor and It wasn't so many people.
Rym: for an extended period of time People would come and go and they'd walk like they bring their own food or we'd like go to someone else's apartment raid their Fridge and then leave.
Scott: Yeah, but now you're expecting to have dinner from anywhere between like 10 and 30 people.
Rym: Yeah, because a half of our friends are cool and we're like, yeah We're coming to your party and half of her friends just disappeared off the internet for the two weeks before.
Scott: Yeah, I mean keep your communications up, especially if you want free food.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Yeah, cuz we had free food We got actual catering and it came and we ate it.
Scott: But anyway, we had.
Scott: we had no idea how much to get.
Scott: so we pretty much just did a crapshoot saying well We'll learn this time and get it right the next time.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, no one said I'm hungry after we ate.
Guest: there's no plenty left downstairs.
Scott: We just called the pizza guys and we said bring two trays of this and a tray of garlic knots and all those garlic knots.
Rym: Yeah, we should have gotten twice as many of those.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know why we got so I didn't realize there were a lot Of garlic knots and I opened it up and I said that'll be gone.
Guest: I had like one and there was like a whole plate of so someone was like scarfing someone.
Scott: I had three or four So we're like there were like 50 in there.
Guest: Somebody just just jacked like a whole bunch of them once.
Scott: it must have been.
Scott: But I didn't eat the the chicken.
Scott: I only ate the noodles, which is very very good.
Rym: Yeah, the chicken Marsala was okay, but a lot of people like did like mushrooms and wouldn't eat it.
Guest: I dug the mushroom.
Guest: I definitely dug the ziti when I dug the Marsala.
Guest: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, we'll learn next time.
Scott: We won't get the chicken Marsala again, especially because it made a big mess.
Guest: Yeah, I have I have.
Guest: I have serious concerns about any food that is so much slathered in sauce that it is its own soup.
Guest: Yeah, it's like.
Guest: yeah I want to eat the chicken But I got to find it like I got to dig around in there first under the brown to find where the chicken is.
Rym: The one issue that we had and we didn't realize we had it until right before we ordered the food Was that one of our friends and only one is a vegetarian?
Rym: So we planned out all the food and then we looked and we're like, wait a minute.
Rym: every single piece of food We're providing has meat in it somewhere.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Like alright crap.
Rym: What are we gonna do?
Rym: and we're the most places who provide food like catering food don't seem to have vegetarian food.
Rym: That doesn't suck.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, at least the problem is is that we can't really ask.
Rym: At the party I made that salad in a pair of boxers like earlier in the day.
Guest: Wow Yeah, I've never.
Guest: I've never had salad that has been mixed inside of boxers before.
Guest: I'm glad I didn't eat it.
Scott: Well, the thing is that you know, we as meat-eating people look at vegetarian food and go that's not good.
Scott: But then the vegetarian people might think differently, but we can't really order for them.
Guest: Oh, well, oh speaking of vegetarian food I told this story earlier today, but I should probably tell it again.
Guest: an old roommate of mine Was was dating a girl who was a vegetarian and this is in college.
Guest: so I had three roommates at the time and one of them was dating a girl who was vegetarian and one of them was very Considerate and decided that she was going to make dinner for everyone when she when this girl came over and she was going to make vegetarian vegan lasagna.
Scott: and Well, I'm not sure if anybody knows I mean I think important ingredient in lasagna is meat.
Guest: Yeah, so, you know an important ingredient in everything that is vegan and not including meat is usually soy Or tofu or some other soy based product.
Rym: So unless you're a Neville level 9 vegan a level 9 vegan that's a militant vegan.
Rym: No, you're only allowed to eat things that don't cast a shadow.
Guest: So anyhow, she decided that tofu would make a good replacement for the ricotta cheese in lasagna and That it's wrong with cheese.
Guest: I don't know.
Scott: It's from a. So you can't do that.
Guest: vegans are like, oh no, you're stealing from it's from vitamin D from Vegetarian.
Rym: is I don't eat animals vegan is I don't eat animals or things that come from animals?
Scott: Well, I thought it was just they didn't eat like eggs and things.
Guest: Yeah eggs come from animals milk come from man.
Scott: I mean, I know vegetarians who do eat eggs, you know, but Vegan was just not egg.
Scott: I didn't think it was not milk.
Rym: Either vegan is a step more militant and a step more restrictive.
Guest: Yeah, I got I got sworn it by a vegan once and I was like screw you heavy.
Guest: I'm higher for the food chain Got a job.
Guest: But so she makes this this thing and one of the properties of tofu and this is sort of like little known is that it will absorb the flavor and odor of anything that it is cooked with.
Rym: and so Hmm.
Scott: Yeah, so I like about tofu is that it doesn't really taste like much except for the flavor you put into it.
Scott: Yeah, so you just want to you have a sauce that you really like and you just want to eat it straight.
Scott: I just pour it right on there.
Guest: You know, you could like make spaghetti with meat sauce.
Guest: Yeah, instead of meat just throw in some like, you know Maybe meat flavoring of some sort and then throw in some tofu and hey, you got like fake meatballs.
Scott: Yeah, you can.
Scott: I love it when you just want to eat teriyaki for dinner.
Scott: You just know tofu little teriyaki.
Guest: So anyhow, she decides to cook the this this ricotta Not ricotta tofu with broccoli mix and I'm not sure if anybody here has ever smelled like steaming broccoli.
Guest: But go ahead and do it sometime and but it smells.
Guest: nothing like broccoli.
Guest: taste it smells.
Rym: I don't even know what it smells like the things that aren't in the broccoli when you eat it.
Rym: That does not smell good.
Scott: There must be some chemical in the broccoli that breaks down when you heat it and it evaporate comes out In the air.
Guest: Yes, I agree.
Guest: I think I think it pretty much smells like ass like like ass and old socks Like that have been up and ass smells like sweat and dead haws Something like that.
Guest: So yeah, so the tofu.
Guest: she makes this whole dish right.
Guest: then I'm like, I'm gonna be like the anime hero I'm gonna go and you know, I think it's gonna taste bad, but I'm gonna eat it and I'll swallow it down and I'll be whole and she'll think I'm a nice guy.
Guest: and I wasn't trying to like Mack on her or Anything was just trying to be a nice guy, right?
Rym: You weren't trying to Mack on her a god.
Guest: No We won't go into that.
Guest: That's that's for another show.
Guest: But uh, so she makes this stuff and she serves it and you know She serves me first and then she serves, you know my my other roommate and his girlfriend who's the vegan and she serves herself and I go and take a bite out of it and I cannot explain how bad this tasted.
Guest: I mean the tofu had absorbed the smell and converted it into taste.
Guest: so you had.
Guest: you had semi tasteless broccoli with ass flavored tofu and Like some red sauce between like coot noodles and stuff.
Guest: So I take a bite and I'm like, I'm like I'll just I'll.
Guest: just took it down took it down I tried to swallow it now just like put like right back on the plate and she looked at me like horrified.
Guest: She was like, what'd you do that for?
Guest: I was like, I'm sorry, but just just try it please and I won't feel so bad.
Guest: And I went.
Guest: I was like, I'm sorry.
Guest: I have to do this.
Guest: Don't just scraping it off into the garbage.
Guest: She was like, it can't possibly be that bad.
Guest: I said just just try it and she tries it.
Guest: This is the girl who cooked it and she goes.
Guest: Oh Right back on the plate.
Guest: And so naturally, you know the other two people are like no they got to be screwing with us.
Guest: It can't possibly be that bad.
Rym: So naturally So pizza was There's just like when you see someone they eat something there and they make a bad face like oh god.
Rym: and then they like want Some.
Guest: That's a guy thing.
Guest: It's like this tastes awful.
Guest: It tastes like ass.
Guest: try some.
Scott: I'm always worried about like spitting out food because there's only two times I spit out food or like if You know There's something in my mouth and I'm coughing and I'm gonna time lick or something or if like I can't chew it Like.
Scott: that happens a lot where this food is just tough and I can't chew it enough to the point where I can swallow it Even if it tastes good.
Scott: Yeah, like half the stir-fry we try to make yeah And then I'm just trying to find a way to spit it out like nicely.
Rym: You know what the best technique is because I can actually get a good nap in on mouth.
Scott: is that my mouth.
Rym: you dab the Mouth and you go put and then you just kind of put the napkin aside kind of crumpled So you can't see the giant wad of food.
Guest: Yeah, I do the five-year-old thing.
Guest: We just sort of go like bridal and you just lay it right there on the plate Someone else's house.
Rym: You spit under the table.
Guest: They won't notice Only if they have animals pets or something.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: just pile your Calvin and Hobbes.
Guest: Have you ever had meat gum?
Rym: Wait meat gum.
Guest: This is this is not meat flavored gum.
Guest: This is a term I came up with that was to my mom had made a veal Feels good veal or pork chops or something and had made it Poorly, yeah, I distinctly remember walking around the house chewing and not being able to like break it down in my mouth.
Guest: And I said mom you made meat gum And I'm not sure if that had any effect on her, but she never made it after that.
Guest: Mom, I'm sorry if I if I killed your your your cooking in the veal area.
Rym: We have a serious problem with our stir-fry and basically meat gums.
Rym: we now have a word for it.
Scott: I don't know my stir-fry doesn't end up as meat gum But it's not much.
Scott: doesn't taste anything like stir-fry.
Scott: I get it real places of awesome.
Rym: We've watched professional chefs do stir-fry and we try to do like we do make the exact same motions and not the same thing comes Out.
Scott: I just don't know what it is.
Guest: It's it's you've probably done the British thing and just cook the flavor right out of the food.
Rym: Yeah, but if I don't cook it that much then it's like uncooked chicken.
Rym: Yeah It pretty much goes from raw to black in one second.
Scott: Wow, I think it's just a large part of it is because we have an electric oven and yeah every stir-fry guy I've ever seen do something well had some sort of fire.
Rym: Yeah, actually the Culinary Institute people who do the all the cooking in my cafeteria at work They use.
Rym: it's an electric But it's that cool ceramic electric.
Rym: where it's like ceramic pad and then the whole thing heats up at once.
Guest: No words like down in the oven.
Rym: Oh, no, it's up.
Rym: It's just like a pad that ceramic and it gets hot.
Rym: Oh, I'm not sure what the mechanism is for getting hot.
Guest: Probably electricity.
Rym: Yeah, something like that.
Scott: No a little a little like hamsters on fire That's ceramic is very good because I reheated up a lot without it breaking or melting or anything.
Rym: Yeah, hence, you know the ceramic tiles a lot a lot better than metal.
Guest: Okay, metal spaceships over.
Guest: well except dolomite God does that count as inside?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Futurama is one reference to dolomite.
Guest: I said I I was trying to explain He the Hebrew hammer to somebody and I said, oh god the Hebrew ham.
Guest: I was trying to explain it as juice playtation to a co-worker who was black and I was like It's just like a blacks playtation only its juice playtation.
Guest: and he was like, what's blacks playtation?
Scott: I'm gonna admit something so everyone can laugh.
Scott: I have no clue what dolomite is.
Guest: Okay Well, I could see not knowing what dolomite, you know blacks playtation is though, right?
Scott: Of course I'm a huge fan of blacks.
Rym: Well, then you should see dolomite.
Rym: He's one.
Scott: Oh, it's a movie called dolomite.
Scott: That is a blaxploitation film.
Rym: I don't know the movies called dolomite, but there's a character named dolomite.
Guest: Yeah, I think I think there is actually a movie called dolomite in which the character is Dolomite.
Rym: Yeah, and in Futurama they make a reference to dolomite at some point.
Guest: Yeah, geeks know we're talking about.
Rym: Yeah.
Guest: Yeah, if you're not a geek should be listening anyhow.
Rym: Three comments in the forums like yeah, it's seasoned blah blah blah in the last four minutes.
Scott: I'm a dolomite calm and it is quite awesome.
Guest: Another thing of the day I feel bad.
Guest: I feel like I should have a thing of the day, but I had nothing.
Guest: Rym took mine that I sent him.
Rym: Yeah, that sushi thing was given to me by Adam and it was given to him by his girlfriend Mike and you know what?
Rym: It's mine.
Rym: now bitches Beyonce.
Guest: gotta get that right?
Guest: She's looking at you angry.
Rym: Yeah, I see her there.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: She can't talk cuz we're on the air live Now she's trying to gesture to me and I can't tell what she's trying to tell me to say.
Rym: Now she's acting like she's eating something.
Guest: She's saying either eat me or bite me.
Rym: one of the two I don't know, but now she's giving up.
Scott: So in a reverse non sequitur when you're searching for dolomite reverse Don't type in do lo mit.
Scott: that's that's the name of a mineral discovered by some French mineralogist.
Scott: It's sedimentary search for dolomite like do le like Bob Dole.
Rym: is.
Rym: what about ammo night?
Scott: Yeah, I don't think so.
Scott: I'm definitely checking this movie out though.
Guest: What don't?
Guest: yeah check out here hammer, dude.
Guest: That's a cool one.
Guest: Yeah I know I always mean to but I think the Hebrew hammer that's a holiday treat for the whole family.
Rym: Well, we've still got Black Samurai which is supposed to be a blaxploitation about samurai I mean still have yet to watch it.
Scott: like we could watch like we've just been saving it and saving it and saving it.
Rym: We could watch it after we do the show.
Guest: Oh my god You have something next time to talk about again.
Rym: Or we could just save it forever and never actually watch it because it's probably Running now than it will be after we see it.
Guest: You see I thought that you were talking.
Guest: I thought you were explaining the show earlier when you were talking about like the guy getting off the plane and being attacked by ninjas All the time.
Rym: No, that's a different move.
Scott: That's a different movie.
Scott: We love this box set of DVDs.
Rym: This set is just ninja movies movies involving ninjas and I've discovered that while I like ninjas almost every movie involving them is terrible.
Scott: Yep,
Guest: like you just scroll
Rym: or three ninjas
Scott: Stop making movies.
Scott: a bunch of people in Hong Kong and other places made a whole crap ton of crap movies with people like Bruce Lay Bruce Lee Bruce lie Bruce lie, but Bruce Lee spelled differently Bruce low.
Rym: and they're all these guys.
Scott: They look like Bruce Lee, but they're not as good Yeah, or they're close to Bruce Lee But some of them are good and some of them are but they were just like Bruce Lee clones And they just try to imitate him and make those kind of movies.
Guest: Brandon Lee met that horrible fate and he was pretty cool, too Which is damn shame because he could have been like the next like American martial arts guy.
Rym: Yes There's that new guy the like.
Rym: it's the Filipino kickbox or songs on Bock.
Scott: Well, that's that's the name of the movie.
Scott: Is that his name actually?
Scott: I watched a trailer for that movie and I said that looks awesome, but I haven't seen the movie.
Rym: Yeah, cuz it looked like normal fighting like Jackie Jackie Chan style fighting and then they're like, yeah, no stuntman It's just like Jackie Chan only there was also explosions and it looked serious instead of funny.
Guest: Then you have the other end of the spectrum, which is like the the Steven Chow.
Guest: Oh God Yeah, we and we were pointed out today that like oh, yeah We watched was a kung fu hustle and that was awesome and challenge soccer was awesome and God of cookery was strange But awesome, you know what?
Rym: That's a nice reverse non-sequitur Cookery.
Guest: I must have leveled up in radio or something.
Scott: Yeah, we're not.
Scott: well God of cookery.
Scott: Hey, we're talking about food again.
Rym: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: So if you need to see a movie and you're bored and it's I think it's on Netflix This movie is called God of cookery and it is quite literally about the God of cooking Like you think.
Guest: it's just like oh the guy is so good.
Guest: He's got.
Guest: no no There's actually a God of cooking in the show that appears and it's it's it's.
Guest: it falls along the lines of Steven Chow's movies and his Ridiculousness.
Rym: I mean if you like Iron Chef because a lot of geeks are fans of Iron Chef for some inexplicable reason This movie is up your alley You have no idea.
Guest: Yeah, we had some good time.
Guest: The Steven Chow movies I think are there's.
Guest: this thing going backwards is something that what he pointed out is that there are tons and tons and tons and tons of Steven Chow movies and 90% of them suck and I don't know why I Mean, I've seen three of his movies and they were all awesome.
Rym: So I thought all right I'm gonna look up and see what other movies I can get.
Rym: and he has like 40 movies in Netflix.
Rym: So I added them all to the queue and then we watched.
Rym: I watched like one and it was like the worst movie I've ever seen.
Rym: Hmm.
Rym: It just went on and on and on and there was this thing with a mole and it wasn't cool.
Scott: It could have been funnier if they cut out a lot of the dumb scenes.
Scott: Maybe it was just like maybe better editing.
Guest: who's like his early stuff or something Like?
Guest: maybe maybe he's later stuff that we know that we know what love is good and his early stuff like sucked.
Rym: Yeah, cuz I know kung-fu hustle is kind of new and very natural.
Guest: It's new.
Rym: Yeah, God of Cookery is kind of new, too.
Guest: You're Beijing.
Guest: I think was it from Beijing with love.
Guest: There's another one that I have them watched yet?
Guest: I don't know.
Scott: not I have to see that one.
Scott: I think that was like in the late 90s even if it's any good To do the third reverse non-sequitur.
Scott: He actually hires like the same actors for a lot of his movies.
Scott: like if you just watch all the recent ones You'll see like the same actors over and over again And people like the Beast.
Scott: the Beast is actually one of those old Bruce Lee clone guys that he thought was good.
Scott: So he hired him and turned him into not a Bruce Lee clone.
Rym: Oh, really?
Scott: Yeah There's a lot of guys like that like that woman the the fat.
Scott: what the landlady and her husband Shallon soccer she was in a lot of other stuff like that was old and crappy.
Scott: So he brings back people who actually like have some martial arts movie talent and puts them in his somewhat good or even better movies You know so that they can fix their reputation for making a bunch of crap movies.
Rym: now If you need any kind of impetus to watch God of Cookery There is a scene where they introduce these seven or the nine or some number.
Rym: I'll just go with nine because I don't remember the nine brass monks and Basically the main character trained with these monks for a long time and They show the training and basically every time he screws up the monks would punish him and by punishing him They would all appear like on the screen and they would do like these crazy.
Rym: You know kung-fu movies.
Rym: I'm about to do awesome kung-fu setup, and then they would just run over him hit him with a chair.
Rym: It's that kind of humor.
Scott: the movie can be summed up in three words pissing beefballs.
Rym: And That was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Thanks for listening.
Scott: Please remember to point your favorite podcatcher at feeds feed burner comm slash GeekNights to get the latest episodes as soon as they're released.
Scott: also, please visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com For the latest updates and forum discussion and whether you love or hate our podcast.
Scott: We won't know unless you send your feedback to us at GeekNights at gmail.com.