Rym: It's Wednesday, January 25th, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we talk about Last Exile and Kagehime.
Scott: Let's do this!
Rym: So you might have noticed that the show, uh, didn't get uploaded till this morning.
Scott: Uh, screw you, Optimum Online.
Rym: Yeah, it's not even that Optimum Online went down.
Rym: I mean, I would have understood if they just had a problem.
Rym: They had planned maintenance from midnight till 6 AM, and the show was done, and I was just about to upload it, and then, uh, my internet died.
Scott: And, uh, it's fine if they want to have their maintenance, but they should freakin' tell someone.
Scott: I had to wake up when I was sleeping at, like, midnight, and Rym was bothering me about the internet being down, saying it was this and that and this and that, and it took me, like, ten minutes to figure out it was Cablevision.
Rym: It took him a few minutes to, uh, wake up enough to realize I was talking, first off.
Scott: Yeah, all right.
Rym: And then it took me--.
Rym: Did you realize what answers you gave me when I said the internet is down?
Rym: You were laying there, and you're like, "In five minutes, it'll...".
Rym: And then, you just, like, trail off and roll over.
Scott: Well, that's what happens when you try to wake me up at the freakin'... whatever.
Rym: It was, like, 12, 15.
Rym: It wasn't that late.
Scott: I was trying to get sleep.
Scott: I'm tired.
Scott: I'm gonna go to sleep early today, probably, too.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: As soon as you're done with this.
Scott: But anyway, uh, it freakin' sucked, and they should freakin' tell me when they're gonna do maintenance.
Scott: If they planned it out, they should tell me.
Scott: That way I know, and I don't rely on it.
Rym: Yeah, some small measure of professionalism is all I ask from people.
Scott: Uh, I guess they kinda have us over a barrel, though.
Rym: Well, I guess I've discovered that, despite what people tell you when you're a child, when you grow up, don't expect anyone to actually act in a professional manner about anything.
Rym: Almost no one does.
Scott: Except for yourself.
Scott: You should expect yourself to act in a professional manner.
Rym: Well, yeah, but I've learned that I can't trust other people to ever handle things professionally.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: That's what makes us awesome.
Rym: And speaking of professionals who can't handle themselves professionally, uh, we all know that politicians lie.
Scott: All the time.
Rym: And that politicians, uh, ignore facts.
Rym: Well, uh, now there's scientific backing to this.
Scott: Ah.
Scott: Uh.
Scott: So, the facts which they ignore say they ignore facts.
Scott: So, yeah.
Rym: Yeah, but basically they did this study where they would give a politician various data that were true, or that were false but were part of the study, about an opponent and about a political ally.
Rym: Things like that.
Rym: And they discovered that, even if they weren't intending to, politicians tended to greatly gloss over any factual information that was damaging to their cause or to anyone they cared about.
Scott: You know, um, you really can't blame 'em.
Scott: If you don't want to be damaged, and there's a fact that is damaging to you, you know, your choices are either say that you suck and hurt yourself, or ignore it.
Scott: I mean, if someone comes in-- It's like if there's a knife about to stab you, and somehow ignoring the knife prevents it from stabbing you, then, yeah.
Rym: Well, I mean, part of it was at one point, they were given statements by either George Bush, if they were Republican, or John Kerry, if they were a Democrat.
Rym: And they would play two statements by the people in rapid succession that clearly contradicted each other.
Rym: And then they were asked to consider and rate the discrepancy.
Rym: They always rated the discrepancy of their opponent hundreds of times higher than the discrepancy of the guy they're supporting.
Scott: Ah, so basically, they don't consider what the facts actually are.
Scott: They just say, "Oh, that's my side, blah.
Scott: That's their side,
Scott: blah.".
Rym: Yeah, they seem to pick their side and stick to it no matter what.
Rym: No matter what evidence is presented, they just don't even remember the evidence that is against them.
Scott: So, they're just unthinking, uh, useless people who just-- They're automatons.
Scott: Yeah, basically.
Scott: They're programmed to be on one side or the other, and they're just stuck on that side.
Scott: They don't actually think about issues or anything like that.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You know, that's just fantastic.
Scott: I think, uh, anyone who doesn't know how to use the internet should not be allowed to govern, because it seems that-- How is-- wait, wait, wait.
Rym: How is using the internet-- Well, no, no, no.
Rym: -any precursor to intelligence?
Rym: It's not, but the thing is-- I submit to you Myspace, 4chan, The Style Project, and FARC.
Scott: But I submit to you that, uh, even the punk kids who argue about whether, uh, the PS3 or the Xbox 360 is gonna be better, or which one's worth more, put more thought into it than these politicians are putting into their positions.
Rym: Now, one interesting bit, they also discovered in this study that apparently Tom Hanks is awesome.
Scott: Is he really that awesome?
Rym: No, but what they did is they also-- they used Tom Hanks as a neutral person when they were doing this study.
Rym: And the politicians on both sides tended to rate his statements equally.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So they really only showed their bias when it was against, uh, if they're a Republican or Democrat, or if they're a Democrat or Republican.
Scott: Did they-- did they try having people who were, um, like, not Democrat or Republican, say things that were very Republican or very Democratic?
Scott: Like, have-- have Tom Hanks say, you know, "Healthcare for everyone is great," or "War is
Scott: great."?
Rym: No, they were only evaluating statements of fact.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Scott: I get it.
Scott: That would've been interesting, though, to see them evaluate, you know, political statements said by people who weren't associated with either side.
Scott: You know, that way to see if they're actually even thinking about the issue at all or just totally basing it on the person who says it.
Rym: I mean, I don't know the-- many of the details of the study.
Rym: That's just what I get from the article that I'm, uh, linking to here.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, like, imagine if, like, Bush went around-- Let's say you got a recording of Bush or a fake recording of Bush saying, you know, "Universal healthcare is
Scott: great.".
Scott: Would Republicans go, "Yeah, just 'cause Bush was saying it," or they'd be like, "Uh, no, because I'm a
Scott: Republican.".
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: Yeah, that-- that's what I really want to see, that kind of thing.
Scott: 'Cause then you'll know, are they actually thinking about the issues at all?
Scott: Or are they just following in tow?
Rym: I'm gonna go with no on that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But I still want to see, get some facts and not guesses.
Rym: But at least there's some good news.
Rym: West Virginia is taking steps to, uh, fight childhood obesity in an awesome way.
Scott: Hooray!
Scott: Obesity sucks.
Rym: They're using Dance Dance Revolution in their gym classes, officially.
Rym: They have a three-year deal with Konami.
Scott: Yeah, well, there used to be, um, I think a bunch of schools and gym teachers all over the place figured out that DDR is a way to get kids to move their ass, and it worked at getting kids to lose weight.
Scott: So, but West Virginia is the first place to say, "All right, we're gonna do this big time in all the schools that we can,
Scott: everywhere."
Scott: Where as opposed to just, you know, a few lucky schools had cool gym teachers.
Scott: Now it's all the lucky schools in West Virginia are gonna have some DDR action.
Rym: It seemed to have come out of the fact that DDR was extremely successful.
Rym: Kids actually are, were more fit in the school, and they, uh, they didn't really give us any good data since we're not in West Virginia.
Rym: It's definitely local news to them.
Scott: Yeah, well, you think about this, right, if I remember high school gym class, right, the kids who were all sporty would, let's say you were gonna run the mile, 'cause you ran the mile every gym class, right?
Scott: They would, uh, the kids who were all sporty would be like, "Yeah, let's go," and they'd run.
Scott: And the fat kids would be like, "I don't wanna," and they might not even do it.
Scott: They would just, they would either just sit there, or they would just walk, or they would barely run and not even try.
Rym: Wow, so I never talked to them in high school, so I really have no idea.
Scott: Yeah, they had, they had absolute, well, also in middle school and elementary school, the kids who didn't have athletic ability were not motivated to do athletics and thus remain without athletic ability.
Rym: Huh.
Scott: You know, so DDR, I think, works great because it's something that kids who have no athletic ability will still want to do and be good at because it's a fun video game, and thus they will gain athletic, uh, abilities and lose weight and such.
Rym: Well, I'm glad that people are at least taking a creative approach to this instead of just doing the same old "make 'em play dodgeball" or "force 'em to
Rym: run.".
Scott: Yeah, see, dodgeball is great and fun, and I, you know, I think every kid should still play it once in a while in gym class, but it really doesn't, you know, make anyone have better, uh, health.
Scott: 'Cause if you're, you know, some fat kid, you don't really move, you just get hit right away and then you sit down, you know?
Rym: Of course, I mean, honestly, to me, I don't think gym class should really be the, the operative factor here.
Rym: I don't think a kid who has a bad lifestyle is gonna suddenly turn around because they're taking a gym class.
Scott: No, they won't turn around because of the gym class, but actually, if, you know, I'm two ways about it.
Scott: On the one hand, you know, I'm like, "Oh, we shouldn't have gym class in school.
Scott: "School's for
Scott: learning.".
Rym: Yeah, I was that way when I was a kid and I didn't take gym 'cause they just, I didn't need to, so from fifth grade on, I just never took a gym class.
Scott: But at the same time, there is significant scientific evidence to suggest that when you have better, you know, physical health and such that can, you know, be gained from a gym class, that you have better mental health,
Rym: I know, I just, honestly, I think that that's the realm of the parents.
Rym: And if parents are raising their kids so poorly that the kids are unfit, well, the parents need to be in trouble.
Scott: Yeah, of course, but, you know, you could say the same thing.
Scott: If parents are raising their kids so dumbly that they're dumb-- Yeah, and you know what?
Rym: I do.
Scott: Then why even have school in the first place?
Rym: Honestly, I've got a lot of gripes with the current public education system in the US.
Scott: Oh yeah, I got gripes with it, but I'm not saying that there should be no public education system.
Rym: No, I'm not saying that either.
Scott: Yeah, so, no matter how broken it may be, I do think that some sort of physical gym activity is important and should be had.
Scott: And it has a lot of benefits.
Scott: You know, people always put it down like, oh, look at all the evils of school sports in contrast to like, you know, 'cause it takes away from the other good things like the school music program or education time and too much emphasis is put on this high school football team.
Scott: that doesn't mean anything, really.
Scott: It's just BS.
Scott: And there's something to that.
Scott: But don't rub that off onto the perfectly good gym class, which, you know, might be the one chance you have to make the fat kid not fat.
Scott: You know, and people do get, you know, they've done, like, it's true, schools that have gym every day, even if it's like 15 minutes, half hour gym classes, those schools have a lot smarter kids than the schools that don't have so much gym or have gym less.
Rym: I mean, honestly, the only reason I never took gym was that I didn't want to get all sweaty in school and my schools never gave you enough time to actually take a shower.
Scott:  Oh, okay.
Scott: In our school, everyone had to take gym, normal gym, but if you wanted to, you could take, like, special gym, like net games where you'd play any game involving a net, which was like, you know, ping pong, tennis, badminton.
Rym:  I technically took a class called Individual Sports that was supposed to be about, like, badminton and ping pong and tennis and whatever, but I never actually attended it and I still passed.
Rym:  I just kind of signed up for it and then I just hung out in other places in the school during that period.
Scott:  They had some other games, like, where you'd play all the games that involved going from back and forth, basketball, hockey, soccer, all those.
Scott: So you could take a special gym class, you know, just to play the things you wanted, or you could take the general gym class where you just did whatever.
Scott: And I always took the general gym class and I think it was like, it was every day, right?
Scott: I think it was every day.
Scott: And, you know, you would go to the gym class and there was a locker room and you'd change your clothes and you had a locker, and then you did gym, then you came out and you showered and you changed your clothes and you left.
Rym:  There was no frickin' time to shower.
Scott:  I don't know, how many periods a day did your school have?
Rym:  We had eight, in my high school, we had eight periods a day, 45 minutes each.
Rym: That was it.
Scott:  Oh, we had seven.
Scott: So you had more time.
Scott: You had time, it was like 10 minutes in between each one.
Rym:  What, we only got five minutes in between each one.
Rym:  I realized I showed up to school at like 7.30 and I was out by two.
Scott:  We showed up at 7.30 and we were out a little after two.
Rym:  Yeah, and I could take eight classes and I got a 45 minute lunch, if I wanted it.
Rym: Lunch was just a class and you took it if you wanted it whenever you wanted it.
Scott:  See, ours was a little different than that.
Scott: But I guess, you know, we had time to shower, it was all good, and gym was actually a lot of fun.
Scott: Like, I didn't like gym so much in middle school, it was just kind of boring.
Scott: And they always made us do just like boring exercise things and stuff like that.
Scott: But in high school we had a lot of fun in gym doing all kinds of sports.
Scott: We played like floor hockey and speedball and all kinds of stuff.
Rym:  So my last several things of the day, for those of you who've been paying attention, have been things that in some way angered me and have driven me to a righteous indignation at minimum.
Scott:  Anger.
Rym:  Yeah, though at least I got a lot of positive feedback on my chiropractic bit.
Rym: But today I have something that is the exact 180 degree opposite of that.
Rym: These kids and what they did brought a little tiny man tear to my eye.
Scott:  I like how you call them kids when they're like college kids.
Rym:  I consider myself a kid when I talk about things like this.
Scott:  All right.
Rym:  But I mean, these guys are the definition of testicular fortitude.
Scott:  They are awesome.
Scott: Fear them.
Rym:  So basically, Alberto Gonzalez, you know, Mr.
Rym: Torture is perfectly legal.
Scott:  The Attorney General of the United States of America.
Rym:  Yeah, I'm not gonna mince words, he's a giant asshole.
Scott:  He sucks.
Rym:  Political, however you wanna slice it, whichever side of the fence you're on, Alberto Gonzalez is a terrible man and should not be holding that office.
Scott:  I don't care who you are, if you say torture is awesome.
Scott: First off, God, torture isn't even useful as an interrogation mechanism.
Rym:  Yeah, I tried to explain, of course I tried to have this argument with some people at my job, and they're like, yeah, we should torture the terrorists to protect me.
Rym: And they didn't seem to believe me when I told them that there are in fact scientific studies done by the CIA back when they used to torture people, and they discovered that torturing people is so useless, you actually get worse information.
Scott:  Yeah, 'cause when you torture someone, all they want you to do is stop torturing them.
Scott:  They'll say whatever you want, they think that they have to say to make you stop torturing them.
Scott: They'll say, yes, I did it, he did it, they don't care, they'll make up anything, you won't know what's true and what's a lie.
Scott: So the CIA doesn't wanna do torture, the NSA doesn't wanna do torture, no one who's actually in the interrogation business wants to torture because they know it's useless and stupid and wrong, and yet, Gonzalez says we should and it's okay.
Scott: This is a bad man, a very bad man.
Rym:  Well, he was at Georgetown University, and it's a school, obviously, and he was giving a little talk on a panel about the NSA spying and how it's a good thing, and people are worked up about it for no good reason.
Rym: And in the middle of it, all these punk kids pull out a little bit of civil disobedience.
Scott:  Woot.
Rym:  And I don't know all the details because this is just some live journal post about it, but apparently they made a ruckus and then a whole bunch more of 'em stormed the room with a giant banner that has my favorite quote from Ben Franklin ever, "Those who would sacrifice liberty for security "deserve
Rym: neither.".
Rym: This huge friggin' banner and they held it up.
Scott:  Actually, I think what it was is a bunch of them stood up and turned their backs to him, like, you know, he was giving a speech to a room full of people sitting facing towards him, so people standing up and facing away all in unison is kinda like, "Eh, what's goin'
Scott: on?".
Scott: And then kids all dressed in black with like little cowls on came in with the banner from an outside room.
Rym:  Oh, I just looked at it, they're wearing the outfit that the one, you know the famous picture of the Iraqi being tortured with the black hood on?
Rym: They were wearing those.
Scott:  Ah.
Rym:  I didn't notice that, I was just lookin' at the picture in greater detail here.
Scott:  Yeah, so they came in like that, carrying this banner, and then they all unfurled it and held it, so.
Scott:  Now,
Rym: once someone on the panel, well, I don't need to read all the quotes from the site because you have the same link I have, but David Cole, who was a professor, a law professor at this school after seeing this said, "In light of this, I'm proud of the very civil, "civil disobedience that was shown here
Rym: today.".
Scott:  Yay, civil, civil disobedience.
Rym:  So, my thing of the day was awesome, but Scott's, I gotta admit, is equally awesome in a completely different way.
Scott:  This thing of the day, when I saw it this morning, I was like, oh my God, that is like one of the top 10 things of the day ever.
Rym:  Now, we're pretty sure that it was at least mostly staged just because the thing that they dug up in the desert, as far as we know, was ground up into bits before it was buried.
Scott:  Yeah, well, let me explain the whole story.
Scott: For those of you who don't know, there was an
Scott: E.T.,
Scott: as in E.T.
Scott: the extraterrestrial, the Steven Spielberg movie with, you know, E.T.
Scott: telefono la casa, I mean, E.T.
Scott: phone home.
Rym:  What is it with you in the Spanish version of that movie?
Scott:  They made us watch it in Spanish class in high school.
Rym:  We watched The Lion King in French.
Scott:  E.T.
Scott: telefono la casa.
Scott: Anyway, so, they made a game for the Atari called
Scott: E.T.,
Scott: based on the movie, and everyone says it was a terrible, terrible game, and you know what, it is a bad game, but I think it is slightly less terrible than everyone else thinks it is.
Rym:  See, have you actually played that fucker?
Scott:  Yes, I have.
Rym:  It's mostly unplayable.
Scott:  It is mostly unplayable, but it is slightly less terrible than everyone else says it is.
Rym:  The cognitive dissonance between what I think I should be doing to win and what I actually need to be doing to win is immense.
Scott:  Anyway, it's a terrible game, and they thought they were gonna sell a hajillion copies of it 'cause it was so awesome, and E.T.
Scott: was like the most popular thing in the world in that time, but they made more copies than there were Ataris.
Scott: They just made too many copies of it.
Rym:  Millions of 'em didn't get sold.
Scott:  Yeah, and the fact that it was a bad game didn't help it.
Scott: They didn't even sell a copy for every Atari.
Scott: Yet everyone with an Atari seems to have one.
Rym:  'Cause there's so many.
Scott:  I know, so-- - I have one.
Rym:  Yeah.
Rym:  It's sitting right there.
Scott:  So, what ended up happening is not only did they lose a shit ton of money, but all these extra E.T.
Scott: for the Atari cartridges were put in a landfill, and we're pretty sure that they were ground up.
Scott: Nah, but we don't know that for sure.
Scott: So, this band wrote a song.
Scott: There's just some band, I don't know who they are.
Scott: I don't care.
Scott: They made a song, and their music video was all about this Atari game, and it shows footage of them playing it.
Scott: I like the parallel where it shows them digging up the landfill to get E.T.
Scott: cartridges, and it shows E.T.
Scott: in the game going into a pit to collect a piece of his spaceship.
Rym:  Just watch it.
Rym: It's got really high production values, and it's really well done.
Scott:  Yeah, it's really cool.
Rym:  And it'll tell you in greater detail than we did the actual story of the E.T.
Rym: cartridge.
Scott:  And if you are someone who already knows the story of the E.T.
Scott: cartridge, it will still entertain you and make you feel good.
Rym: So, today being anime day, we have two anime to talk about.
Rym: We're gonna take a look at Kagehime Monogatari A.Q.
Rym: Ellis Rondo.
Rym: Most people just call it Kagehime.
Scott:  Yeah, that's the name that was on the torrent.
Rym:  Yeah, we only watched one episode, and suffice to say that's all we need to watch of that show.
Rym: We'll get into that in a minute.
Rym: And we're gonna talk about, we'll actually review Last Exile, which we're more than halfway through currently.
Scott:  That's a good show.
Rym:  'Cause basically we've decided that in terms of the way we talk about anime, there are three types of discussions we're gonna have from this point on.
Rym: We'll try to be very clear about what they are.
Rym: Well, if we watch just like one episode, we're just gonna talk about our impressions of the show.
Rym: It's like a look or a preview or something like that.
Rym: Once we've seen enough of the show to review it, we'll do a full-on review.
Rym: And then when we've seen the end of a show, we'll always do a sort of final thoughts.
Scott:  Well, if it's a good show.
Rym:  Yeah, if it's a show that's worth talking about.
Scott:  We're not gonna do final thoughts and something that was crap.
Scott:  Yeah.
Scott:  We're not even gonna do a review if the preview was, you know.
Rym:  Kagehime's not getting a review.
Scott:  That's a good way to tell how good we think a show is, is how many times we'll talk about it.
Rym: At most, we can talk about it three times.
Scott:  Yeah, and that would be like the best show in the world.
Scott: we talk about three times.
Rym:  Now, the reason that we're splitting up the review and the final thoughts, just in case you're curious, is simply that we wanna have a review of the show that anyone can listen to, that won't ruin anything.
Rym: But when we talk about a show that we've seen all of, we want to have the ability to spoil it so we can actually talk about it.
Scott:  So basically, the purpose of previewing a show is to know whether you should start watching it now or not.
Scott: The purpose of a review of a show is, you know, once enough of it is out, that's pretty much like, all right, is it a good show or is it a bad show after you've seen enough of it to make good judgment.
Scott: And you know, if you're really, you know about a show and you wanna know whether it's good or not, the review is what you're looking for.
Scott: And the final thoughts is like more of a discussion of the show itself.
Scott: So if you've already seen the show and you wanna hear us talk about why, what happened in the show in a nerdy discussion, that's what final thoughts is for.
Rym:  Yeah, and if you want a nice example of that, go back to the one we did about Big O2, the end of that one.
Rym: We ranted for like an hour about the existential blah, blah, blah.
Scott:  Allegory, whatever.
Scott: Yeah, I think we should do the same thing for, you know, video games and stuff.
Rym:  Yeah, I think that'll be our terminology from now on.
Rym: We'll probably make a post or a forum thing about it at some point.
Scott:  Yeah, board games don't really need that.
Scott: Board games, pretty much, you played it, you can talk about it, you know.
Rym:  Now, like we said, we'll talk about Kagehime first, and this is a first look or a preview.
Scott:  Right, so Kagehime was a pretty normal magical girl show.
Rym:  It looked like it had potential just based on the opener and the first little bit of it.
Scott:  Yeah, I mean, the girl had bunny ears and stuff, and there was a guy and another girl and whatever, and there was a school, I think, but the school didn't play into it so much.
Rym:  Yeah, it started out really kinda weird.
Scott:  And they had this really blatant Alice in Wonderland metaphor, but it was actually a big part of the show.
Scott: They would just keep saying Alice, Alice, Alice, and they, you know, Looking Glass, and there were rabbits everywhere, and clocks and pocket watches.
Rym:  But it's actually quite literally, they're looking for, basically they're looking for the way to make the Lost Alice, or the Infinite Alice, which is the last book in the Alice in Wonderland series that was never written.
Scott:  Yeah, 'cause it's Alice in Wonderland, then there's Alice in the Looking Glass, and there's some imaginary third book.
Scott: So the point of the show is that they're trying to get the third book.
Rym:  Now, the show wouldn't have been that bad, 'cause I mean, I'm a man who sat through all of Sailor Moon, so I can take a magical girl show pretty handily.
Scott:  Yeah, I'm not a fan of magical girl shows, but I wouldn't mind watching Fancy Lala to find out what happens with those dinosaurs.
Rym:  Now, Akagi Hime wouldn't have been that bad, except that it had 100% more horrible rape than I expect from a magical girl show.
Scott:  Yeah, and it wasn't even a hentai, man.
Rym:  Oh my God.
Rym: I'm not sure what to say other than that in the first five minutes of the first episode, the main character magical girl horribly rapes another magical girl with a giant key, and then the same thing happens again near the end of the episode.
Scott:  Yeah, we're not even joking.
Scott: Like, he takes this giant key, we're talking, like, Kingdom Hearts key, jams it into this girl's chest, and starts turning it, and the girl is just crying and whimpering as if she is being raped.
Rym: I really don't know how to, it's like the most, it's horrible.
Rym: We were watching it, and we're looking at each other, and we're like, this is just a rape scene that doesn't involve rape.
Rym: It's just, I don't know what to say.
Scott:  There were some, there were even up skirts and boobage and everything, so it's kinda like, ugh.
Scott: Made it even worse.
Scott: I mean, you thought like the man-loving, what was it, cluster edge is bad.
Scott: That doesn't even come close.
Scott: I would take that in a second over this key rape business.
Rym:  Oh my God.
Rym:  Yeah.
Rym:  I mean, it's still just a happy, cute, magical girl show, but all the magical girls, and there's a whole bunch of 'em, and they're all trying to get these pages of the book, and you know how they get the page of the book?
Rym: First, they rape the other girl with the key in this horrible way, and then apparently a book pops out of their chest, and it's like their actual life story, like all their innermost secrets.
Rym: Then she flips through it, finds a piece she likes, rips it out, and takes it.
Rym: Meanwhile, the other girl's screaming, "Please don't read my
Rym: secret.".
Rym: It's rape on every level that you can have rape.
Scott:  They should just call it rape-a-hime, or kage rape, or something.
Rym:  I mean, I wish I was kidding.
Rym: Don't fucking watch this show.
Rym: It's just terrible.
Scott:  Unless you really, really like magical girls, or raping people with keys.
Scott:  Yeah.
Scott:  If you have a key rape fetish.
Rym:  I mean.
Rym: We were a little taken aback.
Scott:  Yeah, so kage-hime, not good.
Rym:  Yeah, it's not, unless you wanna see what we're talking about, because the show is really kind of, Watch the first episode.
Scott: Go ahead, be my guest.
Rym:  Yeah, 'cause you might be thinking, there's no way they're serious.
Rym: There's no way there's actually rape in that cute magical girl show.
Rym: that's not at all hentai.
Rym:  Oh.
Scott:  No, yeah.
Scott:  Oh, and it's not hentai, by the way, for real.
Scott:  Yeah, it's really not hentai.
Rym: Nothing bad is shown other than the horrible rape.
Scott:  Yep.
Scott:  So, nothing bad is shown except the horrible rape.
Rym:  It's, yeah.
Scott:  I think that's enough of that.
Rym:  All right, I wanna talk about a real show now.
Scott:  Last Exile, it's on DVD now, all of it.
Scott: It's been out for a while, actually.
Scott: We're just slow in watching it.
Rym:  I mean, I hadn't really seen any of it until we started watching it recently.
Scott:  I hadn't seen the first DVD, and I knew it was good, but it always got put down on the list under other stuff.
Scott: And then when I started watching Fullmetal Alchemist, I just had no time to watch this one.
Scott: So, it fell by the wayside, and now we picked it up again.
Rym:  And I gotta say, it's regrettable that it fell by the wayside.
Rym: Last Exile is fairly awesome.
Scott:  It's damn awesome.
Scott: Holy crap, awesome.
Rym:  Pretty much, it has all the tidings of an A anime, of a good, engaging, solid show.
Rym: It starts right away with a good plot.
Rym: The plot makes sense, the plot's contiguous.
Scott:  The characters are good.
Rym: There are so many characters, and they're all fleshed out and unique.
Scott:  And it's not like those other animes we talked about recently, where you didn't get to know the characters, 'cause they were in it for two seconds.
Scott: There's the right number of characters that you can know them all, and they're cool, most of them.
Rym:  And the thing is, even the characters you don't get to know they're still really fleshed out.
Rym: There's this one character, you only see him three or four times in the whole show, at least as far as we've seen.
Rym: And you don't know much about him, but he does things, and he's about as developed as that kind of character can be.
Scott:  The thing is, the one thing that bothers me about the show is that it's so, it feels like someone wrote an RPG, and then decided they couldn't make an RPG and made an anime instead.
Rym:  The thing is, I kinda like that, 'cause it feels like an RPG.
Rym: Oh, now they're playing the Getting Fish game.
Rym: Oh, now they're like, it's RPG anime style music, is through the whole thing.
Scott:  Well, it's good, because RPG plots tend to be good and enjoyable, and there's nothing more that I want than to get an RPG plot without actually having to push A a thousand times in the combat system.
Scott: But at the same time, the parts of the show that are just so blatantly mini-game are a little bit, it's not painful, but it's a little twinge.
Scott: It's like, oh, RPG, it doesn't really fit in.
Rym:  I think, haha, RPG.
Scott:  Well, if they did it more blatantly, instead of this trying to be subtle, but not really, and they did it less often, I think it would be actually good.
Scott: It would add to the show, but the way it's done, it kinda minuses.
Scott: One time they're having a race, oh, that's right, the show is about these kids who fly these things called Vanships.
Rym:  Well, basically, I'll say a bunch of words, and these words together really tell you what the show is about.
Rym: Steampunk, air pirates, that's all you need to know.
Rym: It's steampunk air pirates.
Scott:  Yeah, so basically they have these things called Vanships, Vanships, whatever.
Scott: They're basically fighter planes, but they look different and work on a principle of made-up fantasy.
Rym:  Yeah, but it seems a lot like a helium-filled thing, or a hydrogen-filled thing.
Scott:  As far as you're concerned, it's just fighter pilots.
Scott: It just looks different.
Rym:  It's got a lot of the same feeling that Crimson Skies does.
Scott:  So there's a scene where they're racing them, and it's just so blatant that someone wanted to have a racing minigame in the RPG, and there's another part where it's just real RPG, especially the music and stuff.
Rym:  Which is really cool.
Rym: The only thing that bothers me in that aspect is that while the overarching plot is not at all predictable, as in I have no frickin' idea what's actually going on yet.
Scott:  Yeah, I mean, it's not that it's not predictable.
Scott: It's that you don't have any information.
Scott: You can't even follow it, really.
Rym:  But while the overarching plot is unknowable currently, but I don't feel bad about not knowing it, 'cause there's no way to know it.
Rym: I could just make crazy guesses.
Rym: Even though, honestly, the show's a lot like Scrap Princess, and I think it's gonna go the same way.
Rym: Scrap Princess does, for anyone who's seen that.
Rym: That's my guess.
Scott: But anyway-- - From what I know about Scrap Princess, I think that it's pretty true.
Rym:  Well, let me put it this way.
Rym: I watched Scrap Princess while I was at RIT, basically on my computer, instead of doing a lab that I had to do to graduate.
Rym: I graduated anyway, but barely.
Rym: But Scott didn't actually watch the show.
Rym: He just caught bits of it while I was watching it.
Scott:  I saw the first few episodes.
Rym:  Yeah, so when I said the show's a lot like Scrap Princess, Scott says, "Oh, so you mean the girl's gonna explode "or
Rym: something?".
Scott:  Yeah.
Rym:  Yeah, so if you've seen Scrap Princess, I found that funny.
Scott:  'Cause it does seem like the girl's gonna explode in Last Exile, but we don't know yet.
Scott: We haven't finished it.
Rym:  But to get to my point, the individual plot points within the show are very predictable.
Rym: It's very much the principle of, if you don't see someone die, they're not dead, but everyone's gonna think they're dead.
Rym: That way you get to have all the character development of them dying, but yet you get to keep 'em around.
Scott:  They do that a lot.
Scott: That's a mechanism a lot of animes use.
Rym:  It's one of those shows that gives you the sense of no one can die.
Rym: Like, everything's just always perfect.
Scott:  You know that people are gonna die.
Rym:  Yeah, but it's all gonna come in the end.
Scott:  If the series is good anime, someone always dies.
Rym:  Yeah, the thing is, we've picked out all the people we think are gonna die, and I think we're gonna be pretty accurate on that.
Rym: Like, one character, he's been kinda quiet for most of the show, and then he's about to do something awesome, and we looked at each other, and we praised each other and said, well, he just sealed his fate, and sure enough.
Scott:  Yep, we were just dead on.
Scott: That guy, but he was still cool the way he did it.
Scott: He was awesome.
Rym:  Now, one thing that I really like is that the technical bits, like the ships and all the technology in this world is really well-drawn and well-defined and self-consistent.
Scott:  Oh yeah, it's very, like.
Scott: the consistency is really great.
Scott: You ever see like a racing show, and like every car, like F-Zero is a great example, where every car seems to be working on some different mechanical mechanism.
Scott: You know, it's like one has a giant engine sticking out the front, one has a rocket in the back.
Scott: You know, it's all different stuff.
Scott: This one, it's like everything, you know, it seems like they have a consistent universe with a consistent laws of physics, and they all have the same kind of engine.
Scott: It's like, you even see this sort of flying propulsion mechanism on the Vanships, and then the giant capital ship, the Urbanus, has just a giant one sticking out of it.
Scott: You know, it's pretty cool.
Rym:  Now, the really cool thing about that is they never come straight out and say how everything works, but throughout the show, they always show you like bits of when they're repairing something, or when they're talking to each other, and basically you figure out how this stuff all works throughout the course of the show.
Scott:  It's like, if you didn't know anything about cars, but you just sat in the mechanic's garage and watched him and listened to what he was saying, you know, you kinda eventually figure out, oh, so there's this internal combustion going on, you know?
Scott: So, it's sort of like that thing.
Scott: All the characters know how everything works, and they just talk to each other about stuff the way they normally would, as if they knew how it worked.
Scott: And then, by listening to them, you figure it out.
Rym:  Now, one thing I gotta say is that, at first, because the individual plot point's very predictable, and I got the feeling that the love interest romance angle was gonna be predictable, too.
Rym: Oh my god, it's not.
Scott:  No, no it wasn't.
Rym:  Basically, all the romance you think is going to happen, because that's what happens in any anime like this, not at all, it's all completely backwards, and everyone likes everyone else different, and it's complicated and awesome.
Scott:  Well, except for the one guy.
Scott:  No.
Scott: (laughs) - The musketeer guy.
Rym:  Yeah, that guy's great.
Scott:  Actually, I thought he was the main character of the show, if you've never seen it before, 'cause he's the first one you see.
Rym:  Yeah, he's just this musketeer, because the show starts, we're in the middle of this conflict between two fleets in the sky, and they're fighting in a very chivalrous, like French-era Napoleon-style of two armies standing there, shooting muskets at each other, not moving.
Rym: And it's really cool, but the main character, that you think is the main character, at least, is standing there, before the battle, just chanting to himself, "The bullets will pass me
Rym: by.".
Rym: "The bullets will pass me
Scott:  And then later, he becomes a not-main character, but his big thing is he has these survival medals, 'cause he said that one in three musketeers dies in every battle, so after three battles, you're probably gonna die, yet he survived a whole shit-ton of 'em.
Rym:  Yeah, the show definitely has this whole chivalry, nobility, royalty, noble blood, we're going to talk about that in a metaphorical way, angle going to it.
Scott:  And it seems to be against the chivalry, very much.
Rym:  Well, it seems to be very much for honor and nobility, and very much against blood, nobility, and silliness.
Scott:  Yeah, 'cause it seems like they're trying to say, like, "Hey, look, this chivalry is pretty dumb, you know?
Scott: "Look at this, just people standing there, "shooting each other, just right out, it's really
Scott: stupid.".
Scott: And you say to yourself, "Yeah, that is really
Scott: But then they show you this war without chivalry, where there's lots of killing, and cannons, and people just cheating and killing each other, and you're like, "Oh, that's even
Scott: worse.".
Scott: But at the same time, it's not, because it's not, it's sort of less pointless, but more destructive.
Rym:  Now, I don't know how much more we can really say, 'cause like we said, we're trying to really avoid spoiling anything, and normally we could talk a lot about the plot of a show without spoiling it, but half of watching Last Exile is just figuring everything out on your own, and watching it unfold before you.
Rym: It's like an adventure.
Rym: It's like playing an RPG.
Scott:  Without having to push the buttons.
Rym:  Yeah, so I can't really say much, give you more information, other than just watch the show.
Rym: Last Exile is well worth watching, and I regret the fact that I hadn't seen it sooner.
Scott:  Yeah, if you haven't seen the show, get right on that.
Rym:  I mean, I've even got a little stuffed Lavi.
Rym: Lavi's the female protagonist.
Scott:  We got it for a dollar at an out of business media play.
Rym:  Yep, we went to media play the day before it went out of business for good, 90% off, and I got a little stuffed Lavi.
Scott:  Okay, so there's this comic that I knew about for quite a while, I just didn't pick up, called Owly.
Rym:  Oh really?
Scott:  Yeah, really.
Scott: It's called Owly, O-W-L-Y.
Rym:  Oh really?
Scott:  Like a cute owl, yeah really.
Scott: So, I got it this week because there really weren't that many new comics this week, so I said, you know what, I can get something old, I'll get Owly.
Scott: I got the first volume of Owly, which is called The Way Home and the Bittersweet Summer.
Scott: Oh, I guess those are the names of the two stories contained in it, and it's drawn and written completely by this one guy, Andy Runton.
Rym:  It's really light, quick reading.
Rym: I flipped through it and read it in like two minutes while I was doing my laundry today.
Scott:  Yeah, I read it on the train in like maybe five minutes, but that's 'cause I took my time and tried to absorb the insane amounts of cute.
Rym:  I don't know how to describe how cute, there is as much cute in this as there is rape in Kagehime.
Scott:  No, no, I think the amount of cute in Owly would, in this one volume of Owly, it equals the amount of rape in the entire show of Kagehime, every single episode of it.
Rym:  Now, there's no dialogue in Owly.
Scott:  Well, there is dialogue, it's just very awesome dialogue.
Rym:  Yeah, instead of having words, there'll just be a little picture.
Scott:  So, for example, Owly meets up with Wormy.
Scott: Wormy's the best character, at least my favorite character.
Rym:  He's a little worm.
Scott:  He's really cute.
Scott: Like everything else in the comic, but Wormy is like, Owly's like, what happened to you?
Scott: He doesn't actually say what happened to you, but he's like, there's a question mark.
Scott: And then, Wormy has speech bubbles, and there's like a picture of Wormy getting rained on, and his little dirt comb.
Rym:  Well, basically skip a bit to the actual, try to explain it better.
Rym: Owly asks the worm where he's from, where he lives.
Rym: And the way he says that is the speech bubble shows like, tree equals house, picture of a tree equals picture of a house.
Rym: And then, Wormy's like, picture of a little mud hut equals house.
Rym: And they're like, oh, okay.
Scott:  Yeah, it's like they don't actually use words in the speech bubbles, they just use pictures and symbols.
Scott: Like, instead of affirmative, they'll be like, an exclamation point, and you reading it just from the pictures, 'cause it's so, the art isn't really complicated, awesome art, but the way it's drawn is like, all the meaning comes across in the picture itself.
Scott: So the exclamation point, like, speaks, you know, just volumes and volumes of text about what the guy said, and you get the full meaning without actually having a word there.
Rym:  It's really cute and lighthearted.
Scott:  And if you're illiterate, you can still read it.
Scott: So the first story in Owly is about how Owly, well, he's this owl, and he's really cute, and he's the main character.
Rym:  You know, I would just like to say that, considering how simple it is, I don't think we should really go into a plot synopsis.
Scott:  You know how to do a plot synopsis?
Rym:  That would kind of ruin Owly.
Scott:  I guess, yeah.
Rym:  Even though it's fairly predictable, as one would expect.
Scott:  All right, just, if you like cute.
Rym:  It's real cute, I enjoyed it, it was worth the, well, I didn't spend any money on it, it was worth the money Scott spent on it.
Scott:  That's for sure.
Scott: I recommend, if you get it, and then share it with everyone, like little kids, parents, grandma.
Rym:  Honestly, I think this would be an excellent book for a small child.
Rym:  Yeah.
Rym:  It's also an excellent book for me.
Scott:  It's an excellent book for everybody.
Rym:  Unless you hate owls.
Rym: I mean, if you really hate owls, and worms, and little raccoon florists, you're not gonna like Owly.
Scott:  Yeah, if you don't like hummingbirds, you won't like Owly either.
Rym:  Oh, the hummingbirds, they're the best characters as far as I'm concerned.
Scott:  Nah, it's all about wormy, but the, if you don't like cute things, I think, I don't think you'll like Owly.
Scott: So, oh, they're apparently gonna make stuffed owlies soon, I don't know if I'll be able to resist.
Rym:  Yeah, we'll probably have a house full of stuffed owlies.
Scott:  I think they're only gonna make a few thousand.
Scott: We'll only get one.
Rym:  And that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott:  Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: If you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums, make sure you visit 'em.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to geeknights@gmail.com, and if you want, you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym:  GeekNights airs every weeknight, Monday through Thursday.
Scott:  GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows, it's actually recorded at night.