Rym: So, a lot of you seem to really like cheesy 80's style metal, and for some reason seem to really like that tiny, half-assed clip of Zelda music that I put in as Thing of the Day music one day to make fun of myself.
Rym: Thus, I present to you as a gig night special, a few minutes of me playing just kind of unedited.
Rym: I just was recording, playing around with the keyboard, and I decided, you know what?
Rym: I'll just hit record, and whatever I play, I will put up.
Rym: This is incredibly cheesy, and not very good, but you wanted it, so you're gonna get it.
Rym: If this is your first episode of GeekNights, I will point out, as I always do, that this is not a normal episode of GeekNights.
Rym: This is not even an episode.
Rym: This is what we call a special.
Rym: I highly recommend that you go to the feed and look at any other episode besides this one.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com, where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our frapper map, and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week, covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights, and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com, or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Scott: Just click the link that says "send me an Odeo" on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives, visit the website, which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution Non-Commercial Share-A-Like 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it, as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.