Rym: It's Thursday March 30th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We review V for Vendetta the movie.
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: so today Scott got Calus Yep came home from work pull into the driveway, and then there's a FedEx truck in my way.
Scott: And well I got out of the car says you Scott Reuben yep Gave me box and inside was the much anticipated hard-to-get board game Calus.
Rym: now we played it once.
Rym: we'll probably talk about it some Tuesday to come.
Rym: after we played it a little bit more.
Scott: Yeah, all we did.
Scott: we learned how to play and we pretty much figured out how everything works.
Scott: I'm gonna read the rules a couple more times to make goddamn sure we don't mess it up.
Rym: Yeah, we've gotten a little lazy and full of hubris when it comes to board game rules lately.
Scott: Yeah, I mean apparently we've never played Amun Ray correctly And yet we played it hundreds of time.
Rym: the last last last time you played it online you played it correctly.
Scott: I played it online two or three times correctly.
Scott: now all right, and I haven't been able to win.
Rym: But anyway, that's for another day.
Scott: Yeah, I won Calus though you suck.
Rym: Yeah, I did lose Calus.
Rym: However, I do think the two-player game is a little bit broken.
Scott: I think it's broken.
Scott: I just think it is missing a lot of the exciting factors most of the factors.
Rym: Yeah, anyway Yeah, so in the news The UMD format which is the format of disc that the PlayStation portable takes for watching movies and playing games.
Rym: Sony a while ago Claimed that they had shipped millions and millions millions and that in fact production could not keep up with demand.
Rym: It is now turned out that this was in fact a complete fabrication and UMDs are almost completely worthless.
Scott: Yeah, I mean whenever I went to the store I kind of believed it because I saw so many movies on UMD I was like wow because originally I thought I would see maybe five UMD movies ever and that would be it.
Scott: But you would go to the store, and there was a pretty decent selection.
Rym: You know well according to Reuters.
Rym: Well first off no one no studio has so much as broken even on UMDs Let alone made a profit.
Rym: well not only that a universal is completely dropping it.
Rym: They said that they've had almost zero sales.
Rym: Paramount completely dropping the format unless something crazy happens They've never made a profit is not worth it.
Rym: image entertainment Buena Vista Fox home entertainment They're all getting rid of it or at least drastically scaling back.
Rym: there you a there UMD releases.
Scott: You can't sell something in a digital or hardware format for which there is only one player.
Rym: Walmart is even dropping the the format entirely.
Rym: they won't carry him anymore.
Rym: Well.
Scott: They're gonna sell PSP games though.
Rym: So yeah, but they're not gonna sell UMD movies.
Scott: Yeah, it's like I saw the bunch of them in stores, so I figured someone must be buying him.
Scott: You know you go to GameStop, and it's like good almost a hundred UMD movies to choose from.
Rym: yeah apparently No one was buying them, and it was basically a factor of one.
Rym: Sony was really pushing them And it's rumored no one can prove this that Sony was probably paying people to put these things displayed prominently - Sony had a massive Marketing campaign trying to convince people that they were actually selling really well.
Rym: I mean you saw a while ago all the articles about how crazy well UMD was doing.
Scott: and Yeah, I believe those because they saw so many in stores, but now I believe this because yeah I've never seen one in public.
Scott: I've never seen a single person using a UMD movie in a PSP ever.
Rym: now the thing is Sony I don't think was technically lying when they said that they've sold that many UMD movies because the number they claimed is the same reason why they always claimed that the PlayStation 2 or their games or whatever always sell so well or that the PSP is doing so well.
Rym: in general They only count the number of units that they have shipped to retailers.
Rym: They never say how many units have been sold to consumers.
Rym: So every store that carries UMDs has a giant giant stock of unsold ones that they can't sell for anything Mmm.
Scott: It's just screwed up the Sony.
Scott: We need to start a thing on a website that says the Sony tally.
Scott: every time Sony gets worse We put a little check mark.
Rym: I mean Sony's just done.
Rym: as far as I'm concerned They've got no product.
Scott: How can a company consistently time after time for the past?
Scott: I don't know how many years just do something?
Scott: Since the ps2 everything that Sony has done has been bad for Sony that and bad for everyone else.
Rym: Really.
Rym: I think the place PSPs UMDs my raise see my thinking here is that one.
Rym: the PlayStation was a fluke.
Rym: it only succeeded like we've said many times because Square and Final Fantasy jumped shit.
Rym: the PlayStation 2 only succeeded because it came out real early.
Rym: it was significantly better than the PlayStation 1 and The Xbox really had a piss-poor showing early on and it was backwards compatible with the ps1.
Scott: The Xbox didn't come out till lay way later Yep, plus the GameCube.
Rym: while it was doing reasonably well and Nintendo made very good profits on it I think people were kind of wary from the not quite as awesome and 64 as they had expected.
Scott: Yeah, if the n64 would have had I don't know CDs and some Final Fantasies.
Rym: There would be no PlayStation Yeah, but anyway, Sony they just kind of dropped the ball in every single facet of their company this time around In the past five or six times around.
Rym: Yeah So anyway enough about this.
Rym: the.
Rym: the moral of the story is that UMD is a dead format And if you have a PSP You're actually probably in luck for now because you'll be able to buy every UMD out there for next to nothing In the coming few months.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Well, okay There are a lot of people who like to quote this crazy old Study about how some people prayed for.
Scott: there's some about prayer healing and how it worked.
Scott: Of course that study has been debunked many many times.
Scott: Today there came out this study.
Scott: That is real science.
Scott: They took about 1800 patients 604 of them were prayed for and were being told that they may or may not be being prayed for.
Scott: So they didn't know if they were prayed for or not.
Rym: now They were being prayed for a paracord as far as I can tell I'm gonna get to that by devout people who were who had Seared severely held beliefs.
Scott: Yes 597 people were not prayed for and they were told they might or may not being prayed for.
Scott: So they didn't know if they were being prayed for or not, but they were.
Scott: Six hundred and one people were prayed for and we're told that they would be the subject of prayer.
Scott: So you pretty much covered all the bases.
Scott: you got your control you got your experience.
Rym: It's all perfect science and As perfect as science can be when you're studying something like that.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, so you got six hundred people and three different groups.
Scott: That's pretty statistically significant.
Scott: The praying was done by members of three Christian groups and monasteries and elsewhere to Catholic one Protestant.
Scott: They were given written prayers.
Scott: the first name initial last name of the prayer subjects bla bla bla bla bla.
Scott: Who cares?
Rym: the results were The results were actually hilarious.
Scott: There was really no difference between any of the groups.
Rym: Not only was there no statistical Statistically significant correlation whatsoever between prayer and healing.
Rym: but in fact If you look at the raw numbers people who were prayed for had a slightly higher rate of complications and death.
Scott: Yeah, these are people who recently had heart surgery or bypass surgery and they you know, so that way there was no variation.
Scott: It was all people who had recent bypass surgery and they wanted to see how well they did based on that.
Scott: So it wasn't like all kinds of illnesses across the board.
Scott: It was one kind of illness and the people who were prayed for and knew it they had fifty nine percent more Though fifty nine percent of them had complications, which is a higher percentage of complications than any of the other groups.
Rym: Now, of course a study like this is hard to really vet scientifically mainly because every case was slightly different and unless you had an identical List of people who all had the exact same condition operated on by the same doctor, you know All that sort of thing.
Rym: There's really no way to make this study perfect.
Rym: however a lot of people really like to quote that old batshit study that said prayer actually helped people heal and This is just one more chink in the fact that that study was complete bullshit.
Rym: It was never replicated ever by anyone.
Scott: Yeah, and while this study isn't perfect, it's far less bullshit.
Scott: In fact, it's pretty damn good as far as science goes.
Rym: so things of the day my thing of the day is Something that I thought was fairly interesting and I found it a long time ago.
Rym: Not a long time ago Maybe a couple weeks ago, but back then the link to the trailer for this movie was dead.
Rym: So I really wasn't sure if it was legitimate or hoax.
Scott: I think it's cuz it was dug.
Rym: Well now they're hosting the videos on YouTube So I was able to watch them and I have verified that at least as far as I can tell this is legitimate.
Rym: Basically a bunch of fans have gotten together and made a low budget.
Rym: now low budget not no budget.
Rym: There's a big distinction there.
Rym: Legend of Zelda movie called the hero of time and I got to say watching the trailer I'm fairly impressed with the level of production that they've put on.
Scott: I didn't see it So it's not much I can say about it.
Rym: It looks fairly badass and well done.
Rym: The makeup and the characters and everything looks amazing except the guy they got to play link looks kind of like a doof Mm-hmm.
Scott: Is it like that fan-made Star Wars movie?
Scott: That was out a while ago.
Scott: You can watch on the internet for free.
Rym: a little bit.
Rym: I mean imagine a really well done looking movie.
Rym: I mean the trailer looks not professional but definitely very much above average.
Rym: the show You know, it's like awesome scene.
Rym: awesome scene cool guy and makeup.
Rym: Oh, there's link.
Rym: He's a doof Fighting scene.
Rym: guy on a horse in the distance.
Rym: Oh link in the distance.
Rym: He looks good.
Rym: Oh link up close.
Rym: He's a doof Mm-hmm, but honestly, I kind of want to see this and I'm kind of looking forward to it.
Scott: Yeah I was looking forward to that Star Wars fan-made movie and then I watched it and it was really just a video fanfic.
Scott: Everyone in it was like a scary person you see at a sci-fi convention and it can't be as scary as those Star Trek people We saw at ubercon.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean they had pretty high production values in that that Star Wars one and they had CG scenes of spaceships and everything.
Rym: Yeah, the Zelda one has a lot of CG.
Rym: Yeah, they're done filming and they're just finishing up the CG.
Scott: Yeah, but it was still a little painful to watch And I couldn't sit through the whole thing.
Scott: So we'll see if I can sit through this whole thing.
Rym: I think it's pretty cool.
Rym: I'd like to see it and maybe if you see the trailer, you'll change your mind.
Scott: or Yeah, yeah, it better be free though not paying for it.
Rym: Well, don't?
Rym: the only thing they have is they have a PayPal donate but it's not very prominent.
Scott: Yeah, anyway, so I'm not exactly sure where this robot is from.
Scott: Yeah, you might have seen a thread about, you know, robot ninja pirate, etc, etc.
Scott: Well, this is about robot.
Scott: I think it's from the Robo one competition or something.
Scott: Basically, it's a little tiny robot.
Scott: I'm not sure if it's remote controlled or not because the sites in Japanese it probably is remote controlled.
Scott: I'm thinking Scott found this literally five minutes before we went on the air So he doesn't have any idea except there's a video of the robot in action fighting other robots with robot kung fu.
Scott: and I must say If the world were only robots and only robots that exist for real count This is currently the kung fu master of the whole world.
Rym: this robots badass
Scott: Like it literally like uses the same techniques a couple times But it has like three or four good techniques for knocking other robots down and like towards the end of the video It fights a robot that's bigger than itself and weighs twice as much and it still manages to knock it down.
Scott: And when the robot falls on its back It does that little kung fu trick where you like you put your legs up in the air and then you flip up.
Scott: It's it's pretty awesome.
Scott: Yeah, and also like all the other robots are kind of slow and doofy.
Scott: This one's like dancing around like Muhammad Ali like me.
Rym: I'll note that you said doofy.
Rym: That's a word you would never say.
Rym: I would submit in fact that the fact that I use the word so many times in my previous bit Virally implanted your brain to say that word could be doof doofus.
Rym: So it's Thursday And as we promised we're here to talk about V for Vendetta the movie
Scott: and then we'll cross the spoiler line Just like yesterday where beyond that line You probably shouldn't listen unless you've seen it and we'll probably draw some comparisons between the movie and the comic and such-and-such.
Rym: Yep, now for starters, we'll go real briefly over this because we know some people don't listen to all days of the show.
Rym: But V for Vendetta was a comic first by Alan Moore and art by David Lloyd and you should read it.
Rym: It's a very good comic.
Rym: You could.
Rym: you should listen to yesterday's episode if you want to know more about it as we talked about it in fairly great detail.
Scott: Yeah, if you don't even if you don't like comics, you should read this one.
Scott: Probably I would have to suggest after you read them after you watch the movie.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I read it Immediately before the movie.
Rym: as in I read it I finished it we got in the car and went to the theater Mm-hmm, but I think they both stand on their own.
Scott: They do both stand on their own.
Rym: Having having one of them ruin what happens at the end for you does not ruin the other one by any means.
Scott: No, not at all.
Scott: Not at all.
Scott: But I got to say that like I can imagine someone like me We're like.
Scott: I saw the Akira movie and it was great.
Scott: Then I read the Akira manga and that was a zillion great.
Scott: and then I saw the Akira movie again And it wasn't as great.
Scott: as a result I can't.
Scott: I can imagine some people also being kind of like me in where if you read the Comic first and then see the movie it won't be as great.
Scott: But I can't imagine anyone seeing the movie and then that making the comic less great.
Rym: Yeah, except maybe with a fake computer thing that I think was dumb but quiet.
Scott: Keep going on about how you think the fake computer was dumb.
Rym: I just don't think it really belonged in the story But we'll talk about it later.
Rym: All right.
Rym: All right But anyway to real real.
Rym: briefly V for Vendetta the comic and the movie.
Rym: it's about a guy literally a guy Guy Fawkes G UI FAW KES.
Rym: now, if you don't know who Guy Fawkes is one I have I pity your soul.
Scott: You are not an intelligent person.
Rym: It's a. it's a. it's a British holiday based on the fact that a long time ago a man named Guy Fawkes Tried to blow up Parliament almost got a member.
Rym: Remember the 5th of November of gunpowder treason and plot, you know that old rhyme Really?
Scott: I know it.
Scott: Yeah, but really this guy put barrels of gunpowder under the Parliament building and tried to blow it up.
Scott: like imagine if some terrorists Tried to blow up the White House and they caught them like a minute before it blew up like these guys are standing under the White House literally with bombs.
Scott: and then we caught them and then we made a holiday about it and we celebrated it for hundreds of years Afterwards.
Scott: so we didn't forget.
Rym: Now in this story, it's set in a 1984 ish kind of futuristic Alternate history kind of world very realistic future not laser guns and all that.
Scott: But yeah, this it's sort of like a near future the movie, right?
Rym: So now definitely the movie is is set further in the future than the comic.
Scott: Yeah Oh, absolutely.
Rym: more importantly it draws heavily on current events extrapolate what we're doing right now in the world Forward 20 or 40 years.
Scott: Mm-hmm I mean The comic is sort of set in what they thought the late 90s would be like in the 80s and the movie is Set in what we thought think like the 2010s might be like or the 2015s might be like now.
Rym: now in this 1984 ish Fascist society like no bones about it fascist.
Rym: Yeah, not even kidding.
Rym: They don't even it's like alright look fascism Mm-hmm.
Rym: and the guy the main character or at least the motive character V Who wears the Guy Fawkes mask basically goes to blow up Parliament again.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Well, actually in the comic it's the first difference is that right at the beginning of the comic blows up Parliament But right at the beginning of the movie he blows up.
Scott: What's the name of the building?
Rym: Oh, I don't remember what he blows up.
Rym: take the Barbary the one with the statue of justice on top of it.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway, well, we'll talk about the main differences between the comic and the movie later because that involves a lot of spoilers.
Rym: Yep, but he's basically a revolutionary trying to undermine this fascist society.
Rym: and That's the movie.
Rym: I can't really go into much more without spoiling a lot.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, there's some other characters.
Scott: They're the the fascist guys trying to stop him.
Rym: Yeah, the leaders of all the various government agencies Mm-hmm.
Scott: There's a The girl Evie who's sort of the main character.
Rym: Yeah, she's definitely the Movie seems to be very much from her Perspective or from these perspective or from the third main character or at least main Protagonist character the good detective guy.
Scott: Yeah, the good detective guy He's like I selected a favorite guy and he's definitely portrayed in a good better light in the movie than he is in the comic I don't know.
Scott: I think in the comic he was also portrayed.
Scott: I mean, oh he was he was.
Rym: I definitely agree He was pretty in a good light But it definitely seems like the movie was much the comic.
Rym: the I. the fact that you know things like Larkhill Existed was much more commonly known and accepted and in the movie.
Rym: It was more of a. this was a government secret Mm-hmm, things like that.
Rym: little things best.
Scott: That's definitely my favorite guy in both versions.
Rym: Yes Somewhat different decision in the end of both of them though.
Scott: He does sort of make.
Rym: that's fine.
Scott: I think that's also because the circumstances were different.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway, the movie just goes from there.
Rym: so you've got the fascist future society and the Revolutionary going at it and this is a.
Scott: the screenplay was written by the matrix dudes.
Scott: So there's a lot of cool knife fighting awesome.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: If you've read V for vendetta his main means of killing people because we'll make no bones about it in both the movie in the comic He is introduced immediately as the villain and he goes around Fucking killing people with knives
Scott: lots of knives throwing knives stabbing knives pointy fancy knives.
Rym: He kills people and he makes no bones about it.
Rym: I mean there are scenes where so he's.
Rym: someone asks him like are you going to kill me?
Rym: and he says yes And then he kills them with knives.
Rym: or did you kill that guy?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Did you blow up Parliament?
Rym: Yeah, I did that.
Rym: Yeah, what of it?
Rym: It's good stuff, but the final knife fighting scene in the movie is very matrix Styling.
Scott: Yeah, like I saw it coming a mile away.
Scott: So that way it's like it's like here it comes and then you stop and you start to pay attention and watch Every single second of knife Action,
Rym: of course despite the fact that V kills a lot of people throughout the course of this movie I was very sympathetic toward V. In fact, I would hope that most of you out there would also be.
Scott: I think that's sort of the point is It's one of those things.
Scott: so they take a bat the guy who's you're not supposed to be all friendly with or a guy Who's sort of the bad guy and then they make you feel like the bad guy or like the bad guy and it's and then you I'm liking the bad guy.
Scott: Am I bad?
Scott: Oh my god It's one of those sorts of things.
Rym: now the movie that there are a lot of themes in the movie but the movie very much is Looking at our current political situation mostly in the United States actually And in a very direct way showing how it's bad.
Scott: I mean, this is the most blatant metaphor analogy stuff I've ever ever seen.
Scott: it's like that guy is Bush.
Scott: He's scaring all the people into doing what he wants and making war.
Scott: The people have to rise up and make him stop because we don't want it to be that way.
Rym: Yes, now the book involved a lot of ideas as we talked about yesterday, you know transhumanism and etc.
Rym: Now the movie is much more distilled.
Rym: the main driving idea behind the movie seems to be the political ideas.
Rym: Yeah the ideas of freedom greater than fascism freedom freedom greater than all.
Rym: and the quote that I just love quoting Governments.
Rym: people should not.
Rym: I keep saying wrong.
Rym: people should not be afraid of their governments.
Rym: Governments should be afraid of their people.
Scott: I think they use that in the trailer actually.
Rym: Yes, and it is spoken very Poignantly in the movie.
Scott: Yeah, it's like they stop and then he says it slowly and loudly and then they stop again.
Scott: It's like there it is.
Scott: Aha Yeah, there are a lot of.
Scott: the movie does I think touch on a lot more points than just the political stuff.
Scott: But it's sort of like they touch on one to go back to the politics They touching another one back to the politics Like the comic was definitely more the I the ideology of freedom and anarchy and then everything else was secondary to that.
Rym: the movie is Political.
Rym: Wow America and Bush are bad.
Rym: all this other cool stuff along with it.
Scott: Yeah, someone had told me I saw it on the internet somewhere that The comic book is anarchy verse fascism, but that the movie he said it was liberal verse conservative.
Scott: after watching the movie I don't think I can agree with that.
Scott: I think it's more fascism verse Getting rid of fascism.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: The enemy is definitely absent.
Rym: We won't talk about the end yet We're not at the spoiler line.
Rym: but the end of the movie while Essentially is the same as the end of the comic in terms of the ideas and what happens and the sense you get at the End it stops just short of making the full point that the comic made which I'm not saying is it go to a bad thing?
Rym: But it definitely stops short and makes a slightly different point a slightly less Biting point or less bad medicine.
Scott: I think pretty much the the movie.
Scott: It wasn't the people trying to make the movie weren't just trying to take the comic and make a movie out of it.
Scott: they were trying to you know change the opinions or put some ideas into the populace that is watching this movie and As a result, you know, they made some decisions that changed it and that's where the anarchy went.
Rym: Yep Now I do believe that a lot of those decisions were well done and I think that the movie overall was very well done.
Rym: I'm very impressed with it.
Scott: It's better than a lot of movies.
Rym: I seen they can't deny Yep, and honestly I expected them to dumb it down and soften the edges a lot more than they did.
Rym: I mean early on in the comic the main girl Evie is a prostitute or she's going to be a prostitute straight out of process.
Scott: She's she's going she's like a waitress or something.
Scott: You're short on money and she goes out to prostitute herself for the first time ever in the movie and these aren't spoilers happens Right away in the movie.
Rym: that doesn't happen.
Rym: It's something completely - it's something similar.
Rym: But they don't come right out and say it.
Rym: Yeah, but other than that they don't.
Rym: I mean like.
Rym: there's the priest in both And pretty much his lines are identical in both the comic and the movie.
Scott: Yeah, I thought that was pretty funny.
Scott: the priest guy.
Rym: Yeah, I mean basically there's this priest and he hired.
Rym: basically he's hired a prostitute girl and his advisors like.
Rym: I'm sorry, sir.
Rym: There was a mix-up at the agency.
Rym: She's not as young as you like and he's like, oh dear and the guy's like, yeah, she's 15 We're sorry.
Scott: Yeah, did Evie in the movie seem a lot older?
Scott: I mean, yeah in the cut Evie in the comic is supposed to be like 16 or 17.
Rym: Yeah, Evie seemed more like me our age like mid 20s kind of deal in the movie.
Scott: Maybe that's just because the actor is that old and they couldn't really.
Rym: yeah I think that was part of it and it just.
Rym: it seemed to work better because they definitely made Evie a much Stronger character in the movie in terms of her fear of mental willpower.
Scott: Well, she's a good actor.
Scott: So I really don't think they could have chosen anyone better.
Scott: so better to just change the age which didn't matter so much.
Scott: Yeah, you know except it only makes it kind of silly when she's trying to pass for 15.
Rym: But other than that, yeah, but you know what they do that scene really well.
Scott: Yeah, other than that.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Rym: So yeah, but I guess the movie is not to be taken lightly.
Rym: It is definitely not soft around the edges as you might expect And there's a lot of brutality a lot of blood a lot of murder a lot of death a lot of terrorism.
Scott: Mm-hmm Yeah, it's like I figured you know, they wouldn't show certain things or certain things you modified but they you know.
Scott: It's like when they do soften something.
Scott: if you've read the comic you notice it and it may or may not bother you But they do it less frequently than you would guess just reading the comic and trying to say oh they'll soften that they'll soften that And really a lot of.
Rym: I mean, I don't want to make this a political show right now But even though you all know our political feelings mostly they're unlike any other.
Rym: But the way they handle the politics and the way they set it up if any of the Conservative leaders in America actually see this movie.
Rym: They're going to be incredibly pissed.
Scott: I think I think they're already pissed.
Rym: I mean, I've seen some rumblings already on FARC and such about this movie.
Scott: There is a chance that they're so incredibly dumb that they don't realize that this movie's saying.
Scott: but yeah I don't know how you could be that dumb.
Rym: and I mean I'll go out on a limb right now and say that this movie is a an Indictment against the Republican Party and George W Bush and the government of the United States and the comic is not.
Rym: Yeah, the comic is much broader than that and much more timeless.
Rym: This is definitely Wow America.
Rym: Oh my god What WTF?
Scott: Yeah, that's the one thing I have to say is that I don't think and maybe there if we're still still world in 50 years, I don't think the movie will make as much sense.
Scott: Unless you know during like this movie wouldn't have made so much sense.
Scott: Say in the mid 90s when Clinton was around, you know, we would have been like, huh?
Rym: See, I think it would have though because then if they would have just it would have felt more like a 1984 kind of Deal, maybe maybe not who knows?
Rym: it's hard to say.
Rym: All I know is that in the world we live in now this movie.
Rym: if Anyone out there who is very right-wing doesn't think this movie is about them for good or ill well done or not You've got to watch the movie again.
Scott: Yeah The movie is basically Republican suck.
Scott: Yeah, it doesn't really say Democrats good though.
Scott: It just says Republican suck.
Rym: Yeah, because it does.
Rym: that's the one thing the movie stopped short on at the end.
Rym: Is that at the end the pivotal event happens, but unlike the comic it doesn't follow through with the.
Rym: here's the alternative Mm-hmm, which I don't know if it matters or not.
Rym: It depends on your taste.
Rym: We'll talk about that more when we pass the spoiler line.
Scott: Should we bring that spoiler line right up now?
Rym: I think we're yeah.
Rym: at the point of spoiler I'll just say one last thing for all of you out there who haven't seen the movie that go see it.
Rym: V for Vendetta is a fantastic movie and a minimum rent it.
Rym: the fact that Scott and I went to the theater to see it Speaks volumes because we hate movie theaters.
Scott: Yeah, and actually let's talk about that for before we cross the official spoiler line.
Rym: All right, god damn it ads.
Scott: I hate the movie theater still god damn it.
Rym: now I like the movie theater I go to in New York City all the time because one I always watch anime movies there and two they don't show ads they Just show trailers for other like art house type movies.
Scott: I think that's the thing is.
Scott: in an art house type movie You don't show ads and the people there are people there who want to watch the movie.
Scott: They're not you know, I don't want to say this but the dregs of society.
Rym: Yeah, luckily We didn't run into too many dregs on Sunday.
Scott: It wasn't as bad as it could be actually, you know There wasn't anyone yelling or talking so loud.
Rym: There was some kid next to me eating candy out of a crinkly bag.
Scott: Oh, I hate the crinkly.
Scott: Oh, that's the worst.
Scott: Especially.
Scott: I remember in college people kids would have those like potato chip bags.
Scott: Oh Yeah, ugly.
Scott: Oh, that's painful.
Rym: But honestly them if you're gonna go see a movie in a theater The movie is actually worth seeing in a theater.
Scott: I'd say if you can get a cheap maybe the dollar theater for sure.
Rym: No, yeah, I might go see it again at a dollar theater again in the dollar.
Rym: Yeah Now that I've seen it and I know exactly the differences I'd like to read the comic again and then watch it again.
Scott: You know while this may not I don't think it was as good as you know Some other movies like Lord of the Rings or whatever that I would pay to see in the theater.
Scott: But it's so much better than every other movie that's been in the theater for months and months And it's probably gonna be in the theater for months and months That if you don't go see it, you're probably not gonna be in the theater for like a year.
Scott: Yeah, if you're anything if you're anyone like us at least plus honestly, you know voting with your dollars.
Rym: This is a good movie.
Rym: So if this movie makes a lot of money compared to all the crap movies out there right now
Scott: You'll see a lot more movies based on comic books and the guy who wrote Watchmen will be even and Veeve will be even More pissed off because they'll make a Watchmen movie.
Rym: Even though meanwhile we saw the trailers and one they're remaking the Poseidon adventure.
Rym: I don't know what I think about that.
Scott: I never saw the Poseidon adventure But my general opinion of remakes is eh and two.
Rym: we saw a trailer for a movie.
Rym: What was it called?
Scott: I already forgot but one that was kind of like a snatch ripoff.
Rym: Yeah, there's this movie coming out.
Scott: Oh Lucky number 11 lucky number 11.
Rym: It looks it's almost exactly like snatch.
Scott: It looks like snatch plus America minus the number of characters though.
Rym: There might be more.
Rym: I mean that was just a trailer but that movie I think we're gonna see that movie I was sold.
Scott: see I thought it was just a snatch ripoff.
Scott: So I was kind of lukewarm and now I'm slightly less Cautiously optimistic than I was about Vee, but then they were like there's a guy named a rabbi.
Scott: Yeah, like.
Rym: alright They're like, there's this other crime boss who lives across the street that zooms in on him snatch style.
Rym: It's like the rabbi and then classic snatch kind of line.
Rym: Why do they call him the rabbi?
Scott: Cuz he's a rabbi.
Rym: Alright anyway go CV for vendetta.
Rym: It's well worth it.
Scott: Oh, yeah, the most exciting trailer I saw was there's a Beastie Boys movie gonna coming out.
Scott: I'm totally getting that Download or DVD or something.
Rym: Beastie Boys are gonna let the beat drop.
Rym: All right, all right spoiler line, all right from this point forward We are going to spoil both the comic and the movie of no land for vendetta.
Rym: All right Spoilers spoilers spoiler.
Rym: do not keep listening If you do not want V for vendetta to be spoiled.
Scott: if you haven't seen both the comic and the movie and you care Don't keep listening.
Rym: Yeah, I think we've given you enough time.
Scott: All right, that's it.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So in bow dies at the end But the fact that V dies in both of them was good.
Scott: I was worried and he dies in the same way.
Rym: Yeah, I was very worried as the movie got toward the end that they were gonna take V's mask off.
Scott: I was very worried about that.
Rym: Also that would have like killed the whole thing Like I would have been disgusted if that had happened and the fact that they did they didn't Despite the fact that that's a very.
Rym: I don't want to sound prejudiced against Americans.
Rym: That's definitely something that Americans in general would probably have wanted to have seen.
Scott: Mm-hmm, at least people who if people were watching the movie because people who read the comic I mean if you're already bought this comic or got it from the library or something You're already smart enough that you're gonna get it, you know, or at least get the main point.
Scott: if you're in a movie theater I mean, this is the number one movie this week.
Scott: There are people who went to see it who are.
Scott: obviously There's at least someone who's not smart enough to get it and that person is still thinking they want to see what's behind the mask.
Rym: Well also in the comic book in case you didn't realize it about the mask It goes into.
Rym: there's a whole page where they show like she imagines herself taking off the mask and seeing a face Mm-hmm, and then they backpedal like no that was just in her head and then she does it again And it's a different face and she does it again.
Rym: It's a different face.
Scott: Well in the movie they do the same thing.
Scott: She's like the.
Scott: the detective is like who was he?
Scott: and she's like he's me and you and my dad and Gordon and everyone.
Rym: I thought it was really cool how they did that the how she starts naming all the names of Who V really was and she keeps naming everyone and then finally she says herself and then she says you And then as that's happening keeps cutting to that crowd of people all wearing V masks and they all start taking their masks off.
Rym: Yep, it was just.
Rym: it was a good piece of cinematography there.
Scott: it seemed like the movie definitely took a lot of the scenes from the book not all of them, but enough of them and Truthfully acted them out you know very very accurately.
Scott: and The transitions between them and a few of the details were changed and a lot of the things that were represented by comic book imagery or comic book narration were done differently like just there instead of showing the pictures of the different Faces, which would have taken like a whole minute.
Scott: They just have her say who you know all these different names.
Scott: It's the same thing Yep.
Rym: And just little things like the detective in the first one shoots V and V actually dies in a different way in the movie.
Rym: Obviously since you you know, you've seen it all of you, I hope.
Rym: But despite that the end is that I mean the.
Rym: the idea of the end is the same.
Rym: It just happens in a slightly different way because the way it happens in the comic would have taken another half hour of screen time To put to draw out.
Scott: well for the way things happen in the comic this is the.
Scott: this is if all the things that are missing the only one the one that I'm most upset about is There's a guy named almond and he dies right away in the comic.
Scott: But his wife is like a very important character in the comic like she is there like from the beginning doing stuff Right up to the end and then in the comic she kills the head head leader guy.
Rym: now I'm glad they took it out because in a movie a movie is a very different type of media from a comic in the sense that it's more distilled it's shorter and Having that in there because it basically you would have had to had this extra character in whereas this whole extra plot from beginning To end of the entire movie and it just would have complicated the movie and made it longer
Scott: I think I just think that it was really important.
Rym: I don't think it was at all.
Rym: It's not important at all to the message.
Rym: It's just.
Scott: it's not important to the message, but it's important to what?
Scott: There's a whole separate message that has to do with her.
Scott: It's like her message which is separate from the message of the whole.
Scott: the main story was lost.
Rym: Yeah, and you know what?
Rym: I think that's good because the more if you put too much into a movie it just dilutes everything and ruins it.
Rym: one of the one of the best signs of a good filmmaker at least in my opinion is someone who can distill a movie down to Where every you get everything.
Rym: everything's there.
Rym: You're never distracted by other plots that aren't meaningful.
Rym: you drive the movie toward an end and you end it.
Scott: Yeah, but then this movie could have been made in five minutes.
Scott: I mean if you want to distill it, you know to the max not to the max But there's definitely a level of distillation.
Rym: and if they'd put everything that was in the comic in the movie No, you can't put everything in.
Scott: that's just silly.
Rym: Well, even that plot adding that plot would have added at least a half hour or not If not more to the movie, that's actually I wouldn't mind it extra half hour.
Scott: The movie was kind of short I didn't.
Rym: the movie was actually pretty long.
Rym: It would have complicated the plot unnecessarily because I doesn't add anything to the plot or story it's just an extra side thing.
Scott: No, I think it definitely adds a lot.
Rym: What does it add?
Rym: well
Scott: it the Almonds wife sort of shows you how you don't see in the movie Like what the normal people's lives are like and like the terrible things that you know, it's like, okay You see that in general life there is kind of terrible, but you don't actually sort of know what the other people are doing.
Scott: She's like the person who's you know, who is a normal person living in this terrible society and all the terrible things She has to go through because of you know, the way that things are going.
Rym: and then you see I think that just wasn't necessary for the movie.
Scott: and then you can see as her attitude is changing you.
Scott: That's the attitude of all the people like when she you know gets pissed at the government.
Scott: That's when the people are see.
Rym: I think the movie does it in a very good simple way.
Rym: Instead of having all that extra plot and characters and scenes they just kept cutting to normal families all around Britain sitting in their houses watching TV and watching the news and showing them reacting to the news and it kept.
Rym: there's this bar that they keep cutting to as well and it keeps showing all the common people and How they're they're mumbling and their reactions and what they're saying Just changes every time.
Rym: it cuts to them as things have happened in the movie.
Rym: These characters are have a different attitude.
Rym: and then the final scene when the final you know The revolution is happening and it cuts the camera very specifically cuts again to all these places and all of those places are empty.
Rym: now It cuts to the bar and it's empty.
Rym: cuts to the old folks home and it's empty.
Rym: It cuts to every one of those houses.
Rym: It kept showing and they're all empty because and then at the very end you see all those faces from all those places In the line when they take off their v-masks at the end.
Rym: I think that serves the same purpose as that woman only much more screen ready.
Scott: It does serve the same purpose but I think the reason that I enjoyed the the woman doing that better than the all the families is it seemed like Watching that woman's life was a lot more darker and it kept the the.
Scott: the theme of the comic seemed to be like dark and Underground like the Sun was never out and shining, you know And a lot of those people's houses like.
Scott: we're all bright and happy and it didn't really feel terrible It's you know, it felt like those people had fine lives, you know, why were they upset with the government?
Scott: You know.
Scott: and it seemed like this woman actually had a reason to be upset with the government.
Rym: and see I just think from a Filmmaking perspective life was terrible.
Scott: These people were just people watching TV.
Rym: Yeah, well you also complained about the fact that they took the whole fake computer thing out of the movie.
Scott: It's not the fake computer itself It's the the the message of V love justice.
Scott: But the leader guy took justice away and justice of sleeping with him.
Rym: metaphorically speaking Yeah, and what again?
Scott: and the compute.
Scott: the leader guy was in love with the computer and V took that away from him.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: That's just another side plot that would have just complicated the movie.
Rym: It would have made the movie less of a movie.
Rym: It would have made it longer and more complicated.
Scott: You know when I you don't have to add everything in but there you know ways clever ways to do things.
Rym: Oh, yeah and I think the way they dealt with not having the woman in was very clever and I think I just think it's my opinion that Having the woman and her plot in the movie would have made the movie overall complicated longer and just overall worse.
Scott: See, you know it's just that the Lord of the Rings took a book and they made it into a movie and they didn't include everything and they Did compress a lot and change quite a bit?
Scott: But I didn't feel like anything was missing and it was quite long and a million people went to see it.
Rym: Here's the thing they did.
Scott: it in such a clever way Like this was good.
Scott: V for that.
Scott: it did the same thing.
Scott: It's just almost as good and it's just because it isn't as good as something someone else has done.
Scott: I feel like you could have done it better.
Rym: the thing you feel that way and I disagree because I read V for vendetta Literally 10 minutes before I went to see the movie.
Scott: I read it like a couple days.
Rym: I understand I read it I went immediately to the movie and Despite the fact that you know the woman subplot and the fate subplot were in my mind directly.
Rym: I didn't miss them at all.
Rym: In fact, I was glad the fate plot was not in the movie at all because I didn't like it.
Rym: And I was glad that the woman plot wasn't in because it just would have complicated the movie.
Rym: I didn't feel like I was missing anything.
Rym: And in fact, I would have been disappointed if they had appeared.
Scott: Yeah, I felt like they were missing and I felt like they could have been added without making it that much longer or more complicated.
Rym: I don't think they could have at all.
Rym: I'd like to ask someone who has experience in film what they have to say about that But I don't think it would have could have been done reasonably.
Scott: The real the real reason I've said about the woman missing is, you know, not so much, you know, okay Yeah, her purpose was still served by something else in the movie But the you know the tone of it wasn't dark.
Rym: I think the tone of the movie was very dark.
Scott: No, the movie the book definitely felt a lot darker there.
Rym: I mean, I don't think I mean one.
Rym: you said the Sun was never out.
Rym: The Sun's never out in the movie either.
Rym: It's always night.
Rym: It's always dark.
Rym: Everything's always dark the bat There's almost no background in most of the scenes.
Scott: no, but I'm talking about in those people's houses.
Scott: that was the time It was light.
Rym: All right I point out that that might just be a side effect of the fact that the art in the comic is very very Simple and very colorless.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: I mean look here I'm looking to see right now where it's bright and sunny and the detective sitting on the beach.
Scott: That's cuz he's far away from everything that's going on.
Rym: Yeah, I just I don't think that's an issue.
Rym: I don't think your concern really matters.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It's just that when it went to those people's houses I understood the purpose of going to those people's houses and seeing what they were doing.
Scott: But it felt when it went there It felt a little weird because you know It was like these happy.
Scott: it seemed like they were just like happy American homes.
Rym: See to me it seemed like they were just completely ignorant of what was going on.
Scott: Oh, I didn't feel like these people were ignorant.
Scott: They seemed to be paying it like even that little girl seemed to understand what was going on.
Scott: No right away the first time they went to her house She would like went over to the TV and was like, you know bollocks.
Rym: No, that wasn't the first time pretty sure.
Rym: No, I remember very specifically the first time they show all these people.
Rym: they're just complacently watching the television not saying a word and then it's not until Things start happening and the government starts covering up more and more and it becomes more and more obvious that the government's lying That people start reacting and every time they cut back to them.
Rym: They're reacting more and more as they realize what's called.
Scott: they do react more and more, but they're reacting right from the start.
Scott: I mean where you would expect.
Rym: again, I point out it's a movie.
Rym: It's short.
Scott: It's a different media I know but it doesn't have to be that short.
Scott: You can still have more things.
Rym: I don't like this even longer.
Rym: I just don't think having those extra plots would have helped the movie at all.
Rym: I think they would have just heard it if the movie wasn't perfect.
Scott: There are ways to help it.
Scott: That's so I'm not saying the movie was you know, it didn't detract from the movie to the point where it was terrible.
Scott: This is still you know, pretty good, but it is just like the potential was lost that was there.
Scott: I disagree that they're saying the movie was absolutely flawless.
Rym: No, I was saying that the points you make about how to make the movie better are wrong.
Rym: I don't think that.
Rym: I think that if we did what you wanted the movie would be worse.
Scott: See it, but I'm not saying specifically what to do.
Scott: I'm yeah.
Rym: I think the way to do it in the woman's plot in at all would have made the movie worse no matter how you did It.
Rym: no, I think it's no matter how you did it.
Rym: It would have taken a decent amount of screen time So there.
Scott: so you're saying adding any amount of screen time at all would have made the movie worse.
Rym: in the case of this movie Yeah, I think it would have disrupted the flow.
Rym: the movie flowed very well because remember the movie takes place over the course of a year from Guy Fawkes day one year until Guy Fawkes day the next year.
Rym: and Yet the movie steadily progresses through this entire year and it works.
Rym: I think adding more Action and more motive force and more characters interacting with each other in other settings within the movie Would have made it much harder to keep that continuity and keep that flow.
Scott: Well, actually that's another thing.
Scott: I just remembered the movie.
Scott: It seemed like right up front towards the beginning.
Scott: It's like the flow is sort of going day by day.
Scott: It's like the first Guy Fawkes day then November the 6th, November the 7th.
Scott: It seems like it's going this day the next day the next day the next day.
Scott: I mean, there's some points in the movie or you could say, okay This might be next week, you know.
Scott: and then it reaches a point and then it's sort of Fast forwards like months and months and months and months and months like all at once.
Rym: See I never really got that impression.
Scott: no right after she like In the movie after she gets out of the prison It seems like and then she leaves V then it seems to skip over a whole bunch of months.
Scott: He's like come back on November 5th and then whoop.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: All right Yeah Now while time in terms of the mechanics of time went by in terms of the plot I didn't feel as though I missed anything.
Rym: I felt as though it was progressing at the rate it should have.
Rym: I didn't feel gypped.
Rym: I didn't feel like anything was missing.
Rym: I didn't feel like anything was rushed.
Rym: It just seemed like a natural flow and I think by having those other plots that flow would have been disrupted.
Scott: See, yeah It's just.
Scott: I think the flow could have been more like instead of a whole bunch of events that happened at the beginning of the Year in rapid succession skipping over a bunch.
Scott: It could have been evenly paced like, you know month You say that but yet I didn't notice that at all.
Rym: And I don't know if that's.
Rym: even if that even happens that might just be the way you perceived it.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Yeah, I don't even know if that because there are a lot of they don't even let you know What day it is a lot of the time?
Rym: Yeah, you know what that's fine That means.
Rym: that's why that makes the flow move so much so smoothly.
Scott: But that's the way that I perceived.
Scott: It was a whole bunch of events That was skipped over.
Rym: you should have heard how much Scott bitched about this movie.
Scott: I wasn't bitching about it I was just I had.
Scott: I have this thing where it's not that the movie's bad But it's like because I know so much and because I keep thinking about other things.
Scott: It's hard to you know, when you watch a movie sometimes and like get into the groove, you know like you feel like you're in the movie or like, you know, everything around your eyeballs goes away and you're like Aha or like when you're watching Star Wars and it's like, you know, it's like time for the like, you know Awesome lightsaber fight and you're just like yeah, and you forget about everything else in the world and you're into it.
Rym: Yeah, see that happens to me every movie I watch.
Scott: see that doesn't happen to me every movie.
Rym: Well, that's your problem.
Scott: is when I think about it so much then, you know, I can't get into the groove.
Scott: It just keeps me out.
Scott: and if a movie is terrible, even if I'm not thinking about anything, I can't get into it.
Scott: You know, it's like.
Rym: well, you know, I mean honestly, that's your problem.
Rym: I mean you you nitpick the movie to death on the way home And I just I really like to pick every movie.
Scott: but some movies can't you know?
Scott: Hmm.
Scott: I mean there are movies that are much less there.
Scott: I mean there are movies that are Like worse than this one yet.
Scott: I'll still get into a groove on them.
Scott: You know, I don't know what it is All right.
Rym: See your problem is just.
Rym: it seemed like when we were driving home you very much kept comparing the movie to the comic.
Scott: That's the problem and once you've read one, you can't help but compare the two.
Rym: see I can take each one individually on its own.
Rym: I take the move.
Rym: I was watching the movie and I just read the comic.
Rym: but the comic While it might have colored some of my perceptions of the movie I saw it as a completely separate entity and I took it for what it was.
Scott: Yes, I just have a hard time.
Scott: Maybe I watched it more times and tried real hard But it's like even if I'm you know, I think try to think about it as a separate entity.
Scott: I can do so Consciously, but I can't do so, you know in a feeling good sort of way.
Scott: well honestly because like you just can't help but think it's like if I tried to read Lord of the Rings.
Scott: now, right and I read the word and it says like Aragorn stabs the guy all like.
Scott: I can't help but think of that guy.
Scott: He was acting as Aragorn in the movie.
Scott: There's no way I can't picture What I pictured Aragorn as when I read the book before the movie existed.
Rym: Well, I hate to say it but that's just a failing on your part in my opinion.
Scott: No Anyone out there if you've ever seen a music video and you remember the music video and then you hear the song.
Scott: You cannot help but think of the music video.
Scott: There is no way.
Scott: that's why they make music videos.
Scott: Yeah, it depends unless you've forgotten the music video or something.
Rym: But I'm just saying I can take V for Vendetta the movie completely independent of you for a net of the comic Even though I've seen and read both.
Scott: I can take it independently on a you know conscious thought level Like I can think about it separately, but I can't watch it without, you know I can't watch or read one without thinking about the other.
Rym: Yeah Which to me was just annoying because we couldn't talk about the movie on the way home because you kept nitpicking it and complaining About it.
Scott: I wasn't nitpicking and complaining.
Scott: I Was just comparing and saying, you know, this wasn't in there and that was.
Scott: and this is you know Cuz that's all.
Scott: you can't help but think about those things.
Scott: They're just.
Rym: I thought about him and I ignored him because they didn't seem relevant to the idea of either the movie or the comic.
Scott: Cuz it.
Scott: the idea in the main idea was the same.
Scott: well mostly the same for except for the politics The main idea was the same.
Rym: actually I think the politics idea was the same too.
Rym: the thing was the movie just went more into the politics and lessened everything else.
Scott: hmm, the politics are the same but different, you know is like The same general idea.
Scott: but the movie politics are very much more honed in and pointed.
Rym: I think that was.
Rym: I mean, I don't think that matters the ID the political ideas were the same.
Rym: The only difference was the examples they made and the way they did it.
Rym: in terms of the actual political idea I think they were almost identical Mm-hmm, except I guess except for the subtraction of the anarchy bit.
Rym: now I mean the anarchy bit was the problem.
Rym: You couldn't have all that in the movie.
Rym: It would have just complicated it too much.
Rym: all them Like I said way back all the movie did at the end differently was that it had the punch of the end result.
Rym: You know the fascism is overthrown, but it didn't have the follow-through with.
Rym: now we have anarchy Mmm, it just it didn't follow through.
Rym: it just stopped at.
Rym: the government has fallen.
Rym: You know at the fascism was fallen, but the idea was the same.
Rym: They just didn't follow through with the secondary idea.
Scott: Yeah, well that didn't really matter so much actually, but I mean, that's the only difference I saw.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: I Don't know.
Scott: it seems to me like your main complaint against anything that you know.
Scott: My complaints were all like it wasn't complicated enough and yours were it would have made it too complicated.
Scott: Yet you're always the person who's like.
Scott: I like complex things.
Rym: yeah, I like complex things, but you know what movies are a specific type of media and a Good movie is not overly Complicated because then it's not fun to watch or it's not useful to watch or it's not enjoyable or the flow is wrong.
Scott: That is true.
Scott: However, you know the only point I'm making is that if you're going to you know just make a new movie that happens to have the same characters and setting as some other media because you didn't you know like a comic or a video game or something and You're not actually going to try to do the exact same thing.
Rym: I think they did.
Rym: I think they did almost the exact same thing.
Scott: No, I don't think they did the exact same thing.
Rym: Yeah, I think they did just as well as Lord of the Rings did.
Scott: no not even close.
Rym: I'd say so.
Rym: I would definitely say so.
Scott: no cuz Lord of the Rings is on like my a-list of movies.
Scott: This is like oh, yeah I a-list of movies.
Rym: how good a movie is or how good something has nothing to do with it.
Scott: No Because the comic if it like if you trans somehow magically translated the comic into like a perfect movie somehow By magic, right?
Scott: All right, and that would be on my a-list of movies.
Scott: Well, I'd even like a question.
Rym: see for me It's like I mean this is animated a - I can talk about.
Rym: All right, you've got the Count of Monte Cristo the book And you've got gone cuts.
Rym: Whoa, the the animation.
Rym: now I've seen many of the Count of Monte Cristo movies over the years and in my opinion, they're all terrible.
Rym: now The book is long and specific and exacting and detailed.
Rym: now gone cuts Oh the anime representation of the Count of Monte Cristo.
Rym: It varies and diverges wildly from the book in terms of the actual plot, especially towards the end.
Rym: It just goes off and everything's different.
Rym: but the ideas between the two and the end to set it in the theme and Just the ideology are identical and as far as I'm concerned gone cuts Oh is probably the best film representation of the Count of Monte Cristo I've ever seen and I haven't seen
Scott: all of it.
Scott: So, I don't know if you can actually say that.
Rym: but anyway Well, I've seen the end and I've seen the first like eight and I've got a good idea of what happens in the middle.
Rym: I've read spoilers and it follows the same idea.
Rym: It just does it differently and I think that that's what matters a lot more than following what actually happens point for point.
Scott: See, I don't watch things to to know what the idea is.
Scott: I mean if someone tells me what their idea is, it's like yeah, I've heard every idea there there is to hear.
Scott: You're not telling me anything new.
Scott: The reason I watch or read something is to discover the idea the act of discovering and reading and finding things out.
Rym: So if that's the case, why did you watch the movie V for Vendetta?
Rym: Because you already knew what the idea was.
Rym: you weren't gonna learn anything new by watching it because it's a cool movie.
Scott: So,
Rym: alright but other than that then you you'll admit that you had no reason to watch it that you wouldn't have gotten anything out it because You already know the idea and there's no way The movie could have been good for you because you already know the idea unless it presented a new idea.
Rym: But then you would have been mad because it didn't follow the book.
Scott: Because it doesn't matter if I know what the idea is already It's that when you go and you you know They put up symbolisms in front of you and analogies and then you figure them out and even if you already know what the result is it's the Figuring out of them.
Scott: That is the fun part for you.
Rym: I very much disagree.
Scott: I know it's like if I know you know The result is for and then someone puts a math puzzle in front of me I still go through figuring it out and then I get to four at the end and I'm like, aha
Rym: Alright, so but
Scott: if it's too it's it's sort of like.
Scott: if it's too easy It's like.
Rym: so your complaint is that the movie was too easy to figure out.
Rym: kind of Wow, that's I hate to say it.
Rym: I don't want to sound rude, but that's a really fanboy kind of thinking in my eyes.
Scott: It's not really.
Scott: See, that's the thing about fanboy not fanboy.
Rym: I'd say comic book nerd.
Scott: No, it's not cuz.
Scott: nowadays anyone who says ooh The the comic did not exactly match the movie in every single panel and the dialogue was off by one word Oh my god, that's a fanboy.
Scott: But now it seems like anyone who says, you know Oh, it wasn't.
Scott: you know, the the exact same thing is now labeled as a fanboy.
Scott: It's not that I'm not saying.
Scott: it is the exact same thing.
Scott: I know that it to be the exact.
Rym: I'm saying that I think you're really overly critical here.
Scott: I'm not overly critical.
Scott: Look the Lord of the Rings didn't have Tom Bombadil.
Scott: who gives a shit.
Scott: Yeah, that has nothing to do with it.
Rym: because while Tom Bombadil was great and important for the book Yeah, I think putting him in the movie would have just complicated thing.
Rym: cuz made it.
Scott: Tom Bombadil is like this You know crazy kind of fairy guy.
Scott: He doesn't fit with the movie, you know, here's see might is that Tom Bombadil?
Rym: Is the same as the fake computer in that it was unnecessary?
Scott: No, cuz I can feel how Tom Bombadil just doesn't fit in with.
Scott: you know, what the movies are doing at all.
Rym: But yeah, and you know what the fake computer definitely feels like it fits in not at all.
Scott: There's a totally different feeling.
Rym: not to me.
Rym: to me the fake computer is completely unnecessary I don't know.
Scott: I get a different feeling from it.
Rym: All right to me the fake computer is this extraneous thing that didn't even need to be in the comic.
Scott: No, I felt that the fake computer.
Scott: I was constantly thinking about it in the comic.
Rym: Every time I saw the fake computer stuff after I realized what was going on with it I basically just ignored it.
Rym: It just wasn't.
Rym: it didn't seem to fit with everything else in the book.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: when I read the comic it was like.
Scott: You know I was just once you knew that there was this fake computer running everything.
Scott: you would start to see what it was running all over The place you'd be like, oh there it is.
Scott: Oh, that's the fake computer, too.
Scott: I
Rym: mean so once again It's you you want to have a movie or a book where you have to figure all these things out and I just want to get The idea from it and the treatment of the idea
Scott: mmm, maybe Well,
Rym: yeah, cuz I know what I want.
Rym: I'm.
Rym: I know very much what I want out of movies and comics and V for Vendetta the movie very much gave me what I Wanted, you
Scott: know, it's just that I've seen you know, so many things and and I guess my sense is sort of dull It's like I just need intellectual exercise is what I'm looking for.
Rym: And if I don't well then why watch blockbuster movies?
Scott: Because I also enjoy blatant complete pulp Non-intellectual fighting and knife-throwing action.
Scott: That's awesome.
Scott: All right and explosions great cuz.
Scott: I'm a man Uh-huh, and you know Biologies and such.
Rym: so somehow biologies are linked to explosions.
Scott: Hey, I like the the Predators.
Rym: and see I never really liked any of the predator movies.
Scott: I've only seen one the the one first ones the only one you want to see.
Rym: I didn't really like it.
Rym: No, I love the predator and we were talking about Rambo earlier.
Rym: I thought Rambo was dumb.
Scott: Rambo one is also it seems like the number ones of all.
Scott: those are okay.
Scott: predator one Rambo one.
Scott: Well, actually terminator one and two not three.
Rym: Well, most of our generation saw terminator two before we saw terminator one, but that's a whole other issue Not me.
Rym: most people I've spoken to saw two first.
Scott: Well, that's because two made it a lot bigger in the theaters and thing.
Rym: Yep, and then everyone saw two.
Rym: Wait a minute, and they went back and found one.
Scott: Yep It doesn't matter cuz those movies aren't you don't really need to see both of them in any particular order.
Rym: But anyway, we've gone long case in point.
Rym: I thought you friend that it was fantastic.
Rym: If you're now, I don't think any many people listen to our show who are this way.
Rym: but if you were a right-winger or a right-wing Republican or Very conservative in any way.
Rym: I don't think you're gonna like view for vendetta.
Scott: No Wait, if you're a real conservative like Abraham Lincoln, you will love this movie.
Scott: If you are a George Bushite, you will hate this movie so much.
Rym: Actually, I wish you hadn't used Abraham Lincoln as an example, oh, yeah, that's true.
Scott: Abraham Lincoln My me think of someone better.
Scott: Hold on cuz I forgot about his heaviest corpus BS.
Rym: Yeah, I don't get into it.
Rym: But Abraham Lincoln is not a. I'm not pleased with Abraham Lincoln as a president.
Scott: Yeah, he's just the first name that comes to mind when I think of old and conservative together.
Rym: Yeah John Adams actually kind of as compared to Thomas Jefferson wasn't Madison a conservative.
Rym: He was a fiscal conservative.
Rym: I don't know much else about his policies me.
Rym: They're honestly after Jefferson and Adams.
Rym: I skipped a bit.
Scott: Yeah, I mean all those middle guys Taft and whatnot.
Rym: I know a lot about Taft, but that's it's like.
Scott: that's irrespective, you know days It's from Abraham Lincoln up through Teddy Roosevelt, no one cares what I care.
Rym: What about the reconstruction the Gilded Age?
Scott: you mean it was grant and then Alright, whatever.
Rym: We're not.
Rym: We're not gonna get into another show on funny presidents And not so funny presidents and this whole bit of presidents.
Rym: You seem to have forgotten about.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: So, uh real conservatives be at peace, but modern ones Neoconservatives, I guess perhaps.
Rym: Yeah V for Vendetta is an indictment against everything you believe.
Scott: if you are a neo conservative Well, that's because the Wachowski guys who made the matrix who wrote this screenplay are this, you know liberal kind of dude.
Rym: So well also I mean V for Vendetta if you read the comic Is very.
Rym: I mean it has all these other ideas in it but it's a very relevant bit of political writing among other things mm-hmm and The movie just takes that and applies it to the current political situation.
Rym: Mm-hmm Now the pro.
Rym: the only problem with it is that anyone who would get riled up by this I think has already been riled up By things like Fahrenheit 9/11 and all these other sorts of movies that have come out lately.
Rym: a control room.
Scott: Yep You know what?
Scott: Actually, I could draw a lot of comparisons to this with Death Note.
Rym: Easily Actually, I I mentioned the.
Rym: my kind of thought is though That is one difference between V for Vendetta the movie and the comic.
Rym: is that in the movie?
Rym: They bring up the Count of Monte Cristo several times.
Scott: Yeah, they show you the coolest thing.
Rym: Well, they the original one of the original movies.
Rym: They actually shows the last scene of the Count of Monte Cristo and they show it multiple times.
Rym: So if you have you don't know how the Count of Monte Cristo ends V for Vendetta ruins it.
Rym: Mm-hmm Like the part of the movie when I was just like.
Rym: ah at the end when they asks who V was and The first thing that Evie says is Edmund dance.
Rym: Yep, who is obviously the Count of Monte Cristo.
Scott: Mm-hmm Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, I said before I'll say it again.
Rym: We're wrapping up here that we've talked long enough Mm-hmm.
Scott: Thus concludes our non themed week that the Should we have a themed week next week or not?
Rym: Let's not lock it in since we're actually recording already a week in advance.
Scott: fine two weeks from now is the second theme Unless something happens.
Rym: Yeah, but two weeks from now depends on when you all listen to this.
Rym: Yeah Let's just stop before we dig ourselves deeper.
Scott: I'll take the convention schedule to make sure.
Rym: yeah I will say one thing a final meta bit here.
Rym: Well, you know we say always like.
Rym: we record at night.
Rym: We're a real night show even though we're recording like this current episode.
Rym: ahead of time I'll tell you all right now that it is currently 10 12 p.m Fuck it's night and we're recording.
Rym: we never ever record during the day.
Scott: Well, that's good because not a lot of V for Vendetta takes place during the day.
Rym: Yeah, yeah The funniest thing on my final bit is that a friend of ours called me I hadn't seen the movie yet And I hadn't really read the comic yet like a few days ago.
Rym: She called and she says and this is funny Hey this movies out and I think it's really up your alley V for Vendetta.
Rym: It's like yeah, tell me something I haven't known about for six months, but the funniest thing she goes on to say that Yeah, V really reminded me of you, you know, if you were crazy But I'd like she that's totally what you would do and you know what?
Rym: Yeah, maybe to a point.
Rym: I don't think I'd wear a guy fox mask and run around with knives killing people.
Scott: if I was more badass I might be the detective guy.
Rym: but in terms of political philosophy and specifically in the comic the idea of anarchy as a Movement as opposed to anarchy as you know, well anarchy in the UK.
Rym: Yeah, it fairly succinctly sums up some of my political ideas.
Scott: some of them some of them.
Scott: Yeah, I mean no one here is gonna say there should be no government.
Rym: It depends.
Scott: There should be at least something.
Rym: Yeah, there should be something not nothing.
Rym: That's another Thursday show.
Scott: Yeah, it is.
Rym: All right, we're out of here.
Rym: Mm-hmm And that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at Www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.