Scott: It's Wednesday, April 5th, and this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight we talk about one of our favorite anime series Lupin de Sun.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So yesterday my thing of the day for all of you who listen to all nights of GeekNights Was about World of Warcraft and that funeral.
Rym: Well that stupid thing for whatever reason made it all over the internet and made it on to the actual real national news.
Scott: I can't believe that.
Rym: I know it did so because my co-workers discovered it and They always.
Rym: they know me as that guy who knows all that stuff that we don't know.
Rym: So whenever they encounter something strange They bring it to me like it's this golden thing and they want me to enlighten them as to what it is and why it matters.
Rym: Now none of them had ever heard of World of Warcraft.
Rym: In fact, they'd never heard of an MMO.
Rym: They don't even know what one is.
Rym: when I tried to explain what one is they didn't understand.
Scott: That's sort of like when I try to tell my grandma like close the window She doesn't know how to close and she doesn't know what a window is.
Rym: Yeah I mean I was like, it's a persistent world and they're like, what do you mean persistent?
Rym: and I try to explain.
Rym: it doesn't go away and people are in it and they have fake characters that they move around and fight with each other and They're like and this is fun.
Rym: And I said no, it's stupid.
Rym: I hate it and I hate everyone who plays.
Rym: But anyway, then they showed me the video that they'd found which was actually my thing of the day from yesterday and the screen shows a guy running and they turn to me and they ask so what's this guy doing?
Rym: and I looked at the screen and I looked at them and I said he's running and Then it got to the point where they're killing everyone at the funeral and they say what's going on now and I said They're fighting.
Rym: I tried to explain how MMOs work or just the basic concept like five times It's lost on them.
Rym: They still can't imagine that people would pay money to do something like this.
Scott: I can't either.
Scott: One thing we have in common.
Rym: I did though.
Rym: I played the realm for three and a half years.
Scott: I played muds when they were free and then I realized oh typing in kill rat a thousand times to make a number bigger It's stupid.
Rym: Yeah, well, I'll say that when I played the realm I did it mostly to hang out in the village square in Leenster and talk to all my idiot friends.
Scott: Yeah, I played games and I hung out with all kinds of people but you know what I said.
Scott: Oh, this is just a chat room.
Scott: and then I went to chat rooms and then chat rooms are boring.
Scott: So I stopped doing that - you know what?
Rym: It was just a chat room.
Rym: The thing was I had the same kind of deal you had with puzzle pirates.
Rym: I was a beta tester So I really didn't pay much And the enjoyment I got all told was probably well worth it.
Rym: But yeah, anyway, that's my saga.
Scott: Let's see puzzle pirates.
Scott: Yeah, sure There was a little chat room and stuff But if that was all that was there wouldn't have been good enough.
Scott: the fact that it had fun puzzle games.
Scott: That was where.
Scott: that's what helped it out.
Rym: I was like a freshman in high school and MMOs didn't exist yet.
Rym: This is the first one and it was frickin awesome.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, whatever.
Rym: Yeah So Singapore is a country.
Scott: It is a country.
Scott: It's not a very good country.
Scott: Oh No, it's a rather unpleasant.
Scott: Remember that guy who got like cane?
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I remember that very clearly and I submit to this day that that guy deserved it.
Scott: He did deserve it he wasn't.
Scott: he was an asshole.
Rym: He goes to someone else's country where he fully understands the laws of this country Breaks the laws and then is mad when the US government doesn't save him from the consequences.
Scott: That's not the point.
Scott: The point is is that Singapore for all intents and purposes is like 1984 city.
Scott: Oh, yeah, like they've got video cameras everywhere and crazy laws and everything.
Scott: So like London It's a little weird a little bit.
Scott: It's twice as bad.
Rym: So anyway, why is Singapore in the news?
Scott: Singapore has some elections coming up soon And they've passed a new law or edict or whatever during those elections.
Scott: and that let me read it to you As a measure against the use of new internet technologies during hustings in Singapore, I guess hustings is elections or election time.
Scott: Channel news Asia reported from a parliamentary hearing on Monday that podcasting is not allowed during elections.
Rym: Really?
Scott: Here's a five-point breakdown.
Scott: and what this means.
Scott: Who podcasts political content in Singapore on The bandwagon websites blogs and podcasts.
Scott: how far did this content regulations go?
Scott: blah blah blah blah blah.
Scott: Basically, no one's going to be allowed to do any sort of political podcasting or blogging or anything During the Singapore elections in Singapore, and I think you're gonna need like a license from the government to do certain sorts of press.
Rym: so I Think we have a very valid and typical Possibly expected response to this.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: My response is I don't know much about Singaporean politics.
Scott: Singaporean what else is the word?
Rym: I don't know but Singaporean sounds funny.
Rym: It's like a little fusion.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, so I went to Wikipedia to be politics of Singapore webpage and seeing as I don't live in Singapore They can't really persecute me for talking about Singaporean politics.
Scott: Wait a minute.
Rym: Wait a minute.
Rym: You realize if we go any further we're gonna be in violation of Singapore law.
Rym: Yes, if we ever go there, they might cane us.
Scott: I did find out one interesting thing about Singaporean politics.
Scott: Oh, really?
Scott: They have a parliamentary government.
Scott: They have quite a few political parties.
Scott: Okay, the People's Action Party, which has this cool little lightning bolt for a symbol.
Rym: Lightning bolt is not always the best symbol for a political party.
Scott: No, but anyway They have 82 of the 84 seats in In.
Scott: They have pretty much They control the government.
Scott: Yeah, and they have controlled the government since.
Scott: Oh forever.
Scott: So to anyone who can vote in the Singaporean elections I tell you vote for anyone except the political action party.
Scott: Anyone else at all.
Scott: vote for them.
Scott: do not vote for the people who have been running Singapore forever.
Scott: They're evil.
Scott: 1984. fuck tards.
Scott: Fuck them fuck them fuck them fuck them.
Scott: If I lived in Singapore, I would get guns and people and kill them.
Scott: god damn evil dictatorship Parliament fuckers.
Rym: Yeah, so we can't ever go to Singapore now, that's fine.
Scott: Yeah, we don't want to unless of course they kill all these political action party fuckers and then up then we can go there.
Rym: Yeah, we could.
Rym: maybe someone will go all V for Vendetta over there.
Scott: Awesome.
Scott: Yeah start doing some pirate radio Podcasting.
Rym: you can vote for schkneidel if you want.
Rym: there should be a recession.
Scott: you had to throw that joke in there somewhere.
Rym: I was waiting for it.
Scott: Couldn't you save it till Election Day?
Rym: No, no I'm gonna say that every time it's relevant for the rest of GeekNights.
Scott: Well the next time that'll be November When you'll be able to vote for schkneidel.
Rym: Alright, so there was a second news that we're not really gonna talk about.
Rym: I just want to mention it.
Rym: a lot of people have said they know how much the PlayStation 3 is going to cost and I'm sure we're gonna get yelled at if we don't talk about it.
Rym: And you know what screw you all.
Rym: it's not verified yet And even if it is it doesn't matter.
Rym: It's whatever number they say is too expensive unless it's less than 300 Which it won't be.
Scott: yeah, the PlayStation 3 cause doesn't mean anything.
Scott: I mean, all right, if it's $400 then it's comparable to the Xbox 360 $500.
Rym: I'm just gonna start laughing hysterically for the rest of this month.
Scott: Yeah, the PlayStation 3 is going to be too expensive.
Scott: It's not going to be worth the money.
Scott: only the RPG playing nuts and the people who are just Blindly and stupidly loyal to the PlayStation name because they're not actual gamers will buy it.
Scott: who who cares go home.
Rym: Yeah, so we're really.
Rym: we're gonna talk about this But we're gonna wait until the actual price is official and I see it from a legitimate news source.
Scott: Oh, there is one the sentence I can add to that.
Scott: The next Grand Theft Auto has been announced.
Scott: It's Grand Theft Auto Chicago First Grand Theft Auto that's named after a real city and it's going to.
Scott: it's probably gonna be all gangland, which is cool by me Whatever, but it's gonna be a PlayStation 3 exclusive sometime in 2000.
Rym: I think it's like July 2007 or something like that now exclusive as in Exclusive or exclusive as in it'll be on the Xbox two months later.
Scott: It'll probably be on the Xbox a few months later.
Rym: I'd buy an Xbox.
Scott: Yeah, me too.
Rym: I like boxes All right.
Rym: Anyway, so we can't really avoid talking about the third news because it's been everywhere And in fact, I did not hear about it as early as I could have.
Rym: I was sitting in my office and as all of you who listen often know my office mate is Korean and awesome.
Scott: Oh, it was an April Fool's prank and they didn't say.
Scott: I Just went to the GTA Chicago website and apparently it was an April Fool's prank that fooled Real news gaming news sites and they didn't take the joke down.
Rym: And apparently it fooled you too.
Scott: No because see the thing is is that I didn't see the joke on the website.
Scott: I heard it from a reliable other source and they weren't saying it as if it was April Fool's.
Scott: So they got fooled then.
Rym: as a result, I was fooled All right, so I'm not gonna go back and undo what we just put on the air.
Rym: That's on to everyone out there listening.
Rym: Hahaha, it's Scott.
Scott: There's no such thing as GTA Chicago, but Word to Rockstar.
Scott: that's not a bad idea.
Rym: Oh, no, I said, oh think of this one the Mafia to the crazy controversy and thus publicity Mm-hmm.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, it says come Their website is pretty good because actually that's how they found out about previous GTA games that Rockstar would always reserve the domain and stuff and We should reserve a domain Yeah and cause some trouble.
Rym: But anyway, so the Korean guy I shared office with is awesome And he's probably the only person in the place I work and all of IBM really that I really like.
Rym: we both play games.
Rym: We know about gaming and he's cool.
Rym: and He turns to me this morning and says boot camp is out and I look at him and I say what.
Rym: and then he says You usually look on the internet and I look and sure enough boot camp is out And boot camp is awesome.
Scott: I don't know about you, but I like to stay away from boot camp.
Scott: I mean heard they make you do a lot of painful exercises and such.
Rym: This is probably the least painful boot camp that has ever existed unless there is possibly a pornography That happens to have boot camp involved in it.
Rym: Somehow.
Scott: I'm sure there is.
Rym: I'm actually I'm a hundred percent sure there is yes In fact the first person to post a link to one in our forums will win nothing.
Scott: Please don't link to pornography in our forums.
Rym: I thought we had a policy of letting people link to whatever they wanted and say whatever they wanted no matter how illegal it may Be because we have no editorial law.
Scott: Yeah, we do but at the same time.
Scott: I don't want a bunch of porn spam.
Rym: Oh Well, I think we'll talk about the forums later because the forums have been rocking though.
Rym: Scott is starting new somewhat draconian initiative that I'm sure you're sure you've all discovered.
Rym: awesome Yeah, but anyway boot camp is actually Apple's official sanctioned legal awesome.
Rym: Well done way to boot Windows XP on a new Mac.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: It's.
Rym: I mean I've not much is known about it yet because people who haven't been using it enough to write things in their blogs about it, but basically It burns you a little CD full of drivers the drivers that Windows needs to use the crazy Mac hardware.
Rym: Okay, then it has a whole bunch of little utilities that let you do everything easily.
Rym: you put in the windows CD And you can you know install windows.
Rym: it'll let you repartition your drives.
Rym: However, you want does give space to windows and give space to the max.
Rym: still it'll let you set up the bootloader So you can pick which one to boot into It'll basically do everything you need to make Windows XP service pack to run perfectly on the new max.
Scott: And as anyone how fast does it go?
Scott: um?
Rym: I haven't seen any numbers, but the few people who have talked about it online said that these machines are fast now How does it go with like the wind different keyboards?
Scott: and said uh?
Rym: Actually, no one said anything about that.
Scott: Oh cuz II that's kind of important.
Rym: Yeah, well.
Rym: I mean this was announced today.
Rym: I'm pretty sure that the the whatever meta key will just work as a Windows key.
Rym: I mean I Guess yeah, there's not too much of a difference.
Rym: I mean the keyboard will probably map in some way.
Scott: Yeah, I guess it's just I don't like the Apple keyboards.
Rym: Yeah there's not much out on exactly how well this works yet other than the fact that it works and That Apple is actually supporting this.
Rym: and it's a beta test.
Rym: now you have to sign up And then they'll send you the stuff, but yeah, I don't know if they're actually supporting windows, but they're supporting boot camp.
Rym: Yeah, so they're supporting you being able to run windows.
Rym: They're not supporting windows itself.
Scott: now Wait here's the is the real question can you boot camp Linux or something?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: they were oddly specific in that you can only run Windows XP Service pack 2 if you have an original non upgrade non media center install CD.
Rym: You cannot run windows 2000 or 2003 server and his boot camp.
Scott: only work on the power books is work on any Intel Mac.
Rym: It appears to work on any Intel Mac even the Mac mini one.
Rym: I believe so, but don't quote me on that.
Scott: uh-huh How do I be out of Mac mini?
Scott: I don't know why you run around windows on that one though.
Rym: Yeah, I mean the only real purpose for this I'd see is one if you're a graphic designer or something and you have an awesome awesome MacBook and you would occasionally have to run some windows thing for your publishing company or something like that you need windows for work.
Scott: Man, I remember back in the day like the old power PC max You'd be able to push open Apple enter and it would reboot like you wouldn't even reboot.
Scott: It would just kind of switch to DOS slash windows.
Rym: Well Apple still been saying that there's gonna possibly be that compatibility layer.
Rym: That'll basically emulate windows.
Scott: Yeah, they had perfect wine on a Mac.
Scott: I might buy a Mac.
Scott: Yeah, like perfect wine I just like good fun.
Rym: No, I got to say even dual boot is good enough for me.
Rym: Yeah You know the only thing preventing me from already having a MacBook is that it costs a lot of money.
Scott: The only thing preventing me from not having windows is is steam.
Scott: I have to have windows as long as steam exists.
Scott: Yeah, I don't even play the stupid steam.
Rym: I just have it Because you don't want to.
Rym: you don't want to wake up one day and realize that you currently could not if you wanted to Play natural selection exactly.
Rym: That would be a painful morning, and I don't think I get out of bed But I haven't played it in a year.
Rym: Yeah, but all the memories.
Scott: Yeah, indeed.
Scott: All right.
Rym: so anyway, it was news, but we don't really know a lot about it yet and Really only time will tell I expect.
Rym: in the next few weeks a lot of people are gonna be posting a lot of information about what works and what doesn't and Tricks and hacks and I'll bet someone's get Linux to work.
Rym: Someone will get DOS to work.
Rym: Someone will get OS 9.
Scott: Oh It's not.
Scott: that'll be awesome.
Scott: I don't know why you'd want to do that because it already runs OS 9 apps like perfectly.
Rym: Yeah, some freakin nerd hacker will do it because he can.
Scott: All right, cool.
Scott: So apparently Rym tells me that there was a movie called American pimp, which is a documentary on real pimps.
Rym: It's fairly disturbing.
Scott: Yeah, that's what he said.
Scott: But anyway, so once I knew that I got this thing of the day became a lot more interesting.
Scott: What it is is it's a parody of American pimp.
Scott: only instead of the guys pimping hose They're pimping Pokemon.
Scott: omg, lol the poke a pimp hilarious.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: So this is a video parodying.
Scott: a movie parodying Pokemon.
Scott: Pokey pimps reminds me of that guy who was the pokey pimp at one of those cons that you went to Yeah, and he had all the Pika girls around him.
Rym: Yeah, that guy was awesome cos I gotta say there's almost no finer sight in the world than a posse of poke pimps.
Scott: poke pimps with Pika girls.
Rym: Too many peas Pika hose.
Rym: Actually, there was a girl at anime central who followed along with all them, but she was dressed up as a jigglypuff Uh-huh.
Rym: Yeah only of course her idea of jigglypuff was basically she was wearing pink fur and little else.
Scott: Hey, you see jigglypuff like when you pull up the jigglypuff.
Scott: It's like a list of powers like sing attack turn a trick.
Rym: But Really?
Rym: This is like this is well done and funny.
Scott: Yeah, so if you know anything about Pokemon and you know anything about American pimp or pimps and pimpin pimp hats watch this All right.
Rym: So my thing of the day I tend to do things like this now.
Rym: It usually means you there's something so awesome that I can't pass it up or it's about Egypt Which means that I can't pass it up or I couldn't find anything better.
Rym: Today it's the third one.
Rym: But actually this is kind of cool in Mexico.
Rym: They discovered another Giant buried pyramid from back when there were non-hispanics in that area.
Scott: You mean like Aztec pyramid?
Rym: Yeah, like.
Rym: it's apparently the same size as the famous Pyramid of the Moon.
Scott: That's a big pyramid.
Rym: Now the reason they just found it The reason they didn't find it for so long is that there's this big hill and this hill is where every year Lots of Christians get together and they reenact in a very gory fashion the crucifixion of Christ and This archaeologist named Jesus Sanchez.
Rym: Haha, Jesus was talking about how they discovered this giant pyramid two feet beneath the dirt that made up this mound.
Rym: Apparently the pyramid was buried under dirt for whatever reason around 500 AD and we just found it again.
Scott: So, let me get this straight Jesus Sanchez who was a Archaeologist.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: He so Jesus bended off the Christians who were trying to crucify him So that he could dig up the pyramid of ancient times of awesome.
Rym: now Apparently half of the pyramid has been destroyed because of the Christians who dig into this tent this mound constantly to Recrucify Jesus over and over again.
Rym: So they've damaged it significantly.
Rym: Now I don't know how much many of you know about the pre-christian history of Mexico and South America and Central America As Tex Mayas and Incas.
Rym: Yeah, but basically there are also other tribes.
Rym: but the main thing here is that and it's the relevant part at least is that there were all these pyramids and Temples and various things because they were all various pagan religions.
Rym: They worship various gods.
Rym: My favorite being Quetzalcoatl Quetzalcoatl.
Rym: Yes, who supposedly will come back in 2012 and do something?
Scott: Dude if he comes back, I'm totally converting to as Techism.
Scott: Oh, yeah That's a religion.
Rym: lest this become the order of Quetzalcoatl.
Scott: I mean if someone comes out to me and says they're a Christian I'm just like whatever.
Scott: And someone comes up to me says they're as techism.
Scott: I'm like, that's fine.
Rym: You know, there are people who actually are pantheistic Greek Like even Zeus.
Scott: Yes, like they think there's a real Zeus that they climbed Mount Olympus lately.
Rym: They're a fairly significant.
Rym: They're not huge and I don't know how devout they are but they exist.
Scott: have they seen a Medusa lately?
Scott: How about any siren?
Rym: No one's ever seen a Medusa.
Rym: and if they did well That's my point.
Scott: Yes, I don't see any people made of stone unless you tell that all those guys in the museum were made by the Medusa.
Rym: but anyway the Christian missionaries and their converts would build their churches either out of or on top of all the old pagan temples So almost all these old pyramids and everything.
Rym: they dismantle them and use the stones to build big cathedrals and whatever.
Rym: and Basically, the only reason they didn't destroy this one is most likely that they didn't know it was there.
Scott: Maybe there was some smart Aztecs in the area who said oh shit and they buried their pyramid in dirt.
Rym: Yeah, we really don't know.
Rym: Hopefully we'll find out soon.
Rym: The problem I have with stories like this is that I'm really interested in this kind of archaeology and I love it when they find cool things like this But the mainstream media almost never follows up with what they find out about the culture as a result of these finds because
Scott: that's usually Not interesting.
Rym: Yeah, so they'll say woot pyramid found or woot There's a thing in the Great Pyramid and then that is never talked about it again.
Scott: It's the same when you're playing like civilization - it's like your guys found a great old Spaceship or your guys found a spaceship.
Scott: Well, that's a Master of Orion game.
Scott: You'll find a spaceship You know a spaceship of an ancient alien race or you'll find a pyramid from an ancient civilization and then it'd be like the effect Is your research increases by two?
Scott: Yeah, no one cares about research increasing by two.
Scott: That's boring.
Rym: See I care.
Scott: Yeah, yeah you do.
Rym: Yeah, I do.
Rym: So if you don't know what that music is from I want to cry.
Scott: I'm already crying and I do know what it's from.
Rym: Yeah, Lupin the third as a as a whole the whole entity that is Lupin.
Rym: the third is as we mentioned in our favorite Anime bit one of our favorite shows ever Shows.
Scott: I've read the manga animes movies mostly the movies.
Scott: Yeah, and the music Yeah, the all one songs.
Rym: So we just watched the fuma conspiracy for the third time.
Rym: It was only my second time Yeah, and you fell asleep during it.
Scott: I always seem to fall asleep watching Lupin movies late at night.
Scott: What's up with that?
Rym: You seem to fall asleep late at night in general.
Scott: It's not cuz.
Scott: I don't like Lupin movies or anything.
Scott: I like them a whole lot.
Scott: It's just I'm tired.
Scott: I have a hard time staying awake when I'm motionless in front of a television But you're the one always suggests we watch those movies late at night.
Scott: Yeah, what's up with that?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It's just cuz.
Scott: I like them a lot.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway for those of you who are unaware we'll talk a bit about Lupin.
Scott: Lupin was created in the 60s or 70s a long time ago before we were born by this guy named monkey punch.
Scott: It's not his real name.
Scott: That's his manga writer name.
Scott: I don't know what his real name is.
Scott: He might even change his name to that but that's what he's known by like.
Scott: people say hey monkey punch.
Scott: They don't say hey what his real name is.
Scott: and he made a funny manga about this guy Who's an awesome thief and the manga is kind of different from the TV shows and the movies.
Rym: The manga is more like the anime pilot we saw.
Scott: yeah It's like Lupin kills people and he steals and he's you know He's much more dirty and mean and ger Like a Han who shoots first and not a Han who shoots second.
Rym: So I guess the main difference there is to give a kind of broad thing when it comes to Lupin movies.
Rym: Different people have been responsible for all different kinds of Lupin movies.
Rym: It's like everyone takes their turn making a Lupin movie and depending on who did it they range from just full of T&A and boobies and and Scannily clad women to really heartwarming and serious and very ghibli esque or anything in between.
Scott: yep The TV shows.
Scott: I think there's one season that you probably haven't seen.
Scott: that's really really old.
Scott: Where like it?
Scott: I think I've sung the music on the show before or maybe what is?
Scott: that was one of the pre-show?
Scott: It's well this.
Scott: it's his old Japanese guy going loop on the third.
Scott: It's old.
Scott: it's really old.
Rym: Yeah, I don't think it was ever translated really by anyone.
Scott: I think there were a few fansubs on the internet that I saw once and they were not good.
Scott: This is like an old old TV show from the 70s.
Scott: You don't want to watch it.
Scott: the second series, which is the first series ended and then there was like, you know They didn't make any more and then they made it again.
Scott: And that's what you're gonna see on Cartoon Network.
Scott: And those are the TV DVDs you're buying in the store is the second season and the second season Of what I've seen of it is pretty good now.
Rym: It's campy and hilarious and just very very silly at times.
Rym: Casanova was the Santa Claus of sex But I mean basically it they've marketed is like here's the Lupin the TV show and they don't talk about the old series.
Rym: but the first episode of that Lupin that was on Cartoon Network is them all coming back together and Reminiscing about the past and then an old villain comes back to get them.
Scott: Mm-hmm and They don't like try to hide that fact at all.
Rym: You know, it's like, okay I'm just actually I got to say the dub is fairly well done.
Scott: Yeah, I watched the dub of Lupin TV, you know the Pretty good voice acting compared to most and the Japanese Lupin really isn't always that good.
Scott: I mean sometimes depending on what you watch There's like a base set of voice actors and sometimes people it's not the same voice actors But they get the voice so close because it's not particularly difficult that you don't notice.
Scott: But sometimes you watch certain things and the voices are just off from what you're used to for Lupin by a million miles.
Rym: Yeah, I forget which movie it was but Lupin had this really really deep annoying voice.
Rym: I mean, there's annoying voice anyway, but it was just deep and it was bothering me.
Scott: Yeah, Lupin's voice is supposed to be like Like a crazy monkey guy whatever.
Rym: well, he is a crazy monkey guy.
Scott: that's the point.
Scott: but sometimes You know, he can always also be like, you know a little bit more serious, but his voice doesn't really change.
Scott: He just you know talks more less crazy.
Scott: Yeah, if that makes any sense at all.
Rym: Yeah, so what can we say about Lupin?
Rym: I guess we go through all the characters and kind of give you a rundown of what the show is actually about.
Rym: Yep, now Lupin the main guy the the the central center of all of this.
Scott: He's the third Lupin.
Scott: Yes, and there was indeed a Lupin the second and Lupin the first.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: He's the descendant of Arsene Lupin.
Rym: Arsene Lupin, which is a real French guy, I think or no I think it's just the name of a French guy in a story that was written.
Rym: Okay I mean the stories online fairly widely available the original story of Lupin the great thief Yep, and he is a. he's Japanese and he just runs around stealing things.
Rym: His basic personality changes from movie to movie episode episode, but he's a monkey man.
Rym: He's very good at what he does.
Rym: He's silly.
Rym: He likes Fujiko.
Scott: imagine James Bond.
Scott: But instead of being a secret agent who stops evil guys from taking over the world He's a thief who steals things not well somewhat to get things.
Scott: But he also basically just wants to steal things for the fun of stealing them.
Rym: Why do they attack the gas station for fun?
Scott: Yeah, but you know, he never gets the gold in the end because that's the way it is, you know now He's always after Fujiko.
Rym: Mine who is the the arch typical woman of the Lupin world.
Scott: Yet where James Bond goes after a different woman each movie and and always gets her in the bag Lupin goes after Fujiko in every movie depending on her hair color.
Rym: Yeah, they always draw Fujiko very differently in every movie.
Rym: It's like a thing in the Lupin movie.
Rym: She's always completely different.
Scott: Well, sometimes this is Fujiko drawing styles that appear more often than others, but she's different from here to there.
Rym: Well part of it is that she's supposed to be a master of disguise.
Scott: Oh, really?
Rym: Well, so is Lupin?
Rym: Oh Lupin is totally the master of disguise But almost every Lupin movie ends up with Fujiko in disguise actually working for the bad guy But then she screws up and gets kidnapped or something.
Rym: then he rescues her but then she steals it and then craziness.
Scott: Yeah, she basically Lupin never actually gets her, you know, like he wants.
Scott: but they you know They sort of have a romantic relationship.
Rym: The level of the relationship really varies depending on the movie.
Rym: It ranges from they have this unspoken bond between each other - he's after her body and she hates him and just wants his money.
Scott: It also ranges to where they're just friends and occasionally he goes ooh boobies.
Rym: Yeah Now other than in two Lupin movies and a couple of the TV episodes Fujiko serves as nothing more than a problem.
Scott: Yeah, I mean a couple of times.
Scott: she's really good.
Scott: whenever they're in prison She'll break them out or whenever they're about to die and there's no way out She'll appear and save them and let's go him on.
Scott: does it who we'll talk about in a minute?
Scott: Yep but other than that all she does is really make things difficult for Lupin.
Scott: like if she wasn't there he would steal a lot of freakin shit and She just gets in the way and then if they ever actually do steal something she always ends up getting Whatever loot they managed to escape with.
Scott: she gets it though.
Rym: Usually then she loses it anyway.
Scott: Yeah, sometimes she'll be like I got the only gold that we escaped with and the place is destroyed.
Scott: Oh, I lost it shit.
Scott: Now the pot is like great.
Scott: if you never showed up, I would have all the gold.
Rym: But yet he always has to go try to save her if she gets in trouble.
Rym: Of course, even though Jigen and going on don't want to usually yeah, they're smart.
Rym: now Lupin's best friend in the whole world is Jigen.
Scott: Jigen is awesome.
Rym: Yeah, he's my favorite character.
Rym: Yeah, maybe now I'm not sure of his origin but in the live-action Lupin at least He was one of the members of the original crew of Lupin the second.
Rym: So he tracked down Lupin the third to try to get him to take up the mantle of you know, the Lupin thief, whatever.
Scott: I don't think that's the official because it always seems like Jigen wants to go away from Lupin because Lupin's being stupid.
Rym: No, cuz I a lot of the movies I mean Jigen always says he wants to go away, but he always follows Lupin anyway.
Scott: Yeah, but a lot of times what happens is Lupin wants to do some job and Jigen's like that job is stupid.
Scott: I'm not doing it.
Rym: Well, he's like that in the live-action, too.
Rym: Yeah, he wants him to be a proper thief like Lupin.
Rym: the second was hmm.
Scott: He's basically this he's quiet.
Rym: He's cool You know half Japanese half American.
Scott: Yeah, he's got a little beard.
Scott: You don't see his eyes too often, but they do, you know It's cuz.
Scott: he has a hat that he wears low, but you do see his eyes and they're kind of funny.
Rym: He's a lush.
Scott: Yeah, he drinks a lot.
Scott: You know, he's they all smoke.
Scott: It seems like in this show He's ever go home.
Scott: I don't think he smokes.
Rym: He doesn't smoke drink or anything.
Scott: Yeah, but go G again is a master of guns.
Rym: Yeah, I mean if we're talking burning wheel he has gun as a trait.
Scott: It's a white.
Rym: I mean, it's white with a lot of big number next to it in a castle cagliostro They're they're about to have the final, you know big battle and he's standing there with going on.
Rym: We'll talk about in a minute.
Rym: and he says the words Don't worry with your sword and my anti-tank rifle and then he pulls out an anti-tank rifle.
Scott: Yeah It's just fantastic.
Scott: Usually has this revolver and he always pulls it out when he needs it.
Scott: And then he shoots and he never misses and all that good J.
Rym: He's the quiet stoic competent one.
Scott: Yep I liked you again a lot.
Scott: He's way cool.
Rym: Yeah, then there's going on who in the pilot was trying to kill Lupin.
Rym: He was sworn to kill Lupin the third Mm-hmm.
Rym: I don't know what was up with that and we never saw the first TV show.
Rym: So we don't know how that was resolved.
Scott: Goemon is an honor bound traditional samurai guy living in modern times But he has a sword that depending on which show you're watching is either just a really normal sword or is incredibly magical and invincible and His skills depending, you know, no matter what you're watching are incredibly magical and invincible.
Rym: Basically his skill with the sword is the same level as Jigen skill with the gun and In any movie those two will be pegged at a level and that'll kind of determine how the movie is gonna go if it's gonna Be serious or silly.
Scott: Yeah, like in some movies Goemon will run around cutting up trees occasionally cutting up rocks One time he cut an entire building cutting up people in crazy movies.
Scott: He cuts buildings.
Scott: He cuts airplanes While they're flying cuts cars cuts castle.
Rym: Yeah, though in them in the really really serious Lupin's he just has sword fights with other sword wielding guys Yeah, and sometimes he just you know beats them easily and does amazing stuff.
Scott: I like it when he does lots of crazy silly stuff.
Rym: Yeah, well, I like the over-the-top.
Rym: Whoo Lupin.
Scott: Yeah, that's the best bond to me.
Rym: The best pond the best pond.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I like kougepon.
Scott: Yeah kougepons good too.
Rym: Now that basically is the crew of Lupin.
Rym: there's in every movie There's always one extra character who is the the girl who at the plot surrounds and Lupin always falls in love with her Except in fuma conspiracy where going on has the girl?
Rym: Yeah, the fuma conspiracy is one of the best Lupin movies ever definitely now.
Rym: I mean, that's the main crew.
Rym: No, the only other bar.
Rym: No, that's the crew.
Rym: now There's one more character who's kind of a member of the crew, but not really it depends on what's going on And he's my man Zenigata.
Scott: now at first when you watch Lupin you think Zenigata who he what he is.
Scott: He's an inner pole detective and he's in charge of catching Lupin.
Scott: That's all he does.
Rym: He is like the stereotypical Japanese salary man in that he is just dedicated to his job above all else.
Scott: now At first you think you know Zenigata is just a comic relief Goofy detective who can't do anything, you know, he sucks.
Scott: He always loses etc.
Scott: But once you learn about Zenigata and maybe you see a few other Lupin's you start to realize he's freaking awesome.
Rym: Yeah, I mean he always knows where Lupin is.
Rym: He catches him almost every time.
Rym: Yeah, I think is all the people under him either don't believe him or stupid.
Scott: if Zenigata was after anyone with less skill than Lupin.
Scott: He would bag them in a second.
Scott: You don't even realize You know the it's.
Scott: the only reason he can't catch Lupin is because he's fucking Lupin and he's so good, you know.
Rym: Yeah, I mean his life is dedicated to catching Lupin to the point that in one of them in fact is in fuma conspiracy He thinks Lupin is dead So he becomes a monk and just sits there Chanting over Lupin's soul for all of eternity because he has no more reason to live.
Scott: There are a lot of times we're like someone's gonna kill Lupin and he's like no we have to catch him.
Scott: We can't kill him because then he can't get out and I won't be able to catch me.
Rym: Yep Plus there's a lot of times where Lupin's crew and Zenigata will have some sort of thing going on where like they both realize that the real enemy is over there and Have an unspoken truce for a little while now.
Scott: Here's something interesting that I found out on the Wikipedia and some other places.
Scott: There's actually an old Japanese.
Scott: I think it might be a TV show or a book or something where there was another character.
Scott: I think his name was Zenigata or something else like close to Zenigata.
Scott: that Zenigata was based on this old Japanese detective character and the old Japanese detective character He's based on.
Scott: all he did was throw coins To catch guys.
Scott: like he would throw coins at guys and like knock him out or hurt him real bad and they'd fall over.
Scott: Or he'd knock guns out of people's hands by throwing coins.
Scott: Zenigata does the same thing by throwing handcuffs and if you know about the old classic Japanese character Then you know about Zenigata.
Scott: and when he throws the handcuffs to catch Lupin It's funny because they're making a joke about this old guy and that's not something you'll notice if you're just an American anime fan watching Lupin, yeah Now in terms of the movies.
Rym: I mean we could definitely rank them and I guess we'll just throw out the names of the ones that if you don't know anything About Lupin you should see these movies probably in the order.
Rym: We're about to say them.
Scott: Well, you already said Fuma conspiracy.
Rym: Yeah, but the Fuma conspiracy and the castle Cagliostro.
Scott: Yeah, that's the one that's made by Ghibli.
Rym: Yeah, those two are widely considered to be the best that Lupin has to offer in terms of funny yet Serious just good solid movies.
Scott: Yep, if you see no other Lupin watch those two movies.
Rym: now There's also Babylon gold, which is probably.
Rym: that's the one Lupin.
Scott: You don't want to see?
Rym: well, let me put it this way It's the worst Lupin ever made as far as I can tell because there's a lot of Lupin.
Rym: It's at the bottom bottom bottom of the list.
Scott: motorcycles riding on a clown face a giant clown face not Exaggerating motorcycle chase on a clown face and the giant pyramid of gold and a goddess.
Scott: and yeah That one is just crazy and silly like.
Scott: but you know what?
Rym: It's still fun to watch.
Scott: It's still funny just because it's so crazy and so silly.
Scott: It's just beyond the level of craziness and silliness that you want now.
Rym: What was the one with mom.
Rym: Oh in it the secret of mom secret of mom?
Rym: Oh, that one's good.
Scott: That one's okay.
Scott: Most of the other ones that we haven't mentioned any Lupin movie is okay.
Scott: There's one with Air Mafrodyte.
Scott: Oh, that's a great one.
Scott: That's that's just a terrific one.
Rym: That was the one in the desert, right?
Scott: It might it might be that's one of the newer ones.
Scott: There's all the big muscly guy in the helicopter.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, that was that one.
Rym: Mm-hmm Basically any Lupin movie you ever see that isn't Babylon gold is worth picking up.
Scott: All of them are available on DVD in this country at least most of them are.
Scott: there are a few.
Scott: See.
Scott: the thing is all these to you look like normal movies.
Scott: Some of them were theater movies.
Scott: some of them were TV movies in Japan.
Scott: some of them are OAV movies in Japan.
Scott: Yeah, but to us they're all 90-minute to 2-hour something movies.
Scott: Some of them actually get pretty long, you know, depending.
Rym: But yeah, the one with the giant brain at the end.
Scott: That's mom.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Mom was probably the longest one.
Scott: Yeah, some of them can get a little long, but they're all good.
Scott: No matter how long they are Just make sure you don't watch them too late at night or else you'll fall asleep And not because it's bad because it's too late and don't watch Babylon gold until you've seen some other.
Rym: Otherwise you might get a bad impression because that movie is kind of bad.
Scott: Well, at least people listening to this won't get a bad impression because we told them but don't show it to anyone else first.
Rym: Yeah, that's like showing someone Excel saga if they've never seen anime before.
Scott: yep And do watch the as much of the second TV series of Lupin as you can and don't worry They're not in any particular order so you can just pick up any DVDs you want.
Rym: Yep, in fact, I'd say if you can watch them on Cartoon Network if they're showing them.
Scott: Yeah I don't know if they're showing them anymore.
Scott: We watched them on Cartoon Network when they first showed him.
Scott: Yeah until they started to rerun them.
Rym: Yeah, they showed him at midnight and we'd all huddle around plug our TV into the wall just so we could watch it.
Scott: Yep There is one thing to know though.
Scott: There was an episode in the second series that they didn't show on Cartoon Network in the first go-around.
Scott: I think that involved a lot of Nazis and stuff and it was supposed to be this big Nazi joke Yeah, and I don't know.
Scott: I think it eventually did make it onto one of the DVDs somewhere but not in the correct order.
Rym: Yeah stuff like that happens at least it's in there.
Rym: it finally came out.
Scott: what was really funny was that if you watch the shows when you watch them on Cartoon Network you would watch and After like episode 4 they'd be like next episode crazy Nazis and the next episode wasn't crazy Nazis.
Scott: Yeah, that was good.
Rym: Now my only real big piece of advice here is that if you're gonna watch Lupin don't watch it alone.
Rym: I mean you can but The more people are in the room at the same time you have a Lupin movie on the more you're going to enjoy it.
Scott: It's really not something you can enjoy by yourself.
Rym: I mean I mean, I remember watching Castle Cagliostro with the RIT Anime Club and at that showing they were like 80 90 Maybe a hundred people in the room.
Rym: It was crazy people yelling and screaming and cheering every time something happened.
Scott: I don't understand what it is but when someone you know is in a car chase and A guy jumps out from behind the wall and cuts up the car in the rear with a sword and you're just watching it.
Scott: It's just like okay, whatever.
Scott: But when you're watching it with a hundred people and some guy jumps out and cuts up a car with a sword Leaving the driver just in his underpants.
Scott: Everyone just starts cracking up everywhere.
Scott: I don't know what the hell it is But there you have it.
Rym: Yeah consider that advice.
Rym: in general Very few anime need the silence of you know Like the otaku sitting in his room watching in the perfect environment to get every detail.
Rym: most anime is best enjoyed in a crowd Mm-hmm.
Rym: I mean there are exceptions like mushishi.
Rym: I think is good to watch with a small group.
Scott: Yeah, the only other thing about Lupin is the manga which I honestly haven't read much of.
Scott: I think I read part of the first Volume that Tokyo pop ever printed and that was it and it wasn't cuz I didn't like it.
Scott: It was just because there's so much of it.
Scott: It's not really and it wasn't good enough to warrant paying all that money for all those volumes.
Scott: You know what I mean?
Rym: Yeah, it's the kind of thing if you see a deal at a con just pick it up.
Scott: Yeah, you might be able to get a whole mess of Lupin.
Scott: maybe I'll try to do that at Otakon.
Rym: I was gonna do that at Otakon.
Scott: All right, they actually there's like two or three series of it now so you can get one of them and I can get one Of them or something.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But anyway, there's a whole lot of it and It's got the same characters as all the movies and TV shows, but it's a little darker and a little more evil and But the humor is a lot darker.
Scott: basically Yeah Like Lupin will shoot down a bunch of people with an assault rifle and they'd be bloody everywhere.
Scott: and the TV shows and movies Lupin tends to be more like Batman where he won't kill anyone.
Rym: Yeah, like in the darker even the darkest Lupin movies He doesn't kill people outright so much as by inaction.
Rym: a bunch of people around him might die.
Scott: Yeah, like in the TV show Lupin won't you know blow a bunch of people up or shoot anyone?
Scott: But if there's a bomb he'll just escape and let the whole shit blow up like in the first episode of the second.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, I totally forgot.
Rym: everyone on that cruise ship died except Lupin and his crew.
Scott: Yeah Well, I guess some of them might have got away in lifeboats, but not many.
Scott: I mean Lupin doesn't even kill Zenigata.
Scott: He you know, he just let's see.
Rym: Well, he couldn't.
Rym: I mean they're friends when it comes down To it there.
Scott: In fact, I think there was one movie actually where like Zenigata was down to dump So he lost his job or something and then he was with Lupin or we pawn helped him out.
Rym: Yep Well in Cagliostro, Zenigata plays a big role because Cagliostro to not ruin anything but basically it most of it takes place in this scary kind of country like this castley evil weird country.
Rym: and Zenigata goes there because he knows Lupin's there and even he is like whoa.
Rym: This place isn't right and he's kind of on Lupin side.
Scott: Yeah, what generally happens is Some Lupin's Zenigata is highly involved like it's about Zenigata and Lupin running away from him.
Scott: but some of them Zenigata just appears once or twice to make a little plot twist or force Lupin to change directions or take a turn or To add a chase scene where otherwise it would be boring You know because it doesn't make sense for the real bad guy to be there.
Scott: but every Lupin movie has a real bad guy who is neither Zenigata nor Lupin and Sometimes that bad guy is recognized by Zenigata and Zenigata and Lupin will semi Team up to beat that bad guy and then right at the end Zenigata We'll try to catch Lupin and Lupin will get away and the movie will be over.
Rym: Yeah, almost every Lupin movie ends with Zenigata chasing Lupin into the sunset.
Scott: Yeah, I'd say about more than half of them end that way.
Rym: Yeah, I mean some of the movies are about other characters like there's the Fuma conspiracy kind of follows Goemon and his wife-to-be Mm-hmm.
Rym: There's one movie where Fujiko loses her memory and the whole movie is basically about her.
Scott: Yeah, different characters have different amounts of You know importance depending on the movie, you know, Lupin never really has any movie where he's particularly important.
Rym: Well other than the fact that he's generally the plot mover Yeah, it's like he's the total protagonist but nothing.
Scott: the plot never really involves him or his past directly.
Scott: It's always him doing stuff and stealing things against other forces.
Rym: You know, yeah now of Lupin, I mean my favorite Lupin movies are the ones that focus mostly on Lupin and Jigen Two of them doing stuff.
Rym: I mean Zenigata and everyone else are around.
Rym: but I like the movies that just follow these two mostly Mm-hmm.
Scott: One of the best ones was that one where they were in Brazil first and there was like a carnival and Zenigata was there.
Rym: Oh, yeah, the one that started really like weird and creepily with like Zenigata chasing Lupin through the carnival slowly.
Scott: Yeah, if you want if you don't believe what I said before about Zenigata actually being awesome the beginning of this movie Well is where Zenigata is awesome.
Rym: Wasn't that?
Rym: Not really Zenigata or something?
Scott: Yeah, it was really weird and It's actually on DVD in this country.
Scott: I think it was something I downloaded.
Rym: Still have it.
Rym: I kind of want to watch it again.
Scott: Maybe I remember it had some really good scenes.
Scott: We're like there was a fake date.
Scott: Lupin and friends set up a fake house to fool I remember and then it fell over and it was just hilarious.
Scott: Wasn't that the one we're at the end?
Scott: There was the like they were going at the Lupin treasure.
Scott: or was that a different one?
Rym: I think that was a different one.
Scott: Okay, you know what?
Rym: There's so many Lupin movies.
Rym: I lose track.
Scott: I just all blur together.
Rym: just watch as much Lupin as you can in whatever order you can find it.
Scott: Yeah, there's also the assassin one with the island and the submarines and the girl.
Rym: Yeah What a girl that doesn't help the blonde girl with the short hair.
Rym: Yeah, there's also the one with James Bond.
Scott: Yeah The pond is awesome.
Scott: If you don't know about Lupin or you don't haven't watched the pond or anything.
Scott: if you like anime or you like funny things So you like James Bond or any watch freaking Lupin?
Rym: all right now a last little bit.
Rym: you might wonder why we suddenly decided to talk about Lupin and Dominally, it's because we just watched the fuma conspiracy again.
Rym: but really it's because we've got a lot of anime to review and we've been watching it and Today we sat down and we watched a bunch of shows and we didn't see enough of any one show to actually talk about it.
Rym: We want those.
Scott: I don't want to see more.
Rym: Yeah that one show we watched in a whole episode.
Rym: It didn't go anywhere and we're still not sure what the show is about.
Scott: really Well, I do know that it's about pretty boys.
Rym: Yeah, but we're not sure if it's pretty boys kissing or just happens to be pretty boys and then they fight.
Scott: I have a feeling the show is not targeted at us straight older males.
Rym: No, and then we're still watching ergo proxy and we still haven't seen enough to know if it's good or not.
Scott: But I do know the second episode got me a lot more interested in the first episode.
Rym: Yeah, because the first episode was you know, they set everything up weird like what's going on?
Rym: Okay.
Rym: It's just dramatic scene goth Looking girl cool music.
Rym: dramatic scene cool music goth looking girl.
Scott: The second episode made freaking sense.
Rym: Yeah, like suddenly there was a plot like an actual plot and characters were doing things other than striking poses and it was a good.
Rym: Yeah Definitely gonna watch episode 3 and before and once we've seen enough episodes to know what the hell's going on We're gonna talk about ergo proxy.
Rym: So hold out.
Scott: and there was another show we watched which you don't need to see more.
Rym: Oh god, the one we're gonna talk about.
Rym: Yeah next time probably This is a show that masqueraded as a cute funny asa manga dial like show but actually it's just pedophile horrible disgusting creepy not funny harem stupid.
Rym: Many adjectives.
Scott: Yeah, I think there were fives.
Scott: We'll talk about it when we talk about.
Scott: Yeah God.
Rym: and a last little anime.
Rym: bit of news for any of you who are planning to attend Otakon the hotels are all fucking sold out.
Rym: You by the way, the artist's alley isn't sold out not as of our recording Which you might not hear this episode for several weeks.
Scott: So yeah, but If you're an artist and you want a table go get one because you know we could have taken a table if you wanted but we didn't have anything to do with it.
Scott: and I didn't want to take a Table away from an artist.
Scott: and now I kind of feel bad because well, no artist is taking the table.
Scott: So frickin artists take the tables.
Rym: Yeah, cuz seriously we might just take the free table They're gonna offer us and we'll just dump business cards on it and maybe a tape playing us doing GeekNights.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I don't know either.
Scott: Maybe we'll sit at it occasionally.
Rym: Yeah, it'll be our base of operations.
Scott: Yeah Whatever.
Scott: yeah, I want more artists to be.
Scott: and if they're gonna make artists alley bigger Which I think they did and they added more tables to it I want it to be full because that makes the con better for me.
Rym: and while you're at it if you're an artist Yeah, my last metabit.
Rym: We got a lot of bits.
Rym: if you're an artist and you're any good even if you're not good We don't care.
Rym: We have a lot of friends who are artists and they're all fairly amazing in various ways and all of them said at one point Yeah, we'll make a logo for GeekNights and none of them have actually done it except one.
Rym: One person actually did something for us and that person is awesome.
Rym: She posted in the forums a while ago.
Rym: I'll bump it up so you can all see.
Rym: If anyone makes us a logo or something We'd be very happy and appreciative and we talked about it on the show here.
Scott: Let's give them a little bit of direction.
Scott: All right, it needs to be some sort of logo that can go in a square, you know Like an out like I think.
Scott: make it like it's a CD cover.
Scott: if there was gonna be a GeekNights CD Make the cover for that CD because that's the shape and Type of design that we need to go into the mp3s for iTunes and all the feeds and all that BS.
Scott: But also if you go to the forums, which have been getting one or two new users a day, which is way cool
Rym: Yeah They're actually getting really kind of big like to the point where if it keeps growing at this rate We're gonna have to start appointing people maybe to be moderators like big forums do and all that sort of.
Scott: yeah Like I can go there every few hours and there'll be a new post.
Scott: It used to be a new post every few days.
Scott: So way to go at front row crew comm slash forum.
Scott: Yeah anyway So we want a logo that that's that size and shape.
Scott: But also if you go to the forums and you look at the top of the forums how it's sort of like this blue Dark blue to lighter blue gradient we need are the new website that I'm designing Which is mostly done has the same thing at the top of it.
Scott: So if the logo looks good against that background, that would be excellent.
Scott: And then we're also thinking maybe like We'll have like that slight variations of the logo for each different day of GeekNights.
Scott: It's like we'll have GeekNights Monday, which I have like a little flask with little bubblies coming out of it or something Or GeekNights Tuesday.
Scott: We'll have like a little NES controller.
Scott: Who knows?
Rym: Yeah, we're not sure yet.
Scott: Yeah, everything's really just ideas I'm throwing out there in case artists are looking for direction instead of just shooting blanks in the dark.
Rym: Yeah, just mainly because the fact that I mean we're appearing at Tora con we're appearing at Otakon We're appearing at Katsucon next year.
Rym: We're appearing at an amazement.
Rym: least one of us are we're.
Rym: we're starting to really be around a lot and we kind of have to have things like business cards and flyers and and Banners and things for these events.
Rym: So we kind of have to move on this whole art thing.
Scott: yeah, and There are a lot of websites out there where I could pay a hundred bucks and they would have professional graphic designers all You know sketch out logos and we can pick which one we liked and then they would give it to us if we liked it.
Scott: You know for the hundred dollars but I really don't want to do that.
Scott: if I have the alternative of like giving an artist friend or artist fan like 50 bucks or 25 bucks or whatever Yeah at some point we might announce an actual contest like we are looking for this and this.
Rym: the prizes are X and Y. Here are the details in the forum, but we're not at that stage yet.
Rym: We're still very up in the air.
Scott: It's really weird because usually my problem with art is I can imagine an image in my mind and then I can.
Scott: I just can't Put it on a paper or on the thing.
Rym: How many logos have we come up with and we both look at him?
Rym: Like is that good?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Do we should we use it?
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: I'm not I don't know what's good.
Scott: You know, it's like if I see something good, I know it when I see it.
Scott: But so far nothing I've come up with is something that I see and is good.
Scott: Like I've come up with some things like all.
Scott: right, we need to come on geek and night.
Scott: Well, maybe I'll make a crescent moon for night and then I'll sort of add a geeky thing to the bottom of the moon.
Scott: that because it turns into a G because a crescent Moon is like a C.
Rym: Yeah, you ended up adding a lens flare, I believe.
Scott: yeah No But like if you make a letter C With a crescent moon to look like night and then you put an NES controller on the bottom pointy bit.
Scott: It looks like a G. What a how I know.
Scott: I know I'm not an artist.
Rym: Yeah We just thought we'd bring it up today because it's anime day and we found that there seems to be a high Correlation between people who are good at drawing and people who like anime.
Scott: there is indeed at least among our friends.
Scott: No, there is indeed a hole.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Oh to con artists alley and such.
Scott: It's also with comic books.
Scott: A lot of people are artists.
Scott: any people who like things involving art like to do art.
Scott: It's just like people who like video games and things often like to be programmers or such.
Scott: You know people like computers.
Scott: Yeah, it's all.
Scott: it all goes hand in hand.
Scott: people like to do what they like to see And that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.