Rym: It's Monday September 11th, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We begin origins week bringing you the origin stories of the fabled geekly interests of Rym and Scott's.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So today work was crazy and usually work is nothing really.
Rym: so did you do work?
Scott: No well I guess I did do things with my body to help the company in a way.
Rym: What did you move furniture around?
Scott: No, but I basically I get to work and my plan today at work was to go in play DDR.
Scott: at work I had my DDR pad in the trunk.
Rym: Yeah, you had this crazy idea the hatch the hatch.
Rym: Yeah, bring in the DDR pad to work, which would be brilliant.
Scott: It would have been brilliant except today of all days.
Scott: There was people at my work.
Scott: Oh My god.
Scott: what they were doing is they were taking the furniture out of the office and they're sending it somewhere God knows where and they're gonna get new furniture and hopefully after they get new furniture they'll get new people besides just me, but Today I had to clear off computers from a bunch of desks so that they could take the furniture away.
Rym: So you didn't bring the DDR pad.
Scott: I didn't bring DDR petting cuz there's people there.
Scott: They would have seen it.
Rym: so So you've done other things with your body before.
Scott: yeah Yeah, but people weren't there seeing it anyway.
Rym: How do you know?
Rym: how do you know there isn't some security camera that is in the ceiling that you don't know about?
Scott: How do you know?
Scott: I know you can make real tiny cameras I'm 100% sure anyway.
Scott: Then I had to go to my parents house to fix their computer Which is mad broken.
Scott: and let me tell you this computer is crazy broken Crazy broken like.
Scott: you'll turn it on and it'll work.
Scott: then you'll turn it on again And you'll get a kernel panic right away about the.
Scott: it'll say like the kernel tar ball is in an improper compressed format you'll reboot it again and it'll start uncompressing the kernel and then give a different kernel panic about not being able to Mount the VFS.
Rym: know it seems like many of the computer the computers you have given to your parents have always had problems And you keep having to do things to them.
Scott: Yeah, and then check this out.
Scott: So I try to boot in Ubuntu CD on the thing and it starts to boot the CD and then gives a kernel panic from a CD.
Scott: from a CD I Think the last computer they had the IDE controller broke and the one they have now.
Scott: I'm pretty sure the IDE controller broke now.
Scott: So I'm thinking that they they have some sort of power Problems and I'm gonna buy them a UPS.
Scott: when I cuz I ordered them a new motherboard CPU and RAM.
Scott: By the way, the motherboard and CPU RAM I got them was a 1.6 gigahertz sempron with 512 megabytes of RAM with a motherboard that has a built-in g4 6100 micro ATX 64 bits processor for a hundred and seventy four dollars.
Scott: that's faster than either of our computer Faster than any computer that any of my friends own period hands down and it was $174 for the motherboard CPU RAM video card sound card network card.
Scott: So all rolled into one.
Rym: so who was in the forums?
Rym: who thought that building a thousand dollar computer was a good idea?
Scott: I don't know, but they were dumbass.
Scott: I Mean this thing.
Scott: granted this thing has an onboard video card and it's not.
Scott: it's a 6100 and the one in my computer is a 5900 and You're not gonna play half-life 2 at Really good speeds.
Scott: I mean, it'll be barely playable.
Scott: However, you can just for a few hundred bucks slap You know a newer GeForce in the PCI Express slot and you are good to go.
Rym: You could spend $500 on a video card and still be cheaper than that thousand dollar computer.
Scott: Yeah, not only that but you know the sempron not the fastest processor But 1.6 gigahertz 64-bit processor is enough for anything you're gonna do.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: And I only got 512 megs of RAM, but to double that add 50 bucks.
Scott: So 250 plus a video card and you're set.
Rym: Anyway, the UPS is probably a good idea.
Rym: I mean we UPS.
Scott: if I had our entire house, I'm beginning to think that's the problem because they had this really Strange old ghetto power strip.
Scott: That was mad shady.
Rym: Why did you let them use that?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I I didn't really have much say in that matter.
Scott: You pretty much just brought a computer to their house and it was plugged in and you didn't look at what it was plugged into In those days.
Scott: I didn't pay much attention.
Scott: So I'm gonna replace their motherboard CPU and RAM.
Scott: see what I can do with the old motherboard CPU and RAM.
Scott: I mean, I bought this computer for them back in the day for $400 and They never gave me the $400.
Rym: So it's you know what they did.
Rym: help you, you know, go to school and pay for that's all your upper side.
Scott: Do you want here?
Scott: That's what they say.
Scott: Anyway the point is Is that I'm gonna fix this computer up and computers are wicked cheap and also this computer is strangely broken.
Rym: Better call Randy.
Rym: there's a ghost in there.
Scott: I know it's a non-deterministic computer.
Scott: What's the world coming?
Rym: We better get a skepticality on it.
Scott: I know it's craziness.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So anyway in the actual news Wikipedia now there's been a lot lately about how Google and Yahoo and Microsoft have been kowtowing in various ways to the oppressive regime in China.
Scott: Yeah, it seems like your choices are kowtow, which is look down upon but then you can do business in China Where there's a billion people to pay you.
Scott: Yeah, or you cannot kowtow, which is good, but then a billion people in China.
Scott: It's like, you know, it's like what's better not to influence those people at all or to influence them in a censored way.
Rym: Now kind of like the way I always like to break up the way France Britain Spain and Portugal treated natives they ran across.
Rym: It seems like the companies here.
Rym: you can break it down the same way.
Rym: at the bottom end You have Yahoo who pretty much just openly collaborate Helping the Chinese find dissidents that they can then torture and kill or whatever they do to them.
Rym: then you have Google who allows the censorship and does all the censoring China wants.
Rym: but on Any time something is censored Google says hey we censored something and they only censor the Chinese one.
Rym: Then there is Wikipedia.
Rym: That is the news today.
Rym: Wikipedia has given China the big double-deuce and said we're not going to censor shit anybody and You can take that.
Rym: however, you want China responded by banning Wikipedia from China.
Scott: See here's the problem is that if there's no Chinese people on Wikipedia The Chinese Wikipedia won't be edited very much and therefore won't have much information to be censored and no one will see it.
Scott: So it basically makes they might as well not have the Chinese Wikipedia if they're not going to censor.
Rym: Well, I think they block normal Wikipedia, too Because there there's now.
Rym: the one thing I found interesting a lot of people slash dot pointed this out was Why doesn't China let Wikipedia do whatever it wants and just edit Wikipedia to talk about how great communism is.
Rym: There are more people.
Rym: The Chinese government can hire more people to edit it the way they want it.
Rym: then Wikipedia could have Preventing it from being edited.
Scott: But Wikipedia can do is prevent it from being edited by China.
Rym: Yeah long term There are no long term protections in Wikipedia.
Rym: There are short-term protections for things like abuse Like if a million people suddenly decide to change an article about something stupid like to try to add bananas to an article.
Scott: Well doesn't every IP address in China begin with you know, some range of numbers that they can just block Tor?
Rym: Yeah, there are many ways around that.
Scott: Do you think see this is the thing?
Scott: Governments like China don't seem to understand that Tor exists and that their citizens are using it.
Scott: How are they gonna know to use it for their advantage?
Rym: Of course?
Rym: Germany recently has been attacking Tor.
Scott: Oh, yeah, they.
Scott: they took a bunch of Tor servers.
Rym: Yeah on the auspicious grounds that child pornography might be involved in some way.
Scott: Therefore we're taking all these people's computers, even though these computers Don't actually have child pornography on them.
Rym: Not only that but if their argument were we're going to seize these computers look at the logs and track down the child porn I would while I would disagree with parts of that on fundamental, you know freedom issues at least it would make sense.
Rym: Good, but here's the thing There are no logs.
Rym: Seizing those computers can do nothing because there's absolutely no way from seizing one computer to find out who connected to that Tor server.
Rym: That's how Tor works.
Scott: yeah, the thing is you know would be cool is if I had some sort of Tor server and there was a way to tell From the logs who was a child pornographer or whatever.
Rym: Oh, I'd turn him in.
Scott: Yeah, I would have no problem just like setting up.
Scott: Here's an anonymous thing.
Scott: You can everyone can be anonymous on the internet, but I'll know if you're doing child porn.
Scott: That's the only thing that will show up is if you're a child pornographer then you're in.
Scott: your anonymity will be you know destroyed.
Scott: That way child pornographers wouldn't be able to use it.
Rym: The problem here is just the collateral damage because it seems like whenever Governments try to tackle this problem of child porn and while I it is definitely a problem.
Rym: It's a very bad thing.
Rym: I don't I wonder how wide spread of a problem It is that the collateral damage of all these measures governments take to prevent it are worth it.
Scott: Well, here's what bothers me right is that they're like doing all these things You know to stop child porn and taking things down that are mostly used for non child porn.
Scott: I mean, I'm sure there's a torrent somewhere of a child porn.
Scott: there has to be just because the internet exists.
Scott: But take you know attacking bit torrent because someone made a bit torrent of a child porn is not good.
Scott: But if you go on IRC, you know in certain IRC networks When I used to go on IRC to go to like, you know I would go to some room about a video game to get a help or I'd go to some room about Linux to ask.
Rym: So I used IRC for any reason other than finding illegal.
Scott: That's the only reason I used IRC and you would go in there and like.
Scott: the top 100 rooms would all be Child porn kitty xxx.
Rym: Well, you know what the secret there is.
Rym: every one of those rooms are full of nothing but FBI agents.
Scott: It could be.
Scott: But the point is even if those rooms aren't just full of FBI agents Why don't they just it's so there's so many obvious.
Scott: there's a you know, hi.
Scott: I'm a child pornographer.
Scott: I'm a. I look at child porn guys And they caught that kid.
Scott: Yeah, there was some kid who is on my floor and he was stupid and he didn't know how to secure his computer.
Scott: So he accidentally was sharing One, you know a folder on his machine on you know Local network area and it had child porn in it and they busted him.
Rym: Yeah, because the way RIT works the network is pretty much the Wild West.
Rym: So if your computer is in any way compromised and you go to RIT Everyone else in the school other than maybe the frat boys Will be in your computer rooting around looking for whatever fun stuff and usually be printed a goat siata some random shared printer.
Rym: Yes, we did.
Rym: Yeah Anyway, yeah, he was reported to the police like a hundred times by from all the people who found that Mmm, but anyway in the whole Wikipedia thing Jimmy Wales, you know the Wikipedia guy His quote was quote we occupy a position in the culture that I wish Google would take up Which is that we stand for the freedom of information
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And now the one thing I would say is I mean everyone says oh, this is great Wikipedia is standing up against China and Wikipedia is the only service that has the balls to tell China They're not going to censor.
Rym: but at the same time I think Google's policy is also equally valid because they're basic something they basically go after.
Rym: is that alright?
Rym: the choice is either no one in China has any access to Google at all and they lose all that information or they will get access to everything we can give them access to and We will tell them straight up that the government is censoring everything else.
Rym: Yeah, that's pretty much, you know, the other difference is that Google and Yahoo have a financial interest.
Rym: Wikipedia has no financial interest.
Rym: So there is almost zero pressure on Wikipedia to deal with China or not deal with China.
Rym: they could care less.
Rym: it wouldn't affect them at all.
Rym: Mm-hmm, if Google doesn't deal in China that is going to be a serious long-term economic consequence.
Scott: So really neat is someone like Microsoft to not deal in China?
Scott: Yeah, this is actually one of the failings of open-source software is that you can just you use it in.
Rym: You know remember you could have GPL but then have a clause in there that says accept the Chinese government.
Scott: I think that's something actually that they're talking about for GPL 3 if I recall correctly is there you know.
Scott: They're saying you can't use this if you're a horrible repressive government.
Rym: There's also an anti-military clause that's been propping up now and again.
Scott: I don't know about that.
Scott: Shouldn't be?
Scott: you, you know, cuz you know, you could use Linux on like soldiers laptops.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But what if?
Rym: what if someone who made an Application decided that they didn't want soldiers to use it or they didn't want militaries to use it.
Scott: They can add that to their own license.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: No, it's they use the GPL plus this add-on.
Rym: Yeah, it's like.
Rym: it's like a mod to the GPL a plug-in.
Scott: Yeah, it's just kind of like I don't know.
Scott: Well, I agree with the you, you know, if your government partakes in genocide You can't use my software to aid your genocide.
Scott: that way you don't end up being IBM where everyone's like Oh IBM help Nazis but at the same time You know if some legitimate army wants to use your software, what's the difference?
Rym: I mean the question is do you when you create something that is if I'm you know Just bits you create some data or a program you arrange some bits?
Rym: What are the rights you have regarding how it is used?
Rym: because the GPL basically says that I?
Rym: Like other people to use my stuff, but I reserve all these rights and I can fuck you if you violate.
Scott: Well, it's mostly if I default.
Scott: all rights are reserved.
Scott: So you're saying I am NOT reserving a whole mess of rights and only reserving so.
Rym: that means I have the right to restrict anything I make in any way I want.
Rym: so I could just say no one named Bob no women and No people with one eye are allowed to use my media player.
Scott: go for it.
Scott: That'd be awesome.
Scott: Oh That'd be so cool.
Scott: We should make software like that.
Scott: so yet again They have released the list of the top 50 most expensive ad words.
Rym: now if you don't know how Google AdWords works Mesothelioma is worth a lot of money and nothing else matters.
Scott: well mesothelioma was worth a lot of money.
Scott: Oh really the way it works is let's say you want to put an advertisement on Google in the Google Ads.
Scott: You have to pay money for every click, so let's say I want To get a hundred visitors to my website.
Scott: I have to pay a hundred times the amount of money Depending on what words I want.
Scott: So let's say I have a video game website and the video game the word video game costs five bucks And I want a hundred visitors.
Scott: I have to pay five hundred bucks.
Scott: Then Google will put my ad up and keep putting it up Until there are five hundred clicks on it.
Rym: now there are numerous problems with this.
Rym: mainly one thing and actually I've done this before A lot of people had little movements where say you don't like chiropractors Google for chiropractor or back pain and every time you see a chiropractor's ad word click on it.
Rym: It took almost no effort from you, and you just cost them a reasonable amount of money.
Scott: yep And if you know sometimes the ad words are on Google.
Scott: Google likes that because Google makes money.
Scott: But if the ad were if the advertisements appear on some other websites like you'll go to some.
Scott: you know your friends Webcomic and it has Google ads on it.
Scott: if you click on that not only you know not only does that subtract one click from The person advertising, but it gives the person with the website money.
Scott: You know so.
Scott: anyway This is a list of the 50 most expensive ad words.
Scott: So if you're an advertiser and you want to advertise You know specific words.
Scott: some cost more than others.
Scott: very popular words cost a lot and very unpopular words Don't cost so much.
Rym: so what words are currently winning?
Scott: the currently most expensive in terms of average cost per click ad word is school loan consolidation.
Rym: now that makes a lot of sense because interest rates are going up and A lot of people who don't know a lot about how loans work Really think that consolidating their student loans is a good idea in case the interest rates go higher.
Scott: Yep, and there's a lot of spam going on about school loan consolidation.
Rym: God you wouldn't believe how much how many letters we get in the mail that look legitimate like they act like they're from the federal Government, but they're actually just student student loan consolidation.
Rym: bullshit scams.
Scott: Yeah, I mean God what?
Scott: It's basically it when you think about it.
Scott: It's a sort of a good system and sort of a bad system in that one horrible spammers are able to advertise and That's not so good.
Scott: I mean, I'll be much happier if they just got they can advertise anyway.
Scott: freedom of speech I know I know but it's like if I was running an ad system and someone came to me to buy ads and they said Yeah, I want to run this, you know scam ad.
Scott: I would say no you can't run the scam ad.
Scott: However, it is sort of a self filtering system because if a scam gets popular it gets very expensive.
Scott: I mean if you want to run an ad about school loan consolidation You have to pay sixty nine dollars and sixteen cents on average for one click.
Scott: That means if you want to scam a hundred people you have to pay at least Sixty nine.
Rym: not only that I can cost you sixty nine dollars just by clicking on something in my web browser.
Scott: Yep So it does.
Scott: it is sort of a self-fixing system and it's well the thing someone ends up paying a ton of money is basically dying anyway.
Rym: Google is looking for a way to get away from this system entirely because they keep getting sued about false clicks Like the ones I was talking about.
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: click fraud is a huge problem and a topic for another day but the point is is that the Google ad system is where most of Google's money comes from and that's why they're so powerful and huge and This is a pretty good insight into how the system works.
Scott: If you don't understand
Rym: not only that It's a good insight into what's going on in the world because before Mesothelioma was the number one thing because there were a lot of lawyers who were basically scamming old people who may or may not have had this cancer that is caused partially by exposure to asbestos and Getting them to try to sue the people who may have exposed them to it.
Rym: And while the lawsuits would often be lost The lawyer would get a bunch of money from the old person and if the lawsuit won The lawyer got a whole bunch of money from the old person and from the company.
Rym: It was win-win unless you're the old person with mesothelioma.
Scott: Yeah, if you just look at the list of the most expensive ad words, it's basically hey I wonder what the most popular scams are going on.
Scott: Oh, there they are.
Rym: Anyway things of the day Who?
Scott: I got a good one.
Rym: I had a good one But because of very the fact that my computer is old and busted and it's steady state meaning I'm not upgrading anything on it until I buy a new one.
Rym: Also the fact that the flash players in Linux don't work so well.
Rym: Firefox crashed and I couldn't find this thing again.
Scott: So what are you gonna do?
Rym: Well, I might set myself on fire and jump off of - Tereth.
Rym: Yeah See now because my the thing of the day which was a fat scary guy who made a video Yelling at people on 4chan for messing with him on the internets.
Rym: Which was you got?
Rym: this guy got old?
Rym: Okay, anyway, mm-hmm, I have to go with an old classic that I can't believe we haven't talked about on the show.
Rym: I'm sure I've referenced it Many times.
Rym: you've probably heard me say something and you wondered what the hell I was talking about.
Rym: There's a good chance.
Rym: I was talking about Lord of the Rings on the go.
Rym: Oh Yeah, now this is something that has brought belly laughs from Hundreds of people.
Rym: I'm in and around the front row crew for many years.
Scott: Then a third.
Rym: it has brought so many inside jokes into our lives to this day.
Rym: If I look at Lord of the Rings on the go within two pages of it I will be laughing out loud.
Rym: Even if I try not to.
Scott: so what is Lord of the Rings on the go?
Rym: Well, I'm glad you asked.
Rym: Lord of the Rings on the go was a. it wasn't a Photoshop Friday But it was a comedy goldmine on something awful years ago like pretty much right after the third Lord of the Rings movie came out the Return of the King and What it was is that was years ago.
Rym: Yeah, we're old.
Scott: Yeah, we are.
Scott: Okay, go on.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well my favorite thing if you want to remember how old you are The nightmare before Christmas came out more than ten years ago.
Scott: Yeah, it sure did.
Rym: So this is a basically, you know, something awful has the amazing Photoshop contest.
Rym: They're always hilarious.
Rym: This was like that except instead of making good photoshops you were encouraged to make bad Photoshops not only bad photoshops, but bad photoshops involving cars and the Lord of the Rings.
Rym: Yeah, now the it's hard to explain the humor.
Rym: you just have to look at it.
Rym: but imagine like a car and it's crashed into another car and you see a badly photoshopped Aragorn sitting in it.
Rym: and Then underneath you see Pippin yelling.
Rym: He was stabbed by a four-door blade Ha ha ha.
Scott: That was a good one.
Rym: Yes, it was.
Rym: and of course the the the Triumphal moment of this entire comedy.
Rym: gold mine though.
Rym: There are hundreds of them Like that's no or corn.
Rym: one does not simply drive into mold or.
Rym: But there's this.
Rym: now you all remember the scene in the Lord of the Rings the Return of the King.
Rym: this is a spoiler.
Rym: Denethor sets himself on fire and jumps off of minus Tereth to his death.
Rym: Yep, and despite the fact that it was a very serious scene it ended up being hilarious in the movie partly because Denethor the way The cinematography went he had to run like two minutes to get to that cliff and jump off of it.
Scott: If you had to go all the way from the castle around the tree down the walkway and off the cliff and they showed you just Now the video or the video God the Photoshop.
Rym: here is there is a Pinto as in the car.
Scott: It is, you know, the one that is famous for setting on fire.
Rym: It is on fire.
Rym: Denethor is in it as in his face is there in the driver's seat and he's screaming and he is also on fire and it is Flying off of minus Tereth.
Rym: Whoa If you want to laugh, it's much funnier if you look at it.
Scott: Yes, and you know that you get the joke.
Scott: It's sort of like if you don't know Lord of the Rings and you don't know cars Even just a little bit.
Scott: you need to know cars But you got to know Lord of the Rings and then this will be funny.
Scott: if you don't know Lord of the Rings You're not gonna get any of this.
Scott: you can go why.
Rym: you've also got to know a lot of those funny old internet picture cliches like the guy really like a Yeah, really like there's.
Rym: this guy was a car and he stacked too much stuff on it and the suspension is failing.
Rym: And of course, there's the potato potato joke.
Rym: Mmm, anyway, it is hilarious.
Rym: It is old if you haven't seen it before.
Rym: welcome to the internet if you don't get it.
Rym: Welcome to the internet.
Scott: So my thing of the day here, I'm I like a whole lot.
Rym: It's called Unix the whole hog H-o-l-e H-a-w-g and you'll see why that's well, I guess if you make someone a eunuch, then there's really just a hole there.
Scott: It's it's Unix the whole hog the whole hog of operating systems by Neal Stevenson author of snow crash and diamond age and kryptonomic on and all those good books that everyone who's a geek likes.
Scott: and this is a Short essay that you can read in a few minutes.
Scott: Comparing this particular drill like a drill as in it makes holes in wood and other materials.
Scott: That is made by the Milwaukee tool company called the whole hog And this drill is pretty much the motherfucker of drills I think like he in the in the piece here he tells a story about a guy who was drilling into the side of a house.
Scott: the bit on the drill got stuck and Instead of the you know drill going digga digga digga or stopping or anything like that The drill the guy was still holding on to it spun the guy around holding the drill.
Scott: This is a motherfucker of a drill and basically, the whole thing is using this drill as a metaphor for how the Unix operating system is You know and trying to explain to normal people why people who use Unix are the way they are and why Unix is the way it is and I just want to read a short paragraph about it here.
Scott: a Smaller tool is dangerous, too but for a completely different reason.
Scott: it tries to do what you tell it to and fails in some way that is Unpredictable and most always undesirable.
Scott: But the whole hog is like the genie of the ancient fairy tales who carries out his master's restrictions literally and precisely and with unlimited power often with disastrous unforeseen consequences.
Scott: And that is what Unix is like.
Scott: So everyone should read this because it's hilarious and especially because now that I know about this drill I kind of want this drill.
Rym: Well, like think about if you're in Unix and you type RM - RF star star and you forget that star dot star Or you you've meant to type something you type something else.
Rym: You're fucked.
Rym: It's over Because it does exactly what you wanted it to do with unlimited power no Unforeseen consequence.
Rym: it does what you told it to do not what you wanted it to do.
Scott: I know he's.
Scott: that's exactly the point of this pieces.
Scott: He says how this drill is such a powerful incredibly dangerous You know monster of a drill that you can drill anything with it But if it fails to drill that's your fault.
Scott: and he compares it to.
Scott: you know He compares Windows and Macintosh to like power drills you buy in Home Depot that are basically crap compared to the whole hog.
Scott: But with those you can't really screw up because they're nice, you know homeowner drills.
Rym: But anyway today being Monday and being a new week We were debating what to talk about and we realized we hadn't done a theme week in a while Theme week.
Rym: and this there's an idea We've been kicking around for a while and we decided this would be the perfect week to do it for a number of reasons.
Rym: But we decided to do our origin stories Now not the physical origin of the front row crew which we've already done But instead the origins of all of our geekeries know.
Rym: how did we get into computers?
Rym: How did we get into anime?
Rym: How did we find manga or video games or the secret topic?
Rym: We'll talk about on Thursday?
Scott: How did we become so skilled and knowledgeable in so many different areas?
Rym: see that's Scott's view.
Rym: I'm looking at it.
Rym: more is how did I become interested in this?
Scott: See, I think the thing is is that for me personally I'm interested in things that I have skills in or I build skills in things I'm interested in.
Scott: so they kind of go hand in hand.
Rym: What about race car driving?
Rym: You have no race car driving skills and you're already do I mr.
Scott: Go kart loser One.
Rym: those were Wildwood go-karts where the only determiner and who wins is who got the one car that doesn't Constantly backfire.
Scott: and is it any different in f1?
Scott: Is it?
Rym: I don't know if Kimi and Alonzo were in the same car?
Scott: Well next year Kimi is gonna be in a Ferrari and Alonzo is gonna be in a McLaren.
Scott: So we'll see what happens.
Rym: Yeah anyway Yeah, now I was also inspired to this partly because in the forums lately There seemed to be a lot of recurring threads of how did you get into anime?
Rym: What was your first anime?
Scott: Yep, so we're gonna cover that Wednesday.
Scott: Yeah today we're gonna cover How do we get into the computer gig?
Scott: because that's our jobs.
Rym: So anyway today computers, you know, obviously we're interested in computers.
Rym: We're geeks.
Rym: We use computers a lot and it seems like a lot of people Really take computers for granted or just you know, their tools and nothing more which I'd take that view to a point.
Rym: But at the same time I can remember precisely how I became interested in computers and how I became good at them.
Scott: Well, how did you?
Rym: oh so you want me to go first?
Scott: I could go first also because I also precisely remember my early interactions with computerized devices.
Rym: Yeah Well, very simply I Always wanted to get on the Internet.
Rym: I always wanted to have a computer.
Rym: I'd seen war games and I was absolutely convinced that I could do all of those things with a computer.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: And then when I got to middle school, I mean we had no computers in my elementary school It was the Catholic school We had like one Apple computer and one IBM computer that they never let me touch.
Rym: But then when I got to fifth grade, I went to public school.
Rym: They had a lot more money and they had a whole bunch of like Windows 311 computers with a terrible word processor on them in addition to a whole bunch of terrible terrible games.
Rym: and I remember that I had to read this book called The Bear Stone.
Rym: it was called the Bear Stone.
Rym: It was about air stone.
Rym: it was about this Indian kid as a reservation Indian kid and I had to write a book report on it.
Rym: and Because I was one of the smart kids in the class.
Rym: They let like the five smart kids go to the computer lab and use this word processor to type their book report Instead of writing it by hand.
Rym: So I made this book report and I put a bunch of clip art in it and I used three different fonts and I thought it was really awesome.
Rym: and I made it and there was the spell checker and that was amazing to me and I printed it out on the special printer that at the school and I brought it home.
Rym: And my grandpa is a newspaper guy as in a typesetter.
Rym: he spent most of his life working in old-school newspapers like manual mechanical printing presses and I showed this to him and he said something to the effect of I'm glad I'm retiring because my job is now obsolete
Scott: yeah,
Rym: and he'd show that he took that book report and he brought it to his work and he showed it to people and he Basically said look what my grandson did he can do all the work that we do.
Rym: Yeah Wow, but then I mean still there was no internet.
Rym: There was no online.
Rym: I didn't have a computer.
Rym: It wasn't until I joined the computer club at my middle school.
Rym: now Don't be under any illusions the computer club at my middle school was quite Oregon Trail the club.
Rym: every Monday We would hang out after school in the computer lab with the nerdy guy who ran it playing Oregon.
Scott: Yeah, that's right.
Scott: and scorched earth in Carmen Sandiego.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: No Carmen Sandiego We had and scorched earth and stunts 4d racing.
Rym: Oh, that was the best frickin game And lhx which was a really good 286 Helicopter fighting game.
Rym: All right, and just even then I didn't know anything about computers.
Rym: I barely knew how they worked.
Rym: I knew to type scorch bat and I could play scorched earth.
Rym: Yeah, and I kind of knew that the bigger the resolution was the smaller things were on the screen.
Rym: But I didn't know why.
Rym: mm-hmm and I often broke the computers.
Rym: Oh, but I bothered my parents complete.
Rym: I wanted a computer, you know, can I have a computer dad?
Rym: can I have a computer?
Rym: that have a computer?
Rym: that can have a computer dad.
Rym: and One day my parents decided that This that happened often.
Rym: we didn't have a lot of money, but I was a kid and I didn't know better.
Rym: So I thought we had a lot of money.
Rym: So I always asked for things like give me a piano.
Rym: I need a piano I need a computer and I usually got them and eventually my parents bought me a computer.
Rym: So we went and we bought a Packard Bell Sx2.
Rym: a hacker tell that was my first computer.
Rym: It came with Windows 3 1 1.
Rym: Oh for work groups.
Rym: Well, it came with Windows 3 1 on it, but it came with the discs to upgrade that to 3 1 1 for work groups.
Rym: Well work groups, which was the first windows that had network capabilities that worked.
Scott: that yeah, but they were kind of useless.
Rym: They didn't actually work because I didn't have a LAN or anything Hyper terminal.
Scott: But I got I used it.
Rym: It came also.
Rym: Windows was not the primary operating system on this computer nor was DOS.
Rym: They were both there but over both of them Like running on top of Windows, which itself was running on top of DOS was Packard Bell Navigator.
Rym: Oh My god, did that make me hate computers?
Rym: It was the worst thing ever and it didn't make sense.
Rym: but I eventually started using DOS and learning how to do things.
Rym: and I started learning how to actually you know install programs correctly by asking people in trial and error and breaking things and fixing things.
Rym: and Eventually, I learned how to get on BBS's by dialing a phone number at hyper terminal.
Rym: I Guess I'll stop there and let Scott tell his first bit before I go on about the rest because I sure we can talk a Lot about our first internet experiences.
Scott: That's a good place right there.
Scott: So I guess I kind of knew about computers before Kindergarten like I'd seen them on TV and I had an Atari 2600 at some point and you know all that stuff.
Scott: So I was definitely interested in technologies and stuff.
Scott: and you know, if you had put a computer near me I would have been like ooh.
Scott: But it wasn't until kindergarten.
Scott: where I actually got at.
Scott: one is in my school elementary school.
Scott: every single classroom in the school or at least the majority of them had an Apple - in them somewhere and there was a lab or two.
Scott: that was basically a room full of Apple - and You know, I didn't get very many opportunities to actually touch the Apple - we just kind of sat there looking at you And I remember always looking at it.
Scott: Like I want to play with that.
Scott: I want to play with that.
Scott: When am I gonna get to play with that?
Scott: and day after day, you know kindergartens a half day.
Scott: So what you know what chance are you gonna get?
Scott: They eventually let me play with it a few times and you know All I remember from elementary school was that I pretty much used the Apple - and later on Macintosh's all throughout elementary school in school and Every chance I could and we mostly played Oregon Trail and this other really good game With dr.
Scott: Livingston and you had to find him I presume and all sorts of other fun games.
Scott: But the one thing I remember the most was that teachers would always like slowly Oh number word munchers Fucking word munchers, man.
Scott: That was shit.
Scott: They would always slowly explain to everyone like exactly how to use the computer.
Scott: They'd like art.
Scott: everyone push down All right, everyone push enter.
Scott: and I just like.
Scott: I just looked at it and it made sense.
Scott: I'm like their arrows.
Scott: that thing is highlighted.
Scott: I pushed the number of what I want to do.
Scott: I push enter to make things go.
Scott: I'm all set.
Rym: I guess that seems to be the common thread among you.
Rym: know Geeks know about computers versus people who don't.
Rym: is that we didn't have any inherent skill or anything.
Rym: We just weren't afraid to dick around with a computer break it Break out try to fix it and just constantly poke at it and try to figure out why things Remember
Scott: I was messing around with like word munchers debug menus and stuff and switching discs out and trying different things and you know Everyone else seemed to be pretty uncomfortable with me fooling around I guess because those things cost a lot of money.
Rym: Oh God when we brought the computer home My parents were like the whole family was standing around it like it was fire and we were cavemen.
Rym: We've got it on and it's sitting there in packet Bell Navigator and my parents are like So what do we use it for?
Rym: and I was like, I'll handle this.
Rym: and I sat down and I knew probably 1% more about that computer than my family.
Rym: Yeah, but because of that 1% I was God to them about it.
Rym: But yet they were afraid I was gonna break it.
Rym: So they tell me to do something but then when I started to move the mouse around they'd yell at me Don't break it.
Rym: Don't break it.
Rym: You want me to do it or not?
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Scott: Yeah anyway.
Scott: So in elementary school, I got a lot of Apple to skills and in the summer, you know a couple summers I forget which ones I went the like the local school system had like a summer program where you could like take two classes Classes and basically you spent half your day doing one thing and half your day doing another thing and then lunch in the middle.
Scott: So I would go there and I would always choose Gym and computers.
Scott: cuz I'd go and I spent half my day playing dodgeball and that's been half my day playing Oregon Trail.
Scott: But I also learned logo.
Scott: I was programming from the start bitches.
Rym: I remember logo.
Scott: I'm moving that turtle around like a nobody's business.
Rym: I turn the turtle into a helicopter and I use that instead.
Scott: No, no, you gotta use the classic turtle.
Scott: I mean Anyway, I was having the turtle solve mazes and stuff all on his own and shit like that.
Scott: I knew what I was doing.
Scott: I was mostly getting really really good at stunts 40 racing Yeah, and then in middle school, I think around the time I was 13 we got finally a computer in our house a 486 a spectacle Graphics and sound.
Rym: yeah, we both had 486.
Rym: Scott had a DA.
Rym: it was an IBM Aptiva.
Scott: It had a 100 megahertz 486 DX for processor with 16 megabytes of RAM.
Scott: I had four but it started out with eight and we upgraded it to six.
Rym: So you started with four and for like $200 upgraded it to eight.
Scott: It was like for a hundred to a lot of money.
Scott: We upgraded it to 16.
Scott: It started out with eight megabytes.
Scott: We upgraded it to 16. now this thing it came with Windows 3.1 regular Windows 3.1 But it also came with OS to warp.
Rym: I have a copy of the final version of OS to war.
Rym: now.
Scott: Let me say OS to warp was actually kind of good.
Scott: The problem was is that no so that we there wasn't OS to warp native software.
Scott: besides what came with the computer?
Scott: So we use the OS to warp native software sometimes but most of the time, you know, I wanted to play DOS games.
Scott: That was pretty much the purpose of this computer was DOS games and a few Windows 3.1 games and yep printing out things for school.
Rym: We all get into games.
Rym: But good God did I have an intricate series of batch scripts that would run the various games?
Rym: I had in the boot disks.
Rym: I needed they needed a boot disk to play doom - yep.
Scott: So eventually, you know, we I Rebooted the computer into you know, DOS Windows 3.1 mode, which I don't now understand is a dual boot and how that works.
Scott: And we kept it that way most of the time.
Scott: so the DOS games worked and we used Windows and OS 2 eventually faded and then Windows 95 came out and I Learned how to format a hard drive and install Windows 95 and then we got AOL and Netscape.
Rym: See the Internet is the fun part.
Rym: Yeah, we don't dwell long We don't wanna go long in this episode or get into all the various tangents We could follow.
Rym: but the Internet was always this mysterious thing to me because I always heard about it.
Rym: The Internet.
Rym: but no one that because I didn't know anyone who knew about computers could give me a straight answer as to what?
Rym: It was or how I could connect to it.
Rym: I knew that there was Prodigy and CompuServe and AOL But I didn't know which one of those was the Internet.
Rym: I thought that those were separate and they kind of were back then.
Rym: Being actually on the Internet back then was not something we could really do easily And we ended up getting Prodigy Classic.
Scott: oh my friend had that for his P IBM ps1 with my 2400 baud modem.
Rym: that was so slow.
Rym: I couldn't even save my game in Mad Maze.
Rym: Wow I used to play Magic the Gathering and chat rooms on Prodigy and a little bit of trivia.
Rym: My first screen name ever was origins.
Rym: I got it because there's a book on evolution that was sitting on top of our computer desk called origins something something something something Wow, that's kind of crazy though my parents used that name too for a while.
Rym: so did my brother because we had like one handle for the whole house.
Rym: and then eventually I figured out that I could set up different accounts for everybody.
Rym: and But the funny story here is when we got internet access we got Wow, which is a little known.
Rym: It was the first Unlimited access dial-up internet and it was really cheap and that's probably why I went out of business real quick Mmm, but I got it.
Rym: We got the internet.
Rym: I bugged my parents about my parents and we got a better computer and we got a 33 6 modem Holy shit.
Rym: And then I dialed in to Wow and it was on the internet.
Rym: and I opened up Netscape and the first thing I ever did on the internet was type into the search bar in.
Rym: I don't know what search engine I Was in.
Rym: I think it was the Wow search quotes bomb making instruction.
Rym: Oh No, and my parents Harris and my parents who were standing behind me said these days my uncle was there too.
Rym: He has something to the effect of.
Rym: I figured that's what he would search for And I pretty much spent the first month looking for it the most subversive things I could find Yeah, and I didn't find a lot because the internet wasn't actually so happening back then.
Scott: Yeah, basically for me the internet like.
Scott: I wasn't quite sure what the deal was at all.
Scott: like I kind of vaguely understood that the computer was gonna connect to something to get more computer action and Like, you know information coming from somewhere into the computer, but I didn't really get it like.
Scott: oh Eventually, it was like oh shit telephone lines.
Scott: I get it because my friend had an IBM ps1 with prodigy classic and he would you know They would call another computer on the phone and do all this prodigy stuff and I'd be like, oh It's just this program.
Scott: lets you do all these cool things.
Scott: and the OS to warp had an icon in it.
Scott: It's an information superhighway with a little folder Picture of a car and a highway and I was like if only I could get that to work.
Scott: But we had a 14-4 modem in the computer.
Scott: it came with it But we didn't have a phone line if we never hooked it up.
Scott: until later We eventually got AOL and hooked it up and around that time I was you know understanding how this thing worked and you know Minimizing AOL and opening Netscape and I was disconnecting from AOL and dialing into the local library with hyper terminal To check if there were books.
Rym: I was dialing into all sorts of wares things as I discovered There were a lot of wares BBS is about.
Scott: yeah, I didn't quite figure out the wares.
Scott: I was mostly downloading share wares and then deleting the funny funny story about wares.
Rym: I'll talk about this more on gaming day probably but the first games I got for the computer other than the ones my parents bought Right away like with with our second computer the Pentium 200 we bought two games with it But before that the first games I got that weren't with the computer.
Rym: some friend I met at like Starbase, which was like Space Camp Light I I went over to his house one day and he had all these games and I thought they were awesome.
Rym: So he was like, oh here I'll give them to you.
Rym: and I was like what you'll give me these games, dude How much of these.
Rym: cause he's like, I'm just gonna copy the disks.
Rym: I'm not giving you the original.
Rym: and Then at that point I didn't think but isn't that illegal?
Rym: I thought oh games are free Mm-hmm.
Rym: I just did never even occurred to me that you had to pay for things for computers at that point.
Scott: Well, see like I kind of understood that, you know games that came on floppy disks You just copy like.
Scott: that's how he got Wolfenstein 3d.
Scott: It's everyone got Wolfenstein 3d.
Scott: Yeah, but games that came on CDs It's like oh you can't copy that.
Scott: I mean and I was like you could just copy the CD to the hard drive.
Scott: We all understood how you could do that, but no one had a hard drive big enough to get.
Rym: that Drive was 540 megabytes.
Scott: mine was seven hundred and something megabytes.
Scott: So but I get the OS took up too much space.
Rym: remember we knew someone who got a CD burner Real early.
Rym: it burned at 1x.
Scott: See I was cool cuz I had a 4x CD ROM.
Scott: it could read at 4x.
Scott: Damn.
Rym: I had a 2x.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, so see we go in leaps and we like we leapfrog past each other.
Rym: cuz I had the crappy 46s X and Scott had the awesome DX, but then I had the Pentium 200 and then I got the Pentium 3 450 megahertz and then I got the Thunderbird gigahertz.
Scott: Yeah, it was a good time, which I still have.
Scott: and then I got the Athlon XP, which I still have.
Scott: Anyway, yep.
Scott: The point is is that you know after we got on the Internet's our knowledges started to increase exponentially.
Scott: I learned mad programming skills at summer camp and school and elsewhere.
Rym: Yep, my fiddling with serial cables turned into fiddling with giant networks at IBM.
Scott: So anyone who thinks that we don't know about technology, I've been technology and computer since kindergarten I would sit there on my 486 sx2 playing with like Presentation making software for hours.
Scott: Yeah, I mean most of the stuff we did was games.
Scott: I mean, I did a whole lot of playing of CD-ROM based DOS games.
Scott: I did a lot of writing stupid things and basic Yeah, but you know while doing those things I was forced to learn about the computer.
Scott: I mean, how am I supposed to be able to you know?
Scott: Install things and configure sound cards and all that without learning about IRQs DMA hard drives?
Rym: Yes, you kids are spoiled today.
Rym: You realize before sound blaster.
Rym: There was no sound on computers.
Rym: You couldn't play sound.
Scott: Yeah, do you guys understand what DirectX does and what you know as DL and all these other API's do?
Scott: is that?
Scott: If I write a game I can make that game play sound by using DirectX direct sound and that way no matter what sound Card your computer has if that sound card is supported by direct sound which every sound card in the universe is pretty much The sound will work Without direct sound.
Scott: back in the DOS days if you wanted to have a game to have sound That game had to know which sound card you had and it had to have support Specifically for your sound card.
Rym: and then in the install you had to go and specify the IRQs and DMAs which were the interrupt requests and the direct memory access.
Scott: yeah And you know you either had to know them or you had to hope that the automatic detection worked.
Scott: We never worked on my computer.
Scott: It worked all the time because my computer was awesome.
Rym: see a lot.
Rym: on a lot of computers though It would just crash and in fact the auto detects would usually say if nothing happens in five minutes it crashed.
Rym: Don't use it.
Rym: Yep, because it would probe the hardware physically and some hardware didn't like being probed.
Scott: No, some hardware did not like.
Rym: I still remember my sound blaster.
Rym: God.
Rym: I hope I got I had all this.
Scott: is it turning into the Old-dos computer episode and not the?
Scott: where did you learn computer?
Scott: Yeah?
Rym: I think I'll hold that off for another day because I have great stories about my old advanced wave effects.
Scott: 32 I have mad 486.
Rym: Oh and my friend can who had the much vaunted R64?
Rym: whoa, yeah, like the best sound card in the world and I was so envious until now that I know more.
Rym: I realized that we both effectively had the same sound card.
Scott: The point is is like a year before I got out of like my junior senior year of high school.
Scott: I think it was junior year You know I had a job and I saved up a thousand dollars and bought a computer and slowly added more and more stuff to it.
Scott: And I had Windows 95 be on there and I you know I started playing with Red Hat Linux and I had my own 56k modem in my room with my own phone line and my own internet bill and I was really doing some good stuff.
Scott: And that's where I learned most of my shit.
Scott: At least that's where I started to learn most of my shit.
Rym: I was looking at how to make bombs.
Scott: Yeah Well, I think I don't remember what the first thing I did in the internet was but I do remember that I spent a lot of time on like Yahoo AltaVista GeoCities and I was either looking for games or Making HTMLs and all that sort of thing.
Scott: Yep, I learned how to make HTMLs and web pages before I had a computer with an internet connection.
Scott: Yeah because I remember I was at summer camp and I learned HTML and C and then I got home and then we got the 486. so that's you know, and then we all know I think we had the 486 but then we got on the internet We got a. well So it was.
Rym: I remember when someone explained to me what HTML was and he basically said oh You just write text like words and then you have these tags that you stick around that tell the computer how to show those Words and I said, oh, that's easy.
Scott: It's really weird when I think about it now because Even pretty much up until like the second last year of high school I didn't know I wasn't like beyond the line of yeah.
Scott: now, you know God, I wasn't until I got that Pentium 3 that I really knew.
Scott: so it's surprising like how much I learned at RIT Even though in my mind I knew just as much now as I knew at the beginning of RIT except for what I learned in Classes, but that's so not true.
Scott: Yeah, I learned so many things at RIT.
Rym: The thing is a lot of what we've learned wasn't from classes directly.
Scott: No wasn't.
Scott: it was just from having computers.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I've learned more from filling with my busted ass computer here that I've learned in school.
Scott: Yeah, I learned most of my Linux stuff from just dealing with gen 2. for God It's like four years now almost So many years of gen 2ing and Ubuntu ing and Linux ing.
Rym: but we don't want to go long.
Scott: No we don't.
Rym: so stay tuned tomorrow and we'll talk in much greater detail probably about the origins of our video gaming ways or maybe our Role-playing and board gaming ways.
Rym: Oh one of the two.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: It's mystery.
Scott: Maybe we all right.
Scott: If you we're gonna either tomorrow is gonna be an episode talking about our video game Ways or our board and role-playing game ways.
Scott: go to the forum and vote.
Rym: and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at two oh six three three three one five three Seven.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.