Rym: It's Tuesday January 31st, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We nominally talk about gaming clubs with our returning guest Emily, but we mostly just run off on a whole bunch of tangents.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So we're here and once again.
Rym: We have a guest Emily who's been on the show before.
Emily: yep Hello So I don't really have much of a thing of the day except if you want to hear about how to chop onions the right Way.
Emily: I found a video about the correct way to chop onions But I figure you know that might not have a sufficient quotient of geek.
Scott: well We did do a whole episode on food one time on food wasn't really so much about food, but it was supposed to be.
Scott: Yeah, like it was funny stories about any food stories.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, it was just an excuse to get Adam on the show.
Emily: Yeah, well I've just you know come to the conclusion that my food skills are less than adequate.
Emily: so I was like poking around online searching for the correct way to stir-fry.
Emily: but Anyway instead of doing a thing of the day so much I thought I'd relate an anecdote a weird thing that happened to me yesterday.
Emily: Cuz I've you know I've been back home for the last couple of weeks because you know I'm going abroad And I'm not back in school and so I just came back to New York to start to you know wrap things up And you know I had to go see a few of my teachers And you know see my roommate for the last time and everything like that.
Emily: and so I Was.
Emily: it was kind of funny too because I bought my computer and then She's got a sexy little.
Emily: It's just an iBook oh, but it's so so so so wonderful, but anyway, so I The credit card cut me off because I'd never made a purchase over like $30 or something.
Emily: and they're like whoa computer sale what.
Emily: and then they shut it off.
Emily: So I had to you know after this big dramatic exit of like goodbye goodbye everyone I shan't see you for so long.
Emily: I come running back upstairs like five minutes later being like I can't get in the subway.
Emily: I have no money.
Emily: Give me two bucks.
Rym: You know I remember my credit card did that to me when I first ordered my computer when I was in high school.
Emily: Oh, it was so bad like $3,000.
Rym: They must have thought there's no way a kid in high school is $3,000.
Scott: Well, I had problems where the addresses would be messed up, but I never had problems with spending too much money.
Rym: Well a lot of credit cards mostly debit cards more than credit cards like almost exclusively debit cards.
Rym: I'll do this if you take out too much money all at once They'll fight your account and lock it until you call them and tell them that you're not that no one stole your card.
Scott: I guess it's a good thing that I have a credit card and not a debit card.
Emily: then I was late for my train and you know I get up to Grand Central and I'm just kind of hanging around.
Emily: I have about half an hour until my train comes.
Emily: so I'm in the you know the Great Hall.
Emily: It's kind of watching the people Kind of out of the way leaning against the wall And there's this girl next to me reading a book like she's sitting on the floor a couple a couple of yards away And I'm not paying any attention.
Emily: You know I'm just kind of watching and spacing out and got my computer.
Emily: And so she you know this guy in a leather jacket comes up and says something then walks away And you know not paying attention.
Emily: and then a few minutes later You know he's kind of creepy looking, but there's people all around.
Emily: I'm not paying any attention.
Emily: and Then a few minutes later this guy comes back, and he's acting like kind of weird.
Emily: He's like and he says in this like creepy hitting on a woman sort of voice like hey lady That's a nice book.
Emily: you got there, and you know he's being a creep.
Emily: and the lady's like get away from me.
Emily: I told you I'm not interested.
Emily: She's like what get get away from me.
Emily: I told you to go away and Then he starts like getting in close to her and cornering her and like he he hunches down.
Emily: He's like trying to force a kiss on her, and I'm like oh my god.
Emily: It's like some sort of rapist molester.
Scott: Just this sure like cops everywhere.
Emily: Well.
Emily: You know it was kind of out of the way.
Scott: guys right there army guys.
Emily: No, no we were.
Emily: we were kind of.
Emily: you know one of those and you know there wasn't.
Emily: There weren't a whole lot of people where we were.
Emily: we're kind of like in a corner out of the main In place where people go, but anyway it was like what the heck This is like really really out of line here, and so I'm like what a creep.
Emily: and so I come up.
Emily: I like kind of was like girl, and I was gonna.
Emily: I run up, and I'm like yo what the hell.
Emily: I was gonna kick him in the head.
Emily: I had like my leg all raised up like I was gonna kick him in the face And then we were gonna run away.
Emily: and then The girl turns around like with this weird expression on her face And she starts laughing.
Emily: the guy turns around like utterly flabbergasted like.
Emily: And then I realized I'm like oh my god.
Emily: You guys are just fooling around.
Emily: They're like yeah Yeah, we're.
Emily: I was like oh, they're a couple.
Emily: and but we were laughing so hard and she's like no seriously We we were just acting, but if he had been of her real you would have totally been my hero.
Emily: And she's like you totally almost got your ass kicked by a girl.
Emily: So we we hung out for like about five minutes And then like I went home on the train And I felt kind of good about myself because I was thinking like it turned out okay.
Emily: But if he had been like a real jerk who is trying to like Be like what was that?
Emily: Okay Then I would have totally been brave enough to go and stand up for that girl, and she said that yeah You totally stepped up, and that was like I'm gonna.
Scott: Go kick you.
Scott: That's a lot like the The purse snatching story.
Emily: yeah, that's what Rym said you know and that's what makes me feel really good about New York.
Rym: Like everybody's down on the city I mean look at this every time something bad is about to happen everyone around just kind of steps up and does the right thing.
Emily: What's like I'm like after 9/11?
Emily: it's like people really pulled together, and they'd help each other out.
Scott: I was always like What just people led stereotypes, and they were scared because there was he suburbanites.
Scott: he's always been that way.
Emily: well Even in the 80s in the early 90s I mean even in just the past decade It's gotten a lot better as far as crime rates and just cleaned up a lot.
Emily: But you know and some people have mixed emotions about like the Disney vacation and the Giuliani years or whatever.
Emily: But you know it's.
Emily: it's a good place to live.
Rym: It's really I think a bright and shiny Times Square is at least a lot cooler than a porn shop filled time.
Scott: Yeah, and I mean yeah, I just I just miss my three-card Monty.
Rym: That's that's a wonderful
Scott: Yes,
Emily: well I guess I'm just coming from the angle of like you know I live in Manhattan So I can't really speak much for some of the neighborhoods like in the Bronx and stuff because some of those are still a little Iffy, but
Scott: you
Emily: know New York's a good city.
Scott: You know what I really want to learn seriously.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, I mean I love Baltimore, but god damn there are a lot of angry homeless people following me around Whenever I walk outside.
Scott: It's like I had.
Scott: I remember I worked at a summer camp once and the other counselor was from like The worst place in all of Chicago area like the worst place, and she was like.
Scott: you know.
Scott: people think that you know you Suburban people think that like you go to a neighborhood Like Harlem where there's a bunch of black people all standing around in the street And they think that that's like a slum, and it's scary and dangerous.
Scott: No.
Rym: There's people in the street.
Scott: Yes That's not dangerous.
Scott: That's a great place to go.
Scott: you know where I where I've been you know every single window has bars over it No one's out on the street and the snipers in every window You know.
Emily: you gotta say though Even like you know alphabet city in the East Village and stuff that's cleaned up a lot since because my uncle used to live there.
Emily: He was telling stories about.
Emily: he kind of liked living in the building He was living in because it was.
Emily: it was run by drug dealers But they had snipers on the roof.
Emily: so all all other petty crime kind of cleared out and as long as you didn't mess with The drug people they'd leave you alone, and it was kind of like your building was protected by
Rym: In a city of God when Lil Zay and Benny kind of cleaned up the town even though they were selling drugs.
Scott: Yeah, it's like any mafia Mafia or gang in charge.
Scott: they don't let any other Mafias or gangs come in and as long as the police don't try to come in no one really fights or kills each other.
Scott: There's not a lot of violence It's.
Rym: so what do you do when a cruise ship with a thousand Yakuza on it parks in your Harbor?
Rym: Dumb dumb dumb.
Rym: Yeah We've had people complain about inside jokes before.
Rym: so yes, that was an inside joke.
Rym: read a manga called sanctuary.
Scott: It's out of print, but I can get it for you if you really want to.
Rym: yeah Can I spoil it?
Scott: It's like the best manga ever one of the best mangas ever.
Scott: well.
Rym: It's certainly it's not up there with.
Rym: you know Cantarella?
Emily: oh My god, I don't know why I've been.
Emily: I read Cantarella volume 2 when we were in the anime So you did read it.
Rym: Yeah, I did read most of it.
Emily: That's what I was making fun of when I was drawing all those little One I remember.
Rym: do we actually talk about Cantarella on the show?
Rym: Yeah, Cantarella is awesome.
Rym: Yeah in like a way that you just like want to laugh about it, but anyway in actual news The optimist keyboard which we've been nutting about for pretty much as long as we've known about Everyone has been nothing about who's seen it.
Rym: Yeah, it's finally kind of coming out.
Scott: Well, basically it's a but if you don't know it's supposed to be this keyboard where every key has a little monitor on it Made with o LEDs.
Scott: so like you're playing quake instead of having ABCD or AWS D They'll actually be little arrows and instead you know each.
Scott: instead of one two three four five You'll actually see like the little chain blade thing and the little pistol and the rocket launcher on your keys You know matching the icons on the screen or say you're using Photoshop or audacity or some kind of media entity type thing.
Rym: Your keyboard seven letters will have you know, the zoom in button.
Scott: just sitting there looking at you It makes a lot of sense because you know You only need the keyboard that you use it a lot But a lot of times the keyboard doesn't have any functionality.
Scott: like if I'm using I don't know Photoshop Start typing in the middle of the you know picture.
Scott: It doesn't do anything.
Scott: It only does something if I'm using like the text tool.
Scott: Yeah So binding all those things on the screen the buttons on the keyboard really makes it useful Considering it's a lot easier to just push a button then move the mouse click move the mouse again.
Emily: Well actually like at school a lot of the editing suites We have specialized keyboards and like.
Emily: well even my final cut Express came with a bunch of peel-off stickers that you could put over your keyboard saying, you know, yeah this function This is the razor function.
Scott: This is this eliminates all those stickers.
Rym: My nasty keyboard I used for like over a decade that had those marker I'd written things all over the keyboard for like mega TF and quick - yeah.
Scott: So anyway, they were gonna make this thing and they made a picture of it and everything they designed it But it's not out yet.
Scott: What they did make is a little thing.
Scott: That's USB and it has three buttons which have monitors on them and It's basically kind of a tech demo.
Rym: slash prototype slash.
Rym: buy this to give us money to make the real thing.
Rym: buy it to look cool.
Scott: I guess it might be useful to someone but not really useful to me.
Rym: I think it should be really useful to those ricer equivalents for computers.
Rym: People have the cold cathodes and everything all over.
Scott: their PC might be useful if it was wireless.
Scott: because then think about this.
Scott: Right, you could have a little thing next like your bed and you pick it up and it would have a button For like.
Scott: then on the screen It would say how many new emails you have and you could push the button to launch your email thing maybe something that reads your email out loud to you from your computer or The other button.
Scott: Yeah, you know, you're really stretching it Rolling in it and you push it to update the news.
Scott: or you know, you could come up with some pretty good stuff.
Scott: It has uses but nothing worth buying.
Rym: It's low resolution and it doesn't refresh quickly.
Rym: It's basically just a tech demo.
Rym: Yeah, you can actually see physically what this keyboard is going to be like but they are making it and selling it.
Rym: So yeah, I think it's gonna be $100.
Rym: It's kind of hard to tell from the website.
Scott: $100 to three buttons really doesn't cut it because I spent less than $100 and I get a mouse and a numpad Yeah, which doubles as a calculator and a thermometer.
Rym: I mean I guess to me if the Optimus keyboard as the original concept was ever comes out on the market I'd pay a good 200 bucks for that thing.
Scott: I think I don't think it's gonna cause 200 bucks.
Scott: Yeah, that's why I'm kind of leery of the current rate of three buttons for $100.
Scott: That means a hundred and four buttons for Yeah, wow, you're real good at math.
Rym: I like how you just came up with that figure so quickly.
Scott: Mm-hmm You know just out of the blue 104 divided by three That's about thirty four thirty five.
Scott: so thirty five hundred dollars.
Scott: so You may or may not know about this.
Scott: there's a thing called Star Force and Star Force is this software that comes with PC games certain PC games to prevent you from Copying and wheresing the PC games.
Rym: It's basically all of all those copy protection programs that have been out in the past.
Rym: The it seems to be the most effective and at the same time the most horrible.
Scott: So what this does is Installs a new driver Which is kind of funny actually and it which I'll talk about in a second and the driver kind of replaces your CD-ROM IDE driver things But it doesn't work.
Scott: So great.
Scott: So what ends up happening is you end up failing to read CDs and your IDE drivers and modules start failing and Windows like reverts all the way back to 16-bit mode at which point things just don't work.
Scott: And there have even been numerous reports of like Hardware destroying like your DVD roms will just die Because this thing uses the shitty drivers that just screw everything up.
Rym: and before you call shenanigans on that I'd like to note that it is fairly Trivial.
Rym: it's not so trivial anymore.
Rym: But back in the day.
Rym: It was fairly trivial to ruin CD-Rs and DVD readers and monitors by giving them improper input.
Rym: You take an old monitor and give it certain frequencies.
Rym: it'll just destroy itself physically.
Scott: So you basically have a thing designed to prevent people from copying CDs.
Scott: that in effect destroys many DVD roms and ruins computers and makes computers crash because it's unstable and poorly written and a lot of PC game people are using this and There's a new movement to boycott any game that uses star force and a lot of game companies are stopping the use of it But it's still out there.
Rym: I mean, it's.
Rym: I mean if any of you read penny arcade Tycho has been railing about it fairly often lately.
Emily: So what's an example of a game that all right seven sins a neato?
Rym: Africa core versus desert.
Rym: rats beyond divinity blitzkrieg rolling thunder breed chaos.
Scott: You don't have to read the whole list.
Rym: code name outbreak.
Scott: Yeah, it's in the idea that lots of them.
Rym: All right, wait a minute.
Rym: It's in the Garfield game Destroyed by Garfield.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: Point is is Today or the other day boing.
Scott: boing made a story about Star Force and they said yeah, it's it's malware Whatever.
Scott: So the guy in charge of Star Force is his Russian guy I think or Eastern European at the least sent them an email that was like, oh I will sue you.
Scott: You called it malware.
Scott: I called the FBI on you.
Scott: Yeah now obviously he's just lying.
Rym: That's the classic sign.
Rym: I mean sometimes you'll get a real cease-and-desist order from someone.
Scott: it looks like it's from a lawyer.
Scott: Well, it has lawyerly talk and not the kind of lawyerly talk in a Nigerian scam a real lawyerly talk.
Rym: But I guess rule number one because Jack Thompson does this a lot too Is that if you get any sort of legal threat like that and it ever includes something along the lines of I called the police Or I called the FBI or I called the Secret Service.
Rym: You can safely ignore it because it's bullshit.
Scott: yeah, it's someone just trying to scare you and being stupid and evil.
Scott: and If it's a real cease-and-desist, it'll be very lawyerly and very official and Then you should actually be scared of that.
Rym: because that means you know, unless there's something awful They've received hundreds of perfectly legitimate cease-and-desist that they've not only ignored but posted on the website and mocked publicly.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, but that the point is is that if it's something like this, I mean you can go read this thing online.
Scott: it's just hilarious.
Scott: and Apparently this guy has sent similar things to all kinds of people who say that star force is bad and Everyone's making fun of this guy now because he's such an idiot
Emily: Like you can't cover up bad information by just you know, telling people not to talk about
Scott: it.
Scott: He's not telling people not to talk about it.
Scott: He's scaring people into not talking about it.
Rym: Well, yeah, he's telling people not to talk about it Because if people do talk about it.
Rym: Maybe the companies that buy his terrible program will hear about this and realize that oh one it doesn't work - it actually harms my Customers.
Rym: and three the guy who makes it's kind of a nut job.
Scott: They should sue the guy who makes it like for real.
Scott: You know, it's.
Scott: it's like sometimes they sue people and it's stupid.
Scott: This guy should get totally screwed.
Rym: I mean I guess for anyone who's looking at for perspective on this a lot of people who are in the know Consider it as bad as if not worse than the Sony rootkit.
Rym: Yeah So use that as a nice.
Scott: The sunny rootkit would screw you over but it wouldn't destroy your DVD burner Yeah, or even you're just plain old CD-ROM or whatever.
Emily: you had nasty stuff on your.
Rym: I'm still shopping around for a computer and I Found pretty much I can buy a super awesome dual layer DVD burner of awesome speed for like 40 bucks.
Scott: Oh, yeah That's because you know This blu-ray hdvd thing is putting down the prices of the normal burners Which is fine because I have no desire for blu-ray or hdvd whatsoever.
Emily: That's why I totally got the Lower end iBook though because basically the only difference was that the 14-inch had the combo drive And that's just like a DVD burner and I'm like, it's not worth.
Emily: Okay, but I love.
Emily: my new computer opened it last night.
Emily: I was like jumping around the room.
Rym: Yeah, I I was trying to make my computer and I keep looking like.
Rym: I built it today in a new egg and it was About.
Rym: it should have been about five hundred dollars total.
Rym: But I fell into the trap that all computer geeks fall into when they're designing a computer online Where you know Rams not that expensive on four gigs.
Rym: Why not?
Scott: You don't need four gigs.
Rym: I know I ended up going with two gigs and they're like.
Scott: two is fine.
Rym: Three hard drives raid five.
Rym: I'll get the claw hammer.
Rym: It's not that much more.
Scott: Yeah, it is actually.
Rym: no, it's not.
Emily: So what would you use all that RAM for other than like podcast nothing even if he had four.
Rym: I'll point out that I was not literally saying I'll get four gigs.
Rym: it was just like it was an example of a computer geek sitting down and Just slowly expanding the scope of what they wanted just because they're not really looking at the price as much as they should.
Emily: I need RAM.
Emily: I'm the one of everybody who needs RAM because I do all the 3d I get exactly what I need and no more.
Rym: I gotta say PC3200 RAM is about 80 bucks.
Rym: It's almost nothing.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, 80 bucks times four There's.
Scott: three hundred and twenty dollars is quite a bit.
Scott: You can buy almost a whole computer for that.
Emily: Yeah, I'm here I'm be a skin-flint Yankee.
Rym: The main thing that got me was that the claw hammer is only $80 more than the lowest lowest end Athlon that'll fit in.
Scott: you know, there's is quite a bit in terms of CPUs.
Scott: There's some CPUs that can be had for $80.
Scott: Yeah So that's quite a jump.
Scott: I'm you I usually go up as long as the jumps are in the 10 to $20.
Scott: You know less than 20 bucks.
Scott: I'll keep going higher on the CPUs.
Rym: But as soon as there's a jump more than $20 see that's what it was I started at the lowest end CPU that'll fit in my computer and every jump up was 10 to $20 Until the claw hammer that I've settled upon the next chip up was $300.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah It's.
Scott: it's sort of like this graph where it goes up a little bit a little bit a little bit and then it goes crazy Like the next job.
Scott: It's like up by up by a dollar up by $2 up by $5 up by $10 You know and each next chip is only a couple dollars more than the last.
Scott: But then you look at it from beginning to end and you're like, oh all those little $2 is add up to like 50 bucks But that's okay.
Scott: but then eventually you see the next chip is like $50 more than the previous one and you got to say alright, it's not $50 faster than the previous one But it is $50 more.
Scott: so I'm not gonna get it.
Rym: though honestly, what I might do is I'll buy the lowest end chip that'll fit in that socket and Then a year from now.
Rym: I'll put the fastest chip that'll fit in that socket, you know that strategy Works in theory, but it not really because what happens what ends up happening is well keep in mind with computers for me I'm pretty much on a six-year upgrade scale.
Scott: Yeah, me too.
Scott: But you know, what happens is that chip?
Scott: That's the slowest one that goes in the socket will be too slow for anything you do.
Rym: It's more than three times faster than my current chip.
Scott: You have no idea this laptop here that I got from work as a crazy fast CPU, right?
Scott: It is the old.
Scott: the CPU is the only bottleneck for me on this thing.
Scott: It is constantly at a hundred percent is pissing me off and it basically makes it completely useless.
Rym: Well, see for me currently my bottleneck is actually RAM and hard drive.
Scott: you still you're gonna have a CPU bottleneck.
Rym: Trust me Only for encoding mp3 is most of what I do.
Rym: It's just very hard drive intensive.
Rym: That's why I'm getting the raid box.
Scott: It's more CPU intensive than you think.
Scott: you just don't realize because right now your CPU is getting maxed out.
Rym: No, it's not not even close.
Rym: Yeah, no when I do most of my audio filtering on the podcast My CPU sits around 40% and my hard drive is going.
Rym: chugga chugga chugga chugga chugga.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, you know what if your hard drive wasn't going chugga chugga chugga and you had an s8 a drive your CPU would be Going.
Scott: oh, I can't do anything.
Rym: You know what it doesn't because the cheapest chip that goes into my the motherboard I'm looking at is probably gonna be perfectly adequate for at least a couple years.
Scott: Yeah, what chip?
Scott: what chip is it?
Rym: It's uh, Athlon 64 3200.
Scott: that's not really the.
Rym: it's not the cheapest one that'll go in but it's it's very cheap.
Scott: Oh, so it's not the cheapest one.
Rym: Well the cheapest one that'll go in they don't sell on Newegg anymore Really?
Rym: Yeah, at least I didn't see it.
Rym: I Sorted by price and that was the cheapest one that was listed in stock.
Scott: I would still go look at some like Comparisons of chips to make sure.
Scott: because yeah, I did and I saw because it's an athlete, you know, cuz yeah I did.
Rym: I look at all the different cores and I looked at all the benchmarks and this isn't a computer show So I didn't really want to get into it.
Rym: But they're all very similar and the differences in the benchmarks are almost nothing until I get well beyond what I'm willing to spend.
Scott: Yeah, well that's the thing.
Scott: it I always mess that up recently when I look at benchmarks is because the graph doesn't.
Rym: Yeah, you look like a giant jump in the graph and then you looked at the scale is in like two hundredths of a second.
Scott: Well, no, usually what I have been is I look at the graph and it's a tiny jump and then I look closer and it's like a hundred.
Rym: Now I was looking and there's really very little difference in the range of chips that I'm willing to pay money for in terms of Performance.
Rym: if I jump beyond the range, I'm willing to pay.
Rym: there's a crazy jump If I get the at like the Athlon FX whatever but I don't need that.
Scott: Really it's like a thousand dollar processing.
Scott: Yeah, screw that.
Rym: Yeah, let's not get into it.
Rym: cuz you know This is happy get whatever you want.
Scott: But I'm just telling you getting the plan of getting the slowest one and then upgrading to the fastest one doesn't usually work because the fastest one stays crazy expensive.
Rym: Yeah, well it worked for me because honestly the PC I got now has pretty much one of the slowest chips that'll fit in it and I could have bought for very little money and extremely the fastest chip that'll go into this motherboard.
Rym: And the only reason I didn't is because this computer is so old that it's falling apart.
Rym: Anyway, you know things like this once I get my new computer I'm probably gonna buy whatever Athlon will fit in this computer when I make a server.
Scott: I thought about doing that too.
Scott: I can put the Athlon XP 3200 in my computer, but It's still out years later.
Scott: There's like a two or three year old computer.
Scott: that thing is still two or three hundred dollars.
Rym: It hasn't gone down in price at all really because the the fast ones that'll go into my computer are 50 60 bucks.
Scott: Well, that's because your computer is so old.
Rym: My computer is six years old.
Rym: That's about my upgrade.
Scott: My computer is two or three years old.
Rym: Yeah, like I said, I'm using your original plan.
Scott: You said oh, I'll buy the slowest one and then a year later.
Scott: I'll upgrade to the fast.
Rym: No, I was.
Scott: my plan wasn't specifically that I said a year or a year or two that no you need to literally wait six years And you know what.
Scott: then I will but you're not gonna live with that slow processor that whole time.
Scott: Yeah, barely you ever.
Scott: You know out and about the town or maybe drive down a highway or something.
Scott: You got a pee.
Scott: There's no convenient bathrooms.
Scott: There's a nasty bathroom or whatever and you resort to.
Scott: you know, peeing in the woods peeing in an alley something like that.
Scott: Well some guy developed what I think is a pretty awesome solution.
Scott: It's called the pee tree.
Scott: It's basically this giant porcelain tree and you pee on the tree.
Rym: That's just fantastic.
Scott: And the way the tree is made because the material you know The the liquid just kind of go flows down the tree nicely without getting all over the see.
Rym: I'm looking at the picture and one I imagine drunk guys just peeing on people across from them instead of peeing on the tree.
Scott: Well, if you're drunk, but you know, come on, even drunk guys can hit the toilet most of the time.
Scott: No, they can't most of the time.
Scott: no.
Scott: But anyway the tree, you know.
Scott: but the other thing is that the trees are big enough that won't happen.
Scott: and the tree has a little trough at the bottom of it where the P collects and then goes in the sewer.
Scott: and I think it's pretty good because a lot of other countries they have like these public urinals just like in the street like little booths.
Scott: You just go in and pee and it's sometimes it's really hard to pee in this country.
Rym: Yeah, well, it's.
Rym: it's like every business is afraid of having people who aren't gonna spend money coming in and using their bathroom.
Scott: I don't know why you're afraid of that.
Rym: They're afraid that everyone's just gonna vandalize them.
Emily: Yeah Well, it is kind of the case that people And it's also to keep like the bathrooms cleaner, I guess, you know.
Emily: So people don't just go in and use them as a public toilet.
Emily: It's like keeps the number of people down.
Rym: Yeah, well plus if I mean if there were public pay toilets you can bet there'd be a hobo who finds a dollar and lives In it.
Scott: Oh, yeah, that is a problem with the hobos.
Scott: But come on, not every there are many.
Scott: most of the country is a non hobo area.
Scott: They're only hobos in like hobo towns, you know.
Rym: So I got to say even a lot of times now I think about it when I visit New York City like to visit you and I Got a pee and there's nowhere to pee unless I go and pay for something somewhere
Emily: They used to have like public pay toilets like deposit a quarter and you can
Scott: pee.
Scott: They had that though I would totally like.
Scott: I wouldn't live in it like a homeless guy but I'd find a way to get in and hack the.
Scott: you Know the lock or whatever it is.
Emily: I would pee for free, you know Toilet seat is locked and then you then you put the the little coin in and it opens.
Rym: Wow, you know I can see so many problems with that.
Rym: I mean, alright, so you gotta see.
Rym: wait You got to put a quarter in to open it right?
Rym: You just pee on it.
Emily: Yeah People probably did.
Scott: I had an idea once that we should make like at the rest stops There would be like a free bathroom and a pay bathroom.
Rym: So people who were like, oh, you know this again Yeah, are you this to death?
Rym: It's infeasible.
Rym: I know give it up.
Scott: Give it up.
Scott: It's good in in in concept Possible to execute.
Rym: Alright, he had this idea that you could somehow have like a
Scott: premium
Rym: Toilet stall in a rest stops that you have to pay to get into
Scott: so that people who were all like Fussy would pay extra and we basically take all their money because they would spend it to go in the nice toilet That was clean.
Emily: What did have like couches like a perfume?
Scott: Stall yeah, so like all the other ones would be like unflushed or clogged and one that you had to.
Rym: well, no Yeah, Scott, I remember very specifically that you're involved Extortion like she said actually making the other bad.
Rym: No, never my idea when I was in fact the primary.
Scott: No, it wasn't.
Scott: you're just making shit up now.
Rym: We've we've argued this to death to death.
Scott: The only thing that was a extortion e was the fact that we would clean the the other one more frequent the pay one more Frequently.
Rym: then yeah, wasn't your other idea that you have to pay to get out to know?
Scott: But that would be a good idea.
Emily: You know, it would only work if it was like, you know a separate premium like lounge like.
Emily: have you ever been in?
Emily: the bathrooms at like the Eastman theater.
Rym: Actually, you know what?
Rym: I've never had to pee at the Eastman theater.
Emily: Yeah, well the Eastman theater has like these chandelier bathrooms And it's like it looks like a restroom with couches and stuff like that.
Rym: Was there an attendant the guy who stands there in hand you a towel?
Emily: No, but you know close.
Scott: I've been to fancy bathrooms like that.
Scott: Radio City Music Hall has fancy bathrooms.
Scott: Actually.
Emily: Yeah, so You know.
Rym: So I could see.
Scott: so we go to a rest stop and there's a. there's a ballroom Bathroom next to the normal public toilet.
Emily: Yeah You could do.
Emily: it is what I'm saying.
Rym: Yeah, cuz you need what I think you need a person.
Rym: There's no mechanical device that can allow a person into a place to pee Especially a guy and yet not allow them to pee without paying because they could just pee on the thing that takes their money.
Rym: All the vending machines would really stay Apparently Used to back in the day.
Rym: if you poured salt water into most vending machines, they just give you free stuff really It's just totally break them in.
Rym: I know they fixed this problem recently or recently like I think of ten years ago Because most vending machines have a little sign inside if you look that says it's basically warning salt water will not give free food.
Scott: I've never seen that in my life.
Rym: I've seen signs like that everywhere.
Scott: I'm sure that's not a snow.
Rym: I've seen them personally made not my cousin's brother's sister's dog, but I've never ever seen that.
Emily: yet to point it out to me I've seen you know funny pictures that are like do not push the venue.
Scott: Yeah, I see don't put your hand Slot because it'll get stuck.
Scott: That's that's a good one.
Rym: I saw like the one with like the crushed stick figure under a knockover coke machine.
Scott: Yeah, it's a great one.
Scott: Don't try to push it over.
Scott: It'll fall down and kill you.
Rym: But yeah pee is mostly salt and uric acid and water.
Emily: so Wet is like pee.
Emily: you pee out your armpits every day.
Rym: that explains.
Scott: Anyway, the tea tree is cool, and I hope someone installs a pea tree somewhere for me to pee on.
Rym: so This doesn't look like pea tree from the land before time does it?
Scott: no It's a giant white piece of ceramic not a course pterodactyl.
Rym: who likes to eat cherries.
Scott: Maybe it's a porcelain pterodactyl.
Rym: And my other concern is this is great for men.
Rym: What about a woman who has to pee?
Scott: Women don't seem to have a problem finding places to be.
Scott: do they?
Rym: are you serious Scott?
Emily: Have you ever seen the line?
Emily: That's like for all you the Joke.
Scott: not everyone in that line is there to pee.
Scott: women go to the bathroom to do all kinds of other stuff.
Scott: Oh my god, no it takes longer.
Scott: See here we are going on a rant here because you know Scott has just exceeded his quotient of sexism.
Emily: For all you listeners who are not aware Scott is the king of the sexist joke.
Emily: like I was nice I stayed home today because you know I figured going in the city.
Emily: I had other stuff to do.
Emily: I wanted to play with my new computer, and so I stayed at the house, and you know I looked in the fridge.
Emily: There's you know all the stuff.
Emily: I'm like maybe I'll make dinner, so I cook and he comes in the door.
Emily: He's like yeah, that's the way it should be.
Emily: you know the woman made us, but not what's sadder is even So easy?
Emily: no, it's.
Emily: it's like well as easy as it may be it's still like Grotesquely, you know you're like a relic from the 1950s.
Rym: Actually Think the operative thing here is that even when Emily's not here, and I have dinner ready, and he comes home He that he says the same thing to me.
Emily: Yeah We all know Scott's the wife in the relationship.
Rym: Yeah, yeah What the Necco?
Rym: they call it now?
Emily: He is the okay?
Rym: Yeah, but actually there's a funny anecdote related to that because RIT has a very.
Rym: I mean, I'm not.
Scott: I think we sold this one the jeopardy.
Scott: the jeopardy I think we told that.
Scott: I don't think we told this.
Rym: Well tell it anyway because we might.
Rym: I think we told it on one of the unaired lost episodes of GeekNights Maybe but basically the the feminist group at RIT.
Rym: They are a little bit beyond what I would consider rational feminism.
Scott: I think it's just because Yes, it's because the people who have a full-time job of working for the women-centered RIT are a little whoa Yeah, and they're all men too who run it.
Rym: it's kind of weird.
Rym: a couple of them that like all the heads of it are men and the advisor is a man and He's the biggest.
Rym: I mean I've met some simple dicks in my life.
Rym: This guy is the most horrible dick I've ever met.
Rym: he was just a giant jerk every time I ever spoke to this person.
Rym: it was the most adversarial relationship I've ever had with anyone, but We just we noticed that this group was doing a women's history month jeopardy, and you could sign up teams and compete on it and We decided that we were going to do something hilarious and by hilarious.
Rym: I mean offensive.
Rym: We were gonna go and we came up with this kind of like oh, what if we did this?
Rym: Oh, what if we did this and we just stand there with this big grins on our faces and no matter what the question was One of the answer was whatever.
Rym: the answer was yeah, because it's jeopardy.
Rym: see I would have lost right there.
Rym: Something like Pete would just ring in and say back in the kitchen To which you know obviously isn't the answer and then I would ring in and say where she belongs.
Rym: And we wondered how many times we could do this before they just kicked us out And and then we talked ourselves into actually doing it like let's actually do it.
Scott: And then you realize that the jeopardy was over like an hour ago.
Rym: So we spent an hour coming up with a stupid idea.
Rym: Then we spent another like 20 minutes actually working up the courage to go out and I was ready to do it.
Rym: that offense.
Rym: I just needed a team and then we were completely shot down by the fact that we missed it because we spent so much time Talking about it.
Scott: It would have been funny no, but seriously like if I tell a joke like you know a joke about maybe punch out in bicycles It's not because I'm racist or I actually think that people have a different skin or something.
Emily: The thing is though a lot of times you you have misinformation About women.
Emily: you say these things that even if they're not a joke a lot of times You're not joking.
Emily: you just say these really obscure things.
Emily: You're like Why would you think women do that?
Emily: or why would you?
Emily: it's like just intense stereotype like why?
Scott: oh?
Emily: God, let's let's see you're so alright.
Rym: What are women do in the bathroom Scott?
Scott: Put on makeup, and they look in the mirror.
Emily: Women take so long in the bathroom is one.
Emily: men have more places to go because they have urinals - it takes women longer because they Have to take off their pants and sit down.
Emily: then you know go through this whole thing.
Emily: Biological difference.
Rym: Once I was at a band event and we're all like.
Rym: we had eight buses full of kids And we all had to pee.
Rym: so we stopped at this rest stop and the girls all lined up And there's really no way to speed up what they were doing.
Rym: and the men we all had to go.
Rym: so bad that we used every urinal yeah, and the sinks and People took turns at the sink, but how are they?
Scott: there are more urinals than toilets?
Scott: Why don't these urinals take less space?
Scott: Why don't they just make the women's bathroom bigger?
Rym: You know what?
Emily: Actually there were some things that they were saying.
Emily: businesses are trying to go back in and increase the floor space of you know per foot to Versus the male's.
Rym: yeah, actually I saw an article on FARC about that not too long ago.
Rym: They were talking about how the rules originally were that men's and women's bathroom equal square footage And then this much square footage of bathroom per square footage of occupied space.
Emily: And here's here's a good example that this was the time that you made me so mad on the train.
Emily: You almost made me like, you know hit you like I hit you in the knee or something like that.
Emily: Yeah, that was our big train fight and people were like looking at us.
Emily: But the whole yeah, cuz boys play with Barbie doll or?
Emily: no, that was not the way it went.
Emily: It was boys play with video games and girls play with Barbie dolls And that's why there are no girls in the sciences.
Scott: video games.
Emily: Well, that's what I said.
Scott: and you said oh no Matchbox cars not Barbie doll.
Emily: No video games.
Scott: and I didn't say video games.
Scott: There are girly video games.
Emily: No, he's trying to rationalize it.
Emily: We were on the train.
Emily: He was just set on this thing.
Rym: All right, Scott what Barbie horse adventure?
Rym: Yeah Scott that most of the girls we know are quite hip to gaming.
Scott: Those are the girls we know that are like old.
Rym: and talking about little kids here When I was a little kid all my actually when I was in first grade I it was.
Rym: she was my girlfriend and I. you could see me make the quotes.
Rym: cuz we were just friends.
Rym: cuz I was a Little.
Rym: I was a little Mac pimp when I was in first grade.
Rym: I followed all the girls around.
Emily: Yeah, he was the lone blue shirt in the sea of jumpers.
Rym: Yeah, I went to a Catholic school.
Scott: No But that argument anyway All I was trying to say was that the fact that girls play with Barbie and boys play with matchbox cars is not entirely Due to the commercials that they watch during TV shows.
Scott: there is also there is something other reason besides Society and graining that idea into children that that is the way it is.
Emily: I think society is a great part of it.
Emily: I also think there are some psychological differences But all I'm saying is a lot of times the way you present this stuff comes across as incredibly Insufferably sexist.
Scott: Well, I don't know.
Scott: No one else seems to think so.
Scott: Yes, they do Scott You don't see me beating women or Scott.
Rym: you often make very good logical arguments about things.
Rym: However, you often as your evidence will make up a meta a hypothetical situation.
Rym: that is absurd to the point of being offensive.
Rym: I'm not bringing up the classic one that all of us cite because I don't really feel like bothering with it on the air But good God.
Scott: Well, that's the other thing is I don't think that anything is offensive.
Scott: I think people are offended.
Emily: No, I'm just.
Emily: I'm just mainly messing with you because like like I said tonight you've been on a roll.
Emily: What was the gun emcee thing?
Emily: It's like her boobs are big cuz she's pregnant.
Emily: He was making reference.
Emily: cuz we're talking about.
Emily: she's smart enough to be the captain of the spaceship And I said, oh that Scientific American article about you know, the woman's Intelligence changing when they become pregnant, you know that there are different psychological.
Scott: and then I was like There must be something to that.
Scott: Eating pizza and pickles, you know Scott you just made a joke poorly and we Didn't get it wasn't much of a joke.
Scott: It was just more kind of like an a.
Emily: So let's let's stop picking on Scott.
Emily: yeah talk about something though I'll admit there's.
Rym: no I'm glad you came up because I don't know what it is with you people.
Rym: You must be sadis, but I got more feedback about yesterday's episode than about any other freaking episode We've done and everyone was telling me.
Rym: All it was was me and Scott arguing with each other about Wikipedia about Wikipedia and about Nintendo DS.
Rym: Instead of doing the show we wanted to do.
Rym: we just yelled and screamed at each other and I cut out a good 20 minutes Of arguing.
Scott: that wasn't even a good arguing I mean.
Scott: we said I think we ran through the whole argument in Wikipedia and then ran through the whole thing again from the beginning.
Rym: Yep, but then we ran through it yelling at evidence.
Scott: Yeah.
Emily: Yeah when these when it comes to argument these two are pros.
Rym: Why do you people want to listen to us?
Rym: Are you that's?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: They're just nobody nobody cared about when we did a nice series on how to build a computer.
Rym: Everyone cares about.
Rym: Scott.
Rym: remember yelling at each other.
Emily: It's the conflict, you know every.
Emily: they always tell us this and you know screenwriting class But I don't conflict.
Emily: the drama.
Scott: no, I don't know.
Scott: strangers want to hear that though, that's the thing entertaining.
Scott: See any feedback from strangers on that episode.
Scott: No, I only saw feedback from people we know all I gotta say about Wikipedia.
Emily: I'm writing that article about Flemish giant rabbits.
Rym: Yeah Cuz I gotta say I learned one weird thing about rabbits on Wikipedia and it's that rabbits are instrumental to the lemon farming industry.
Emily: I'm gonna go farm me some lemon.
Scott: They protect the lemons from parasites or something.
Rym: No, no, no, it's actually Yeah, it's their their urine and they're dropping and poop all over the lemon fields.
Rym: Yes, and for what?
Rym: the?
Rym: the chemical makeup of those components is a very conducive to citrus Bright because the rabbits are eating citruses.
Rym: No.
Rym: No, I don't think rabbits particularly like a lemon.
Scott: Yeah, well, no, but that's the thing is they don't eat the lemons, but they eat other things that are vegetable fruit type matter.
Emily: I always thought rabbit urine was very acidic in general, but Rym said it's because it has a lot of nitrates in it.
Rym: Yeah, something like that.
Rym: I mean, I'm obviously going on what I remember from a Read a few days ago.
Scott: You should ask a rabbit ologist.
Emily: Oh I'm a rabbit ologist for real.
Emily: No, I just read a lot of.
Emily: I'm probably of anybody in this room.
Emily: I'm probably the best first.
Rym: I would say the the breeding habits.
Scott: I don't know if you're a real rabbit ologist.
Emily: I don't have a degree in rabbits.
Rym: I would say that she knows more about rabbits that I know about dogs and I freaking love dogs.
Emily: I'm obsessive to the point of being kind of scary about it.
Scott: But yes for sure.
Emily: Yep.
Emily: Yeah.
Scott: So anyway, what's the episode today?
Rym: Yeah was going to be about since it's gaming day.
Scott: It's still about.
Emily: we bought the chair fund.
Scott: okay, we're gonna get there.
Rym: so I Want to talk about totally forgotten about that.
Scott: Okay, let's talk about this gaming group.
Scott: That's near here.
Scott: We like board games and in college you had people to play board games with.
Rym: yeah Like we had a whole club of hundreds of people just playing board games.
Scott: It wasn't hundreds, but it was big enough.
Rym: It had hundreds of members.
Rym: They didn't all show up.
Scott: Yes So we had places to play board games.
Scott: We would love to play board games with and board games require usually three and sometimes up to seven people, you know It's hard to make a two-player board game for lots of mathematical.
Scott: there are a few two-player games that I'm gonna try out.
Scott: I think they might be good but I don't know how long that lasts us.
Scott: but the the for the four-player game seems to be like the best games because it's You know, there's no none of that two people ganging up on the third player business and it's just generally good all around.
Scott: so We didn't have anyone to play games with when we were here because only two of us and we were desperate.
Rym: like I moved here Too over two years before he did and I was searching I couldn't find gamers anywhere.
Scott: So finally I found this group of gamers.
Scott: I found out that they existed or had once existed and they were called maws the mid-hud scenario wargame society and It took me like months and months and months to actually contact them because they were so out of touch with reality.
Rym: I guess their website was a tripod site.
Scott: Well, their website tripod site didn't exist.
Scott: They had a website before that was destroyed.
Scott: the tripod site is destroyed like what in a fire I don't know but it no longer existed.
Scott: there were links to it that were all dead.
Rym: How does a website get destroyed?
Scott: they put it on some hosting and they cancel it?
Emily: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Wow So then they got the tripod site very recently.
Scott: then it was terrible and then now he got them a real site.
Scott: but the point is is I went there and You know, they're old crusty wargamers, but they're not you know.
Scott: personality wise they're pretty good compared to some other old scary guys I've you know seen and played games with uh, yeah the people at our way we used to know.
Scott: Yeah, like these guys have okay personalities and they're fun to play games with.
Scott: but even though they look kind of scary And old which they are kind of scary and old and they you know, they play sometimes scary war games Which I don't like so much.
Scott: So I've been there twice so far playing at the local game store and you know these guys are sort of complaining that they can't get more members and After observing two of their meetings it's plain to see why They don't talk to anybody.
Scott: I Was sitting there.
Scott: we were playing this giant train game and there must have been over the course of the day Like over ten people coming over and looking at the train game and going ooh, and they were obviously very interested.
Scott: Did anyone have a conversation with them?
Scott: No Did anyone even so much as say hi only I did.
Scott: You know, I tried to have a conversation with this one cool old guy who came around but you know Then he got up and left because no everyone else is paying so much attention to this game.
Scott: And I was like, hey you guys here to recruit or you're here to play games.
Scott: so Yeah, now they're.
Scott: they have more scary things about them like the chair thing the chair thing that she.
Rym: basically They collect dues.
Scott: They used to collect dues and when I when someone says they collect dues for a club I think oh they're gonna buy advertising they're gonna buy games.
Scott: They're gonna buy a banner They're gonna do something.
Rym: So we asked them what their dues are for.
Rym: they said.
Scott: Oh, that's the broken chair fund And i'm like broken chair fund.
Scott: Oh, I thought it might have been like some sort of tradition like they have a broken chair They pass around or something silly or it might have been, you know, one of those terms that It's.
Emily: it's words, but it means something else.
Rym: Yeah, but no it's quite literally because many of them are rather uh rotund very uh majestic.
Rym: it was literally and They would often break chairs.
Scott: Um, the other thing is I realized these people don't have a lot of money.
Scott: I know it's because they buy too many games or what but um, they didn't seem extremely wealthy.
Rym: That seems to be a trend among uh, not so much video gamers but German board gamers who aren't role-playing gamers and larpers.
Rym: and it's like once you leave college and you're a board gamer It's hard to still make money, which I don't see but apparently that seems to be the case.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: I was the only one there like I was the only one there who didn't mind just going eat out anywhere.
Scott: I was like, yeah, let's go to the neko.
Scott: and they were like, whoa So, you know too too high class, yeah, I guess they couldn't.
Scott: they didn't want to do that.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: one guy was unemployed though, so I can understand him.
Emily: I wouldn't think it's like the most expensive hobby under the sun though You know that you got some people going yachting and of course, maybe it's a different demographic.
Rym: Well, what i'm starting to think is that it seems that most people who like board games The ones who are like they like board games But they also have those other factors of being successful in life.
Rym: Like they're just good at something or whatever Tend to go when they leave college and give up all their fun hobbies and have a normal boring job and work hard at it.
Rym: And because I know a lot of people at ibm who seem like when they were young they were really cool.
Rym: They were into these german board games back 20 30 years ago And now they're married to people who hate board games and they never play them anymore And all they do is work go home talk to their family watch tv go to sleep.
Emily: This sounds like you're being jaded from your experience at ibm.
Rym: Yes god.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: It's like they all fight with their wives and No, but I even see it like uh miserable and sad.
Scott: sometimes when you listen to podcasts or read blogs You see people who are interested in geeky things and like their wives or girlfriend.
Scott: It's always like how do I get my girlfriend to do this with me?
Scott: How do I get my wife to do this?
Scott: or boyfriend?
Rym: i've seen a lot of the other way around too.
Rym: Yeah, there's a cool geeky girl and she she marries or goes with some like dumb old jockey schlub guy who doesn't care.
Emily: Yeah, I don't know.
Emily: I see more more the other way around like I see a lot of geeks.
Rym: There's a skew.
Emily: Yeah, I see a lot of geeks with non-geek girls and you know, I I'm open to trying new things.
Emily: You know, sometimes you guys yell at me.
Emily: you're like, how could you not know this?
Emily: But you know scott yells at Rym.
Scott: So then I don't feel so bad, you know Anyone who doesn't know something they should know?
Rym: no.
Rym: No, I think I should just edit that statement.
Rym: scott you yell at anyone.
Scott: I yell at anyone who knows who doesn't uh know something they should know.
Rym: All right listeners, you know our things today, right?
Rym: well, uh Oftentimes i'll see a thing of the day like like.
Rym: I see a thing like oh that's gonna be awesome.
Rym: And I send it to scott to see what he thinks and he responds that's old archaic archaeological news.
Scott: And I think oh, hey Rym, uh, and then he says with that news.
Scott: It's an antique.
Rym: And then he says something like I saw that an hour ago.
Emily: Yeah You're gonna turn into a gargoyle.
Scott: No, I don't think so.
Rym: I see no crash gargoyle.
Scott: Oh the light on the the eye book is like going bright dim.
Rym: It's breathing.
Scott: It's breathing.
Emily: I love that.
Emily: I I don't know.
Emily: It's such a little.
Emily: it's it's purely cosmetic.
Emily: But when I first got my iMac and I saw that it was
Scott: just like rotate your chair so it doesn't like shine in my eye
Emily: Shine
Rym: in your eye.
Rym: It's getting right It's not it's.
Rym: not only is it the weakest like white led it's behind plastic.
Scott: It gets pretty bright when it's at its maximum, right?
Rym: No, it doesn't.
Emily: No, it doesn't.
Emily: you're all the way across the room.
Emily: Yeah No, no He's got his eye up to it.
Rym: He's like it doesn't hurt my eye.
Rym: Anyway meter from it.
Scott: So so we got off topic at the gamer guys.
Emily: Yes So I I'm geek enough I can run with the rest of them.
Emily: I I make the grade.
Emily: Okay, so moz.
Scott: so these is these scary gamer guys and i'm trying to straighten them out.
Rym: We basically kind of took them over as in.
Rym: we built him a website and a forums and we run their mailing list.
Rym: now.
Rym: And I I see I foresee a transfer of power.
Scott: Yeah, the transfer of power though their election next is in october 2007 election.
Rym: They have like five members.
Scott: Yeah, it doesn't matter because as soon as see as long as I am the guy who actually talks to people Then eventually i'll be the public face that actually says something that people know and i'll be friends with all the new people.
Scott: And as soon as I recruit more new people than there are existing people.
Scott: That's that's the end.
Rym: Yeah I mean i'd like to say i'll do that too and I will.
Rym: but you see the funny thing is Despite all the work we've done for this group I've never met a single one of them because
Scott: every two of their meetings ever
Rym: every time they've met i've gone out of town
Scott: You know, and i'm probably going to be out of town the next time they meet too.
Scott: So it's kind of like Conventions.
Rym: we have social lives.
Scott: Yeah, it seems like a lot of the people though in the group have families and things and don't show up, too.
Emily: But you guys what?
Emily: what's planned for next month?
Emily: You kind of told me about this.
Emily: Yeah, i'm pretty intense.
Emily: we're going to like four conventions.
Rym: we're probably going to rochester this coming weekend and You know, I I mean, I don't even know if I have a hotel room for the country i'm going to next weekend.
Scott: If you don't know if you have a hotel room i'm not going.
Scott: i'm probably going go without your hotel.
Scott: I'll stay home and get something done.
Rym: Maybe I forget which ones when I gotta look.
Rym: figure all this out.
Rym: They're all coming up.
Scott: I can see if i'm getting my new car this week.
Scott: We're going.
Scott: I guess i'm gonna go to rochester if I get the car soon enough.
Rym: Yep Again, then we're gonna go to ubercon for a day.
Scott: We're gonna go to ubercon for a day.
Rym: All right for anyone out there who lives and in new york like downstate new york, new jersey, connecticut ubercon Google it check it out.
Rym: It's just an awesome gaming con.
Rym: We're gonna be there.
Rym: We'll totally play tigers new freddy's with you.
Scott: Yeah, totally.
Scott: And then i'm going to one day of the new york comic con.
Rym: Yep I'm i'm thinking about going more and more now that I know some more people going other than just scott next year.
Emily: next year I'll totally be up for the new york comic con because i've wanted to go To that for years.
Scott: I gotta go.
Scott: see uh, i'm going away there.
Scott: the original minmay minmay.
Scott: Yeah What's her name?
Scott: Mari, is gonna be there.
Emily: Oh, it was weird because I just read an article about her like how she went to america.
Scott: She's totally going all around the country because adv is redubbing macross and they got her to do the english dub.
Emily: That's so cool.
Scott: Yeah, so she's.
Scott: she's been in america for years and the singing and everything.
Emily: That's so neat.
Scott: She even has like her own albums on her own selling them and all that stuff.
Emily: I gotta say that's that's a cool thing.
Emily: to just reprise your voice in a totally different language.
Scott: years after She's gonna be there and my buddy rushkoff's gonna be there.
Scott: I'm gonna finally see him.
Rym: actually Yeah, you should try to strike up a conversation with him.
Rym: since you won his contest You'll have a way to get his notice.
Scott: Oh, yeah, i'll just be like hey i'm scott rubin.
Scott: Then he'll know who I am.
Rym: See if we can get an interview with him or something.
Scott: That could be cool.
Scott: He's the problem with interviewing him is he's 10 000 times smarter than any of us.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: That's good.
Rym: Then we'll we'll set him going on something and then we'll get a nice recording of it.
Emily: Yeah, and just kind of you should emily.
Scott: You should try to take his classes.
Scott: He's an yu professor.
Emily: Really?
Emily: What what?
Scott: uh, he teaches like crazy media studies and things media studies.
Emily: Well, that might be cas but uh, It's it.
Scott: his classes are probably the hardest classes to get into.
Scott: they're like giant lectures at night You know with like lots of people and it probably doesn't count towards your major at all.
Emily: Yeah media studies Well, it could be a gen ed though.
Emily: All right, you know because I do have a certain amount of humanity He always I have to he always announces when he has a new.
Scott: when he he only teaches like one class per semester.
Scott: So the next time I see one of his he always announces on his website because you can get all his course Materials on his website so you can take the class along at home if you want to.
Scott: you know instead if you can't go.
Scott: So the next time I see an announcement for a new class i'll tell you.
Emily: Yeah, give me a heads up on that one.
Emily: that's cool.
Rym: and actually if we get uh, Any sort of portable recording stuff for GeekNights before that weekend, perhaps we'll do some impromptu interviews at it.
Scott: Yeah, that'd be cool.
Rym: or at all the other little because we're not doing appearances in any of these cons coming up We're just kind of going to them as as normal guys.
Scott: Yeah, too bad.
Scott: the comic geek speak guys are the official podcast the new york comic con So they'll be probably interviewing all over the place.
Scott: That's fine.
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: We got otakon.
Scott: Yeah, we do.
Scott: So these gaming guys.
Scott: Let me let me talk about one of the games I played with these guys we played.
Scott: We'll talk about the train game because that was the biggest Train game was railroad tycoon.
Scott: This thing is three boards.
Scott: It was so big it had three boards.
Scott: You ever seen a game with three boards?
Rym: No, uh battle tech.
Scott: You know what.
Scott: it was bigger than three battle tech boards.
Scott: It's pretty big.
Scott: It was so huge.
Scott: So it's basically giant hex map with cities and You would have money.
Scott: and if you didn't have enough money to do what you wanted you to take shares from the bank And then you had to pay like a thousand dollars of your money per share per turn.
Scott: So taking too many shares would cut into your profits And your victory points would be your like income.
Scott: So if you didn't have enough victory points, you had too many shares You would lose money every turn and had to take out more shares.
Scott: and that's what happened to me.
Scott: I lost But you just spent money to build track And then you would ship cubes along the track to get more points.
Rym: do the cubes actually fit in the little trains?
Scott: No, it's not like that.
Rym: Ah, it's just cubes and what good is it?
Scott: It was all right.
Scott: I don't think it was like my favorite game ever, but it was pretty good.
Rym: Well, I think part of our problem is that between puerto rico and tigris and euphrates We've pretty much come upon the current perfection of gaming.
Rym: Yeah, at least that type of gaming this game apex This yes, this game.
Scott: I think would be really fun.
Scott: if you have a lot of people like five or six people And you all want to get around a big table and like, you know, yell about cubes and stuff for like a while
Rym: Why don't we just get a bunch of wooden cubes and take a chessboard and move them around and yell
Scott: because you wouldn't have any trains?
Emily: Anybody out there?
Emily: No bug room.
Emily: Oh, yeah, you're trying to figure out what bug room is because my sister my sister was doing this.
Emily: She's pre-med and biology so she was going on a job shadow thing in an emergency room With one of our doctor friends in wisconsin and scary.
Emily: What?
Emily: why?
Scott: emergency room guts and things?
Emily: Oh, yeah Well, some of the things were pretty intense But anyway, she had some stories.
Emily: but my cousin, you know since she was staying with my aunt my cousin is really A whole bunch of geeky friends really into dnd and a lot of german board games.
Emily: But they were playing this chess thing.
Emily: It's like with two chess boards and you could switch pieces in and out.
Emily: and it was called bug room I think and I had never heard of it and I can't really find any information on it.
Rym: So Hmm, I mean one thing I got to say from what?
Rym: from the vague description we got it seems to sound a lot like It's not chess, but it's it's.
Rym: it is to chess as the Carcassonne expansions are to Carcassonne.
Rym: As in you use chess pieces and chess boards and some chess rules But it doesn't play like chess because it's crazy.
Scott: How do you?
Scott: there's no such thing on board game geeks.
Scott: No, i'm really curious.
Rym: Yeah, you sure you're spelling it Or saying it was like bug room.
Scott: Bug room not bug rum or something.
Emily: Nah, maybe i'm just.
Scott: Where did they learn the game from?
Scott: did like someone teach it to them or something?
Scott: Yeah.
Emily: Yeah She was playing with my cousin's friends.
Scott: Where is the you know any more etymology of it or such,
Emily: uh, I don't know what bug room stands for but
Rym: We'll have to do some research here.
Rym: I mean mafia is on the internet fairly widely now, but that wasn't.
Rym: a lot of people call it werewolf Yeah, and there's some people call it this other thing too.
Rym: They call it like the militia.
Scott: hmm Bugalows bugs bunny game bugs go bug don't bug me.
Rym: Yeah, so if anyone out there has ever played bug room Or a game that involves two chess boards and some sort of teleportation Kind of curious about it Yeah, and uh any progress out there on uh finding that movie kids.
Rym: Oh, nothing lasts forever.
Emily: Yeah, she saw the movie with me.
Emily: We're talking about homeless people.
Emily: they can take you to the moon did you know?
Rym: yeah homeless people.
Rym: you have to meet.
Emily: uh Callous Ticks on the moon and dr.
Emily: Bronner.
Rym: Oh god.
Rym: Dr.
Rym: Bronner.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: Dr Bronner is gonna be my thing of the day tomorrow because I don't think any of you out there know who he is.
Emily: Good morning My favorite part my favorite part of the movie.
Emily: I I can't spoil it It's just too good.
Scott: It's just bug room totally can't be the name of this game because there's nothing on google.
Emily: I'll look at.
Scott: I'll look at either they invent it or they change the name or something.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: And that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: If you like our podcast, you'll love our forums.
Scott: Make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to geekknights@gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-15.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight monday through thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience But unlike those other talk shows it's actually recorded at night.