Rym: It's Thursday June 1st, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We were originally we're going to talk about the airline industry, but we got sidetracked by chemistry and bullies and all sorts of fun stuff.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So it's about a thousand degrees and the humidity is about a billion here right now, but it rained, but it didn't matter.
Rym: Yeah, it rained and the humidity got worse because the rain kind of fell and then stuck around.
Scott: So it's it's like the air couldn't hold any more water But there was.
Scott: it was so hot that water was evaporating.
Scott: Then it wanted to go where there was no room for it.
Scott: So it rained to make room for new humidity that immediately Filled the vacant area where the rain used to be.
Rym: I was walking around downstairs And there's a time you can feel the water everywhere in the carpet on the walls and all the furniture.
Scott: We need to get us a fan down there.
Rym: Yeah, you know what I'm gonna stay up here in my airtight air-conditioned room.
Scott: I'm going to stay upstairs in my airtight air-conditioned room though this weekend.
Rym: We will be at the beach unless the weather is Terrible if it's terrible if I go anyway.
Scott: Yeah, we won't go to the beach.
Scott: We'll go to the.
Rym: we'll go to the shore.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: We'll look at the beach from the from the house.
Rym: Yeah him probably play some games in other news because we've done long episodes for most of the week and Because it's late and we're tired and we're going out of town tomorrow.
Rym: This won't be the longest episode.
Scott: No, it won't be.
Scott: it'll be quite Terse.
Rym: if you wanted a long episode try listening to yesterday or the day before which were both very long At least long for us.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, I've noticed that the length of our episodes has been creeping upward ever slowly.
Scott: Well, let's try to put a cap on that.
Rym: Yeah, I mean originally it when we first started doing this it was tough to get.
Rym: make it out to the 45 minutes We'd always kind of shot for.
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Scott: Well, you know practice and then Actually having something to talk about.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know when we can't think of something to talk about and we pick some crap-ass topic for the day It doesn't go very long.
Rym: Yeah, except that we've gotten good at talking about those crap-ass topics because we've done it so often.
Scott: Yeah, but when we talk about a real good dog, it goes even longer.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I could have gone another couple hours on.
Rym: an amazement great.
Scott: I don't think anyone's dared They seem to.
Rym: everyone seems to like to hear everything we have to say.
Scott: we might as well just sit here going Like exactly that and then I guess people will enjoy it.
Rym: yep top top dilly done.
Scott: You got a problem.
Rym: I like that music.
Scott: you got a problem.
Rym: I think I'm just gonna order the two CDs I found because I can't find them torrent wise anywhere.
Scott: Well, you're not gonna find them on Pirates Bay at least not for a couple days.
Rym: Yeah, that is that.
Rym: that's not really news.
Rym: But for anyone who's following it the Pirates Bay people have stated openly that they will be back up within a few days.
Scott: woohoo, those are my kind of people.
Rym: they have also claimed that it is all a result of corruption and money and influence from foreign countries.
Rym: a They're claiming that the search was illegal and unwarranted and they're going they may possibly sue for a violation of whatever rights they have in Sweden.
Scott: yeah, I don't know how Sweden court works though.
Scott: Usually a lot of those European courts have the professional judges.
Scott: So it's tricky.
Rym: so if any of you out there in Sweden and know anything about Swedish law give us a buzz.
Scott: I know about the Swedish law yeah.
Rym: So you have any actual news?
Scott: Let's see.
Scott: oh we're going to wizard word Philly Saturday, so if you want to see us.
Scott: We'll be there.
Rym: If you happen to be in Wildwood, New Jersey Saturday night and Sunday Let us know before we leave and maybe we'll see you on the beach.
Scott: Yep Half-life 2 episode 1 came out today.
Scott: I'm playing it.
Scott: It's worth.
Rym: He's playing it to the exclusion of life.
Rym: He basically locked himself in his room all day.
Scott: I don't got anything else to do.
Scott: I mean, what would I done if I wasn't playing it?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: read a book go outside Do I do any of those things?
Rym: usually you pretty much just sit in front your computer anyway, so it's a difference.
Scott: I'm just running a different piece of software this time.
Rym: I don't know how you can do it.
Rym: I get sick of sitting in front of my computer after you know several hours.
Scott: Hey, as long as there's something to do on the computer There's an infinite number of things to do.
Rym: you could never run out of things to do on a computer.
Scott: Then why are you questioning?
Scott: I don't know how you could be so sit in front of it for so long And then immediately you answer your own question.
Rym: well because I find most of the things you can do useless.
Scott: Well, I don't do those things.
Rym: I mean I've gotten to the point where I don't even really surf the web anymore.
Rym: now that I have a job where I actually Work as opposed to a job where I can mostly just kind of surf the web.
Rym: I don't surf the web at all in my free time.
Scott: Yeah, I got to get one of those jobs there.
Rym: I only look at the internet like once when I come home from work for a little bit And then right before I do the show and then if someone's online I'll chat with them for a little bit, and then I'll go to sleep.
Scott: I just mostly only visit.
Scott: you know this list of websites that I have feeds for and You know that's.
Scott: I just get information from those sites.
Scott: I don't go browsing around for new stuff all the time actually hardly ever.
Rym: But you do seem to go to those sites a lot.
Scott: I go to them maybe five six times a day because they update.
Scott: you know the ones that only update once a day.
Scott: I read once a day, and you know like penny arcade.
Scott: I'll go once a day.
Rym: realize I only check FARC once a day now that.
Rym: if that?
Scott: Yeah, no, but I'll go to dig.
Scott: maybe like I mean I guess six times
Rym: poking around on the internet looking for news is fine and all if I have nothing better to do because you Know I was at work where I couldn't really do anything else Mm-hmm, but surfing the internet is pretty much at the bottom of my list over everything else.
Rym: I could be doing with my free time.
Scott: Yeah, I just gotta get myself up to actually making something.
Rym: just do it.
Scott: yeah You know the first step is the biggest one and as soon as I start something I can't stop doing it.
Rym: so do it.
Scott: I gotta actually do it.
Rym: Well, then do it just do it.
Rym: Why don't you just do it?
Scott: It's not that easy.
Rym: Yes, it is.
Rym: you could just start.
Rym: you could just sit down and say I'm going to do X and start doing it.
Scott: It's real hard when this is real fun game to play instead.
Rym: Oh, so then you don't have any willpower.
Scott: Yeah, I do Don't want how.
Scott: I'd rather play the game.
Scott: My will makes me play the game instead of doing something else.
Rym: so then why do you want to do something else?
Rym: Cuz obviously the game is the only thing you really want to do.
Scott: yeah It is what I really want to do until it's done, then I don't want to do it anymore, okay?
Rym: I get sick of games real quick nowadays.
Scott:  Yeah, me too.
Scott: That's why it's a damn good game.
Rym: Yeah, keep me interested I'll play it someday.
Rym: I really not don't have any interest in buying a faster computer anytime soon.
Scott: yet You just you haven't played it yet when if you actually played it.
Rym: You'd be like oh, oh yeah It's probably a great game, but keep in mind.
Rym: I never played half-life 1 until a few years ago.
Scott: Yeah, it doesn't matter.
Rym: so I'll probably play half-life 2 a few years from now.
Scott: Yeah, if it's still hey.
Scott: Yes, the thing is that steam could you know at any minute disappear, then it's done.
Scott: so for real news S&P which is standard and poor's.
Scott: if you did not know there's some business II group.
Scott: I guess they have.
Scott: you know the S&P 500 like the 500 companies that are awesome.
Rym: I guess I think everyone knows what the S&P is all right, and if they don't know they probably don't care.
Scott: It's a business thing anyway.
Scott: What they do is they recommend which stocks you should buy and which ones you should sell.
Scott: So you know that's that's how things work now Recommendations for stocks are largely bullshit, and I'm not going to talk about that now.
Scott: But I am going to talk about the recommendation on one particular stock by analyst John Yang.
Scott: Now the previous recommendation for this stock was the worst recommendation possible.
Scott: Strong sell.
Scott: that means holy shit.
Scott: sell this thing sinking ship.
Scott: Oh my god He has changed his recommendation to plain old sell which means alright, yeah, just sell it.
Scott: it's no good.
Scott: and You might have guessed already the stock that is rated so poorly is Sony.
Rym: So apparently they're getting better if it went from strong sell to sell.
Scott: it says here Since the current price of Sony shares is near the 12-month target price of $44 They're going to make it sell whereas it was strong sell.
Scott: But it says here we continue to believe that any potential upside in share price would be limited by a lack of visibility in Sony's games division.
Scott: ha ha ha ha ha.
Scott: so even Business people are saying Sony has no vision in their games division.
Scott: vision vision No visibility in the games division.
Scott: It doesn't matter business people think Sony's games suck, and they don't even play games.
Scott: They're businessmen.
Scott: What the hell do they know?
Rym: they know about wearing suits and yelling at people yeah, and they think Sony sucks, too.
Rym: I had to keep ripping on Sony, but no I don't.
Rym: I freaking love it.
Rym: I hate Sony I don't.
Rym: he used to be all right.
Scott: so 80s they were awesome and then in the 90s they were all right and then now in the 2000s.
Scott: They're poop.
Rym: Yeah, I mean it's not just that they're bad.
Rym: if they were just a bad company that made poor decisions I wouldn't be so hard on him.
Rym: I just say wow they suck, but they've gone out of their way to anger their Consumers and their customers that every step of the way they have put viruses on their customers computers.
Rym: I can't remind you of that enough.
Scott: Yeah Think about this.
Scott: people like Infinium labs are not as bad as Sony because Infinium while they trick idiots out of money.
Scott: Yeah, all Infinium.
Scott: Did is?
Scott: they made a phony product that doesn't really exist.
Scott: they get people to invest in the phony product.
Scott: They're not selling it to anyone.
Scott: They're just providing everywhere all the customers and can you know gamers out there with a lot of humorous anecdotes?
Scott: Sony is putting viruses on your computers and And Stealing your money.
Rym: What was that?
Rym: you were like smacking your lips.
Scott: I burped or something.
Scott: it was kind of okay.
Rym: I was just curious cuz that was louder than usual.
Scott: some Gastroesophagus little movements.
Rym: you should do something about that.
Rym: what I don't know.
Rym: not eat.
Rym: Maybe eat better food.
Scott: I ain't just fine food.
Scott: Yeah, all right Who do I eat?
Scott: that's no good.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: but whatever it is it caused you to be all burpee.
Scott: I'm burpee all the time.
Rym: Yeah, maybe you got a bad intestine.
Scott: No.
Scott: I think my intestines all right.
Rym: Anyway go on with your news.
Rym: I wasn't trying to stop you.
Scott: that was my news.
Scott: Sony sucks.
Rym: That's all you had to say.
Scott: Yeah, so just you know.
Scott: just more evidence on the on the burner.
Rym: Well.
Rym: I'll be real quick on my news.
Rym: there's an article on slash dot about a book and a bunch of associated articles and the gist of them is simply that Chemistry and chemistry hobbyists in the United States are fast disappearing as the government in its fear of terrorism and crystal meth as Systematically work to eliminate any venue of Americans acquiring anything remotely dangerous to themselves or others.
Scott: God crystal meth God all right.
Scott: It's getting so bad with this crystal meth shit that the negative effects That of the laws used to contain crystal meth are probably getting to be worse than crystal meth itself.
Rym: They're directly affecting me, which is something that doesn't have like foreign policy as despite.
Rym: You know the horrible possible You know genocide type things going on in Iraq and all the horrible things our country does.
Rym: it doesn't directly affect my day-to-day Life yet, no it doesn't crystal meth itself.
Rym: people who use crystal meth Do not affect my life directly in any way But the laws trying to stop them from doing their crystal meth are screwing me repeatedly and annoyingly.
Scott: It's I might as well just do crystal meth.
Scott: no No, you really don't want to But it would be only slightly worse than all the things that the laws are doing to me now.
Rym: actually to me Crystal meth is something that only exists because there is a war on drugs in the United States Because crystal meth is a terrible terrible drug.
Rym: I mean say what you will about people who smoke marijuana and people who use cocaine But the negative health effects of marijuana at least are minimal.
Rym: Crystal meth destroys a human being.
Rym: no person who of any intelligence would use crystal meth if anything else were available.
Rym: Yet people manufacture and use crystal meth and the reason they do so is that it's really one of the only drugs left in the world that any idiot can make from any chemicals they can get their hands on.
Rym: as A result the government has tried to make these chemicals illegal Even though these chemicals are highly useful in a wide variety of industries and applications.
Rym: So now when I want, you know Sudafed because I have a cold I have to sign a thing and show ID and I can't buy more than X amount of it and I have to go Behind the counter and a lot of places just won't stock it and a lot of drugs are Taking the Sudafed part out of their drug in order to not have to go through this.
Rym: Luckily we stocked up on all sorts of Sudafed and Nyquil.
Rym: All right, of course I'm sure that flagged us as crystal meth manufacturers somewhere.
Rym: All right But it just seems that I mean laws aren't keeping the crystal meth people down.
Scott: They're keeping normal people down.
Rym: and it's not just that the government is really working Fervently to take away anything that could be dangerous to anyone.
Rym: now I note that for the vast majority of human existence on this earth dangerous things abounded and people died.
Rym: and I guess the modern term for it is acceptable casualties that there is a level or a rate of Accidental death in a population.
Rym: that is acceptable because it not to sound cruel, but it weeds out the stupid people.
Rym: It also Reminds the people who survive that you got to be careful.
Rym: The world isn't Disneyland.
Rym: The world is a dangerous place.
Rym: You can go to the grocery store and there are at least a hundred things you can buy that are deadly if used improperly.
Scott: let's see ammonia and bleach.
Rym: Yeah, see they worry about you know, all these things.
Rym: you could mix ammonia and bleach and make one hell of a chlorine gas bomb in short order.
Scott: Yep, but hell you know what you'll fucking get shit clean.
Scott: god damn it.
Rym: Actually, I don't think it works So well it.
Scott: actually if you take ammonia and bleach and we're like a gas mask or something and try to clean your kitchen floor and You have a kitchen floor that won't be destroyed by ammonia and bleach together.
Scott: God damn.
Scott: Will that be a clean kitchen floor?
Scott: Let me tell you.
Rym: um, are you basing this on anything or is this purely anecdotal?
Scott: I think I read a story somewhere once about Someone who is stupid and mixed ammonia and bleach and clean their kitchen floor.
Scott: real nice, but like almost died and went to the hospital.
Rym: Great, that's the guy you want to listen to when you're looking for your advice on chlorine gas and bleach ammonia.
Scott: Well, I know that you know, it's something you should never do but you know not about to do it to clean the floor.
Rym: Actually, I have a funny chlorine gas story from high school.
Scott: All right, Lee.
Rym: Yeah, we I was in a God actually was when I was in middle school, but they bused me to the high school to take biology.
Rym: so I was over in the high school with my biology and I was.
Rym: I was like a little punk eighth grader, you know with the Tude and we're doing some lab We had nitric acid and all sorts of things and I forget exactly what was in the bottle but there was a bottle of something might have been bleach and This kid I don't know if I don't think it was bleach It was something this kid in the back of the room and we're all working around.
Rym: I hear him say hey I wonder what'll happen if I dump this in here and I look up and I see him pouring nitric acid into an unlabeled bottle And gas started billowing out.
Rym: Oh So I walked outside the room to the teacher and I said, I think Craig just made a bomb of chlorine gas.
Rym: And the teacher walked back into the room and said holy shit.
Rym: And we had to evacuate the school for like two hours and he got a whole school.
Rym: Well, they evacuated the school because they called they someone pulled the fire alarm.
Rym: Oh and then two hours later that I lost back into the classroom and he got fucking suspended.
Rym: Of course, I know that they didn't expel him or call him a terrorist or anything like they probably would today.
Scott: Yeah, cuz he was just stupid.
Scott: He wasn't trying to be all.
Scott: a Terrorist is someone who goes.
Scott: I got a bomb.
Scott: you either give me a billion dollars or I'll blow up the school.
Scott: Someone who goes oh shit.
Scott: I accidentally made a chlorine bomb.
Rym: Oh, no I Mean, I guess my favorite quotation nowadays is never a sign to malice or evil What can easily be explained by stupidity?
Rym: indeed Indeed, but I mean it in general that the gist of a lot this article as I'm trying to get back to my new store Is that the government is trying.
Rym: the government and people who are?
Rym: wusses or People who have gone through a loss and for some reason have decided this is now their crusade Are trying to make America safe from everything.
Rym: as a result We're there's a generation of children growing up right now who don't know that the world is dangerous.
Rym: Or don't realize that it's very easy to hurt yourself and a lot of people just go down like chumps You know hit by a car fall the wrong way in the grocery store and crack your head open and die.
Rym: People die in weird crazy sudden ways.
Rym: read for ya God Yeah, I could spend all day reading the FARC headlines that are relevant to this discussion.
Rym: probably yes I guess I'm really of the mind that you should.
Rym: I mean you should obviously Try to protect the majority of people from things and you should obviously protect people from real Clear dangers like if there's a high-voltage Your fence put a sign on it that says this fence is electrified.
Scott: This is no way to know.
Rym: looking at the fence yeah, if a danger is not obvious then it you should help protect people against it.
Rym: if a danger is obvious and known and Protecting against it is more valuable to society than the benefit gained from ignoring it then go nuts.
Rym: But the moment your protections against something dangerous are worse than the actual effects of the dangerous thing Like, you know the fact that in many playgrounds nowadays kids aren't allowed to run or play tag Because running is dangerous and tag promotes fighting?
Rym: Yeah, I'm not kidding.
Rym: That was a story.
Rym: In fact, that was multiple stories about a month ago I think.
Scott: actually Penn Jillette had the greatest saying when it came to this.
Scott: he said Let those who ride Decide and I think the problem here is that people who are not riding are deciding.
Scott: it should be up to Bikers whether they want to wear helmets or not.
Scott: now at the same time It should be up to kids whether they think playing tag is dangerous or not.
Rym: Well, if not the kit one for the helmets.
Rym: now I would be fine if I gave a city or a government passed a law saying if you would get an accident without a helmet We're not paying for your ass.
Scott: Yeah, no, the law is if you aren't wearing a helmet the cop can pull you over and write you a ticket.
Rym: Oh, yeah, no, but I have.
Rym: now you should have the right to choose to do something stupid that won't harm anyone But you however.
Rym: indeed there should be laws to protect society from your stupid ass.
Scott: Yeah, but if I make a playground with swings and a seesaw and an old-fashioned jungle gym You don't have to use it if you're using it.
Scott: You're accepting the risk.
Rym: now I say for kids.
Rym: I mean it would be alright if the parent could make that decision for a kid.
Scott: Yeah a parent can say I think that if I had a kid and I went to a playground that was all rusty with jagged metal shit And it was crawling with tetanus.
Scott: I'd be like you're not playing on that playground.
Scott: but What you know, you shouldn't force every town to make stupid shit playgrounds.
Scott: some parents want to let their kids plan real playgrounds.
Scott: Yeah, some kids want to play.
Scott: all kids want to plan real playgrounds and they should be allowed to do so.
Scott: You shouldn't?
Scott: you know It's okay to keep people safe or to decide for yourself that you don't want to do something You might think is dangerous But you shouldn't be allowed to deny other people their freedom to take risks.
Scott: as long as those people recognize the risk They are taking and accept, you know their fault if someone gets hurt.
Rym: Yep, the problem is a lot of people and I think this is a byproduct.
Rym: It's like a self-fulfilling prophecy People aren't able to recognize when a situation is dangerous.
Rym: Now the my best way to explain this with a simple kind of an analogy is you know what amusement parks how they have those?
Rym: Like gas-powered cars that you can drive them on a little track with your family But there's a like wire or a cable under it so you can't actually drive it off the track.
Rym: Yep Now those are at every amusement park and kids love them.
Rym: But you know kids know nowadays that you're a hundred percent safe at amusement park Because you know they strap you in and everything's set up for you.
Rym: Can't really hurt yourself.
Rym: So every kid when they're going around the corner and they see the tree They turn the wheel and go straight for the tree because they know the thing will save them.
Rym: Mm-hmm now this is getting that way in real life.
Rym: to people It's like people hold their hands up on a roller coaster because they know That no roller coaster would be set up so that your hands could hit and hurt yourself.
Rym: They stick their hand as far into the lion cage as they can because they know that it's set up so the lion can't get Them in the real world.
Rym: It's not that way and things are dangerous, and it can never be that way.
Scott: If you did make it that way we would be the Lions in the cage and the Lions would be roaming free.
Rym: I Mean it just.
Rym: I think that as kids grow up in these sterile environments where they're protected from every possible danger and None of them have the example of breaking their arm once and realizing that it sucks to break your arm Or having their friend break his hip and knowing that it really sucks to break your hip.
Rym: They won't recognize danger when they're really confronted with it and as a result They're not able to deal with it.
Rym: then as a result when you know some something finally happens.
Rym: The survivors of them who also can't recognize danger Realize that a law needs to be passed to protect people from this and it gets worse and worse and worse.
Scott: Yeah If you're a kid and you never relax never had a swing to jump off of then you don't really know how high you can Jump and fall off a swing without getting hurt.
Rym: Yeah when I was a kid I learned that after about 15 feet it really fucking hurt to fall off of something.
Rym: Yeah, and you know what?
Rym: nowadays I know exactly how far I can fall before I risk hurting myself.
Scott: Let me summarize this whole thing a little less eloquently.
Scott: you ready?
Rym: I'm ready.
Scott: You're all a bunch of sissies and if you get in my way, I'm gonna kick your ass.
Scott: If I'm elected mayor I'll kill a lot of you and burn your town to cinders Exactly making a country of wusses as soon as uh All the old people die and we're left with just the wusses.
Scott: Someone's gonna come over here and beat the shit out of us and we'll deserve it.
Scott: God damn it.
Rym: I I guess look 50 years ago.
Rym: I mean sissies.
Rym: not that many kids died on playgrounds.
Rym: Nowadays a tiny percentage fewer children die on playgrounds, but playgrounds suck a thousand percent more.
Scott: yep, you know the Adults always is one of my major gripes because I come from a town that is literally 90% houses and in half those houses were families with kids and half those houses were old people and they were basically in a constant battle between the old people who didn't want to pay school tax and the families who wanted awesome family shit.
Scott: and People always wonder why are kids doing drugs?
Scott: Why are kids having sex and making teenage girls pregnant?
Scott: Why are kids getting drunk?
Scott: Why are kids doing all this stuff?
Scott: because you took away everything else fun because it was extremely less dangerous.
Rym: Yep, I mean luckily where I grew up there was though Apparently this has changed and it's actually kind of sad to me that I can think back through my life and watch the progression.
Rym: Like when I was a kid my parents complained about how playgrounds weren't the way they used to be and then as I grew up They just got worse In schools and everything, but at least where I grew up
Scott: They got better for a short time when they built all those giant wooden castles.
Rym: Yep, but then they took those away Yep, and then they melt really low to the ground.
Rym: plastic shit castles shit cells Yeah.
Rym: But I grew up in an area where well I think it was mostly because it was Michigan where there was no mass transit or anything and there are a lot of roads.
Scott: Let's change our topic for today to just this.
Rym: All right, then that's good.
Rym: We'll do the airline industry some other time.
Rym: Yes, so Everyone had cars and by the end and kids who didn't have cars new people who had cars.
Rym: so when you know, you were 12 or 13, you know a 15 year old who had a car and As a result we were mostly free.
Rym: so we would all go hang out in an ice cream shop or we'd all drive to the amusement park on a Random day in the summer and there was stuff to do as a result in my neighborhood.
Rym: There was very little drug use.
Rym: There was very little teenage alcoholism and things were going pretty well.
Rym: Bit by bit parents have not allowed their kids to do anything back in my hometown.
Rym: Well, let him drive around.
Rym: they can't get their licenses till they're 18 now and as a result drug problems started appearing and Alcohol problems started appearing because kids had nothing to fuck do.
Scott: Yeah, gee, I'm bored.
Scott: What can I do?
Scott: Well, I can play video games, but I'm a kid with no job and no money So I can't really I can't have no and video games are dangerous.
Rym: Yeah, that video game can't buy the fun video games.
Scott: But even when you can kids don't have enough money to buy enough video games so that they can entertain themselves all the time.
Scott: Kids can't afford to do hobbies.
Scott: We do like building plenty of computers and you know Expensive $40 board game.
Rym: my parents would take me to an arcade like once a month.
Scott: Yeah, I hardly ever.
Scott: We only went to arcades on vacations just cuz there weren't any.
Rym: Now I mean now it's like that real-life comic.
Rym: I can go to an arcade and spend $1,000 if I want to and no one will stop me.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: God, that's bad.
Scott: We shouldn't do that.
Rym: It was actually a good thing.
Rym: I flew to an amazement.
Rym: It prevented me from buying anything in the dealer's room.
Scott: Mmm Yeah, so, you know the old people complain about.
Scott: you know kids having a loud dance party.
Scott: But if kids are smoking weed in their room, no one will know and no one will complain.
Scott: Yep, until they find out they're smoking weed and then they'll complain, you know It's this one thing that kids can do has a consequence, you know Skiing there's a consequence.
Scott: You might break your legs and die.
Scott: Yeah in the the average injury of skiing is not so bad.
Scott: I mean you may break an arm.
Rym: Yeah, very few people die skiing unless you're skiing on like a black diamond or a double black diamond.
Scott: But you can easily prevent people from skiing.
Scott: you just close the ski mountain.
Scott: No one can ski.
Rym: No, no, remember that Google video those kids trying to ski down that sand dune in a box.
Scott: Yeah, but you can't get.
Scott: you know, you can easily prevent people from doing real skiing on snowy mountains.
Scott: You turn off the snow machines you ID people before you let them on the ski lift.
Scott: It's very easy to stop.
Scott: it's very hard to stop people from doing drugs and having sex and all sorts of other things that have much much worse consequences.
Scott: so You know, they prevent any anything they can and the only holes they leave open are you know things that have far worse consequences and they don't realize they're basically forcing their kids to do the worst thing possible or Sit around and do nothing.
Scott: I mean We should go find some parents who were doing this kind of shit and say well What do you think your kid should do after school?
Scott: and that's like homework.
Scott: All right He finishes his homework in 20 minutes because he's not an idiot now.
Scott: What should your kid do?
Scott: watch TV?
Rym: Yeah Yeah, I mean it's scary But I was actually talking a few days ago to a friend of mine who is living still in sterling heights backward.
Rym: I don't know if he's living there now, but he was there.
Rym: He was talking about it.
Rym: We were catching up on your old business when I grew up you know in Detroit a new Baltimore and sterling heights and all those places.
Rym: if I on a random summer day or a day after school just got up got on my bike and went off into the neighborhood Within about five minutes.
Rym: I'd run into a whole pack of kids and we would roam around doing kid things all day my when I was a kid.
Scott: on my block there was a kid who lived down one street and two kids who lived on the other street and Pretty much after school everyone would be doing something in their yard or maybe playing a video game in their house and Before you knew it, you know everyone to go around on their bikes knock on each other's doors.
Scott: if they were inside Play wiffle.
Scott: I remember played wiffle ball every night for a whole summer until it snowed and we couldn't play anymore.
Rym: But I mean you.
Rym: if you walked around outside on any given nice day if the weather was nice there were kids Everywhere outside running around just doing stuff.
Scott: when my mom was a kid, you know, she lived in Queens, New York.
Scott: You know kids you just used to tell your eight-year-old kid go walk down the street to the grocery store and get some eggs.
Scott: You don't do that anymore.
Scott: Your kid can't go out in the street alone.
Rym: Yeah, nowadays that my friend was telling me he was.
Rym: he went back to the hometown.
Rym: He was you know driving around just looking at the old side seeing what was built new.
Rym: It was a beautiful sunny day, but not a kid to be seen.
Rym: There was like one kid playing catch with his dad in their front yard And other than that does nothing.
Rym: the streets were empty.
Scott: see the front.
Scott: the reason the cause of this.
Rym: as I see it All right, I think it's a combination of video games TV and mean world syndrome.
Scott: Well, I think it's.
Scott: There's a perception that the world is more dangerous.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Are you have you ever heard the term mean world syndrome?
Scott: Is that what that is?
Rym: Yes, actually I have a book on it over there.
Rym: I'm not gonna go get it, but we studied this quite a bit in our communications classes.
Rym: basically mean world syndrome is something that has come up basically since World War two where they've really studied it where People have a perception of reality and then there's the actual reality.
Rym: For example, they would ask people do you know or know anyone who knows?
Rym: Someone who was involved in a murder or who was murdered and think questions like that?
Rym: And they compare those and actually my answer really is yes.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: but then they compare those answers to the actual crime statistics or You know things like that and did not get into a lot of detail in America in modern America it is shown that people perceive the crime rates and The dangers of the outside world to be far greater than the actual crime rate.
Rym: That's rather obvious and part of the reason for this and there are a lot of reason news Is that the news is number one?
Rym: Yes one.
Rym: the news reports mostly on bad news.
Scott: So all you do every night is come home turn on the TV and you watch ten stories about Terrible things that happen near you and you begin to think the outside world is terrible just like the news.
Rym: Yep, and it's not just the news.
Rym: I mean TV shows and media.
Rym: They all play a part in it.
Scott: I mean the most popular TV shows.
Scott: my grandma only watches police shows.
Scott: There are that many shows about police and criminals doing bad stuff and then going to jail.
Rym: But it's just that people are much more afraid of the world than the world warrants at least in the United States.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: It's not see.
Scott: here's.
Scott: the other problem is you have kids playing on the block, right?
Scott: Then parents begin to think that there's dangerous child predators out there and maybe there are.
Rym: maybe there aren't but you know What there were back in the 50s and there were back in the 1900s.
Rym: You know what there were probably the same number back in the 1800s.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: And so parents start to protect their kids and don't let them play outside anymore.
Scott: Well now Because there are no kids outside.
Scott: It becomes a more dangerous place.
Scott: See if you go somewhere as a bunch of kids hanging out outside criminals don't go there.
Scott: They.
Scott: that's how it is and anyone who does go over there is either a parent or a pedophile.
Rym: Well, it's like we've said many times and this is for anyone who has never lived in a big city the dangerous neighborhoods are not the ones where dangerous minorities or Punk looking kids are hanging out in the street all the time.
Scott: You see people hanging out in the street.
Scott: That's an awesome party in the street neighborhood or in the very least.
Rym: It's an okay neighborhood.
Scott: It might be a little scuzzy, but if it's not dangerous Yeah, those might be all homeless drunk guys But even then it's.
Rym: that's still a step up.
Rym: the scary neighborhoods are the places where all the windows are barred and no one is Outside.
Scott: Yeah See if no one lets the kids outside Then you can't let your kid outside and be the only one because then it actually is dangerous.
Scott: There's not a bunch of kids, you know running about having fun to scare away criminals and you know Unwanted folks plus kids watch out for each other.
Scott: Yeah, if but if everyone lets the kids outside and you have this whole block full of kids, even if it's just five kids No one's gonna come and try to molest one of the kids and you can't get all five of them.
Scott: Yeah, and what?
Scott: just even if one of them is smart, you're okay, but little Billy might skin his knee.
Rym: We have to protect him from the dangerous world.
Scott: No one ever died from skinning their knee.
Rym: in fact, oh, yeah people have died from that sort of thing.
Scott: Well, they deserve to die.
Rym: I mean skinning your knee.
Rym: take that to this extreme like road rash from falling off a motorcycle.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, it's not skinning your knee from a bike crash.
Rym: That's skinning your knee.
Rym: It's just skinning a lot of other things - It's not to say Road rash you.
Rym: yeah I think I told that story where I skin my knees real bad to the bone and I'd ride my bike home and I was A little kid.
Rym: Yeah, my grandma was home and she screamed Hmm.
Rym: Yeah trail of blood You know what?
Rym: Those were good times.
Rym: I think back upon all the times I hurt myself fondly.
Rym: Yeah, because I never hurt myself bad enough to die.
Rym: I'm still here and the kids that did hurt themselves bad enough to die.
Rym: I hate to say it, but actually I don't know anyone who hurt themselves and died.
Rym: I know some people who broke bones and they mostly deserved it and I think they were slightly smarter as yeah I never broke a bone, but I hurt myself plenty of times.
Rym: I broke my pinky toe twice same pinky toe.
Scott: Oh, no, I did but I broke my collarbone.
Rym: Yeah, I also had a bee sting that pinky bone, you know.
Scott: And that's how kids learn.
Scott: is you get safe to do this?
Scott: It's not safe to do that and maybe there are things that aren't safe to do But then kids build the skills to do it safely.
Scott: I remember We used to like, you know You have a you have a playground and one kid would do something on the playground and all the other kids who did have never Done that would go.
Scott: Whoo Like?
Scott: maybe he would like.
Scott: I had the standard swing set, you know a slide on one end and lucky
Rym: bars down the middle a
Scott: couple swings a swinging bar, you know, and You know one of my friends went up there and he walked across the top of it Which is definitely not the purpose of it.
Scott: now if he would have fallen he might have hurt himself pretty bad.
Rym: Oh, he might have done like what that kid in the trampoline basketball dunk video did something similar.
Scott: It was pretty much a 10-foot drop and then grass and dirt.
Scott: That's what would have happened.
Scott: So, you know we saw him do this and we're like, whoa Now, you know I went up to try and do it cuz that's what kids did in those days Unlike the wusses of today and I was like, oh shit this too dangerous.
Scott: I stopped doing it But then eventually I could do it.
Scott: I Didn't hurt myself.
Rym: Yeah, like our thing was in my elementary school Green Elementary We had really tall swings like old-school giant ass swings.
Rym: They were really big.
Scott: Yeah, like big swings with the big chains.
Rym: Yeah, just a piece of rubber between two long ass chains Yep, and none of that plastic over the chains or anything.
Rym: It was just a chain.
Rym: Yeah, there's some rust there.
Scott: Yep, that's the stuff.
Rym: now when I remember when recess came everyone would line up at the door and then they blow the whistle Which meant it's recess time and you would bolt like high hell because there were only like 20 swings and there were like 400 kids.
Scott: Whoa, they let all of them out at once if you.
Rym: well, I don't know how many they allowed at once I don't remember but crazy.
Rym: It was a huge playground.
Rym: There's all sorts of other stuff to do and there were other swings But there were 20 of these like big swings and when you got on one of those bastards you didn't leave.
Rym: Now some kids would just swing normal like.
Rym: but then there were the daredevils who would either jump off Which I often did or they'd try to pull a Tarzan thing where they jump off and then try to like Tarzan himself back.
Scott: Oh, yeah That's dangerous.
Rym: That was awesome.
Rym: Yeah, it is now the time when it got really interesting was one.
Rym: There were kids who would run the gauntlet.
Rym: Yeah, I think you can figure out what the gauntlet was.
Rym: Many a kid got pooned.
Rym: It was all in good fun.
Rym: Yeah, but the worst thing was some people realized that I don't remember what they called the game But once you got swinging pretty much at the maximum level of swinging because now there's that point at which you really can't get higher.
Scott: Yeah, you're pretty much doing the whole 178 degrees.
Rym: Yeah Like you get up like just above the bar and you go up so high that you kind of fall a little bit before the Chain catches.
Scott: Yeah, you go up so high the chain kind of goes lax And you know what.
Scott: you're not keeping the chain taut for the whole Swing.
Rym: and I learned as a kid right away that once that starts happening don't try to swing higher.
Scott: No, because you will die.
Rym: Yeah, you always heard the stories of he's gonna go over the bar.
Rym: Did you hear what happened to Brian?
Rym: He went over the bar.
Scott: No one's ever gone over the bar.
Rym: I kid almost went over the bar and he broke his neck in my elementary school.
Rym: Oh, yeah, he was okay.
Rym: I mean he broke his neck, but it didn't sever the spine.
Rym: He just had to wear this terrible monstrosity for many months.
Rym: Yeah, he got up like like a hundred and sixty hundred and seventy degrees and then just kind of fell on his head.
Rym: Oh, it was terrible.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: No one ever tried that shit again.
Scott: Cuz you know if you don't let kids swing then they don't know how high they can swing and if they don't see it See you swing this high babies Then you won't realize that you could possibly break your neck someday.
Rym: Yep Yep.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I Mean if you never get into a fight with anyone You don't know how to fight and if someday someone comes to kick your ass, you're fucked.
Rym: Yeah, I got in a bunch of little fights when I was a kid.
Scott: I sure did too.
Rym: Some of them were scrappy one time.
Rym: I got ambushed and punched in the balls.
Scott: It's like until you're punched in the face and you punch someone in the face.
Scott: You don't know really how it goes.
Rym: Yep, you only need to do it once Yep, because one you realize if you don't punch right you'll hurt yourself more than you'll hurt them.
Scott: And if all you know about punching is what you see on TV your impressions gonna be real wrong.
Rym: Yeah, you don't just wind up and pop a guy in the chin and then he goes down you start winding up and suddenly he's Wailing on you.
Scott: Yeah, I think they should bring boxing back to Schools.
Rym: if not boxing some martial art.
Scott: Well boxing is good because anyone can do it and it doesn't really you know It's not.
Scott: it's real simple.
Rym: Yeah, the problem is you don't want to have kids do that a lot because boxing has a lot of long-term Consequences.
Scott: you don't do it a lot.
Scott: But the example is my bio teacher in 11th grade.
Scott: I'll never forget that he told us this story Because there was some fight in the hallway and he's like.
Rym: I've actually already talked about this on the show.
Scott: That's I'm on the show.
Rym: I'm pretty sure you told this story, but go ahead tell it again.
Rym: Just tell the brief version.
Scott: I've told it to you.
Scott: I don't know if I've told it on the show.
Rym: Yeah, I'm like 60/40 that you told it, but I don't know anyway nuts.
Rym: We got whatever doesn't matter.
Scott: We have plenty new listeners.
Scott: Yeah, we can reuse some stuff make clip show someday.
Rym: Yeah, so we do this podcast, right?
Scott: So it was a fight in the hallway and he said, you know, and he's an old guy.
Scott: So he's like back in my day.
Scott: if two kids got into a fight the teachers would grab him pull him apart Bring him down to the gym put him in boxing gloves and throw him in the ring.
Scott: then we take bets And I was like, yeah, that was great.
Scott: Two kids want to fight.
Scott: they say none of this bullshit in the hallways.
Scott: You're gonna fight like real men and we're gonna see who really wins.
Rym: Yep, or when I was in seventh grade and I got into a big fight with a kid and we you know beat on each Other for a while and the teachers came and they just kind of stood there until we finished.
Rym: You know kids fighting can't really hurt each other so much so they tend to just tire out and The fight becomes like you're kind of locked at the shoulders kind of pushing at each other and at that point after we tired ourselves off they broke it up.
Rym: and Nowadays, if you get into a fight, they just fucking expel you.
Rym: Yeah or call the police or suspend.
Rym: You know they did.
Rym: they suspended us both for one day.
Rym: So for the next day we had to sit in the office next to each other quiet.
Rym: I had that too and most of it was we totally got in a fight.
Rym: Yeah, it was awesome.
Rym: Yeah, it was.
Scott: I also had that.
Rym: so Can't do that anymore.
Rym: zero tolerance policies, which we should do a whole show on even though we're all zero tolerance file 99% of zero tolerance policies are bullshit.
Rym: They exist solely so that people in charge of the schools Don't have to make decisions because they're afraid that if they make a decision they might get sued.
Scott: if they follow a policy then they Can't personally be sued and they should just make a policy besides the zero tolerance policy and follow that policy.
Rym: The problem is they get then the school gets sued anyway and loses the money.
Scott: Zero tolerance is like the safest way someone should sue the school for the zero tolerance policy.
Rym: See the problem here is.
Rym: it goes back to this parents are overprotective and stupid.
Rym: They a parent will sue the school at the drop of a hat now.
Rym: So the school is so if they're more afraid of litigation than they are of kids hurting themselves.
Rym: So there's an incentive.
Rym: if a kid has problems Like say a kid is picked on.
Rym: in the old days the school would help them or maybe they wouldn't but they do something.
Rym: Nowadays, there's a great incentive to kick that kid out of school.
Rym: the kid being picked on because he's the one that's most likely going To cause a problem either will not cause.
Rym: the problem would be the problem.
Rym: either his parents are gonna sue because he got picked on or He's gonna lash out or there'll be a fight and then there'll be a lawsuit or something.
Rym: That's real.
Scott: That's usually the reason that the kids who are picked on are Targeted by the administration.
Scott: is because you know kids picking on each other?
Scott: Well, no one.
Scott: there's no liability there if some kid says to another kid, you're stupid poopy pants You know that that happens all the time.
Scott: That's no one has a problem with that.
Rym: But then he's not a legal problem, but then that kid gets pissed off.
Scott: Yeah, but the kid who's picked on is the kid who throws the first punch?
Scott: So he's the problem.
Scott: if they take all that there are plenty of bullies around the school.
Scott: I mean if this one kid worthy of being picked up like Star Wars kid There's one Star Wars kid the whole class makes fun of Star Wars kid.
Scott: together You can't.
Scott: it's either the whole class or Star Wars kid.
Scott: One of them has got to go.
Scott: So it's very easy to just take all the loser kids out of your school.
Scott: There's maybe 20 of them per you know, I guess 500 kids.
Scott: Maybe there's 20 kids being picked on.
Scott: just get rid of them and the rest of the school's fine.
Rym: now That's really a terrible precedent.
Rym: Yep I mean now not only are these kids kicked out of the school, even though they didn't do anything Yeah, and they're usually smarter kids.
Rym: Yeah, they just may didn't do anything yet Yeah, but it's just the school is so afraid of litigation that they'll harm children in order to protect themselves from lawsuits.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: But they have to do.
Scott: is kids who are getting picked on.
Scott: they have to Figure out why those kids are being picked on and get those kids to change their ways.
Rym: Yeah, but at the same time people are being picked on for stupid reasons.
Rym: Then you take care of that and you stop the bully somehow.
Scott: Well, we think we talked.
Scott: we had an old episode on bullying didn't we?
Rym: Yeah, we did.
Scott: I think the summary was if bullies cross the line then they're bad But if they don't cross the line then the picked on kid is doing something stupid.
Rym: Yeah Well, I guess my I mean my main take on it is look at society You don't like if someone has.
Rym: If someone has a silly belief like a stupid belief or does something stupid like say we're walking down the street and someone's like Yeah, or eggs cure cancer and they're smearing eggs into their hair.
Rym: Yeah, just to have a crazy example.
Scott: and they believe it.
Scott: They're not.
Scott: they're not lying.
Rym: No They have a right to believe that.
Rym: they have a right to do whatever they want to do because it doesn't harm me that some Guys smashing eggs into his hair all day, but you know what?
Rym: It's my right to make fun of him.
Scott: Freedom of speech it you do not have a right to not be offended.
Rym: In fact, I generally think that when it comes to children and young adults.
Rym: It's a different situation because when you're that young Bullying and picking on can actually have an effect on your life and it's a bad thing.
Rym: and kids are.
Rym: Kids are kids and kids do their stupid things.
Rym: So it's a whole different ballpark and you really have to you know deal with it in ways that are complicated.
Rym: Once you're an adult If you get picked on as an adult that's there's nothing to be done about that.
Rym: freedom of speech.
Scott: see I'll go so far even to say that hate speech and What's the other?
Scott: sexual harassment speech only speech.
Scott: you know grabbing boobies is right out, you know Burning crosses on people's lawns and lynching people is right out.
Scott: Yeah, but saying you know, I guess I'll Jewish so I can say kike on the show and no one will think I'm a racist.
Scott: You know saying hey you dirty kikes.
Scott: Or saying you know, what was I?
Scott: Oh sexual harassment.
Scott: Hey, those are some nice knockers.
Scott: He got there mind if I grab him sometime, you know saying that it's okay to say that shit It's at least I say it's okay to say that.
Rym: I mean it may.
Rym: it may not be okay in terms of it's tell lightness or it's not polite or it's just a Stupid and if someone says that to you, you can slap them.
Scott: got no problem with that.
Rym: I mean basically people have a right to be a stupid asshole or an ignorant prick.
Scott: Yeah, freedom of speech means the right to say stupid shit.
Scott: No one cares if you say smart shit.
Scott: No one's ever gonna argue with you if you say something Unless you're a stupid person.
Rym: Yeah to you.
Rym: evolution.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: No, but the point is people are only gonna get mad at speech.
Scott: That is disruptive speech and freedom of speech isn't the right to say the normal speech.
Scott: You don't need a right to say normal speech because it's not under attack.
Scott: It doesn't need protection.
Scott: You have to protect the stupid evil fucktard speech.
Rym: I forget who it was who said this but I think it was a Supreme Court justice.
Rym: I'm pretty sure I quoted this on the show a while ago but there was someone who said I gave a long write-up of free speech and the ramifications and Basically, he came to the conclusion that freedom any freedom comes with risk.
Rym: If you give people the freedom to do X then there is the risk that doing X will cause why?
Rym: If you give people the freedom of speech there's the chance that they'll use that freedom to do stupid horrible things.
Rym: Mm-hmm now the Issue with a free society.
Rym: Is that a free society is one wherein not where in people let anything happen Or where it's just crazy anarchy?
Rym: It's a society where people Accept the risk of the freedoms they want and if they cannot accept the risk of a certain freedom Then they agree to give up that freedom to alleviate the risk.
Rym: If you accept the risk of a freedom you have to accept the consequences.
Rym: There's really no middle ground there.
Scott: It seems like people want the freedom to say everything they want except the things they don't like.
Rym: Yeah, that's not cool.
Rym: now if you don't like the idea of freedom of speech or you don't like the ID Risks of having freedom of speech you can go somewhere where there isn't freedom of speech.
Rym: Yeah, I mean people should be.
Rym: I should have the right to create a society for themselves.
Rym: where you don't have a freedom if they Really are fear the consequences of that but you can't force me into your society.
Scott: Yes You can if you don't like saying fuck you can you know?
Scott: Never say fuck and you can go somewhere where people don't say fuck make a little commune or whatever.
Scott: I don't care.
Scott: as long as you don't prevent me from saying fuck then I don't care.
Scott: But if you want to prevent me from saying fuck well, fuck you.
Rym: in regards to saying fuck this happened a long time ago But it wasn't national news.
Rym: It was just local news, but it made me very happy about my home state of Michigan.
Rym: There was a case that went to the Michigan State Supreme Court many years ago where a guy was canoeing I think it was at a Belle Isle or somewhere and he flipped his canoe over.
Rym: So he basically said fuck fuck fuck shit.
Rym: Damn it.
Rym: Son of a bitch.
Rym: Fuck fuck like the stream of obscenities.
Scott: I would have said that if I put my canoe over now.
Rym: there were some parents with kids on the shore who overheard there.
Rym: there was a law that you can't swear in public an old law.
Rym: So they the parents got this guy arrested and there was this whole thing and in the end it got taken all the way up to the Supreme Court of the state and The Supreme Court rules kind
Scott: of confusing because in New York the Supreme Court is the first court.
Scott: Yeah, it's fucked up.
Scott: Don't don't ignore New York courts.
Scott: Ignore that when the Supreme Court is the first court, you know, something's wrong.
Rym: Yeah, this was the highest court in the state of Michigan There you go, and it couldn't go higher than that unless it became a constitutional issue Which it didn't because this court ruled correctly.
Rym: They ruled either unanimously or almost unanimously that the Supreme Court precedent that obscene speech Which is one of the few types of speech that can be regulated by the government.
Rym: It Obscene speech is only considered obscene if it is if it one appeals to a prurient nature in man and to Conveys no meaning Or conveys no actual idea.
Rym: and they ruled that this man was conveying his anger And therefore there is nothing wrong with what he said and there can be no law abridging his right to say those words.
Scott: Everyone should just watch the Penn and Teller bullshit episode about cursing.
Rym: Yeah, I mean bear in mind the Penn and Teller show is great But it's definitely entertainment and they don't always I don't know fully vet out their opinions.
Scott: Some episodes are better than others.
Scott: Yeah the episode about how college is no good.
Scott: They spent two minutes talking about how college is no good Which I think is a pretty weak argument and spent the rest of the episode talking about how Diversity in college is stupid.
Scott: Yeah, which they basically were redundant many times.
Rym: or their show where they took aid.
Rym: I mean, we are very freedom libertarian, but they took a very pro smoking stance in one of their episodes Yeah, which honestly I I mean I I agree with their ideals.
Rym: The problem is the evidence they used to back it up was kind of flimsy and proven wrong later.
Scott: Yeah, and the you know, their argument was like you can't prove that secondhand smoke causes cancer.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I can prove the secondhand smoke smells like an asshole.
Scott: Yeah You can smoke all you want as long as the smoke never goes anywhere near me because it doesn't matter because cancer it's Unpleasant and you cannot force your unpleasantness on me.
Rym: now You know what?
Rym: I have a very simple solution to this and if it ever becomes an issue It's not an issue in New York State anymore because they made smoking in most places illegal.
Rym: still sucks on the streets Yeah, but you know what?
Rym: That's fine because I can eat in my restaurants now.
Rym: Yeah That's the only thing I hate about going to the Jersey Shore.
Rym: as I walk into a restaurant and they say smoking or not And I look at it for a second like what?
Rym: Oh, right Jersey Mm-hmm.
Scott: Well, not New York.
Rym: Yeah though a bunch of other states have banned smoking and those states and actually a lot of states haven't banned it but most Good restaurants ban it on their own anyway, because it keeps riffraff out and it keeps generally the people that suck out.
Scott: It's where the smoking is so expensive and the only people most people do it are poor like that homeless lady on our street.
Scott: It's like are they poor because they're smoking and spending all their money on it?
Scott: or are they smoking because their lives are poor and shitty?
Scott: You know?
Scott: and then the rich people who smoke what are they thinking?
Rym: Oh, they're only smoking like expensive cigars, but my solution to the whole debate about secondhand smoke is very simple All right, fine.
Rym: You can have your right to smoke cigarettes in public places around other people.
Rym: I then have my right to burn my sulfur sticks in public places around you.
Rym: It's no different It doesn't harm you in any way.
Scott: Yeah, I can just carry my stink bombs around while I wear my gas mask.
Rym: Yeah, I can choose not to shower.
Scott: Well, goddamn hippies.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, you can choose to wear a cologne that smells terrible not showering as other effects such as spreading of disease.
Scott: Yeah, so that's a little different.
Rym: But I I would love to see a movement of punk kids going around to smokers in public places burning sulfur sticks.
Scott: Let's get some fucking sulfur sticks and do it.
Rym: Well, I don't want to smell like sulfur.
Scott: I know what we do is when there's a group of smokers standing around like a door of a building We just throw a sulfur stick on the ground and keep walking.
Rym: Actually, we should do it Michael Moore style where we have a hidden camera and we film it and we pay punk kids to walk Over and stand there with the sulfur kit.
Rym: Ooh Yeah, you know what?
Rym: I think once we get that video camera, we'll have to do a few video podcasts of Michael Moore type crap, we're gonna.
Scott: we're gonna have to buy a video camera.
Rym: Yeah, cuz we're real good at causing scenes.
Scott: if anyone doesn't realize this If anyone is unaware is let's end this episode soon.
Scott: There's the episode of the Simpsons where Homer is hanging with the hippies is like Ben and Jerry or something like that.
Scott: Yeah, and he drive.
Scott: they drive around town freaking squares.
Scott: That's what we do.
Scott: We freak the squares.
Rym: Yeah, both both purposefully and by accident.
Scott: Yes Yes, we do It's.
Rym: it's one of our one of our favorite pastimes to do something weird in public and just watch people Not know how to deal with it.
Scott: Are you wanting to end the episode with the things of the day?
Rym: Yeah, so so much for a short episode.
Scott: Well, our original plan was to do an episode about Airlines and public transportation in that shit, but I guess that went out the window pretty quick.
Rym: Yeah, but as a result since we did the main bit just now we'll do the things of the day and that's it.
Scott: I don't even know what this episode was about All right.
Rym: So my thing of the day is real quick.
Rym: I don't really need to say much about it.
Rym: Remember, I'm the juggernaut bitch.
Scott: on the juggernaut bitch.
Rym: Well those guys because I thought I mean there was a lot of there were a lot of really clever jokes in that juggernaut bit How they were just masked by the fact that the audio is kind of terrible.
Rym: It was easy to miss it.
Scott: Yeah they were mumbling a lot and sometimes the volume was too low and I couldn't tell what they were saying.
Scott: and sometimes what they were saying Was very quick or it cut away and it couldn't really make out the joke.
Scott: But if you pay attention, there's a lot of funny jokes in there.
Rym: so they've gotten together again and they're going to start doing a whole bunch of episodes and they've started now with part one of The you know X-men in space series.
Rym: They're just gonna go through the whole thing.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and the production values have increased significantly.
Rym: The jokes are much better and they're right.
Rym: There are a lot of really clever little quips in there.
Scott: Yeah, but you know what?
Scott: I don't think it's gonna fly because you need the catchphrase and there's no new catchphrase.
Rym: No, there are however funny scenes.
Scott: See that's really why all your base took off and stuff Like are you gonna use?
Scott: you know didn't is because all your base had Catchphrases things that people could repeat and would repeat.
Rym: Yep I mean you can have a thing like the juggernaut thing like.
Rym: well that that has its own, you know, I'm the juggernaut bitch Yep, but this new one it's really funny, but it's not a gestalt.
Rym: It's not portable.
Scott: It's like Simpsons sit without.
Scott: I Caramba Simpsons.
Scott: Wouldn't it be here that now?
Rym: But anyway, I'm not gonna say much more about the juggernaut thing And I'm not going to make any more of my things of the day about this.
Rym: I just wanted to note to all of you out there that this is now a continuing series that I find hilarious in a terrible terrible way.
Scott: Yep, all right.
Scott: My thing today is pretty cool.
Scott: Hey Rym if you could live in any structure.
Scott: What structure would you live in?
Rym: Variety of structure I would live in some sort of interdimensional traveling Existing has known to exist some kind.
Scott: There you go castle.
Rym: You're waiting for the word castle, aren't you?
Rym: That was I almost said manor house.
Rym: You're lucky.
Rym: I said castle cars.
Scott: How could you want to live in a manor house instead of a cat?
Rym: You know why cuz it sucks to heat and cool castles without magic.
Rym: so unless you teach me some magic castles suck ass.
Scott: Castles are awesome, and if you want a castle you can go to my thing of the day.
Scott: It's a website with a bunch of castles that you can buy and live in if you really want to.
Scott: Some of them actually look nice.
Scott: They all seem to have pools instead of moats though.
Scott: I don't know what's up with that But yeah If you want to live in a castle, there's the website to hit up.
Scott: There's even a feudal castle which is wicked cool.
Scott: check this thing out Frickin giant ass ballroom with a long table and the giant rug.
Rym: I wouldn't feel comfortable in a place like that without a man servant.
Scott: It comes with a man servant.
Scott: That's he's right there.
Scott: cuz see there's the guy playing golf, and he's peeing into the other guy's cup.
Rym: His name would have to be either Norman or Alfred or I wouldn't deal with it.
Scott: Yeah, you could name whatever you want is what you're paying him.
Scott: I see this or Fred this castle costs 26 million euros, so that's more than 26 million dollars isn't it?
Rym: you know what?
Rym: forget that was buy a PlayStation 3.
Scott: Okay, PlayStation 3 or castle huh cake or death.
Rym: All right, I think we're done for the week.
Scott: Well, you'll be back.
Rym: We'll be in Philly on Saturday and Sunday or Friday night being Wildwood.
Rym: Saturday and Sunday We'll be going to cons constantly Constantly.
Scott: yeah, I'll probably be going to anime next for at least one day.
Scott: Yeah, ConnectiCon Yeah, when's ConnectiCon?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I gotta go check on that right now, but we're gonna go to it.
Rym: probably It's too close not to Yeah, anyway once again to all of our new listeners welcome I'm going to bed And that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: if you like our podcast.
Scott: you'll love our forums.
Scott: make sure you visit them.
Scott: You can send your email feedback to GeekNights at gmail.com, and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206.
Rym: GeekNights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.