Rym: It's Wednesday January 11th, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We review two pretty terrible anime Gundam F91 and Akagi.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: so My job sort of is gonna transfer me from the city to somewhere in the middle of nowhere.
Rym: wow so Well one you're gonna pay me equal rent now cuz I've been kind of subsidizing you or taking that train in whatever.
Scott: but Part of the deal is I get a big raise to buy a car that can get me You know one hour each way every day.
Rym: You know you could just take the big raise and not buy the new car.
Scott: yeah, except my car will die within like a month if I do that because it's a piece of crap and My it'll suck driving real bad.
Scott: if I had a new car at least it wouldn't be so bad driving every day.
Scott: Oh, yeah, and I need a new car.
Scott: anyway.
Scott: I was gonna buy one in like a couple years, but buying one now doesn't hurt, and it's it's.
Scott: it's Technically free because you know I'll get a raise You know equal to or greater than my monthly increased cost of living, so it'll be like whoop Plus.
Scott: you got to remember.
Scott: I'm not gonna be paying $300 a month for a train ticket.
Scott: So you know the monthly payments less than 300 a month, and then my insurance is less than my raise And I'll basically profiting still and getting a car.
Scott: so not bad.
Rym: Yeah, we'll see.
Rym: we'll see what your financing ends up being.
Scott: if I get financing who knows I might lease I might go get a loan from the bank, and then just buy it with the cash from the bank loan who knows?
Rym: yeah I don't know if I'd lease.
Scott: It's generally a bad idea You know, but it's generally a bad idea if you're.
Scott: you know plan is for long term But you know just to get a car, and then you're you want to get rid of it in two years You know it could be alright.
Scott: Oh, yeah, yeah plus.
Scott: You know a lot of people.
Scott: I know like my boss he's a lot loads of money and He just constantly leases cars, which I guess is okay.
Scott: It's like give this eternal monthly payment, and you never own a car But you always have a newish you always have a like a new car like one or two years old You never have an old jalopy, and that's kind of attractive and kind of worth.
Rym: You know yeah It's kind of attractive, but to me.
Rym: I kind of like the fact that my car isn't new.
Rym: I mean my car's not the greatest car, but it's pretty good, and it's nice to not care about it at all.
Rym: Yeah That's true.
Rym: like it like I cuz you put a nice little ding in my car from your door And I got no issues with that.
Rym: people bump into it and scratch it.
Rym: There's little paint chips on it every now and then cuz people just stupid and parking lots.
Scott: I don't care about that kind of stuff either.
Rym: really yeah, you might care if you got a brand new car though.
Scott: Well, you know not like the paint.
Scott: I would care if there was like a dent in it You know, but if you like scratched it.
Scott: I'd be like whatever.
Scott: Okay, I don't even notice scratches on cars.
Scott: Yeah Let alone get you know.
Scott: plus I would probably pay the 20 bucks to get those little strips on the side.
Scott: So if you bump something into the car it'll bump into the strip.
Scott: You know those things.
Rym: yeah, I know those things.
Scott: yeah Plus, I think those actually look better than not you know.
Scott: just a plain Body sheet see I like the plane.
Rym: I like a really minimalistic car like I like really small really streamlined solid colors Like solid colors, but I mean money.
Rym: I just buy a new Miata like right now It depends.
Scott: the thing is is whenever you look at the dealers or at least not the dealers the manufacturers of cars You know you're really smart about bodywork Like every.
Scott: I've gone to lots of car websites and things and customized cars and those little you know web application thingies and You just click and it every you can like change like the front grille piece You could change the little wings in the back and you could change like these runners around like pieces of body work near the doors trunk and windows and fenders and all that stuff.
Scott: and Whenever you click on the more expensive thing it just looks better.
Scott: every time It's like oh look without the wing the car is kind of ugly.
Scott: you click add wing and it's like oh the car looks awesome Now and then it's like hi I wonder what that little piece of body around the fender is.
Scott: you click and it changes around the fender and you're like oh?
Scott: That looks so much better.
Scott: I can't believe it.
Scott: and then by the time you've clicked all of them.
Scott: It's like the cars $5,000 more.
Rym: Well, we'll see how it goes cuz we'll be out test driving this weekend.
Scott: Yep gonna test drive a stick.
Scott: see how it goes.
Rym: Yeah, because both of us we usually both had stick cars like back in the day I didn't have one, but I do.
Rym: we knew how to drive a stick.
Rym: Yeah, it's been a long time since either of so much has touched a clutch.
Scott: yep But the the guy said you know I was like yeah, I haven't driven one in six years.
Scott: the guy was like oh, it's no problem.
Scott: I've known people come in here and after a few minutes.
Scott: They're all good, so it's not my car.
Scott: I'm gonna be test driving.
Scott: so if I destroy the transmission oops Yeah, yeah.
Rym: But in the news we got some nice anime news to go along with our soul.
Rym: anime day Full metal alchemist in Japan on March 29th.
Rym: They're releasing the FMA premium collection.
Scott: It's basically this DVD and on it will be a movie that was originally part of a ride at Universal Studios Japan.
Rym: I really want to ride.
Scott: this ride apparently is an FMA ride at Universal Studios, Japan.
Scott: what the hell I Want to go on the FMA ride?
Scott: It's not fair.
Rym: and also three short OAVs.
Rym: now one of these I'm kind of excited about.
Rym: it's a go Kuro sama.
Rym: all right You know those little chibi things like Minnie Pato Pato or a lotus island.
Rym: lotus island it looks like it's that it's the.
Scott: it's the lotus island of FMA.
Scott: But oh, it's the lotus island of the FMA movie.
Rym: Yes So it's all the characters that are in the movie.
Rym: So if you haven't seen all of the show there might be characters in the show that are not in this.
Rym: yeah Yeah, and you know what if you haven't seen full metal alchemist see it because Spoilers abound and while we won't spoil it for you someone else will And the movie will.
Scott: yep.
Rym: in fact just knowing about the movie can spoil parts of it.
Rym: so go see the show Mmm.
Scott: Yeah, I wasn't a hundred percent sure the Movie spoiled the show.
Rym: well you obviously hadn't seen the second trailer.
Rym: They released that showed things I don't know.
Scott: I saw stuff and And I saw like the first few minutes of the movie, and it didn't seem to do anything, but now I'm not so sure.
Scott: I gotta watch this damn movie.
Scott: Why don't we just watch it?
Rym: We've got it.
Scott: Let's watch it like this weekend or something all right.
Rym: We might have a review of the FMA movie real soon.
Scott: Yeah Then we'll know for sure.
Rym: Well that was quick.
Scott: not so much news today.
Scott: You know since Apple was yesterday.
Rym: yep Yep, yep, but my thing of the day is kind of might be boring, but I think it's kind of neat.
Rym: You've all played monopoly.
Rym: you know that kind of terrible board game That's really popular in the US for some reason.
Rym: they make a million million knockoffs of it like Monopoly New York Edition or Monopoly RIT Edition.
Scott: well they always call it RIT-opoly.
Scott: Yeah, or College-opoly or Stupid-opoly.
Rym: well, this is a nice little website that has a bunch of optional rules that make the game somewhat bearable.
Scott: It's not hard to make the game somewhat bearable if you enable some auctioning and you get rid of Stupidity on free party.
Rym: you know by default.
Rym: I mean most people at least that I've known who play Monopoly.
Rym: They haven't read the rulebook since they were a little kid, and they just play it wrong.
Scott: a lot of people Do play it wrong like I know.
Rym: a lot of people play where all the money that goes to the bank for whatever reason goes Into the middle and if someone lands on free parking they get all that money.
Rym: what?
Scott: yeah That's the craziest one I ever heard.
Rym: that's like the standard house rule that a lot of people I've seen crazy ones, but nothing that crazy.
Scott: I mean the way, I've seen.
Scott: it is like you put $100 in the middle and then if Someone lands on free parking they get the hundred dollars.
Scott: And then you take two hundred dollars from the bank and put it in the middle And then if you land on free parking you get 200.
Rym: Yeah, a lot of people just take all the money that goes to the bank for like luxury tax or whatever And they put it in the middle.
Rym: whoa and anyone who gets bankrupted by the by the board goes in there to all their stuff.
Scott: That's crazy.
Rym: yeah it is and Most people don't realize that the official monopoly rules at least a long time ago.
Rym: if you land on a property And you don't buy it it gets auctioned off.
Rym: Yep, most people don't play that way.
Scott: That's the way you should play.
Scott: yeah I remember there was an old DOS game that used to play that way by default But with a checkbox you could turn it to the the way most people play.
Scott: But we played it with the auction method and we'd be sitting there with our fingers on like the different buttons on the keyboard And an IBM ps1 with like little colored bits appearing.
Scott: and is a varying really monopoly is just such a It seems like with German board games.
Scott: You know there's not really a lot of effort in like Manipulating the game pieces.
Scott: some games have quite a bit, but not so not usually a whole bunch of the time Yeah, and usually when there's a lot of manipulation in a game German board game.
Rym: It's always like intrinsic to the game.
Scott: Yeah, and monopoly.
Scott: there's a lot of like this extra manipulation.
Scott: like you have to fiddle with the the houses and the hotels You have to deal out all the cards of properties and flip them over You have to hand out the money is a huge pain in the ass.
Scott: you get you know and then you get the chance.
Rym: See if I was a little kid I never just my cards my whole family use money, and I just sat there with a calculator.
Scott: I was out there with a calculator calculator and the memory.
Scott: But monopoly is really a game that I really can't stand to play it Unless you have like a real fancy set to kind of add something to it that doesn't add anything.
Scott: Yeah, no it does a little more fun.
Rym: No it doesn't.
Rym: yeah.
Rym: You could play monopoly with pieces of paper where you wrote the numbers down.
Scott: you could but you ever play monopoly with like the big Fancy wooden set with the gold pieces and everything.
Rym: no cuz that's just stupid.
Scott: It's stupid to buy one.
Scott: I agree anybody buys one isn't?
Scott: you know?
Rym: that's the equivalent of saying like yeah war or maybe a dumb game.
Rym: But uh if you play with solid gold cards it becomes awesome.
Scott: It does become a little more interesting.
Scott: You know what while the game is stupid dumb and boring you at least have something else to pay attention to.
Rym: um You know what.
Rym: if that if you actually are serious, and you're not just you know joking then you should really take up baccarat.
Scott: What's baccarat?
Rym: baccarat is the game they play in casinos?
Rym: And it's pretty much the epitome of the fact that you're playing baccarat, and it's all.
Rym: fancy is the only thing It's got going for it really the stupidest game.
Rym: I'm not going to explain how to play baccarat because it's stupid like engine Bond movies.
Rym: people play it in a movie There's always like the famous rich guy, and he plays baccarat.
Rym: It's like in the area in casinos like behind this rope.
Rym: It's it's the stupidest game ever all right.
Scott: Yeah But I mean if you're gonna play it just don't play it.
Scott: Oh, yeah of course.
Rym: and if you're gonna play it I mean just play it correctly.
Rym: You know.
Rym: follow the rules and maybe do some of these nice optional rules like my favorite one is.
Rym: You know the two utilities in the game how?
Rym: they're completely useless.
Scott: They're mostly useless.
Rym: They're completely useless.
Rym: There's absolutely no reason to ever buy them.
Rym: the return on investment is pretty much nothing.
Rym: they cannot help you win the game ever.
Rym: Well these people suggested that they should count as railroads and just extend the railroad money table accordingly.
Rym: That's not so bad that fit because then it makes you the railroad Baron strategy a real big strategy.
Scott: It does Not a bad one.
Scott: I've heard worse.
Scott: Yep I've heard of the.
Scott: there's another one where if you go to jail you got like bail yourself out or get someone to bail you out and Jail more of a suck.
Rym: all you have to do to fix that is if you're in jail you can't collect rent.
Scott: Yeah, well isn't that a rule anyway?
Rym: No?
Scott: Oh that we've always played where if you're in jail you don't get dick.
Rym: That's a good thing to do because otherwise it's a good strategy to put yourself in jail for most of the game after all the Yeah, also you think you should make it harder to get at it.
Scott: Or like you know cuz what can you do to get out of jail like pay?
Scott: $50 or wait three turns or wait three turns.
Scott: Oh if you roll doubles though you get out right.
Scott: yeah That's kind of okay.
Scott: It should be harder to get at it or get it.
Rym: It shouldn't be hard to get out of jail because getting into jail is completely random arbitrary and stupid.
Rym: There's nothing you do that puts you in jail.
Rym: It just happens to you.
Scott: Well because the game is called monopoly right.
Rym: so the logic is that you're committing illegal business dealings constantly Build my hotels and I provide legitimate services to people in exchange for money.
Scott: I find that laughable.
Rym: Hey, you ever stayed in my apartment in Baltic.
Scott: Yeah, what are you doing with that monocle top hat?
Scott: sack of money?
Rym: Monocle top hat?
Rym: what I was always the car or the little dog.
Scott: I was always the battleship, but that's not the poor the iron, but that's not the point.
Scott: the point is That mr.. Monopoly is an evil business fucker.
Rym: No, what if he's one of the old-school capitalists who give money back?
Rym: You know the kind?
Scott: if they were around today would also be in jail Like Rockefeller.
Scott: he built Rockefeller Center, and so yeah he the same thing that people like Warren Buffett and Bill Gates first they do a bunch of evil and they get real rich.
Scott: then they feel bad so they become all.
Scott: You know the word for people who give money away philanthropy.
Scott: yeah, that's the one I knew.
Scott: it was tropic something.
Rym: See the problem is a lot of.
Rym: I mean back in the day there were bad people But at least there were bad people who did some good.
Rym: It seems like most of the uber capitalists these days don't give anything back, and they're not even really capitalist.
Scott: Adam Smith like yeah They just say the word capitalism to me, and I can do whatever I want even if it's evil.
Rym: Yeah, we'll do it.
Rym: We'll get into that some other day.
Scott: Yeah, we don't do that.
Rym: Scott Do you have a thing of the day?
Rym: Yeah?
Scott: I had a funny thing, but and it was a video and it was on Google videos as usual and at work I got to it just fine, but now when I get home to go check it out.
Scott: It's like gone.
Scott: So I had to pick something else.
Scott: That's not as cool, but also not completely lame.
Scott: You know the Hubble telescope?
Scott: Yeah, yeah, it's awesome, and it takes lots of nice pictures that everyone enjoys.
Scott: It can actually take crazy high-resolution pictures, but you never see those if you're just a Joe Schmo.
Scott: Well on the hubble website They have here you can download full Hubble telescope resolution pictures.
Rym: They're big.
Scott: the biggest one is 18,000 by 18,000 pixels.
Rym: there's a warning on the website telling you that if you don't have a lot of RAM Don't download it because it'll probably crash your computer.
Scott: Yeah The big JPEG file is 23 megabytes and the small one which is only six thousand by six thousand pixels Is is only like three megabytes.
Scott: But they have TIFF images which have absolutely no compression whatsoever.
Scott: The small one is 50 megs and the big one is almost 400 megs.
Scott: Yeah, I don't even have 512 megs of RAM all right.
Rym: I dare you to open that.
Scott: I could but Linux Wouldn't care, but Linux wouldn't care.
Scott: it thrash though Windows would crash on my computer But on my work laptop has two gigs of RAM, so I'd be safe.
Rym: maybe Definitely, but still because I was thinking about Windows allocating that RAM properly.
Scott: yeah I just don't want to sit around to download a 400 meg 18,000 by 18,000 picture.
Scott: But I did look at the low-resolution JPEG which is only eight thousand six thousand by six thousand.
Scott: Let me tell you it's really awesome to look at this thing Like stars, which you can't even see.
Scott: you can see like a speck on this thing and Like in the nebula galaxy.
Scott: I think it's a nebula looked in the middle nebula to me.
Scott: You can see like all the details of the nebula.
Rym: It's crazy All right, so it's anime day, and we've got two anime to review and they're all pretty terrible.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, we watched a mobile suit Gundam F91 which is a movie.
Rym: This is a Gundam movie made in 1991 and we watched Akagi Which is some new show and we're gonna start with Gundam because I got to get this out of my head.
Rym: Yep, so well let's talk about the movie what it is first all right well It's it's in the whatever the universal whatever got entries.
Scott: Yeah, it's the it's the default Gundam universe.
Scott: it story about.
Scott: There's some space colonies and then these this pirate group called like.
Scott: what was it?
Scott: crossbone vanguard crossbone vanguard.
Rym: they're like like think about Revolutionary France reactionaries, that's what they're like.
Scott: yeah So these people want to take over a bunch of space colonies because what's has been peace for so long?
Scott: That like all the earth the big head honchos of earth are like just relaxing on earth being losers And you know being all leisurely and not being serious and You know all the normal people have to stay in the colonies.
Scott: They can't go relax on earth.
Scott: so the crossbone vanguard is like we're gonna take over a bunch of colonies and get those people to convert to our us and then go attack the earth.
Rym: now that may sound dumb and it is and it may sound like we're oversimplifying but We're not.
Scott: well see that in itself.
Scott: Well not exactly being the greatest plot anyone's ever come up with isn't really what makes it so incredibly dumb.
Rym: That's like point one percent of the show.
Rym: see if you've seen Gundam seed or the original Gundam or any of those long Gundams.
Rym: you know 50 episodes of robots Mm-hmm.
Rym: imagine if they took all that plot and all those characters and all those events and scrunch them down into a little movie.
Scott: See now this isn't like a summary movie like you know the macross movie.
Scott: Well the macross plus movie takes the four or was it four?
Scott: I think there are four episodes of the macross plus oav and it just compresses them into a single movie and takes some you know Modifications, so it makes sense.
Scott: the This isn't a summary of some 50 episode series.
Scott: This is a movie that was made as a movie You know with content that appears nowhere else, and they didn't like edit it into a shorter movie.
Scott: They just literally just squished it.
Rym: It's just scene scene scene scene scene scene scene with no breakup.
Rym: No, we I mean honestly it may sound like real vague when we actually talk about this in more detail.
Rym: That's because we watched it carefully and we have almost no idea as to what actually happened.
Rym: pretty much They introduced characters like so rapidly like I mean it starts out fine like there's like eight Characters that I could identify, but that's fine because there's like this hectic or scene.
Rym: There's all these civilians and like people are attacking the colony, and it's ignoring the war.
Rym: It's just showing these civilians trying to get away.
Rym: It's real hectic and hard to follow which I thought was cool You know.
Rym: and then it stays just as hectic and hard to follow For the whole movie.
Rym: and they introduced like nine more characters, and then two of them die like right away.
Rym: They introduced characters that all look the same so you can't tell who's who and everyone is everyone's father.
Scott: Yeah, and they keep referring to people like different people with different names And you're not quite sure which names go with which people yet But they're already referring to people off-screen by their name, and you're like who which one is which I don't know.
Rym: also There ends up being to one character who has two different names, and she's confused because they're calling by name She doesn't recognize which only served to confuse us.
Scott: Yeah It's just real confusing and kind of silly.
Rym: I mean there's a guy in an orange suit who's someone's dad and we sat there watching the show debating with each other whose dad It was and then there was another guy in another orange suit.
Scott: It was also someone's dad someone else's dad and one guy was doing good and one guy was doing bad And you couldn't really tell what was going on.
Rym: there was a significant amount of time where I thought they were the same person.
Scott: I definitely thought they were the same person.
Rym: for a few minutes It and it just keeps going and and going and going and there's these bugs And they try to kill everyone in the colony, but and then there's this woman.
Rym: There's another woman who looks just like her who has nothing to do with her.
Rym: mm-hmm.
Rym: people defect from both sides to the other sides But they don't actually show them defecting.
Rym: they just show them on the other side, and you don't know why they're there.
Scott: Yeah, it's like they mentioned it in like a sentence or like like.
Scott: there are characters like The the guy the crossbone vanguard's Leader's son is like a robot pilot, and you see him like early on.
Scott: you're like okay.
Scott: I know that kind of character.
Scott: That's kind of like Who's the crazy guy in Escaflowne with the white hair?
Rym: Oh Delando?
Rym: Yeah?
Scott: It's kind of like that kind of character not as crazy though, but you know spills the same niche.
Scott: You see him once then you see him again But his character doesn't develop, and you don't.
Scott: it's just like oh here.
Scott: He is says a sentence about him.
Scott: Nothing really happens with him And it's like what.
Scott: why did they name this character and put him there to fill my head with more things to figure out?
Scott: When he doesn't really mean anything?
Scott: shit has not had that character.
Scott: He didn't do anything for the movie, and there were a lot of characters like that.
Scott: Yeah shouldn't have been in there.
Rym: It's like there's no one.
Rym: no faceless drone.
Rym: every single person was a person.
Rym: We have a 90% of the people which would have been cool if I if I'd known what the hell was going on.
Rym: Yeah, I was never sure who to pay attention to.
Rym: there'd be someone and you think they're important And then they just wouldn't be.
Scott: it's like you know in a Gundam when they have like the bridge of a ship you had Of the good ship you always had the captain and the whole.
Scott: all the people in there are recognizable and constant.
Scott: So it's like when I look at the captain of the ship.
Scott: I'm like oh, there's the captain of the ship.
Scott: I got to pay attention to them.
Scott: That's another character to remember.
Rym: captain does almost nothing.
Scott: ten does nothing.
Scott: they didn't even need to put the captain in the words.
Rym: The captain looks just like the female protagonist, and I thought it was her.
Rym: at first.
Rym: I couldn't figure out why she was captaining a ship.
Scott: yep It was messed up.
Rym: and and then the female protagonist to make it worse everyone's everyone's everyone's dad and mom whatever.
Rym: She has two dads and one of them dies suddenly.
Rym: Yeah, and by dies suddenly I mean quite literally.
Rym: they're talking and then he just like does a pratfall and she cries And I still don't know what the hell that was all about.
Scott: and it's like all Usual scenes that animes have for you to figure stuff out right are removed.
Scott: so like you know she Her dad dies she cries, but then they don't have like the mourning and consolation scenes like you.
Scott: completely forget that like her dad died And it doesn't have any meaning because you didn't have time to like absorb that.
Scott: it was just onto the next thing and that's never Really referred to again.
Scott: Maybe like in passing like in a sentence once and I just I didn't identify with any character.
Rym: I didn't follow any character.
Rym: I wasn't entirely sure who the protagonist was until I noticed one guy's name was said more often than anyone else's names And I figured out who that name was associated.
Scott: Yeah the problem.
Scott: I had him figure out the protagonist.
Scott: I did read the protagonist name on the back of the DVD case so that helped.
Scott: But at the same time is I really didn't know which one he was because at the beginning they had The opening scene was it was a guy on stage and a guy in the crowd And they both seemed like they were main guys.
Scott: It was Dwight and Arno right.
Rym: I don't fucking know.
Scott: anyway one of them Had like a dad who was a military guy and one of them was the main guy.
Scott: But at the beginning of the show they were both had equal screen time and were doing equally important things and had equal Interaction with like the head female who was pretty quickly obviously the head female
Rym: yep
Scott: Though I didn't know which one is the main character until like one guy just stopped showing up.
Rym: Yeah, whatever happened to him.
Scott: I don't know don't ask me.
Rym: The thing is that the one thing that this show had is one of the really high production values for 1991.
Scott: Yeah, it was made in 91, and it looked like it was made in like 2000 something I just wish they would have put some of that money into making it not suck.
Scott: They put all the money into animation and robot battles which I guess is okay.
Rym: I mean and I gotta say it had every single Gundam cliche Right down to like right away.
Rym: There's the the moral of the show.
Rym: war is bad like right away someone dies and they have this moment of oh war is horrible.
Rym: Why do people fight?
Rym: Oh my god, and Then they have a guy in a mask who's the evil guy?
Rym: he's the square boss and then there's the guy who you think is the evil guy who isn't really.
Rym: and there's there's the guy who's gonna sacrifice himself to save everyone.
Scott: and Yeah, it's got everything.
Rym: It's just it's not worth watching.
Rym: I don't I don't know what happened.
Rym: I bet I could watch it two more times and still have no clue how it ended or what was going on.
Scott: You know what it's good for.
Scott: if you just like watching robot battles This is pretty much the the most robot battle you can get.
Scott: you know what?
Rym: yeah There's a lot of robot battle But it doesn't focus on any one robot fighting long enough for you to know what's going on in the fighting.
Scott: Yeah, but you just like watching robot battles in their raw form.
Scott: This is the way to go.
Rym: you can't even tell who's fighting on what side or who's winning or losing or who's shooting at who?
Rym: It's just robots flying around hitting each other.
Scott: Yeah, I'm saying is that if all you want to see is robots flatter on hitting each other This is the way to go.
Scott: it has no other purpose.
Rym: All right also that they all.
Rym: it's also real implausible and Not just implausible in a giant robots way But implausible in that every major plot development seems to occur when someone overhears someone saying something Despite the fact that they're in space and separate mechs.
Scott: Well, I think they say they like a mention in passing a few times like one time people had a direct wire hookup between Gundams and yeah Or something because at the end they all get psychic powers.
Scott: Oh, yeah, there was some psychic power.
Scott: should I completely ignored?
Rym: Yeah, and then the the the final scene which had a chance to make the movie meaningful in some minor way and they ruined it.
Rym: We're not gonna spoil it But if you watch this movie and you get to the end and you think wow that was kind of sad and poignant no It's stupid.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: They ruin it.
Rym: so who bought this movie.
Scott: I bought it on sale at media play so whatever.
Scott: yeah I mean if it was full price, I would have been pissed but 40% off who cares?
Rym: Now the other show we watched and all I got to warn you about this show is that of the three anime?
Rym: We watched to figure out what to talk about.
Rym: This was the best of them.
Rym: so beware next week when we talk about the other two.
Scott: Yeah So this one is called Akagi like Mount Akagi from initial D Which is kind of funny because this is an initial D type show.
Scott: only it's an initial D type show about It's it's you know it's also if you don't know initial D. It's a Hikaru no go type of show or Prince of Tennis or any of those shows.
Scott: That's like about a hobby you know and then it's people doing that hobby dramatically and with energy and Teaching you about the hobby of you know whatever it is.
Scott: the hobby for this show is mahjong.
Rym: Mahjong not.
Scott: mahjong is in what you play on your freaking Windows computer and not mahjong as in what old Jewish ladies play It's or even what old Chinese guys play.
Scott: Yeah, it's mahjong of what?
Scott: gambling Japanese yakuza play and The thing that really got me is This not it's not like go or you could keep teaching people things for like 50 episodes or more of it.
Rym: Explain how to teach how to play mahjong in like half the first episode.
Scott: It's not a difficult game.
Rym: I could teach you in like five minutes I mean, but I mean there's a lot of ceremony and a lot of craft and a lot of stupid arbitrary things to remember in mahjong But it's essentially gin rummy with little tile.
Rym: Yeah, it's not if the game is just complete lock Basically once you know the basic statistics.
Rym: It's just a game of luck.
Scott: It's pretty much a game of luck and watching what other people put out But you can just look on the table and see what they put out.
Scott: It's it's yeah information.
Scott: So it's paying attention and luck now.
Rym: I'll warn you ahead of time you fry don't care.
Rym: We're gonna spoil the first episode of the show.
Rym: we're gonna spoil the one plot point that we find in this show.
Rym: because Yeah
Scott: So the show starts out where this guy is playing mahjong against some gamblers supposedly for his light against some yakuza Supposedly for his life or at least for his debt, and he's not doing so well And he's all frustrated
Rym: and it's going into great detail about what's going on in mahjong Hand and he's talking like I've got the blah blah blah blah blah blah blah blah blah.
Rym: I don't.
Scott: I can't say mahjong jargon fast enough, so yeah, you know just like all those other shows like oh he's you know He's got car head cam.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Oh his car is turbo.
Scott: You're not gonna win.
Scott: You know he's gonna do the super drift technique blah blah blah.
Scott: only mahjong talk.
Rym: Yeah, but there's no move of God and mahjong It's just pick up a tile and throw a tile down and then flip all your tiles over when you win.
Scott: Yeah, that's all it is so.
Scott: and of course they had the gambling part Which is at least add something.
Rym: no all it adds is flip the tiles over and then collect money from people.
Scott: Yeah pretty much anyway, so The guy is playing for his life, and then all of a sudden this Punk kid shows up like a 13 year old punk kid just shows up at this gambling parlor.
Scott: So the first they're like get the hell out of here, but the guy who's losing is like hey Maybe I need to take a break cuz I'm all nervous.
Scott: Maybe I'll use this kid as an excuse.
Scott: You know what you know what luck.
Scott: So he talks to the kid for like a minute or two.
Rym: then and this is all like crazy dramatic Crazy.
Rym: everything that happens in the show every single instant is just filled with drama.
Scott: That's what they do in these types of shows.
Scott: We still need a word for these types of shows.
Rym: Yeah, we do.
Scott: I'll make one up eventually.
Rym: So he's talking to this kid and then he like the Yakuza want to play again.
Rym: They get back to playing their mahjong, and he comes to a point where he could throw out like a two or a five tile.
Rym: And he's debating because tossing out the five tile is the like the the risky.
Rym: if the other guy needs it he wins But otherwise I have a really good chance of winning.
Rym: or the two tile Which is like the safe throw out and he's about to throw out the two and then the kid Yells at him like you can't do that.
Rym: that just means you're a gambler at the end of his rope.
Rym: You're not taking the risk blah blah blah.
Rym: I can tell Yeah, and the guy's like what you played mahjong and he's like mahjong.
Scott: Yeah, I never played that in my life.
Rym: I can just tell by looking at you and then the guy has this dramatic internal monologue where he's all.
Rym: oh Yes, I must take the risk blah blah blah because I am a gambler.
Scott: then he throws out the five Mm-hmm, and he wins that hand actually.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: He does.
Scott: and then eventually within a minute or two this is on the first episode by the way, the kid be starts playing this game and The kids playing and he starts to kick major ass like whoa, he's winning.
Scott: Then a cop shows up and you learn the plot of the kid is that he's a bad punk kid and he's gonna get in Trouble.
Scott: so then you have the cop hanging out with the main character guy while this kid plays mahjong against the Yakuza All right.
Rym: now what's going on here?
Rym: because this is this is like.
Rym: this is what made the show go from.
Rym: this is the stupidest thing ever - this is the stupidest thing ever with one moment that made us scream and yell and laugh.
Scott: and it's also the one thing that Raises this above the other three shows.
Scott: we watched by the by once nanometer.
Rym: cuz this they do something in the show That's never really been done before.
Rym: so He's playing and he's got like the makings of an awesome awesome hand that'll like super win him the game of mahjong Yep, like a million million points like the dragon tiles.
Scott: and the guy who's who?
Scott: The guy who's in super debt sees the hand and he's like, oh my god He's.
Scott: does he know this guy's never played before?
Scott: does he know what he has in his hand?
Rym: But then the pile he needs to complete this thing and pull off the awesome passes by until eventually like multiple times Until they're all gone and there's no way he can win now and the guy watching is like what?
Rym: Oh, no now I'm gonna die.
Rym: He's gonna lose cuz he's stupid.
Scott: He could have just won and gotten a zillion dollars.
Scott: Oh my god.
Rym: So then the cops are there and they're distracting and then he looks up and he sees the kids hand again And he sees that no the kid actually does have the whole crazy dragon hand Cuz.
Scott: what the kid did is cheat.
Rym: Yeah friggin cheated He.
Scott: just he just pulled the tiles right off the table.
Scott: And since everyone else was worried about the cops being Yakuza.
Rym: They didn't notice Yeah, I didn't see that coming.
Scott: Yeah, I mean imagine if initial D had cheating or if he car no go ahead cheating.
Rym: Yeah, imagine that her car no go he just you know flipped over the other guys.
Rym: He flipped the other guy's tile or a little a pebble off the board.
Rym: Yep when he wasn't looking That'd be great.
Rym: So then like eating technique go Spoilers for like the next many episodes of the show and it just follows the initial D format of.
Rym: he fights bigger and bigger Mahjong guys as far as I can tell like and the cheating thing just keeps going.
Rym: There's one guy who tries to cheat against him, but he'll cheat back.
Rym: Well, which I guess is all they could do because mahjong there's not much to that game.
Scott: Yeah, imagine if we made a show we should I got we should make a parody where it's coin tossing.
Scott: I am the ultimate coin tosser.
Scott: I always know if it is heads or tails thing But I put the poison in your cup.
Rym: therefore blah blah blah blah blah.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: I have a two-headed coin.
Scott: Aha, but look at mine.
Scott: It is actually a. it is it is not a two-headed coin But it has holograms on both sides so I can make it heads or tails.
Rym: at my whim heads or tails I say it's going to land on its edge.
Rym: what?
Rym: but such a thing has never happened.
Scott: I'll use my magic always lend an edge coin.
Scott: Look at my sleight of hand skill.
Scott: Apparently this thing started out in this manga that was printed in a mahjong magazine like a few pages You know in this magazine once in a while, and it got crazy popular somehow I don't know how because the arts.
Scott: so we should talk about the art being all weird.
Rym: It's real real weird.
Rym: like for a second.
Rym: I thought it reminded me of a show that's old and crappy called ji baku, but I watched ji baku again And no I was just dumb.
Scott: Imagine if everyone's real pointy and scratchy.
Rym: pointy and scratchy with really thick lines.
Scott: Yeah, so like the noses are like knives and the chins are like knives like they'll stab you It's just scary.
Rym: It's worth watching.
Rym: if you want to laugh.
Scott: I Recommend watching at least just the first episode.
Scott: It's like you know if you know anything about mahjong at all if you've ever seen it or even if you haven't seen it.
Scott: Just to watch it and laugh, but to watch more than one episode you got a really like it for some reason.
Rym: Yeah, I mean even initial D Which is the same kind of show really?
Rym: When we first saw it we saw the first four episodes and we walked out of our anime club thinking that was the stupidest thing Ever.
Rym: hmm, but I wonder if he wins and then we end up watching the whole show and loving it.
Scott: Well, it's cuz.
Scott: initial D. At least had music to get an energy like you could get into it.
Scott: You know it like had the suspense that you could if you if you really wanted to enjoy the show.
Rym: Hey, Akagi has suspense.
Rym: It has a whole shit ton of it.
Rym: It's nothing but suspense.
Scott: Yeah, but it didn't have the same.
Scott: There's just something you know granted.
Scott: It's the same genre of show and initial D. Doesn't have much more to it than Akagi does but at least car racing at least has a little bit of.
Scott: It's not a first of all it's not just randomness It's actually something to it.
Scott: And it has that live action.
Scott: like cars are driving suspense as opposed to mahjong.
Rym: We're just people sitting there and at least go and across.
Rym: well It's also just people sitting there.
Rym: at least go.
Rym: has the actual strategy.
Rym: think about it.
Scott: Yeah, every episode of a carnal go you learn like techniques and things.
Scott: so there's actually something to that.
Rym: Prince of tennis is kind of But whatever I don't think it's a tennis actually teaches you about ten.
Scott: no no no I think that might not even actually be in the same genre.
Scott: I think it's a. it's just a like a high school story.
Scott: No, I don't know.
Scott: I haven't really seen it.
Rym: It is very much the same kind of show Is it really?
Rym: it has more drama in it?
Rym: But it's very much the prodigy kid who becomes awesome and faces greater and greater challenges, okay?
Scott: But anyway yet it.
Scott: this show is just like all those shows except It's missing that little tiny bit of magic that makes it something you want to watch.
Rym: I guess I was assuming that maybe they made it as a joke to make fun of those other shows.
Scott: That would it be alright, but then why do you assume that?
Scott: because then why did we use computers to like?
Rym: The mahjong tiles if you've seen the first season of initial D like the first half.
Rym: It's pretty much PlayStation 1 graphics mm-hmm.
Rym: So it's normal animation, but whenever the cars are on it's like this terrible 3d Whatever they do the mahjong tiles like that.
Scott: Yeah, well, it's not PlayStation 1 graphics, but it's not exactly the greatest.
Scott: It's just obvious CG for the mahjong tiles when the rest of it is the horrible pointy animation.
Scott: It's horrible very horrible, and this is the best of the shows we watched.
Rym: Yeah, I mean we watched a couple other shows.
Rym: What was that wings of?
Rym: Raima Rheem Rina Rheem Rheem yeah, and then some show that ended up just being about like magical cat girls.
Scott: Yeah We'll talk about those next week.
Rym: Yeah, cuz if you thought Gundam f91 was confusing this wings of whatever show is like that times a million.
Rym: Exactly we pretty much sat there watching it.
Rym: We watched the whole.
Scott: just save it for next week.
Rym: all right all right all right.
Rym: So then are we out and that was GeekNights with Rym and Scott special?
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Thanks for listening.
Scott: Please remember to point your favorite podcatcher at feeds feed burner comm slash.
Scott: GeekNights to get the latest episodes as soon as they're released.
Scott: Also, please visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com for the latest updates and forum discussion and whether you love or hate our podcast.
Scott: We won't know unless you send your feedback to us at GeekNights at gmail.com.